<filme>
 <id>
  1414
 </id>
 <imdburl>
  http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0112702
 </imdburl>
 <ano>
  1995
 </ano>
 <titulo>
  Coldblooded
 </titulo>
 <rating>
  6.4
 </rating>
 <sinopse>
  Cosmo, an affectless mob bookie who lives in the basement of a retirement home, is promoted to hitman. He learns his new trade from Steve, a seasoned killer. He falls in love with a yoga ... &nbsp;&raquo;
 </sinopse>
 <storyline>
  Cosmo, an affectless mob bookie who lives in the basement of a retirement home, is promoted to hitman. He learns his new trade from Steve, a seasoned killer. He falls in love with a yoga teacher, Jasmine, and must figure out a way to leave the mob so they can be together.
 </storyline>
 <generos>
  <genero>
   Action
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Comedy
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Thriller
  </genero>
 </generos>
 <keywords>
  <keyword>
   basement
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   hitman
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   yoga
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   champagne
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   doctor
  </keyword>
 </keywords>
 <diretores>
  <diretor>
   Wallace Wolodarsky
  </diretor>
 </diretores>
 <escritores>
  <escritor>
   Wallace Wolodarsky
  </escritor>
 </escritores>
 <atores>
  <ator>
   Jason Priestley
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Kimberly Williams-Paisley
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Peter Riegert
  </ator>
 </atores>
 <reviews>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Point poorly made
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    drystyx
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/7/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Wolodarsky hasn't a clue. He obviously tries to make a point about the self righteous attitude people have towards others. It's a good point. It was a point poorly made here. A bookie is promoted to hit man. Okay, there's the first clue we have that Wolodarsky doesn't have a clue. He must never have been outside his drawing room. The idea is beyond ludicrous. A bookie is the last person you would want for a hit man. A bookie is working with numbers and times. The bookie is the community's retired man, whom the law knows about, whom the tea party ladies know about, who performs the local service. Often, the mob does drag him in for their own profits, too. However, no one outside of the bubble boy community will believe a bookie would make a natural hit man by virtue of being a bookie. So, the premise is that the "new hit man" is an "everyman", but here again it fails. This "everyman", we learn at the end, is a complete psychopath. The movie spends over an hour on what Saturday Night Live could say in 30 seconds. The idea is that whenever someone is "whacked", the people who know have to "raionalize" it. They need to justify it. Indeed, nearly ever murder, ever atrocity, every war crime, is "self justified" this way. The people who learn of it must think the victim deserves it. It's not funny. It's not even dark humor. It fails miserably. It probably would have been a decent 2 minute sketch or short. But again, Wolodarsky just doesn't have a clue.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Off-beat, dark, and very entertaining
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ema-50
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/2/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I started watching this movie about 10 minutes into it, and I had to see it to the end. Lovely story, great acting, with some truly original scenes. Jason may seem a bit helpless, but that's just clever acting/directing. I'm happy to see that I'm not alone in appreciating this movie. The only thing i can fault this movie for, is casting a teen idol in a grownup movie. But that doesn't diminish the movie in itself. (In that respect it's similar to "17 again", which I also enjoyed a lot.) The fact that I saw it on TV just now (2010) goes to show that this movie has staying power. Brilliant stuff.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I thought I was the only one who loved this movie!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    sumdumgai13
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/2/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Like many of you here, when I saw that Jason Priestly was played the main character I had little hope of enjoying this film (even though I am a closet fan of the first season or two of 90210). I was more than pleasantly surprised when not only was the movie GREAT!!!, but Jason Priestly nailed his performance (and of course the rest of the supporting cast as well. I loved the subtle humor. I loved everything about this movie. This is not spoiler, so I am not going to elaborate. Do yourself a favor, if you can find this movie, rent it. If you like movies like Pulp fiction (as I do), you will love this movie. I just can't believe more people don't know about this movie. I stumbled into here because I found that I couldn't rent this from Netflix so I have decided to buy if from Amazon.com. My wife will soon be a fan of this movie too. It sucks I am going to have to dust off the VCR to watch it though.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    nice hidden gem
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    karo-6
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/11/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is one of those films that i catch by accident on TV while eating a dinner, and that immediately raise my eyebrows, set up a big question-mark above my head, make me forget about how good dinner i cooked, and instead make me immediately look up the title on IMDb while first set of commercials is on. First i see a face from sugary Beverly Hills in a _very_ different role, and he seems to be a hit-man (i didn't see the beginning of the movie), but he goes to yoga classes, and he seems to be at once simple and honest (and a virgin), and a successful professional killer, and the movie seems to somehow balance the opposites quite skillfully. Really, i can still feel my eyebrows up there where they were for the most of the movie. I laughed hard in few places, but like with best films, those funniest scenes had absolutely nothing obviously funny in them... it's the absurdness of the characters and their situations that makes those so funny. Still, i didn't feel this to be a comedy at all, it's here that saw people call it a dark comedy. Well, it's dark alright, and strangely uncomfortable, but i did laugh hard in some scenes so i guess it qualifies as comedy too. Anyway, if you like quirky off-the-beaten-path films, this is one you won't regret seeing.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A DVD Is Long Overdue.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    screenman
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/5/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I was shown this movie last night by someone who had got hold of it on video somehow. At first I was sceptical about his praise, never having heard of it. But soon it had my full attention. Most of the other commentators have hit it right on the mark as a piece of top-drawer black comedy. Jason Priestley is extremely well cast as the nerdish but alarming bookworm turned hit-man. That distracted, rather troubled, stare lends him the sort of frightening expression one sees on those faces of homicidal delinquents all too often featured in the news. It really is creepy. And yet his personality is one of insecurity and psychological vulnerability. He is sexually inexperienced from an emotional standpoint, despite regular visits from a hooker. When it comes to addressing his feelings towards a girl he actually likes; he's lost. We see him blackmailing the ex-boyfriend for seduction and romantic tips, on pain of execution. Later he is even picking the brains of imminent victims. His body language is awkward and childishly gauche, very reminiscent of 'Frank Spencer' in 'Some Mothers Do 'Ave 'Em'. In typical nerdy style he is completely lacking in ambition. He lives in a bedsit basement and is quite content there despite the huge pay rise when promoted to hit-man. Someone suggests he buys a suit to go on a date. And he goes and buys one suit. Priestley's character is groomed for a career in murder by an established and very capable assassin nicely performed by Peter Riegert. This tutor displays an excellent balance of patience and pathos, guiding his new prot&eacute;g&eacute; with a fatherly indulgence. But he is utterly ruthless in a world-weary way, whilst privately haunted by demons. 'The Man' is played to oleaginous perfection by ageing Robert Loggia. His is that kind avuncular charm, concealing an unutterable callousness that you've seen in plenty of other mafia movies. He's just so nice; you know he must be rotten to the core. And so the movie ticks along at its own pace and in its own direction, by an off-beat way that pays very little heed to precedent. You never know quite what's going to happen. I was astonished to see the great Micheal J Fox given little more than a cameo part, only to be obliterated without compunction. There was no DeLorean to save him this time around. The script goes along with it all. There are no really fancy one-liners, just good, steady, dialogue that seems entirely plausible when uttered by the players. The nearest comparison I can think of for this movie is the equally off-beat, violent, and darkly humorous 'Fargo'. And if that ain't a recommendation, I don't know what is. It's lack of availability on DVD is preposterous. Not only is the movie done a dis-service; a great deal of potential revenue is being lost. Don't miss it if you get the chance. This is a cult movie crying out for its audience.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Cold blooded black comedy
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    merklekranz
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/3/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Take one very introverted bookmaker and transform him into a highly successful hit-man. Now add an attractive yoga instructor to the mix and you have a talented killer in love. Though he clearly enjoys his work, he has no clue about relationships. This off-beat scenario easily drives "Cold Blooded" into black comedy territory. With sharp dialog, and fine acting from Jason Priestly, Kimberly Williams, Peter Riegert, and Robert Loggia, this is a must see for admirers of dark humor. The clever script is never boring, but is unpredictable and charming in a perverse sort of way. There is no DVD, but I highly recommend seeking out a VHS copy. - MERK
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Discreet Charm of the Film Noir in Hit Land
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    chowse1
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/1/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is the film that goes all the way to prove that understatement is often more amusing than anything else. Lacking slapstick, funny "characters" and too predictable situations it wanders along its own path and lets us go along. If we want. If we don't, that's okay but we'll miss the fun. Jason Priestly portrays a slacker who finds a calling. He also discovers Yoga and the teacher of same. Peter Riegert gives the sliest performance as the "instructor" for Priestly who quickly discovers that sometimes instinct needs no teaching. There is a delusional casualness to the lives and actions of all involved but this underscores the simplistic plot that relies on character and performance rather than stultified situations. (Garofalo must be the most dis-interested prostitute on screen.) But it all works. One hopes this will over time get a DVD and more exposure. A cult favourite in the making.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An unexpected delight.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    BA_Harrison
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/10/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    With so many over-hyped major releases of recent years proving to be bitter disappointments, it's a real treat when I get to watch an older, lesser-known film with no expectations and am blown away by what I see. Director Wallace Wolodarsky's Coldblooded is such a film. Jason Priestley (of Beverley Hills 90210 fame) plays Cosmo, a socially inept loner working as a bookie for an organised crime syndicate, who unwillingly becomes a hit-man when his gangster boss makes him an offer he can't refuse. After being sent to work alongside seasoned gunman Steve (Peter Riegert), in order to learn the ropes, Cosmo discovers that he is a natural when it comes to dishing out death. Completely ruthless, quick thinking, and a great shot, he takes to the job like a duck to water, but also finds that wasting people for a living is rather stressful. In order to try and relax, he begins yoga, and soon falls for the pretty teacher who takes his class. But is it possible for him to continue in his line of work and be in love at the same time? A quirky blend of dark humour and extreme violence, Coldblooded is a delight from start to finish. Priestly excels as Cosmo, a character that you cannot help but like, despite his monstrous ability to shoot complete strangers without skipping a heartbeat. The young killer's deadpan expression and bizarre mannerisms suggest that his mind functions in a manner different to mosthis perception of right and wrong is certainly severely distortedand whilst this doesn't excuse the fact that he is a brutal murderer, it makes his actions little easier to understand and, perhaps, even forgive. The smart script, also by Wolodarsky, brims with offbeat moments, great incidental characters, and inky black comedy, and his talented cast (which includes great turns by Robert Loggia, as Cosmo's boss, and Kimberly Williams as his girlfriend, plus fine cameos from Janeane Garofolo and Michael J. Fox) don't put a foot wrong, delivering some truly excellent performances. If you too are weary of overblown summer blockbusters that don't live up to the hype, track down this little gem of a movie to be reminded how good cinema can be when it's done right.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An excellent and unjustly overlooked deadpan black comedy gem
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Woodyanders (Woodyanders@aol.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/7/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Beverly Hills 90210" star hunk Jason Priestley gives a startlingly able and engaging performance as Cosmo, a quiet, passive, thoroughly nebbishy and unassuming recluse who works as a bookie for a mob syndicate. When new capo Gordon (a perfectly pernicious Robert Loggia) becomes gang leader after the previous crime boss croaks, Cosmo gets promoted to hit-man. Under the sage, expert tutelage of laid-back, but weary, boozy and guilt-wracked rub-out artist par excellence Steve (a terrifically low-key portrayal by the always ingratiating Peter Riegert), Cosmo proves to be an amazingly quick study and soon surpasses his wise older mentor when it comes to casually bumping off folks for major league dollars. Things become dicey when Cosmo befriends and immediately falls in love with nice gal yoga instructor Jasmine (a winningly perky turn by the eminently adorable Kimberly Williams), who's understandably less than thrilled with Cosmo's deadly profession. Writer/director Wallace Wolodarsky deftly accomplishes the tricky task of blending a gently whimsical romantic comedy with a savagely twisted droll black farce, skillfully creating and maintaining a deliciously dry and deadpan out-of-whack sensibility that's often uproariously screwy, constantly engrossing and occasionally even quite jarringly grotesque. The mixture of brutal violence and playful quirkiness works remarkably well because of Wolodarsky's commendably firm control of a marvelously unpredictable anything-can-happen oddball tone: the characters are a splendidly colorful bunch of delightfully kooky, likable and somehow strangely plausible eccentrics, the story never slips into a straight-down-the-line conventional trajectory, and the assorted unexpected plot complications keep the viewer totally off-guard throughout. Additional kudos are in order for the uniformly on-the-money cast: Priestley, Williams, Loggia and especially Riegert are all outstanding, with spot-on supporting work by the ever-charming Jeneane Garofalo as a sweet-hearted hooker and Michael J. Fox as a weaselly accountant. Idiosyncratic and original, "Coldblooded" qualifies as one of the most undeservedly neglected and unheralded off-center indie sleepers from the 90's.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Too Cute
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    B24
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/6/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    There are many good things to say about this movie from the standpoint of of wanting to find clever ways of commenting on its premise and appreciating its professional cinematography. It is not a bad piece of work at all. So-called "black" humor has its place in modern cinema, as do ironic turns of plot that demonstrate the virtuosity of a film's creators. That having been said, I found this effort a step or two short of reaching a successful or convincing end product. I have no quarrel with Jason Priestly as an actor; indeed, I think he has taken on some very challenging roles right up to the present day, and he can be very impressive as long as he plays them "straight." In this one, however, he is just a bit too tongue-in-cheek, too conscious perhaps of desiring to play with the audience. The role itself is also poorly written in that regard. There are unresolved ambiguities and even contradictions in the character of Cosmo, whether in terms of his basic intelligence or his innate morality. In order for this kind of thing to succeed, it has to be all of the same cloth, rather in the manner of the wildly fanciful Forrest Gump or some of Tarantino's odd characters. In Cosmo we are treated to an impression rather than a portrayal of the real thing. In spite of all that, I recommend this for any adult viewer unencumbered by sentimental ideas of morality or not easily offended by graphic violence. Most of what happens is fairly predictable in any case, however, so it is easy to hit the mute button or go get a sandwich while the shooting is going on.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Point poorly made
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    drystyx
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/7/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Wolodarsky hasn't a clue. He obviously tries to make a point about the self righteous attitude people have towards others. It's a good point. It was a point poorly made here. A bookie is promoted to hit man. Okay, there's the first clue we have that Wolodarsky doesn't have a clue. He must never have been outside his drawing room. The idea is beyond ludicrous. A bookie is the last person you would want for a hit man. A bookie is working with numbers and times. The bookie is the community's retired man, whom the law knows about, whom the tea party ladies know about, who performs the local service. Often, the mob does drag him in for their own profits, too. However, no one outside of the bubble boy community will believe a bookie would make a natural hit man by virtue of being a bookie. So, the premise is that the "new hit man" is an "everyman", but here again it fails. This "everyman", we learn at the end, is a complete psychopath. The movie spends over an hour on what Saturday Night Live could say in 30 seconds. The idea is that whenever someone is "whacked", the people who know have to "raionalize" it. They need to justify it. Indeed, nearly ever murder, ever atrocity, every war crime, is "self justified" this way. The people who learn of it must think the victim deserves it. It's not funny. It's not even dark humor. It fails miserably. It probably would have been a decent 2 minute sketch or short. But again, Wolodarsky just doesn't have a clue.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Off-beat, dark, and very entertaining
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ema-50
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/2/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I started watching this movie about 10 minutes into it, and I had to see it to the end. Lovely story, great acting, with some truly original scenes. Jason may seem a bit helpless, but that's just clever acting/directing. I'm happy to see that I'm not alone in appreciating this movie. The only thing i can fault this movie for, is casting a teen idol in a grownup movie. But that doesn't diminish the movie in itself. (In that respect it's similar to "17 again", which I also enjoyed a lot.) The fact that I saw it on TV just now (2010) goes to show that this movie has staying power. Brilliant stuff.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I thought I was the only one who loved this movie!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    sumdumgai13
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/2/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Like many of you here, when I saw that Jason Priestly was played the main character I had little hope of enjoying this film (even though I am a closet fan of the first season or two of 90210). I was more than pleasantly surprised when not only was the movie GREAT!!!, but Jason Priestly nailed his performance (and of course the rest of the supporting cast as well. I loved the subtle humor. I loved everything about this movie. This is not spoiler, so I am not going to elaborate. Do yourself a favor, if you can find this movie, rent it. If you like movies like Pulp fiction (as I do), you will love this movie. I just can't believe more people don't know about this movie. I stumbled into here because I found that I couldn't rent this from Netflix so I have decided to buy if from Amazon.com. My wife will soon be a fan of this movie too. It sucks I am going to have to dust off the VCR to watch it though.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    nice hidden gem
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    karo-6
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/11/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is one of those films that i catch by accident on TV while eating a dinner, and that immediately raise my eyebrows, set up a big question-mark above my head, make me forget about how good dinner i cooked, and instead make me immediately look up the title on IMDb while first set of commercials is on. First i see a face from sugary Beverly Hills in a _very_ different role, and he seems to be a hit-man (i didn't see the beginning of the movie), but he goes to yoga classes, and he seems to be at once simple and honest (and a virgin), and a successful professional killer, and the movie seems to somehow balance the opposites quite skillfully. Really, i can still feel my eyebrows up there where they were for the most of the movie. I laughed hard in few places, but like with best films, those funniest scenes had absolutely nothing obviously funny in them... it's the absurdness of the characters and their situations that makes those so funny. Still, i didn't feel this to be a comedy at all, it's here that saw people call it a dark comedy. Well, it's dark alright, and strangely uncomfortable, but i did laugh hard in some scenes so i guess it qualifies as comedy too. Anyway, if you like quirky off-the-beaten-path films, this is one you won't regret seeing.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A DVD Is Long Overdue.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    screenman
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/5/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I was shown this movie last night by someone who had got hold of it on video somehow. At first I was sceptical about his praise, never having heard of it. But soon it had my full attention. Most of the other commentators have hit it right on the mark as a piece of top-drawer black comedy. Jason Priestley is extremely well cast as the nerdish but alarming bookworm turned hit-man. That distracted, rather troubled, stare lends him the sort of frightening expression one sees on those faces of homicidal delinquents all too often featured in the news. It really is creepy. And yet his personality is one of insecurity and psychological vulnerability. He is sexually inexperienced from an emotional standpoint, despite regular visits from a hooker. When it comes to addressing his feelings towards a girl he actually likes; he's lost. We see him blackmailing the ex-boyfriend for seduction and romantic tips, on pain of execution. Later he is even picking the brains of imminent victims. His body language is awkward and childishly gauche, very reminiscent of 'Frank Spencer' in 'Some Mothers Do 'Ave 'Em'. In typical nerdy style he is completely lacking in ambition. He lives in a bedsit basement and is quite content there despite the huge pay rise when promoted to hit-man. Someone suggests he buys a suit to go on a date. And he goes and buys one suit. Priestley's character is groomed for a career in murder by an established and very capable assassin nicely performed by Peter Riegert. This tutor displays an excellent balance of patience and pathos, guiding his new prot&eacute;g&eacute; with a fatherly indulgence. But he is utterly ruthless in a world-weary way, whilst privately haunted by demons. 'The Man' is played to oleaginous perfection by ageing Robert Loggia. His is that kind avuncular charm, concealing an unutterable callousness that you've seen in plenty of other mafia movies. He's just so nice; you know he must be rotten to the core. And so the movie ticks along at its own pace and in its own direction, by an off-beat way that pays very little heed to precedent. You never know quite what's going to happen. I was astonished to see the great Micheal J Fox given little more than a cameo part, only to be obliterated without compunction. There was no DeLorean to save him this time around. The script goes along with it all. There are no really fancy one-liners, just good, steady, dialogue that seems entirely plausible when uttered by the players. The nearest comparison I can think of for this movie is the equally off-beat, violent, and darkly humorous 'Fargo'. And if that ain't a recommendation, I don't know what is. It's lack of availability on DVD is preposterous. Not only is the movie done a dis-service; a great deal of potential revenue is being lost. Don't miss it if you get the chance. This is a cult movie crying out for its audience.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Cold blooded black comedy
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    merklekranz
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/3/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Take one very introverted bookmaker and transform him into a highly successful hit-man. Now add an attractive yoga instructor to the mix and you have a talented killer in love. Though he clearly enjoys his work, he has no clue about relationships. This off-beat scenario easily drives "Cold Blooded" into black comedy territory. With sharp dialog, and fine acting from Jason Priestly, Kimberly Williams, Peter Riegert, and Robert Loggia, this is a must see for admirers of dark humor. The clever script is never boring, but is unpredictable and charming in a perverse sort of way. There is no DVD, but I highly recommend seeking out a VHS copy. - MERK
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Discreet Charm of the Film Noir in Hit Land
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    chowse1
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/1/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is the film that goes all the way to prove that understatement is often more amusing than anything else. Lacking slapstick, funny "characters" and too predictable situations it wanders along its own path and lets us go along. If we want. If we don't, that's okay but we'll miss the fun. Jason Priestly portrays a slacker who finds a calling. He also discovers Yoga and the teacher of same. Peter Riegert gives the sliest performance as the "instructor" for Priestly who quickly discovers that sometimes instinct needs no teaching. There is a delusional casualness to the lives and actions of all involved but this underscores the simplistic plot that relies on character and performance rather than stultified situations. (Garofalo must be the most dis-interested prostitute on screen.) But it all works. One hopes this will over time get a DVD and more exposure. A cult favourite in the making.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An unexpected delight.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    BA_Harrison
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/10/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    With so many over-hyped major releases of recent years proving to be bitter disappointments, it's a real treat when I get to watch an older, lesser-known film with no expectations and am blown away by what I see. Director Wallace Wolodarsky's Coldblooded is such a film. Jason Priestley (of Beverley Hills 90210 fame) plays Cosmo, a socially inept loner working as a bookie for an organised crime syndicate, who unwillingly becomes a hit-man when his gangster boss makes him an offer he can't refuse. After being sent to work alongside seasoned gunman Steve (Peter Riegert), in order to learn the ropes, Cosmo discovers that he is a natural when it comes to dishing out death. Completely ruthless, quick thinking, and a great shot, he takes to the job like a duck to water, but also finds that wasting people for a living is rather stressful. In order to try and relax, he begins yoga, and soon falls for the pretty teacher who takes his class. But is it possible for him to continue in his line of work and be in love at the same time? A quirky blend of dark humour and extreme violence, Coldblooded is a delight from start to finish. Priestly excels as Cosmo, a character that you cannot help but like, despite his monstrous ability to shoot complete strangers without skipping a heartbeat. The young killer's deadpan expression and bizarre mannerisms suggest that his mind functions in a manner different to mosthis perception of right and wrong is certainly severely distortedand whilst this doesn't excuse the fact that he is a brutal murderer, it makes his actions little easier to understand and, perhaps, even forgive. The smart script, also by Wolodarsky, brims with offbeat moments, great incidental characters, and inky black comedy, and his talented cast (which includes great turns by Robert Loggia, as Cosmo's boss, and Kimberly Williams as his girlfriend, plus fine cameos from Janeane Garofolo and Michael J. Fox) don't put a foot wrong, delivering some truly excellent performances. If you too are weary of overblown summer blockbusters that don't live up to the hype, track down this little gem of a movie to be reminded how good cinema can be when it's done right.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An excellent and unjustly overlooked deadpan black comedy gem
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Woodyanders (Woodyanders@aol.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/7/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Beverly Hills 90210" star hunk Jason Priestley gives a startlingly able and engaging performance as Cosmo, a quiet, passive, thoroughly nebbishy and unassuming recluse who works as a bookie for a mob syndicate. When new capo Gordon (a perfectly pernicious Robert Loggia) becomes gang leader after the previous crime boss croaks, Cosmo gets promoted to hit-man. Under the sage, expert tutelage of laid-back, but weary, boozy and guilt-wracked rub-out artist par excellence Steve (a terrifically low-key portrayal by the always ingratiating Peter Riegert), Cosmo proves to be an amazingly quick study and soon surpasses his wise older mentor when it comes to casually bumping off folks for major league dollars. Things become dicey when Cosmo befriends and immediately falls in love with nice gal yoga instructor Jasmine (a winningly perky turn by the eminently adorable Kimberly Williams), who's understandably less than thrilled with Cosmo's deadly profession. Writer/director Wallace Wolodarsky deftly accomplishes the tricky task of blending a gently whimsical romantic comedy with a savagely twisted droll black farce, skillfully creating and maintaining a deliciously dry and deadpan out-of-whack sensibility that's often uproariously screwy, constantly engrossing and occasionally even quite jarringly grotesque. The mixture of brutal violence and playful quirkiness works remarkably well because of Wolodarsky's commendably firm control of a marvelously unpredictable anything-can-happen oddball tone: the characters are a splendidly colorful bunch of delightfully kooky, likable and somehow strangely plausible eccentrics, the story never slips into a straight-down-the-line conventional trajectory, and the assorted unexpected plot complications keep the viewer totally off-guard throughout. Additional kudos are in order for the uniformly on-the-money cast: Priestley, Williams, Loggia and especially Riegert are all outstanding, with spot-on supporting work by the ever-charming Jeneane Garofalo as a sweet-hearted hooker and Michael J. Fox as a weaselly accountant. Idiosyncratic and original, "Coldblooded" qualifies as one of the most undeservedly neglected and unheralded off-center indie sleepers from the 90's.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Too Cute
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    B24
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/6/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    There are many good things to say about this movie from the standpoint of of wanting to find clever ways of commenting on its premise and appreciating its professional cinematography. It is not a bad piece of work at all. So-called "black" humor has its place in modern cinema, as do ironic turns of plot that demonstrate the virtuosity of a film's creators. That having been said, I found this effort a step or two short of reaching a successful or convincing end product. I have no quarrel with Jason Priestly as an actor; indeed, I think he has taken on some very challenging roles right up to the present day, and he can be very impressive as long as he plays them "straight." In this one, however, he is just a bit too tongue-in-cheek, too conscious perhaps of desiring to play with the audience. The role itself is also poorly written in that regard. There are unresolved ambiguities and even contradictions in the character of Cosmo, whether in terms of his basic intelligence or his innate morality. In order for this kind of thing to succeed, it has to be all of the same cloth, rather in the manner of the wildly fanciful Forrest Gump or some of Tarantino's odd characters. In Cosmo we are treated to an impression rather than a portrayal of the real thing. In spite of all that, I recommend this for any adult viewer unencumbered by sentimental ideas of morality or not easily offended by graphic violence. Most of what happens is fairly predictable in any case, however, so it is easy to hit the mute button or go get a sandwich while the shooting is going on.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Point poorly made
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    drystyx
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/7/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Wolodarsky hasn't a clue. He obviously tries to make a point about the self righteous attitude people have towards others. It's a good point. It was a point poorly made here. A bookie is promoted to hit man. Okay, there's the first clue we have that Wolodarsky doesn't have a clue. He must never have been outside his drawing room. The idea is beyond ludicrous. A bookie is the last person you would want for a hit man. A bookie is working with numbers and times. The bookie is the community's retired man, whom the law knows about, whom the tea party ladies know about, who performs the local service. Often, the mob does drag him in for their own profits, too. However, no one outside of the bubble boy community will believe a bookie would make a natural hit man by virtue of being a bookie. So, the premise is that the "new hit man" is an "everyman", but here again it fails. This "everyman", we learn at the end, is a complete psychopath. The movie spends over an hour on what Saturday Night Live could say in 30 seconds. The idea is that whenever someone is "whacked", the people who know have to "raionalize" it. They need to justify it. Indeed, nearly ever murder, ever atrocity, every war crime, is "self justified" this way. The people who learn of it must think the victim deserves it. It's not funny. It's not even dark humor. It fails miserably. It probably would have been a decent 2 minute sketch or short. But again, Wolodarsky just doesn't have a clue.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Off-beat, dark, and very entertaining
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ema-50
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/2/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I started watching this movie about 10 minutes into it, and I had to see it to the end. Lovely story, great acting, with some truly original scenes. Jason may seem a bit helpless, but that's just clever acting/directing. I'm happy to see that I'm not alone in appreciating this movie. The only thing i can fault this movie for, is casting a teen idol in a grownup movie. But that doesn't diminish the movie in itself. (In that respect it's similar to "17 again", which I also enjoyed a lot.) The fact that I saw it on TV just now (2010) goes to show that this movie has staying power. Brilliant stuff.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I thought I was the only one who loved this movie!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    sumdumgai13
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/2/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Like many of you here, when I saw that Jason Priestly was played the main character I had little hope of enjoying this film (even though I am a closet fan of the first season or two of 90210). I was more than pleasantly surprised when not only was the movie GREAT!!!, but Jason Priestly nailed his performance (and of course the rest of the supporting cast as well. I loved the subtle humor. I loved everything about this movie. This is not spoiler, so I am not going to elaborate. Do yourself a favor, if you can find this movie, rent it. If you like movies like Pulp fiction (as I do), you will love this movie. I just can't believe more people don't know about this movie. I stumbled into here because I found that I couldn't rent this from Netflix so I have decided to buy if from Amazon.com. My wife will soon be a fan of this movie too. It sucks I am going to have to dust off the VCR to watch it though.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    nice hidden gem
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    karo-6
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/11/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is one of those films that i catch by accident on TV while eating a dinner, and that immediately raise my eyebrows, set up a big question-mark above my head, make me forget about how good dinner i cooked, and instead make me immediately look up the title on IMDb while first set of commercials is on. First i see a face from sugary Beverly Hills in a _very_ different role, and he seems to be a hit-man (i didn't see the beginning of the movie), but he goes to yoga classes, and he seems to be at once simple and honest (and a virgin), and a successful professional killer, and the movie seems to somehow balance the opposites quite skillfully. Really, i can still feel my eyebrows up there where they were for the most of the movie. I laughed hard in few places, but like with best films, those funniest scenes had absolutely nothing obviously funny in them... it's the absurdness of the characters and their situations that makes those so funny. Still, i didn't feel this to be a comedy at all, it's here that saw people call it a dark comedy. Well, it's dark alright, and strangely uncomfortable, but i did laugh hard in some scenes so i guess it qualifies as comedy too. Anyway, if you like quirky off-the-beaten-path films, this is one you won't regret seeing.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A DVD Is Long Overdue.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    screenman
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/5/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I was shown this movie last night by someone who had got hold of it on video somehow. At first I was sceptical about his praise, never having heard of it. But soon it had my full attention. Most of the other commentators have hit it right on the mark as a piece of top-drawer black comedy. Jason Priestley is extremely well cast as the nerdish but alarming bookworm turned hit-man. That distracted, rather troubled, stare lends him the sort of frightening expression one sees on those faces of homicidal delinquents all too often featured in the news. It really is creepy. And yet his personality is one of insecurity and psychological vulnerability. He is sexually inexperienced from an emotional standpoint, despite regular visits from a hooker. When it comes to addressing his feelings towards a girl he actually likes; he's lost. We see him blackmailing the ex-boyfriend for seduction and romantic tips, on pain of execution. Later he is even picking the brains of imminent victims. His body language is awkward and childishly gauche, very reminiscent of 'Frank Spencer' in 'Some Mothers Do 'Ave 'Em'. In typical nerdy style he is completely lacking in ambition. He lives in a bedsit basement and is quite content there despite the huge pay rise when promoted to hit-man. Someone suggests he buys a suit to go on a date. And he goes and buys one suit. Priestley's character is groomed for a career in murder by an established and very capable assassin nicely performed by Peter Riegert. This tutor displays an excellent balance of patience and pathos, guiding his new prot&eacute;g&eacute; with a fatherly indulgence. But he is utterly ruthless in a world-weary way, whilst privately haunted by demons. 'The Man' is played to oleaginous perfection by ageing Robert Loggia. His is that kind avuncular charm, concealing an unutterable callousness that you've seen in plenty of other mafia movies. He's just so nice; you know he must be rotten to the core. And so the movie ticks along at its own pace and in its own direction, by an off-beat way that pays very little heed to precedent. You never know quite what's going to happen. I was astonished to see the great Micheal J Fox given little more than a cameo part, only to be obliterated without compunction. There was no DeLorean to save him this time around. The script goes along with it all. There are no really fancy one-liners, just good, steady, dialogue that seems entirely plausible when uttered by the players. The nearest comparison I can think of for this movie is the equally off-beat, violent, and darkly humorous 'Fargo'. And if that ain't a recommendation, I don't know what is. It's lack of availability on DVD is preposterous. Not only is the movie done a dis-service; a great deal of potential revenue is being lost. Don't miss it if you get the chance. This is a cult movie crying out for its audience.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Cold blooded black comedy
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    merklekranz
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/3/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Take one very introverted bookmaker and transform him into a highly successful hit-man. Now add an attractive yoga instructor to the mix and you have a talented killer in love. Though he clearly enjoys his work, he has no clue about relationships. This off-beat scenario easily drives "Cold Blooded" into black comedy territory. With sharp dialog, and fine acting from Jason Priestly, Kimberly Williams, Peter Riegert, and Robert Loggia, this is a must see for admirers of dark humor. The clever script is never boring, but is unpredictable and charming in a perverse sort of way. There is no DVD, but I highly recommend seeking out a VHS copy. - MERK
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Discreet Charm of the Film Noir in Hit Land
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    chowse1
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/1/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is the film that goes all the way to prove that understatement is often more amusing than anything else. Lacking slapstick, funny "characters" and too predictable situations it wanders along its own path and lets us go along. If we want. If we don't, that's okay but we'll miss the fun. Jason Priestly portrays a slacker who finds a calling. He also discovers Yoga and the teacher of same. Peter Riegert gives the sliest performance as the "instructor" for Priestly who quickly discovers that sometimes instinct needs no teaching. There is a delusional casualness to the lives and actions of all involved but this underscores the simplistic plot that relies on character and performance rather than stultified situations. (Garofalo must be the most dis-interested prostitute on screen.) But it all works. One hopes this will over time get a DVD and more exposure. A cult favourite in the making.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An unexpected delight.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    BA_Harrison
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/10/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    With so many over-hyped major releases of recent years proving to be bitter disappointments, it's a real treat when I get to watch an older, lesser-known film with no expectations and am blown away by what I see. Director Wallace Wolodarsky's Coldblooded is such a film. Jason Priestley (of Beverley Hills 90210 fame) plays Cosmo, a socially inept loner working as a bookie for an organised crime syndicate, who unwillingly becomes a hit-man when his gangster boss makes him an offer he can't refuse. After being sent to work alongside seasoned gunman Steve (Peter Riegert), in order to learn the ropes, Cosmo discovers that he is a natural when it comes to dishing out death. Completely ruthless, quick thinking, and a great shot, he takes to the job like a duck to water, but also finds that wasting people for a living is rather stressful. In order to try and relax, he begins yoga, and soon falls for the pretty teacher who takes his class. But is it possible for him to continue in his line of work and be in love at the same time? A quirky blend of dark humour and extreme violence, Coldblooded is a delight from start to finish. Priestly excels as Cosmo, a character that you cannot help but like, despite his monstrous ability to shoot complete strangers without skipping a heartbeat. The young killer's deadpan expression and bizarre mannerisms suggest that his mind functions in a manner different to mosthis perception of right and wrong is certainly severely distortedand whilst this doesn't excuse the fact that he is a brutal murderer, it makes his actions little easier to understand and, perhaps, even forgive. The smart script, also by Wolodarsky, brims with offbeat moments, great incidental characters, and inky black comedy, and his talented cast (which includes great turns by Robert Loggia, as Cosmo's boss, and Kimberly Williams as his girlfriend, plus fine cameos from Janeane Garofolo and Michael J. Fox) don't put a foot wrong, delivering some truly excellent performances. If you too are weary of overblown summer blockbusters that don't live up to the hype, track down this little gem of a movie to be reminded how good cinema can be when it's done right.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An excellent and unjustly overlooked deadpan black comedy gem
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Woodyanders (Woodyanders@aol.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/7/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Beverly Hills 90210" star hunk Jason Priestley gives a startlingly able and engaging performance as Cosmo, a quiet, passive, thoroughly nebbishy and unassuming recluse who works as a bookie for a mob syndicate. When new capo Gordon (a perfectly pernicious Robert Loggia) becomes gang leader after the previous crime boss croaks, Cosmo gets promoted to hit-man. Under the sage, expert tutelage of laid-back, but weary, boozy and guilt-wracked rub-out artist par excellence Steve (a terrifically low-key portrayal by the always ingratiating Peter Riegert), Cosmo proves to be an amazingly quick study and soon surpasses his wise older mentor when it comes to casually bumping off folks for major league dollars. Things become dicey when Cosmo befriends and immediately falls in love with nice gal yoga instructor Jasmine (a winningly perky turn by the eminently adorable Kimberly Williams), who's understandably less than thrilled with Cosmo's deadly profession. Writer/director Wallace Wolodarsky deftly accomplishes the tricky task of blending a gently whimsical romantic comedy with a savagely twisted droll black farce, skillfully creating and maintaining a deliciously dry and deadpan out-of-whack sensibility that's often uproariously screwy, constantly engrossing and occasionally even quite jarringly grotesque. The mixture of brutal violence and playful quirkiness works remarkably well because of Wolodarsky's commendably firm control of a marvelously unpredictable anything-can-happen oddball tone: the characters are a splendidly colorful bunch of delightfully kooky, likable and somehow strangely plausible eccentrics, the story never slips into a straight-down-the-line conventional trajectory, and the assorted unexpected plot complications keep the viewer totally off-guard throughout. Additional kudos are in order for the uniformly on-the-money cast: Priestley, Williams, Loggia and especially Riegert are all outstanding, with spot-on supporting work by the ever-charming Jeneane Garofalo as a sweet-hearted hooker and Michael J. Fox as a weaselly accountant. Idiosyncratic and original, "Coldblooded" qualifies as one of the most undeservedly neglected and unheralded off-center indie sleepers from the 90's.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Too Cute
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    B24
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/6/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    There are many good things to say about this movie from the standpoint of of wanting to find clever ways of commenting on its premise and appreciating its professional cinematography. It is not a bad piece of work at all. So-called "black" humor has its place in modern cinema, as do ironic turns of plot that demonstrate the virtuosity of a film's creators. That having been said, I found this effort a step or two short of reaching a successful or convincing end product. I have no quarrel with Jason Priestly as an actor; indeed, I think he has taken on some very challenging roles right up to the present day, and he can be very impressive as long as he plays them "straight." In this one, however, he is just a bit too tongue-in-cheek, too conscious perhaps of desiring to play with the audience. The role itself is also poorly written in that regard. There are unresolved ambiguities and even contradictions in the character of Cosmo, whether in terms of his basic intelligence or his innate morality. In order for this kind of thing to succeed, it has to be all of the same cloth, rather in the manner of the wildly fanciful Forrest Gump or some of Tarantino's odd characters. In Cosmo we are treated to an impression rather than a portrayal of the real thing. In spite of all that, I recommend this for any adult viewer unencumbered by sentimental ideas of morality or not easily offended by graphic violence. Most of what happens is fairly predictable in any case, however, so it is easy to hit the mute button or go get a sandwich while the shooting is going on.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Point poorly made
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    drystyx
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/7/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Wolodarsky hasn't a clue. He obviously tries to make a point about the self righteous attitude people have towards others. It's a good point. It was a point poorly made here. A bookie is promoted to hit man. Okay, there's the first clue we have that Wolodarsky doesn't have a clue. He must never have been outside his drawing room. The idea is beyond ludicrous. A bookie is the last person you would want for a hit man. A bookie is working with numbers and times. The bookie is the community's retired man, whom the law knows about, whom the tea party ladies know about, who performs the local service. Often, the mob does drag him in for their own profits, too. However, no one outside of the bubble boy community will believe a bookie would make a natural hit man by virtue of being a bookie. So, the premise is that the "new hit man" is an "everyman", but here again it fails. This "everyman", we learn at the end, is a complete psychopath. The movie spends over an hour on what Saturday Night Live could say in 30 seconds. The idea is that whenever someone is "whacked", the people who know have to "raionalize" it. They need to justify it. Indeed, nearly ever murder, ever atrocity, every war crime, is "self justified" this way. The people who learn of it must think the victim deserves it. It's not funny. It's not even dark humor. It fails miserably. It probably would have been a decent 2 minute sketch or short. But again, Wolodarsky just doesn't have a clue.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Off-beat, dark, and very entertaining
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ema-50
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/2/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I started watching this movie about 10 minutes into it, and I had to see it to the end. Lovely story, great acting, with some truly original scenes. Jason may seem a bit helpless, but that's just clever acting/directing. I'm happy to see that I'm not alone in appreciating this movie. The only thing i can fault this movie for, is casting a teen idol in a grownup movie. But that doesn't diminish the movie in itself. (In that respect it's similar to "17 again", which I also enjoyed a lot.) The fact that I saw it on TV just now (2010) goes to show that this movie has staying power. Brilliant stuff.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I thought I was the only one who loved this movie!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    sumdumgai13
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/2/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Like many of you here, when I saw that Jason Priestly was played the main character I had little hope of enjoying this film (even though I am a closet fan of the first season or two of 90210). I was more than pleasantly surprised when not only was the movie GREAT!!!, but Jason Priestly nailed his performance (and of course the rest of the supporting cast as well. I loved the subtle humor. I loved everything about this movie. This is not spoiler, so I am not going to elaborate. Do yourself a favor, if you can find this movie, rent it. If you like movies like Pulp fiction (as I do), you will love this movie. I just can't believe more people don't know about this movie. I stumbled into here because I found that I couldn't rent this from Netflix so I have decided to buy if from Amazon.com. My wife will soon be a fan of this movie too. It sucks I am going to have to dust off the VCR to watch it though.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    nice hidden gem
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    karo-6
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/11/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is one of those films that i catch by accident on TV while eating a dinner, and that immediately raise my eyebrows, set up a big question-mark above my head, make me forget about how good dinner i cooked, and instead make me immediately look up the title on IMDb while first set of commercials is on. First i see a face from sugary Beverly Hills in a _very_ different role, and he seems to be a hit-man (i didn't see the beginning of the movie), but he goes to yoga classes, and he seems to be at once simple and honest (and a virgin), and a successful professional killer, and the movie seems to somehow balance the opposites quite skillfully. Really, i can still feel my eyebrows up there where they were for the most of the movie. I laughed hard in few places, but like with best films, those funniest scenes had absolutely nothing obviously funny in them... it's the absurdness of the characters and their situations that makes those so funny. Still, i didn't feel this to be a comedy at all, it's here that saw people call it a dark comedy. Well, it's dark alright, and strangely uncomfortable, but i did laugh hard in some scenes so i guess it qualifies as comedy too. Anyway, if you like quirky off-the-beaten-path films, this is one you won't regret seeing.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A DVD Is Long Overdue.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    screenman
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/5/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I was shown this movie last night by someone who had got hold of it on video somehow. At first I was sceptical about his praise, never having heard of it. But soon it had my full attention. Most of the other commentators have hit it right on the mark as a piece of top-drawer black comedy. Jason Priestley is extremely well cast as the nerdish but alarming bookworm turned hit-man. That distracted, rather troubled, stare lends him the sort of frightening expression one sees on those faces of homicidal delinquents all too often featured in the news. It really is creepy. And yet his personality is one of insecurity and psychological vulnerability. He is sexually inexperienced from an emotional standpoint, despite regular visits from a hooker. When it comes to addressing his feelings towards a girl he actually likes; he's lost. We see him blackmailing the ex-boyfriend for seduction and romantic tips, on pain of execution. Later he is even picking the brains of imminent victims. His body language is awkward and childishly gauche, very reminiscent of 'Frank Spencer' in 'Some Mothers Do 'Ave 'Em'. In typical nerdy style he is completely lacking in ambition. He lives in a bedsit basement and is quite content there despite the huge pay rise when promoted to hit-man. Someone suggests he buys a suit to go on a date. And he goes and buys one suit. Priestley's character is groomed for a career in murder by an established and very capable assassin nicely performed by Peter Riegert. This tutor displays an excellent balance of patience and pathos, guiding his new prot&eacute;g&eacute; with a fatherly indulgence. But he is utterly ruthless in a world-weary way, whilst privately haunted by demons. 'The Man' is played to oleaginous perfection by ageing Robert Loggia. His is that kind avuncular charm, concealing an unutterable callousness that you've seen in plenty of other mafia movies. He's just so nice; you know he must be rotten to the core. And so the movie ticks along at its own pace and in its own direction, by an off-beat way that pays very little heed to precedent. You never know quite what's going to happen. I was astonished to see the great Micheal J Fox given little more than a cameo part, only to be obliterated without compunction. There was no DeLorean to save him this time around. The script goes along with it all. There are no really fancy one-liners, just good, steady, dialogue that seems entirely plausible when uttered by the players. The nearest comparison I can think of for this movie is the equally off-beat, violent, and darkly humorous 'Fargo'. And if that ain't a recommendation, I don't know what is. It's lack of availability on DVD is preposterous. Not only is the movie done a dis-service; a great deal of potential revenue is being lost. Don't miss it if you get the chance. This is a cult movie crying out for its audience.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Cold blooded black comedy
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    merklekranz
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/3/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Take one very introverted bookmaker and transform him into a highly successful hit-man. Now add an attractive yoga instructor to the mix and you have a talented killer in love. Though he clearly enjoys his work, he has no clue about relationships. This off-beat scenario easily drives "Cold Blooded" into black comedy territory. With sharp dialog, and fine acting from Jason Priestly, Kimberly Williams, Peter Riegert, and Robert Loggia, this is a must see for admirers of dark humor. The clever script is never boring, but is unpredictable and charming in a perverse sort of way. There is no DVD, but I highly recommend seeking out a VHS copy. - MERK
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Discreet Charm of the Film Noir in Hit Land
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    chowse1
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/1/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is the film that goes all the way to prove that understatement is often more amusing than anything else. Lacking slapstick, funny "characters" and too predictable situations it wanders along its own path and lets us go along. If we want. If we don't, that's okay but we'll miss the fun. Jason Priestly portrays a slacker who finds a calling. He also discovers Yoga and the teacher of same. Peter Riegert gives the sliest performance as the "instructor" for Priestly who quickly discovers that sometimes instinct needs no teaching. There is a delusional casualness to the lives and actions of all involved but this underscores the simplistic plot that relies on character and performance rather than stultified situations. (Garofalo must be the most dis-interested prostitute on screen.) But it all works. One hopes this will over time get a DVD and more exposure. A cult favourite in the making.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An unexpected delight.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    BA_Harrison
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/10/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    With so many over-hyped major releases of recent years proving to be bitter disappointments, it's a real treat when I get to watch an older, lesser-known film with no expectations and am blown away by what I see. Director Wallace Wolodarsky's Coldblooded is such a film. Jason Priestley (of Beverley Hills 90210 fame) plays Cosmo, a socially inept loner working as a bookie for an organised crime syndicate, who unwillingly becomes a hit-man when his gangster boss makes him an offer he can't refuse. After being sent to work alongside seasoned gunman Steve (Peter Riegert), in order to learn the ropes, Cosmo discovers that he is a natural when it comes to dishing out death. Completely ruthless, quick thinking, and a great shot, he takes to the job like a duck to water, but also finds that wasting people for a living is rather stressful. In order to try and relax, he begins yoga, and soon falls for the pretty teacher who takes his class. But is it possible for him to continue in his line of work and be in love at the same time? A quirky blend of dark humour and extreme violence, Coldblooded is a delight from start to finish. Priestly excels as Cosmo, a character that you cannot help but like, despite his monstrous ability to shoot complete strangers without skipping a heartbeat. The young killer's deadpan expression and bizarre mannerisms suggest that his mind functions in a manner different to mosthis perception of right and wrong is certainly severely distortedand whilst this doesn't excuse the fact that he is a brutal murderer, it makes his actions little easier to understand and, perhaps, even forgive. The smart script, also by Wolodarsky, brims with offbeat moments, great incidental characters, and inky black comedy, and his talented cast (which includes great turns by Robert Loggia, as Cosmo's boss, and Kimberly Williams as his girlfriend, plus fine cameos from Janeane Garofolo and Michael J. Fox) don't put a foot wrong, delivering some truly excellent performances. If you too are weary of overblown summer blockbusters that don't live up to the hype, track down this little gem of a movie to be reminded how good cinema can be when it's done right.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An excellent and unjustly overlooked deadpan black comedy gem
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Woodyanders (Woodyanders@aol.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/7/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Beverly Hills 90210" star hunk Jason Priestley gives a startlingly able and engaging performance as Cosmo, a quiet, passive, thoroughly nebbishy and unassuming recluse who works as a bookie for a mob syndicate. When new capo Gordon (a perfectly pernicious Robert Loggia) becomes gang leader after the previous crime boss croaks, Cosmo gets promoted to hit-man. Under the sage, expert tutelage of laid-back, but weary, boozy and guilt-wracked rub-out artist par excellence Steve (a terrifically low-key portrayal by the always ingratiating Peter Riegert), Cosmo proves to be an amazingly quick study and soon surpasses his wise older mentor when it comes to casually bumping off folks for major league dollars. Things become dicey when Cosmo befriends and immediately falls in love with nice gal yoga instructor Jasmine (a winningly perky turn by the eminently adorable Kimberly Williams), who's understandably less than thrilled with Cosmo's deadly profession. Writer/director Wallace Wolodarsky deftly accomplishes the tricky task of blending a gently whimsical romantic comedy with a savagely twisted droll black farce, skillfully creating and maintaining a deliciously dry and deadpan out-of-whack sensibility that's often uproariously screwy, constantly engrossing and occasionally even quite jarringly grotesque. The mixture of brutal violence and playful quirkiness works remarkably well because of Wolodarsky's commendably firm control of a marvelously unpredictable anything-can-happen oddball tone: the characters are a splendidly colorful bunch of delightfully kooky, likable and somehow strangely plausible eccentrics, the story never slips into a straight-down-the-line conventional trajectory, and the assorted unexpected plot complications keep the viewer totally off-guard throughout. Additional kudos are in order for the uniformly on-the-money cast: Priestley, Williams, Loggia and especially Riegert are all outstanding, with spot-on supporting work by the ever-charming Jeneane Garofalo as a sweet-hearted hooker and Michael J. Fox as a weaselly accountant. Idiosyncratic and original, "Coldblooded" qualifies as one of the most undeservedly neglected and unheralded off-center indie sleepers from the 90's.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Too Cute
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    B24
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/6/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    There are many good things to say about this movie from the standpoint of of wanting to find clever ways of commenting on its premise and appreciating its professional cinematography. It is not a bad piece of work at all. So-called "black" humor has its place in modern cinema, as do ironic turns of plot that demonstrate the virtuosity of a film's creators. That having been said, I found this effort a step or two short of reaching a successful or convincing end product. I have no quarrel with Jason Priestly as an actor; indeed, I think he has taken on some very challenging roles right up to the present day, and he can be very impressive as long as he plays them "straight." In this one, however, he is just a bit too tongue-in-cheek, too conscious perhaps of desiring to play with the audience. The role itself is also poorly written in that regard. There are unresolved ambiguities and even contradictions in the character of Cosmo, whether in terms of his basic intelligence or his innate morality. In order for this kind of thing to succeed, it has to be all of the same cloth, rather in the manner of the wildly fanciful Forrest Gump or some of Tarantino's odd characters. In Cosmo we are treated to an impression rather than a portrayal of the real thing. In spite of all that, I recommend this for any adult viewer unencumbered by sentimental ideas of morality or not easily offended by graphic violence. Most of what happens is fairly predictable in any case, however, so it is easy to hit the mute button or go get a sandwich while the shooting is going on.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
 </reviews>
</filme>
