<filme>
 <id>
  142
 </id>
 <imdburl>
  http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0066817
 </imdburl>
 <ano>
  1971
 </ano>
 <titulo>
  Se Minha Cama Voasse
 </titulo>
 <rating>
  6.8
 </rating>
 <sinopse>
  An apprentice witch, three kids and a cynical conman search for the missing component to a magic spell useful to the defense of Britain.
 </sinopse>
 <storyline>
  During WWII in England, Charlie, Carrie, and Paul Rawlins are sent to live with Eglantine Price, an apprentice witch. Charlie blackmails Miss Price that if he is to keep her practices a secret, she must give him something, so she takes a bedknob from her late father's bed and places the "famous magic traveling spell" on it, and only Paul can activate it. Their first journey is to a street in London where they meet Emelius Browne, headmaster of Miss Price's witchcraft training correspondence school. Miss Price tells him of a plan to find the magic words for a spell known as Substitutiary Locomotion, which brings inanimate objects to life. This spell will be her work for the war effort.
 </storyline>
 <generos>
  <genero>
   Adventure
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Family
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Fantasy
  </genero>
 </generos>
 <keywords>
  <keyword>
   magic
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   apprentice
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   witch
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   witchcraft
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   bed
  </keyword>
 </keywords>
 <diretores>
  <diretor>
   Robert Stevenson
  </diretor>
 </diretores>
 <escritores>
  <escritor>
   Ralph Wright
  </escritor>
  <escritor>
   Ted Berman
  </escritor>
 </escritores>
 <atores>
  <ator>
   Angela Lansbury
  </ator>
  <ator>
   David Tomlinson
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Roddy McDowall
  </ator>
 </atores>
 <reviews>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    From Portabello Road to the Beautiful Briny Sea, Angela will take you past the age of Not Believing.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mark.waltz
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    There's more charm to this Disney musical than has been given credit for, even though a huge fan base obviously exists for it. The film was overshadowed by the memory of Disney's previous big movie musical where another British actress (Julie Andrews) shot to super-stardom playing a nanny with extraordinary powers. Here, Angela Lansbury is a wanna be witch who ends up in charge of three kids against her will and assists the British in fighting the Krauts of World War I with the help of her own magic powers. The same song-writing team of Robert and Richard Stevenson have created an equally engaging score, and I think it even tops the one for "Mary Poppins". Lansbury wins your heart immediately when she berates her cranky charges for being past that "Age of Not Believing" then takes them onto a magical journey into the depths of the Atlantic Ocean and into a magical island with its own Lion King and a horde of eccentric soccer playing animals, all with the assistance of her witch professor phony David Tomlinson. More eccentric than his disciplining father from "Mary Poppins", Tomlinson is more than welcomed back and a great co-star for Lansbury. He is hysterically funny in the partly animated soccer match where he is the referee and takes more than his share of abuse from this mythical animal kingdom. Fresh from her success as Broadway's "Mame" (with a few flops in between that have become cult classics thanks to her presence in them), Lansbury proves herself worthy of the movie musical, having been sadly dubbed most of the time when she was at MGM during their heyday. There's a bit of a Harry Potter and "Wicked" feeling to this story with quite the influence of the late 60's/early 70's Broadway feel in the live-action musical numbers. The lyrics are cleverly difficult to sing along with and may have you laughing as you try, especially the final number where Lansbury gets her witchcraft right in aiding a museum filled with ancient war artifacts to take on the German army. Another "Mary Poppins" veteran is back, Lansbury's old MGM co-star Reginald Owen, in one of his final appearances, and Roddy McDowall is amusingly effete as the British preacher who keeps popping in to check on the kiddies. Disney would obviously be influenced by this many years later when making their modern day musical classics such as "The Little Mermaid", "Beauty and the Beast" (by casting Lansbury in a key role) and "The Lion King".
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Dated Fantasy Flick's Finale Too Fast
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    William C. Uchtman (aesgaard41@hotmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    For myself as a boy, this movie's closing scenes with the ghostly army using nothing but Medieval weapons to battle and repulse an attempted Nazi landing in England during World War Two is one of the most lasting images in my mind. However, as an adult watching it today, it comes off as less magical with the horribly dated special effects. Overall, the movie has actually stood the test of time, still enchanting whole new generations of young children. Angela Lansbury as a young actress is charming and attractive, and David Tomlinson is a bit more animated and puckish that he was in "Mary Poppins," which this movie seems to be riding. The notable parallels between the two movies are obvious, but then it is quite clear that the two movies share much of the same production team members. Mostly for laughs, the film has very few scary scenes, and the aforementioned scene does not much more than walk and march except for a select few swinging swords and maces. There's a decent horror movie here once the Disney ingredients are removed. The songs, as effervescent as they are, are not nearly as infectious as the tunes from "Mary Poppins," and Roddy McDowell, who was quite a popular British actor for the time, sadly, gets very little to do in this movie. I don't get how destroying her research robs Lansbury's character of her mystical powers, but I just wish the movie had lasted just a bit longer to reveal the clean-up of the countryside to retrieve the museum artifacts and period costumes now mysteriously damaged and bullet-ridden and scattered through the woods. I mean, come on, how did they explain that?
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Aging Special Effects and Uneven Script
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tabuno
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    At the time, this dazzling display of live action and animation must of been quite a treat for its audience, receiving an Oscar award for best special effects. Alas time has not been kind to this heavily special effects dependent movie which is also weighed down by an uneven script. The director was able to balance this movie's genre or tone - was this to be a musical or just family comedy or drama. This movie appears to have ignored the director's own magical success of Mary Poppins (1964) released seven years earlier. Like Sean Penn directing Into the Wild (2007), director Robert Stevenson perhaps let success go to his head, or maybe insecurity by focusing so much on special effects and musical numbers that the story itself sometimes became secondary to the showing off the supposed "brilliance" of the animations. For example, Emelius fades almost into insignificance during the soccer game, or the primary characters are lost in the overly crowded and extended dance routine in the town. Even the television episode of Buffy: The Vampire Slayer - Once More, With Feeling (2001) displays how to both enhance the storyline and the characters with music instead of hiding them and ignoring the story. Cool World (1992), Jim Carrey's The Mask (1994), Monkey Bones (2001) all built on the break out live animation film Who Framed Roger Rabbit (1988). But even back in 1964, Arthur Lubin known for televisions series Mr. Ed and The Addams Family directed a neat live animation mixture with Don Knott's in The Incredible Mr. Limpet. Overall, what once was a new and delightful children's film has aged and not well.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A failed attempt to recapture the magic of Mary Poppins, but with a good set-piece finale
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    David Conrad
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    All the elements from "Mary Poppins" are here: a stern, magical nanny who flies, a kooky male street performer with whom she has some history, and period-specific English kids who tag along with the unconventional adults through foggy London streets and animated fantasy lands. Even one of the actors, David Tomlinson, is borrowed from Poppins. Yet Disney's attempt to strike gold twice fails. The pacing is much slower, particularly on the restored DVD release in which 30 minutes of footage cut from the theatrical release are reinserted. The songs are bland affairs that Tomlinson and Angela Lansbury meander through without much energy. During the animation sequence, the live actors are sidelined for an interminable soccer match between lions, alligators, and bears. These animal drawings are templates lifted from Disney's "The Jungle Book" (1967), and they would be recycled again in the studio's "Robin Hood" (1973). The final act of "Bedknobs," though it comes too late and lasts too long, does partly redeem it: special effects steal the show as an army of English museum pieces, mainly empty suits of medieval armor, come to life and march against the most incompetent Nazi invasion force in screen history. It would be better to YouTube that sequence than to sit through the movie to get to it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Honestly runs better in the standard cut
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Foux_du_Fafa
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Though far from perfect, "Bedknobs and Broomsticks" has always been a favourite of mine since childhood. The plot may be a bit muddled in places, but the sheer joy and fun of the fantasy material makes up for it. The animated sequences in particular are a real joy, as is the comedy-action climax to the film. Some of the songs are underrated classics, in particular "The Age of Not Believing" and "The Beautiful Briny". Also, the elaborate opening credit sequence is gorgeous to look at. That said, you may want to be careful which version of the film you see. The film premiered at around 135 minutes, but was cut down for general release to 117 minutes. This 117 minute version was the one I first saw as a child. In 1996, Disney restored the film to a length comparable to the premiere version, and this is what was released onto DVD. Ironically, I think the film does run better at a shorter length. Much of what is added are new or extended musical numbers, as well as the extension of a rather superfluous subplot involving a somewhat saucy vicar. I don't particularly find the new musical numbers that engaging, and the numbers that are extended aren't that great. Though there are some interesting extra verses in the extended "Portobello Road" number, the several dance scenes added to it renders it seemingly unending. "Eglantine" also goes on a bit too much for my liking. In addition some re-dubbing was required for some of the new scenes as the original mastertracks were not found. Angela Lansbury was able to come back and sounds fine, but many of the other actors weren't and the results are mixed. It would be nice if an inevitable Blu-Ray showed the film in either two of its versions, or if at least the original dialogue tapes were found for the extended scenes. I do believe that there are still ways to get hold of the 117 minute version. I have the first UK DVD release from around 2002, but I have read on Amazon that a later UK release has the film run at 117 minutes in order to align itself with some old European dubs on the disc, and I've also read online that TCM in the US sometimes shows the shorter version. In any case, "Bedknobs and Broomsticks" is a fun, family classic and easily worthy of my recommendation.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Way Too Long, Way Too Dull
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Joshua Mitchell
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Bedknobs And Broomsticks is rather obscure when compared to Disney's other films. This isn't a bad thing, though, considering most of Disney's other films are far superior to this overlong production. Lacking any excitement, or even laugh-worthy humor, Bedknobs And Broomsticks has little appeal to those over the age of 10, and even the youngest will likely be bored by the constant chatter and uninventive musical numbers. Three children named Carrie, Charlie and Paul are temporarily adopted by Eglantine Price, whom they discover to be a witch. Ms. Prince gives the children a traveling spell, in exchange for keeping her secret, which allows their bed to teleport to any given location. The four also snag Emelius Browne- Ms. Price's witch teacher- into the adventure as well. As one would expect, there are countless plot holes and silly things that are overlooked by the characters, but this is the least of the film's problems. Bedknobs And Broomsticks runs for a taxing two and a half hours. Had Bedknobs And Broomsticks been truly entertaining, this would not be a problem. Another Disney musical, Mary Poppins has a run time around the same length, and is loved and adored by all ages. Needless to say, Bedknobs And Broomsticks is no Mary Poppins. The content of this dull musical, does not justify the relentlessly long length. The number of songs in the film are not nearly as high as that of Mary Poppins, but they are far less inventive. Despite being penned by the Sherman brothers, the same duo that wrote the songs in Mary Poppins, each and every number is dull to limit. Occasionally, dancing takes place during these numbers, though the choreography is poor and uninspired. What's strange is that the beat of the music, often does not meet the beat of the dancing, which seems truly lazy. The score, also by the Sherman brothers isn't too shabby, and the bed traveling theme is relatively strong, but the score often sounds too similar to the Mary Poppins score (especially in the earlier segments). Also, if you hate bagpipes, you will definitely want to avoid this, as the aforementioned instruments make more than one appearance. Bedknobs And Broomsticks is specifically known for the Land of Naboombu, which is completely animated. It's always a marvel to see live-acted characters interact with animated ones. Alas, despite being showcased as the main attraction in Bedknobs And Broomsticks, the Land of Naboombu occupies a measly 30 minutes of the extensive run time. Talk about misleading! Special effects often look dated, and the strings that are used to suspend objects in midair are clearly visible most of the time. There are some decent effects though, make no mistake about it. But not all of the effects are as polished as others. The children are poorly acted, and most other actors fall into the unspectacular area. Only Angela Lansbury and David Tomlinson stand out. Bedknobs And Broomsticks is wholly unspectacular. It lacks the humor and excitement it needed to translate into the fun adventure it fails to be. Add that with the overlong run time and the dull musical numbers, and you get a animated musical that is unlikely to leave anyone coming back for more.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The restored version is a Disney classic but certainly no "Mary Poppins"
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mike48128
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/7/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Mary Poppins is a 10, so what's wrong with "Bedknobs" besides it's too long? A lack of "whimsey and wonder". Like comparing "Sleeping Beauty" to Snow White". (Both classics) So let's begin: The opening credits are far too long, as Disney liked to front-load all the credits during this era. The storyboarded titles tell the entire plot line so nothing is left to the imagination. It's like an overlong movie "trailer" that does the same thing. At first the characters are dreadful, and only start to improve in "likeability" as the story progresses. (Angela Lansbury, especially) The Bookman" and his henchman (who reminds me of the "Creeper" from the Sherlock Holmes series) are woefully-miscast; as they are too weird and sinister. "Portobello Road", a botched attempt at recreating the "Consider Yourself" musical number from "Oliver", is far too long. It seems more like a parade at Walt Disney World than a part of the movie. The Germans are both bumbling and menacing. (How is that possible?) The U-boat captain is far too nice! Now here's what's good about the film: The special effects are outstanding. The "haunted armor" is wonderful, although the kids will enjoy the cartoon sequences better: 1. The soccer game animation is only fair by Disney standards and somewhat "mean spirited." 2. The reason that "Beautiful Briny Sea" is so wonderful is that both the story and song were ideas cut from "Mary Poppins" and used here. The restoration seems a bit odd: David Tomlinson's voice is noticeably re-dubbed and (according to English critics) a song is missing, but all the other songs and scenes are fully-restored. In spite of all my criticism, I really do like this film. After all, it did win two Academy Awards for Special Effects!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Slow to get going and feels a little padded but is good Disney fun overall
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bob the moo
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/5/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Three children evacuated from London end up being reluctantly taken in by an odd woman who lives on her own with a raggedy black cat. They don't even make it to the end of the first night before they observe that their new guardian Miss Price is not just odd, she is an actual witch, trying to perfect a spell to help with the war effort. While the children make this discovery, Miss Price makes her own  the mail-order college she has been training with is going out of business before she has everything she needs. With the help of Paul's knob (don't ask) they set off to London to find the Professor  the start of a much bigger adventure. For my girlfriend this film is a strong childhood memory but for me I don't think I had ever seen it. In an attempt to be nice I got it for her a few years ago to watch at Christmas time but it sat unwatched until a miserable Bank Holiday Monday produced the urge to nest and just watch a couple of easy movies. As far as first impressions go, the film doesn't seem to feel any pressure to make a good one and if I'm honest I wondered if the opening credit sequence would ever end (a sequence that only has context once you have watched the film till the end). The titles rolls for at least five minutes without much to recommend them for and the film opens in much the same vein. Although there are some amusing moments and a bit of fantasy in the opening 20 or so minutes, it is slow and takes a while to get going. It doesn't help that the plot is a little vague and messy so that at one point I was neither sure why they were doing what they were doing, nor sure I particularly cared why they were doing it. This is a bit harsh perhaps  but I was thinking what children (not the most patient demographic) would be doing during this  in particular I was trying to think of any child I know who would be entranced by the Portobello Road song and dance number! It is still OK at this stage though and the good news is that it gets better with plenty of action, fun, invention and wit moving forward. The plotting is still a little bit "hmm" but it gets to where it is going thanks to the timely mini-invasion. The soccer match, the underwater musical number and of course the battle at the end are all great fun and I imagine children will enjoy them as much as I did (well, moreso probably). The old-fashioned feel is nice and I did like the sense of good clean family fun which the whole film had  although I'm not sure why the script calls for Paul to expressly refer to his knob so often; it is too deliberate and scripted to be merely something cynical modern ears pick up on. The pacing of the film is generally good as well but it is a little slower than it needed to be and I think being honest they could have had 15 minutes out of this without too much bother and it would have been a better film for it; not to say it is bad for the length, just that it doesn't always seem to need it. The cast are quite fun and all buy into the family tone. Lansbury in particular sells the role and works very well with Tomlinson in the adult roles. The children are a little annoying until you get used to them having the cockney turned up to 11 throughout; odd that neither of the boys ever did acting after this considering I liked them better than O'Callaghan's Carrie, who has less to do. Regardless they all work well and even when the animated sections turn up, the humans don't get lost in the fantasy but remain solid characters. Bedknobs and Broomsticks isn't brilliant but it is a solidly fun Disney family film. The majority of the musical numbers could have been better, the plot could have been stronger and the pacing/length trimmed to be slicker but it does all work, albeit not as well as it could have done. Enjoyable nonetheless with good wit and imagination  off-target Disney is still good after all.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    a message of hope
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    donnapepper9
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/4/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Bedknobs and Broomsticks was a film of its time. Yes, war is a strong feature - but there are covert references to war and violence in a lot of children's films - Mulan? For me, this is an ideal children's film - there is such a sense of escapism involved, whilst at the same time there is no attempt made to conceal that bad things do happen in life. The moral of this story, in my opinion, is that in the face of adversity there is always hope, and in hope there is strength to face the enemy. Whatever form that enemy might take - kids have far superior imaginations than adults and I don't believe that they would take a negative message from a film like this.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "Any Sufficiently Advanced Technology Is Indistinguishable From Magic"-Clarkes Third Law
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    johnstonjames
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/7/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    do i believe in magic? well, no. i'm sorry to disappoint anyone, but no, there is no such thing as magic. everything can be explained. it's usually all smoke and mirrors. parents should be strongly cautioned about 'Bedknobs and Broomsticks'. not because i believe in witches or magic, that stuff is just a bunch of hocus pocus. there are no such thing as real witches and anyone over the age of six who believes that should have their noggin examined. if someone tries to tell you there is such a thing as real magic or witches, get away from them fast because they are obviously psychotic and probably very dangerous. as a Christian and a person who is concerned with the salvation of man's immortal soul, it's not the magic that bothers me, it's the movie's strong spirit of militarism that bothers me. this movie glorifies war. and what is war good for? absolutely nothing. this movie indoctrinates young children into the military industrial complex at an early age(i mean it's designed for young children). children should not learn to glorify war, they should be wary of it, if not afraid of it. World War II may or may not have been the right decision, but do we need to keep bringing up past wars? especially where children are concerned. nobody wants World War III here. that would be madness. do i like this movie? of course i do. i grew up with this film and it's always been a Disney favorite of mine. it's beautifully handled by director Robert Stevenson, it's very clever, and has a charming musical score by Disney song writers, the Sherman Brothers. the film has many smart insights into history and sometimes i think this film may be more about children than anything else. but every time i get too sentimental and cozy about this film i wake up and think, oh God! THIS IS ABOUT WAR! nobody in their right brain wants a frick'in WAR! as far as the witchcraft element? i said what i think of that. there ain't no such thing and if you believe it's real YOU ARE STUPID. as a Christian does it scare me? oh sometimes i get superstitious and then i wake up. i used to follow astrology in the newspaper and read my horoscope everyday to see if i could find out anything. do you know what happened? absolutely nothing. half the time the stupid horoscope seemed like it was speaking to someone else. hardly any of the advice changed or helped my life in anyway. it just made me believe in silly things. but there are evil, stupid people out there with very little education who actually believe in magic. and it doesn't help that the witchcraft in 'Bedknobs' is far more real than the silly 'Harry Potter' films. i mean 'Astoroth' was a famous occultist and some of the incantation words (though not many) are actual words. does that scare me? of course not dummies. but it does scare some really stupid people who are evil enough to believe it's real. those people's children probably won't mix well with children who come from a more enlightened, intelligent and practical family that won't believe in such idiocy. so be careful with this movie. it could cause you some trouble if you bring it up in the wrong place. as far as my own feelings go, i find this film cute and charming and terribly funny. others might not be as amused. be careful. you are crossing the line with this film. when you endorse or recommend this film you are advocating war. you are also stating that you prefer to take a practical, scientific approach to this world and debunk superstition. for those of you who might read this and still believe witchcraft is real, YOU ARE STUPID. bottom line. keep repeating to yourself "it's only a movie. it's only a movie. than seek therapy. for the families strong and smart enough to deal with this ticking time bomb of a film, take caution and enjoy. it's funny and fun.if you can handle it go for it. HELLBORNE HENBANE AQUINITE GLOW-WORM FIRE FIREFLY LIGHT!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    From Portabello Road to the Beautiful Briny Sea, Angela will take you past the age of Not Believing.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mark.waltz
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    There's more charm to this Disney musical than has been given credit for, even though a huge fan base obviously exists for it. The film was overshadowed by the memory of Disney's previous big movie musical where another British actress (Julie Andrews) shot to super-stardom playing a nanny with extraordinary powers. Here, Angela Lansbury is a wanna be witch who ends up in charge of three kids against her will and assists the British in fighting the Krauts of World War I with the help of her own magic powers. The same song-writing team of Robert and Richard Stevenson have created an equally engaging score, and I think it even tops the one for "Mary Poppins". Lansbury wins your heart immediately when she berates her cranky charges for being past that "Age of Not Believing" then takes them onto a magical journey into the depths of the Atlantic Ocean and into a magical island with its own Lion King and a horde of eccentric soccer playing animals, all with the assistance of her witch professor phony David Tomlinson. More eccentric than his disciplining father from "Mary Poppins", Tomlinson is more than welcomed back and a great co-star for Lansbury. He is hysterically funny in the partly animated soccer match where he is the referee and takes more than his share of abuse from this mythical animal kingdom. Fresh from her success as Broadway's "Mame" (with a few flops in between that have become cult classics thanks to her presence in them), Lansbury proves herself worthy of the movie musical, having been sadly dubbed most of the time when she was at MGM during their heyday. There's a bit of a Harry Potter and "Wicked" feeling to this story with quite the influence of the late 60's/early 70's Broadway feel in the live-action musical numbers. The lyrics are cleverly difficult to sing along with and may have you laughing as you try, especially the final number where Lansbury gets her witchcraft right in aiding a museum filled with ancient war artifacts to take on the German army. Another "Mary Poppins" veteran is back, Lansbury's old MGM co-star Reginald Owen, in one of his final appearances, and Roddy McDowall is amusingly effete as the British preacher who keeps popping in to check on the kiddies. Disney would obviously be influenced by this many years later when making their modern day musical classics such as "The Little Mermaid", "Beauty and the Beast" (by casting Lansbury in a key role) and "The Lion King".
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Dated Fantasy Flick's Finale Too Fast
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    William C. Uchtman (aesgaard41@hotmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    For myself as a boy, this movie's closing scenes with the ghostly army using nothing but Medieval weapons to battle and repulse an attempted Nazi landing in England during World War Two is one of the most lasting images in my mind. However, as an adult watching it today, it comes off as less magical with the horribly dated special effects. Overall, the movie has actually stood the test of time, still enchanting whole new generations of young children. Angela Lansbury as a young actress is charming and attractive, and David Tomlinson is a bit more animated and puckish that he was in "Mary Poppins," which this movie seems to be riding. The notable parallels between the two movies are obvious, but then it is quite clear that the two movies share much of the same production team members. Mostly for laughs, the film has very few scary scenes, and the aforementioned scene does not much more than walk and march except for a select few swinging swords and maces. There's a decent horror movie here once the Disney ingredients are removed. The songs, as effervescent as they are, are not nearly as infectious as the tunes from "Mary Poppins," and Roddy McDowell, who was quite a popular British actor for the time, sadly, gets very little to do in this movie. I don't get how destroying her research robs Lansbury's character of her mystical powers, but I just wish the movie had lasted just a bit longer to reveal the clean-up of the countryside to retrieve the museum artifacts and period costumes now mysteriously damaged and bullet-ridden and scattered through the woods. I mean, come on, how did they explain that?
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Aging Special Effects and Uneven Script
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tabuno
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    At the time, this dazzling display of live action and animation must of been quite a treat for its audience, receiving an Oscar award for best special effects. Alas time has not been kind to this heavily special effects dependent movie which is also weighed down by an uneven script. The director was able to balance this movie's genre or tone - was this to be a musical or just family comedy or drama. This movie appears to have ignored the director's own magical success of Mary Poppins (1964) released seven years earlier. Like Sean Penn directing Into the Wild (2007), director Robert Stevenson perhaps let success go to his head, or maybe insecurity by focusing so much on special effects and musical numbers that the story itself sometimes became secondary to the showing off the supposed "brilliance" of the animations. For example, Emelius fades almost into insignificance during the soccer game, or the primary characters are lost in the overly crowded and extended dance routine in the town. Even the television episode of Buffy: The Vampire Slayer - Once More, With Feeling (2001) displays how to both enhance the storyline and the characters with music instead of hiding them and ignoring the story. Cool World (1992), Jim Carrey's The Mask (1994), Monkey Bones (2001) all built on the break out live animation film Who Framed Roger Rabbit (1988). But even back in 1964, Arthur Lubin known for televisions series Mr. Ed and The Addams Family directed a neat live animation mixture with Don Knott's in The Incredible Mr. Limpet. Overall, what once was a new and delightful children's film has aged and not well.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A failed attempt to recapture the magic of Mary Poppins, but with a good set-piece finale
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    David Conrad
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    All the elements from "Mary Poppins" are here: a stern, magical nanny who flies, a kooky male street performer with whom she has some history, and period-specific English kids who tag along with the unconventional adults through foggy London streets and animated fantasy lands. Even one of the actors, David Tomlinson, is borrowed from Poppins. Yet Disney's attempt to strike gold twice fails. The pacing is much slower, particularly on the restored DVD release in which 30 minutes of footage cut from the theatrical release are reinserted. The songs are bland affairs that Tomlinson and Angela Lansbury meander through without much energy. During the animation sequence, the live actors are sidelined for an interminable soccer match between lions, alligators, and bears. These animal drawings are templates lifted from Disney's "The Jungle Book" (1967), and they would be recycled again in the studio's "Robin Hood" (1973). The final act of "Bedknobs," though it comes too late and lasts too long, does partly redeem it: special effects steal the show as an army of English museum pieces, mainly empty suits of medieval armor, come to life and march against the most incompetent Nazi invasion force in screen history. It would be better to YouTube that sequence than to sit through the movie to get to it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Honestly runs better in the standard cut
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Foux_du_Fafa
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Though far from perfect, "Bedknobs and Broomsticks" has always been a favourite of mine since childhood. The plot may be a bit muddled in places, but the sheer joy and fun of the fantasy material makes up for it. The animated sequences in particular are a real joy, as is the comedy-action climax to the film. Some of the songs are underrated classics, in particular "The Age of Not Believing" and "The Beautiful Briny". Also, the elaborate opening credit sequence is gorgeous to look at. That said, you may want to be careful which version of the film you see. The film premiered at around 135 minutes, but was cut down for general release to 117 minutes. This 117 minute version was the one I first saw as a child. In 1996, Disney restored the film to a length comparable to the premiere version, and this is what was released onto DVD. Ironically, I think the film does run better at a shorter length. Much of what is added are new or extended musical numbers, as well as the extension of a rather superfluous subplot involving a somewhat saucy vicar. I don't particularly find the new musical numbers that engaging, and the numbers that are extended aren't that great. Though there are some interesting extra verses in the extended "Portobello Road" number, the several dance scenes added to it renders it seemingly unending. "Eglantine" also goes on a bit too much for my liking. In addition some re-dubbing was required for some of the new scenes as the original mastertracks were not found. Angela Lansbury was able to come back and sounds fine, but many of the other actors weren't and the results are mixed. It would be nice if an inevitable Blu-Ray showed the film in either two of its versions, or if at least the original dialogue tapes were found for the extended scenes. I do believe that there are still ways to get hold of the 117 minute version. I have the first UK DVD release from around 2002, but I have read on Amazon that a later UK release has the film run at 117 minutes in order to align itself with some old European dubs on the disc, and I've also read online that TCM in the US sometimes shows the shorter version. In any case, "Bedknobs and Broomsticks" is a fun, family classic and easily worthy of my recommendation.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Way Too Long, Way Too Dull
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Joshua Mitchell
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Bedknobs And Broomsticks is rather obscure when compared to Disney's other films. This isn't a bad thing, though, considering most of Disney's other films are far superior to this overlong production. Lacking any excitement, or even laugh-worthy humor, Bedknobs And Broomsticks has little appeal to those over the age of 10, and even the youngest will likely be bored by the constant chatter and uninventive musical numbers. Three children named Carrie, Charlie and Paul are temporarily adopted by Eglantine Price, whom they discover to be a witch. Ms. Prince gives the children a traveling spell, in exchange for keeping her secret, which allows their bed to teleport to any given location. The four also snag Emelius Browne- Ms. Price's witch teacher- into the adventure as well. As one would expect, there are countless plot holes and silly things that are overlooked by the characters, but this is the least of the film's problems. Bedknobs And Broomsticks runs for a taxing two and a half hours. Had Bedknobs And Broomsticks been truly entertaining, this would not be a problem. Another Disney musical, Mary Poppins has a run time around the same length, and is loved and adored by all ages. Needless to say, Bedknobs And Broomsticks is no Mary Poppins. The content of this dull musical, does not justify the relentlessly long length. The number of songs in the film are not nearly as high as that of Mary Poppins, but they are far less inventive. Despite being penned by the Sherman brothers, the same duo that wrote the songs in Mary Poppins, each and every number is dull to limit. Occasionally, dancing takes place during these numbers, though the choreography is poor and uninspired. What's strange is that the beat of the music, often does not meet the beat of the dancing, which seems truly lazy. The score, also by the Sherman brothers isn't too shabby, and the bed traveling theme is relatively strong, but the score often sounds too similar to the Mary Poppins score (especially in the earlier segments). Also, if you hate bagpipes, you will definitely want to avoid this, as the aforementioned instruments make more than one appearance. Bedknobs And Broomsticks is specifically known for the Land of Naboombu, which is completely animated. It's always a marvel to see live-acted characters interact with animated ones. Alas, despite being showcased as the main attraction in Bedknobs And Broomsticks, the Land of Naboombu occupies a measly 30 minutes of the extensive run time. Talk about misleading! Special effects often look dated, and the strings that are used to suspend objects in midair are clearly visible most of the time. There are some decent effects though, make no mistake about it. But not all of the effects are as polished as others. The children are poorly acted, and most other actors fall into the unspectacular area. Only Angela Lansbury and David Tomlinson stand out. Bedknobs And Broomsticks is wholly unspectacular. It lacks the humor and excitement it needed to translate into the fun adventure it fails to be. Add that with the overlong run time and the dull musical numbers, and you get a animated musical that is unlikely to leave anyone coming back for more.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The restored version is a Disney classic but certainly no "Mary Poppins"
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mike48128
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/7/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Mary Poppins is a 10, so what's wrong with "Bedknobs" besides it's too long? A lack of "whimsey and wonder". Like comparing "Sleeping Beauty" to Snow White". (Both classics) So let's begin: The opening credits are far too long, as Disney liked to front-load all the credits during this era. The storyboarded titles tell the entire plot line so nothing is left to the imagination. It's like an overlong movie "trailer" that does the same thing. At first the characters are dreadful, and only start to improve in "likeability" as the story progresses. (Angela Lansbury, especially) The Bookman" and his henchman (who reminds me of the "Creeper" from the Sherlock Holmes series) are woefully-miscast; as they are too weird and sinister. "Portobello Road", a botched attempt at recreating the "Consider Yourself" musical number from "Oliver", is far too long. It seems more like a parade at Walt Disney World than a part of the movie. The Germans are both bumbling and menacing. (How is that possible?) The U-boat captain is far too nice! Now here's what's good about the film: The special effects are outstanding. The "haunted armor" is wonderful, although the kids will enjoy the cartoon sequences better: 1. The soccer game animation is only fair by Disney standards and somewhat "mean spirited." 2. The reason that "Beautiful Briny Sea" is so wonderful is that both the story and song were ideas cut from "Mary Poppins" and used here. The restoration seems a bit odd: David Tomlinson's voice is noticeably re-dubbed and (according to English critics) a song is missing, but all the other songs and scenes are fully-restored. In spite of all my criticism, I really do like this film. After all, it did win two Academy Awards for Special Effects!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Slow to get going and feels a little padded but is good Disney fun overall
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bob the moo
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/5/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Three children evacuated from London end up being reluctantly taken in by an odd woman who lives on her own with a raggedy black cat. They don't even make it to the end of the first night before they observe that their new guardian Miss Price is not just odd, she is an actual witch, trying to perfect a spell to help with the war effort. While the children make this discovery, Miss Price makes her own  the mail-order college she has been training with is going out of business before she has everything she needs. With the help of Paul's knob (don't ask) they set off to London to find the Professor  the start of a much bigger adventure. For my girlfriend this film is a strong childhood memory but for me I don't think I had ever seen it. In an attempt to be nice I got it for her a few years ago to watch at Christmas time but it sat unwatched until a miserable Bank Holiday Monday produced the urge to nest and just watch a couple of easy movies. As far as first impressions go, the film doesn't seem to feel any pressure to make a good one and if I'm honest I wondered if the opening credit sequence would ever end (a sequence that only has context once you have watched the film till the end). The titles rolls for at least five minutes without much to recommend them for and the film opens in much the same vein. Although there are some amusing moments and a bit of fantasy in the opening 20 or so minutes, it is slow and takes a while to get going. It doesn't help that the plot is a little vague and messy so that at one point I was neither sure why they were doing what they were doing, nor sure I particularly cared why they were doing it. This is a bit harsh perhaps  but I was thinking what children (not the most patient demographic) would be doing during this  in particular I was trying to think of any child I know who would be entranced by the Portobello Road song and dance number! It is still OK at this stage though and the good news is that it gets better with plenty of action, fun, invention and wit moving forward. The plotting is still a little bit "hmm" but it gets to where it is going thanks to the timely mini-invasion. The soccer match, the underwater musical number and of course the battle at the end are all great fun and I imagine children will enjoy them as much as I did (well, moreso probably). The old-fashioned feel is nice and I did like the sense of good clean family fun which the whole film had  although I'm not sure why the script calls for Paul to expressly refer to his knob so often; it is too deliberate and scripted to be merely something cynical modern ears pick up on. The pacing of the film is generally good as well but it is a little slower than it needed to be and I think being honest they could have had 15 minutes out of this without too much bother and it would have been a better film for it; not to say it is bad for the length, just that it doesn't always seem to need it. The cast are quite fun and all buy into the family tone. Lansbury in particular sells the role and works very well with Tomlinson in the adult roles. The children are a little annoying until you get used to them having the cockney turned up to 11 throughout; odd that neither of the boys ever did acting after this considering I liked them better than O'Callaghan's Carrie, who has less to do. Regardless they all work well and even when the animated sections turn up, the humans don't get lost in the fantasy but remain solid characters. Bedknobs and Broomsticks isn't brilliant but it is a solidly fun Disney family film. The majority of the musical numbers could have been better, the plot could have been stronger and the pacing/length trimmed to be slicker but it does all work, albeit not as well as it could have done. Enjoyable nonetheless with good wit and imagination  off-target Disney is still good after all.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    a message of hope
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    donnapepper9
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/4/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Bedknobs and Broomsticks was a film of its time. Yes, war is a strong feature - but there are covert references to war and violence in a lot of children's films - Mulan? For me, this is an ideal children's film - there is such a sense of escapism involved, whilst at the same time there is no attempt made to conceal that bad things do happen in life. The moral of this story, in my opinion, is that in the face of adversity there is always hope, and in hope there is strength to face the enemy. Whatever form that enemy might take - kids have far superior imaginations than adults and I don't believe that they would take a negative message from a film like this.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "Any Sufficiently Advanced Technology Is Indistinguishable From Magic"-Clarkes Third Law
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    johnstonjames
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/7/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    do i believe in magic? well, no. i'm sorry to disappoint anyone, but no, there is no such thing as magic. everything can be explained. it's usually all smoke and mirrors. parents should be strongly cautioned about 'Bedknobs and Broomsticks'. not because i believe in witches or magic, that stuff is just a bunch of hocus pocus. there are no such thing as real witches and anyone over the age of six who believes that should have their noggin examined. if someone tries to tell you there is such a thing as real magic or witches, get away from them fast because they are obviously psychotic and probably very dangerous. as a Christian and a person who is concerned with the salvation of man's immortal soul, it's not the magic that bothers me, it's the movie's strong spirit of militarism that bothers me. this movie glorifies war. and what is war good for? absolutely nothing. this movie indoctrinates young children into the military industrial complex at an early age(i mean it's designed for young children). children should not learn to glorify war, they should be wary of it, if not afraid of it. World War II may or may not have been the right decision, but do we need to keep bringing up past wars? especially where children are concerned. nobody wants World War III here. that would be madness. do i like this movie? of course i do. i grew up with this film and it's always been a Disney favorite of mine. it's beautifully handled by director Robert Stevenson, it's very clever, and has a charming musical score by Disney song writers, the Sherman Brothers. the film has many smart insights into history and sometimes i think this film may be more about children than anything else. but every time i get too sentimental and cozy about this film i wake up and think, oh God! THIS IS ABOUT WAR! nobody in their right brain wants a frick'in WAR! as far as the witchcraft element? i said what i think of that. there ain't no such thing and if you believe it's real YOU ARE STUPID. as a Christian does it scare me? oh sometimes i get superstitious and then i wake up. i used to follow astrology in the newspaper and read my horoscope everyday to see if i could find out anything. do you know what happened? absolutely nothing. half the time the stupid horoscope seemed like it was speaking to someone else. hardly any of the advice changed or helped my life in anyway. it just made me believe in silly things. but there are evil, stupid people out there with very little education who actually believe in magic. and it doesn't help that the witchcraft in 'Bedknobs' is far more real than the silly 'Harry Potter' films. i mean 'Astoroth' was a famous occultist and some of the incantation words (though not many) are actual words. does that scare me? of course not dummies. but it does scare some really stupid people who are evil enough to believe it's real. those people's children probably won't mix well with children who come from a more enlightened, intelligent and practical family that won't believe in such idiocy. so be careful with this movie. it could cause you some trouble if you bring it up in the wrong place. as far as my own feelings go, i find this film cute and charming and terribly funny. others might not be as amused. be careful. you are crossing the line with this film. when you endorse or recommend this film you are advocating war. you are also stating that you prefer to take a practical, scientific approach to this world and debunk superstition. for those of you who might read this and still believe witchcraft is real, YOU ARE STUPID. bottom line. keep repeating to yourself "it's only a movie. it's only a movie. than seek therapy. for the families strong and smart enough to deal with this ticking time bomb of a film, take caution and enjoy. it's funny and fun.if you can handle it go for it. HELLBORNE HENBANE AQUINITE GLOW-WORM FIRE FIREFLY LIGHT!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    From Portabello Road to the Beautiful Briny Sea, Angela will take you past the age of Not Believing.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mark.waltz
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    There's more charm to this Disney musical than has been given credit for, even though a huge fan base obviously exists for it. The film was overshadowed by the memory of Disney's previous big movie musical where another British actress (Julie Andrews) shot to super-stardom playing a nanny with extraordinary powers. Here, Angela Lansbury is a wanna be witch who ends up in charge of three kids against her will and assists the British in fighting the Krauts of World War I with the help of her own magic powers. The same song-writing team of Robert and Richard Stevenson have created an equally engaging score, and I think it even tops the one for "Mary Poppins". Lansbury wins your heart immediately when she berates her cranky charges for being past that "Age of Not Believing" then takes them onto a magical journey into the depths of the Atlantic Ocean and into a magical island with its own Lion King and a horde of eccentric soccer playing animals, all with the assistance of her witch professor phony David Tomlinson. More eccentric than his disciplining father from "Mary Poppins", Tomlinson is more than welcomed back and a great co-star for Lansbury. He is hysterically funny in the partly animated soccer match where he is the referee and takes more than his share of abuse from this mythical animal kingdom. Fresh from her success as Broadway's "Mame" (with a few flops in between that have become cult classics thanks to her presence in them), Lansbury proves herself worthy of the movie musical, having been sadly dubbed most of the time when she was at MGM during their heyday. There's a bit of a Harry Potter and "Wicked" feeling to this story with quite the influence of the late 60's/early 70's Broadway feel in the live-action musical numbers. The lyrics are cleverly difficult to sing along with and may have you laughing as you try, especially the final number where Lansbury gets her witchcraft right in aiding a museum filled with ancient war artifacts to take on the German army. Another "Mary Poppins" veteran is back, Lansbury's old MGM co-star Reginald Owen, in one of his final appearances, and Roddy McDowall is amusingly effete as the British preacher who keeps popping in to check on the kiddies. Disney would obviously be influenced by this many years later when making their modern day musical classics such as "The Little Mermaid", "Beauty and the Beast" (by casting Lansbury in a key role) and "The Lion King".
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Dated Fantasy Flick's Finale Too Fast
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    William C. Uchtman (aesgaard41@hotmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    For myself as a boy, this movie's closing scenes with the ghostly army using nothing but Medieval weapons to battle and repulse an attempted Nazi landing in England during World War Two is one of the most lasting images in my mind. However, as an adult watching it today, it comes off as less magical with the horribly dated special effects. Overall, the movie has actually stood the test of time, still enchanting whole new generations of young children. Angela Lansbury as a young actress is charming and attractive, and David Tomlinson is a bit more animated and puckish that he was in "Mary Poppins," which this movie seems to be riding. The notable parallels between the two movies are obvious, but then it is quite clear that the two movies share much of the same production team members. Mostly for laughs, the film has very few scary scenes, and the aforementioned scene does not much more than walk and march except for a select few swinging swords and maces. There's a decent horror movie here once the Disney ingredients are removed. The songs, as effervescent as they are, are not nearly as infectious as the tunes from "Mary Poppins," and Roddy McDowell, who was quite a popular British actor for the time, sadly, gets very little to do in this movie. I don't get how destroying her research robs Lansbury's character of her mystical powers, but I just wish the movie had lasted just a bit longer to reveal the clean-up of the countryside to retrieve the museum artifacts and period costumes now mysteriously damaged and bullet-ridden and scattered through the woods. I mean, come on, how did they explain that?
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Aging Special Effects and Uneven Script
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tabuno
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    At the time, this dazzling display of live action and animation must of been quite a treat for its audience, receiving an Oscar award for best special effects. Alas time has not been kind to this heavily special effects dependent movie which is also weighed down by an uneven script. The director was able to balance this movie's genre or tone - was this to be a musical or just family comedy or drama. This movie appears to have ignored the director's own magical success of Mary Poppins (1964) released seven years earlier. Like Sean Penn directing Into the Wild (2007), director Robert Stevenson perhaps let success go to his head, or maybe insecurity by focusing so much on special effects and musical numbers that the story itself sometimes became secondary to the showing off the supposed "brilliance" of the animations. For example, Emelius fades almost into insignificance during the soccer game, or the primary characters are lost in the overly crowded and extended dance routine in the town. Even the television episode of Buffy: The Vampire Slayer - Once More, With Feeling (2001) displays how to both enhance the storyline and the characters with music instead of hiding them and ignoring the story. Cool World (1992), Jim Carrey's The Mask (1994), Monkey Bones (2001) all built on the break out live animation film Who Framed Roger Rabbit (1988). But even back in 1964, Arthur Lubin known for televisions series Mr. Ed and The Addams Family directed a neat live animation mixture with Don Knott's in The Incredible Mr. Limpet. Overall, what once was a new and delightful children's film has aged and not well.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A failed attempt to recapture the magic of Mary Poppins, but with a good set-piece finale
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    David Conrad
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    All the elements from "Mary Poppins" are here: a stern, magical nanny who flies, a kooky male street performer with whom she has some history, and period-specific English kids who tag along with the unconventional adults through foggy London streets and animated fantasy lands. Even one of the actors, David Tomlinson, is borrowed from Poppins. Yet Disney's attempt to strike gold twice fails. The pacing is much slower, particularly on the restored DVD release in which 30 minutes of footage cut from the theatrical release are reinserted. The songs are bland affairs that Tomlinson and Angela Lansbury meander through without much energy. During the animation sequence, the live actors are sidelined for an interminable soccer match between lions, alligators, and bears. These animal drawings are templates lifted from Disney's "The Jungle Book" (1967), and they would be recycled again in the studio's "Robin Hood" (1973). The final act of "Bedknobs," though it comes too late and lasts too long, does partly redeem it: special effects steal the show as an army of English museum pieces, mainly empty suits of medieval armor, come to life and march against the most incompetent Nazi invasion force in screen history. It would be better to YouTube that sequence than to sit through the movie to get to it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Honestly runs better in the standard cut
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Foux_du_Fafa
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Though far from perfect, "Bedknobs and Broomsticks" has always been a favourite of mine since childhood. The plot may be a bit muddled in places, but the sheer joy and fun of the fantasy material makes up for it. The animated sequences in particular are a real joy, as is the comedy-action climax to the film. Some of the songs are underrated classics, in particular "The Age of Not Believing" and "The Beautiful Briny". Also, the elaborate opening credit sequence is gorgeous to look at. That said, you may want to be careful which version of the film you see. The film premiered at around 135 minutes, but was cut down for general release to 117 minutes. This 117 minute version was the one I first saw as a child. In 1996, Disney restored the film to a length comparable to the premiere version, and this is what was released onto DVD. Ironically, I think the film does run better at a shorter length. Much of what is added are new or extended musical numbers, as well as the extension of a rather superfluous subplot involving a somewhat saucy vicar. I don't particularly find the new musical numbers that engaging, and the numbers that are extended aren't that great. Though there are some interesting extra verses in the extended "Portobello Road" number, the several dance scenes added to it renders it seemingly unending. "Eglantine" also goes on a bit too much for my liking. In addition some re-dubbing was required for some of the new scenes as the original mastertracks were not found. Angela Lansbury was able to come back and sounds fine, but many of the other actors weren't and the results are mixed. It would be nice if an inevitable Blu-Ray showed the film in either two of its versions, or if at least the original dialogue tapes were found for the extended scenes. I do believe that there are still ways to get hold of the 117 minute version. I have the first UK DVD release from around 2002, but I have read on Amazon that a later UK release has the film run at 117 minutes in order to align itself with some old European dubs on the disc, and I've also read online that TCM in the US sometimes shows the shorter version. In any case, "Bedknobs and Broomsticks" is a fun, family classic and easily worthy of my recommendation.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Way Too Long, Way Too Dull
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Joshua Mitchell
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Bedknobs And Broomsticks is rather obscure when compared to Disney's other films. This isn't a bad thing, though, considering most of Disney's other films are far superior to this overlong production. Lacking any excitement, or even laugh-worthy humor, Bedknobs And Broomsticks has little appeal to those over the age of 10, and even the youngest will likely be bored by the constant chatter and uninventive musical numbers. Three children named Carrie, Charlie and Paul are temporarily adopted by Eglantine Price, whom they discover to be a witch. Ms. Prince gives the children a traveling spell, in exchange for keeping her secret, which allows their bed to teleport to any given location. The four also snag Emelius Browne- Ms. Price's witch teacher- into the adventure as well. As one would expect, there are countless plot holes and silly things that are overlooked by the characters, but this is the least of the film's problems. Bedknobs And Broomsticks runs for a taxing two and a half hours. Had Bedknobs And Broomsticks been truly entertaining, this would not be a problem. Another Disney musical, Mary Poppins has a run time around the same length, and is loved and adored by all ages. Needless to say, Bedknobs And Broomsticks is no Mary Poppins. The content of this dull musical, does not justify the relentlessly long length. The number of songs in the film are not nearly as high as that of Mary Poppins, but they are far less inventive. Despite being penned by the Sherman brothers, the same duo that wrote the songs in Mary Poppins, each and every number is dull to limit. Occasionally, dancing takes place during these numbers, though the choreography is poor and uninspired. What's strange is that the beat of the music, often does not meet the beat of the dancing, which seems truly lazy. The score, also by the Sherman brothers isn't too shabby, and the bed traveling theme is relatively strong, but the score often sounds too similar to the Mary Poppins score (especially in the earlier segments). Also, if you hate bagpipes, you will definitely want to avoid this, as the aforementioned instruments make more than one appearance. Bedknobs And Broomsticks is specifically known for the Land of Naboombu, which is completely animated. It's always a marvel to see live-acted characters interact with animated ones. Alas, despite being showcased as the main attraction in Bedknobs And Broomsticks, the Land of Naboombu occupies a measly 30 minutes of the extensive run time. Talk about misleading! Special effects often look dated, and the strings that are used to suspend objects in midair are clearly visible most of the time. There are some decent effects though, make no mistake about it. But not all of the effects are as polished as others. The children are poorly acted, and most other actors fall into the unspectacular area. Only Angela Lansbury and David Tomlinson stand out. Bedknobs And Broomsticks is wholly unspectacular. It lacks the humor and excitement it needed to translate into the fun adventure it fails to be. Add that with the overlong run time and the dull musical numbers, and you get a animated musical that is unlikely to leave anyone coming back for more.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The restored version is a Disney classic but certainly no "Mary Poppins"
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mike48128
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/7/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Mary Poppins is a 10, so what's wrong with "Bedknobs" besides it's too long? A lack of "whimsey and wonder". Like comparing "Sleeping Beauty" to Snow White". (Both classics) So let's begin: The opening credits are far too long, as Disney liked to front-load all the credits during this era. The storyboarded titles tell the entire plot line so nothing is left to the imagination. It's like an overlong movie "trailer" that does the same thing. At first the characters are dreadful, and only start to improve in "likeability" as the story progresses. (Angela Lansbury, especially) The Bookman" and his henchman (who reminds me of the "Creeper" from the Sherlock Holmes series) are woefully-miscast; as they are too weird and sinister. "Portobello Road", a botched attempt at recreating the "Consider Yourself" musical number from "Oliver", is far too long. It seems more like a parade at Walt Disney World than a part of the movie. The Germans are both bumbling and menacing. (How is that possible?) The U-boat captain is far too nice! Now here's what's good about the film: The special effects are outstanding. The "haunted armor" is wonderful, although the kids will enjoy the cartoon sequences better: 1. The soccer game animation is only fair by Disney standards and somewhat "mean spirited." 2. The reason that "Beautiful Briny Sea" is so wonderful is that both the story and song were ideas cut from "Mary Poppins" and used here. The restoration seems a bit odd: David Tomlinson's voice is noticeably re-dubbed and (according to English critics) a song is missing, but all the other songs and scenes are fully-restored. In spite of all my criticism, I really do like this film. After all, it did win two Academy Awards for Special Effects!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Slow to get going and feels a little padded but is good Disney fun overall
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bob the moo
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/5/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Three children evacuated from London end up being reluctantly taken in by an odd woman who lives on her own with a raggedy black cat. They don't even make it to the end of the first night before they observe that their new guardian Miss Price is not just odd, she is an actual witch, trying to perfect a spell to help with the war effort. While the children make this discovery, Miss Price makes her own  the mail-order college she has been training with is going out of business before she has everything she needs. With the help of Paul's knob (don't ask) they set off to London to find the Professor  the start of a much bigger adventure. For my girlfriend this film is a strong childhood memory but for me I don't think I had ever seen it. In an attempt to be nice I got it for her a few years ago to watch at Christmas time but it sat unwatched until a miserable Bank Holiday Monday produced the urge to nest and just watch a couple of easy movies. As far as first impressions go, the film doesn't seem to feel any pressure to make a good one and if I'm honest I wondered if the opening credit sequence would ever end (a sequence that only has context once you have watched the film till the end). The titles rolls for at least five minutes without much to recommend them for and the film opens in much the same vein. Although there are some amusing moments and a bit of fantasy in the opening 20 or so minutes, it is slow and takes a while to get going. It doesn't help that the plot is a little vague and messy so that at one point I was neither sure why they were doing what they were doing, nor sure I particularly cared why they were doing it. This is a bit harsh perhaps  but I was thinking what children (not the most patient demographic) would be doing during this  in particular I was trying to think of any child I know who would be entranced by the Portobello Road song and dance number! It is still OK at this stage though and the good news is that it gets better with plenty of action, fun, invention and wit moving forward. The plotting is still a little bit "hmm" but it gets to where it is going thanks to the timely mini-invasion. The soccer match, the underwater musical number and of course the battle at the end are all great fun and I imagine children will enjoy them as much as I did (well, moreso probably). The old-fashioned feel is nice and I did like the sense of good clean family fun which the whole film had  although I'm not sure why the script calls for Paul to expressly refer to his knob so often; it is too deliberate and scripted to be merely something cynical modern ears pick up on. The pacing of the film is generally good as well but it is a little slower than it needed to be and I think being honest they could have had 15 minutes out of this without too much bother and it would have been a better film for it; not to say it is bad for the length, just that it doesn't always seem to need it. The cast are quite fun and all buy into the family tone. Lansbury in particular sells the role and works very well with Tomlinson in the adult roles. The children are a little annoying until you get used to them having the cockney turned up to 11 throughout; odd that neither of the boys ever did acting after this considering I liked them better than O'Callaghan's Carrie, who has less to do. Regardless they all work well and even when the animated sections turn up, the humans don't get lost in the fantasy but remain solid characters. Bedknobs and Broomsticks isn't brilliant but it is a solidly fun Disney family film. The majority of the musical numbers could have been better, the plot could have been stronger and the pacing/length trimmed to be slicker but it does all work, albeit not as well as it could have done. Enjoyable nonetheless with good wit and imagination  off-target Disney is still good after all.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    a message of hope
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    donnapepper9
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/4/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Bedknobs and Broomsticks was a film of its time. Yes, war is a strong feature - but there are covert references to war and violence in a lot of children's films - Mulan? For me, this is an ideal children's film - there is such a sense of escapism involved, whilst at the same time there is no attempt made to conceal that bad things do happen in life. The moral of this story, in my opinion, is that in the face of adversity there is always hope, and in hope there is strength to face the enemy. Whatever form that enemy might take - kids have far superior imaginations than adults and I don't believe that they would take a negative message from a film like this.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "Any Sufficiently Advanced Technology Is Indistinguishable From Magic"-Clarkes Third Law
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    johnstonjames
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/7/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    do i believe in magic? well, no. i'm sorry to disappoint anyone, but no, there is no such thing as magic. everything can be explained. it's usually all smoke and mirrors. parents should be strongly cautioned about 'Bedknobs and Broomsticks'. not because i believe in witches or magic, that stuff is just a bunch of hocus pocus. there are no such thing as real witches and anyone over the age of six who believes that should have their noggin examined. if someone tries to tell you there is such a thing as real magic or witches, get away from them fast because they are obviously psychotic and probably very dangerous. as a Christian and a person who is concerned with the salvation of man's immortal soul, it's not the magic that bothers me, it's the movie's strong spirit of militarism that bothers me. this movie glorifies war. and what is war good for? absolutely nothing. this movie indoctrinates young children into the military industrial complex at an early age(i mean it's designed for young children). children should not learn to glorify war, they should be wary of it, if not afraid of it. World War II may or may not have been the right decision, but do we need to keep bringing up past wars? especially where children are concerned. nobody wants World War III here. that would be madness. do i like this movie? of course i do. i grew up with this film and it's always been a Disney favorite of mine. it's beautifully handled by director Robert Stevenson, it's very clever, and has a charming musical score by Disney song writers, the Sherman Brothers. the film has many smart insights into history and sometimes i think this film may be more about children than anything else. but every time i get too sentimental and cozy about this film i wake up and think, oh God! THIS IS ABOUT WAR! nobody in their right brain wants a frick'in WAR! as far as the witchcraft element? i said what i think of that. there ain't no such thing and if you believe it's real YOU ARE STUPID. as a Christian does it scare me? oh sometimes i get superstitious and then i wake up. i used to follow astrology in the newspaper and read my horoscope everyday to see if i could find out anything. do you know what happened? absolutely nothing. half the time the stupid horoscope seemed like it was speaking to someone else. hardly any of the advice changed or helped my life in anyway. it just made me believe in silly things. but there are evil, stupid people out there with very little education who actually believe in magic. and it doesn't help that the witchcraft in 'Bedknobs' is far more real than the silly 'Harry Potter' films. i mean 'Astoroth' was a famous occultist and some of the incantation words (though not many) are actual words. does that scare me? of course not dummies. but it does scare some really stupid people who are evil enough to believe it's real. those people's children probably won't mix well with children who come from a more enlightened, intelligent and practical family that won't believe in such idiocy. so be careful with this movie. it could cause you some trouble if you bring it up in the wrong place. as far as my own feelings go, i find this film cute and charming and terribly funny. others might not be as amused. be careful. you are crossing the line with this film. when you endorse or recommend this film you are advocating war. you are also stating that you prefer to take a practical, scientific approach to this world and debunk superstition. for those of you who might read this and still believe witchcraft is real, YOU ARE STUPID. bottom line. keep repeating to yourself "it's only a movie. it's only a movie. than seek therapy. for the families strong and smart enough to deal with this ticking time bomb of a film, take caution and enjoy. it's funny and fun.if you can handle it go for it. HELLBORNE HENBANE AQUINITE GLOW-WORM FIRE FIREFLY LIGHT!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    From Portabello Road to the Beautiful Briny Sea, Angela will take you past the age of Not Believing.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mark.waltz
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    There's more charm to this Disney musical than has been given credit for, even though a huge fan base obviously exists for it. The film was overshadowed by the memory of Disney's previous big movie musical where another British actress (Julie Andrews) shot to super-stardom playing a nanny with extraordinary powers. Here, Angela Lansbury is a wanna be witch who ends up in charge of three kids against her will and assists the British in fighting the Krauts of World War I with the help of her own magic powers. The same song-writing team of Robert and Richard Stevenson have created an equally engaging score, and I think it even tops the one for "Mary Poppins". Lansbury wins your heart immediately when she berates her cranky charges for being past that "Age of Not Believing" then takes them onto a magical journey into the depths of the Atlantic Ocean and into a magical island with its own Lion King and a horde of eccentric soccer playing animals, all with the assistance of her witch professor phony David Tomlinson. More eccentric than his disciplining father from "Mary Poppins", Tomlinson is more than welcomed back and a great co-star for Lansbury. He is hysterically funny in the partly animated soccer match where he is the referee and takes more than his share of abuse from this mythical animal kingdom. Fresh from her success as Broadway's "Mame" (with a few flops in between that have become cult classics thanks to her presence in them), Lansbury proves herself worthy of the movie musical, having been sadly dubbed most of the time when she was at MGM during their heyday. There's a bit of a Harry Potter and "Wicked" feeling to this story with quite the influence of the late 60's/early 70's Broadway feel in the live-action musical numbers. The lyrics are cleverly difficult to sing along with and may have you laughing as you try, especially the final number where Lansbury gets her witchcraft right in aiding a museum filled with ancient war artifacts to take on the German army. Another "Mary Poppins" veteran is back, Lansbury's old MGM co-star Reginald Owen, in one of his final appearances, and Roddy McDowall is amusingly effete as the British preacher who keeps popping in to check on the kiddies. Disney would obviously be influenced by this many years later when making their modern day musical classics such as "The Little Mermaid", "Beauty and the Beast" (by casting Lansbury in a key role) and "The Lion King".
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Dated Fantasy Flick's Finale Too Fast
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    William C. Uchtman (aesgaard41@hotmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    For myself as a boy, this movie's closing scenes with the ghostly army using nothing but Medieval weapons to battle and repulse an attempted Nazi landing in England during World War Two is one of the most lasting images in my mind. However, as an adult watching it today, it comes off as less magical with the horribly dated special effects. Overall, the movie has actually stood the test of time, still enchanting whole new generations of young children. Angela Lansbury as a young actress is charming and attractive, and David Tomlinson is a bit more animated and puckish that he was in "Mary Poppins," which this movie seems to be riding. The notable parallels between the two movies are obvious, but then it is quite clear that the two movies share much of the same production team members. Mostly for laughs, the film has very few scary scenes, and the aforementioned scene does not much more than walk and march except for a select few swinging swords and maces. There's a decent horror movie here once the Disney ingredients are removed. The songs, as effervescent as they are, are not nearly as infectious as the tunes from "Mary Poppins," and Roddy McDowell, who was quite a popular British actor for the time, sadly, gets very little to do in this movie. I don't get how destroying her research robs Lansbury's character of her mystical powers, but I just wish the movie had lasted just a bit longer to reveal the clean-up of the countryside to retrieve the museum artifacts and period costumes now mysteriously damaged and bullet-ridden and scattered through the woods. I mean, come on, how did they explain that?
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Aging Special Effects and Uneven Script
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tabuno
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    At the time, this dazzling display of live action and animation must of been quite a treat for its audience, receiving an Oscar award for best special effects. Alas time has not been kind to this heavily special effects dependent movie which is also weighed down by an uneven script. The director was able to balance this movie's genre or tone - was this to be a musical or just family comedy or drama. This movie appears to have ignored the director's own magical success of Mary Poppins (1964) released seven years earlier. Like Sean Penn directing Into the Wild (2007), director Robert Stevenson perhaps let success go to his head, or maybe insecurity by focusing so much on special effects and musical numbers that the story itself sometimes became secondary to the showing off the supposed "brilliance" of the animations. For example, Emelius fades almost into insignificance during the soccer game, or the primary characters are lost in the overly crowded and extended dance routine in the town. Even the television episode of Buffy: The Vampire Slayer - Once More, With Feeling (2001) displays how to both enhance the storyline and the characters with music instead of hiding them and ignoring the story. Cool World (1992), Jim Carrey's The Mask (1994), Monkey Bones (2001) all built on the break out live animation film Who Framed Roger Rabbit (1988). But even back in 1964, Arthur Lubin known for televisions series Mr. Ed and The Addams Family directed a neat live animation mixture with Don Knott's in The Incredible Mr. Limpet. Overall, what once was a new and delightful children's film has aged and not well.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A failed attempt to recapture the magic of Mary Poppins, but with a good set-piece finale
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    David Conrad
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    All the elements from "Mary Poppins" are here: a stern, magical nanny who flies, a kooky male street performer with whom she has some history, and period-specific English kids who tag along with the unconventional adults through foggy London streets and animated fantasy lands. Even one of the actors, David Tomlinson, is borrowed from Poppins. Yet Disney's attempt to strike gold twice fails. The pacing is much slower, particularly on the restored DVD release in which 30 minutes of footage cut from the theatrical release are reinserted. The songs are bland affairs that Tomlinson and Angela Lansbury meander through without much energy. During the animation sequence, the live actors are sidelined for an interminable soccer match between lions, alligators, and bears. These animal drawings are templates lifted from Disney's "The Jungle Book" (1967), and they would be recycled again in the studio's "Robin Hood" (1973). The final act of "Bedknobs," though it comes too late and lasts too long, does partly redeem it: special effects steal the show as an army of English museum pieces, mainly empty suits of medieval armor, come to life and march against the most incompetent Nazi invasion force in screen history. It would be better to YouTube that sequence than to sit through the movie to get to it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Honestly runs better in the standard cut
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Foux_du_Fafa
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Though far from perfect, "Bedknobs and Broomsticks" has always been a favourite of mine since childhood. The plot may be a bit muddled in places, but the sheer joy and fun of the fantasy material makes up for it. The animated sequences in particular are a real joy, as is the comedy-action climax to the film. Some of the songs are underrated classics, in particular "The Age of Not Believing" and "The Beautiful Briny". Also, the elaborate opening credit sequence is gorgeous to look at. That said, you may want to be careful which version of the film you see. The film premiered at around 135 minutes, but was cut down for general release to 117 minutes. This 117 minute version was the one I first saw as a child. In 1996, Disney restored the film to a length comparable to the premiere version, and this is what was released onto DVD. Ironically, I think the film does run better at a shorter length. Much of what is added are new or extended musical numbers, as well as the extension of a rather superfluous subplot involving a somewhat saucy vicar. I don't particularly find the new musical numbers that engaging, and the numbers that are extended aren't that great. Though there are some interesting extra verses in the extended "Portobello Road" number, the several dance scenes added to it renders it seemingly unending. "Eglantine" also goes on a bit too much for my liking. In addition some re-dubbing was required for some of the new scenes as the original mastertracks were not found. Angela Lansbury was able to come back and sounds fine, but many of the other actors weren't and the results are mixed. It would be nice if an inevitable Blu-Ray showed the film in either two of its versions, or if at least the original dialogue tapes were found for the extended scenes. I do believe that there are still ways to get hold of the 117 minute version. I have the first UK DVD release from around 2002, but I have read on Amazon that a later UK release has the film run at 117 minutes in order to align itself with some old European dubs on the disc, and I've also read online that TCM in the US sometimes shows the shorter version. In any case, "Bedknobs and Broomsticks" is a fun, family classic and easily worthy of my recommendation.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Way Too Long, Way Too Dull
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Joshua Mitchell
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Bedknobs And Broomsticks is rather obscure when compared to Disney's other films. This isn't a bad thing, though, considering most of Disney's other films are far superior to this overlong production. Lacking any excitement, or even laugh-worthy humor, Bedknobs And Broomsticks has little appeal to those over the age of 10, and even the youngest will likely be bored by the constant chatter and uninventive musical numbers. Three children named Carrie, Charlie and Paul are temporarily adopted by Eglantine Price, whom they discover to be a witch. Ms. Prince gives the children a traveling spell, in exchange for keeping her secret, which allows their bed to teleport to any given location. The four also snag Emelius Browne- Ms. Price's witch teacher- into the adventure as well. As one would expect, there are countless plot holes and silly things that are overlooked by the characters, but this is the least of the film's problems. Bedknobs And Broomsticks runs for a taxing two and a half hours. Had Bedknobs And Broomsticks been truly entertaining, this would not be a problem. Another Disney musical, Mary Poppins has a run time around the same length, and is loved and adored by all ages. Needless to say, Bedknobs And Broomsticks is no Mary Poppins. The content of this dull musical, does not justify the relentlessly long length. The number of songs in the film are not nearly as high as that of Mary Poppins, but they are far less inventive. Despite being penned by the Sherman brothers, the same duo that wrote the songs in Mary Poppins, each and every number is dull to limit. Occasionally, dancing takes place during these numbers, though the choreography is poor and uninspired. What's strange is that the beat of the music, often does not meet the beat of the dancing, which seems truly lazy. The score, also by the Sherman brothers isn't too shabby, and the bed traveling theme is relatively strong, but the score often sounds too similar to the Mary Poppins score (especially in the earlier segments). Also, if you hate bagpipes, you will definitely want to avoid this, as the aforementioned instruments make more than one appearance. Bedknobs And Broomsticks is specifically known for the Land of Naboombu, which is completely animated. It's always a marvel to see live-acted characters interact with animated ones. Alas, despite being showcased as the main attraction in Bedknobs And Broomsticks, the Land of Naboombu occupies a measly 30 minutes of the extensive run time. Talk about misleading! Special effects often look dated, and the strings that are used to suspend objects in midair are clearly visible most of the time. There are some decent effects though, make no mistake about it. But not all of the effects are as polished as others. The children are poorly acted, and most other actors fall into the unspectacular area. Only Angela Lansbury and David Tomlinson stand out. Bedknobs And Broomsticks is wholly unspectacular. It lacks the humor and excitement it needed to translate into the fun adventure it fails to be. Add that with the overlong run time and the dull musical numbers, and you get a animated musical that is unlikely to leave anyone coming back for more.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The restored version is a Disney classic but certainly no "Mary Poppins"
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mike48128
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/7/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Mary Poppins is a 10, so what's wrong with "Bedknobs" besides it's too long? A lack of "whimsey and wonder". Like comparing "Sleeping Beauty" to Snow White". (Both classics) So let's begin: The opening credits are far too long, as Disney liked to front-load all the credits during this era. The storyboarded titles tell the entire plot line so nothing is left to the imagination. It's like an overlong movie "trailer" that does the same thing. At first the characters are dreadful, and only start to improve in "likeability" as the story progresses. (Angela Lansbury, especially) The Bookman" and his henchman (who reminds me of the "Creeper" from the Sherlock Holmes series) are woefully-miscast; as they are too weird and sinister. "Portobello Road", a botched attempt at recreating the "Consider Yourself" musical number from "Oliver", is far too long. It seems more like a parade at Walt Disney World than a part of the movie. The Germans are both bumbling and menacing. (How is that possible?) The U-boat captain is far too nice! Now here's what's good about the film: The special effects are outstanding. The "haunted armor" is wonderful, although the kids will enjoy the cartoon sequences better: 1. The soccer game animation is only fair by Disney standards and somewhat "mean spirited." 2. The reason that "Beautiful Briny Sea" is so wonderful is that both the story and song were ideas cut from "Mary Poppins" and used here. The restoration seems a bit odd: David Tomlinson's voice is noticeably re-dubbed and (according to English critics) a song is missing, but all the other songs and scenes are fully-restored. In spite of all my criticism, I really do like this film. After all, it did win two Academy Awards for Special Effects!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Slow to get going and feels a little padded but is good Disney fun overall
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bob the moo
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/5/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Three children evacuated from London end up being reluctantly taken in by an odd woman who lives on her own with a raggedy black cat. They don't even make it to the end of the first night before they observe that their new guardian Miss Price is not just odd, she is an actual witch, trying to perfect a spell to help with the war effort. While the children make this discovery, Miss Price makes her own  the mail-order college she has been training with is going out of business before she has everything she needs. With the help of Paul's knob (don't ask) they set off to London to find the Professor  the start of a much bigger adventure. For my girlfriend this film is a strong childhood memory but for me I don't think I had ever seen it. In an attempt to be nice I got it for her a few years ago to watch at Christmas time but it sat unwatched until a miserable Bank Holiday Monday produced the urge to nest and just watch a couple of easy movies. As far as first impressions go, the film doesn't seem to feel any pressure to make a good one and if I'm honest I wondered if the opening credit sequence would ever end (a sequence that only has context once you have watched the film till the end). The titles rolls for at least five minutes without much to recommend them for and the film opens in much the same vein. Although there are some amusing moments and a bit of fantasy in the opening 20 or so minutes, it is slow and takes a while to get going. It doesn't help that the plot is a little vague and messy so that at one point I was neither sure why they were doing what they were doing, nor sure I particularly cared why they were doing it. This is a bit harsh perhaps  but I was thinking what children (not the most patient demographic) would be doing during this  in particular I was trying to think of any child I know who would be entranced by the Portobello Road song and dance number! It is still OK at this stage though and the good news is that it gets better with plenty of action, fun, invention and wit moving forward. The plotting is still a little bit "hmm" but it gets to where it is going thanks to the timely mini-invasion. The soccer match, the underwater musical number and of course the battle at the end are all great fun and I imagine children will enjoy them as much as I did (well, moreso probably). The old-fashioned feel is nice and I did like the sense of good clean family fun which the whole film had  although I'm not sure why the script calls for Paul to expressly refer to his knob so often; it is too deliberate and scripted to be merely something cynical modern ears pick up on. The pacing of the film is generally good as well but it is a little slower than it needed to be and I think being honest they could have had 15 minutes out of this without too much bother and it would have been a better film for it; not to say it is bad for the length, just that it doesn't always seem to need it. The cast are quite fun and all buy into the family tone. Lansbury in particular sells the role and works very well with Tomlinson in the adult roles. The children are a little annoying until you get used to them having the cockney turned up to 11 throughout; odd that neither of the boys ever did acting after this considering I liked them better than O'Callaghan's Carrie, who has less to do. Regardless they all work well and even when the animated sections turn up, the humans don't get lost in the fantasy but remain solid characters. Bedknobs and Broomsticks isn't brilliant but it is a solidly fun Disney family film. The majority of the musical numbers could have been better, the plot could have been stronger and the pacing/length trimmed to be slicker but it does all work, albeit not as well as it could have done. Enjoyable nonetheless with good wit and imagination  off-target Disney is still good after all.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    a message of hope
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    donnapepper9
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/4/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Bedknobs and Broomsticks was a film of its time. Yes, war is a strong feature - but there are covert references to war and violence in a lot of children's films - Mulan? For me, this is an ideal children's film - there is such a sense of escapism involved, whilst at the same time there is no attempt made to conceal that bad things do happen in life. The moral of this story, in my opinion, is that in the face of adversity there is always hope, and in hope there is strength to face the enemy. Whatever form that enemy might take - kids have far superior imaginations than adults and I don't believe that they would take a negative message from a film like this.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "Any Sufficiently Advanced Technology Is Indistinguishable From Magic"-Clarkes Third Law
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    johnstonjames
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/7/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    do i believe in magic? well, no. i'm sorry to disappoint anyone, but no, there is no such thing as magic. everything can be explained. it's usually all smoke and mirrors. parents should be strongly cautioned about 'Bedknobs and Broomsticks'. not because i believe in witches or magic, that stuff is just a bunch of hocus pocus. there are no such thing as real witches and anyone over the age of six who believes that should have their noggin examined. if someone tries to tell you there is such a thing as real magic or witches, get away from them fast because they are obviously psychotic and probably very dangerous. as a Christian and a person who is concerned with the salvation of man's immortal soul, it's not the magic that bothers me, it's the movie's strong spirit of militarism that bothers me. this movie glorifies war. and what is war good for? absolutely nothing. this movie indoctrinates young children into the military industrial complex at an early age(i mean it's designed for young children). children should not learn to glorify war, they should be wary of it, if not afraid of it. World War II may or may not have been the right decision, but do we need to keep bringing up past wars? especially where children are concerned. nobody wants World War III here. that would be madness. do i like this movie? of course i do. i grew up with this film and it's always been a Disney favorite of mine. it's beautifully handled by director Robert Stevenson, it's very clever, and has a charming musical score by Disney song writers, the Sherman Brothers. the film has many smart insights into history and sometimes i think this film may be more about children than anything else. but every time i get too sentimental and cozy about this film i wake up and think, oh God! THIS IS ABOUT WAR! nobody in their right brain wants a frick'in WAR! as far as the witchcraft element? i said what i think of that. there ain't no such thing and if you believe it's real YOU ARE STUPID. as a Christian does it scare me? oh sometimes i get superstitious and then i wake up. i used to follow astrology in the newspaper and read my horoscope everyday to see if i could find out anything. do you know what happened? absolutely nothing. half the time the stupid horoscope seemed like it was speaking to someone else. hardly any of the advice changed or helped my life in anyway. it just made me believe in silly things. but there are evil, stupid people out there with very little education who actually believe in magic. and it doesn't help that the witchcraft in 'Bedknobs' is far more real than the silly 'Harry Potter' films. i mean 'Astoroth' was a famous occultist and some of the incantation words (though not many) are actual words. does that scare me? of course not dummies. but it does scare some really stupid people who are evil enough to believe it's real. those people's children probably won't mix well with children who come from a more enlightened, intelligent and practical family that won't believe in such idiocy. so be careful with this movie. it could cause you some trouble if you bring it up in the wrong place. as far as my own feelings go, i find this film cute and charming and terribly funny. others might not be as amused. be careful. you are crossing the line with this film. when you endorse or recommend this film you are advocating war. you are also stating that you prefer to take a practical, scientific approach to this world and debunk superstition. for those of you who might read this and still believe witchcraft is real, YOU ARE STUPID. bottom line. keep repeating to yourself "it's only a movie. it's only a movie. than seek therapy. for the families strong and smart enough to deal with this ticking time bomb of a film, take caution and enjoy. it's funny and fun.if you can handle it go for it. HELLBORNE HENBANE AQUINITE GLOW-WORM FIRE FIREFLY LIGHT!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    From Portabello Road to the Beautiful Briny Sea, Angela will take you past the age of Not Believing.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mark.waltz
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    There's more charm to this Disney musical than has been given credit for, even though a huge fan base obviously exists for it. The film was overshadowed by the memory of Disney's previous big movie musical where another British actress (Julie Andrews) shot to super-stardom playing a nanny with extraordinary powers. Here, Angela Lansbury is a wanna be witch who ends up in charge of three kids against her will and assists the British in fighting the Krauts of World War I with the help of her own magic powers. The same song-writing team of Robert and Richard Stevenson have created an equally engaging score, and I think it even tops the one for "Mary Poppins". Lansbury wins your heart immediately when she berates her cranky charges for being past that "Age of Not Believing" then takes them onto a magical journey into the depths of the Atlantic Ocean and into a magical island with its own Lion King and a horde of eccentric soccer playing animals, all with the assistance of her witch professor phony David Tomlinson. More eccentric than his disciplining father from "Mary Poppins", Tomlinson is more than welcomed back and a great co-star for Lansbury. He is hysterically funny in the partly animated soccer match where he is the referee and takes more than his share of abuse from this mythical animal kingdom. Fresh from her success as Broadway's "Mame" (with a few flops in between that have become cult classics thanks to her presence in them), Lansbury proves herself worthy of the movie musical, having been sadly dubbed most of the time when she was at MGM during their heyday. There's a bit of a Harry Potter and "Wicked" feeling to this story with quite the influence of the late 60's/early 70's Broadway feel in the live-action musical numbers. The lyrics are cleverly difficult to sing along with and may have you laughing as you try, especially the final number where Lansbury gets her witchcraft right in aiding a museum filled with ancient war artifacts to take on the German army. Another "Mary Poppins" veteran is back, Lansbury's old MGM co-star Reginald Owen, in one of his final appearances, and Roddy McDowall is amusingly effete as the British preacher who keeps popping in to check on the kiddies. Disney would obviously be influenced by this many years later when making their modern day musical classics such as "The Little Mermaid", "Beauty and the Beast" (by casting Lansbury in a key role) and "The Lion King".
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Dated Fantasy Flick's Finale Too Fast
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    William C. Uchtman (aesgaard41@hotmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    For myself as a boy, this movie's closing scenes with the ghostly army using nothing but Medieval weapons to battle and repulse an attempted Nazi landing in England during World War Two is one of the most lasting images in my mind. However, as an adult watching it today, it comes off as less magical with the horribly dated special effects. Overall, the movie has actually stood the test of time, still enchanting whole new generations of young children. Angela Lansbury as a young actress is charming and attractive, and David Tomlinson is a bit more animated and puckish that he was in "Mary Poppins," which this movie seems to be riding. The notable parallels between the two movies are obvious, but then it is quite clear that the two movies share much of the same production team members. Mostly for laughs, the film has very few scary scenes, and the aforementioned scene does not much more than walk and march except for a select few swinging swords and maces. There's a decent horror movie here once the Disney ingredients are removed. The songs, as effervescent as they are, are not nearly as infectious as the tunes from "Mary Poppins," and Roddy McDowell, who was quite a popular British actor for the time, sadly, gets very little to do in this movie. I don't get how destroying her research robs Lansbury's character of her mystical powers, but I just wish the movie had lasted just a bit longer to reveal the clean-up of the countryside to retrieve the museum artifacts and period costumes now mysteriously damaged and bullet-ridden and scattered through the woods. I mean, come on, how did they explain that?
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Aging Special Effects and Uneven Script
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tabuno
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    At the time, this dazzling display of live action and animation must of been quite a treat for its audience, receiving an Oscar award for best special effects. Alas time has not been kind to this heavily special effects dependent movie which is also weighed down by an uneven script. The director was able to balance this movie's genre or tone - was this to be a musical or just family comedy or drama. This movie appears to have ignored the director's own magical success of Mary Poppins (1964) released seven years earlier. Like Sean Penn directing Into the Wild (2007), director Robert Stevenson perhaps let success go to his head, or maybe insecurity by focusing so much on special effects and musical numbers that the story itself sometimes became secondary to the showing off the supposed "brilliance" of the animations. For example, Emelius fades almost into insignificance during the soccer game, or the primary characters are lost in the overly crowded and extended dance routine in the town. Even the television episode of Buffy: The Vampire Slayer - Once More, With Feeling (2001) displays how to both enhance the storyline and the characters with music instead of hiding them and ignoring the story. Cool World (1992), Jim Carrey's The Mask (1994), Monkey Bones (2001) all built on the break out live animation film Who Framed Roger Rabbit (1988). But even back in 1964, Arthur Lubin known for televisions series Mr. Ed and The Addams Family directed a neat live animation mixture with Don Knott's in The Incredible Mr. Limpet. Overall, what once was a new and delightful children's film has aged and not well.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A failed attempt to recapture the magic of Mary Poppins, but with a good set-piece finale
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    David Conrad
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    All the elements from "Mary Poppins" are here: a stern, magical nanny who flies, a kooky male street performer with whom she has some history, and period-specific English kids who tag along with the unconventional adults through foggy London streets and animated fantasy lands. Even one of the actors, David Tomlinson, is borrowed from Poppins. Yet Disney's attempt to strike gold twice fails. The pacing is much slower, particularly on the restored DVD release in which 30 minutes of footage cut from the theatrical release are reinserted. The songs are bland affairs that Tomlinson and Angela Lansbury meander through without much energy. During the animation sequence, the live actors are sidelined for an interminable soccer match between lions, alligators, and bears. These animal drawings are templates lifted from Disney's "The Jungle Book" (1967), and they would be recycled again in the studio's "Robin Hood" (1973). The final act of "Bedknobs," though it comes too late and lasts too long, does partly redeem it: special effects steal the show as an army of English museum pieces, mainly empty suits of medieval armor, come to life and march against the most incompetent Nazi invasion force in screen history. It would be better to YouTube that sequence than to sit through the movie to get to it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Honestly runs better in the standard cut
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Foux_du_Fafa
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Though far from perfect, "Bedknobs and Broomsticks" has always been a favourite of mine since childhood. The plot may be a bit muddled in places, but the sheer joy and fun of the fantasy material makes up for it. The animated sequences in particular are a real joy, as is the comedy-action climax to the film. Some of the songs are underrated classics, in particular "The Age of Not Believing" and "The Beautiful Briny". Also, the elaborate opening credit sequence is gorgeous to look at. That said, you may want to be careful which version of the film you see. The film premiered at around 135 minutes, but was cut down for general release to 117 minutes. This 117 minute version was the one I first saw as a child. In 1996, Disney restored the film to a length comparable to the premiere version, and this is what was released onto DVD. Ironically, I think the film does run better at a shorter length. Much of what is added are new or extended musical numbers, as well as the extension of a rather superfluous subplot involving a somewhat saucy vicar. I don't particularly find the new musical numbers that engaging, and the numbers that are extended aren't that great. Though there are some interesting extra verses in the extended "Portobello Road" number, the several dance scenes added to it renders it seemingly unending. "Eglantine" also goes on a bit too much for my liking. In addition some re-dubbing was required for some of the new scenes as the original mastertracks were not found. Angela Lansbury was able to come back and sounds fine, but many of the other actors weren't and the results are mixed. It would be nice if an inevitable Blu-Ray showed the film in either two of its versions, or if at least the original dialogue tapes were found for the extended scenes. I do believe that there are still ways to get hold of the 117 minute version. I have the first UK DVD release from around 2002, but I have read on Amazon that a later UK release has the film run at 117 minutes in order to align itself with some old European dubs on the disc, and I've also read online that TCM in the US sometimes shows the shorter version. In any case, "Bedknobs and Broomsticks" is a fun, family classic and easily worthy of my recommendation.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Way Too Long, Way Too Dull
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Joshua Mitchell
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Bedknobs And Broomsticks is rather obscure when compared to Disney's other films. This isn't a bad thing, though, considering most of Disney's other films are far superior to this overlong production. Lacking any excitement, or even laugh-worthy humor, Bedknobs And Broomsticks has little appeal to those over the age of 10, and even the youngest will likely be bored by the constant chatter and uninventive musical numbers. Three children named Carrie, Charlie and Paul are temporarily adopted by Eglantine Price, whom they discover to be a witch. Ms. Prince gives the children a traveling spell, in exchange for keeping her secret, which allows their bed to teleport to any given location. The four also snag Emelius Browne- Ms. Price's witch teacher- into the adventure as well. As one would expect, there are countless plot holes and silly things that are overlooked by the characters, but this is the least of the film's problems. Bedknobs And Broomsticks runs for a taxing two and a half hours. Had Bedknobs And Broomsticks been truly entertaining, this would not be a problem. Another Disney musical, Mary Poppins has a run time around the same length, and is loved and adored by all ages. Needless to say, Bedknobs And Broomsticks is no Mary Poppins. The content of this dull musical, does not justify the relentlessly long length. The number of songs in the film are not nearly as high as that of Mary Poppins, but they are far less inventive. Despite being penned by the Sherman brothers, the same duo that wrote the songs in Mary Poppins, each and every number is dull to limit. Occasionally, dancing takes place during these numbers, though the choreography is poor and uninspired. What's strange is that the beat of the music, often does not meet the beat of the dancing, which seems truly lazy. The score, also by the Sherman brothers isn't too shabby, and the bed traveling theme is relatively strong, but the score often sounds too similar to the Mary Poppins score (especially in the earlier segments). Also, if you hate bagpipes, you will definitely want to avoid this, as the aforementioned instruments make more than one appearance. Bedknobs And Broomsticks is specifically known for the Land of Naboombu, which is completely animated. It's always a marvel to see live-acted characters interact with animated ones. Alas, despite being showcased as the main attraction in Bedknobs And Broomsticks, the Land of Naboombu occupies a measly 30 minutes of the extensive run time. Talk about misleading! Special effects often look dated, and the strings that are used to suspend objects in midair are clearly visible most of the time. There are some decent effects though, make no mistake about it. But not all of the effects are as polished as others. The children are poorly acted, and most other actors fall into the unspectacular area. Only Angela Lansbury and David Tomlinson stand out. Bedknobs And Broomsticks is wholly unspectacular. It lacks the humor and excitement it needed to translate into the fun adventure it fails to be. Add that with the overlong run time and the dull musical numbers, and you get a animated musical that is unlikely to leave anyone coming back for more.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The restored version is a Disney classic but certainly no "Mary Poppins"
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mike48128
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/7/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Mary Poppins is a 10, so what's wrong with "Bedknobs" besides it's too long? A lack of "whimsey and wonder". Like comparing "Sleeping Beauty" to Snow White". (Both classics) So let's begin: The opening credits are far too long, as Disney liked to front-load all the credits during this era. The storyboarded titles tell the entire plot line so nothing is left to the imagination. It's like an overlong movie "trailer" that does the same thing. At first the characters are dreadful, and only start to improve in "likeability" as the story progresses. (Angela Lansbury, especially) The Bookman" and his henchman (who reminds me of the "Creeper" from the Sherlock Holmes series) are woefully-miscast; as they are too weird and sinister. "Portobello Road", a botched attempt at recreating the "Consider Yourself" musical number from "Oliver", is far too long. It seems more like a parade at Walt Disney World than a part of the movie. The Germans are both bumbling and menacing. (How is that possible?) The U-boat captain is far too nice! Now here's what's good about the film: The special effects are outstanding. The "haunted armor" is wonderful, although the kids will enjoy the cartoon sequences better: 1. The soccer game animation is only fair by Disney standards and somewhat "mean spirited." 2. The reason that "Beautiful Briny Sea" is so wonderful is that both the story and song were ideas cut from "Mary Poppins" and used here. The restoration seems a bit odd: David Tomlinson's voice is noticeably re-dubbed and (according to English critics) a song is missing, but all the other songs and scenes are fully-restored. In spite of all my criticism, I really do like this film. After all, it did win two Academy Awards for Special Effects!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Slow to get going and feels a little padded but is good Disney fun overall
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bob the moo
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/5/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Three children evacuated from London end up being reluctantly taken in by an odd woman who lives on her own with a raggedy black cat. They don't even make it to the end of the first night before they observe that their new guardian Miss Price is not just odd, she is an actual witch, trying to perfect a spell to help with the war effort. While the children make this discovery, Miss Price makes her own  the mail-order college she has been training with is going out of business before she has everything she needs. With the help of Paul's knob (don't ask) they set off to London to find the Professor  the start of a much bigger adventure. For my girlfriend this film is a strong childhood memory but for me I don't think I had ever seen it. In an attempt to be nice I got it for her a few years ago to watch at Christmas time but it sat unwatched until a miserable Bank Holiday Monday produced the urge to nest and just watch a couple of easy movies. As far as first impressions go, the film doesn't seem to feel any pressure to make a good one and if I'm honest I wondered if the opening credit sequence would ever end (a sequence that only has context once you have watched the film till the end). The titles rolls for at least five minutes without much to recommend them for and the film opens in much the same vein. Although there are some amusing moments and a bit of fantasy in the opening 20 or so minutes, it is slow and takes a while to get going. It doesn't help that the plot is a little vague and messy so that at one point I was neither sure why they were doing what they were doing, nor sure I particularly cared why they were doing it. This is a bit harsh perhaps  but I was thinking what children (not the most patient demographic) would be doing during this  in particular I was trying to think of any child I know who would be entranced by the Portobello Road song and dance number! It is still OK at this stage though and the good news is that it gets better with plenty of action, fun, invention and wit moving forward. The plotting is still a little bit "hmm" but it gets to where it is going thanks to the timely mini-invasion. The soccer match, the underwater musical number and of course the battle at the end are all great fun and I imagine children will enjoy them as much as I did (well, moreso probably). The old-fashioned feel is nice and I did like the sense of good clean family fun which the whole film had  although I'm not sure why the script calls for Paul to expressly refer to his knob so often; it is too deliberate and scripted to be merely something cynical modern ears pick up on. The pacing of the film is generally good as well but it is a little slower than it needed to be and I think being honest they could have had 15 minutes out of this without too much bother and it would have been a better film for it; not to say it is bad for the length, just that it doesn't always seem to need it. The cast are quite fun and all buy into the family tone. Lansbury in particular sells the role and works very well with Tomlinson in the adult roles. The children are a little annoying until you get used to them having the cockney turned up to 11 throughout; odd that neither of the boys ever did acting after this considering I liked them better than O'Callaghan's Carrie, who has less to do. Regardless they all work well and even when the animated sections turn up, the humans don't get lost in the fantasy but remain solid characters. Bedknobs and Broomsticks isn't brilliant but it is a solidly fun Disney family film. The majority of the musical numbers could have been better, the plot could have been stronger and the pacing/length trimmed to be slicker but it does all work, albeit not as well as it could have done. Enjoyable nonetheless with good wit and imagination  off-target Disney is still good after all.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    a message of hope
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    donnapepper9
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/4/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Bedknobs and Broomsticks was a film of its time. Yes, war is a strong feature - but there are covert references to war and violence in a lot of children's films - Mulan? For me, this is an ideal children's film - there is such a sense of escapism involved, whilst at the same time there is no attempt made to conceal that bad things do happen in life. The moral of this story, in my opinion, is that in the face of adversity there is always hope, and in hope there is strength to face the enemy. Whatever form that enemy might take - kids have far superior imaginations than adults and I don't believe that they would take a negative message from a film like this.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "Any Sufficiently Advanced Technology Is Indistinguishable From Magic"-Clarkes Third Law
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    johnstonjames
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/7/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    do i believe in magic? well, no. i'm sorry to disappoint anyone, but no, there is no such thing as magic. everything can be explained. it's usually all smoke and mirrors. parents should be strongly cautioned about 'Bedknobs and Broomsticks'. not because i believe in witches or magic, that stuff is just a bunch of hocus pocus. there are no such thing as real witches and anyone over the age of six who believes that should have their noggin examined. if someone tries to tell you there is such a thing as real magic or witches, get away from them fast because they are obviously psychotic and probably very dangerous. as a Christian and a person who is concerned with the salvation of man's immortal soul, it's not the magic that bothers me, it's the movie's strong spirit of militarism that bothers me. this movie glorifies war. and what is war good for? absolutely nothing. this movie indoctrinates young children into the military industrial complex at an early age(i mean it's designed for young children). children should not learn to glorify war, they should be wary of it, if not afraid of it. World War II may or may not have been the right decision, but do we need to keep bringing up past wars? especially where children are concerned. nobody wants World War III here. that would be madness. do i like this movie? of course i do. i grew up with this film and it's always been a Disney favorite of mine. it's beautifully handled by director Robert Stevenson, it's very clever, and has a charming musical score by Disney song writers, the Sherman Brothers. the film has many smart insights into history and sometimes i think this film may be more about children than anything else. but every time i get too sentimental and cozy about this film i wake up and think, oh God! THIS IS ABOUT WAR! nobody in their right brain wants a frick'in WAR! as far as the witchcraft element? i said what i think of that. there ain't no such thing and if you believe it's real YOU ARE STUPID. as a Christian does it scare me? oh sometimes i get superstitious and then i wake up. i used to follow astrology in the newspaper and read my horoscope everyday to see if i could find out anything. do you know what happened? absolutely nothing. half the time the stupid horoscope seemed like it was speaking to someone else. hardly any of the advice changed or helped my life in anyway. it just made me believe in silly things. but there are evil, stupid people out there with very little education who actually believe in magic. and it doesn't help that the witchcraft in 'Bedknobs' is far more real than the silly 'Harry Potter' films. i mean 'Astoroth' was a famous occultist and some of the incantation words (though not many) are actual words. does that scare me? of course not dummies. but it does scare some really stupid people who are evil enough to believe it's real. those people's children probably won't mix well with children who come from a more enlightened, intelligent and practical family that won't believe in such idiocy. so be careful with this movie. it could cause you some trouble if you bring it up in the wrong place. as far as my own feelings go, i find this film cute and charming and terribly funny. others might not be as amused. be careful. you are crossing the line with this film. when you endorse or recommend this film you are advocating war. you are also stating that you prefer to take a practical, scientific approach to this world and debunk superstition. for those of you who might read this and still believe witchcraft is real, YOU ARE STUPID. bottom line. keep repeating to yourself "it's only a movie. it's only a movie. than seek therapy. for the families strong and smart enough to deal with this ticking time bomb of a film, take caution and enjoy. it's funny and fun.if you can handle it go for it. HELLBORNE HENBANE AQUINITE GLOW-WORM FIRE FIREFLY LIGHT!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    From Portabello Road to the Beautiful Briny Sea, Angela will take you past the age of Not Believing.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mark.waltz
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    There's more charm to this Disney musical than has been given credit for, even though a huge fan base obviously exists for it. The film was overshadowed by the memory of Disney's previous big movie musical where another British actress (Julie Andrews) shot to super-stardom playing a nanny with extraordinary powers. Here, Angela Lansbury is a wanna be witch who ends up in charge of three kids against her will and assists the British in fighting the Krauts of World War I with the help of her own magic powers. The same song-writing team of Robert and Richard Stevenson have created an equally engaging score, and I think it even tops the one for "Mary Poppins". Lansbury wins your heart immediately when she berates her cranky charges for being past that "Age of Not Believing" then takes them onto a magical journey into the depths of the Atlantic Ocean and into a magical island with its own Lion King and a horde of eccentric soccer playing animals, all with the assistance of her witch professor phony David Tomlinson. More eccentric than his disciplining father from "Mary Poppins", Tomlinson is more than welcomed back and a great co-star for Lansbury. He is hysterically funny in the partly animated soccer match where he is the referee and takes more than his share of abuse from this mythical animal kingdom. Fresh from her success as Broadway's "Mame" (with a few flops in between that have become cult classics thanks to her presence in them), Lansbury proves herself worthy of the movie musical, having been sadly dubbed most of the time when she was at MGM during their heyday. There's a bit of a Harry Potter and "Wicked" feeling to this story with quite the influence of the late 60's/early 70's Broadway feel in the live-action musical numbers. The lyrics are cleverly difficult to sing along with and may have you laughing as you try, especially the final number where Lansbury gets her witchcraft right in aiding a museum filled with ancient war artifacts to take on the German army. Another "Mary Poppins" veteran is back, Lansbury's old MGM co-star Reginald Owen, in one of his final appearances, and Roddy McDowall is amusingly effete as the British preacher who keeps popping in to check on the kiddies. Disney would obviously be influenced by this many years later when making their modern day musical classics such as "The Little Mermaid", "Beauty and the Beast" (by casting Lansbury in a key role) and "The Lion King".
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Dated Fantasy Flick's Finale Too Fast
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    William C. Uchtman (aesgaard41@hotmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    For myself as a boy, this movie's closing scenes with the ghostly army using nothing but Medieval weapons to battle and repulse an attempted Nazi landing in England during World War Two is one of the most lasting images in my mind. However, as an adult watching it today, it comes off as less magical with the horribly dated special effects. Overall, the movie has actually stood the test of time, still enchanting whole new generations of young children. Angela Lansbury as a young actress is charming and attractive, and David Tomlinson is a bit more animated and puckish that he was in "Mary Poppins," which this movie seems to be riding. The notable parallels between the two movies are obvious, but then it is quite clear that the two movies share much of the same production team members. Mostly for laughs, the film has very few scary scenes, and the aforementioned scene does not much more than walk and march except for a select few swinging swords and maces. There's a decent horror movie here once the Disney ingredients are removed. The songs, as effervescent as they are, are not nearly as infectious as the tunes from "Mary Poppins," and Roddy McDowell, who was quite a popular British actor for the time, sadly, gets very little to do in this movie. I don't get how destroying her research robs Lansbury's character of her mystical powers, but I just wish the movie had lasted just a bit longer to reveal the clean-up of the countryside to retrieve the museum artifacts and period costumes now mysteriously damaged and bullet-ridden and scattered through the woods. I mean, come on, how did they explain that?
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Aging Special Effects and Uneven Script
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tabuno
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    At the time, this dazzling display of live action and animation must of been quite a treat for its audience, receiving an Oscar award for best special effects. Alas time has not been kind to this heavily special effects dependent movie which is also weighed down by an uneven script. The director was able to balance this movie's genre or tone - was this to be a musical or just family comedy or drama. This movie appears to have ignored the director's own magical success of Mary Poppins (1964) released seven years earlier. Like Sean Penn directing Into the Wild (2007), director Robert Stevenson perhaps let success go to his head, or maybe insecurity by focusing so much on special effects and musical numbers that the story itself sometimes became secondary to the showing off the supposed "brilliance" of the animations. For example, Emelius fades almost into insignificance during the soccer game, or the primary characters are lost in the overly crowded and extended dance routine in the town. Even the television episode of Buffy: The Vampire Slayer - Once More, With Feeling (2001) displays how to both enhance the storyline and the characters with music instead of hiding them and ignoring the story. Cool World (1992), Jim Carrey's The Mask (1994), Monkey Bones (2001) all built on the break out live animation film Who Framed Roger Rabbit (1988). But even back in 1964, Arthur Lubin known for televisions series Mr. Ed and The Addams Family directed a neat live animation mixture with Don Knott's in The Incredible Mr. Limpet. Overall, what once was a new and delightful children's film has aged and not well.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A failed attempt to recapture the magic of Mary Poppins, but with a good set-piece finale
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    David Conrad
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    All the elements from "Mary Poppins" are here: a stern, magical nanny who flies, a kooky male street performer with whom she has some history, and period-specific English kids who tag along with the unconventional adults through foggy London streets and animated fantasy lands. Even one of the actors, David Tomlinson, is borrowed from Poppins. Yet Disney's attempt to strike gold twice fails. The pacing is much slower, particularly on the restored DVD release in which 30 minutes of footage cut from the theatrical release are reinserted. The songs are bland affairs that Tomlinson and Angela Lansbury meander through without much energy. During the animation sequence, the live actors are sidelined for an interminable soccer match between lions, alligators, and bears. These animal drawings are templates lifted from Disney's "The Jungle Book" (1967), and they would be recycled again in the studio's "Robin Hood" (1973). The final act of "Bedknobs," though it comes too late and lasts too long, does partly redeem it: special effects steal the show as an army of English museum pieces, mainly empty suits of medieval armor, come to life and march against the most incompetent Nazi invasion force in screen history. It would be better to YouTube that sequence than to sit through the movie to get to it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Honestly runs better in the standard cut
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Foux_du_Fafa
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Though far from perfect, "Bedknobs and Broomsticks" has always been a favourite of mine since childhood. The plot may be a bit muddled in places, but the sheer joy and fun of the fantasy material makes up for it. The animated sequences in particular are a real joy, as is the comedy-action climax to the film. Some of the songs are underrated classics, in particular "The Age of Not Believing" and "The Beautiful Briny". Also, the elaborate opening credit sequence is gorgeous to look at. That said, you may want to be careful which version of the film you see. The film premiered at around 135 minutes, but was cut down for general release to 117 minutes. This 117 minute version was the one I first saw as a child. In 1996, Disney restored the film to a length comparable to the premiere version, and this is what was released onto DVD. Ironically, I think the film does run better at a shorter length. Much of what is added are new or extended musical numbers, as well as the extension of a rather superfluous subplot involving a somewhat saucy vicar. I don't particularly find the new musical numbers that engaging, and the numbers that are extended aren't that great. Though there are some interesting extra verses in the extended "Portobello Road" number, the several dance scenes added to it renders it seemingly unending. "Eglantine" also goes on a bit too much for my liking. In addition some re-dubbing was required for some of the new scenes as the original mastertracks were not found. Angela Lansbury was able to come back and sounds fine, but many of the other actors weren't and the results are mixed. It would be nice if an inevitable Blu-Ray showed the film in either two of its versions, or if at least the original dialogue tapes were found for the extended scenes. I do believe that there are still ways to get hold of the 117 minute version. I have the first UK DVD release from around 2002, but I have read on Amazon that a later UK release has the film run at 117 minutes in order to align itself with some old European dubs on the disc, and I've also read online that TCM in the US sometimes shows the shorter version. In any case, "Bedknobs and Broomsticks" is a fun, family classic and easily worthy of my recommendation.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Way Too Long, Way Too Dull
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Joshua Mitchell
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Bedknobs And Broomsticks is rather obscure when compared to Disney's other films. This isn't a bad thing, though, considering most of Disney's other films are far superior to this overlong production. Lacking any excitement, or even laugh-worthy humor, Bedknobs And Broomsticks has little appeal to those over the age of 10, and even the youngest will likely be bored by the constant chatter and uninventive musical numbers. Three children named Carrie, Charlie and Paul are temporarily adopted by Eglantine Price, whom they discover to be a witch. Ms. Prince gives the children a traveling spell, in exchange for keeping her secret, which allows their bed to teleport to any given location. The four also snag Emelius Browne- Ms. Price's witch teacher- into the adventure as well. As one would expect, there are countless plot holes and silly things that are overlooked by the characters, but this is the least of the film's problems. Bedknobs And Broomsticks runs for a taxing two and a half hours. Had Bedknobs And Broomsticks been truly entertaining, this would not be a problem. Another Disney musical, Mary Poppins has a run time around the same length, and is loved and adored by all ages. Needless to say, Bedknobs And Broomsticks is no Mary Poppins. The content of this dull musical, does not justify the relentlessly long length. The number of songs in the film are not nearly as high as that of Mary Poppins, but they are far less inventive. Despite being penned by the Sherman brothers, the same duo that wrote the songs in Mary Poppins, each and every number is dull to limit. Occasionally, dancing takes place during these numbers, though the choreography is poor and uninspired. What's strange is that the beat of the music, often does not meet the beat of the dancing, which seems truly lazy. The score, also by the Sherman brothers isn't too shabby, and the bed traveling theme is relatively strong, but the score often sounds too similar to the Mary Poppins score (especially in the earlier segments). Also, if you hate bagpipes, you will definitely want to avoid this, as the aforementioned instruments make more than one appearance. Bedknobs And Broomsticks is specifically known for the Land of Naboombu, which is completely animated. It's always a marvel to see live-acted characters interact with animated ones. Alas, despite being showcased as the main attraction in Bedknobs And Broomsticks, the Land of Naboombu occupies a measly 30 minutes of the extensive run time. Talk about misleading! Special effects often look dated, and the strings that are used to suspend objects in midair are clearly visible most of the time. There are some decent effects though, make no mistake about it. But not all of the effects are as polished as others. The children are poorly acted, and most other actors fall into the unspectacular area. Only Angela Lansbury and David Tomlinson stand out. Bedknobs And Broomsticks is wholly unspectacular. It lacks the humor and excitement it needed to translate into the fun adventure it fails to be. Add that with the overlong run time and the dull musical numbers, and you get a animated musical that is unlikely to leave anyone coming back for more.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The restored version is a Disney classic but certainly no "Mary Poppins"
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mike48128
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/7/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Mary Poppins is a 10, so what's wrong with "Bedknobs" besides it's too long? A lack of "whimsey and wonder". Like comparing "Sleeping Beauty" to Snow White". (Both classics) So let's begin: The opening credits are far too long, as Disney liked to front-load all the credits during this era. The storyboarded titles tell the entire plot line so nothing is left to the imagination. It's like an overlong movie "trailer" that does the same thing. At first the characters are dreadful, and only start to improve in "likeability" as the story progresses. (Angela Lansbury, especially) The Bookman" and his henchman (who reminds me of the "Creeper" from the Sherlock Holmes series) are woefully-miscast; as they are too weird and sinister. "Portobello Road", a botched attempt at recreating the "Consider Yourself" musical number from "Oliver", is far too long. It seems more like a parade at Walt Disney World than a part of the movie. The Germans are both bumbling and menacing. (How is that possible?) The U-boat captain is far too nice! Now here's what's good about the film: The special effects are outstanding. The "haunted armor" is wonderful, although the kids will enjoy the cartoon sequences better: 1. The soccer game animation is only fair by Disney standards and somewhat "mean spirited." 2. The reason that "Beautiful Briny Sea" is so wonderful is that both the story and song were ideas cut from "Mary Poppins" and used here. The restoration seems a bit odd: David Tomlinson's voice is noticeably re-dubbed and (according to English critics) a song is missing, but all the other songs and scenes are fully-restored. In spite of all my criticism, I really do like this film. After all, it did win two Academy Awards for Special Effects!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Slow to get going and feels a little padded but is good Disney fun overall
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bob the moo
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/5/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Three children evacuated from London end up being reluctantly taken in by an odd woman who lives on her own with a raggedy black cat. They don't even make it to the end of the first night before they observe that their new guardian Miss Price is not just odd, she is an actual witch, trying to perfect a spell to help with the war effort. While the children make this discovery, Miss Price makes her own  the mail-order college she has been training with is going out of business before she has everything she needs. With the help of Paul's knob (don't ask) they set off to London to find the Professor  the start of a much bigger adventure. For my girlfriend this film is a strong childhood memory but for me I don't think I had ever seen it. In an attempt to be nice I got it for her a few years ago to watch at Christmas time but it sat unwatched until a miserable Bank Holiday Monday produced the urge to nest and just watch a couple of easy movies. As far as first impressions go, the film doesn't seem to feel any pressure to make a good one and if I'm honest I wondered if the opening credit sequence would ever end (a sequence that only has context once you have watched the film till the end). The titles rolls for at least five minutes without much to recommend them for and the film opens in much the same vein. Although there are some amusing moments and a bit of fantasy in the opening 20 or so minutes, it is slow and takes a while to get going. It doesn't help that the plot is a little vague and messy so that at one point I was neither sure why they were doing what they were doing, nor sure I particularly cared why they were doing it. This is a bit harsh perhaps  but I was thinking what children (not the most patient demographic) would be doing during this  in particular I was trying to think of any child I know who would be entranced by the Portobello Road song and dance number! It is still OK at this stage though and the good news is that it gets better with plenty of action, fun, invention and wit moving forward. The plotting is still a little bit "hmm" but it gets to where it is going thanks to the timely mini-invasion. The soccer match, the underwater musical number and of course the battle at the end are all great fun and I imagine children will enjoy them as much as I did (well, moreso probably). The old-fashioned feel is nice and I did like the sense of good clean family fun which the whole film had  although I'm not sure why the script calls for Paul to expressly refer to his knob so often; it is too deliberate and scripted to be merely something cynical modern ears pick up on. The pacing of the film is generally good as well but it is a little slower than it needed to be and I think being honest they could have had 15 minutes out of this without too much bother and it would have been a better film for it; not to say it is bad for the length, just that it doesn't always seem to need it. The cast are quite fun and all buy into the family tone. Lansbury in particular sells the role and works very well with Tomlinson in the adult roles. The children are a little annoying until you get used to them having the cockney turned up to 11 throughout; odd that neither of the boys ever did acting after this considering I liked them better than O'Callaghan's Carrie, who has less to do. Regardless they all work well and even when the animated sections turn up, the humans don't get lost in the fantasy but remain solid characters. Bedknobs and Broomsticks isn't brilliant but it is a solidly fun Disney family film. The majority of the musical numbers could have been better, the plot could have been stronger and the pacing/length trimmed to be slicker but it does all work, albeit not as well as it could have done. Enjoyable nonetheless with good wit and imagination  off-target Disney is still good after all.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    a message of hope
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    donnapepper9
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/4/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Bedknobs and Broomsticks was a film of its time. Yes, war is a strong feature - but there are covert references to war and violence in a lot of children's films - Mulan? For me, this is an ideal children's film - there is such a sense of escapism involved, whilst at the same time there is no attempt made to conceal that bad things do happen in life. The moral of this story, in my opinion, is that in the face of adversity there is always hope, and in hope there is strength to face the enemy. Whatever form that enemy might take - kids have far superior imaginations than adults and I don't believe that they would take a negative message from a film like this.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "Any Sufficiently Advanced Technology Is Indistinguishable From Magic"-Clarkes Third Law
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    johnstonjames
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/7/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    do i believe in magic? well, no. i'm sorry to disappoint anyone, but no, there is no such thing as magic. everything can be explained. it's usually all smoke and mirrors. parents should be strongly cautioned about 'Bedknobs and Broomsticks'. not because i believe in witches or magic, that stuff is just a bunch of hocus pocus. there are no such thing as real witches and anyone over the age of six who believes that should have their noggin examined. if someone tries to tell you there is such a thing as real magic or witches, get away from them fast because they are obviously psychotic and probably very dangerous. as a Christian and a person who is concerned with the salvation of man's immortal soul, it's not the magic that bothers me, it's the movie's strong spirit of militarism that bothers me. this movie glorifies war. and what is war good for? absolutely nothing. this movie indoctrinates young children into the military industrial complex at an early age(i mean it's designed for young children). children should not learn to glorify war, they should be wary of it, if not afraid of it. World War II may or may not have been the right decision, but do we need to keep bringing up past wars? especially where children are concerned. nobody wants World War III here. that would be madness. do i like this movie? of course i do. i grew up with this film and it's always been a Disney favorite of mine. it's beautifully handled by director Robert Stevenson, it's very clever, and has a charming musical score by Disney song writers, the Sherman Brothers. the film has many smart insights into history and sometimes i think this film may be more about children than anything else. but every time i get too sentimental and cozy about this film i wake up and think, oh God! THIS IS ABOUT WAR! nobody in their right brain wants a frick'in WAR! as far as the witchcraft element? i said what i think of that. there ain't no such thing and if you believe it's real YOU ARE STUPID. as a Christian does it scare me? oh sometimes i get superstitious and then i wake up. i used to follow astrology in the newspaper and read my horoscope everyday to see if i could find out anything. do you know what happened? absolutely nothing. half the time the stupid horoscope seemed like it was speaking to someone else. hardly any of the advice changed or helped my life in anyway. it just made me believe in silly things. but there are evil, stupid people out there with very little education who actually believe in magic. and it doesn't help that the witchcraft in 'Bedknobs' is far more real than the silly 'Harry Potter' films. i mean 'Astoroth' was a famous occultist and some of the incantation words (though not many) are actual words. does that scare me? of course not dummies. but it does scare some really stupid people who are evil enough to believe it's real. those people's children probably won't mix well with children who come from a more enlightened, intelligent and practical family that won't believe in such idiocy. so be careful with this movie. it could cause you some trouble if you bring it up in the wrong place. as far as my own feelings go, i find this film cute and charming and terribly funny. others might not be as amused. be careful. you are crossing the line with this film. when you endorse or recommend this film you are advocating war. you are also stating that you prefer to take a practical, scientific approach to this world and debunk superstition. for those of you who might read this and still believe witchcraft is real, YOU ARE STUPID. bottom line. keep repeating to yourself "it's only a movie. it's only a movie. than seek therapy. for the families strong and smart enough to deal with this ticking time bomb of a film, take caution and enjoy. it's funny and fun.if you can handle it go for it. HELLBORNE HENBANE AQUINITE GLOW-WORM FIRE FIREFLY LIGHT!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    From Portabello Road to the Beautiful Briny Sea, Angela will take you past the age of Not Believing.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mark.waltz
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    There's more charm to this Disney musical than has been given credit for, even though a huge fan base obviously exists for it. The film was overshadowed by the memory of Disney's previous big movie musical where another British actress (Julie Andrews) shot to super-stardom playing a nanny with extraordinary powers. Here, Angela Lansbury is a wanna be witch who ends up in charge of three kids against her will and assists the British in fighting the Krauts of World War I with the help of her own magic powers. The same song-writing team of Robert and Richard Stevenson have created an equally engaging score, and I think it even tops the one for "Mary Poppins". Lansbury wins your heart immediately when she berates her cranky charges for being past that "Age of Not Believing" then takes them onto a magical journey into the depths of the Atlantic Ocean and into a magical island with its own Lion King and a horde of eccentric soccer playing animals, all with the assistance of her witch professor phony David Tomlinson. More eccentric than his disciplining father from "Mary Poppins", Tomlinson is more than welcomed back and a great co-star for Lansbury. He is hysterically funny in the partly animated soccer match where he is the referee and takes more than his share of abuse from this mythical animal kingdom. Fresh from her success as Broadway's "Mame" (with a few flops in between that have become cult classics thanks to her presence in them), Lansbury proves herself worthy of the movie musical, having been sadly dubbed most of the time when she was at MGM during their heyday. There's a bit of a Harry Potter and "Wicked" feeling to this story with quite the influence of the late 60's/early 70's Broadway feel in the live-action musical numbers. The lyrics are cleverly difficult to sing along with and may have you laughing as you try, especially the final number where Lansbury gets her witchcraft right in aiding a museum filled with ancient war artifacts to take on the German army. Another "Mary Poppins" veteran is back, Lansbury's old MGM co-star Reginald Owen, in one of his final appearances, and Roddy McDowall is amusingly effete as the British preacher who keeps popping in to check on the kiddies. Disney would obviously be influenced by this many years later when making their modern day musical classics such as "The Little Mermaid", "Beauty and the Beast" (by casting Lansbury in a key role) and "The Lion King".
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Dated Fantasy Flick's Finale Too Fast
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    William C. Uchtman (aesgaard41@hotmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    For myself as a boy, this movie's closing scenes with the ghostly army using nothing but Medieval weapons to battle and repulse an attempted Nazi landing in England during World War Two is one of the most lasting images in my mind. However, as an adult watching it today, it comes off as less magical with the horribly dated special effects. Overall, the movie has actually stood the test of time, still enchanting whole new generations of young children. Angela Lansbury as a young actress is charming and attractive, and David Tomlinson is a bit more animated and puckish that he was in "Mary Poppins," which this movie seems to be riding. The notable parallels between the two movies are obvious, but then it is quite clear that the two movies share much of the same production team members. Mostly for laughs, the film has very few scary scenes, and the aforementioned scene does not much more than walk and march except for a select few swinging swords and maces. There's a decent horror movie here once the Disney ingredients are removed. The songs, as effervescent as they are, are not nearly as infectious as the tunes from "Mary Poppins," and Roddy McDowell, who was quite a popular British actor for the time, sadly, gets very little to do in this movie. I don't get how destroying her research robs Lansbury's character of her mystical powers, but I just wish the movie had lasted just a bit longer to reveal the clean-up of the countryside to retrieve the museum artifacts and period costumes now mysteriously damaged and bullet-ridden and scattered through the woods. I mean, come on, how did they explain that?
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Aging Special Effects and Uneven Script
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tabuno
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    At the time, this dazzling display of live action and animation must of been quite a treat for its audience, receiving an Oscar award for best special effects. Alas time has not been kind to this heavily special effects dependent movie which is also weighed down by an uneven script. The director was able to balance this movie's genre or tone - was this to be a musical or just family comedy or drama. This movie appears to have ignored the director's own magical success of Mary Poppins (1964) released seven years earlier. Like Sean Penn directing Into the Wild (2007), director Robert Stevenson perhaps let success go to his head, or maybe insecurity by focusing so much on special effects and musical numbers that the story itself sometimes became secondary to the showing off the supposed "brilliance" of the animations. For example, Emelius fades almost into insignificance during the soccer game, or the primary characters are lost in the overly crowded and extended dance routine in the town. Even the television episode of Buffy: The Vampire Slayer - Once More, With Feeling (2001) displays how to both enhance the storyline and the characters with music instead of hiding them and ignoring the story. Cool World (1992), Jim Carrey's The Mask (1994), Monkey Bones (2001) all built on the break out live animation film Who Framed Roger Rabbit (1988). But even back in 1964, Arthur Lubin known for televisions series Mr. Ed and The Addams Family directed a neat live animation mixture with Don Knott's in The Incredible Mr. Limpet. Overall, what once was a new and delightful children's film has aged and not well.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A failed attempt to recapture the magic of Mary Poppins, but with a good set-piece finale
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    David Conrad
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    All the elements from "Mary Poppins" are here: a stern, magical nanny who flies, a kooky male street performer with whom she has some history, and period-specific English kids who tag along with the unconventional adults through foggy London streets and animated fantasy lands. Even one of the actors, David Tomlinson, is borrowed from Poppins. Yet Disney's attempt to strike gold twice fails. The pacing is much slower, particularly on the restored DVD release in which 30 minutes of footage cut from the theatrical release are reinserted. The songs are bland affairs that Tomlinson and Angela Lansbury meander through without much energy. During the animation sequence, the live actors are sidelined for an interminable soccer match between lions, alligators, and bears. These animal drawings are templates lifted from Disney's "The Jungle Book" (1967), and they would be recycled again in the studio's "Robin Hood" (1973). The final act of "Bedknobs," though it comes too late and lasts too long, does partly redeem it: special effects steal the show as an army of English museum pieces, mainly empty suits of medieval armor, come to life and march against the most incompetent Nazi invasion force in screen history. It would be better to YouTube that sequence than to sit through the movie to get to it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Honestly runs better in the standard cut
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Foux_du_Fafa
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Though far from perfect, "Bedknobs and Broomsticks" has always been a favourite of mine since childhood. The plot may be a bit muddled in places, but the sheer joy and fun of the fantasy material makes up for it. The animated sequences in particular are a real joy, as is the comedy-action climax to the film. Some of the songs are underrated classics, in particular "The Age of Not Believing" and "The Beautiful Briny". Also, the elaborate opening credit sequence is gorgeous to look at. That said, you may want to be careful which version of the film you see. The film premiered at around 135 minutes, but was cut down for general release to 117 minutes. This 117 minute version was the one I first saw as a child. In 1996, Disney restored the film to a length comparable to the premiere version, and this is what was released onto DVD. Ironically, I think the film does run better at a shorter length. Much of what is added are new or extended musical numbers, as well as the extension of a rather superfluous subplot involving a somewhat saucy vicar. I don't particularly find the new musical numbers that engaging, and the numbers that are extended aren't that great. Though there are some interesting extra verses in the extended "Portobello Road" number, the several dance scenes added to it renders it seemingly unending. "Eglantine" also goes on a bit too much for my liking. In addition some re-dubbing was required for some of the new scenes as the original mastertracks were not found. Angela Lansbury was able to come back and sounds fine, but many of the other actors weren't and the results are mixed. It would be nice if an inevitable Blu-Ray showed the film in either two of its versions, or if at least the original dialogue tapes were found for the extended scenes. I do believe that there are still ways to get hold of the 117 minute version. I have the first UK DVD release from around 2002, but I have read on Amazon that a later UK release has the film run at 117 minutes in order to align itself with some old European dubs on the disc, and I've also read online that TCM in the US sometimes shows the shorter version. In any case, "Bedknobs and Broomsticks" is a fun, family classic and easily worthy of my recommendation.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Way Too Long, Way Too Dull
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Joshua Mitchell
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Bedknobs And Broomsticks is rather obscure when compared to Disney's other films. This isn't a bad thing, though, considering most of Disney's other films are far superior to this overlong production. Lacking any excitement, or even laugh-worthy humor, Bedknobs And Broomsticks has little appeal to those over the age of 10, and even the youngest will likely be bored by the constant chatter and uninventive musical numbers. Three children named Carrie, Charlie and Paul are temporarily adopted by Eglantine Price, whom they discover to be a witch. Ms. Prince gives the children a traveling spell, in exchange for keeping her secret, which allows their bed to teleport to any given location. The four also snag Emelius Browne- Ms. Price's witch teacher- into the adventure as well. As one would expect, there are countless plot holes and silly things that are overlooked by the characters, but this is the least of the film's problems. Bedknobs And Broomsticks runs for a taxing two and a half hours. Had Bedknobs And Broomsticks been truly entertaining, this would not be a problem. Another Disney musical, Mary Poppins has a run time around the same length, and is loved and adored by all ages. Needless to say, Bedknobs And Broomsticks is no Mary Poppins. The content of this dull musical, does not justify the relentlessly long length. The number of songs in the film are not nearly as high as that of Mary Poppins, but they are far less inventive. Despite being penned by the Sherman brothers, the same duo that wrote the songs in Mary Poppins, each and every number is dull to limit. Occasionally, dancing takes place during these numbers, though the choreography is poor and uninspired. What's strange is that the beat of the music, often does not meet the beat of the dancing, which seems truly lazy. The score, also by the Sherman brothers isn't too shabby, and the bed traveling theme is relatively strong, but the score often sounds too similar to the Mary Poppins score (especially in the earlier segments). Also, if you hate bagpipes, you will definitely want to avoid this, as the aforementioned instruments make more than one appearance. Bedknobs And Broomsticks is specifically known for the Land of Naboombu, which is completely animated. It's always a marvel to see live-acted characters interact with animated ones. Alas, despite being showcased as the main attraction in Bedknobs And Broomsticks, the Land of Naboombu occupies a measly 30 minutes of the extensive run time. Talk about misleading! Special effects often look dated, and the strings that are used to suspend objects in midair are clearly visible most of the time. There are some decent effects though, make no mistake about it. But not all of the effects are as polished as others. The children are poorly acted, and most other actors fall into the unspectacular area. Only Angela Lansbury and David Tomlinson stand out. Bedknobs And Broomsticks is wholly unspectacular. It lacks the humor and excitement it needed to translate into the fun adventure it fails to be. Add that with the overlong run time and the dull musical numbers, and you get a animated musical that is unlikely to leave anyone coming back for more.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The restored version is a Disney classic but certainly no "Mary Poppins"
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mike48128
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/7/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Mary Poppins is a 10, so what's wrong with "Bedknobs" besides it's too long? A lack of "whimsey and wonder". Like comparing "Sleeping Beauty" to Snow White". (Both classics) So let's begin: The opening credits are far too long, as Disney liked to front-load all the credits during this era. The storyboarded titles tell the entire plot line so nothing is left to the imagination. It's like an overlong movie "trailer" that does the same thing. At first the characters are dreadful, and only start to improve in "likeability" as the story progresses. (Angela Lansbury, especially) The Bookman" and his henchman (who reminds me of the "Creeper" from the Sherlock Holmes series) are woefully-miscast; as they are too weird and sinister. "Portobello Road", a botched attempt at recreating the "Consider Yourself" musical number from "Oliver", is far too long. It seems more like a parade at Walt Disney World than a part of the movie. The Germans are both bumbling and menacing. (How is that possible?) The U-boat captain is far too nice! Now here's what's good about the film: The special effects are outstanding. The "haunted armor" is wonderful, although the kids will enjoy the cartoon sequences better: 1. The soccer game animation is only fair by Disney standards and somewhat "mean spirited." 2. The reason that "Beautiful Briny Sea" is so wonderful is that both the story and song were ideas cut from "Mary Poppins" and used here. The restoration seems a bit odd: David Tomlinson's voice is noticeably re-dubbed and (according to English critics) a song is missing, but all the other songs and scenes are fully-restored. In spite of all my criticism, I really do like this film. After all, it did win two Academy Awards for Special Effects!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Slow to get going and feels a little padded but is good Disney fun overall
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bob the moo
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/5/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Three children evacuated from London end up being reluctantly taken in by an odd woman who lives on her own with a raggedy black cat. They don't even make it to the end of the first night before they observe that their new guardian Miss Price is not just odd, she is an actual witch, trying to perfect a spell to help with the war effort. While the children make this discovery, Miss Price makes her own  the mail-order college she has been training with is going out of business before she has everything she needs. With the help of Paul's knob (don't ask) they set off to London to find the Professor  the start of a much bigger adventure. For my girlfriend this film is a strong childhood memory but for me I don't think I had ever seen it. In an attempt to be nice I got it for her a few years ago to watch at Christmas time but it sat unwatched until a miserable Bank Holiday Monday produced the urge to nest and just watch a couple of easy movies. As far as first impressions go, the film doesn't seem to feel any pressure to make a good one and if I'm honest I wondered if the opening credit sequence would ever end (a sequence that only has context once you have watched the film till the end). The titles rolls for at least five minutes without much to recommend them for and the film opens in much the same vein. Although there are some amusing moments and a bit of fantasy in the opening 20 or so minutes, it is slow and takes a while to get going. It doesn't help that the plot is a little vague and messy so that at one point I was neither sure why they were doing what they were doing, nor sure I particularly cared why they were doing it. This is a bit harsh perhaps  but I was thinking what children (not the most patient demographic) would be doing during this  in particular I was trying to think of any child I know who would be entranced by the Portobello Road song and dance number! It is still OK at this stage though and the good news is that it gets better with plenty of action, fun, invention and wit moving forward. The plotting is still a little bit "hmm" but it gets to where it is going thanks to the timely mini-invasion. The soccer match, the underwater musical number and of course the battle at the end are all great fun and I imagine children will enjoy them as much as I did (well, moreso probably). The old-fashioned feel is nice and I did like the sense of good clean family fun which the whole film had  although I'm not sure why the script calls for Paul to expressly refer to his knob so often; it is too deliberate and scripted to be merely something cynical modern ears pick up on. The pacing of the film is generally good as well but it is a little slower than it needed to be and I think being honest they could have had 15 minutes out of this without too much bother and it would have been a better film for it; not to say it is bad for the length, just that it doesn't always seem to need it. The cast are quite fun and all buy into the family tone. Lansbury in particular sells the role and works very well with Tomlinson in the adult roles. The children are a little annoying until you get used to them having the cockney turned up to 11 throughout; odd that neither of the boys ever did acting after this considering I liked them better than O'Callaghan's Carrie, who has less to do. Regardless they all work well and even when the animated sections turn up, the humans don't get lost in the fantasy but remain solid characters. Bedknobs and Broomsticks isn't brilliant but it is a solidly fun Disney family film. The majority of the musical numbers could have been better, the plot could have been stronger and the pacing/length trimmed to be slicker but it does all work, albeit not as well as it could have done. Enjoyable nonetheless with good wit and imagination  off-target Disney is still good after all.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    a message of hope
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    donnapepper9
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/4/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Bedknobs and Broomsticks was a film of its time. Yes, war is a strong feature - but there are covert references to war and violence in a lot of children's films - Mulan? For me, this is an ideal children's film - there is such a sense of escapism involved, whilst at the same time there is no attempt made to conceal that bad things do happen in life. The moral of this story, in my opinion, is that in the face of adversity there is always hope, and in hope there is strength to face the enemy. Whatever form that enemy might take - kids have far superior imaginations than adults and I don't believe that they would take a negative message from a film like this.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "Any Sufficiently Advanced Technology Is Indistinguishable From Magic"-Clarkes Third Law
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    johnstonjames
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/7/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    do i believe in magic? well, no. i'm sorry to disappoint anyone, but no, there is no such thing as magic. everything can be explained. it's usually all smoke and mirrors. parents should be strongly cautioned about 'Bedknobs and Broomsticks'. not because i believe in witches or magic, that stuff is just a bunch of hocus pocus. there are no such thing as real witches and anyone over the age of six who believes that should have their noggin examined. if someone tries to tell you there is such a thing as real magic or witches, get away from them fast because they are obviously psychotic and probably very dangerous. as a Christian and a person who is concerned with the salvation of man's immortal soul, it's not the magic that bothers me, it's the movie's strong spirit of militarism that bothers me. this movie glorifies war. and what is war good for? absolutely nothing. this movie indoctrinates young children into the military industrial complex at an early age(i mean it's designed for young children). children should not learn to glorify war, they should be wary of it, if not afraid of it. World War II may or may not have been the right decision, but do we need to keep bringing up past wars? especially where children are concerned. nobody wants World War III here. that would be madness. do i like this movie? of course i do. i grew up with this film and it's always been a Disney favorite of mine. it's beautifully handled by director Robert Stevenson, it's very clever, and has a charming musical score by Disney song writers, the Sherman Brothers. the film has many smart insights into history and sometimes i think this film may be more about children than anything else. but every time i get too sentimental and cozy about this film i wake up and think, oh God! THIS IS ABOUT WAR! nobody in their right brain wants a frick'in WAR! as far as the witchcraft element? i said what i think of that. there ain't no such thing and if you believe it's real YOU ARE STUPID. as a Christian does it scare me? oh sometimes i get superstitious and then i wake up. i used to follow astrology in the newspaper and read my horoscope everyday to see if i could find out anything. do you know what happened? absolutely nothing. half the time the stupid horoscope seemed like it was speaking to someone else. hardly any of the advice changed or helped my life in anyway. it just made me believe in silly things. but there are evil, stupid people out there with very little education who actually believe in magic. and it doesn't help that the witchcraft in 'Bedknobs' is far more real than the silly 'Harry Potter' films. i mean 'Astoroth' was a famous occultist and some of the incantation words (though not many) are actual words. does that scare me? of course not dummies. but it does scare some really stupid people who are evil enough to believe it's real. those people's children probably won't mix well with children who come from a more enlightened, intelligent and practical family that won't believe in such idiocy. so be careful with this movie. it could cause you some trouble if you bring it up in the wrong place. as far as my own feelings go, i find this film cute and charming and terribly funny. others might not be as amused. be careful. you are crossing the line with this film. when you endorse or recommend this film you are advocating war. you are also stating that you prefer to take a practical, scientific approach to this world and debunk superstition. for those of you who might read this and still believe witchcraft is real, YOU ARE STUPID. bottom line. keep repeating to yourself "it's only a movie. it's only a movie. than seek therapy. for the families strong and smart enough to deal with this ticking time bomb of a film, take caution and enjoy. it's funny and fun.if you can handle it go for it. HELLBORNE HENBANE AQUINITE GLOW-WORM FIRE FIREFLY LIGHT!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    From Portabello Road to the Beautiful Briny Sea, Angela will take you past the age of Not Believing.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mark.waltz
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    There's more charm to this Disney musical than has been given credit for, even though a huge fan base obviously exists for it. The film was overshadowed by the memory of Disney's previous big movie musical where another British actress (Julie Andrews) shot to super-stardom playing a nanny with extraordinary powers. Here, Angela Lansbury is a wanna be witch who ends up in charge of three kids against her will and assists the British in fighting the Krauts of World War I with the help of her own magic powers. The same song-writing team of Robert and Richard Stevenson have created an equally engaging score, and I think it even tops the one for "Mary Poppins". Lansbury wins your heart immediately when she berates her cranky charges for being past that "Age of Not Believing" then takes them onto a magical journey into the depths of the Atlantic Ocean and into a magical island with its own Lion King and a horde of eccentric soccer playing animals, all with the assistance of her witch professor phony David Tomlinson. More eccentric than his disciplining father from "Mary Poppins", Tomlinson is more than welcomed back and a great co-star for Lansbury. He is hysterically funny in the partly animated soccer match where he is the referee and takes more than his share of abuse from this mythical animal kingdom. Fresh from her success as Broadway's "Mame" (with a few flops in between that have become cult classics thanks to her presence in them), Lansbury proves herself worthy of the movie musical, having been sadly dubbed most of the time when she was at MGM during their heyday. There's a bit of a Harry Potter and "Wicked" feeling to this story with quite the influence of the late 60's/early 70's Broadway feel in the live-action musical numbers. The lyrics are cleverly difficult to sing along with and may have you laughing as you try, especially the final number where Lansbury gets her witchcraft right in aiding a museum filled with ancient war artifacts to take on the German army. Another "Mary Poppins" veteran is back, Lansbury's old MGM co-star Reginald Owen, in one of his final appearances, and Roddy McDowall is amusingly effete as the British preacher who keeps popping in to check on the kiddies. Disney would obviously be influenced by this many years later when making their modern day musical classics such as "The Little Mermaid", "Beauty and the Beast" (by casting Lansbury in a key role) and "The Lion King".
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Dated Fantasy Flick's Finale Too Fast
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    William C. Uchtman (aesgaard41@hotmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    For myself as a boy, this movie's closing scenes with the ghostly army using nothing but Medieval weapons to battle and repulse an attempted Nazi landing in England during World War Two is one of the most lasting images in my mind. However, as an adult watching it today, it comes off as less magical with the horribly dated special effects. Overall, the movie has actually stood the test of time, still enchanting whole new generations of young children. Angela Lansbury as a young actress is charming and attractive, and David Tomlinson is a bit more animated and puckish that he was in "Mary Poppins," which this movie seems to be riding. The notable parallels between the two movies are obvious, but then it is quite clear that the two movies share much of the same production team members. Mostly for laughs, the film has very few scary scenes, and the aforementioned scene does not much more than walk and march except for a select few swinging swords and maces. There's a decent horror movie here once the Disney ingredients are removed. The songs, as effervescent as they are, are not nearly as infectious as the tunes from "Mary Poppins," and Roddy McDowell, who was quite a popular British actor for the time, sadly, gets very little to do in this movie. I don't get how destroying her research robs Lansbury's character of her mystical powers, but I just wish the movie had lasted just a bit longer to reveal the clean-up of the countryside to retrieve the museum artifacts and period costumes now mysteriously damaged and bullet-ridden and scattered through the woods. I mean, come on, how did they explain that?
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Aging Special Effects and Uneven Script
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tabuno
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    At the time, this dazzling display of live action and animation must of been quite a treat for its audience, receiving an Oscar award for best special effects. Alas time has not been kind to this heavily special effects dependent movie which is also weighed down by an uneven script. The director was able to balance this movie's genre or tone - was this to be a musical or just family comedy or drama. This movie appears to have ignored the director's own magical success of Mary Poppins (1964) released seven years earlier. Like Sean Penn directing Into the Wild (2007), director Robert Stevenson perhaps let success go to his head, or maybe insecurity by focusing so much on special effects and musical numbers that the story itself sometimes became secondary to the showing off the supposed "brilliance" of the animations. For example, Emelius fades almost into insignificance during the soccer game, or the primary characters are lost in the overly crowded and extended dance routine in the town. Even the television episode of Buffy: The Vampire Slayer - Once More, With Feeling (2001) displays how to both enhance the storyline and the characters with music instead of hiding them and ignoring the story. Cool World (1992), Jim Carrey's The Mask (1994), Monkey Bones (2001) all built on the break out live animation film Who Framed Roger Rabbit (1988). But even back in 1964, Arthur Lubin known for televisions series Mr. Ed and The Addams Family directed a neat live animation mixture with Don Knott's in The Incredible Mr. Limpet. Overall, what once was a new and delightful children's film has aged and not well.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A failed attempt to recapture the magic of Mary Poppins, but with a good set-piece finale
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    David Conrad
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    All the elements from "Mary Poppins" are here: a stern, magical nanny who flies, a kooky male street performer with whom she has some history, and period-specific English kids who tag along with the unconventional adults through foggy London streets and animated fantasy lands. Even one of the actors, David Tomlinson, is borrowed from Poppins. Yet Disney's attempt to strike gold twice fails. The pacing is much slower, particularly on the restored DVD release in which 30 minutes of footage cut from the theatrical release are reinserted. The songs are bland affairs that Tomlinson and Angela Lansbury meander through without much energy. During the animation sequence, the live actors are sidelined for an interminable soccer match between lions, alligators, and bears. These animal drawings are templates lifted from Disney's "The Jungle Book" (1967), and they would be recycled again in the studio's "Robin Hood" (1973). The final act of "Bedknobs," though it comes too late and lasts too long, does partly redeem it: special effects steal the show as an army of English museum pieces, mainly empty suits of medieval armor, come to life and march against the most incompetent Nazi invasion force in screen history. It would be better to YouTube that sequence than to sit through the movie to get to it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Honestly runs better in the standard cut
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Foux_du_Fafa
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Though far from perfect, "Bedknobs and Broomsticks" has always been a favourite of mine since childhood. The plot may be a bit muddled in places, but the sheer joy and fun of the fantasy material makes up for it. The animated sequences in particular are a real joy, as is the comedy-action climax to the film. Some of the songs are underrated classics, in particular "The Age of Not Believing" and "The Beautiful Briny". Also, the elaborate opening credit sequence is gorgeous to look at. That said, you may want to be careful which version of the film you see. The film premiered at around 135 minutes, but was cut down for general release to 117 minutes. This 117 minute version was the one I first saw as a child. In 1996, Disney restored the film to a length comparable to the premiere version, and this is what was released onto DVD. Ironically, I think the film does run better at a shorter length. Much of what is added are new or extended musical numbers, as well as the extension of a rather superfluous subplot involving a somewhat saucy vicar. I don't particularly find the new musical numbers that engaging, and the numbers that are extended aren't that great. Though there are some interesting extra verses in the extended "Portobello Road" number, the several dance scenes added to it renders it seemingly unending. "Eglantine" also goes on a bit too much for my liking. In addition some re-dubbing was required for some of the new scenes as the original mastertracks were not found. Angela Lansbury was able to come back and sounds fine, but many of the other actors weren't and the results are mixed. It would be nice if an inevitable Blu-Ray showed the film in either two of its versions, or if at least the original dialogue tapes were found for the extended scenes. I do believe that there are still ways to get hold of the 117 minute version. I have the first UK DVD release from around 2002, but I have read on Amazon that a later UK release has the film run at 117 minutes in order to align itself with some old European dubs on the disc, and I've also read online that TCM in the US sometimes shows the shorter version. In any case, "Bedknobs and Broomsticks" is a fun, family classic and easily worthy of my recommendation.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Way Too Long, Way Too Dull
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Joshua Mitchell
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Bedknobs And Broomsticks is rather obscure when compared to Disney's other films. This isn't a bad thing, though, considering most of Disney's other films are far superior to this overlong production. Lacking any excitement, or even laugh-worthy humor, Bedknobs And Broomsticks has little appeal to those over the age of 10, and even the youngest will likely be bored by the constant chatter and uninventive musical numbers. Three children named Carrie, Charlie and Paul are temporarily adopted by Eglantine Price, whom they discover to be a witch. Ms. Prince gives the children a traveling spell, in exchange for keeping her secret, which allows their bed to teleport to any given location. The four also snag Emelius Browne- Ms. Price's witch teacher- into the adventure as well. As one would expect, there are countless plot holes and silly things that are overlooked by the characters, but this is the least of the film's problems. Bedknobs And Broomsticks runs for a taxing two and a half hours. Had Bedknobs And Broomsticks been truly entertaining, this would not be a problem. Another Disney musical, Mary Poppins has a run time around the same length, and is loved and adored by all ages. Needless to say, Bedknobs And Broomsticks is no Mary Poppins. The content of this dull musical, does not justify the relentlessly long length. The number of songs in the film are not nearly as high as that of Mary Poppins, but they are far less inventive. Despite being penned by the Sherman brothers, the same duo that wrote the songs in Mary Poppins, each and every number is dull to limit. Occasionally, dancing takes place during these numbers, though the choreography is poor and uninspired. What's strange is that the beat of the music, often does not meet the beat of the dancing, which seems truly lazy. The score, also by the Sherman brothers isn't too shabby, and the bed traveling theme is relatively strong, but the score often sounds too similar to the Mary Poppins score (especially in the earlier segments). Also, if you hate bagpipes, you will definitely want to avoid this, as the aforementioned instruments make more than one appearance. Bedknobs And Broomsticks is specifically known for the Land of Naboombu, which is completely animated. It's always a marvel to see live-acted characters interact with animated ones. Alas, despite being showcased as the main attraction in Bedknobs And Broomsticks, the Land of Naboombu occupies a measly 30 minutes of the extensive run time. Talk about misleading! Special effects often look dated, and the strings that are used to suspend objects in midair are clearly visible most of the time. There are some decent effects though, make no mistake about it. But not all of the effects are as polished as others. The children are poorly acted, and most other actors fall into the unspectacular area. Only Angela Lansbury and David Tomlinson stand out. Bedknobs And Broomsticks is wholly unspectacular. It lacks the humor and excitement it needed to translate into the fun adventure it fails to be. Add that with the overlong run time and the dull musical numbers, and you get a animated musical that is unlikely to leave anyone coming back for more.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The restored version is a Disney classic but certainly no "Mary Poppins"
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mike48128
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/7/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Mary Poppins is a 10, so what's wrong with "Bedknobs" besides it's too long? A lack of "whimsey and wonder". Like comparing "Sleeping Beauty" to Snow White". (Both classics) So let's begin: The opening credits are far too long, as Disney liked to front-load all the credits during this era. The storyboarded titles tell the entire plot line so nothing is left to the imagination. It's like an overlong movie "trailer" that does the same thing. At first the characters are dreadful, and only start to improve in "likeability" as the story progresses. (Angela Lansbury, especially) The Bookman" and his henchman (who reminds me of the "Creeper" from the Sherlock Holmes series) are woefully-miscast; as they are too weird and sinister. "Portobello Road", a botched attempt at recreating the "Consider Yourself" musical number from "Oliver", is far too long. It seems more like a parade at Walt Disney World than a part of the movie. The Germans are both bumbling and menacing. (How is that possible?) The U-boat captain is far too nice! Now here's what's good about the film: The special effects are outstanding. The "haunted armor" is wonderful, although the kids will enjoy the cartoon sequences better: 1. The soccer game animation is only fair by Disney standards and somewhat "mean spirited." 2. The reason that "Beautiful Briny Sea" is so wonderful is that both the story and song were ideas cut from "Mary Poppins" and used here. The restoration seems a bit odd: David Tomlinson's voice is noticeably re-dubbed and (according to English critics) a song is missing, but all the other songs and scenes are fully-restored. In spite of all my criticism, I really do like this film. After all, it did win two Academy Awards for Special Effects!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Slow to get going and feels a little padded but is good Disney fun overall
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bob the moo
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/5/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Three children evacuated from London end up being reluctantly taken in by an odd woman who lives on her own with a raggedy black cat. They don't even make it to the end of the first night before they observe that their new guardian Miss Price is not just odd, she is an actual witch, trying to perfect a spell to help with the war effort. While the children make this discovery, Miss Price makes her own  the mail-order college she has been training with is going out of business before she has everything she needs. With the help of Paul's knob (don't ask) they set off to London to find the Professor  the start of a much bigger adventure. For my girlfriend this film is a strong childhood memory but for me I don't think I had ever seen it. In an attempt to be nice I got it for her a few years ago to watch at Christmas time but it sat unwatched until a miserable Bank Holiday Monday produced the urge to nest and just watch a couple of easy movies. As far as first impressions go, the film doesn't seem to feel any pressure to make a good one and if I'm honest I wondered if the opening credit sequence would ever end (a sequence that only has context once you have watched the film till the end). The titles rolls for at least five minutes without much to recommend them for and the film opens in much the same vein. Although there are some amusing moments and a bit of fantasy in the opening 20 or so minutes, it is slow and takes a while to get going. It doesn't help that the plot is a little vague and messy so that at one point I was neither sure why they were doing what they were doing, nor sure I particularly cared why they were doing it. This is a bit harsh perhaps  but I was thinking what children (not the most patient demographic) would be doing during this  in particular I was trying to think of any child I know who would be entranced by the Portobello Road song and dance number! It is still OK at this stage though and the good news is that it gets better with plenty of action, fun, invention and wit moving forward. The plotting is still a little bit "hmm" but it gets to where it is going thanks to the timely mini-invasion. The soccer match, the underwater musical number and of course the battle at the end are all great fun and I imagine children will enjoy them as much as I did (well, moreso probably). The old-fashioned feel is nice and I did like the sense of good clean family fun which the whole film had  although I'm not sure why the script calls for Paul to expressly refer to his knob so often; it is too deliberate and scripted to be merely something cynical modern ears pick up on. The pacing of the film is generally good as well but it is a little slower than it needed to be and I think being honest they could have had 15 minutes out of this without too much bother and it would have been a better film for it; not to say it is bad for the length, just that it doesn't always seem to need it. The cast are quite fun and all buy into the family tone. Lansbury in particular sells the role and works very well with Tomlinson in the adult roles. The children are a little annoying until you get used to them having the cockney turned up to 11 throughout; odd that neither of the boys ever did acting after this considering I liked them better than O'Callaghan's Carrie, who has less to do. Regardless they all work well and even when the animated sections turn up, the humans don't get lost in the fantasy but remain solid characters. Bedknobs and Broomsticks isn't brilliant but it is a solidly fun Disney family film. The majority of the musical numbers could have been better, the plot could have been stronger and the pacing/length trimmed to be slicker but it does all work, albeit not as well as it could have done. Enjoyable nonetheless with good wit and imagination  off-target Disney is still good after all.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    a message of hope
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    donnapepper9
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/4/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Bedknobs and Broomsticks was a film of its time. Yes, war is a strong feature - but there are covert references to war and violence in a lot of children's films - Mulan? For me, this is an ideal children's film - there is such a sense of escapism involved, whilst at the same time there is no attempt made to conceal that bad things do happen in life. The moral of this story, in my opinion, is that in the face of adversity there is always hope, and in hope there is strength to face the enemy. Whatever form that enemy might take - kids have far superior imaginations than adults and I don't believe that they would take a negative message from a film like this.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "Any Sufficiently Advanced Technology Is Indistinguishable From Magic"-Clarkes Third Law
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    johnstonjames
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/7/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    do i believe in magic? well, no. i'm sorry to disappoint anyone, but no, there is no such thing as magic. everything can be explained. it's usually all smoke and mirrors. parents should be strongly cautioned about 'Bedknobs and Broomsticks'. not because i believe in witches or magic, that stuff is just a bunch of hocus pocus. there are no such thing as real witches and anyone over the age of six who believes that should have their noggin examined. if someone tries to tell you there is such a thing as real magic or witches, get away from them fast because they are obviously psychotic and probably very dangerous. as a Christian and a person who is concerned with the salvation of man's immortal soul, it's not the magic that bothers me, it's the movie's strong spirit of militarism that bothers me. this movie glorifies war. and what is war good for? absolutely nothing. this movie indoctrinates young children into the military industrial complex at an early age(i mean it's designed for young children). children should not learn to glorify war, they should be wary of it, if not afraid of it. World War II may or may not have been the right decision, but do we need to keep bringing up past wars? especially where children are concerned. nobody wants World War III here. that would be madness. do i like this movie? of course i do. i grew up with this film and it's always been a Disney favorite of mine. it's beautifully handled by director Robert Stevenson, it's very clever, and has a charming musical score by Disney song writers, the Sherman Brothers. the film has many smart insights into history and sometimes i think this film may be more about children than anything else. but every time i get too sentimental and cozy about this film i wake up and think, oh God! THIS IS ABOUT WAR! nobody in their right brain wants a frick'in WAR! as far as the witchcraft element? i said what i think of that. there ain't no such thing and if you believe it's real YOU ARE STUPID. as a Christian does it scare me? oh sometimes i get superstitious and then i wake up. i used to follow astrology in the newspaper and read my horoscope everyday to see if i could find out anything. do you know what happened? absolutely nothing. half the time the stupid horoscope seemed like it was speaking to someone else. hardly any of the advice changed or helped my life in anyway. it just made me believe in silly things. but there are evil, stupid people out there with very little education who actually believe in magic. and it doesn't help that the witchcraft in 'Bedknobs' is far more real than the silly 'Harry Potter' films. i mean 'Astoroth' was a famous occultist and some of the incantation words (though not many) are actual words. does that scare me? of course not dummies. but it does scare some really stupid people who are evil enough to believe it's real. those people's children probably won't mix well with children who come from a more enlightened, intelligent and practical family that won't believe in such idiocy. so be careful with this movie. it could cause you some trouble if you bring it up in the wrong place. as far as my own feelings go, i find this film cute and charming and terribly funny. others might not be as amused. be careful. you are crossing the line with this film. when you endorse or recommend this film you are advocating war. you are also stating that you prefer to take a practical, scientific approach to this world and debunk superstition. for those of you who might read this and still believe witchcraft is real, YOU ARE STUPID. bottom line. keep repeating to yourself "it's only a movie. it's only a movie. than seek therapy. for the families strong and smart enough to deal with this ticking time bomb of a film, take caution and enjoy. it's funny and fun.if you can handle it go for it. HELLBORNE HENBANE AQUINITE GLOW-WORM FIRE FIREFLY LIGHT!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    From Portabello Road to the Beautiful Briny Sea, Angela will take you past the age of Not Believing.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mark.waltz
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    There's more charm to this Disney musical than has been given credit for, even though a huge fan base obviously exists for it. The film was overshadowed by the memory of Disney's previous big movie musical where another British actress (Julie Andrews) shot to super-stardom playing a nanny with extraordinary powers. Here, Angela Lansbury is a wanna be witch who ends up in charge of three kids against her will and assists the British in fighting the Krauts of World War I with the help of her own magic powers. The same song-writing team of Robert and Richard Stevenson have created an equally engaging score, and I think it even tops the one for "Mary Poppins". Lansbury wins your heart immediately when she berates her cranky charges for being past that "Age of Not Believing" then takes them onto a magical journey into the depths of the Atlantic Ocean and into a magical island with its own Lion King and a horde of eccentric soccer playing animals, all with the assistance of her witch professor phony David Tomlinson. More eccentric than his disciplining father from "Mary Poppins", Tomlinson is more than welcomed back and a great co-star for Lansbury. He is hysterically funny in the partly animated soccer match where he is the referee and takes more than his share of abuse from this mythical animal kingdom. Fresh from her success as Broadway's "Mame" (with a few flops in between that have become cult classics thanks to her presence in them), Lansbury proves herself worthy of the movie musical, having been sadly dubbed most of the time when she was at MGM during their heyday. There's a bit of a Harry Potter and "Wicked" feeling to this story with quite the influence of the late 60's/early 70's Broadway feel in the live-action musical numbers. The lyrics are cleverly difficult to sing along with and may have you laughing as you try, especially the final number where Lansbury gets her witchcraft right in aiding a museum filled with ancient war artifacts to take on the German army. Another "Mary Poppins" veteran is back, Lansbury's old MGM co-star Reginald Owen, in one of his final appearances, and Roddy McDowall is amusingly effete as the British preacher who keeps popping in to check on the kiddies. Disney would obviously be influenced by this many years later when making their modern day musical classics such as "The Little Mermaid", "Beauty and the Beast" (by casting Lansbury in a key role) and "The Lion King".
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Dated Fantasy Flick's Finale Too Fast
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    William C. Uchtman (aesgaard41@hotmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    For myself as a boy, this movie's closing scenes with the ghostly army using nothing but Medieval weapons to battle and repulse an attempted Nazi landing in England during World War Two is one of the most lasting images in my mind. However, as an adult watching it today, it comes off as less magical with the horribly dated special effects. Overall, the movie has actually stood the test of time, still enchanting whole new generations of young children. Angela Lansbury as a young actress is charming and attractive, and David Tomlinson is a bit more animated and puckish that he was in "Mary Poppins," which this movie seems to be riding. The notable parallels between the two movies are obvious, but then it is quite clear that the two movies share much of the same production team members. Mostly for laughs, the film has very few scary scenes, and the aforementioned scene does not much more than walk and march except for a select few swinging swords and maces. There's a decent horror movie here once the Disney ingredients are removed. The songs, as effervescent as they are, are not nearly as infectious as the tunes from "Mary Poppins," and Roddy McDowell, who was quite a popular British actor for the time, sadly, gets very little to do in this movie. I don't get how destroying her research robs Lansbury's character of her mystical powers, but I just wish the movie had lasted just a bit longer to reveal the clean-up of the countryside to retrieve the museum artifacts and period costumes now mysteriously damaged and bullet-ridden and scattered through the woods. I mean, come on, how did they explain that?
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Aging Special Effects and Uneven Script
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tabuno
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    At the time, this dazzling display of live action and animation must of been quite a treat for its audience, receiving an Oscar award for best special effects. Alas time has not been kind to this heavily special effects dependent movie which is also weighed down by an uneven script. The director was able to balance this movie's genre or tone - was this to be a musical or just family comedy or drama. This movie appears to have ignored the director's own magical success of Mary Poppins (1964) released seven years earlier. Like Sean Penn directing Into the Wild (2007), director Robert Stevenson perhaps let success go to his head, or maybe insecurity by focusing so much on special effects and musical numbers that the story itself sometimes became secondary to the showing off the supposed "brilliance" of the animations. For example, Emelius fades almost into insignificance during the soccer game, or the primary characters are lost in the overly crowded and extended dance routine in the town. Even the television episode of Buffy: The Vampire Slayer - Once More, With Feeling (2001) displays how to both enhance the storyline and the characters with music instead of hiding them and ignoring the story. Cool World (1992), Jim Carrey's The Mask (1994), Monkey Bones (2001) all built on the break out live animation film Who Framed Roger Rabbit (1988). But even back in 1964, Arthur Lubin known for televisions series Mr. Ed and The Addams Family directed a neat live animation mixture with Don Knott's in The Incredible Mr. Limpet. Overall, what once was a new and delightful children's film has aged and not well.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A failed attempt to recapture the magic of Mary Poppins, but with a good set-piece finale
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    David Conrad
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    All the elements from "Mary Poppins" are here: a stern, magical nanny who flies, a kooky male street performer with whom she has some history, and period-specific English kids who tag along with the unconventional adults through foggy London streets and animated fantasy lands. Even one of the actors, David Tomlinson, is borrowed from Poppins. Yet Disney's attempt to strike gold twice fails. The pacing is much slower, particularly on the restored DVD release in which 30 minutes of footage cut from the theatrical release are reinserted. The songs are bland affairs that Tomlinson and Angela Lansbury meander through without much energy. During the animation sequence, the live actors are sidelined for an interminable soccer match between lions, alligators, and bears. These animal drawings are templates lifted from Disney's "The Jungle Book" (1967), and they would be recycled again in the studio's "Robin Hood" (1973). The final act of "Bedknobs," though it comes too late and lasts too long, does partly redeem it: special effects steal the show as an army of English museum pieces, mainly empty suits of medieval armor, come to life and march against the most incompetent Nazi invasion force in screen history. It would be better to YouTube that sequence than to sit through the movie to get to it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Honestly runs better in the standard cut
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Foux_du_Fafa
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Though far from perfect, "Bedknobs and Broomsticks" has always been a favourite of mine since childhood. The plot may be a bit muddled in places, but the sheer joy and fun of the fantasy material makes up for it. The animated sequences in particular are a real joy, as is the comedy-action climax to the film. Some of the songs are underrated classics, in particular "The Age of Not Believing" and "The Beautiful Briny". Also, the elaborate opening credit sequence is gorgeous to look at. That said, you may want to be careful which version of the film you see. The film premiered at around 135 minutes, but was cut down for general release to 117 minutes. This 117 minute version was the one I first saw as a child. In 1996, Disney restored the film to a length comparable to the premiere version, and this is what was released onto DVD. Ironically, I think the film does run better at a shorter length. Much of what is added are new or extended musical numbers, as well as the extension of a rather superfluous subplot involving a somewhat saucy vicar. I don't particularly find the new musical numbers that engaging, and the numbers that are extended aren't that great. Though there are some interesting extra verses in the extended "Portobello Road" number, the several dance scenes added to it renders it seemingly unending. "Eglantine" also goes on a bit too much for my liking. In addition some re-dubbing was required for some of the new scenes as the original mastertracks were not found. Angela Lansbury was able to come back and sounds fine, but many of the other actors weren't and the results are mixed. It would be nice if an inevitable Blu-Ray showed the film in either two of its versions, or if at least the original dialogue tapes were found for the extended scenes. I do believe that there are still ways to get hold of the 117 minute version. I have the first UK DVD release from around 2002, but I have read on Amazon that a later UK release has the film run at 117 minutes in order to align itself with some old European dubs on the disc, and I've also read online that TCM in the US sometimes shows the shorter version. In any case, "Bedknobs and Broomsticks" is a fun, family classic and easily worthy of my recommendation.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Way Too Long, Way Too Dull
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Joshua Mitchell
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Bedknobs And Broomsticks is rather obscure when compared to Disney's other films. This isn't a bad thing, though, considering most of Disney's other films are far superior to this overlong production. Lacking any excitement, or even laugh-worthy humor, Bedknobs And Broomsticks has little appeal to those over the age of 10, and even the youngest will likely be bored by the constant chatter and uninventive musical numbers. Three children named Carrie, Charlie and Paul are temporarily adopted by Eglantine Price, whom they discover to be a witch. Ms. Prince gives the children a traveling spell, in exchange for keeping her secret, which allows their bed to teleport to any given location. The four also snag Emelius Browne- Ms. Price's witch teacher- into the adventure as well. As one would expect, there are countless plot holes and silly things that are overlooked by the characters, but this is the least of the film's problems. Bedknobs And Broomsticks runs for a taxing two and a half hours. Had Bedknobs And Broomsticks been truly entertaining, this would not be a problem. Another Disney musical, Mary Poppins has a run time around the same length, and is loved and adored by all ages. Needless to say, Bedknobs And Broomsticks is no Mary Poppins. The content of this dull musical, does not justify the relentlessly long length. The number of songs in the film are not nearly as high as that of Mary Poppins, but they are far less inventive. Despite being penned by the Sherman brothers, the same duo that wrote the songs in Mary Poppins, each and every number is dull to limit. Occasionally, dancing takes place during these numbers, though the choreography is poor and uninspired. What's strange is that the beat of the music, often does not meet the beat of the dancing, which seems truly lazy. The score, also by the Sherman brothers isn't too shabby, and the bed traveling theme is relatively strong, but the score often sounds too similar to the Mary Poppins score (especially in the earlier segments). Also, if you hate bagpipes, you will definitely want to avoid this, as the aforementioned instruments make more than one appearance. Bedknobs And Broomsticks is specifically known for the Land of Naboombu, which is completely animated. It's always a marvel to see live-acted characters interact with animated ones. Alas, despite being showcased as the main attraction in Bedknobs And Broomsticks, the Land of Naboombu occupies a measly 30 minutes of the extensive run time. Talk about misleading! Special effects often look dated, and the strings that are used to suspend objects in midair are clearly visible most of the time. There are some decent effects though, make no mistake about it. But not all of the effects are as polished as others. The children are poorly acted, and most other actors fall into the unspectacular area. Only Angela Lansbury and David Tomlinson stand out. Bedknobs And Broomsticks is wholly unspectacular. It lacks the humor and excitement it needed to translate into the fun adventure it fails to be. Add that with the overlong run time and the dull musical numbers, and you get a animated musical that is unlikely to leave anyone coming back for more.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The restored version is a Disney classic but certainly no "Mary Poppins"
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mike48128
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/7/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Mary Poppins is a 10, so what's wrong with "Bedknobs" besides it's too long? A lack of "whimsey and wonder". Like comparing "Sleeping Beauty" to Snow White". (Both classics) So let's begin: The opening credits are far too long, as Disney liked to front-load all the credits during this era. The storyboarded titles tell the entire plot line so nothing is left to the imagination. It's like an overlong movie "trailer" that does the same thing. At first the characters are dreadful, and only start to improve in "likeability" as the story progresses. (Angela Lansbury, especially) The Bookman" and his henchman (who reminds me of the "Creeper" from the Sherlock Holmes series) are woefully-miscast; as they are too weird and sinister. "Portobello Road", a botched attempt at recreating the "Consider Yourself" musical number from "Oliver", is far too long. It seems more like a parade at Walt Disney World than a part of the movie. The Germans are both bumbling and menacing. (How is that possible?) The U-boat captain is far too nice! Now here's what's good about the film: The special effects are outstanding. The "haunted armor" is wonderful, although the kids will enjoy the cartoon sequences better: 1. The soccer game animation is only fair by Disney standards and somewhat "mean spirited." 2. The reason that "Beautiful Briny Sea" is so wonderful is that both the story and song were ideas cut from "Mary Poppins" and used here. The restoration seems a bit odd: David Tomlinson's voice is noticeably re-dubbed and (according to English critics) a song is missing, but all the other songs and scenes are fully-restored. In spite of all my criticism, I really do like this film. After all, it did win two Academy Awards for Special Effects!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Slow to get going and feels a little padded but is good Disney fun overall
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bob the moo
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/5/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Three children evacuated from London end up being reluctantly taken in by an odd woman who lives on her own with a raggedy black cat. They don't even make it to the end of the first night before they observe that their new guardian Miss Price is not just odd, she is an actual witch, trying to perfect a spell to help with the war effort. While the children make this discovery, Miss Price makes her own  the mail-order college she has been training with is going out of business before she has everything she needs. With the help of Paul's knob (don't ask) they set off to London to find the Professor  the start of a much bigger adventure. For my girlfriend this film is a strong childhood memory but for me I don't think I had ever seen it. In an attempt to be nice I got it for her a few years ago to watch at Christmas time but it sat unwatched until a miserable Bank Holiday Monday produced the urge to nest and just watch a couple of easy movies. As far as first impressions go, the film doesn't seem to feel any pressure to make a good one and if I'm honest I wondered if the opening credit sequence would ever end (a sequence that only has context once you have watched the film till the end). The titles rolls for at least five minutes without much to recommend them for and the film opens in much the same vein. Although there are some amusing moments and a bit of fantasy in the opening 20 or so minutes, it is slow and takes a while to get going. It doesn't help that the plot is a little vague and messy so that at one point I was neither sure why they were doing what they were doing, nor sure I particularly cared why they were doing it. This is a bit harsh perhaps  but I was thinking what children (not the most patient demographic) would be doing during this  in particular I was trying to think of any child I know who would be entranced by the Portobello Road song and dance number! It is still OK at this stage though and the good news is that it gets better with plenty of action, fun, invention and wit moving forward. The plotting is still a little bit "hmm" but it gets to where it is going thanks to the timely mini-invasion. The soccer match, the underwater musical number and of course the battle at the end are all great fun and I imagine children will enjoy them as much as I did (well, moreso probably). The old-fashioned feel is nice and I did like the sense of good clean family fun which the whole film had  although I'm not sure why the script calls for Paul to expressly refer to his knob so often; it is too deliberate and scripted to be merely something cynical modern ears pick up on. The pacing of the film is generally good as well but it is a little slower than it needed to be and I think being honest they could have had 15 minutes out of this without too much bother and it would have been a better film for it; not to say it is bad for the length, just that it doesn't always seem to need it. The cast are quite fun and all buy into the family tone. Lansbury in particular sells the role and works very well with Tomlinson in the adult roles. The children are a little annoying until you get used to them having the cockney turned up to 11 throughout; odd that neither of the boys ever did acting after this considering I liked them better than O'Callaghan's Carrie, who has less to do. Regardless they all work well and even when the animated sections turn up, the humans don't get lost in the fantasy but remain solid characters. Bedknobs and Broomsticks isn't brilliant but it is a solidly fun Disney family film. The majority of the musical numbers could have been better, the plot could have been stronger and the pacing/length trimmed to be slicker but it does all work, albeit not as well as it could have done. Enjoyable nonetheless with good wit and imagination  off-target Disney is still good after all.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    a message of hope
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    donnapepper9
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/4/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Bedknobs and Broomsticks was a film of its time. Yes, war is a strong feature - but there are covert references to war and violence in a lot of children's films - Mulan? For me, this is an ideal children's film - there is such a sense of escapism involved, whilst at the same time there is no attempt made to conceal that bad things do happen in life. The moral of this story, in my opinion, is that in the face of adversity there is always hope, and in hope there is strength to face the enemy. Whatever form that enemy might take - kids have far superior imaginations than adults and I don't believe that they would take a negative message from a film like this.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "Any Sufficiently Advanced Technology Is Indistinguishable From Magic"-Clarkes Third Law
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    johnstonjames
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/7/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    do i believe in magic? well, no. i'm sorry to disappoint anyone, but no, there is no such thing as magic. everything can be explained. it's usually all smoke and mirrors. parents should be strongly cautioned about 'Bedknobs and Broomsticks'. not because i believe in witches or magic, that stuff is just a bunch of hocus pocus. there are no such thing as real witches and anyone over the age of six who believes that should have their noggin examined. if someone tries to tell you there is such a thing as real magic or witches, get away from them fast because they are obviously psychotic and probably very dangerous. as a Christian and a person who is concerned with the salvation of man's immortal soul, it's not the magic that bothers me, it's the movie's strong spirit of militarism that bothers me. this movie glorifies war. and what is war good for? absolutely nothing. this movie indoctrinates young children into the military industrial complex at an early age(i mean it's designed for young children). children should not learn to glorify war, they should be wary of it, if not afraid of it. World War II may or may not have been the right decision, but do we need to keep bringing up past wars? especially where children are concerned. nobody wants World War III here. that would be madness. do i like this movie? of course i do. i grew up with this film and it's always been a Disney favorite of mine. it's beautifully handled by director Robert Stevenson, it's very clever, and has a charming musical score by Disney song writers, the Sherman Brothers. the film has many smart insights into history and sometimes i think this film may be more about children than anything else. but every time i get too sentimental and cozy about this film i wake up and think, oh God! THIS IS ABOUT WAR! nobody in their right brain wants a frick'in WAR! as far as the witchcraft element? i said what i think of that. there ain't no such thing and if you believe it's real YOU ARE STUPID. as a Christian does it scare me? oh sometimes i get superstitious and then i wake up. i used to follow astrology in the newspaper and read my horoscope everyday to see if i could find out anything. do you know what happened? absolutely nothing. half the time the stupid horoscope seemed like it was speaking to someone else. hardly any of the advice changed or helped my life in anyway. it just made me believe in silly things. but there are evil, stupid people out there with very little education who actually believe in magic. and it doesn't help that the witchcraft in 'Bedknobs' is far more real than the silly 'Harry Potter' films. i mean 'Astoroth' was a famous occultist and some of the incantation words (though not many) are actual words. does that scare me? of course not dummies. but it does scare some really stupid people who are evil enough to believe it's real. those people's children probably won't mix well with children who come from a more enlightened, intelligent and practical family that won't believe in such idiocy. so be careful with this movie. it could cause you some trouble if you bring it up in the wrong place. as far as my own feelings go, i find this film cute and charming and terribly funny. others might not be as amused. be careful. you are crossing the line with this film. when you endorse or recommend this film you are advocating war. you are also stating that you prefer to take a practical, scientific approach to this world and debunk superstition. for those of you who might read this and still believe witchcraft is real, YOU ARE STUPID. bottom line. keep repeating to yourself "it's only a movie. it's only a movie. than seek therapy. for the families strong and smart enough to deal with this ticking time bomb of a film, take caution and enjoy. it's funny and fun.if you can handle it go for it. HELLBORNE HENBANE AQUINITE GLOW-WORM FIRE FIREFLY LIGHT!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
 </reviews>
</filme>
