<filme>
 <id>
  1425
 </id>
 <imdburl>
  http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0110097
 </imdburl>
 <ano>
  1994
 </ano>
 <titulo>
  Disposto a Tudo
 </titulo>
 <rating>
  5.5
 </rating>
 <sinopse>
  Matt Hobbs is a talented but unsuccessful actor. When estranged (and strange) ex-wife Beth dumps their daughter Jeannie on Matt, father and daughter have a lot of adjusting to do. His ... &nbsp;&raquo;
 </sinopse>
 <storyline>
  Matt Hobbs is a talented but unsuccessful actor. When estranged (and strange) ex-wife Beth dumps their daughter Jeannie on Matt, father and daughter have a lot of adjusting to do. His budding relationship with attractive production assistant Cathy Breslow is made complicated, while the precocious child is overly accustomed to getting her own way. Matt eventually faces the choice of family vs career in a particularly difficult way.
 </storyline>
 <generos>
  <genero>
   Comedy
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Drama
  </genero>
 </generos>
 <keywords>
  <keyword>
   daughter
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   actor
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   father
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   ex wife
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   contraction in title
  </keyword>
 </keywords>
 <diretores>
  <diretor>
   James L. Brooks
  </diretor>
 </diretores>
 <escritores>
  <escritor>
   James L. Brooks
  </escritor>
 </escritores>
 <atores>
  <ator>
   Nick Nolte
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Albert Brooks
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Whittni Wright
  </ator>
 </atores>
 <reviews>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Child actress should have become a star; great story
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Michael Morrison (morrisonhimself@consultant.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/4/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Not usually a fan of Nick Nolte, I thought he was great in this. Even more, Julie Kavner was GREAT in this. She was so charming, so eye- catching, so ear-catching, she would have been considered the movie- stealer if little Whittni Wright hadn't been there. That child was absolutely astonishing. With no previous movie experience, she carried out her role as if she had done it a hundred times. I hope she changes her (still young) mind and returns to film. Albert Brooks is one of my entertainment heroes, and his role here is different for him -- and he too is great. There is a sweetness -- and I don't mean sugariness -- in this film that could make it worth watching even with a lesser cast, but with such a strong and lovable bunch, it is an almost perfect movie.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Improv feel to this delightful film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Al Rodbell
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/2/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This film could have been shot in a month, since everything in it had a freshness and spontaneity that can only come when nothing is labored. I don't know the film world, but this seemed genuine, with the characters each with their own struggles. Nick Nolte's relation with his "difficult" daughter was something to enjoy. When his hopes were raised to get the big role, only to find out it wasn't going to happen, devastation, closing the door and crying in the bathroom, was what could be expected. We only get so many chances in life, and when we miss one that very well could be our last, our life is altered irretrievable. Nothing could be more real, whether it is getting a movie part or a promotion to manager at Walmart. And the six year old who played his daughter, recruited from a clogging class in Georgia from a working class family. She was just a normal little girl, not a child actress, but someone who fit perfectly. And she went back to Georgia and then on to a local College to study Business Administration. Somehow, this film received a low rating here and apparently was a box office failure, yet every written comment was of the vein of this one, laudatory. Perhaps that was the subplot of the film exemplified by its lack of success. Brooks producer character made his films with loud explosions and tested it as a product to satisfy an audience. Artistry had nothing to do with what he was manufacturing. This film was a rare treat, but would never been made by Brooks, or anyone else apparently. But this one got through, and is a pleasure for those who can appreciate it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Summation / Review
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    vedder611
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/10/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    One of Nolte's best roles i'd say. Impressive debut by Whittni Wright. She apparently only made one other film (Van Damme's "sudden death" the following year). Can't believe that's all she's done since. I heard that the film was originally a musical. Later it was then chopped down to cut the musical numbers totally out aside from a short song by Whittni to her dad. Still works as a nice father daughter get to know each other story mixed with the chronicles of an on the cusp of fame actor. As they get to know each other the daughter shows a dramatic prowess that impresses her actor dad, and moves another character to nudge her into the business. Would love to see the missing musical numbers at some point. Is this summation long enough yet?. Is it ten lines? Not Yet? How bout now?
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Excellent Fillm, Nolte at His Best
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Ken Williams
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/8/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I've been a Nick Nolte fan ever since his "Rich Man Poor Man" days. "I'll Do Anything" is a big studio film with a sensitvity and quality OF performance I usually expect only in "art house" films. It's a character study of a struggling actor (Nolte) forced to come to grips with his life, career, and destiny after many factors like children/responsibility, age (mid-life crisis), relationships and values come to an intersection, and Nolte's character is forced to re-evaluate the way he lives in order to keep his sanity. The story is fueled by the insane film industry against which it is set. It's a crazy story presented with great warmth. People who would love it: couples or groups of women especially, but anyone looking for a heart breaking comedy. Lots to discuss after the film such as plot, performances, values that affect the characters' livessuch as kids vs career, career vs romance, art vs material success, responsibility vs dreams, and on and on. Have a party. Pop some corn, Have a great time. Laugh. Cry.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Cute
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    CrystalSparkles4
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/11/2005
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I probably wouldn't be able to find one other person that I know that has seen this movie. But that doesn't say anything about the film, which I think is obnoxiously cute. The little girl Jeanie is SO wise in her youth, she's this typical spoiled, wild child that is left with this man (Nick Nolte) that she doesn't know and acts the way she should (which is mostly why I like the movies so much) It's realistic in it's portrayal of her. It's one of those movies that I only see when it comes on UPN Sunday mornings (which I believe another commented on ha-ha) but it's true. That's the only that that anyone will probably ever see it. Don't look for too much to happen during it, it's a flat plot but full of really good characters and nice crying scenes for the girls ha-ha.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Good One!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jc-curtis
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/8/2005
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I saw this movie recently on cable TV and liked it a lot . I was looking for something other than the usual action/shootout/special effect types and ended up selecting this one. I'm glad I did. The supporting actors were excellent and Nick Nolte & Whittni Wright were outstanding in their roles. It was refreshing to see Nolti do this type of thing, although I'm not surprised that he did it well. He's an actor who has, over time, honed his skills to an art form. I'm not sure that he is appreciated as much as he should be. Anyway, in my opinion, "I'll do Anything" is underrated here. I give this flick a high mark and hope that my participation in the "vote" will raise the average score of this fine movie. For those who have had their fill of movies that focus on violence, try this delightful James L Brooks production for a change of pace. Or if you simply want to watch a movie that entertains... go for this one.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Irony Incarnate
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    knightm7
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/12/2004
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is a movie about making movies and standing up for your beliefs and not having to bow down under the pressures of audience expectations and studio involvements, and it had musical numbers which were cut and writers come in to dumb it down because of audience expectations and studio involvements. But I found all that out after I first saw the movie and thought it was great entertainment. I love Nick Nolte, he's so grave and gruff and depressed that I hope he doesn't kill himself cause I really like everything he's done, even The Hulk, and especially Affliction and that Martin Short with a kid movie. Joely Richardson is gorgeous! Julie Kavner and James Brooks are great. I highly recommend this film, and hope to see it again soon on DVD with all of the deleted scenes.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A gem, despite its shortcomings - *possible spoilers*
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    MeinFuhrerICanWalk
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/9/2003
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is one of those movies that I have grown to love almost inspite of itself. Yes, it's haphazard and kind of all over the place, and yet I am compelled to watch it through to the end whenever it plays on the telly. I can't quite figure out how well the characters are actually written, but they are played so beautifully that it really doesn't matter. I've always liked Nick Nolte but he's never been one of my 'favourites'. When I saw this film though, he completely won me over: he's selfish yet tender, brusque yet warm - just a wonderful, brave performance. Whitni Wright as Jeannie is remarkable - for any age. She is so utterly natural and believable, capturing the exasperating but ultimately disarming precociousness of childhood perfectly. It's a pity she has stopped acting, I think she would be amazing. It's also great to see Julie 'Marge Simpson' Kavner on the screen, she's severely underused by Hollywood - a great talent (remember 'Radio Days'?) And by the way, the film is about much more than an errant father mending his ways and changing his attitude toward his neglected kid, it's about a man unsure of his own worth finally changing his attitude toward HIMSELF. All in all, a gem despite its shortcomings.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Wrong actor
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    steinw
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/8/2002
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    When I watched this movie I had two questions in my head: 1) Where have I seen her (Joely Richardson) before? 2) Why is Nick Nolte doing this part, and not Ted Danson? The answer to Q1) is not so very interesting, but it is 101 Dalmatians. The answer to Q2) is more interesting. It seemed like Nick Nolte was trying to look and act like Ted Danson, especially in the beginning (when the character was young). And normally the original is better than the copy. Besides those two questions I think the movie was OK entertainment, but not more than that. The film is not trying to tell us something. If they wanted they could have made much more out of the issue "How is it to be a child actor?", but they didn't. Fair enough. Don't spend your money buying this film, but watch it if it gets aired on a TV.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Brooks' Bosses Decide To Not Do `Anything'
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tedg (tedg@FilmsFolded.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/7/2002
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Spoilers herein. There's a remarkably intelligent film hidden in here. I love watching old Welles films and trying to imagine the parts that the studios hacked out. And so here. The original idea was to have a deeply self-aware film, moreso than `The Player.' It was to have leveraged the shift inherent in a film musical : at some times, the audience is invited to see the story as representative of life, and at other times as representative of a show. Brooks puts tons of this stuff in `The Simpsons' and one can see the notion in his other TeeVee projects as well. But as I gather, this was actually supposed to be intelligent. Prince at this point was into self-referential songs and apparently increased the folding of an already baroque structure of who's looking at who. But (as with Welles), the studio financiers thought the paying audience was too dumb for all that, so brought in script doctor Elaine May (She of `Ishtar,' but nonetheless famously valuable as an invisible fixer). She straightened this film out so that a moron could understand it. Now it is not about the film business, but an ordinary sop about a dad discovering his precocious daughter. But you can see the joints where clever stuff might have been and the notion that parenting is a performance. They have kept one memorable Nolte moment. He is preparing to transform to a role. Watch how he changes, and also plays the meta-actor managing that change, and at the same time plays Nolte creating all three. It is his finest moment on film. I wonder if we will ever see the original version? Ted's Rating -- 2 of 4: Has some interesting elements.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Child actress should have become a star; great story
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Michael Morrison (morrisonhimself@consultant.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/4/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Not usually a fan of Nick Nolte, I thought he was great in this. Even more, Julie Kavner was GREAT in this. She was so charming, so eye- catching, so ear-catching, she would have been considered the movie- stealer if little Whittni Wright hadn't been there. That child was absolutely astonishing. With no previous movie experience, she carried out her role as if she had done it a hundred times. I hope she changes her (still young) mind and returns to film. Albert Brooks is one of my entertainment heroes, and his role here is different for him -- and he too is great. There is a sweetness -- and I don't mean sugariness -- in this film that could make it worth watching even with a lesser cast, but with such a strong and lovable bunch, it is an almost perfect movie.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Improv feel to this delightful film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Al Rodbell
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/2/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This film could have been shot in a month, since everything in it had a freshness and spontaneity that can only come when nothing is labored. I don't know the film world, but this seemed genuine, with the characters each with their own struggles. Nick Nolte's relation with his "difficult" daughter was something to enjoy. When his hopes were raised to get the big role, only to find out it wasn't going to happen, devastation, closing the door and crying in the bathroom, was what could be expected. We only get so many chances in life, and when we miss one that very well could be our last, our life is altered irretrievable. Nothing could be more real, whether it is getting a movie part or a promotion to manager at Walmart. And the six year old who played his daughter, recruited from a clogging class in Georgia from a working class family. She was just a normal little girl, not a child actress, but someone who fit perfectly. And she went back to Georgia and then on to a local College to study Business Administration. Somehow, this film received a low rating here and apparently was a box office failure, yet every written comment was of the vein of this one, laudatory. Perhaps that was the subplot of the film exemplified by its lack of success. Brooks producer character made his films with loud explosions and tested it as a product to satisfy an audience. Artistry had nothing to do with what he was manufacturing. This film was a rare treat, but would never been made by Brooks, or anyone else apparently. But this one got through, and is a pleasure for those who can appreciate it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Summation / Review
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    vedder611
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/10/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    One of Nolte's best roles i'd say. Impressive debut by Whittni Wright. She apparently only made one other film (Van Damme's "sudden death" the following year). Can't believe that's all she's done since. I heard that the film was originally a musical. Later it was then chopped down to cut the musical numbers totally out aside from a short song by Whittni to her dad. Still works as a nice father daughter get to know each other story mixed with the chronicles of an on the cusp of fame actor. As they get to know each other the daughter shows a dramatic prowess that impresses her actor dad, and moves another character to nudge her into the business. Would love to see the missing musical numbers at some point. Is this summation long enough yet?. Is it ten lines? Not Yet? How bout now?
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Excellent Fillm, Nolte at His Best
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Ken Williams
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/8/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I've been a Nick Nolte fan ever since his "Rich Man Poor Man" days. "I'll Do Anything" is a big studio film with a sensitvity and quality OF performance I usually expect only in "art house" films. It's a character study of a struggling actor (Nolte) forced to come to grips with his life, career, and destiny after many factors like children/responsibility, age (mid-life crisis), relationships and values come to an intersection, and Nolte's character is forced to re-evaluate the way he lives in order to keep his sanity. The story is fueled by the insane film industry against which it is set. It's a crazy story presented with great warmth. People who would love it: couples or groups of women especially, but anyone looking for a heart breaking comedy. Lots to discuss after the film such as plot, performances, values that affect the characters' livessuch as kids vs career, career vs romance, art vs material success, responsibility vs dreams, and on and on. Have a party. Pop some corn, Have a great time. Laugh. Cry.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Cute
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    CrystalSparkles4
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/11/2005
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I probably wouldn't be able to find one other person that I know that has seen this movie. But that doesn't say anything about the film, which I think is obnoxiously cute. The little girl Jeanie is SO wise in her youth, she's this typical spoiled, wild child that is left with this man (Nick Nolte) that she doesn't know and acts the way she should (which is mostly why I like the movies so much) It's realistic in it's portrayal of her. It's one of those movies that I only see when it comes on UPN Sunday mornings (which I believe another commented on ha-ha) but it's true. That's the only that that anyone will probably ever see it. Don't look for too much to happen during it, it's a flat plot but full of really good characters and nice crying scenes for the girls ha-ha.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Good One!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jc-curtis
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/8/2005
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I saw this movie recently on cable TV and liked it a lot . I was looking for something other than the usual action/shootout/special effect types and ended up selecting this one. I'm glad I did. The supporting actors were excellent and Nick Nolte & Whittni Wright were outstanding in their roles. It was refreshing to see Nolti do this type of thing, although I'm not surprised that he did it well. He's an actor who has, over time, honed his skills to an art form. I'm not sure that he is appreciated as much as he should be. Anyway, in my opinion, "I'll do Anything" is underrated here. I give this flick a high mark and hope that my participation in the "vote" will raise the average score of this fine movie. For those who have had their fill of movies that focus on violence, try this delightful James L Brooks production for a change of pace. Or if you simply want to watch a movie that entertains... go for this one.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Irony Incarnate
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    knightm7
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/12/2004
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is a movie about making movies and standing up for your beliefs and not having to bow down under the pressures of audience expectations and studio involvements, and it had musical numbers which were cut and writers come in to dumb it down because of audience expectations and studio involvements. But I found all that out after I first saw the movie and thought it was great entertainment. I love Nick Nolte, he's so grave and gruff and depressed that I hope he doesn't kill himself cause I really like everything he's done, even The Hulk, and especially Affliction and that Martin Short with a kid movie. Joely Richardson is gorgeous! Julie Kavner and James Brooks are great. I highly recommend this film, and hope to see it again soon on DVD with all of the deleted scenes.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A gem, despite its shortcomings - *possible spoilers*
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    MeinFuhrerICanWalk
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/9/2003
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is one of those movies that I have grown to love almost inspite of itself. Yes, it's haphazard and kind of all over the place, and yet I am compelled to watch it through to the end whenever it plays on the telly. I can't quite figure out how well the characters are actually written, but they are played so beautifully that it really doesn't matter. I've always liked Nick Nolte but he's never been one of my 'favourites'. When I saw this film though, he completely won me over: he's selfish yet tender, brusque yet warm - just a wonderful, brave performance. Whitni Wright as Jeannie is remarkable - for any age. She is so utterly natural and believable, capturing the exasperating but ultimately disarming precociousness of childhood perfectly. It's a pity she has stopped acting, I think she would be amazing. It's also great to see Julie 'Marge Simpson' Kavner on the screen, she's severely underused by Hollywood - a great talent (remember 'Radio Days'?) And by the way, the film is about much more than an errant father mending his ways and changing his attitude toward his neglected kid, it's about a man unsure of his own worth finally changing his attitude toward HIMSELF. All in all, a gem despite its shortcomings.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Wrong actor
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    steinw
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/8/2002
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    When I watched this movie I had two questions in my head: 1) Where have I seen her (Joely Richardson) before? 2) Why is Nick Nolte doing this part, and not Ted Danson? The answer to Q1) is not so very interesting, but it is 101 Dalmatians. The answer to Q2) is more interesting. It seemed like Nick Nolte was trying to look and act like Ted Danson, especially in the beginning (when the character was young). And normally the original is better than the copy. Besides those two questions I think the movie was OK entertainment, but not more than that. The film is not trying to tell us something. If they wanted they could have made much more out of the issue "How is it to be a child actor?", but they didn't. Fair enough. Don't spend your money buying this film, but watch it if it gets aired on a TV.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Brooks' Bosses Decide To Not Do `Anything'
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tedg (tedg@FilmsFolded.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/7/2002
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Spoilers herein. There's a remarkably intelligent film hidden in here. I love watching old Welles films and trying to imagine the parts that the studios hacked out. And so here. The original idea was to have a deeply self-aware film, moreso than `The Player.' It was to have leveraged the shift inherent in a film musical : at some times, the audience is invited to see the story as representative of life, and at other times as representative of a show. Brooks puts tons of this stuff in `The Simpsons' and one can see the notion in his other TeeVee projects as well. But as I gather, this was actually supposed to be intelligent. Prince at this point was into self-referential songs and apparently increased the folding of an already baroque structure of who's looking at who. But (as with Welles), the studio financiers thought the paying audience was too dumb for all that, so brought in script doctor Elaine May (She of `Ishtar,' but nonetheless famously valuable as an invisible fixer). She straightened this film out so that a moron could understand it. Now it is not about the film business, but an ordinary sop about a dad discovering his precocious daughter. But you can see the joints where clever stuff might have been and the notion that parenting is a performance. They have kept one memorable Nolte moment. He is preparing to transform to a role. Watch how he changes, and also plays the meta-actor managing that change, and at the same time plays Nolte creating all three. It is his finest moment on film. I wonder if we will ever see the original version? Ted's Rating -- 2 of 4: Has some interesting elements.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
 </reviews>
</filme>
