<filme>
 <id>
  1426
 </id>
 <imdburl>
  http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0116442
 </imdburl>
 <ano>
  1996
 </ano>
 <titulo>
  Grace of My Heart
 </titulo>
 <rating>
  6.4
 </rating>
 <sinopse>
  An aspiring singer, Denise Waverly/Edna Buxton, sacrifices her own singing career to write hit songs that launch the careers of other singers. The film follows her life from her first break... &nbsp;&raquo;
 </sinopse>
 <storyline>
  An aspiring singer, Denise Waverly/Edna Buxton, sacrifices her own singing career to write hit songs that launch the careers of other singers. The film follows her life from her first break, through the pain of rejection from the recording industry and a bad marriage, to her final triumph in realizing her dream to record her own hit album.
 </storyline>
 <generos>
  <genero>
   Comedy
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Drama
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Music
  </genero>
 </generos>
 <keywords>
  <keyword>
   beach house
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   script writer
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   drugs
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   1970s
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   nanny
  </keyword>
 </keywords>
 <diretores>
  <diretor>
   Allison Anders
  </diretor>
 </diretores>
 <escritores>
  <escritor>
   Allison Anders
  </escritor>
 </escritores>
 <atores>
  <ator>
   Illeana Douglas
  </ator>
  <ator>
   John Turturro
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Sissy Boyd
  </ator>
 </atores>
 <reviews>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Wonderful movie and amazing soundtrack...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    BettiePageGirl
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I love this movie and watch it EVERY time it comes on TV, even better when it's on a premium movie channel and you don't have to put up with ridiculous commercials. Ileana Douglas is an amazing actress with both comedy and drama ability. Beautiful woman with the most amazing doe eyes. She portrays a woman struggling (as we women always seem to have to do) in a "mans" world to be a music writer. With a bad marriage under her skirt and several other issues, she knows pain and heartache all too well which gives her the ammo she needs. Not doing too well with recording her own music she needs a little more courage to put herself out there. Well, it's a great portrayal of a woman who can't seem to get a break in her personal life but flourishes as a song writer. The music is great, going from the 60's to the 70's and for someone like me who was born in '59, appreciates when music was music and you could actually stand to even listen to a little pop music. Sure, there are a few comparisons to real musicians, writers and producers like Jay (Brian Wilson), Denise/Edna (Carole King), Joel (Phil Spector)but it takes on it's own story line and you just to have to come to your own conclusion. I appreciate the story and music and hail Alison Anders as an excellent director and phenomenal writer. Go figure, this good of a movie, written and directed by a woman. Wow, imagine that!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    17 years later and it's still a yawn
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    abundidi1184
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I saw when it came into the theater, and I thought it was okay. I saw it today and it's still okay. Personally I think it could have benefited from some editing. The main character,played by Ileana Douglas wasn't strong enough to carry the movie. She was mousy, and if it were not for the extremely talented supporting cast, it would have been a total snooze. I lived through the 50's and 60's. I loved the way the film showed the the evolution of rock and roll. I was disappointed not in the music, which was spot on, but Edna's role. John Tuturro was magnificent as always. Although Eric Stolz was good, if I was editing, I would have cut most of his scenes. Fast forward to the "caught in bed with another woman" scene. The script really was totally predictable. The affair with the married man; Matt Dillon's suicide, no surprise there. But the most disappointing was Ileana Douglas. A better actor could have carried the movie. She is not star material. The 4 stars were for John Tuturro and the song, "God Give Me Strength".
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Sharing Her Heartache With the World in Hit Songs
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Rod Morgan
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/11/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A wonderful performance by Illeana Douglas is the main attraction of this roman a clef of what might have happened if Carole King and Brian Wilson had become a couple. Not entirely successful but much more than a chick flick romance. Parallel to this version of the early days of rock and roll, the undervalued Laraine Newman plays another Carole King avatar in "American Hot Wax," a heartfelt tribute to Alan Freed featuring Screamin' Jay Hawkins, Jerry Lee Lewis and Chuck Berry playing themselves 20 years earlier as well as a goofy Jay Leno. Warner Brothers record producer Richard Perry eerily channels Lou Reed in the Phil Spector role John Turturro has here.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Pop Movie Hits All the Right Notes
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tonyblass
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/1/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    One of my favorite movies of any genre. You may be put off at first by the efficient TV movie opening which quickly and perhaps a bit glibly sums up the relationship of a domineering, aristocratic mother and quirky daughter who yearns to break free of her privileged suburban upbringing to become a pop music singer. But hang in there. A few scenes later you realize the rapid pacing and concise storytelling is the director's unusual and apparently risky choice of creating a film in the manner of it's subject: the breezy and innocently naive world of pop music of the late 1950s and early 60s. You will soon become captivated by the plucky "That Girl" adventures of the heiress turned streetwise bubble gum songstress (played to perfection by the creamy, otherworldly Illeana Douglas) as she defers her dreams of pop stardom to write some of the biggest hits of the girl (and boy) group era. The ensemble is brilliant, including the lovably domineering John Tuturro as the Svengali-like visionary producer and the pouty, preening ego-maniacal boyfriend and writing partner (Eric Stolz). The rest of the characters are amalgams of many of the legends of 60s pop music our heroine meets on the journey toward finding her own voice. And if any of this seems too familiar, it is loosely based on the amazing life and career of Carole King. In some ways, this is the female bookend to another great, under appreciated movie about pop music of this era, "The Idolmaker." But don't go dismissing this as a "girl's movie," just because it's director Allison Anders is perhaps the finest female auteur in the business. This is a story that crosses sex, age and all other boundaries. For anyone who has ever felt they didn't fit in, who tried to please everyone and played it safe, waiting to follow their own dreams until "the time was right," and then woke up afraid that it was too late ... this is a story for you. And the soundtrack. My God, the soundtrack. Far from parody, slavish recreation or disco-influenced revisionism, Ms. Anders has wisely chosen some of the heavyweights of the era to create pop hits that easily could have been hits on their own merits. The film is chock full of wondrous, alternate universe creations by such composers as Burt Bacharach and King's real-life partner Gerry Goffin, and even one by her daughter Lousie Goffin. This film is a joy from the first frame to the last. More than an homage to an era, it is an important addition to its story. "But what if I can't just write another song?" "Keep your eyes and ears open ... everyone is in pain"
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Inspirational with some great songs.....
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Maddyclassicfilms
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/10/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Directed by Allison Anders Grace Of My Heart is loosely based on the story of real life singer/songwriter Carole King.It's shockingly underrated and features songs that should be out there topping the charts. Beginning in late 1950's aspiring singer Edna Buxton(Illeana Douglas)is entering a singing competition and does not sing what her rich uptight mother wishes her to.Edna wins the competition and gets a recording contract.Moving to New York she meets famous song manager Joel Millner(John Tuturro)who helps her on the road to stardom and becomes her lifelong friend and confidant. Changing her name to Denise Waverley she writes a number of hits and becomes a famous and much sought after name in the music industry.She faces a lot of tragedies including the suicide of her husband but she overcomes all the hardship and gets her life back on track and produces and brings out a new album which sells over a million copies. Also starring Eric Stoltz as her co writer boyfriend and Christine Pickles as her mum.Grace Of The Heart is a beautiful and touching film filled with great music some of my favorite songs are Born To Love That Boy and Living In Another World.If you haven't heard of this one try and find it on DVD it's well worth watching and is filled with fantastic performances.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Started to watch it....
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Tweetypez
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/1/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Just wasn't my cup of tea. I didn't care for Ileana Douglas's acting. Also, I think that the time has passed where Hollywood needs to hire an actor that needs to be dubbed. There is so much talent out there who can sing AND act. It just didn't seem well done to me. Sort of like a cheaply made-for-TV movie. I didn't like the strange accent that John Turturro was doing for his character. I've seen other films that depict past years of the music business that I liked better such as "Coal Miner's Daughter" and "Ray" and "What's Love Got to Do with It" I would recommend those to anyone who want to watch a similar premise. Just my opinion.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Started to watch it....
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Tweetypez
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/1/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Just wasn't my cup of tea. I didn't care for Ileana Douglas's acting. Also, I think that the time has passed where Hollywood needs to hire an actor that needs to be dubbed. There is so much talent out there who can sing AND act. It just didn't seem well done to me. Sort of like a cheaply made-for-TV movie. I didn't like the strange accent that John Turturro was doing for his character. I've seen other films that depict past years of the music business that I liked better such as "Coal Miner's Daughter" and "Ray" and "What's Love Got to Do with It" I would recommend those to anyone who want to watch a similar premise. Just my opinion.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Maybe I put too much of myself into my songs.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    lastliberal
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/11/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It's Martin Scorsese day. he didn't direct this one, but produced it, and it's a winner. After 3 and a half hours of Bob Dylan, I was enchanted by the songs here. The soundtrack is a real tribute to love in all it's forms and fashions. Writer/Director Allison Anders, who started accumulating award nominations from her first movies (Border Radio; Sugar Town; Gas, Food Lodging) gives us a beautifully flowing story of a singer trying to break into the business, but settling for a career as a songwriter. It featured a lot of singers from the era, including one inspired by Lesley Gore, a favorite of mine, and who helped write songs for the movie. Illeana Douglas (Stir of Echoes, Happy, Texas, Cape Fear) was magnificent as the "Carol King"-inspired lead, as was John Turturro (The Big Lebowski, Fear X) as her manager. If you like the music of the sixties, and you want to see the first time a woman's water breaks on film, then this is it. A good use of your time.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    i loved this movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    steve-carter
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/11/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    i don't expect everyone to love this movie. I do think that while it isn't a masterpiece that it has one of the best story lines ever. I loved it pure and simple for the musical it wanted to be and the drama that it was. best Illeana douglas act i have seen. haven't seen her since goodfellas but i think she did well had it been by some large star the movie would have been huge still im disappointed i'm struggling to find this movie in Aussie format on DVD for my sister this Christmas. she loves the movie. someone suggest another movie to find. or give me details of where to get it in PAL format
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I love this film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    trish_p
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/10/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I came across this film one late night several years ago and I thought it was excellent. I just finished watching it a few minutes ago, and it stood the test of time for sure. It was every bit as good this time as it was the first time I saw it. Since the movie is loosely based on the life of Carol King, one of the things I enjoy about the film is trying to figure out what "real life" singing groups and songs were represented in this film. This film really has it all. Great acting, great music and a story that is definitely a tear jerker. I highly recommend this film. I would definitely include it in an evening of "chick flick" film watching!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Wonderful movie and amazing soundtrack...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    BettiePageGirl
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I love this movie and watch it EVERY time it comes on TV, even better when it's on a premium movie channel and you don't have to put up with ridiculous commercials. Ileana Douglas is an amazing actress with both comedy and drama ability. Beautiful woman with the most amazing doe eyes. She portrays a woman struggling (as we women always seem to have to do) in a "mans" world to be a music writer. With a bad marriage under her skirt and several other issues, she knows pain and heartache all too well which gives her the ammo she needs. Not doing too well with recording her own music she needs a little more courage to put herself out there. Well, it's a great portrayal of a woman who can't seem to get a break in her personal life but flourishes as a song writer. The music is great, going from the 60's to the 70's and for someone like me who was born in '59, appreciates when music was music and you could actually stand to even listen to a little pop music. Sure, there are a few comparisons to real musicians, writers and producers like Jay (Brian Wilson), Denise/Edna (Carole King), Joel (Phil Spector)but it takes on it's own story line and you just to have to come to your own conclusion. I appreciate the story and music and hail Alison Anders as an excellent director and phenomenal writer. Go figure, this good of a movie, written and directed by a woman. Wow, imagine that!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    17 years later and it's still a yawn
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    abundidi1184
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I saw when it came into the theater, and I thought it was okay. I saw it today and it's still okay. Personally I think it could have benefited from some editing. The main character,played by Ileana Douglas wasn't strong enough to carry the movie. She was mousy, and if it were not for the extremely talented supporting cast, it would have been a total snooze. I lived through the 50's and 60's. I loved the way the film showed the the evolution of rock and roll. I was disappointed not in the music, which was spot on, but Edna's role. John Tuturro was magnificent as always. Although Eric Stolz was good, if I was editing, I would have cut most of his scenes. Fast forward to the "caught in bed with another woman" scene. The script really was totally predictable. The affair with the married man; Matt Dillon's suicide, no surprise there. But the most disappointing was Ileana Douglas. A better actor could have carried the movie. She is not star material. The 4 stars were for John Tuturro and the song, "God Give Me Strength".
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Sharing Her Heartache With the World in Hit Songs
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Rod Morgan
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/11/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A wonderful performance by Illeana Douglas is the main attraction of this roman a clef of what might have happened if Carole King and Brian Wilson had become a couple. Not entirely successful but much more than a chick flick romance. Parallel to this version of the early days of rock and roll, the undervalued Laraine Newman plays another Carole King avatar in "American Hot Wax," a heartfelt tribute to Alan Freed featuring Screamin' Jay Hawkins, Jerry Lee Lewis and Chuck Berry playing themselves 20 years earlier as well as a goofy Jay Leno. Warner Brothers record producer Richard Perry eerily channels Lou Reed in the Phil Spector role John Turturro has here.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Pop Movie Hits All the Right Notes
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tonyblass
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/1/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    One of my favorite movies of any genre. You may be put off at first by the efficient TV movie opening which quickly and perhaps a bit glibly sums up the relationship of a domineering, aristocratic mother and quirky daughter who yearns to break free of her privileged suburban upbringing to become a pop music singer. But hang in there. A few scenes later you realize the rapid pacing and concise storytelling is the director's unusual and apparently risky choice of creating a film in the manner of it's subject: the breezy and innocently naive world of pop music of the late 1950s and early 60s. You will soon become captivated by the plucky "That Girl" adventures of the heiress turned streetwise bubble gum songstress (played to perfection by the creamy, otherworldly Illeana Douglas) as she defers her dreams of pop stardom to write some of the biggest hits of the girl (and boy) group era. The ensemble is brilliant, including the lovably domineering John Tuturro as the Svengali-like visionary producer and the pouty, preening ego-maniacal boyfriend and writing partner (Eric Stolz). The rest of the characters are amalgams of many of the legends of 60s pop music our heroine meets on the journey toward finding her own voice. And if any of this seems too familiar, it is loosely based on the amazing life and career of Carole King. In some ways, this is the female bookend to another great, under appreciated movie about pop music of this era, "The Idolmaker." But don't go dismissing this as a "girl's movie," just because it's director Allison Anders is perhaps the finest female auteur in the business. This is a story that crosses sex, age and all other boundaries. For anyone who has ever felt they didn't fit in, who tried to please everyone and played it safe, waiting to follow their own dreams until "the time was right," and then woke up afraid that it was too late ... this is a story for you. And the soundtrack. My God, the soundtrack. Far from parody, slavish recreation or disco-influenced revisionism, Ms. Anders has wisely chosen some of the heavyweights of the era to create pop hits that easily could have been hits on their own merits. The film is chock full of wondrous, alternate universe creations by such composers as Burt Bacharach and King's real-life partner Gerry Goffin, and even one by her daughter Lousie Goffin. This film is a joy from the first frame to the last. More than an homage to an era, it is an important addition to its story. "But what if I can't just write another song?" "Keep your eyes and ears open ... everyone is in pain"
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Inspirational with some great songs.....
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Maddyclassicfilms
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/10/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Directed by Allison Anders Grace Of My Heart is loosely based on the story of real life singer/songwriter Carole King.It's shockingly underrated and features songs that should be out there topping the charts. Beginning in late 1950's aspiring singer Edna Buxton(Illeana Douglas)is entering a singing competition and does not sing what her rich uptight mother wishes her to.Edna wins the competition and gets a recording contract.Moving to New York she meets famous song manager Joel Millner(John Tuturro)who helps her on the road to stardom and becomes her lifelong friend and confidant. Changing her name to Denise Waverley she writes a number of hits and becomes a famous and much sought after name in the music industry.She faces a lot of tragedies including the suicide of her husband but she overcomes all the hardship and gets her life back on track and produces and brings out a new album which sells over a million copies. Also starring Eric Stoltz as her co writer boyfriend and Christine Pickles as her mum.Grace Of The Heart is a beautiful and touching film filled with great music some of my favorite songs are Born To Love That Boy and Living In Another World.If you haven't heard of this one try and find it on DVD it's well worth watching and is filled with fantastic performances.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Started to watch it....
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Tweetypez
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/1/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Just wasn't my cup of tea. I didn't care for Ileana Douglas's acting. Also, I think that the time has passed where Hollywood needs to hire an actor that needs to be dubbed. There is so much talent out there who can sing AND act. It just didn't seem well done to me. Sort of like a cheaply made-for-TV movie. I didn't like the strange accent that John Turturro was doing for his character. I've seen other films that depict past years of the music business that I liked better such as "Coal Miner's Daughter" and "Ray" and "What's Love Got to Do with It" I would recommend those to anyone who want to watch a similar premise. Just my opinion.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Started to watch it....
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Tweetypez
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/1/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Just wasn't my cup of tea. I didn't care for Ileana Douglas's acting. Also, I think that the time has passed where Hollywood needs to hire an actor that needs to be dubbed. There is so much talent out there who can sing AND act. It just didn't seem well done to me. Sort of like a cheaply made-for-TV movie. I didn't like the strange accent that John Turturro was doing for his character. I've seen other films that depict past years of the music business that I liked better such as "Coal Miner's Daughter" and "Ray" and "What's Love Got to Do with It" I would recommend those to anyone who want to watch a similar premise. Just my opinion.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Maybe I put too much of myself into my songs.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    lastliberal
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/11/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It's Martin Scorsese day. he didn't direct this one, but produced it, and it's a winner. After 3 and a half hours of Bob Dylan, I was enchanted by the songs here. The soundtrack is a real tribute to love in all it's forms and fashions. Writer/Director Allison Anders, who started accumulating award nominations from her first movies (Border Radio; Sugar Town; Gas, Food Lodging) gives us a beautifully flowing story of a singer trying to break into the business, but settling for a career as a songwriter. It featured a lot of singers from the era, including one inspired by Lesley Gore, a favorite of mine, and who helped write songs for the movie. Illeana Douglas (Stir of Echoes, Happy, Texas, Cape Fear) was magnificent as the "Carol King"-inspired lead, as was John Turturro (The Big Lebowski, Fear X) as her manager. If you like the music of the sixties, and you want to see the first time a woman's water breaks on film, then this is it. A good use of your time.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    i loved this movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    steve-carter
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/11/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    i don't expect everyone to love this movie. I do think that while it isn't a masterpiece that it has one of the best story lines ever. I loved it pure and simple for the musical it wanted to be and the drama that it was. best Illeana douglas act i have seen. haven't seen her since goodfellas but i think she did well had it been by some large star the movie would have been huge still im disappointed i'm struggling to find this movie in Aussie format on DVD for my sister this Christmas. she loves the movie. someone suggest another movie to find. or give me details of where to get it in PAL format
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I love this film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    trish_p
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/10/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I came across this film one late night several years ago and I thought it was excellent. I just finished watching it a few minutes ago, and it stood the test of time for sure. It was every bit as good this time as it was the first time I saw it. Since the movie is loosely based on the life of Carol King, one of the things I enjoy about the film is trying to figure out what "real life" singing groups and songs were represented in this film. This film really has it all. Great acting, great music and a story that is definitely a tear jerker. I highly recommend this film. I would definitely include it in an evening of "chick flick" film watching!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Wonderful movie and amazing soundtrack...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    BettiePageGirl
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I love this movie and watch it EVERY time it comes on TV, even better when it's on a premium movie channel and you don't have to put up with ridiculous commercials. Ileana Douglas is an amazing actress with both comedy and drama ability. Beautiful woman with the most amazing doe eyes. She portrays a woman struggling (as we women always seem to have to do) in a "mans" world to be a music writer. With a bad marriage under her skirt and several other issues, she knows pain and heartache all too well which gives her the ammo she needs. Not doing too well with recording her own music she needs a little more courage to put herself out there. Well, it's a great portrayal of a woman who can't seem to get a break in her personal life but flourishes as a song writer. The music is great, going from the 60's to the 70's and for someone like me who was born in '59, appreciates when music was music and you could actually stand to even listen to a little pop music. Sure, there are a few comparisons to real musicians, writers and producers like Jay (Brian Wilson), Denise/Edna (Carole King), Joel (Phil Spector)but it takes on it's own story line and you just to have to come to your own conclusion. I appreciate the story and music and hail Alison Anders as an excellent director and phenomenal writer. Go figure, this good of a movie, written and directed by a woman. Wow, imagine that!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    17 years later and it's still a yawn
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    abundidi1184
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I saw when it came into the theater, and I thought it was okay. I saw it today and it's still okay. Personally I think it could have benefited from some editing. The main character,played by Ileana Douglas wasn't strong enough to carry the movie. She was mousy, and if it were not for the extremely talented supporting cast, it would have been a total snooze. I lived through the 50's and 60's. I loved the way the film showed the the evolution of rock and roll. I was disappointed not in the music, which was spot on, but Edna's role. John Tuturro was magnificent as always. Although Eric Stolz was good, if I was editing, I would have cut most of his scenes. Fast forward to the "caught in bed with another woman" scene. The script really was totally predictable. The affair with the married man; Matt Dillon's suicide, no surprise there. But the most disappointing was Ileana Douglas. A better actor could have carried the movie. She is not star material. The 4 stars were for John Tuturro and the song, "God Give Me Strength".
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Sharing Her Heartache With the World in Hit Songs
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Rod Morgan
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/11/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A wonderful performance by Illeana Douglas is the main attraction of this roman a clef of what might have happened if Carole King and Brian Wilson had become a couple. Not entirely successful but much more than a chick flick romance. Parallel to this version of the early days of rock and roll, the undervalued Laraine Newman plays another Carole King avatar in "American Hot Wax," a heartfelt tribute to Alan Freed featuring Screamin' Jay Hawkins, Jerry Lee Lewis and Chuck Berry playing themselves 20 years earlier as well as a goofy Jay Leno. Warner Brothers record producer Richard Perry eerily channels Lou Reed in the Phil Spector role John Turturro has here.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Pop Movie Hits All the Right Notes
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tonyblass
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/1/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    One of my favorite movies of any genre. You may be put off at first by the efficient TV movie opening which quickly and perhaps a bit glibly sums up the relationship of a domineering, aristocratic mother and quirky daughter who yearns to break free of her privileged suburban upbringing to become a pop music singer. But hang in there. A few scenes later you realize the rapid pacing and concise storytelling is the director's unusual and apparently risky choice of creating a film in the manner of it's subject: the breezy and innocently naive world of pop music of the late 1950s and early 60s. You will soon become captivated by the plucky "That Girl" adventures of the heiress turned streetwise bubble gum songstress (played to perfection by the creamy, otherworldly Illeana Douglas) as she defers her dreams of pop stardom to write some of the biggest hits of the girl (and boy) group era. The ensemble is brilliant, including the lovably domineering John Tuturro as the Svengali-like visionary producer and the pouty, preening ego-maniacal boyfriend and writing partner (Eric Stolz). The rest of the characters are amalgams of many of the legends of 60s pop music our heroine meets on the journey toward finding her own voice. And if any of this seems too familiar, it is loosely based on the amazing life and career of Carole King. In some ways, this is the female bookend to another great, under appreciated movie about pop music of this era, "The Idolmaker." But don't go dismissing this as a "girl's movie," just because it's director Allison Anders is perhaps the finest female auteur in the business. This is a story that crosses sex, age and all other boundaries. For anyone who has ever felt they didn't fit in, who tried to please everyone and played it safe, waiting to follow their own dreams until "the time was right," and then woke up afraid that it was too late ... this is a story for you. And the soundtrack. My God, the soundtrack. Far from parody, slavish recreation or disco-influenced revisionism, Ms. Anders has wisely chosen some of the heavyweights of the era to create pop hits that easily could have been hits on their own merits. The film is chock full of wondrous, alternate universe creations by such composers as Burt Bacharach and King's real-life partner Gerry Goffin, and even one by her daughter Lousie Goffin. This film is a joy from the first frame to the last. More than an homage to an era, it is an important addition to its story. "But what if I can't just write another song?" "Keep your eyes and ears open ... everyone is in pain"
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Inspirational with some great songs.....
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Maddyclassicfilms
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/10/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Directed by Allison Anders Grace Of My Heart is loosely based on the story of real life singer/songwriter Carole King.It's shockingly underrated and features songs that should be out there topping the charts. Beginning in late 1950's aspiring singer Edna Buxton(Illeana Douglas)is entering a singing competition and does not sing what her rich uptight mother wishes her to.Edna wins the competition and gets a recording contract.Moving to New York she meets famous song manager Joel Millner(John Tuturro)who helps her on the road to stardom and becomes her lifelong friend and confidant. Changing her name to Denise Waverley she writes a number of hits and becomes a famous and much sought after name in the music industry.She faces a lot of tragedies including the suicide of her husband but she overcomes all the hardship and gets her life back on track and produces and brings out a new album which sells over a million copies. Also starring Eric Stoltz as her co writer boyfriend and Christine Pickles as her mum.Grace Of The Heart is a beautiful and touching film filled with great music some of my favorite songs are Born To Love That Boy and Living In Another World.If you haven't heard of this one try and find it on DVD it's well worth watching and is filled with fantastic performances.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Started to watch it....
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Tweetypez
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/1/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Just wasn't my cup of tea. I didn't care for Ileana Douglas's acting. Also, I think that the time has passed where Hollywood needs to hire an actor that needs to be dubbed. There is so much talent out there who can sing AND act. It just didn't seem well done to me. Sort of like a cheaply made-for-TV movie. I didn't like the strange accent that John Turturro was doing for his character. I've seen other films that depict past years of the music business that I liked better such as "Coal Miner's Daughter" and "Ray" and "What's Love Got to Do with It" I would recommend those to anyone who want to watch a similar premise. Just my opinion.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Started to watch it....
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Tweetypez
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/1/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Just wasn't my cup of tea. I didn't care for Ileana Douglas's acting. Also, I think that the time has passed where Hollywood needs to hire an actor that needs to be dubbed. There is so much talent out there who can sing AND act. It just didn't seem well done to me. Sort of like a cheaply made-for-TV movie. I didn't like the strange accent that John Turturro was doing for his character. I've seen other films that depict past years of the music business that I liked better such as "Coal Miner's Daughter" and "Ray" and "What's Love Got to Do with It" I would recommend those to anyone who want to watch a similar premise. Just my opinion.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Maybe I put too much of myself into my songs.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    lastliberal
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/11/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It's Martin Scorsese day. he didn't direct this one, but produced it, and it's a winner. After 3 and a half hours of Bob Dylan, I was enchanted by the songs here. The soundtrack is a real tribute to love in all it's forms and fashions. Writer/Director Allison Anders, who started accumulating award nominations from her first movies (Border Radio; Sugar Town; Gas, Food Lodging) gives us a beautifully flowing story of a singer trying to break into the business, but settling for a career as a songwriter. It featured a lot of singers from the era, including one inspired by Lesley Gore, a favorite of mine, and who helped write songs for the movie. Illeana Douglas (Stir of Echoes, Happy, Texas, Cape Fear) was magnificent as the "Carol King"-inspired lead, as was John Turturro (The Big Lebowski, Fear X) as her manager. If you like the music of the sixties, and you want to see the first time a woman's water breaks on film, then this is it. A good use of your time.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    i loved this movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    steve-carter
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/11/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    i don't expect everyone to love this movie. I do think that while it isn't a masterpiece that it has one of the best story lines ever. I loved it pure and simple for the musical it wanted to be and the drama that it was. best Illeana douglas act i have seen. haven't seen her since goodfellas but i think she did well had it been by some large star the movie would have been huge still im disappointed i'm struggling to find this movie in Aussie format on DVD for my sister this Christmas. she loves the movie. someone suggest another movie to find. or give me details of where to get it in PAL format
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I love this film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    trish_p
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/10/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I came across this film one late night several years ago and I thought it was excellent. I just finished watching it a few minutes ago, and it stood the test of time for sure. It was every bit as good this time as it was the first time I saw it. Since the movie is loosely based on the life of Carol King, one of the things I enjoy about the film is trying to figure out what "real life" singing groups and songs were represented in this film. This film really has it all. Great acting, great music and a story that is definitely a tear jerker. I highly recommend this film. I would definitely include it in an evening of "chick flick" film watching!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Wonderful movie and amazing soundtrack...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    BettiePageGirl
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I love this movie and watch it EVERY time it comes on TV, even better when it's on a premium movie channel and you don't have to put up with ridiculous commercials. Ileana Douglas is an amazing actress with both comedy and drama ability. Beautiful woman with the most amazing doe eyes. She portrays a woman struggling (as we women always seem to have to do) in a "mans" world to be a music writer. With a bad marriage under her skirt and several other issues, she knows pain and heartache all too well which gives her the ammo she needs. Not doing too well with recording her own music she needs a little more courage to put herself out there. Well, it's a great portrayal of a woman who can't seem to get a break in her personal life but flourishes as a song writer. The music is great, going from the 60's to the 70's and for someone like me who was born in '59, appreciates when music was music and you could actually stand to even listen to a little pop music. Sure, there are a few comparisons to real musicians, writers and producers like Jay (Brian Wilson), Denise/Edna (Carole King), Joel (Phil Spector)but it takes on it's own story line and you just to have to come to your own conclusion. I appreciate the story and music and hail Alison Anders as an excellent director and phenomenal writer. Go figure, this good of a movie, written and directed by a woman. Wow, imagine that!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    17 years later and it's still a yawn
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    abundidi1184
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I saw when it came into the theater, and I thought it was okay. I saw it today and it's still okay. Personally I think it could have benefited from some editing. The main character,played by Ileana Douglas wasn't strong enough to carry the movie. She was mousy, and if it were not for the extremely talented supporting cast, it would have been a total snooze. I lived through the 50's and 60's. I loved the way the film showed the the evolution of rock and roll. I was disappointed not in the music, which was spot on, but Edna's role. John Tuturro was magnificent as always. Although Eric Stolz was good, if I was editing, I would have cut most of his scenes. Fast forward to the "caught in bed with another woman" scene. The script really was totally predictable. The affair with the married man; Matt Dillon's suicide, no surprise there. But the most disappointing was Ileana Douglas. A better actor could have carried the movie. She is not star material. The 4 stars were for John Tuturro and the song, "God Give Me Strength".
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Sharing Her Heartache With the World in Hit Songs
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Rod Morgan
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/11/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A wonderful performance by Illeana Douglas is the main attraction of this roman a clef of what might have happened if Carole King and Brian Wilson had become a couple. Not entirely successful but much more than a chick flick romance. Parallel to this version of the early days of rock and roll, the undervalued Laraine Newman plays another Carole King avatar in "American Hot Wax," a heartfelt tribute to Alan Freed featuring Screamin' Jay Hawkins, Jerry Lee Lewis and Chuck Berry playing themselves 20 years earlier as well as a goofy Jay Leno. Warner Brothers record producer Richard Perry eerily channels Lou Reed in the Phil Spector role John Turturro has here.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Pop Movie Hits All the Right Notes
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tonyblass
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/1/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    One of my favorite movies of any genre. You may be put off at first by the efficient TV movie opening which quickly and perhaps a bit glibly sums up the relationship of a domineering, aristocratic mother and quirky daughter who yearns to break free of her privileged suburban upbringing to become a pop music singer. But hang in there. A few scenes later you realize the rapid pacing and concise storytelling is the director's unusual and apparently risky choice of creating a film in the manner of it's subject: the breezy and innocently naive world of pop music of the late 1950s and early 60s. You will soon become captivated by the plucky "That Girl" adventures of the heiress turned streetwise bubble gum songstress (played to perfection by the creamy, otherworldly Illeana Douglas) as she defers her dreams of pop stardom to write some of the biggest hits of the girl (and boy) group era. The ensemble is brilliant, including the lovably domineering John Tuturro as the Svengali-like visionary producer and the pouty, preening ego-maniacal boyfriend and writing partner (Eric Stolz). The rest of the characters are amalgams of many of the legends of 60s pop music our heroine meets on the journey toward finding her own voice. And if any of this seems too familiar, it is loosely based on the amazing life and career of Carole King. In some ways, this is the female bookend to another great, under appreciated movie about pop music of this era, "The Idolmaker." But don't go dismissing this as a "girl's movie," just because it's director Allison Anders is perhaps the finest female auteur in the business. This is a story that crosses sex, age and all other boundaries. For anyone who has ever felt they didn't fit in, who tried to please everyone and played it safe, waiting to follow their own dreams until "the time was right," and then woke up afraid that it was too late ... this is a story for you. And the soundtrack. My God, the soundtrack. Far from parody, slavish recreation or disco-influenced revisionism, Ms. Anders has wisely chosen some of the heavyweights of the era to create pop hits that easily could have been hits on their own merits. The film is chock full of wondrous, alternate universe creations by such composers as Burt Bacharach and King's real-life partner Gerry Goffin, and even one by her daughter Lousie Goffin. This film is a joy from the first frame to the last. More than an homage to an era, it is an important addition to its story. "But what if I can't just write another song?" "Keep your eyes and ears open ... everyone is in pain"
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Inspirational with some great songs.....
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Maddyclassicfilms
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/10/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Directed by Allison Anders Grace Of My Heart is loosely based on the story of real life singer/songwriter Carole King.It's shockingly underrated and features songs that should be out there topping the charts. Beginning in late 1950's aspiring singer Edna Buxton(Illeana Douglas)is entering a singing competition and does not sing what her rich uptight mother wishes her to.Edna wins the competition and gets a recording contract.Moving to New York she meets famous song manager Joel Millner(John Tuturro)who helps her on the road to stardom and becomes her lifelong friend and confidant. Changing her name to Denise Waverley she writes a number of hits and becomes a famous and much sought after name in the music industry.She faces a lot of tragedies including the suicide of her husband but she overcomes all the hardship and gets her life back on track and produces and brings out a new album which sells over a million copies. Also starring Eric Stoltz as her co writer boyfriend and Christine Pickles as her mum.Grace Of The Heart is a beautiful and touching film filled with great music some of my favorite songs are Born To Love That Boy and Living In Another World.If you haven't heard of this one try and find it on DVD it's well worth watching and is filled with fantastic performances.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Started to watch it....
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Tweetypez
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/1/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Just wasn't my cup of tea. I didn't care for Ileana Douglas's acting. Also, I think that the time has passed where Hollywood needs to hire an actor that needs to be dubbed. There is so much talent out there who can sing AND act. It just didn't seem well done to me. Sort of like a cheaply made-for-TV movie. I didn't like the strange accent that John Turturro was doing for his character. I've seen other films that depict past years of the music business that I liked better such as "Coal Miner's Daughter" and "Ray" and "What's Love Got to Do with It" I would recommend those to anyone who want to watch a similar premise. Just my opinion.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Started to watch it....
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Tweetypez
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/1/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Just wasn't my cup of tea. I didn't care for Ileana Douglas's acting. Also, I think that the time has passed where Hollywood needs to hire an actor that needs to be dubbed. There is so much talent out there who can sing AND act. It just didn't seem well done to me. Sort of like a cheaply made-for-TV movie. I didn't like the strange accent that John Turturro was doing for his character. I've seen other films that depict past years of the music business that I liked better such as "Coal Miner's Daughter" and "Ray" and "What's Love Got to Do with It" I would recommend those to anyone who want to watch a similar premise. Just my opinion.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Maybe I put too much of myself into my songs.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    lastliberal
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/11/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It's Martin Scorsese day. he didn't direct this one, but produced it, and it's a winner. After 3 and a half hours of Bob Dylan, I was enchanted by the songs here. The soundtrack is a real tribute to love in all it's forms and fashions. Writer/Director Allison Anders, who started accumulating award nominations from her first movies (Border Radio; Sugar Town; Gas, Food Lodging) gives us a beautifully flowing story of a singer trying to break into the business, but settling for a career as a songwriter. It featured a lot of singers from the era, including one inspired by Lesley Gore, a favorite of mine, and who helped write songs for the movie. Illeana Douglas (Stir of Echoes, Happy, Texas, Cape Fear) was magnificent as the "Carol King"-inspired lead, as was John Turturro (The Big Lebowski, Fear X) as her manager. If you like the music of the sixties, and you want to see the first time a woman's water breaks on film, then this is it. A good use of your time.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    i loved this movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    steve-carter
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/11/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    i don't expect everyone to love this movie. I do think that while it isn't a masterpiece that it has one of the best story lines ever. I loved it pure and simple for the musical it wanted to be and the drama that it was. best Illeana douglas act i have seen. haven't seen her since goodfellas but i think she did well had it been by some large star the movie would have been huge still im disappointed i'm struggling to find this movie in Aussie format on DVD for my sister this Christmas. she loves the movie. someone suggest another movie to find. or give me details of where to get it in PAL format
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I love this film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    trish_p
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/10/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I came across this film one late night several years ago and I thought it was excellent. I just finished watching it a few minutes ago, and it stood the test of time for sure. It was every bit as good this time as it was the first time I saw it. Since the movie is loosely based on the life of Carol King, one of the things I enjoy about the film is trying to figure out what "real life" singing groups and songs were represented in this film. This film really has it all. Great acting, great music and a story that is definitely a tear jerker. I highly recommend this film. I would definitely include it in an evening of "chick flick" film watching!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Wonderful movie and amazing soundtrack...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    BettiePageGirl
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I love this movie and watch it EVERY time it comes on TV, even better when it's on a premium movie channel and you don't have to put up with ridiculous commercials. Ileana Douglas is an amazing actress with both comedy and drama ability. Beautiful woman with the most amazing doe eyes. She portrays a woman struggling (as we women always seem to have to do) in a "mans" world to be a music writer. With a bad marriage under her skirt and several other issues, she knows pain and heartache all too well which gives her the ammo she needs. Not doing too well with recording her own music she needs a little more courage to put herself out there. Well, it's a great portrayal of a woman who can't seem to get a break in her personal life but flourishes as a song writer. The music is great, going from the 60's to the 70's and for someone like me who was born in '59, appreciates when music was music and you could actually stand to even listen to a little pop music. Sure, there are a few comparisons to real musicians, writers and producers like Jay (Brian Wilson), Denise/Edna (Carole King), Joel (Phil Spector)but it takes on it's own story line and you just to have to come to your own conclusion. I appreciate the story and music and hail Alison Anders as an excellent director and phenomenal writer. Go figure, this good of a movie, written and directed by a woman. Wow, imagine that!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    17 years later and it's still a yawn
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    abundidi1184
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I saw when it came into the theater, and I thought it was okay. I saw it today and it's still okay. Personally I think it could have benefited from some editing. The main character,played by Ileana Douglas wasn't strong enough to carry the movie. She was mousy, and if it were not for the extremely talented supporting cast, it would have been a total snooze. I lived through the 50's and 60's. I loved the way the film showed the the evolution of rock and roll. I was disappointed not in the music, which was spot on, but Edna's role. John Tuturro was magnificent as always. Although Eric Stolz was good, if I was editing, I would have cut most of his scenes. Fast forward to the "caught in bed with another woman" scene. The script really was totally predictable. The affair with the married man; Matt Dillon's suicide, no surprise there. But the most disappointing was Ileana Douglas. A better actor could have carried the movie. She is not star material. The 4 stars were for John Tuturro and the song, "God Give Me Strength".
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Sharing Her Heartache With the World in Hit Songs
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Rod Morgan
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/11/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A wonderful performance by Illeana Douglas is the main attraction of this roman a clef of what might have happened if Carole King and Brian Wilson had become a couple. Not entirely successful but much more than a chick flick romance. Parallel to this version of the early days of rock and roll, the undervalued Laraine Newman plays another Carole King avatar in "American Hot Wax," a heartfelt tribute to Alan Freed featuring Screamin' Jay Hawkins, Jerry Lee Lewis and Chuck Berry playing themselves 20 years earlier as well as a goofy Jay Leno. Warner Brothers record producer Richard Perry eerily channels Lou Reed in the Phil Spector role John Turturro has here.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Pop Movie Hits All the Right Notes
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tonyblass
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/1/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    One of my favorite movies of any genre. You may be put off at first by the efficient TV movie opening which quickly and perhaps a bit glibly sums up the relationship of a domineering, aristocratic mother and quirky daughter who yearns to break free of her privileged suburban upbringing to become a pop music singer. But hang in there. A few scenes later you realize the rapid pacing and concise storytelling is the director's unusual and apparently risky choice of creating a film in the manner of it's subject: the breezy and innocently naive world of pop music of the late 1950s and early 60s. You will soon become captivated by the plucky "That Girl" adventures of the heiress turned streetwise bubble gum songstress (played to perfection by the creamy, otherworldly Illeana Douglas) as she defers her dreams of pop stardom to write some of the biggest hits of the girl (and boy) group era. The ensemble is brilliant, including the lovably domineering John Tuturro as the Svengali-like visionary producer and the pouty, preening ego-maniacal boyfriend and writing partner (Eric Stolz). The rest of the characters are amalgams of many of the legends of 60s pop music our heroine meets on the journey toward finding her own voice. And if any of this seems too familiar, it is loosely based on the amazing life and career of Carole King. In some ways, this is the female bookend to another great, under appreciated movie about pop music of this era, "The Idolmaker." But don't go dismissing this as a "girl's movie," just because it's director Allison Anders is perhaps the finest female auteur in the business. This is a story that crosses sex, age and all other boundaries. For anyone who has ever felt they didn't fit in, who tried to please everyone and played it safe, waiting to follow their own dreams until "the time was right," and then woke up afraid that it was too late ... this is a story for you. And the soundtrack. My God, the soundtrack. Far from parody, slavish recreation or disco-influenced revisionism, Ms. Anders has wisely chosen some of the heavyweights of the era to create pop hits that easily could have been hits on their own merits. The film is chock full of wondrous, alternate universe creations by such composers as Burt Bacharach and King's real-life partner Gerry Goffin, and even one by her daughter Lousie Goffin. This film is a joy from the first frame to the last. More than an homage to an era, it is an important addition to its story. "But what if I can't just write another song?" "Keep your eyes and ears open ... everyone is in pain"
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Inspirational with some great songs.....
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Maddyclassicfilms
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/10/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Directed by Allison Anders Grace Of My Heart is loosely based on the story of real life singer/songwriter Carole King.It's shockingly underrated and features songs that should be out there topping the charts. Beginning in late 1950's aspiring singer Edna Buxton(Illeana Douglas)is entering a singing competition and does not sing what her rich uptight mother wishes her to.Edna wins the competition and gets a recording contract.Moving to New York she meets famous song manager Joel Millner(John Tuturro)who helps her on the road to stardom and becomes her lifelong friend and confidant. Changing her name to Denise Waverley she writes a number of hits and becomes a famous and much sought after name in the music industry.She faces a lot of tragedies including the suicide of her husband but she overcomes all the hardship and gets her life back on track and produces and brings out a new album which sells over a million copies. Also starring Eric Stoltz as her co writer boyfriend and Christine Pickles as her mum.Grace Of The Heart is a beautiful and touching film filled with great music some of my favorite songs are Born To Love That Boy and Living In Another World.If you haven't heard of this one try and find it on DVD it's well worth watching and is filled with fantastic performances.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Started to watch it....
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Tweetypez
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/1/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Just wasn't my cup of tea. I didn't care for Ileana Douglas's acting. Also, I think that the time has passed where Hollywood needs to hire an actor that needs to be dubbed. There is so much talent out there who can sing AND act. It just didn't seem well done to me. Sort of like a cheaply made-for-TV movie. I didn't like the strange accent that John Turturro was doing for his character. I've seen other films that depict past years of the music business that I liked better such as "Coal Miner's Daughter" and "Ray" and "What's Love Got to Do with It" I would recommend those to anyone who want to watch a similar premise. Just my opinion.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Started to watch it....
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Tweetypez
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/1/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Just wasn't my cup of tea. I didn't care for Ileana Douglas's acting. Also, I think that the time has passed where Hollywood needs to hire an actor that needs to be dubbed. There is so much talent out there who can sing AND act. It just didn't seem well done to me. Sort of like a cheaply made-for-TV movie. I didn't like the strange accent that John Turturro was doing for his character. I've seen other films that depict past years of the music business that I liked better such as "Coal Miner's Daughter" and "Ray" and "What's Love Got to Do with It" I would recommend those to anyone who want to watch a similar premise. Just my opinion.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Maybe I put too much of myself into my songs.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    lastliberal
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/11/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It's Martin Scorsese day. he didn't direct this one, but produced it, and it's a winner. After 3 and a half hours of Bob Dylan, I was enchanted by the songs here. The soundtrack is a real tribute to love in all it's forms and fashions. Writer/Director Allison Anders, who started accumulating award nominations from her first movies (Border Radio; Sugar Town; Gas, Food Lodging) gives us a beautifully flowing story of a singer trying to break into the business, but settling for a career as a songwriter. It featured a lot of singers from the era, including one inspired by Lesley Gore, a favorite of mine, and who helped write songs for the movie. Illeana Douglas (Stir of Echoes, Happy, Texas, Cape Fear) was magnificent as the "Carol King"-inspired lead, as was John Turturro (The Big Lebowski, Fear X) as her manager. If you like the music of the sixties, and you want to see the first time a woman's water breaks on film, then this is it. A good use of your time.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    i loved this movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    steve-carter
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/11/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    i don't expect everyone to love this movie. I do think that while it isn't a masterpiece that it has one of the best story lines ever. I loved it pure and simple for the musical it wanted to be and the drama that it was. best Illeana douglas act i have seen. haven't seen her since goodfellas but i think she did well had it been by some large star the movie would have been huge still im disappointed i'm struggling to find this movie in Aussie format on DVD for my sister this Christmas. she loves the movie. someone suggest another movie to find. or give me details of where to get it in PAL format
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I love this film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    trish_p
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/10/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I came across this film one late night several years ago and I thought it was excellent. I just finished watching it a few minutes ago, and it stood the test of time for sure. It was every bit as good this time as it was the first time I saw it. Since the movie is loosely based on the life of Carol King, one of the things I enjoy about the film is trying to figure out what "real life" singing groups and songs were represented in this film. This film really has it all. Great acting, great music and a story that is definitely a tear jerker. I highly recommend this film. I would definitely include it in an evening of "chick flick" film watching!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
 </reviews>
</filme>
