<filme>
 <id>
  1427
 </id>
 <imdburl>
  http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0112907
 </imdburl>
 <ano>
  1995
 </ano>
 <titulo>
  Uma Dose de Esperan&ccedil;a
 </titulo>
 <rating>
  6.0
 </rating>
 <sinopse>
  At the beginning of a nightly Alcoholics Anonymous meeting, Jim seems particularly troubled. His sponsor encourages him to talk that night, the first time in seven months, so he does - and ... &nbsp;&raquo;
 </sinopse>
 <storyline>
  At the beginning of a nightly Alcoholics Anonymous meeting, Jim seems particularly troubled. His sponsor encourages him to talk that night, the first time in seven months, so he does - and leaves the meeting right after. As Jim wanders the night, searching for some solace in his old stomping grounds, bars and parks where he bought drugs, the meeting goes on, and we hear the stories of survivors and addicts - some, like Louis, who claim to have wandered in looking for choir practice, who don't call themselves alcoholic, and others, like Joseph, whose drinking almost caused the death of his child - as they talk about their lives at the meeting.
 </storyline>
 <generos>
  <genero>
   Drama
  </genero>
 </generos>
 <keywords>
  <keyword>
   alcoholic
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   drugs
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   alcoholics anonymous
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   bar
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   bartender
  </keyword>
 </keywords>
 <diretores>
  <diretor>
   Peter Cohn
  </diretor>
 </diretores>
 <escritores>
  <escritor>
   Gary Lennon
  </escritor>
 </escritores>
 <atores>
  <ator>
   Richard Lewis
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Liza Harris
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Liam Ahern
  </ator>
 </atores>
 <reviews>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not Bad
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Dhaval Vyas (vogolsong@yahoo.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The title of the movie pretty much sums up it subject matter. At the same time, 'Drunks' is shown from the perspective of those persons who are trying to save themselves from alcoholism. It shows them talking about their problems and lives through an Alcoholics Anonymous meeting. Most of the film takes place in one night, and centers around one main character - Jim (Richard Lewis). His character is just about the only one we get to know deeply. In an act of desperate rebellion, he walks out of the AA meeting in order to get a drink (or maybe two, three, or four?). The film juxtaposes Jim's desperate night out from one liquor store and bar to the next with the other reforming alcoholics talking during their meeting. As the night progresses, Richard Lewis gets more and more drunk, wasted, and out of control. He also begins to experiment with other drugs. Overall, this is not a bad film - it is mostly a character study. The stories the alcoholics have to tell are funny, tragic, and moving. Those who enjoy dialog movies will likely enjoy this film. Faye Dunaway also plays a small role in it. I really liked the ending of the movie. It goes to show how so many alcoholics don't succeed in becoming sober and they are trapped in an endless and dangerous cycle. This cycle perhaps has no way out.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Excellent, honest and a new voice has come.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gfelidi
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/8/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Excellent, honest, does not pull any punches in it's grim reality of addiction and the struggles to get clean. The writing by Mr. Lennon is so truthful that it does not seem like a movie we are watching, but peeking into people's lives. The acting and direction were inspired and very realistic. If you want to see an honest movie about addiction and the ravages it causes...this is it. Be ready because it is not some Hollywood sugar coated piece of fluff thatt we are sujected to. Looking forward to seeing more of Mr. Lennon's writing transfered to film...a truly honest and unique voice. Incredible performances by all of the cast. Tight direction as well. Stands up to films in this genre..."Panic in Neddle Park", "Hatful of Rain"...etc...Don't miss it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Fantastic Film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Brettcurtissanders
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/6/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Wow. What a BRILLIANT piece of cinema. Drunks has to be hands down one of the most important and accurate films I've seen to date about Substance abuse. As a person with a father who died of Alcoholism, this film really helped me gain understanding. It helped me not only cope with my father's disease but gave me tremendous understanding to what he went through as an addict. Having attended a lot of the AAA meetings in my life, the film was spot on. Brilliant, real, funny, and full of heart... and tears. I would recommend adding this to your library if you haven't already.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    As good as a meeting
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    kamalkicks
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/1/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    they say in the program "one day at a time". some days are harder than others. DRUNKs represents that better than any film i have ever seen. I am the member of a twelve step program. I think it is one of the greatest international communities that exists. it has changed countless lives and i am hard pressed to think or find one person who's life hasn't been affected positively by it's existence. it is a secular religion -if you will. I believe this is the most realistic and resonant film that has ever taken as it's focus the program and it's demographic busting community. i think the level of talent that came together to make this is a testament to it's quality. it is not a rose colored take on the community. it reflects as does the program the myriad ways that people use, don't use, succeed and fail. it is the truth as i experience it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Emotionally honest drama
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ingmanagement
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/7/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I saw Blackout, the play that this movie is based, when it played in Los Angeles. The play itself is incredible and is one of the best plays in theater, in my opinion. The movie, Drunks, captures what is best about the play: the great writing and dialog that when given to talented actors, create unforgettable performances that will make you laugh and cry. The characters, their stories, and their world are real. There is no preaching or message or apologetic reason given. The characters are all in transit in their own lives and for their own reasons. And you're allowed a fascinating glimpse into their lives. If you enjoy great writing and performances and watching people in their nakedly honest moments, you should watch Drunks.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    reality and acting on the dark side of inebriation
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    MisterWhiplash
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/2/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Richard Lewis is one of my all-time favorite comedians. Mel Brooks once called him the Franz Kafka of comedy, and it's not far from the truth. The guy crafts such agonizing and harrowing comedy out of neuroses and problems and just common familial and relationship and whatever dread that it's staggering to watch (seeing him recently it was even more free-form and stream-of-conscious than ever, like Kurt Vonnegut and Woody Allen in a Bowery bar telling penis jokes). But he also was, in his past, troubled and on drugs and alcohol and went to a therapist for years and so on, and finally kicked it for good in the early 90s (he even wrote a sprawling, scatter-shot tell-all book called The Other Great Depression). So, in 1995, he took the lead part in Drunks, and if it may seem like his performance as Jim is so spot on and incredible it's more than likely because he knows this character, maybe all too well. I go on about Lewis so much just because he's the character most on the edge, the one falling off amongst all these other AA people meeting in a Manhattan Church, that it's impossible to take your eyes off him when he shows up. Jim, who speaks very reluctantly to the couple of dozen people at the AA meeting, lost his wife to a brain aneurysm two years after becoming sober from booze and junk. Then he slipped and went back and at the time of the meeting he hasn't had a drink in several months. Right after this long and heartfelt confession he leaves and wanders the streets, tempted at first and finally giving in to his insatiable craving to whiskey and beer. While he goes from either bar to his apartment or on the streets for drugs the film cuts back to the AA meeting where other people share their experiences, some fatally tragic like the blackout guy, or Dianne Wiest's doctor, or Faye Dunaway's upper-class mother, or Sam Rockwell's seemingly regular guy, or even Parker Posey as an ex-hippie chick. Hell, even Calista Flockheart gives a showstopper of a performance, which is an indicator of how on top of things the actors are here. It is, if as a real liability, written and performed like a play, and it's broken up as a series of monologues inter-cut with Jim in his downward spiral mode. The good thing about director Peter Cohn's approach is that even if a monologue falls kind of flat- I actually didn't care much for Spalding Gray who sort of mumbled through his character's turn as the guy who just showed up not knowing it was an AA meeting in the basement of the church- it can cut back to Richard Lewis who, in particular in one later scene at a bar, lays it down to such a heartbreaking beat that you almost wish he was in a Bergman movie or something - or, for that matter, one of Woody Allen's serious films. He's that amazing here, whether it's just how he is or if it's a "performance" or whatever. It's an actor's movie, and for that it works well. Just don't watch it for anything fancy or flashy; it's slightly obscure for that reason, since it doesn't have a real "star" attached.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Great Film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jorgedanieljdn
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/5/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I rented this and was very surprised by how good it was. The writing was so strong and the actors took those words and soared. There is not one false note. It felt like a CASSAVETTES film. Honesty on screen is what I look for in films. This film felt like real life. Real time. I could relate to these characters. Feel their pain. Their stories were compelling. I couldn't take my eyes of the screen My favorite performances were Lisa Gay Hamilton and the late Howard Rollins. They moved me to tears. I hope this movie gets to be seen by others who are struggling with addiction. The message finally got to me and it is interesting that it came to me in the guise of a movie. I am now going out and buying the DVD and the play that the film is based on. Thank you to the film makers.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Best substance abuse film ever!!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    paukenmeister
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/5/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I agree with several posters who say that people in recovery should watch this film. I also believe that every treatment facility should show this to the patients/clients based on the raw, gritty and realistic portrayals of addiction and addicts. However, I would be careful showing this movie in a substance abuse program at a men's prison due to the brief depiction of nude breasts. Some of the audience members *may* be distracted by the flash of flesh and forget the true message/intention of the movie. I would also not recommend this film if you're offended by "F-bombs". **SPOILER ALERT - sorta** There's a scene where Jim (Richard Lewis) is "sharing his grief" with a complete stranger at a bar - a stranger who's trying to be polite but wants to escape. Anyway, as I watched this scene with the "Closed-Captioning" activated, I noticed that each new caption on the screen had "f**k" (or a variation thereof) displaying. **END MILD SPOILER ALERT** Here's my synopsis of the film. **SPOILER ALERT #2** Jim, a recovering alcoholic/heroin addict is getting a room in a church ready for an AA meeting. His sponsor (George Martin) asks him to speak since the original speaker couldn't make it. Jim's reluctant to speak, but his sponsor presses him on. As Jim gives a half-hearted lead, we learn that he got sober simply to keep his wife happy. Since his wife has passed away, we can see that Jim's motivation to stay sober has gone as well. We see this as Jim wanders New York, getting wasted on booze. He's so desperate for companionship that he seeks a hooker - who only wants heroin. Jim goes to a park, buys heroin and steals a syringe from another junkie passed out in the park. Jim staggers back to his old bar and attempts to cook the heroin when he's thrown out. The film ends with a thoroughly wasted Jim at an AA meeting admitting that at the end of the day he'll have a full day of sobriety. I feel as though the film is trying to say that even if a recovering person relapses, they can always try their recovery again. **END SPOILER ALERT #2** "F-bombs" and nudity aside, I highly recommend this film to people in recovery and substance abuse counselors as well.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Shattering and depressing...as it should be
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Wayne Malin (wwaayynnee51@hotmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/3/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Jim (Richard Lewis) attends an AA meeting very worried about something. His sponsor encourages him to talk. He does...and immediately leaves. The rest of the movie involves him trying not to drink and it keeps going back to the meeting where we, one by one, hear each member say why they're there. I caught this at a small art cinema way back in 1997 and I never forgot it. It perfectly captures what an AA meeting is like and the stories related are harrowing. Quite a few well known actors play members: Sam Rockwell (still unknown at the time), Amanda Plummer, Parkey Posey, Dianne Wiest, Calista Flockheart and Faye Dunaway. Their considerable acting talents make the stories seem realistic and hard to shake off. There's no happy endings here. Grim and disturbing but realistic. Sometime the staginess shows through (you can tell this was based on a play) which is why I can only give it an 8. Still, it's well worth watching.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    If you know someone and care about them, this drama may help
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    somehope
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/3/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Drunks" deserves a better wide release than it received in the early 90's. It's not an easy film to digest, but if "Six Feet Under" can make us look at mortality, death, and grieving a little easier, than this film can help others see this disease a little more clearly. Hollywood has portrayed drunks as lovable figures, whether it be W.C. Fields' characters to "Barfly" (was Bukowski ever truly happy, though, or was Rourke's characterization just an acceptance of a barfly's life? Yet, we all know people who have gone from social drinker to lost in themselves. "Once Were Warriors." The great "The Lost Weekend." "Reqiuem for a Dream." "Nil by Mouth." "Under the Volcano." Leaving Las Vegas." "Less Than Zero." Thousands of lives have been damaged by alcoholism, and if you ever want to see a real tragedy, look at the people on these screens and, if you see yourself, you might be in real trouble. Back to the film. Basically, this a film of monologues, yet each contains more power than you might think when you hear the word "monologue." Lewis' performance is of course, great, as the reviews say, but please read his autobiography to discover how far he was from becoming Jim. It is a must-read for any addict, and while not an addict, it has helped me personally with some of my problems. Another great performances include the late Howard Rollins, of TV's "In the Heat of the Night" fame, who also was an addict at various points in his life. Splading Gray, a brilliant actor who committed suicide due to depression, also gives a brilliant performance as a man who wanders upon the meeting, and realizes he is one of them. A young Calista Flockhart and Faye Dunway find the right notes as addicts who need to sponsor each other. Even performances from Lisa Gay Hamilton (TV's "The Pratice")as an HIV positive woman, are damn strong. That's the key to the film. There may be no happy endings, but there is no preaching, and no sermonizing. Please, I urge you to seek this one out if you ever wonder what a real AA meeting is about, and get it more accessible to your friends who might need it to see it ... or yourself. It's not preachy, but it's a good drama. I'm off my soapbox: Please see this as drama. And remember if you need help, there is always someone there, don't give up. And hopefully, this film, will help you see that even the most self-destructive person can survive.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not Bad
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Dhaval Vyas (vogolsong@yahoo.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The title of the movie pretty much sums up it subject matter. At the same time, 'Drunks' is shown from the perspective of those persons who are trying to save themselves from alcoholism. It shows them talking about their problems and lives through an Alcoholics Anonymous meeting. Most of the film takes place in one night, and centers around one main character - Jim (Richard Lewis). His character is just about the only one we get to know deeply. In an act of desperate rebellion, he walks out of the AA meeting in order to get a drink (or maybe two, three, or four?). The film juxtaposes Jim's desperate night out from one liquor store and bar to the next with the other reforming alcoholics talking during their meeting. As the night progresses, Richard Lewis gets more and more drunk, wasted, and out of control. He also begins to experiment with other drugs. Overall, this is not a bad film - it is mostly a character study. The stories the alcoholics have to tell are funny, tragic, and moving. Those who enjoy dialog movies will likely enjoy this film. Faye Dunaway also plays a small role in it. I really liked the ending of the movie. It goes to show how so many alcoholics don't succeed in becoming sober and they are trapped in an endless and dangerous cycle. This cycle perhaps has no way out.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Excellent, honest and a new voice has come.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gfelidi
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/8/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Excellent, honest, does not pull any punches in it's grim reality of addiction and the struggles to get clean. The writing by Mr. Lennon is so truthful that it does not seem like a movie we are watching, but peeking into people's lives. The acting and direction were inspired and very realistic. If you want to see an honest movie about addiction and the ravages it causes...this is it. Be ready because it is not some Hollywood sugar coated piece of fluff thatt we are sujected to. Looking forward to seeing more of Mr. Lennon's writing transfered to film...a truly honest and unique voice. Incredible performances by all of the cast. Tight direction as well. Stands up to films in this genre..."Panic in Neddle Park", "Hatful of Rain"...etc...Don't miss it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Fantastic Film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Brettcurtissanders
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/6/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Wow. What a BRILLIANT piece of cinema. Drunks has to be hands down one of the most important and accurate films I've seen to date about Substance abuse. As a person with a father who died of Alcoholism, this film really helped me gain understanding. It helped me not only cope with my father's disease but gave me tremendous understanding to what he went through as an addict. Having attended a lot of the AAA meetings in my life, the film was spot on. Brilliant, real, funny, and full of heart... and tears. I would recommend adding this to your library if you haven't already.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    As good as a meeting
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    kamalkicks
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/1/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    they say in the program "one day at a time". some days are harder than others. DRUNKs represents that better than any film i have ever seen. I am the member of a twelve step program. I think it is one of the greatest international communities that exists. it has changed countless lives and i am hard pressed to think or find one person who's life hasn't been affected positively by it's existence. it is a secular religion -if you will. I believe this is the most realistic and resonant film that has ever taken as it's focus the program and it's demographic busting community. i think the level of talent that came together to make this is a testament to it's quality. it is not a rose colored take on the community. it reflects as does the program the myriad ways that people use, don't use, succeed and fail. it is the truth as i experience it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Emotionally honest drama
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ingmanagement
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/7/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I saw Blackout, the play that this movie is based, when it played in Los Angeles. The play itself is incredible and is one of the best plays in theater, in my opinion. The movie, Drunks, captures what is best about the play: the great writing and dialog that when given to talented actors, create unforgettable performances that will make you laugh and cry. The characters, their stories, and their world are real. There is no preaching or message or apologetic reason given. The characters are all in transit in their own lives and for their own reasons. And you're allowed a fascinating glimpse into their lives. If you enjoy great writing and performances and watching people in their nakedly honest moments, you should watch Drunks.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    reality and acting on the dark side of inebriation
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    MisterWhiplash
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/2/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Richard Lewis is one of my all-time favorite comedians. Mel Brooks once called him the Franz Kafka of comedy, and it's not far from the truth. The guy crafts such agonizing and harrowing comedy out of neuroses and problems and just common familial and relationship and whatever dread that it's staggering to watch (seeing him recently it was even more free-form and stream-of-conscious than ever, like Kurt Vonnegut and Woody Allen in a Bowery bar telling penis jokes). But he also was, in his past, troubled and on drugs and alcohol and went to a therapist for years and so on, and finally kicked it for good in the early 90s (he even wrote a sprawling, scatter-shot tell-all book called The Other Great Depression). So, in 1995, he took the lead part in Drunks, and if it may seem like his performance as Jim is so spot on and incredible it's more than likely because he knows this character, maybe all too well. I go on about Lewis so much just because he's the character most on the edge, the one falling off amongst all these other AA people meeting in a Manhattan Church, that it's impossible to take your eyes off him when he shows up. Jim, who speaks very reluctantly to the couple of dozen people at the AA meeting, lost his wife to a brain aneurysm two years after becoming sober from booze and junk. Then he slipped and went back and at the time of the meeting he hasn't had a drink in several months. Right after this long and heartfelt confession he leaves and wanders the streets, tempted at first and finally giving in to his insatiable craving to whiskey and beer. While he goes from either bar to his apartment or on the streets for drugs the film cuts back to the AA meeting where other people share their experiences, some fatally tragic like the blackout guy, or Dianne Wiest's doctor, or Faye Dunaway's upper-class mother, or Sam Rockwell's seemingly regular guy, or even Parker Posey as an ex-hippie chick. Hell, even Calista Flockheart gives a showstopper of a performance, which is an indicator of how on top of things the actors are here. It is, if as a real liability, written and performed like a play, and it's broken up as a series of monologues inter-cut with Jim in his downward spiral mode. The good thing about director Peter Cohn's approach is that even if a monologue falls kind of flat- I actually didn't care much for Spalding Gray who sort of mumbled through his character's turn as the guy who just showed up not knowing it was an AA meeting in the basement of the church- it can cut back to Richard Lewis who, in particular in one later scene at a bar, lays it down to such a heartbreaking beat that you almost wish he was in a Bergman movie or something - or, for that matter, one of Woody Allen's serious films. He's that amazing here, whether it's just how he is or if it's a "performance" or whatever. It's an actor's movie, and for that it works well. Just don't watch it for anything fancy or flashy; it's slightly obscure for that reason, since it doesn't have a real "star" attached.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Great Film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jorgedanieljdn
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/5/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I rented this and was very surprised by how good it was. The writing was so strong and the actors took those words and soared. There is not one false note. It felt like a CASSAVETTES film. Honesty on screen is what I look for in films. This film felt like real life. Real time. I could relate to these characters. Feel their pain. Their stories were compelling. I couldn't take my eyes of the screen My favorite performances were Lisa Gay Hamilton and the late Howard Rollins. They moved me to tears. I hope this movie gets to be seen by others who are struggling with addiction. The message finally got to me and it is interesting that it came to me in the guise of a movie. I am now going out and buying the DVD and the play that the film is based on. Thank you to the film makers.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Best substance abuse film ever!!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    paukenmeister
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/5/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I agree with several posters who say that people in recovery should watch this film. I also believe that every treatment facility should show this to the patients/clients based on the raw, gritty and realistic portrayals of addiction and addicts. However, I would be careful showing this movie in a substance abuse program at a men's prison due to the brief depiction of nude breasts. Some of the audience members *may* be distracted by the flash of flesh and forget the true message/intention of the movie. I would also not recommend this film if you're offended by "F-bombs". **SPOILER ALERT - sorta** There's a scene where Jim (Richard Lewis) is "sharing his grief" with a complete stranger at a bar - a stranger who's trying to be polite but wants to escape. Anyway, as I watched this scene with the "Closed-Captioning" activated, I noticed that each new caption on the screen had "f**k" (or a variation thereof) displaying. **END MILD SPOILER ALERT** Here's my synopsis of the film. **SPOILER ALERT #2** Jim, a recovering alcoholic/heroin addict is getting a room in a church ready for an AA meeting. His sponsor (George Martin) asks him to speak since the original speaker couldn't make it. Jim's reluctant to speak, but his sponsor presses him on. As Jim gives a half-hearted lead, we learn that he got sober simply to keep his wife happy. Since his wife has passed away, we can see that Jim's motivation to stay sober has gone as well. We see this as Jim wanders New York, getting wasted on booze. He's so desperate for companionship that he seeks a hooker - who only wants heroin. Jim goes to a park, buys heroin and steals a syringe from another junkie passed out in the park. Jim staggers back to his old bar and attempts to cook the heroin when he's thrown out. The film ends with a thoroughly wasted Jim at an AA meeting admitting that at the end of the day he'll have a full day of sobriety. I feel as though the film is trying to say that even if a recovering person relapses, they can always try their recovery again. **END SPOILER ALERT #2** "F-bombs" and nudity aside, I highly recommend this film to people in recovery and substance abuse counselors as well.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Shattering and depressing...as it should be
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Wayne Malin (wwaayynnee51@hotmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/3/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Jim (Richard Lewis) attends an AA meeting very worried about something. His sponsor encourages him to talk. He does...and immediately leaves. The rest of the movie involves him trying not to drink and it keeps going back to the meeting where we, one by one, hear each member say why they're there. I caught this at a small art cinema way back in 1997 and I never forgot it. It perfectly captures what an AA meeting is like and the stories related are harrowing. Quite a few well known actors play members: Sam Rockwell (still unknown at the time), Amanda Plummer, Parkey Posey, Dianne Wiest, Calista Flockheart and Faye Dunaway. Their considerable acting talents make the stories seem realistic and hard to shake off. There's no happy endings here. Grim and disturbing but realistic. Sometime the staginess shows through (you can tell this was based on a play) which is why I can only give it an 8. Still, it's well worth watching.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    If you know someone and care about them, this drama may help
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    somehope
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/3/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Drunks" deserves a better wide release than it received in the early 90's. It's not an easy film to digest, but if "Six Feet Under" can make us look at mortality, death, and grieving a little easier, than this film can help others see this disease a little more clearly. Hollywood has portrayed drunks as lovable figures, whether it be W.C. Fields' characters to "Barfly" (was Bukowski ever truly happy, though, or was Rourke's characterization just an acceptance of a barfly's life? Yet, we all know people who have gone from social drinker to lost in themselves. "Once Were Warriors." The great "The Lost Weekend." "Reqiuem for a Dream." "Nil by Mouth." "Under the Volcano." Leaving Las Vegas." "Less Than Zero." Thousands of lives have been damaged by alcoholism, and if you ever want to see a real tragedy, look at the people on these screens and, if you see yourself, you might be in real trouble. Back to the film. Basically, this a film of monologues, yet each contains more power than you might think when you hear the word "monologue." Lewis' performance is of course, great, as the reviews say, but please read his autobiography to discover how far he was from becoming Jim. It is a must-read for any addict, and while not an addict, it has helped me personally with some of my problems. Another great performances include the late Howard Rollins, of TV's "In the Heat of the Night" fame, who also was an addict at various points in his life. Splading Gray, a brilliant actor who committed suicide due to depression, also gives a brilliant performance as a man who wanders upon the meeting, and realizes he is one of them. A young Calista Flockhart and Faye Dunway find the right notes as addicts who need to sponsor each other. Even performances from Lisa Gay Hamilton (TV's "The Pratice")as an HIV positive woman, are damn strong. That's the key to the film. There may be no happy endings, but there is no preaching, and no sermonizing. Please, I urge you to seek this one out if you ever wonder what a real AA meeting is about, and get it more accessible to your friends who might need it to see it ... or yourself. It's not preachy, but it's a good drama. I'm off my soapbox: Please see this as drama. And remember if you need help, there is always someone there, don't give up. And hopefully, this film, will help you see that even the most self-destructive person can survive.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not Bad
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Dhaval Vyas (vogolsong@yahoo.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The title of the movie pretty much sums up it subject matter. At the same time, 'Drunks' is shown from the perspective of those persons who are trying to save themselves from alcoholism. It shows them talking about their problems and lives through an Alcoholics Anonymous meeting. Most of the film takes place in one night, and centers around one main character - Jim (Richard Lewis). His character is just about the only one we get to know deeply. In an act of desperate rebellion, he walks out of the AA meeting in order to get a drink (or maybe two, three, or four?). The film juxtaposes Jim's desperate night out from one liquor store and bar to the next with the other reforming alcoholics talking during their meeting. As the night progresses, Richard Lewis gets more and more drunk, wasted, and out of control. He also begins to experiment with other drugs. Overall, this is not a bad film - it is mostly a character study. The stories the alcoholics have to tell are funny, tragic, and moving. Those who enjoy dialog movies will likely enjoy this film. Faye Dunaway also plays a small role in it. I really liked the ending of the movie. It goes to show how so many alcoholics don't succeed in becoming sober and they are trapped in an endless and dangerous cycle. This cycle perhaps has no way out.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Excellent, honest and a new voice has come.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gfelidi
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/8/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Excellent, honest, does not pull any punches in it's grim reality of addiction and the struggles to get clean. The writing by Mr. Lennon is so truthful that it does not seem like a movie we are watching, but peeking into people's lives. The acting and direction were inspired and very realistic. If you want to see an honest movie about addiction and the ravages it causes...this is it. Be ready because it is not some Hollywood sugar coated piece of fluff thatt we are sujected to. Looking forward to seeing more of Mr. Lennon's writing transfered to film...a truly honest and unique voice. Incredible performances by all of the cast. Tight direction as well. Stands up to films in this genre..."Panic in Neddle Park", "Hatful of Rain"...etc...Don't miss it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Fantastic Film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Brettcurtissanders
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/6/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Wow. What a BRILLIANT piece of cinema. Drunks has to be hands down one of the most important and accurate films I've seen to date about Substance abuse. As a person with a father who died of Alcoholism, this film really helped me gain understanding. It helped me not only cope with my father's disease but gave me tremendous understanding to what he went through as an addict. Having attended a lot of the AAA meetings in my life, the film was spot on. Brilliant, real, funny, and full of heart... and tears. I would recommend adding this to your library if you haven't already.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    As good as a meeting
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    kamalkicks
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/1/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    they say in the program "one day at a time". some days are harder than others. DRUNKs represents that better than any film i have ever seen. I am the member of a twelve step program. I think it is one of the greatest international communities that exists. it has changed countless lives and i am hard pressed to think or find one person who's life hasn't been affected positively by it's existence. it is a secular religion -if you will. I believe this is the most realistic and resonant film that has ever taken as it's focus the program and it's demographic busting community. i think the level of talent that came together to make this is a testament to it's quality. it is not a rose colored take on the community. it reflects as does the program the myriad ways that people use, don't use, succeed and fail. it is the truth as i experience it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Emotionally honest drama
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ingmanagement
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/7/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I saw Blackout, the play that this movie is based, when it played in Los Angeles. The play itself is incredible and is one of the best plays in theater, in my opinion. The movie, Drunks, captures what is best about the play: the great writing and dialog that when given to talented actors, create unforgettable performances that will make you laugh and cry. The characters, their stories, and their world are real. There is no preaching or message or apologetic reason given. The characters are all in transit in their own lives and for their own reasons. And you're allowed a fascinating glimpse into their lives. If you enjoy great writing and performances and watching people in their nakedly honest moments, you should watch Drunks.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    reality and acting on the dark side of inebriation
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    MisterWhiplash
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/2/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Richard Lewis is one of my all-time favorite comedians. Mel Brooks once called him the Franz Kafka of comedy, and it's not far from the truth. The guy crafts such agonizing and harrowing comedy out of neuroses and problems and just common familial and relationship and whatever dread that it's staggering to watch (seeing him recently it was even more free-form and stream-of-conscious than ever, like Kurt Vonnegut and Woody Allen in a Bowery bar telling penis jokes). But he also was, in his past, troubled and on drugs and alcohol and went to a therapist for years and so on, and finally kicked it for good in the early 90s (he even wrote a sprawling, scatter-shot tell-all book called The Other Great Depression). So, in 1995, he took the lead part in Drunks, and if it may seem like his performance as Jim is so spot on and incredible it's more than likely because he knows this character, maybe all too well. I go on about Lewis so much just because he's the character most on the edge, the one falling off amongst all these other AA people meeting in a Manhattan Church, that it's impossible to take your eyes off him when he shows up. Jim, who speaks very reluctantly to the couple of dozen people at the AA meeting, lost his wife to a brain aneurysm two years after becoming sober from booze and junk. Then he slipped and went back and at the time of the meeting he hasn't had a drink in several months. Right after this long and heartfelt confession he leaves and wanders the streets, tempted at first and finally giving in to his insatiable craving to whiskey and beer. While he goes from either bar to his apartment or on the streets for drugs the film cuts back to the AA meeting where other people share their experiences, some fatally tragic like the blackout guy, or Dianne Wiest's doctor, or Faye Dunaway's upper-class mother, or Sam Rockwell's seemingly regular guy, or even Parker Posey as an ex-hippie chick. Hell, even Calista Flockheart gives a showstopper of a performance, which is an indicator of how on top of things the actors are here. It is, if as a real liability, written and performed like a play, and it's broken up as a series of monologues inter-cut with Jim in his downward spiral mode. The good thing about director Peter Cohn's approach is that even if a monologue falls kind of flat- I actually didn't care much for Spalding Gray who sort of mumbled through his character's turn as the guy who just showed up not knowing it was an AA meeting in the basement of the church- it can cut back to Richard Lewis who, in particular in one later scene at a bar, lays it down to such a heartbreaking beat that you almost wish he was in a Bergman movie or something - or, for that matter, one of Woody Allen's serious films. He's that amazing here, whether it's just how he is or if it's a "performance" or whatever. It's an actor's movie, and for that it works well. Just don't watch it for anything fancy or flashy; it's slightly obscure for that reason, since it doesn't have a real "star" attached.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Great Film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jorgedanieljdn
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/5/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I rented this and was very surprised by how good it was. The writing was so strong and the actors took those words and soared. There is not one false note. It felt like a CASSAVETTES film. Honesty on screen is what I look for in films. This film felt like real life. Real time. I could relate to these characters. Feel their pain. Their stories were compelling. I couldn't take my eyes of the screen My favorite performances were Lisa Gay Hamilton and the late Howard Rollins. They moved me to tears. I hope this movie gets to be seen by others who are struggling with addiction. The message finally got to me and it is interesting that it came to me in the guise of a movie. I am now going out and buying the DVD and the play that the film is based on. Thank you to the film makers.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Best substance abuse film ever!!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    paukenmeister
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/5/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I agree with several posters who say that people in recovery should watch this film. I also believe that every treatment facility should show this to the patients/clients based on the raw, gritty and realistic portrayals of addiction and addicts. However, I would be careful showing this movie in a substance abuse program at a men's prison due to the brief depiction of nude breasts. Some of the audience members *may* be distracted by the flash of flesh and forget the true message/intention of the movie. I would also not recommend this film if you're offended by "F-bombs". **SPOILER ALERT - sorta** There's a scene where Jim (Richard Lewis) is "sharing his grief" with a complete stranger at a bar - a stranger who's trying to be polite but wants to escape. Anyway, as I watched this scene with the "Closed-Captioning" activated, I noticed that each new caption on the screen had "f**k" (or a variation thereof) displaying. **END MILD SPOILER ALERT** Here's my synopsis of the film. **SPOILER ALERT #2** Jim, a recovering alcoholic/heroin addict is getting a room in a church ready for an AA meeting. His sponsor (George Martin) asks him to speak since the original speaker couldn't make it. Jim's reluctant to speak, but his sponsor presses him on. As Jim gives a half-hearted lead, we learn that he got sober simply to keep his wife happy. Since his wife has passed away, we can see that Jim's motivation to stay sober has gone as well. We see this as Jim wanders New York, getting wasted on booze. He's so desperate for companionship that he seeks a hooker - who only wants heroin. Jim goes to a park, buys heroin and steals a syringe from another junkie passed out in the park. Jim staggers back to his old bar and attempts to cook the heroin when he's thrown out. The film ends with a thoroughly wasted Jim at an AA meeting admitting that at the end of the day he'll have a full day of sobriety. I feel as though the film is trying to say that even if a recovering person relapses, they can always try their recovery again. **END SPOILER ALERT #2** "F-bombs" and nudity aside, I highly recommend this film to people in recovery and substance abuse counselors as well.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Shattering and depressing...as it should be
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Wayne Malin (wwaayynnee51@hotmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/3/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Jim (Richard Lewis) attends an AA meeting very worried about something. His sponsor encourages him to talk. He does...and immediately leaves. The rest of the movie involves him trying not to drink and it keeps going back to the meeting where we, one by one, hear each member say why they're there. I caught this at a small art cinema way back in 1997 and I never forgot it. It perfectly captures what an AA meeting is like and the stories related are harrowing. Quite a few well known actors play members: Sam Rockwell (still unknown at the time), Amanda Plummer, Parkey Posey, Dianne Wiest, Calista Flockheart and Faye Dunaway. Their considerable acting talents make the stories seem realistic and hard to shake off. There's no happy endings here. Grim and disturbing but realistic. Sometime the staginess shows through (you can tell this was based on a play) which is why I can only give it an 8. Still, it's well worth watching.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    If you know someone and care about them, this drama may help
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    somehope
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/3/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Drunks" deserves a better wide release than it received in the early 90's. It's not an easy film to digest, but if "Six Feet Under" can make us look at mortality, death, and grieving a little easier, than this film can help others see this disease a little more clearly. Hollywood has portrayed drunks as lovable figures, whether it be W.C. Fields' characters to "Barfly" (was Bukowski ever truly happy, though, or was Rourke's characterization just an acceptance of a barfly's life? Yet, we all know people who have gone from social drinker to lost in themselves. "Once Were Warriors." The great "The Lost Weekend." "Reqiuem for a Dream." "Nil by Mouth." "Under the Volcano." Leaving Las Vegas." "Less Than Zero." Thousands of lives have been damaged by alcoholism, and if you ever want to see a real tragedy, look at the people on these screens and, if you see yourself, you might be in real trouble. Back to the film. Basically, this a film of monologues, yet each contains more power than you might think when you hear the word "monologue." Lewis' performance is of course, great, as the reviews say, but please read his autobiography to discover how far he was from becoming Jim. It is a must-read for any addict, and while not an addict, it has helped me personally with some of my problems. Another great performances include the late Howard Rollins, of TV's "In the Heat of the Night" fame, who also was an addict at various points in his life. Splading Gray, a brilliant actor who committed suicide due to depression, also gives a brilliant performance as a man who wanders upon the meeting, and realizes he is one of them. A young Calista Flockhart and Faye Dunway find the right notes as addicts who need to sponsor each other. Even performances from Lisa Gay Hamilton (TV's "The Pratice")as an HIV positive woman, are damn strong. That's the key to the film. There may be no happy endings, but there is no preaching, and no sermonizing. Please, I urge you to seek this one out if you ever wonder what a real AA meeting is about, and get it more accessible to your friends who might need it to see it ... or yourself. It's not preachy, but it's a good drama. I'm off my soapbox: Please see this as drama. And remember if you need help, there is always someone there, don't give up. And hopefully, this film, will help you see that even the most self-destructive person can survive.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
 </reviews>
</filme>
