<filme>
 <id>
  1431
 </id>
 <imdburl>
  http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0130073
 </imdburl>
 <ano>
  1997
 </ano>
 <titulo>
  Legal Deceit
 </titulo>
 <rating>
  3.8
 </rating>
 <sinopse>
  Sydney Banks learns the hard way that being driven and educated is not the path to success. With the help of Todd Hunter her career takes off. Sydney gets pulled into corporate blackmail ... &nbsp;&raquo;
 </sinopse>
 <storyline>
  Sydney Banks learns the hard way that being driven and educated is not the path to success. With the help of Todd Hunter her career takes off. Sydney gets pulled into corporate blackmail and murder. With the help of boyfriend Derek, she begins her own deception.
 </storyline>
 <generos>
  <genero>
   Thriller
  </genero>
 </generos>
 <keywords>
  <keyword>
   independent film
  </keyword>
 </keywords>
 <diretores>
  <diretor>
   Monika Harris
  </diretor>
 </diretores>
 <escritores>
  <escritor>
   Monika Harris
  </escritor>
 </escritores>
 <atores>
  <ator>
   Lela Rochon
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Jeffrey Dean Morgan
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Phil Morris
  </ator>
 </atores>
 <reviews>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    It is deceit to call this a movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    (sallen7)
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/10/2001
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie was beyond cheese and camp. At least campy movies can be fun but this was utterly miserable. I spent one dollar at the local video rental place for this piece of junk. I would rather watch QVC. There is but a faint shred of goodness in this film and that is Lela Rochon. She is extremely beautiful in this film. The script just was not for her. She must have been in a bind to appear in this. I am thinking rent was due. Everything else was all cliche. A person who was just learning the English language could do better with the dialogue. Please, avoid this film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    It is so bad it is good.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Andre Stewart
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/8/2000
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The only reason I voted this movie so high was due to it's campy-ness. I don't know if camp was intended, but it was definitely there. Lela Rochon was a trooper. She played the part as strait as possible. Every other character was so exageratted until it was funny. I don't recommend this one unless you are a fan of bad "B" movies. If you are, you will definitly enjoy this one.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    This is a burner..
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    puma-15
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/2/2000
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This has to be one of the all-time poorest movies to ever waste film stock. At first you think it's going to be some kind of pyscho comedy, then it seems to get serious. after about 10 minutes you realize " It Sucks ". An example of how poor it really is, it was shown on Cinemax, Friday night at 5:00 and 8:00, Feb 4 2K, and today, Feb 16, it still doesn't even have 5 votes, good, bad or indifferent....
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Awful Movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    kmw55860
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/11/1999
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is the worst movie I have ever seen. The story was weak and the acting was terrible. This movie is about a lawyer (Rochon) who gets romantically involved with another lawyer who likes to blackmail clients. He eventually wants her to get involved in this scam too and when she threatens to go to the police he tries to kill her.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Probably the worst movie about law and lawyers ever made
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Michael Asimow (asimow@law.ucla.edu)
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/1/1999
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This film is of interest to fans who like films about law and lawyers because it can serve as the answer to the question "what is the worst movie about lawyers ever made?" The film takes every lawyer cliche and hauls it far over the top. The film is set in a law firm which is equivalent in manners and morals to a shark tank. It begins with a down-sizing in which the managing partner literally hauls an associate out of her office and throws her in the elevator. Another disgruntled associate shoots up the joint. Our heroine, an African American from Harvard Law School, with some semblance of ethics is trying to survive in this environment but can only do so if she can generate business. The plot degenerates into some nonsense which I gather has to do with digging up dirt on potential clients, then blackmailing them into retaining the lawyer. More and more people get shot, but most viewers, like myself, will have lost interest long before the film winds down. Everything about the film is amateurish; the acting is comical and the screenplay sounds like a middle school writing project.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
 </reviews>
</filme>
