<filme>
 <id>
  1434
 </id>
 <imdburl>
  http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0120122
 </imdburl>
 <ano>
  1997
 </ano>
 <titulo>
  Atirando em Peixes
 </titulo>
 <rating>
  6.4
 </rating>
 <sinopse>
  Two con artists' plan to steal enough for a house are twisted when a pretty girl enters the picture.
 </sinopse>
 <storyline>
  Dylan and Jez are con artists, Dylan is a charming American who's run from some characters in the states and Jez is an English techno nerd. During one of their scams selling a voice recognition computer they hire Georgie as a secretary for the job. The romantic triangle between Dylan, Jez and Georgie appears, but she is also not a secretary, but a student, and her marriage with rich Roger is upcoming.
 </storyline>
 <generos>
  <genero>
   Comedy
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Crime
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Romance
  </genero>
 </generos>
 <keywords>
  <keyword>
   scam
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   secretary
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   con artist
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   money
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   orphan
  </keyword>
 </keywords>
 <diretores>
  <diretor>
   Stefan Schwartz
  </diretor>
 </diretores>
 <escritores>
  <escritor>
   Stefan Schwartz
  </escritor>
  <escritor>
   Richard Holmes
  </escritor>
 </escritores>
 <atores>
  <ator>
   Dan Futterman
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Stuart Townsend
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Kate Beckinsale
  </ator>
 </atores>
 <reviews>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Very light, surreal British three-way romcom
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Framescourer
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/11/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A comedy before it's time - it's all about sustainable resources! This is a brave little film, having neither big names nor obvious genre. The three principals are the latterday highwaymen Dylan and Jez, pulling scams on individuals and corporations alike to make a living. Their plans are big - they need a vast sum in order to move from their (ivory) tower to townhouse and hire - in typically unconventional fashion - a secretary to help them organise their income. Kate Beckinsdale's Georgie is far too lovely a PA to allow things to continue between the friends as smoothly as it had and soon they are on the back foot with only the fresh object of their contention to bail them out. Stuart Townsend and Dan Futterman (especially the latter) are good value and engage with the nuttiness of their ruses to the extent that you just go along with it all. I like Beckinsdale in this - acting fresh fair and occasionally feisty is nothing to be ashamed-and-run-off-to-Hollywood about. Perfect for a Bank Holiday weekend. 4/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Never Mind the Fish, Shoot ME!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tonstant viewer
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/5/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This film has a promising First Act. After around 20 minutes, you begin to suspect that things will go wrong. Then they get much worse than that, they get terrible. The Third Act is in slow-motion, with nine too many plot twists and no pace at all. By this time you are clawing the stuffing out of your couch. I hate these people for having wasted a night out of my life. Dan Futterman, a kind of low-rent baby Richard Gere, plays the American the English love to hate - smug, glib, an updated version of "over-paid, over-sexed and over here." Stuart Townsend plays a shambling English wonk, good hearted and socially undeveloped. Hey, there's something new in films! Kate Beckinsale's charm is unable to salvage the proceedings, and she projects none of the intelligence one would hope to find in a budding doctor. Totally implausible. And there are some very good character actors who are completely wasted in unrewarding roles. I suspect the script was written using one of those screen writing software programs, as the characters, twists and paradoxes are all arbitrary, every single last blinking one of them. Including the blow-up dolls. If the Surgeon General's Office could place a Health Warning on this film, the world would be a safer place. I can't imagine where the positive reviews for this film originate - probably in a misplaced sense of charity. As Jay Sherman, of "The Critic," would say, "IT STINKS!"
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Heart-warming and irrepressibly cheery
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    fes23
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/5/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Call me hopelessly sentimental but I actually find this film very touching! Once you totally suspend your disbelief (this is a film, it's kind of expected...) Jez and Dylan really sell the orphans concept. Here you have two lonely, needy, love-starved guys who through hard work, self-denial and sheer determination win themselves a family and a home. How can your heart not melt? The acting by the male leads is strong enough (mostly - the 'why do I have to get so technical?' scene falters a bit) to make you invest emotionally in Dylan and Jez' quest despite the fact that - all soft-heartedness aside - they are two lying, selfish, close to morally bankrupt con-merchants. By the end of the film you'll be cheering them on. What am I saying? By five minutes in you'll be cheering them on! Yes, it's full of clich&eacute;s. Yes, it's pretty predictable. Yes, it's soppy. But this film proves that you can get away with anything if you have lovable characters and a fantastic soundtrack (see also Ocean's 11). Never fails to cheer me up - I'd recommend it to anyone not entirely hard-boiled.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I don't care, I like it!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bernie-122
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/12/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    There's something wrong about dropping an American con-artist into London, but somehow here it works. There are lots of potential reasons not to like this film, but most of them don't seem to really matter. It just works, anyway. Maybe it's because this was the first time I ever saw Kate Beckinsale, and I was just stunned. Anyway, I was hugely amused when I heard that there was a boycott organized against this film by some people who thought it was going to be about someone shooting at fish (bang, bang). Poor fishies. No, of course, it's no such thing. If you haven't seen this, then I can pretty much guarantee that you will not waste your time if the opportunity comes up.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Wonderful
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Dynesh Vijayaraghavan
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/6/2005
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Normally when it comes to voting for movies on the IMDb, I'm quite liberal. I don't set very high standards for movies. I always tend to rate films based on how much I enjoy them and this means that most of the time I always rate films highly cos I try and find something good in every film I see. I saw this film when I was vacationing in England. BBC One actually transmitted this at 11 PM, since they believed that The Peacemaker was a film more deserving of the 9:00 slot. Unlike the Peacemaker, Shooting Fish is a film that almost anybody would enjoy, unless he/she was the kind of person who found simple effective storytelling a turnoff. Everything about this movie seems in perfect harmony. The chemistry between Dan Futterman and Stuart Townsend is perfect, word for word. And Kate Beckinsale is a perfect third piece to the puzzle; When the conversations in the movie occur, you never get the feeling you're watching a contrived conversation written by someone else, you get the feeling you're watching real life unfold. That's a hallmark of a good scriptwriter and the people who wrote this deserve credit for the story. As for the story itself, it never lets itself become too complicated and lends itself to a lot of funny situations. Fast-talking Dylan and socially naive Jez (Futterman and Townsend) are two con men trying to raise money to build their dream house. They end up enlisting Georgina's (short-haired Kate Beckinsale in a beautiful role from her pre-Hollywood Glamourpuss days) help on a particular scam. Soon she discovers what they're up to and the story unfolds from there, with both Dylan and Jez seemingly falling for Georgie. Here again, the movie doesn't nosedive and morph into a conventional love story; rather, the romance builds in a backdrop to the main story and culminates in a heartwarming finale. As for Dan and Jez, some of their schemes may not be very believable and yet you cant help but be amused by the way they go about implementing them. This film is a good reason why small budget comedy romances are popular - simply put, they work. On every level. Watching this film gives you the same kind of feeling as watching While you were Sleeping, for example. For the sheer sweetness of the film and for Kate Beckinsale's performance, I'd give it 7 on 10.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Stefan Schwartz Shoots Himself In The Foot
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Theo Robertson
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/6/2005
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    As many people have mentioned on this page SHOOTING FISH had a lot of potential as it centered around loud mouthed American Dylan and geeky Englishman Jez who are a couple of scam artists . We British have a sort of sneaking respect for these type of con artists ( As long as they con other people of course ) and there's a lot of room for explosive comedy potential as we see Dylan revealing a new type of computer word processor that has a volcabury of hundreds of thousands of words in its database so I sat back ready to enjoy this British comedy but halfway through I was bored senseless It's very obvious what went wrong . Director and co-writer Stefan Schwartz has decided that a laddish comedy will only appeal to 50% of a potential audience so has made a movie that will also appeal to fans of soppy romance by introducing a love triangle featuring Dylan , Jez and Georgie . Unfortunately SHOOTING FISH will ONLY appeal to fans of soppy romance which probably makes up 3% of the audience . This actually seems to be a problem with Schwartz as his future films like THE ABDUCTION CLUB and THE BEST MAN also feature soppy romance in abundance. Fair enough if you want to make a gooey rom com then go ahead but make sure the central premise allows it . Watching very patchy funny scenes like " LESLEY IS DEAD MAN " convinced me that this would have worked without the lovey dovey stuff which seems to have been shoehorned in and it's this that brings the film down Interesting trivia point about Stefan Schwartz : He once had a walk on part in Battlefield , my least favourite DOCTOR WHO story
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Typical English boredom
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    sveknu
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/5/2005
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I think I have to stop watching English movies. Apart from the James Bond-movies and a small number of comedies, they are usually pure crap. This movie is definitely one of those. The first ten minutes starts out OK, and the movie has potential at this time. Sadly, it doesn't continue in this style at all. The story is about two swindlers who tries to earn a lot of money by tricking people in different ways. None of the ways they do this are funny at all. It's supposed to be a comedy, but personally I didn't laugh one single time during the movie. In addition, the story really sucks, especially because they threw a bit of romance on top of it. Alos, the ending is very bad, and it was just what I had expected because movies like this leave you with no surprises. If you want to see a movie about swindlers, watch "Dirty Rotten Scoundrels" instead.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Wonderful
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    kellyjoehayes
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/7/2004
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    After reading some of the comments about this film I just had to express my view. This is one of my favorite films. I admit for some it may be an acquired taste. You'll either love it or hate it. I love it and have recommended it to many of my friends. I lent the video to a friend and she loved it so much she kept showing it to her friends and family and I never got it back. I ended up buying a second copy. Maybe not the best of movies but certainly one you may need to see a couple of times to get the "whole" picture. (and little things like the wallpaper in the guys place). I think the idea and premise is very imaginative. If you like this film you may want to check out Cold Comfort Farm. Another quirky "British humor" movie with Kate Beckinsale.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Ealing-type comedy
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    didi-5
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/6/2004
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie by Stefan Schwartz (co-written with Richard Holmes) thinks it is cleverer than it actually is, and comes out as an odd hybrid of crime caper and romance. Two conmen - the charmless Dan Futterman as American Dylan, and geeky Stuart Townsend as Jez - have long-standing dreams of making lots of cash by any means to fund their very own stately home. Posh totty Kate Beckinsale as Georgie (a doctor-in-training with secretarial skills) joins them as the beauty and brains of the team and causes havoc between them. Involved in this semi-engaging brew are voice recognition computer systems, cremation, loft insulation, blow-up dolls, light sabres, a tatty old racehorse, &pound;50 bills, and the music of Burt Bacharach. Glimpsed in the cast are Phyllis Logan, Annette Crosbie, Peter Capaldi, Jane Lapotaire, Nickolas Grace, Nicholas Woodeson, and (in a small but wickedly funny role as Georgie's boyfriend) Dominic Mafham. 'Shooting Fish' is fairly enjoyable but tends to shoot itself down quite early on, without much chance of recovering. Does it know what it is supposed to be? An idea with potential and some laughs, but this movie doesn't know which way to jump.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A really bad film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    lsjh2
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/6/2004
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I remembered this film being popular when it came out, and after seeing it for the first time yesterday, I couldn't believe how bad and embarrassingly unfunny the script and story were. This film falls into the trap which other British comedies like Sliding Doors have made. It panders to outmoded unrealistic stereotypes about what Britain is like - a quaint world of red telephone boxes and bumbling, nervous Hugh Grant-like men where everyone is white and middle or upper class and speak with plums in their mouths (posh accents). This is absolute rubbish! Where's the vibrant edginess and hectic buzz of London with its multi-culturalism and ethnic diversity, and why do British film makers have to perpetuate these stale myths? I personally find it sad that British film makers think that making these kinds of patronising films is the only way to appeal to the foreign market.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Very light, surreal British three-way romcom
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Framescourer
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/11/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A comedy before it's time - it's all about sustainable resources! This is a brave little film, having neither big names nor obvious genre. The three principals are the latterday highwaymen Dylan and Jez, pulling scams on individuals and corporations alike to make a living. Their plans are big - they need a vast sum in order to move from their (ivory) tower to townhouse and hire - in typically unconventional fashion - a secretary to help them organise their income. Kate Beckinsdale's Georgie is far too lovely a PA to allow things to continue between the friends as smoothly as it had and soon they are on the back foot with only the fresh object of their contention to bail them out. Stuart Townsend and Dan Futterman (especially the latter) are good value and engage with the nuttiness of their ruses to the extent that you just go along with it all. I like Beckinsdale in this - acting fresh fair and occasionally feisty is nothing to be ashamed-and-run-off-to-Hollywood about. Perfect for a Bank Holiday weekend. 4/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Never Mind the Fish, Shoot ME!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tonstant viewer
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/5/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This film has a promising First Act. After around 20 minutes, you begin to suspect that things will go wrong. Then they get much worse than that, they get terrible. The Third Act is in slow-motion, with nine too many plot twists and no pace at all. By this time you are clawing the stuffing out of your couch. I hate these people for having wasted a night out of my life. Dan Futterman, a kind of low-rent baby Richard Gere, plays the American the English love to hate - smug, glib, an updated version of "over-paid, over-sexed and over here." Stuart Townsend plays a shambling English wonk, good hearted and socially undeveloped. Hey, there's something new in films! Kate Beckinsale's charm is unable to salvage the proceedings, and she projects none of the intelligence one would hope to find in a budding doctor. Totally implausible. And there are some very good character actors who are completely wasted in unrewarding roles. I suspect the script was written using one of those screen writing software programs, as the characters, twists and paradoxes are all arbitrary, every single last blinking one of them. Including the blow-up dolls. If the Surgeon General's Office could place a Health Warning on this film, the world would be a safer place. I can't imagine where the positive reviews for this film originate - probably in a misplaced sense of charity. As Jay Sherman, of "The Critic," would say, "IT STINKS!"
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Heart-warming and irrepressibly cheery
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    fes23
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/5/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Call me hopelessly sentimental but I actually find this film very touching! Once you totally suspend your disbelief (this is a film, it's kind of expected...) Jez and Dylan really sell the orphans concept. Here you have two lonely, needy, love-starved guys who through hard work, self-denial and sheer determination win themselves a family and a home. How can your heart not melt? The acting by the male leads is strong enough (mostly - the 'why do I have to get so technical?' scene falters a bit) to make you invest emotionally in Dylan and Jez' quest despite the fact that - all soft-heartedness aside - they are two lying, selfish, close to morally bankrupt con-merchants. By the end of the film you'll be cheering them on. What am I saying? By five minutes in you'll be cheering them on! Yes, it's full of clich&eacute;s. Yes, it's pretty predictable. Yes, it's soppy. But this film proves that you can get away with anything if you have lovable characters and a fantastic soundtrack (see also Ocean's 11). Never fails to cheer me up - I'd recommend it to anyone not entirely hard-boiled.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I don't care, I like it!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bernie-122
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/12/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    There's something wrong about dropping an American con-artist into London, but somehow here it works. There are lots of potential reasons not to like this film, but most of them don't seem to really matter. It just works, anyway. Maybe it's because this was the first time I ever saw Kate Beckinsale, and I was just stunned. Anyway, I was hugely amused when I heard that there was a boycott organized against this film by some people who thought it was going to be about someone shooting at fish (bang, bang). Poor fishies. No, of course, it's no such thing. If you haven't seen this, then I can pretty much guarantee that you will not waste your time if the opportunity comes up.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Wonderful
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Dynesh Vijayaraghavan
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/6/2005
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Normally when it comes to voting for movies on the IMDb, I'm quite liberal. I don't set very high standards for movies. I always tend to rate films based on how much I enjoy them and this means that most of the time I always rate films highly cos I try and find something good in every film I see. I saw this film when I was vacationing in England. BBC One actually transmitted this at 11 PM, since they believed that The Peacemaker was a film more deserving of the 9:00 slot. Unlike the Peacemaker, Shooting Fish is a film that almost anybody would enjoy, unless he/she was the kind of person who found simple effective storytelling a turnoff. Everything about this movie seems in perfect harmony. The chemistry between Dan Futterman and Stuart Townsend is perfect, word for word. And Kate Beckinsale is a perfect third piece to the puzzle; When the conversations in the movie occur, you never get the feeling you're watching a contrived conversation written by someone else, you get the feeling you're watching real life unfold. That's a hallmark of a good scriptwriter and the people who wrote this deserve credit for the story. As for the story itself, it never lets itself become too complicated and lends itself to a lot of funny situations. Fast-talking Dylan and socially naive Jez (Futterman and Townsend) are two con men trying to raise money to build their dream house. They end up enlisting Georgina's (short-haired Kate Beckinsale in a beautiful role from her pre-Hollywood Glamourpuss days) help on a particular scam. Soon she discovers what they're up to and the story unfolds from there, with both Dylan and Jez seemingly falling for Georgie. Here again, the movie doesn't nosedive and morph into a conventional love story; rather, the romance builds in a backdrop to the main story and culminates in a heartwarming finale. As for Dan and Jez, some of their schemes may not be very believable and yet you cant help but be amused by the way they go about implementing them. This film is a good reason why small budget comedy romances are popular - simply put, they work. On every level. Watching this film gives you the same kind of feeling as watching While you were Sleeping, for example. For the sheer sweetness of the film and for Kate Beckinsale's performance, I'd give it 7 on 10.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Stefan Schwartz Shoots Himself In The Foot
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Theo Robertson
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/6/2005
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    As many people have mentioned on this page SHOOTING FISH had a lot of potential as it centered around loud mouthed American Dylan and geeky Englishman Jez who are a couple of scam artists . We British have a sort of sneaking respect for these type of con artists ( As long as they con other people of course ) and there's a lot of room for explosive comedy potential as we see Dylan revealing a new type of computer word processor that has a volcabury of hundreds of thousands of words in its database so I sat back ready to enjoy this British comedy but halfway through I was bored senseless It's very obvious what went wrong . Director and co-writer Stefan Schwartz has decided that a laddish comedy will only appeal to 50% of a potential audience so has made a movie that will also appeal to fans of soppy romance by introducing a love triangle featuring Dylan , Jez and Georgie . Unfortunately SHOOTING FISH will ONLY appeal to fans of soppy romance which probably makes up 3% of the audience . This actually seems to be a problem with Schwartz as his future films like THE ABDUCTION CLUB and THE BEST MAN also feature soppy romance in abundance. Fair enough if you want to make a gooey rom com then go ahead but make sure the central premise allows it . Watching very patchy funny scenes like " LESLEY IS DEAD MAN " convinced me that this would have worked without the lovey dovey stuff which seems to have been shoehorned in and it's this that brings the film down Interesting trivia point about Stefan Schwartz : He once had a walk on part in Battlefield , my least favourite DOCTOR WHO story
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Typical English boredom
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    sveknu
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/5/2005
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I think I have to stop watching English movies. Apart from the James Bond-movies and a small number of comedies, they are usually pure crap. This movie is definitely one of those. The first ten minutes starts out OK, and the movie has potential at this time. Sadly, it doesn't continue in this style at all. The story is about two swindlers who tries to earn a lot of money by tricking people in different ways. None of the ways they do this are funny at all. It's supposed to be a comedy, but personally I didn't laugh one single time during the movie. In addition, the story really sucks, especially because they threw a bit of romance on top of it. Alos, the ending is very bad, and it was just what I had expected because movies like this leave you with no surprises. If you want to see a movie about swindlers, watch "Dirty Rotten Scoundrels" instead.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Wonderful
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    kellyjoehayes
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/7/2004
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    After reading some of the comments about this film I just had to express my view. This is one of my favorite films. I admit for some it may be an acquired taste. You'll either love it or hate it. I love it and have recommended it to many of my friends. I lent the video to a friend and she loved it so much she kept showing it to her friends and family and I never got it back. I ended up buying a second copy. Maybe not the best of movies but certainly one you may need to see a couple of times to get the "whole" picture. (and little things like the wallpaper in the guys place). I think the idea and premise is very imaginative. If you like this film you may want to check out Cold Comfort Farm. Another quirky "British humor" movie with Kate Beckinsale.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Ealing-type comedy
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    didi-5
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/6/2004
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie by Stefan Schwartz (co-written with Richard Holmes) thinks it is cleverer than it actually is, and comes out as an odd hybrid of crime caper and romance. Two conmen - the charmless Dan Futterman as American Dylan, and geeky Stuart Townsend as Jez - have long-standing dreams of making lots of cash by any means to fund their very own stately home. Posh totty Kate Beckinsale as Georgie (a doctor-in-training with secretarial skills) joins them as the beauty and brains of the team and causes havoc between them. Involved in this semi-engaging brew are voice recognition computer systems, cremation, loft insulation, blow-up dolls, light sabres, a tatty old racehorse, &pound;50 bills, and the music of Burt Bacharach. Glimpsed in the cast are Phyllis Logan, Annette Crosbie, Peter Capaldi, Jane Lapotaire, Nickolas Grace, Nicholas Woodeson, and (in a small but wickedly funny role as Georgie's boyfriend) Dominic Mafham. 'Shooting Fish' is fairly enjoyable but tends to shoot itself down quite early on, without much chance of recovering. Does it know what it is supposed to be? An idea with potential and some laughs, but this movie doesn't know which way to jump.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A really bad film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    lsjh2
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/6/2004
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I remembered this film being popular when it came out, and after seeing it for the first time yesterday, I couldn't believe how bad and embarrassingly unfunny the script and story were. This film falls into the trap which other British comedies like Sliding Doors have made. It panders to outmoded unrealistic stereotypes about what Britain is like - a quaint world of red telephone boxes and bumbling, nervous Hugh Grant-like men where everyone is white and middle or upper class and speak with plums in their mouths (posh accents). This is absolute rubbish! Where's the vibrant edginess and hectic buzz of London with its multi-culturalism and ethnic diversity, and why do British film makers have to perpetuate these stale myths? I personally find it sad that British film makers think that making these kinds of patronising films is the only way to appeal to the foreign market.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Very light, surreal British three-way romcom
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Framescourer
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/11/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A comedy before it's time - it's all about sustainable resources! This is a brave little film, having neither big names nor obvious genre. The three principals are the latterday highwaymen Dylan and Jez, pulling scams on individuals and corporations alike to make a living. Their plans are big - they need a vast sum in order to move from their (ivory) tower to townhouse and hire - in typically unconventional fashion - a secretary to help them organise their income. Kate Beckinsdale's Georgie is far too lovely a PA to allow things to continue between the friends as smoothly as it had and soon they are on the back foot with only the fresh object of their contention to bail them out. Stuart Townsend and Dan Futterman (especially the latter) are good value and engage with the nuttiness of their ruses to the extent that you just go along with it all. I like Beckinsdale in this - acting fresh fair and occasionally feisty is nothing to be ashamed-and-run-off-to-Hollywood about. Perfect for a Bank Holiday weekend. 4/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Never Mind the Fish, Shoot ME!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tonstant viewer
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/5/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This film has a promising First Act. After around 20 minutes, you begin to suspect that things will go wrong. Then they get much worse than that, they get terrible. The Third Act is in slow-motion, with nine too many plot twists and no pace at all. By this time you are clawing the stuffing out of your couch. I hate these people for having wasted a night out of my life. Dan Futterman, a kind of low-rent baby Richard Gere, plays the American the English love to hate - smug, glib, an updated version of "over-paid, over-sexed and over here." Stuart Townsend plays a shambling English wonk, good hearted and socially undeveloped. Hey, there's something new in films! Kate Beckinsale's charm is unable to salvage the proceedings, and she projects none of the intelligence one would hope to find in a budding doctor. Totally implausible. And there are some very good character actors who are completely wasted in unrewarding roles. I suspect the script was written using one of those screen writing software programs, as the characters, twists and paradoxes are all arbitrary, every single last blinking one of them. Including the blow-up dolls. If the Surgeon General's Office could place a Health Warning on this film, the world would be a safer place. I can't imagine where the positive reviews for this film originate - probably in a misplaced sense of charity. As Jay Sherman, of "The Critic," would say, "IT STINKS!"
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Heart-warming and irrepressibly cheery
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    fes23
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/5/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Call me hopelessly sentimental but I actually find this film very touching! Once you totally suspend your disbelief (this is a film, it's kind of expected...) Jez and Dylan really sell the orphans concept. Here you have two lonely, needy, love-starved guys who through hard work, self-denial and sheer determination win themselves a family and a home. How can your heart not melt? The acting by the male leads is strong enough (mostly - the 'why do I have to get so technical?' scene falters a bit) to make you invest emotionally in Dylan and Jez' quest despite the fact that - all soft-heartedness aside - they are two lying, selfish, close to morally bankrupt con-merchants. By the end of the film you'll be cheering them on. What am I saying? By five minutes in you'll be cheering them on! Yes, it's full of clich&eacute;s. Yes, it's pretty predictable. Yes, it's soppy. But this film proves that you can get away with anything if you have lovable characters and a fantastic soundtrack (see also Ocean's 11). Never fails to cheer me up - I'd recommend it to anyone not entirely hard-boiled.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I don't care, I like it!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bernie-122
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/12/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    There's something wrong about dropping an American con-artist into London, but somehow here it works. There are lots of potential reasons not to like this film, but most of them don't seem to really matter. It just works, anyway. Maybe it's because this was the first time I ever saw Kate Beckinsale, and I was just stunned. Anyway, I was hugely amused when I heard that there was a boycott organized against this film by some people who thought it was going to be about someone shooting at fish (bang, bang). Poor fishies. No, of course, it's no such thing. If you haven't seen this, then I can pretty much guarantee that you will not waste your time if the opportunity comes up.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Wonderful
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Dynesh Vijayaraghavan
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/6/2005
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Normally when it comes to voting for movies on the IMDb, I'm quite liberal. I don't set very high standards for movies. I always tend to rate films based on how much I enjoy them and this means that most of the time I always rate films highly cos I try and find something good in every film I see. I saw this film when I was vacationing in England. BBC One actually transmitted this at 11 PM, since they believed that The Peacemaker was a film more deserving of the 9:00 slot. Unlike the Peacemaker, Shooting Fish is a film that almost anybody would enjoy, unless he/she was the kind of person who found simple effective storytelling a turnoff. Everything about this movie seems in perfect harmony. The chemistry between Dan Futterman and Stuart Townsend is perfect, word for word. And Kate Beckinsale is a perfect third piece to the puzzle; When the conversations in the movie occur, you never get the feeling you're watching a contrived conversation written by someone else, you get the feeling you're watching real life unfold. That's a hallmark of a good scriptwriter and the people who wrote this deserve credit for the story. As for the story itself, it never lets itself become too complicated and lends itself to a lot of funny situations. Fast-talking Dylan and socially naive Jez (Futterman and Townsend) are two con men trying to raise money to build their dream house. They end up enlisting Georgina's (short-haired Kate Beckinsale in a beautiful role from her pre-Hollywood Glamourpuss days) help on a particular scam. Soon she discovers what they're up to and the story unfolds from there, with both Dylan and Jez seemingly falling for Georgie. Here again, the movie doesn't nosedive and morph into a conventional love story; rather, the romance builds in a backdrop to the main story and culminates in a heartwarming finale. As for Dan and Jez, some of their schemes may not be very believable and yet you cant help but be amused by the way they go about implementing them. This film is a good reason why small budget comedy romances are popular - simply put, they work. On every level. Watching this film gives you the same kind of feeling as watching While you were Sleeping, for example. For the sheer sweetness of the film and for Kate Beckinsale's performance, I'd give it 7 on 10.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Stefan Schwartz Shoots Himself In The Foot
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Theo Robertson
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/6/2005
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    As many people have mentioned on this page SHOOTING FISH had a lot of potential as it centered around loud mouthed American Dylan and geeky Englishman Jez who are a couple of scam artists . We British have a sort of sneaking respect for these type of con artists ( As long as they con other people of course ) and there's a lot of room for explosive comedy potential as we see Dylan revealing a new type of computer word processor that has a volcabury of hundreds of thousands of words in its database so I sat back ready to enjoy this British comedy but halfway through I was bored senseless It's very obvious what went wrong . Director and co-writer Stefan Schwartz has decided that a laddish comedy will only appeal to 50% of a potential audience so has made a movie that will also appeal to fans of soppy romance by introducing a love triangle featuring Dylan , Jez and Georgie . Unfortunately SHOOTING FISH will ONLY appeal to fans of soppy romance which probably makes up 3% of the audience . This actually seems to be a problem with Schwartz as his future films like THE ABDUCTION CLUB and THE BEST MAN also feature soppy romance in abundance. Fair enough if you want to make a gooey rom com then go ahead but make sure the central premise allows it . Watching very patchy funny scenes like " LESLEY IS DEAD MAN " convinced me that this would have worked without the lovey dovey stuff which seems to have been shoehorned in and it's this that brings the film down Interesting trivia point about Stefan Schwartz : He once had a walk on part in Battlefield , my least favourite DOCTOR WHO story
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Typical English boredom
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    sveknu
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/5/2005
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I think I have to stop watching English movies. Apart from the James Bond-movies and a small number of comedies, they are usually pure crap. This movie is definitely one of those. The first ten minutes starts out OK, and the movie has potential at this time. Sadly, it doesn't continue in this style at all. The story is about two swindlers who tries to earn a lot of money by tricking people in different ways. None of the ways they do this are funny at all. It's supposed to be a comedy, but personally I didn't laugh one single time during the movie. In addition, the story really sucks, especially because they threw a bit of romance on top of it. Alos, the ending is very bad, and it was just what I had expected because movies like this leave you with no surprises. If you want to see a movie about swindlers, watch "Dirty Rotten Scoundrels" instead.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Wonderful
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    kellyjoehayes
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/7/2004
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    After reading some of the comments about this film I just had to express my view. This is one of my favorite films. I admit for some it may be an acquired taste. You'll either love it or hate it. I love it and have recommended it to many of my friends. I lent the video to a friend and she loved it so much she kept showing it to her friends and family and I never got it back. I ended up buying a second copy. Maybe not the best of movies but certainly one you may need to see a couple of times to get the "whole" picture. (and little things like the wallpaper in the guys place). I think the idea and premise is very imaginative. If you like this film you may want to check out Cold Comfort Farm. Another quirky "British humor" movie with Kate Beckinsale.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Ealing-type comedy
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    didi-5
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/6/2004
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie by Stefan Schwartz (co-written with Richard Holmes) thinks it is cleverer than it actually is, and comes out as an odd hybrid of crime caper and romance. Two conmen - the charmless Dan Futterman as American Dylan, and geeky Stuart Townsend as Jez - have long-standing dreams of making lots of cash by any means to fund their very own stately home. Posh totty Kate Beckinsale as Georgie (a doctor-in-training with secretarial skills) joins them as the beauty and brains of the team and causes havoc between them. Involved in this semi-engaging brew are voice recognition computer systems, cremation, loft insulation, blow-up dolls, light sabres, a tatty old racehorse, &pound;50 bills, and the music of Burt Bacharach. Glimpsed in the cast are Phyllis Logan, Annette Crosbie, Peter Capaldi, Jane Lapotaire, Nickolas Grace, Nicholas Woodeson, and (in a small but wickedly funny role as Georgie's boyfriend) Dominic Mafham. 'Shooting Fish' is fairly enjoyable but tends to shoot itself down quite early on, without much chance of recovering. Does it know what it is supposed to be? An idea with potential and some laughs, but this movie doesn't know which way to jump.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A really bad film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    lsjh2
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/6/2004
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I remembered this film being popular when it came out, and after seeing it for the first time yesterday, I couldn't believe how bad and embarrassingly unfunny the script and story were. This film falls into the trap which other British comedies like Sliding Doors have made. It panders to outmoded unrealistic stereotypes about what Britain is like - a quaint world of red telephone boxes and bumbling, nervous Hugh Grant-like men where everyone is white and middle or upper class and speak with plums in their mouths (posh accents). This is absolute rubbish! Where's the vibrant edginess and hectic buzz of London with its multi-culturalism and ethnic diversity, and why do British film makers have to perpetuate these stale myths? I personally find it sad that British film makers think that making these kinds of patronising films is the only way to appeal to the foreign market.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Very light, surreal British three-way romcom
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Framescourer
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/11/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A comedy before it's time - it's all about sustainable resources! This is a brave little film, having neither big names nor obvious genre. The three principals are the latterday highwaymen Dylan and Jez, pulling scams on individuals and corporations alike to make a living. Their plans are big - they need a vast sum in order to move from their (ivory) tower to townhouse and hire - in typically unconventional fashion - a secretary to help them organise their income. Kate Beckinsdale's Georgie is far too lovely a PA to allow things to continue between the friends as smoothly as it had and soon they are on the back foot with only the fresh object of their contention to bail them out. Stuart Townsend and Dan Futterman (especially the latter) are good value and engage with the nuttiness of their ruses to the extent that you just go along with it all. I like Beckinsdale in this - acting fresh fair and occasionally feisty is nothing to be ashamed-and-run-off-to-Hollywood about. Perfect for a Bank Holiday weekend. 4/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Never Mind the Fish, Shoot ME!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tonstant viewer
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/5/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This film has a promising First Act. After around 20 minutes, you begin to suspect that things will go wrong. Then they get much worse than that, they get terrible. The Third Act is in slow-motion, with nine too many plot twists and no pace at all. By this time you are clawing the stuffing out of your couch. I hate these people for having wasted a night out of my life. Dan Futterman, a kind of low-rent baby Richard Gere, plays the American the English love to hate - smug, glib, an updated version of "over-paid, over-sexed and over here." Stuart Townsend plays a shambling English wonk, good hearted and socially undeveloped. Hey, there's something new in films! Kate Beckinsale's charm is unable to salvage the proceedings, and she projects none of the intelligence one would hope to find in a budding doctor. Totally implausible. And there are some very good character actors who are completely wasted in unrewarding roles. I suspect the script was written using one of those screen writing software programs, as the characters, twists and paradoxes are all arbitrary, every single last blinking one of them. Including the blow-up dolls. If the Surgeon General's Office could place a Health Warning on this film, the world would be a safer place. I can't imagine where the positive reviews for this film originate - probably in a misplaced sense of charity. As Jay Sherman, of "The Critic," would say, "IT STINKS!"
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Heart-warming and irrepressibly cheery
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    fes23
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/5/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Call me hopelessly sentimental but I actually find this film very touching! Once you totally suspend your disbelief (this is a film, it's kind of expected...) Jez and Dylan really sell the orphans concept. Here you have two lonely, needy, love-starved guys who through hard work, self-denial and sheer determination win themselves a family and a home. How can your heart not melt? The acting by the male leads is strong enough (mostly - the 'why do I have to get so technical?' scene falters a bit) to make you invest emotionally in Dylan and Jez' quest despite the fact that - all soft-heartedness aside - they are two lying, selfish, close to morally bankrupt con-merchants. By the end of the film you'll be cheering them on. What am I saying? By five minutes in you'll be cheering them on! Yes, it's full of clich&eacute;s. Yes, it's pretty predictable. Yes, it's soppy. But this film proves that you can get away with anything if you have lovable characters and a fantastic soundtrack (see also Ocean's 11). Never fails to cheer me up - I'd recommend it to anyone not entirely hard-boiled.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I don't care, I like it!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bernie-122
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/12/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    There's something wrong about dropping an American con-artist into London, but somehow here it works. There are lots of potential reasons not to like this film, but most of them don't seem to really matter. It just works, anyway. Maybe it's because this was the first time I ever saw Kate Beckinsale, and I was just stunned. Anyway, I was hugely amused when I heard that there was a boycott organized against this film by some people who thought it was going to be about someone shooting at fish (bang, bang). Poor fishies. No, of course, it's no such thing. If you haven't seen this, then I can pretty much guarantee that you will not waste your time if the opportunity comes up.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Wonderful
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Dynesh Vijayaraghavan
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/6/2005
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Normally when it comes to voting for movies on the IMDb, I'm quite liberal. I don't set very high standards for movies. I always tend to rate films based on how much I enjoy them and this means that most of the time I always rate films highly cos I try and find something good in every film I see. I saw this film when I was vacationing in England. BBC One actually transmitted this at 11 PM, since they believed that The Peacemaker was a film more deserving of the 9:00 slot. Unlike the Peacemaker, Shooting Fish is a film that almost anybody would enjoy, unless he/she was the kind of person who found simple effective storytelling a turnoff. Everything about this movie seems in perfect harmony. The chemistry between Dan Futterman and Stuart Townsend is perfect, word for word. And Kate Beckinsale is a perfect third piece to the puzzle; When the conversations in the movie occur, you never get the feeling you're watching a contrived conversation written by someone else, you get the feeling you're watching real life unfold. That's a hallmark of a good scriptwriter and the people who wrote this deserve credit for the story. As for the story itself, it never lets itself become too complicated and lends itself to a lot of funny situations. Fast-talking Dylan and socially naive Jez (Futterman and Townsend) are two con men trying to raise money to build their dream house. They end up enlisting Georgina's (short-haired Kate Beckinsale in a beautiful role from her pre-Hollywood Glamourpuss days) help on a particular scam. Soon she discovers what they're up to and the story unfolds from there, with both Dylan and Jez seemingly falling for Georgie. Here again, the movie doesn't nosedive and morph into a conventional love story; rather, the romance builds in a backdrop to the main story and culminates in a heartwarming finale. As for Dan and Jez, some of their schemes may not be very believable and yet you cant help but be amused by the way they go about implementing them. This film is a good reason why small budget comedy romances are popular - simply put, they work. On every level. Watching this film gives you the same kind of feeling as watching While you were Sleeping, for example. For the sheer sweetness of the film and for Kate Beckinsale's performance, I'd give it 7 on 10.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Stefan Schwartz Shoots Himself In The Foot
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Theo Robertson
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/6/2005
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    As many people have mentioned on this page SHOOTING FISH had a lot of potential as it centered around loud mouthed American Dylan and geeky Englishman Jez who are a couple of scam artists . We British have a sort of sneaking respect for these type of con artists ( As long as they con other people of course ) and there's a lot of room for explosive comedy potential as we see Dylan revealing a new type of computer word processor that has a volcabury of hundreds of thousands of words in its database so I sat back ready to enjoy this British comedy but halfway through I was bored senseless It's very obvious what went wrong . Director and co-writer Stefan Schwartz has decided that a laddish comedy will only appeal to 50% of a potential audience so has made a movie that will also appeal to fans of soppy romance by introducing a love triangle featuring Dylan , Jez and Georgie . Unfortunately SHOOTING FISH will ONLY appeal to fans of soppy romance which probably makes up 3% of the audience . This actually seems to be a problem with Schwartz as his future films like THE ABDUCTION CLUB and THE BEST MAN also feature soppy romance in abundance. Fair enough if you want to make a gooey rom com then go ahead but make sure the central premise allows it . Watching very patchy funny scenes like " LESLEY IS DEAD MAN " convinced me that this would have worked without the lovey dovey stuff which seems to have been shoehorned in and it's this that brings the film down Interesting trivia point about Stefan Schwartz : He once had a walk on part in Battlefield , my least favourite DOCTOR WHO story
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Typical English boredom
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    sveknu
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/5/2005
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I think I have to stop watching English movies. Apart from the James Bond-movies and a small number of comedies, they are usually pure crap. This movie is definitely one of those. The first ten minutes starts out OK, and the movie has potential at this time. Sadly, it doesn't continue in this style at all. The story is about two swindlers who tries to earn a lot of money by tricking people in different ways. None of the ways they do this are funny at all. It's supposed to be a comedy, but personally I didn't laugh one single time during the movie. In addition, the story really sucks, especially because they threw a bit of romance on top of it. Alos, the ending is very bad, and it was just what I had expected because movies like this leave you with no surprises. If you want to see a movie about swindlers, watch "Dirty Rotten Scoundrels" instead.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Wonderful
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    kellyjoehayes
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/7/2004
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    After reading some of the comments about this film I just had to express my view. This is one of my favorite films. I admit for some it may be an acquired taste. You'll either love it or hate it. I love it and have recommended it to many of my friends. I lent the video to a friend and she loved it so much she kept showing it to her friends and family and I never got it back. I ended up buying a second copy. Maybe not the best of movies but certainly one you may need to see a couple of times to get the "whole" picture. (and little things like the wallpaper in the guys place). I think the idea and premise is very imaginative. If you like this film you may want to check out Cold Comfort Farm. Another quirky "British humor" movie with Kate Beckinsale.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Ealing-type comedy
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    didi-5
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/6/2004
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie by Stefan Schwartz (co-written with Richard Holmes) thinks it is cleverer than it actually is, and comes out as an odd hybrid of crime caper and romance. Two conmen - the charmless Dan Futterman as American Dylan, and geeky Stuart Townsend as Jez - have long-standing dreams of making lots of cash by any means to fund their very own stately home. Posh totty Kate Beckinsale as Georgie (a doctor-in-training with secretarial skills) joins them as the beauty and brains of the team and causes havoc between them. Involved in this semi-engaging brew are voice recognition computer systems, cremation, loft insulation, blow-up dolls, light sabres, a tatty old racehorse, &pound;50 bills, and the music of Burt Bacharach. Glimpsed in the cast are Phyllis Logan, Annette Crosbie, Peter Capaldi, Jane Lapotaire, Nickolas Grace, Nicholas Woodeson, and (in a small but wickedly funny role as Georgie's boyfriend) Dominic Mafham. 'Shooting Fish' is fairly enjoyable but tends to shoot itself down quite early on, without much chance of recovering. Does it know what it is supposed to be? An idea with potential and some laughs, but this movie doesn't know which way to jump.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A really bad film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    lsjh2
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/6/2004
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I remembered this film being popular when it came out, and after seeing it for the first time yesterday, I couldn't believe how bad and embarrassingly unfunny the script and story were. This film falls into the trap which other British comedies like Sliding Doors have made. It panders to outmoded unrealistic stereotypes about what Britain is like - a quaint world of red telephone boxes and bumbling, nervous Hugh Grant-like men where everyone is white and middle or upper class and speak with plums in their mouths (posh accents). This is absolute rubbish! Where's the vibrant edginess and hectic buzz of London with its multi-culturalism and ethnic diversity, and why do British film makers have to perpetuate these stale myths? I personally find it sad that British film makers think that making these kinds of patronising films is the only way to appeal to the foreign market.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Very light, surreal British three-way romcom
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Framescourer
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/11/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A comedy before it's time - it's all about sustainable resources! This is a brave little film, having neither big names nor obvious genre. The three principals are the latterday highwaymen Dylan and Jez, pulling scams on individuals and corporations alike to make a living. Their plans are big - they need a vast sum in order to move from their (ivory) tower to townhouse and hire - in typically unconventional fashion - a secretary to help them organise their income. Kate Beckinsdale's Georgie is far too lovely a PA to allow things to continue between the friends as smoothly as it had and soon they are on the back foot with only the fresh object of their contention to bail them out. Stuart Townsend and Dan Futterman (especially the latter) are good value and engage with the nuttiness of their ruses to the extent that you just go along with it all. I like Beckinsdale in this - acting fresh fair and occasionally feisty is nothing to be ashamed-and-run-off-to-Hollywood about. Perfect for a Bank Holiday weekend. 4/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Never Mind the Fish, Shoot ME!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tonstant viewer
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/5/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This film has a promising First Act. After around 20 minutes, you begin to suspect that things will go wrong. Then they get much worse than that, they get terrible. The Third Act is in slow-motion, with nine too many plot twists and no pace at all. By this time you are clawing the stuffing out of your couch. I hate these people for having wasted a night out of my life. Dan Futterman, a kind of low-rent baby Richard Gere, plays the American the English love to hate - smug, glib, an updated version of "over-paid, over-sexed and over here." Stuart Townsend plays a shambling English wonk, good hearted and socially undeveloped. Hey, there's something new in films! Kate Beckinsale's charm is unable to salvage the proceedings, and she projects none of the intelligence one would hope to find in a budding doctor. Totally implausible. And there are some very good character actors who are completely wasted in unrewarding roles. I suspect the script was written using one of those screen writing software programs, as the characters, twists and paradoxes are all arbitrary, every single last blinking one of them. Including the blow-up dolls. If the Surgeon General's Office could place a Health Warning on this film, the world would be a safer place. I can't imagine where the positive reviews for this film originate - probably in a misplaced sense of charity. As Jay Sherman, of "The Critic," would say, "IT STINKS!"
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Heart-warming and irrepressibly cheery
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    fes23
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/5/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Call me hopelessly sentimental but I actually find this film very touching! Once you totally suspend your disbelief (this is a film, it's kind of expected...) Jez and Dylan really sell the orphans concept. Here you have two lonely, needy, love-starved guys who through hard work, self-denial and sheer determination win themselves a family and a home. How can your heart not melt? The acting by the male leads is strong enough (mostly - the 'why do I have to get so technical?' scene falters a bit) to make you invest emotionally in Dylan and Jez' quest despite the fact that - all soft-heartedness aside - they are two lying, selfish, close to morally bankrupt con-merchants. By the end of the film you'll be cheering them on. What am I saying? By five minutes in you'll be cheering them on! Yes, it's full of clich&eacute;s. Yes, it's pretty predictable. Yes, it's soppy. But this film proves that you can get away with anything if you have lovable characters and a fantastic soundtrack (see also Ocean's 11). Never fails to cheer me up - I'd recommend it to anyone not entirely hard-boiled.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I don't care, I like it!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bernie-122
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/12/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    There's something wrong about dropping an American con-artist into London, but somehow here it works. There are lots of potential reasons not to like this film, but most of them don't seem to really matter. It just works, anyway. Maybe it's because this was the first time I ever saw Kate Beckinsale, and I was just stunned. Anyway, I was hugely amused when I heard that there was a boycott organized against this film by some people who thought it was going to be about someone shooting at fish (bang, bang). Poor fishies. No, of course, it's no such thing. If you haven't seen this, then I can pretty much guarantee that you will not waste your time if the opportunity comes up.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Wonderful
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Dynesh Vijayaraghavan
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/6/2005
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Normally when it comes to voting for movies on the IMDb, I'm quite liberal. I don't set very high standards for movies. I always tend to rate films based on how much I enjoy them and this means that most of the time I always rate films highly cos I try and find something good in every film I see. I saw this film when I was vacationing in England. BBC One actually transmitted this at 11 PM, since they believed that The Peacemaker was a film more deserving of the 9:00 slot. Unlike the Peacemaker, Shooting Fish is a film that almost anybody would enjoy, unless he/she was the kind of person who found simple effective storytelling a turnoff. Everything about this movie seems in perfect harmony. The chemistry between Dan Futterman and Stuart Townsend is perfect, word for word. And Kate Beckinsale is a perfect third piece to the puzzle; When the conversations in the movie occur, you never get the feeling you're watching a contrived conversation written by someone else, you get the feeling you're watching real life unfold. That's a hallmark of a good scriptwriter and the people who wrote this deserve credit for the story. As for the story itself, it never lets itself become too complicated and lends itself to a lot of funny situations. Fast-talking Dylan and socially naive Jez (Futterman and Townsend) are two con men trying to raise money to build their dream house. They end up enlisting Georgina's (short-haired Kate Beckinsale in a beautiful role from her pre-Hollywood Glamourpuss days) help on a particular scam. Soon she discovers what they're up to and the story unfolds from there, with both Dylan and Jez seemingly falling for Georgie. Here again, the movie doesn't nosedive and morph into a conventional love story; rather, the romance builds in a backdrop to the main story and culminates in a heartwarming finale. As for Dan and Jez, some of their schemes may not be very believable and yet you cant help but be amused by the way they go about implementing them. This film is a good reason why small budget comedy romances are popular - simply put, they work. On every level. Watching this film gives you the same kind of feeling as watching While you were Sleeping, for example. For the sheer sweetness of the film and for Kate Beckinsale's performance, I'd give it 7 on 10.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Stefan Schwartz Shoots Himself In The Foot
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Theo Robertson
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/6/2005
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    As many people have mentioned on this page SHOOTING FISH had a lot of potential as it centered around loud mouthed American Dylan and geeky Englishman Jez who are a couple of scam artists . We British have a sort of sneaking respect for these type of con artists ( As long as they con other people of course ) and there's a lot of room for explosive comedy potential as we see Dylan revealing a new type of computer word processor that has a volcabury of hundreds of thousands of words in its database so I sat back ready to enjoy this British comedy but halfway through I was bored senseless It's very obvious what went wrong . Director and co-writer Stefan Schwartz has decided that a laddish comedy will only appeal to 50% of a potential audience so has made a movie that will also appeal to fans of soppy romance by introducing a love triangle featuring Dylan , Jez and Georgie . Unfortunately SHOOTING FISH will ONLY appeal to fans of soppy romance which probably makes up 3% of the audience . This actually seems to be a problem with Schwartz as his future films like THE ABDUCTION CLUB and THE BEST MAN also feature soppy romance in abundance. Fair enough if you want to make a gooey rom com then go ahead but make sure the central premise allows it . Watching very patchy funny scenes like " LESLEY IS DEAD MAN " convinced me that this would have worked without the lovey dovey stuff which seems to have been shoehorned in and it's this that brings the film down Interesting trivia point about Stefan Schwartz : He once had a walk on part in Battlefield , my least favourite DOCTOR WHO story
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Typical English boredom
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    sveknu
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/5/2005
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I think I have to stop watching English movies. Apart from the James Bond-movies and a small number of comedies, they are usually pure crap. This movie is definitely one of those. The first ten minutes starts out OK, and the movie has potential at this time. Sadly, it doesn't continue in this style at all. The story is about two swindlers who tries to earn a lot of money by tricking people in different ways. None of the ways they do this are funny at all. It's supposed to be a comedy, but personally I didn't laugh one single time during the movie. In addition, the story really sucks, especially because they threw a bit of romance on top of it. Alos, the ending is very bad, and it was just what I had expected because movies like this leave you with no surprises. If you want to see a movie about swindlers, watch "Dirty Rotten Scoundrels" instead.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Wonderful
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    kellyjoehayes
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/7/2004
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    After reading some of the comments about this film I just had to express my view. This is one of my favorite films. I admit for some it may be an acquired taste. You'll either love it or hate it. I love it and have recommended it to many of my friends. I lent the video to a friend and she loved it so much she kept showing it to her friends and family and I never got it back. I ended up buying a second copy. Maybe not the best of movies but certainly one you may need to see a couple of times to get the "whole" picture. (and little things like the wallpaper in the guys place). I think the idea and premise is very imaginative. If you like this film you may want to check out Cold Comfort Farm. Another quirky "British humor" movie with Kate Beckinsale.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Ealing-type comedy
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    didi-5
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/6/2004
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie by Stefan Schwartz (co-written with Richard Holmes) thinks it is cleverer than it actually is, and comes out as an odd hybrid of crime caper and romance. Two conmen - the charmless Dan Futterman as American Dylan, and geeky Stuart Townsend as Jez - have long-standing dreams of making lots of cash by any means to fund their very own stately home. Posh totty Kate Beckinsale as Georgie (a doctor-in-training with secretarial skills) joins them as the beauty and brains of the team and causes havoc between them. Involved in this semi-engaging brew are voice recognition computer systems, cremation, loft insulation, blow-up dolls, light sabres, a tatty old racehorse, &pound;50 bills, and the music of Burt Bacharach. Glimpsed in the cast are Phyllis Logan, Annette Crosbie, Peter Capaldi, Jane Lapotaire, Nickolas Grace, Nicholas Woodeson, and (in a small but wickedly funny role as Georgie's boyfriend) Dominic Mafham. 'Shooting Fish' is fairly enjoyable but tends to shoot itself down quite early on, without much chance of recovering. Does it know what it is supposed to be? An idea with potential and some laughs, but this movie doesn't know which way to jump.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A really bad film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    lsjh2
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/6/2004
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I remembered this film being popular when it came out, and after seeing it for the first time yesterday, I couldn't believe how bad and embarrassingly unfunny the script and story were. This film falls into the trap which other British comedies like Sliding Doors have made. It panders to outmoded unrealistic stereotypes about what Britain is like - a quaint world of red telephone boxes and bumbling, nervous Hugh Grant-like men where everyone is white and middle or upper class and speak with plums in their mouths (posh accents). This is absolute rubbish! Where's the vibrant edginess and hectic buzz of London with its multi-culturalism and ethnic diversity, and why do British film makers have to perpetuate these stale myths? I personally find it sad that British film makers think that making these kinds of patronising films is the only way to appeal to the foreign market.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
 </reviews>
</filme>
