<filme>
 <id>
  1439
 </id>
 <imdburl>
  http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0110186
 </imdburl>
 <ano>
  1994
 </ano>
 <titulo>
  Jason's Lyric
 </titulo>
 <rating>
  6.3
 </rating>
 <sinopse>
  The story of a young man who must confront his own fears about love as well as his relationships with family and friends. Allen Payne (I) plays Jason, a sales clerk at a T.V. store. He ... &nbsp;&raquo;
 </sinopse>
 <storyline>
  The story of a young man who must confront his own fears about love as well as his relationships with family and friends. Allen Payne (I) plays Jason, a sales clerk at a T.V. store. He falls in love with Lyric (Jada Pinkett Smith) and finds happiness, but his family history and crazy father Maddog (played by Forest Whitaker) come back to haunt him before he can leave it all for a better life.
 </storyline>
 <generos>
  <genero>
   Crime
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Drama
  </genero>
 </generos>
 <keywords>
  <keyword>
   punctuation in title
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   ghetto
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   mother son relationship
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   train
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   violence
  </keyword>
 </keywords>
 <diretores>
  <diretor>
   Doug McHenry
  </diretor>
 </diretores>
 <escritores>
  <escritor>
   Bobby Smith Jr.
  </escritor>
 </escritores>
 <atores>
  <ator>
   Allen Payne
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Jada Pinkett Smith
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Bokeem Woodbine
  </ator>
 </atores>
 <reviews>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The best, heartbreaking love story about an Afro-American couple back in the day.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mizit286
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    SPOILER... I am sure I have seen this movie before, but never really "saw" it until I found it in WalMart's movie bin. I have always wanted to just watch old shows and movies when I retired, and now, I can see movies completely. It is an old movie, but by far the best movie I have ever cried over. Jada does not wait until she is older and more experienced to rock. The story contains lives of Afro-Americans who work for a living, hang on the streets, do time in prison, love, mistake love, crime and reality. When Jada meets the love of her life, (a hunk), they decide to move away, riding the greyhound bus. The very ending will make the strongest person in the world cry. Their love had problems as her boyfriend is the man of his house, helping mother to raise a troubled brother. The younger brother spends lots of time locked up, while Jason is troubled with nightmares. We find that one of the children shoots and kills their father when he once again abuses their mother. I am leaving out a lot because it is so wonderful to just watch this movie and wonder. You will not be sorry. Thanks to the makers, I found this film on a DVD that also included three other movies, all starring Afro-American Women. GET THIS MOVIE! Seeing it once will not satisfy you, and each time you will cry. The music to the movie is fantastic and the ending song will bring back the flood of tears.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Timeless...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Jade
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/9/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This film is captivating!!! It brilliantly tells a story of Love and Sacrifice. This cast was the perfect group for this production. Payne, Pinkett, Woodbine, Wittaker... Everyone has already stated how well their performances was; but, one that mustn't be forgotten is Lisa Carson (Marti - Alonzo's girlfriend/Pinkett's co-worker)... Her character left an impact on me because of how she faced her reality by quoting others. She played her facade but her hurt began to shed light during her last conversation with Lyric... I don't want to give away too much but I will say that if you're looking for a nice movie that will tap into your senses, make you laugh and cry, and one that is very relate-able... Give Jason's Lyric a try!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Excellent Movie, I own the rottweiler puppy, Lyric that was in this movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    vtlric
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/6/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I was very surprised at how good this movie was. My rottweiler, Lyric, who is now 13 years old was in this movie when she was 7 weeks old. I named her Lyric after the role of Jada Pinkett. Lyric went on to be an American/Canadian Champion. Her show name is Am/Ca CH. Von Traeger's Lyric. The movie took place in the 3rd Ward in Houston, Texas. It was awesome being on the set during the filming of this movie. I am looking at showing Lyric at the "Reliant Center World Dog Show" in Houston this next Month. She will be shown in Veterens Class 12 years and older. This is a rottweiler specialty show. Thank you for letting me share. Kerri
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Great stuff..
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Liakot Ali
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/6/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Jason's Lyric wasn't a great film theatrically, as it had small promotions. Judging by the title and cast, i didn't expect a good film. It was actually a great film with powerful performances. It tells the story of Two brothers (One good and One Bad) living with their mother in a rough area. Jason played by Allen Payne is sensible and taking care of his younger brother Joshu. Joshua played by Bokeem Woodbine is a little crazy and has a violent side to his personality. Its a half love story and half action movie thats worth the watch. Allen Payne delivers a good performance. Bokeem Woodbine is terrific, see him in Dead Presidents also. Jada Pinkett looks ultra sexy and plays the love life of Jason. There are some fabulous Sex scenes, Jada looks fantastic. Overall, Good realistic storyline and deserves a chance.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The underused Pinkett and Payne shine in this urban love story
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Reginald D. Garrard
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/4/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    If Hollywood was more equitable in its hiring practices, Jada Pinkett would be in the league with Halle Berry, Sandra Bullock, and others of her generation. Pinkett, who gave a bravura performance (along with Queen Latifah) in the earlier "Set It Off," is no less than brilliant as "Lyric," sought after by the hard-working "Jason," played by another neglected thespian, Alan Payne. Both Pinkett and Payne deliver as the lovers torn between the attraction to each other and the responsibilities of family and work that interferes with their relationship. Forest Whitaker is marvelous as Payne's father, a man that must deal with his own personal demons, along with an estranged relationship with his wife, wondrously played by Suzanne Douglas. The rest of the cast (Bokeem Woodbine, Lisa Nicole Carson, Eddie Griffin, among others) are exceptional in a story that is both tragic and uplifting. And the "love scene" between "Jason" and "Lyric" is enough to make the most open-minded of viewers blush.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Good, But Could Have Been Better
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Brian Washington (Sargebri@att.net)
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/6/2004
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This film pretty much came out at a time when more and more films featuring blacks in positive images were coming out. This film came out around the same time as another film that Jada Pinkett was in, The Inkwell. However, this film tries to be three films at once. First its a story about the tragic events in the brother's past. The second story is almost an urban version of "Romeo and Juliet". The third plot revolves around how Jason's brother constantly gets into trouble leading to his tragic end. The love story would have been enough for me because it shows that African Americans can have very loving relationships and can be romantic. Unfortunately, in the end it turns into a typical bloody shootout, but it does have a twist ending and that helped to save it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The film's direction is plain, simple and obvious - in a bad way...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    scroll2b
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/12/2003
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    There must be 10+ setups for each scene, where the lighting is perfect, as if it was a student filmmaker's first 35mm film. There's absolutely no style, and no thought of how the film would work as a whole. Most of the pickups are wasted coverage. There's hardly any genuine suspense, and the ending feels totally forced, as does the last tacked-on song. Why is it that most new filmmakers are too busy trying to prove they can run a film production, run a show just like the pros? Why can't they focus on the end point - how the film will affect those who witness it? This filmmaker makes absolutely no point in what he does, except to show how unskilled he is as a storyteller. Not to compare the two, since they are completely different types of films, but if you want to see real amazing direction, in which the story unfolds with tremendous, unsuspecting power, see THE PIANO. Jane Campion's direction could teach many that it's not the coverage, and multiple set-ups, but the performances, pacing and story that goes first.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Is blood thicker than water?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    IrockGswift (IrockGswift@aol.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/2/2003
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Two young men living with a single parent mother,and one has to step up to be the man. You have one brother that always in and out of trouble,and the other trying to make a living by selling TVs and helping his mother. Though Josh is back home he cannot work no ordinary 9 to 5 due to his past life as a drug-dealer. Jason on the other hand falls in loves with a waitress who's brother lives for the life of crime. By Lyric(the waitress) overhearing a plan to rob a bank that involves Jason's brother(Josh) she tells Jason not to get between that,meaning this could end their relationship. So Jason confronted Josh about it but Josh went on and foiled their plans,leaving Josh beat up and bloody. Jason felt he had to do something and not let Lyric's brother nearly kill him. As the day Jason and Lyric plan to elope,Jason arrived at their meeting place late with Lyric suspecting he got involved. Jason felt that his brother Josh knows he all he's got so he felt responsible. Lyric became heart-broken and left him. As Josh plans to murder the guys who nearly beat him to death. Friends of Jason tells him that Josh has lost it and is going after the guys who beat him down. But Jason had arrived to the scene a little too late as Josh corners Lyric at gunpoint to tell him where her brother is and to leave his brother alone. Josh accidently shoots her and Jason was devastated and carried her lifeless body out the house. WOW! I don't know why this movie didn't win an award for urban drama. This movie should have been as popular as it's soundtrack. The decision where Jason had to choose between his brother's life or turning his back on him to leave with a lover. This can't get anymore dramatic as that.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Nothing short of exquisite
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Paz (fuxing626)
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/8/2002
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    One endeavor in filmmaking that quite frequently doesn't turn out well is mixing genres. "Jason's Lyric" combines crime drama, love story, and ghetto film-and does it surprisingly beautifully. The acting is remarkable, the script is remarkable, and the emotion is remarkable. This movie could have turned out very pretentious and very cheesy. Apparently, the directors, writers, and producers completely acknowledged this, and refused to let that happen. The characters are very well developed and, while the movie doesn't justify Josh's actions, it does convey compassion for him. It also provides new insight on what it's really like to live in a ghetto. If you can find this movie (after all, I saw it on Showtime and haven't the video in any stores) totally see it!!!!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A urban love story
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    DunnDeeDaGreat
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/4/2002
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Jason's Lyric is clearly one of the best urban love stories ever put on film. The direction by Doug McHerny showed real talent as did his screenpaly. Allen Payne and Jada Pinkett both showed early lead acting roles in this good film. Finally I think Forrest Whitaker and Bokeem Woodbine both deserved Oscar nods for their work. I give it **** out of ****.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The best, heartbreaking love story about an Afro-American couple back in the day.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mizit286
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    SPOILER... I am sure I have seen this movie before, but never really "saw" it until I found it in WalMart's movie bin. I have always wanted to just watch old shows and movies when I retired, and now, I can see movies completely. It is an old movie, but by far the best movie I have ever cried over. Jada does not wait until she is older and more experienced to rock. The story contains lives of Afro-Americans who work for a living, hang on the streets, do time in prison, love, mistake love, crime and reality. When Jada meets the love of her life, (a hunk), they decide to move away, riding the greyhound bus. The very ending will make the strongest person in the world cry. Their love had problems as her boyfriend is the man of his house, helping mother to raise a troubled brother. The younger brother spends lots of time locked up, while Jason is troubled with nightmares. We find that one of the children shoots and kills their father when he once again abuses their mother. I am leaving out a lot because it is so wonderful to just watch this movie and wonder. You will not be sorry. Thanks to the makers, I found this film on a DVD that also included three other movies, all starring Afro-American Women. GET THIS MOVIE! Seeing it once will not satisfy you, and each time you will cry. The music to the movie is fantastic and the ending song will bring back the flood of tears.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Timeless...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Jade
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/9/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This film is captivating!!! It brilliantly tells a story of Love and Sacrifice. This cast was the perfect group for this production. Payne, Pinkett, Woodbine, Wittaker... Everyone has already stated how well their performances was; but, one that mustn't be forgotten is Lisa Carson (Marti - Alonzo's girlfriend/Pinkett's co-worker)... Her character left an impact on me because of how she faced her reality by quoting others. She played her facade but her hurt began to shed light during her last conversation with Lyric... I don't want to give away too much but I will say that if you're looking for a nice movie that will tap into your senses, make you laugh and cry, and one that is very relate-able... Give Jason's Lyric a try!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Excellent Movie, I own the rottweiler puppy, Lyric that was in this movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    vtlric
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/6/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I was very surprised at how good this movie was. My rottweiler, Lyric, who is now 13 years old was in this movie when she was 7 weeks old. I named her Lyric after the role of Jada Pinkett. Lyric went on to be an American/Canadian Champion. Her show name is Am/Ca CH. Von Traeger's Lyric. The movie took place in the 3rd Ward in Houston, Texas. It was awesome being on the set during the filming of this movie. I am looking at showing Lyric at the "Reliant Center World Dog Show" in Houston this next Month. She will be shown in Veterens Class 12 years and older. This is a rottweiler specialty show. Thank you for letting me share. Kerri
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Great stuff..
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Liakot Ali
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/6/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Jason's Lyric wasn't a great film theatrically, as it had small promotions. Judging by the title and cast, i didn't expect a good film. It was actually a great film with powerful performances. It tells the story of Two brothers (One good and One Bad) living with their mother in a rough area. Jason played by Allen Payne is sensible and taking care of his younger brother Joshu. Joshua played by Bokeem Woodbine is a little crazy and has a violent side to his personality. Its a half love story and half action movie thats worth the watch. Allen Payne delivers a good performance. Bokeem Woodbine is terrific, see him in Dead Presidents also. Jada Pinkett looks ultra sexy and plays the love life of Jason. There are some fabulous Sex scenes, Jada looks fantastic. Overall, Good realistic storyline and deserves a chance.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The underused Pinkett and Payne shine in this urban love story
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Reginald D. Garrard
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/4/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    If Hollywood was more equitable in its hiring practices, Jada Pinkett would be in the league with Halle Berry, Sandra Bullock, and others of her generation. Pinkett, who gave a bravura performance (along with Queen Latifah) in the earlier "Set It Off," is no less than brilliant as "Lyric," sought after by the hard-working "Jason," played by another neglected thespian, Alan Payne. Both Pinkett and Payne deliver as the lovers torn between the attraction to each other and the responsibilities of family and work that interferes with their relationship. Forest Whitaker is marvelous as Payne's father, a man that must deal with his own personal demons, along with an estranged relationship with his wife, wondrously played by Suzanne Douglas. The rest of the cast (Bokeem Woodbine, Lisa Nicole Carson, Eddie Griffin, among others) are exceptional in a story that is both tragic and uplifting. And the "love scene" between "Jason" and "Lyric" is enough to make the most open-minded of viewers blush.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Good, But Could Have Been Better
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Brian Washington (Sargebri@att.net)
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/6/2004
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This film pretty much came out at a time when more and more films featuring blacks in positive images were coming out. This film came out around the same time as another film that Jada Pinkett was in, The Inkwell. However, this film tries to be three films at once. First its a story about the tragic events in the brother's past. The second story is almost an urban version of "Romeo and Juliet". The third plot revolves around how Jason's brother constantly gets into trouble leading to his tragic end. The love story would have been enough for me because it shows that African Americans can have very loving relationships and can be romantic. Unfortunately, in the end it turns into a typical bloody shootout, but it does have a twist ending and that helped to save it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The film's direction is plain, simple and obvious - in a bad way...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    scroll2b
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/12/2003
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    There must be 10+ setups for each scene, where the lighting is perfect, as if it was a student filmmaker's first 35mm film. There's absolutely no style, and no thought of how the film would work as a whole. Most of the pickups are wasted coverage. There's hardly any genuine suspense, and the ending feels totally forced, as does the last tacked-on song. Why is it that most new filmmakers are too busy trying to prove they can run a film production, run a show just like the pros? Why can't they focus on the end point - how the film will affect those who witness it? This filmmaker makes absolutely no point in what he does, except to show how unskilled he is as a storyteller. Not to compare the two, since they are completely different types of films, but if you want to see real amazing direction, in which the story unfolds with tremendous, unsuspecting power, see THE PIANO. Jane Campion's direction could teach many that it's not the coverage, and multiple set-ups, but the performances, pacing and story that goes first.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Is blood thicker than water?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    IrockGswift (IrockGswift@aol.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/2/2003
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Two young men living with a single parent mother,and one has to step up to be the man. You have one brother that always in and out of trouble,and the other trying to make a living by selling TVs and helping his mother. Though Josh is back home he cannot work no ordinary 9 to 5 due to his past life as a drug-dealer. Jason on the other hand falls in loves with a waitress who's brother lives for the life of crime. By Lyric(the waitress) overhearing a plan to rob a bank that involves Jason's brother(Josh) she tells Jason not to get between that,meaning this could end their relationship. So Jason confronted Josh about it but Josh went on and foiled their plans,leaving Josh beat up and bloody. Jason felt he had to do something and not let Lyric's brother nearly kill him. As the day Jason and Lyric plan to elope,Jason arrived at their meeting place late with Lyric suspecting he got involved. Jason felt that his brother Josh knows he all he's got so he felt responsible. Lyric became heart-broken and left him. As Josh plans to murder the guys who nearly beat him to death. Friends of Jason tells him that Josh has lost it and is going after the guys who beat him down. But Jason had arrived to the scene a little too late as Josh corners Lyric at gunpoint to tell him where her brother is and to leave his brother alone. Josh accidently shoots her and Jason was devastated and carried her lifeless body out the house. WOW! I don't know why this movie didn't win an award for urban drama. This movie should have been as popular as it's soundtrack. The decision where Jason had to choose between his brother's life or turning his back on him to leave with a lover. This can't get anymore dramatic as that.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Nothing short of exquisite
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Paz (fuxing626)
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/8/2002
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    One endeavor in filmmaking that quite frequently doesn't turn out well is mixing genres. "Jason's Lyric" combines crime drama, love story, and ghetto film-and does it surprisingly beautifully. The acting is remarkable, the script is remarkable, and the emotion is remarkable. This movie could have turned out very pretentious and very cheesy. Apparently, the directors, writers, and producers completely acknowledged this, and refused to let that happen. The characters are very well developed and, while the movie doesn't justify Josh's actions, it does convey compassion for him. It also provides new insight on what it's really like to live in a ghetto. If you can find this movie (after all, I saw it on Showtime and haven't the video in any stores) totally see it!!!!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A urban love story
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    DunnDeeDaGreat
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/4/2002
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Jason's Lyric is clearly one of the best urban love stories ever put on film. The direction by Doug McHerny showed real talent as did his screenpaly. Allen Payne and Jada Pinkett both showed early lead acting roles in this good film. Finally I think Forrest Whitaker and Bokeem Woodbine both deserved Oscar nods for their work. I give it **** out of ****.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
 </reviews>
</filme>
