<filme>
 <id>
  1441
 </id>
 <imdburl>
  http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0113851
 </imdburl>
 <ano>
  1995
 </ano>
 <titulo>
  O Jogo da Verdade
 </titulo>
 <rating>
  5.7
 </rating>
 <sinopse>
  A young widow still grieving over the death of her husband finds herself being comforted by a local housepainter.
 </sinopse>
 <storyline>
  College poetry professor and poet Rebecca Trager Lott's husband Ben Lott has just died in a freak accident. Rebecca's support during this difficult time consists of her best friend Sylvie Morrow, her sister Lucy Trager, and her ex-stepmother Alberta Trager. Earth mother Sylvie is dealing with what she sees as the probable end of her own marriage to her husband Paul Morrow. Chain smoking Lucy is a directionless and insecure woman who is still mourning their mother's death fourteen years earlier from cancer. And Wall Street executive Alberta, who Lucy in particular doesn't like in her life (especially as Alberta and their father have since divorced) is a domineering but admittedly efficient woman who treats her personal life as an extension of her professional life. As time progresses and each woman deals with her own issues while trying to help Rebecca, a hunky house painter who they have nicknamed "Valentino" enters their collective lives. "Valentino" profoundly affects each of their ...
 </storyline>
 <generos>
  <genero>
   Drama
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Romance
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Comedy
  </genero>
 </generos>
 <keywords>
  <keyword>
   widow
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   grief
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   friendship between women
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   female protagonist
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   death of husband
  </keyword>
 </keywords>
 <diretores>
  <diretor>
   David Anspaugh
  </diretor>
 </diretores>
 <escritores>
  <escritor>
   Ellen Simon
  </escritor>
 </escritores>
 <atores>
  <ator>
   Elizabeth Perkins
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Whoopi Goldberg
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Kathleen Turner
  </ator>
 </atores>
 <reviews>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Very tasteful, very sensitive and incredibly boring
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    James Hitchcock
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/6/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Rebecca Lott, a thirtysomething. college lecturer, is widowed when her husband Ben is killed by a car while jogging. The rest of the film is taken up with Rebecca endlessly talking over her emotional problems with her younger sister Lucy, her best friend Sylvie and her former stepmother Alberta. There are subplots about Lucy's romance with Stephen, one of Rebecca's students, and Rebecca's brief romance with a handsome young man hired to paint her house. The film ends with the four women performing a bizarre quasi-pagan ritual designed to help Rebecca cope with her grief. And that's it. The film is what used to be called a "woman's picture", but with one major difference. The traditional "woman's picture" had as its primary character a strong female figure, with the male characters as secondary ones, defined in terms of their relationship to her. Here the primary character is the rather passive figure of Rebecca, with Lucy, Sylvie and Alberta as the secondary ones and the male characters, insofar as we see them at all, vague tertiary ones. The film-makers are, essentially, trying to make a film about the romantic and emotional lives of a group of heterosexual women while airbrushing men out of the picture as far as possible. Ben never appears (his death is announced right at the beginning of the film), and Rebecca and Lucy's father Thomas only appears briefly. (Their mother Joanna died from cancer fourteen years earlier). Stephen is a minor character and Sylvie's husband Paul an even more minor one, although we learn that their marriage is an unhappy one. The nearest thing to a major male character is The Painter, and it is noteworthy that we never learn his name and that he is played not by a professional actor but by a rock star with virtually no previous acting experience. The result is that the film ends up devoid of any dramatic conflict or tension. The nearest we get is the suggestion that the two sisters, especially Lucy, resent their stepmother for usurping their mother's role in their lives. Yet we do not sense from the film itself that Alberta, who is supposed to be a hard-bitten career woman, has done anything that might provoke resentment; indeed, she treats the sisters with great kindness, doing far more to console Rebecca, who was only briefly her stepdaughter, in her bereavement than does her father. Stephen Holden of the New York Times, called the film "a genteel, buttoned-up soap opera", which strikes me as being unfair to soap operas, much as I dislike that particular genre. "Moonlight and Valentino" is around four times the length of an episode of most British soaps, and any scriptwriter for "Coronation Street" or "East Enders" would soon find themselves out of a job if they wasted four entire episodes with as little drama or action as is included in the 105 minutes of this film. I watched this film when it was recently shown on television largely because the cast included two actresses I had admired in other films, Gwyneth Paltrow in "Sylvia" and Kathleen Turner in films like "The Accidental Tourist" and "Serial Mom". Unfortunately, it turned out to be a big disappointment to me, which was not really the fault of Paltrow, Turner and the two other leading actresses, all of whom gave the impression that they could do much more with better material. (Although if Whoopi Goldberg wants to be taken seriously as a serious actress as opposed to a comedienne, she might consider getting rid of her childish stage name. Naming herself after a whoopee cushion was not perhaps her greatest career move). Instead the fault lies with the script, based on a play by Ellen Simon, who unfortunately does not seem to have inherited the dramatic talents of her more famous father Neil, and with David Anspaugh's direction. Roger Ebert described it as "very sincere, very heartfelt and very bad", a judgement from which I would not dissent, although I would also add very tasteful, very sensitive and incredibly boring. The whole thing is done with the sort of excruciatingly ghastly good taste that makes you long for someone to say or do something tasteless just to relieve the monotony of four people sitting round being nice to one another. 4/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Mid 90's Catch and Release....
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    michael_agalvan
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/6/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A Young English professor (Elizabeth Perkins) loses her husband while an anxiety ridden best friend (Whoopi Goldberg), a quirky younger sister (Gwenyth Paltrow), and an attached ex-stepmother (Kathleen Turner) help her come to terms with life and love. First lead role I've seen Perkins take charge, Gwenyth in a new light a role that made me love her even more, Goldberg in the same light as Boys on The Side (1996), and Kathleen Turner pulls off a successful business mother vying for the affection of a daughter that doesn't belong to her, a beautiful thing. Joining the cast are a few of films sexiest men Jeremy Sisto and Jon Bon Jovi. Definitely worth the watch!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    loved it
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    kristin_headrick
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/5/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I am only 21, but i watched this movie a LONG time ago with my mom & never really appreciated it...I thought it was awful, but now that I have lost someone (a boyfriend) and have had to learn to lean on other people I really appreciate it and know that it really is a great movie!!! To me it seemed kind of surreal when i was younger that anyone could be like that... but the speech at the end when she tells Ben bye...now that i have watched it again makes me tear up now just thinking about it. Its hard to look back and have regrets and i get it now. I loved this movie and i'm thinking about buying it...helps you deal a little bit
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    You know you're watching a bad Movie when the only critic quoted in the newspaper ads is LARRY KING
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    slightlymad22
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/4/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    You know you're watching an awful Movie when After it's over you say to yourself, "Wow, and the best part of that was Jon Bon Jovi's performance!" Even though i had snuck into the cinema(something me and my mates did a lot in the mid 90's), I still felt like demanding my money back afterwards! i knew i wasn't enjoying the movie when i started to long for the thespian skills of Pauly Shore. I remember going to see this movie like it was yesterday and the bad taste still clings to the back of my throat like the memory of a romance that went sour.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Quite good, but could have been better
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ipekmine
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/3/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I admit, the main reason that made me wanna watch this movie was Jon Bon Jovi's part in it. Being a huge fan of his, I try to see all of his movies thus I watched Moonlight & Valentino as well. And not just once but four times. The way I see it, the cast did a great job, but the script could have been turned into a better film, had a less flat ending been made, if you know what I mean. I think it's a soft, sweet movie but in a way it's rather dull, or at least ordinary. What I'm trying to say is, with this cast and story, a more effective and more impressive movie could have been made. But maybe that's just me. Other than that, the songs in the movie were real, good. And, on a side note, the part where the ladies think that the painter doesn't speak English but then he surprises them about it is hilarious in my opinion.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Romantic Fantasy
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    dizzjay
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/1/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I saw this film shortly before watching In Her Shoes with Toni Collette and Cameron Diaz. There are a lot of similarities between the two films. They both have great casts and good acting. They both have stock characters of sisters who are very different, an offensive stepmother, a woman friend/confidant, an emotionally unavailable father, a dead mother and a surprise lover. Both films have the characters experience life-changing realizations and both films suffer from a kind of 'love conquers all' sentimentality. They both add a little titillation with Cameron Diaz in black underwear and a partial back shot of Gwyneth Paltrow naked. Both films seem contrived, as if the writers of the works the films are based on did market research and said, "Ok, there's a market for stories about relationships between women, so I'm going to write about two sisters with an offensive stepmother" In other words, instead of the drama emerging from the truth of the relationship, the relationship is invented to fit the dramatic situation. It seems forced, the characters don't seem real, the relationships are unbelievable. The resolution of the tensions between the characters is simplistic with simple apologies completely whisking away years of acrimony leaving everyone feeling warm and fuzzy ever after. It's just not real. Romantic fantasy. The characters in In Her Shoes are a little more overblown than Moonlight & Valentino, especially the stepmother part. Sydelle Feller, in In Her Shoes is so evil that it is difficult to believe that the father would stay with her, or even marry her in the first place. Kathleen Turner at least shows some emotional vulnerability as the stepmother in Moonlight & Valentino. If you liked Moonlight & Valentino you will probably like In Her Shoes as well. Enjoyable performances in both, in fact, the actors bring depth to their parts that goes way beyond the contrived sentimentality of the scripts.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Embarrassingly shallow
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    sstuart3-1
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/10/2005
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It's hard to rate this movie because it had such a terrific cast. The script was dreadful, stupid, silly. You shouldn't actually have to lose a husband to see the absolute falseness of the script. But to cast these great actresses in that story and require that they say those lines was an appalling waste. It is a tribute to their skill that the movie was even possible to watch at all. They did the best they could, but I found it painful to watch, not because I found the story touching but because it was so embarrassingly shallow. You can be sad and funny without being trivial. There are plenty of movies out there to prove it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Common People Vote Higher
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    oiwiein
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/6/2005
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I'm not one to usually admit I was teared up during a movie but this movie got me at least three times. That alone should give it a 7 rating but I added one more. I guess I really understood Lucy in the movie since those are the type of women I would date. Once you get to know them all, all 4 that is, you can really understand this complex relationship. I will not go into too many details but this is a must watch movie and not a perfect 10 but pretty darn good. I cannot believe that this has under a 6 rating not true at all. So i have to add a few more lines. OK then vote for this movie with your heart not from a spectacularly sensational Hollywood standpoint.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Great actresses in a mediocre film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Maoui
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/8/2003
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Moonlight and Valentino is the sincere attempt to portray a grieving woman.When I saw the film for the first time I was amazed by the acting abilities of Elizabeth Perkins. The rest of the cast was also great. (Gwyneth Paltrow,Kathleen Turner, Whoopi Goldberg give all great performances)Unfortunately the film is not coherent enough and the ending is also very flat.So it was not a great movie but at least entertaining with great and charming actresses. 6/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    It was alright....a bit boring though...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    crystalc1020
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/4/2003
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I just got finished watching this movie last night. I had always wanted to see it and so when it unexpectedly came on tv last night, I decided to watch it. Well...I have mixed feelings about this movie. ****************NOTE!! SPOILERS!!!!************************* I thought the acting overall was good...I was a bit dissapointed however in Perkin's character, and how emotionless she was after he husband died. I know that part of this was because she was partly shocked and in denial, but still....I expected a STRONGER outburst of emotion from her. This is your HUSBAND that has just died for goodness sakes! Not only that, but I felt like this movie tended to go on and on with not real point. IT felt very boring at times, and just plotless. I liked how the movie focuses on each of the women's lives and the problems they are facing in them, however if I were the director, I would have had the movie continue on with a slightly FASTER pace. The movie felt like 2 hours long when I had only watched an hour of it! Bottom line: I didn't even finish this movie because it was just sooo slow and kind of boring. I was already tired to begin with...I didn't need this movie to put me even faster to sleep. However, if you want a good chick flick about women overcoming thier problems in life, then this movie is for you. The acting is great (except that little part I mentioned above) and the it's a touching story about enduring hardships, and moving on with your life after a tragic death.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Very tasteful, very sensitive and incredibly boring
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    James Hitchcock
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/6/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Rebecca Lott, a thirtysomething. college lecturer, is widowed when her husband Ben is killed by a car while jogging. The rest of the film is taken up with Rebecca endlessly talking over her emotional problems with her younger sister Lucy, her best friend Sylvie and her former stepmother Alberta. There are subplots about Lucy's romance with Stephen, one of Rebecca's students, and Rebecca's brief romance with a handsome young man hired to paint her house. The film ends with the four women performing a bizarre quasi-pagan ritual designed to help Rebecca cope with her grief. And that's it. The film is what used to be called a "woman's picture", but with one major difference. The traditional "woman's picture" had as its primary character a strong female figure, with the male characters as secondary ones, defined in terms of their relationship to her. Here the primary character is the rather passive figure of Rebecca, with Lucy, Sylvie and Alberta as the secondary ones and the male characters, insofar as we see them at all, vague tertiary ones. The film-makers are, essentially, trying to make a film about the romantic and emotional lives of a group of heterosexual women while airbrushing men out of the picture as far as possible. Ben never appears (his death is announced right at the beginning of the film), and Rebecca and Lucy's father Thomas only appears briefly. (Their mother Joanna died from cancer fourteen years earlier). Stephen is a minor character and Sylvie's husband Paul an even more minor one, although we learn that their marriage is an unhappy one. The nearest thing to a major male character is The Painter, and it is noteworthy that we never learn his name and that he is played not by a professional actor but by a rock star with virtually no previous acting experience. The result is that the film ends up devoid of any dramatic conflict or tension. The nearest we get is the suggestion that the two sisters, especially Lucy, resent their stepmother for usurping their mother's role in their lives. Yet we do not sense from the film itself that Alberta, who is supposed to be a hard-bitten career woman, has done anything that might provoke resentment; indeed, she treats the sisters with great kindness, doing far more to console Rebecca, who was only briefly her stepdaughter, in her bereavement than does her father. Stephen Holden of the New York Times, called the film "a genteel, buttoned-up soap opera", which strikes me as being unfair to soap operas, much as I dislike that particular genre. "Moonlight and Valentino" is around four times the length of an episode of most British soaps, and any scriptwriter for "Coronation Street" or "East Enders" would soon find themselves out of a job if they wasted four entire episodes with as little drama or action as is included in the 105 minutes of this film. I watched this film when it was recently shown on television largely because the cast included two actresses I had admired in other films, Gwyneth Paltrow in "Sylvia" and Kathleen Turner in films like "The Accidental Tourist" and "Serial Mom". Unfortunately, it turned out to be a big disappointment to me, which was not really the fault of Paltrow, Turner and the two other leading actresses, all of whom gave the impression that they could do much more with better material. (Although if Whoopi Goldberg wants to be taken seriously as a serious actress as opposed to a comedienne, she might consider getting rid of her childish stage name. Naming herself after a whoopee cushion was not perhaps her greatest career move). Instead the fault lies with the script, based on a play by Ellen Simon, who unfortunately does not seem to have inherited the dramatic talents of her more famous father Neil, and with David Anspaugh's direction. Roger Ebert described it as "very sincere, very heartfelt and very bad", a judgement from which I would not dissent, although I would also add very tasteful, very sensitive and incredibly boring. The whole thing is done with the sort of excruciatingly ghastly good taste that makes you long for someone to say or do something tasteless just to relieve the monotony of four people sitting round being nice to one another. 4/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Mid 90's Catch and Release....
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    michael_agalvan
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/6/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A Young English professor (Elizabeth Perkins) loses her husband while an anxiety ridden best friend (Whoopi Goldberg), a quirky younger sister (Gwenyth Paltrow), and an attached ex-stepmother (Kathleen Turner) help her come to terms with life and love. First lead role I've seen Perkins take charge, Gwenyth in a new light a role that made me love her even more, Goldberg in the same light as Boys on The Side (1996), and Kathleen Turner pulls off a successful business mother vying for the affection of a daughter that doesn't belong to her, a beautiful thing. Joining the cast are a few of films sexiest men Jeremy Sisto and Jon Bon Jovi. Definitely worth the watch!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    loved it
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    kristin_headrick
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/5/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I am only 21, but i watched this movie a LONG time ago with my mom & never really appreciated it...I thought it was awful, but now that I have lost someone (a boyfriend) and have had to learn to lean on other people I really appreciate it and know that it really is a great movie!!! To me it seemed kind of surreal when i was younger that anyone could be like that... but the speech at the end when she tells Ben bye...now that i have watched it again makes me tear up now just thinking about it. Its hard to look back and have regrets and i get it now. I loved this movie and i'm thinking about buying it...helps you deal a little bit
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    You know you're watching a bad Movie when the only critic quoted in the newspaper ads is LARRY KING
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    slightlymad22
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/4/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    You know you're watching an awful Movie when After it's over you say to yourself, "Wow, and the best part of that was Jon Bon Jovi's performance!" Even though i had snuck into the cinema(something me and my mates did a lot in the mid 90's), I still felt like demanding my money back afterwards! i knew i wasn't enjoying the movie when i started to long for the thespian skills of Pauly Shore. I remember going to see this movie like it was yesterday and the bad taste still clings to the back of my throat like the memory of a romance that went sour.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Quite good, but could have been better
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ipekmine
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/3/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I admit, the main reason that made me wanna watch this movie was Jon Bon Jovi's part in it. Being a huge fan of his, I try to see all of his movies thus I watched Moonlight & Valentino as well. And not just once but four times. The way I see it, the cast did a great job, but the script could have been turned into a better film, had a less flat ending been made, if you know what I mean. I think it's a soft, sweet movie but in a way it's rather dull, or at least ordinary. What I'm trying to say is, with this cast and story, a more effective and more impressive movie could have been made. But maybe that's just me. Other than that, the songs in the movie were real, good. And, on a side note, the part where the ladies think that the painter doesn't speak English but then he surprises them about it is hilarious in my opinion.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Romantic Fantasy
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    dizzjay
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/1/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I saw this film shortly before watching In Her Shoes with Toni Collette and Cameron Diaz. There are a lot of similarities between the two films. They both have great casts and good acting. They both have stock characters of sisters who are very different, an offensive stepmother, a woman friend/confidant, an emotionally unavailable father, a dead mother and a surprise lover. Both films have the characters experience life-changing realizations and both films suffer from a kind of 'love conquers all' sentimentality. They both add a little titillation with Cameron Diaz in black underwear and a partial back shot of Gwyneth Paltrow naked. Both films seem contrived, as if the writers of the works the films are based on did market research and said, "Ok, there's a market for stories about relationships between women, so I'm going to write about two sisters with an offensive stepmother" In other words, instead of the drama emerging from the truth of the relationship, the relationship is invented to fit the dramatic situation. It seems forced, the characters don't seem real, the relationships are unbelievable. The resolution of the tensions between the characters is simplistic with simple apologies completely whisking away years of acrimony leaving everyone feeling warm and fuzzy ever after. It's just not real. Romantic fantasy. The characters in In Her Shoes are a little more overblown than Moonlight & Valentino, especially the stepmother part. Sydelle Feller, in In Her Shoes is so evil that it is difficult to believe that the father would stay with her, or even marry her in the first place. Kathleen Turner at least shows some emotional vulnerability as the stepmother in Moonlight & Valentino. If you liked Moonlight & Valentino you will probably like In Her Shoes as well. Enjoyable performances in both, in fact, the actors bring depth to their parts that goes way beyond the contrived sentimentality of the scripts.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Embarrassingly shallow
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    sstuart3-1
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/10/2005
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It's hard to rate this movie because it had such a terrific cast. The script was dreadful, stupid, silly. You shouldn't actually have to lose a husband to see the absolute falseness of the script. But to cast these great actresses in that story and require that they say those lines was an appalling waste. It is a tribute to their skill that the movie was even possible to watch at all. They did the best they could, but I found it painful to watch, not because I found the story touching but because it was so embarrassingly shallow. You can be sad and funny without being trivial. There are plenty of movies out there to prove it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Common People Vote Higher
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    oiwiein
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/6/2005
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I'm not one to usually admit I was teared up during a movie but this movie got me at least three times. That alone should give it a 7 rating but I added one more. I guess I really understood Lucy in the movie since those are the type of women I would date. Once you get to know them all, all 4 that is, you can really understand this complex relationship. I will not go into too many details but this is a must watch movie and not a perfect 10 but pretty darn good. I cannot believe that this has under a 6 rating not true at all. So i have to add a few more lines. OK then vote for this movie with your heart not from a spectacularly sensational Hollywood standpoint.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Great actresses in a mediocre film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Maoui
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/8/2003
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Moonlight and Valentino is the sincere attempt to portray a grieving woman.When I saw the film for the first time I was amazed by the acting abilities of Elizabeth Perkins. The rest of the cast was also great. (Gwyneth Paltrow,Kathleen Turner, Whoopi Goldberg give all great performances)Unfortunately the film is not coherent enough and the ending is also very flat.So it was not a great movie but at least entertaining with great and charming actresses. 6/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    It was alright....a bit boring though...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    crystalc1020
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/4/2003
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I just got finished watching this movie last night. I had always wanted to see it and so when it unexpectedly came on tv last night, I decided to watch it. Well...I have mixed feelings about this movie. ****************NOTE!! SPOILERS!!!!************************* I thought the acting overall was good...I was a bit dissapointed however in Perkin's character, and how emotionless she was after he husband died. I know that part of this was because she was partly shocked and in denial, but still....I expected a STRONGER outburst of emotion from her. This is your HUSBAND that has just died for goodness sakes! Not only that, but I felt like this movie tended to go on and on with not real point. IT felt very boring at times, and just plotless. I liked how the movie focuses on each of the women's lives and the problems they are facing in them, however if I were the director, I would have had the movie continue on with a slightly FASTER pace. The movie felt like 2 hours long when I had only watched an hour of it! Bottom line: I didn't even finish this movie because it was just sooo slow and kind of boring. I was already tired to begin with...I didn't need this movie to put me even faster to sleep. However, if you want a good chick flick about women overcoming thier problems in life, then this movie is for you. The acting is great (except that little part I mentioned above) and the it's a touching story about enduring hardships, and moving on with your life after a tragic death.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
 </reviews>
</filme>
