<filme>
 <id>
  1444
 </id>
 <imdburl>
  http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0059793
 </imdburl>
 <ano>
  1965
 </ano>
 <titulo>
  O Diab&oacute;lico Agente D.C.
 </titulo>
 <rating>
  6.4
 </rating>
 <sinopse>
  A woman is kidnapped. While in captivity, she manages to send a message out with a wandering cat. The cat's owner calls the FBI. The FBI tries to follow the cat. Jealous boyfriends and nosy... &nbsp;&raquo;
 </sinopse>
 <storyline>
  A woman is kidnapped. While in captivity, she manages to send a message out with a wandering cat. The cat's owner calls the FBI. The FBI tries to follow the cat. Jealous boyfriends and nosy neighbours also get in the act.
 </storyline>
 <generos>
  <genero>
   Comedy
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Thriller
  </genero>
 </generos>
 <keywords>
  <keyword>
   cat
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   fbi
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   wristwatch
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   bank robbery
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   kidnapping
  </keyword>
 </keywords>
 <diretores>
  <diretor>
   Robert Stevenson
  </diretor>
 </diretores>
 <escritores>
  <escritor>
   Gordon Gordon
  </escritor>
  <escritor>
   Mildred Gordon
  </escritor>
 </escritores>
 <atores>
  <ator>
   Hayley Mills
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Dean Jones
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Dorothy Provine
  </ator>
 </atores>
 <reviews>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    What time is it Kitty Kat?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    JohnRouseMerriottChard
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    That Darn Cat! is out of Disney Productions and directed by Robert Stevenson. Collectively written by Bill Walsh and The Gordons (Mildred & Gordon), it stars Hayley Mills, Dean Jones, Dorothy Provine, Roddy McDowall, Neville Brand and Frank Gorshin. Music is by Robert F. Brunner and cinematography by Edward Colman. When DC the Siamese cat is found to have a watch around his neck, one of his owners, Pattii Randall (Mills), alerts the FBI to the possibility it's a clue to a recent kidnapping. Cue much malarkey as humans and cat try to solve the crime whilst staying one step/paw ahead of the criminals... Utterly harmless fluff from the House of the Mouse, That Darn Cat! is basically a live action cartoon. Away from the wonderful cat(s) performance - and the skillful capturing of said cat(s) reactions to situations - there's no great technical genius here. Nothing wrong with that, this is good old fashioned entertainment for the kids to chuckle along with and for the adults to smile at. Yes some of the performances are twee or precious, and the story is silly, but it's honest family fare that's also boosted by Ed Wynn and Elsa Lanchester in secondary support slots. 6.5/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Unthrilling Uncomic Thriller Comedy !
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ahmed elshikh (ahmed_abd_elreheem@yahoo.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/6/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is one of the longest movies in history. It was more boring than watching water vaporizing in a glass under the sun ! And at one of the authentic posters you'll read "Walt Disney's Most Hilarious Comedy". LIARS, LIARS ! It is an insult to both Disney's studio and us !! The cat is dull, and most of all incredibly ugly. His presence is awful on screen. The kidnapped woman was creepy, I wonder how the 2 kidnappers didn't die out of the horror of looking to her face ! Frank Gorshin is the best one ever impersonated Richard Burton and Burt Lancaster, the thing is here he gave the worst impersonation of Richard Wedmark. He was overacting with no comedy, and watching him was nothing but PAIN. Roddy McDowall was totally wasted, as much as everybody I think. Dean Jones did one of his worst roles and movies. His comedy as someone who's allergic to saying the word cat (??) was damn pathetic. His sudden cold whenever he faces the cat was there, then wasn't. He seemed unfunny idiot for half of the time, and stiff for the rest ! And how come Hayley Mills talks with a British accent ?! Nobody contributed to give any explanation for that ! Even the title song, sang by Bobby Darin or else, isn't great or entertaining ! This movie suffers from too many unfunny characters (adulator nervous neighbor, elegant FBI agent, chief of police who works as a chief of police, older sister who combs her hair before sleep, ..) I felt bland all over. Look at the old lady next door, played by Elsa Lanchester. According to the way she looked and shot, she was horrendous, and anything but laughable. At one moment she does slap her poor husband. Not a funny thing by any mean ! True there were more amusing characters (noisy landlady, neurotic jeweler, subdued semi-deaf husband), however  sorrowfully  they were all unused ! The main situation is dealt with by shamefully uncreative style. The sketches are dry, and there is absolutely no step goes ahead in the matter of the hostage or the search for her. Simply the comedy and the thrill are beaten to death in this movie. I watched so empty, so talkative, so silly first and second act. Then there was a short third act where some comedy and thrill appeared, yet didn't pay off 2 hours of useless nonentity before it. Being 80 minutes movie should have been more merciful ! There is something greatly sexy about Hayley Mills. I believe that Hollywood, and the life, of today don't have girls of that shape anymore. Her short blond hair reminded me of my obsession; Marilyn Monroe, her type of clothes did seduce me more than looking decent, and with those glasses she oozed special sex appeal. But that too much politeness annoyed me. At times I wanted that crazy-about-surfing boy to give his girl a French kiss, that FBI agent run accidentally into the older sister while she's naked in the shower, I wanted the unforgettably raunchy weather forecast's girl, with the black swimsuit, dance erotically non-stop for as long as she can. Well, I see daydreams such as these only when it concerns a movie with nothing to love or watch ! What I'll remember form it though is some lines. The old "I know what cooks in your tiny little mind". The witty "I didn't come in from Stupidsville on last night's bus!". The expressive "I look yuck in yellow!". And the most funny, rather the only funny, : "Get me the police. I want to report a prowler. Yeah, he's dressed like an old woman. Running around, looking in windows. And tell your men to be careful. He's dangerous!". In other cases I may say "For the nostalgic feel of it.." NO. FORGET IT UTTERLY. THIS TIME I WOULDN'T. Because except very few factors : The bright image, Hayley Mills' presence, some lines, and that unforgettably raunchy weather forecast's girl, this is a movie that fails at achieving its goals. It ends up as bad memory, or  at best  sweet torture. A darn cat, a darn movie !
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A heady mix of Disney-cat cinema and crime drama - say yes!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Dahlia M.
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/1/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is one of the best films I have seen, it's very funny in the sort of whimsical way which you should be aspiring to appreciate--it is also a compelling and well-paced thriller with plenty of menace and mounting tension. Hayley Mills is excellent; the main bloke (the one who is an F.B.I. agent) is very good; the one who is Hayley Mills' boyfriend is fantastic, very very funny; Roddy McDowall is always adequate; the sister is quite good; Elsa Lanchester is great; the one who is Elsa Lanchester's husband is also really good--I don't know his name but I saw him in an episode of The Twilight Zone or one of those shows the other day and he was very good there too; the main baddie is excellent, very scary; Frank Gorshin is the other baddie who is a bit nicer but also dangerous! ...And of course this film is notable because it also features a cat, which is very rare; the cat is actually not that great, it's in some ways the weakest member of the cast and doesn't really pull its weight--it's not a cute cat (which is good): that would have been an elementary error, all the same it gives a lacklustre and disinterested performance reminiscent of recent Robert de Niro roles. Let's not worry about that though, this film is bloody brilliant and you must all try to see it if you haven't already. Yes!!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Much better than the remake by a country mile
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    TheLittleSongbird
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/5/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This film may be unexceptional and not a 5-star masterpiece but goodness isn't it an improvement over the 1997 remake? Even with Christina Ricci in it, that film turned out to be very disappointing if somewhat watchable with one or two decent performances to savour. This 1965 film is a little too long and dated, and there are some parts where it is a little slow, however it is a lively piece of entertainment that is efficiently directed and is further advantaged by an exceptional cast. The script does have some nice, subtle, humorous touches while the music is nice and the plot carefully constructed. The cast elevate this though from a moderately enjoyable film to an entertaining, lively if somewhat unexceptional one. Hayley Mills is just perky enough in the title role, and William Damerest and Elsa Lanchester are fun support. However it is Dean Jones as the FBI agent with a cat allergy and Roddy McDowall as a drip whose ducks are the feline's favourite playmates who are the standouts in the human cast, while it is the cat who steals the film by a considerable whisker. Overall, not always exceptional, but a vast improvement over its remake. 7/10 Bethany Cox
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    great entertainer
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    arun_singh300-1
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/5/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    a little black tom cat on a night prowl ,a kidnapped bank cashier puts her watch around his neck.the cat's owner a teenage girl discovers the watch alerts FBI .FBI follow cat around.ultimately it leads to the kidnappers and bank robbers. Hayley Mills is really good and funny.Dean Jones is much harassed by the girl and her sister and is allergic to cats.he is the one posted at their house. Roddy McDowell too is funny. the drive-in scene is quite hilarious.cat trying to steal duck or trying to steal pigeons.dean Jones trying to get cat's paw prints.cat stealing dog's food and hoodwinking FBI agents.listening intelligibly to human conversation as if understanding everything. this a nice entertainer.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Best Feline Performance in Movie History
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Rob-120 (lindsayrs@msn.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/4/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    If you've ever had a Siamese cat, you will know that they are the wise guys of the cat world. In the history of the movies, there haven't been too many significant cat performances. Cats do not take direction well. On the movie set, they probably spend a lot of time arguing with directors over how to play a scene. If the studio would let them, cats would probably want to direct the movie themselves. "That Darn Cat!" features the best movie performance ever by a cat. The leading man -- or cat, in this case -- is a crafty Siamese named D.C. (Darn Cat). He is the star of the movie, the one who carries the story. And he does it with suave feline sophistication. (Never mind that several cats played the role of D.C. in making the film. They were *all* good.) D.C. is a smooth operator. Like Bogart, he prowls the back streets of his suburban L.A. neighborhood, the king of his territory, his blue eyes observing everything, his nose to the wind, his mind working out all the angles. Throughout the movie, D.C. is performing tricks and stunts that would make Lassie or Rin-Tin-Tin envious. Take the movie's opening scene. D.C. hops up on a backyard fence, attracting the neighbor's dog, a Scottie, who jumps up and down at the fence, barking furiously, trying to get the cat. Then, D.C. hops down and slips into the yard through a crack in the fence. He strolls casually past the barking, leaping dog, and helps himself to the dog's supper dish. Eventually, the dog turns around. He does a double-take and runs at D.C., who calmly slips out through another crack in the fence. It's a classic Siamese trick! I have *owned* Siamese cats who would pull tricks like that on the neighborhood dogs. One night, when he is out for a stroll, D.C. stumbles into the hideout of two bumbling bank robbers (Frank Gorshin; Neville Brand) who took a female bank teller (Grayson Hall) as a hostage in their last robbery. The bank teller puts her wristwatch around D.C.'s neck with a message for "help" on the back, and tosses D.C. out the door. When D.C. returns home, his young owner, Patti Randall (Hayley Mills), finds the watch and the message. Patti is smart enough to figure out what has happened, and contacts F.B.I. agent Zeke Kelso (Dean Jones). The following night, the F.B.I. sets up a unique operation to track D.C. through the neighborhood, hoping the cat will lead them back to the bank robbers' hideout. The movie has a genuinely funny script, co-written by Bill Walsh (screenwriter on "Mary Poppins") and Gordon and Mildred Gordon, authors of the novel, "Undercover Cat," on which the movie was based. I've read the novel, and the Gordons really knew their cats, and how cats relate (or don't relate) to humans. A lot of the humor in the movie comes from D.C. having to deal with "non-cat people," especially Agent Kelso, who is allergic to cats. One of the funniest scenes in the movie comes when Kelso has to take D.C.'s paw print, and can't figure out how to fit D.C.'s prints onto the standard FBI fingerprint card. Needless to say, D.C. does not like having his paw printed. Hayley Mills does well in her last role for Disney. As Patti, she projects a kind of eager, Nancy Drew-like enthusiasm when she finds herself embroiled in a mystery. Even when the FBI starts to doubt her theory that D.C. has found the bank robbers, she still persists in her investigation. She knows she is right! Perhaps that's why she is the only human in the film that D.C. puts up with -- he finds her to be of equal intelligence to himself. There are small but ingenious supporting performances in the movie, little gems of character acting. Dorothy Provine plays Patti's older sister, Ingrid, who can't believe the fuss that occurs. Roddy McDowell is Ingrid's snobbish boyfriend. Elsa Lanchester and William Demarest are a pair of squabbling neighbors who know that something is going on next door. And Tom Lowell plays Patti's dopey boyfriend, Canoe, who is obsessed with surfing movies. (Some of the funniest gags in the movie occur late in the film, when Canoe accidentally gets involved in the FBI's trailing of D.C. through the neighborhood.) There are some funny cameos. Ed Wynn plays a nervous shop owner that Patti cons into helping her with the investigation. Iris Adrian has a great scene as a landlady who bullies the two bank robbers. And Richard Deacon has a funny role as a drive-in manager. But again, it is D.C. the cat who really carries the picture. It is the cat who outwits both the FBI and the bad guys, and saves the day at the end of the film. He probably wouldn't even care that Hayley Mills got star billing in the movie. For D.C., the greatest joy would be in the giving of his performance -- for what greater joy is there for a cat than simply the joy of...being a cat? P.S. The sly opening song, written by the Sherman Brothers, and sung by Bobby Darin, sets the tone of D.C.'s character perfectly. It is the most accurate song ever written about the character of a cat.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    the book was better!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    rosedawson-2
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/12/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The novel, "That Darn Cat," was written by The Gordons and published a few years before the movie came out. I read the book and it's excellent. It's set in Los Angeles and clearly has an adult slant, although people of all ages who like mysteries would enjoy the novel. There was both humor and suspense in the book---but the movie was written like a sitcom and everyone acted too silly and zany. The movie should have been filmed on the streets of Los Angeles rather than the fake-looking backlot of Disney Studios! Obviously The Gordons (husband & wife mystery writers) knew that in order to turn their excellent novel into a Disney film (circa 1965) they had to write a screenplay that was bland and silly. The movie is okay but the novel is much better!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Gosh Darn It
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    fom4life
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/10/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    As I re-watched TDC, I was planning on giving it a recommendation for inclusion in a family library. That was because it has such a talented and wonderful cast and because this film is considered a Disney classic. They even made a remake for Pete's sake. I was only mildly amused in the beginning and somewhere part way through something clicked in the film for me. I noticed all the chases and characters running here and there and everywhere and then realized that 'Hey, this really is worth writing home about. I was busy reading a book on Bob Hope when I was watching it, so I didn't pay as much attention as I should have given the film. Gosh if I'm going to review films I should give them the attention they deserve gosh DARN it. But I have seen it before and should see it again. But despite the non-descriptive review, I can say it is another Disney film that is worth putting in your library because it is a fun harmless picture that little ones can watch without cause to worry.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    just lovely...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    comeonandrock
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/3/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    one of my favorite movies of all times...reminds me of a quiet childhood...sparkly, intelligent script...lovely acting(the way it's supposed to be, not your lame nowadays style)...a treasure...enriched my life. i was so happy to see the DVD in the store... probably seen it fifty times already, since i got it...my daughter liked it too....i'll keep watching it until i know it by heart...it just brings so much joy... well...some movies rock and this is one of them, in my opinion... i also enjoyed the soundtrack....thanks for posting the lyrics, though you can copy them from the subtitles...
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Cute, sweet comedy
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Grann-Bach (Grann-Bach@jubii.dk)
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/7/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    My first thought as the movie started was that it was "a live action Tom & Jerry". The film spends a lot of its time following the title cat, and whilst the cinematography and editing(complete with footage that has been sped up for comedic effect) might not break any new ground, it works really well, and the overall product is entertaining and never really slow or repetitive. The humor remains fresh throughout, and in spite of several changes of perspective and which characters it focuses on, the whole thing runs smoothly. The picture may not be intricate, but it's good for what it is, it's good to watch without having to think, and hey, it never claims to be Shakespeare. This is good, slightly goofy and occasionally overplayed(but never to the point of annoyance) fun, with a Siamese cat in the lead. The score, as my fianc&eacute;e pointed out, surely to fill with just the cat on the screen, is most apparent when, well, it's only the cat on the screen. It works very well, a nice jazz composition(keep your ears open for a Batman-esquire cue(although this precedes the infamous show)). The acting is fitting... some is over the top, some nicely underplayed. Grayson Hall does well with fairly little in amount. The plot is fairly simplistic, and many of the situations come from complications and such. I recommend it to fans of Hayley Mills, cats and Disney. 7/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    What time is it Kitty Kat?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    JohnRouseMerriottChard
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    That Darn Cat! is out of Disney Productions and directed by Robert Stevenson. Collectively written by Bill Walsh and The Gordons (Mildred & Gordon), it stars Hayley Mills, Dean Jones, Dorothy Provine, Roddy McDowall, Neville Brand and Frank Gorshin. Music is by Robert F. Brunner and cinematography by Edward Colman. When DC the Siamese cat is found to have a watch around his neck, one of his owners, Pattii Randall (Mills), alerts the FBI to the possibility it's a clue to a recent kidnapping. Cue much malarkey as humans and cat try to solve the crime whilst staying one step/paw ahead of the criminals... Utterly harmless fluff from the House of the Mouse, That Darn Cat! is basically a live action cartoon. Away from the wonderful cat(s) performance - and the skillful capturing of said cat(s) reactions to situations - there's no great technical genius here. Nothing wrong with that, this is good old fashioned entertainment for the kids to chuckle along with and for the adults to smile at. Yes some of the performances are twee or precious, and the story is silly, but it's honest family fare that's also boosted by Ed Wynn and Elsa Lanchester in secondary support slots. 6.5/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Unthrilling Uncomic Thriller Comedy !
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ahmed elshikh (ahmed_abd_elreheem@yahoo.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/6/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is one of the longest movies in history. It was more boring than watching water vaporizing in a glass under the sun ! And at one of the authentic posters you'll read "Walt Disney's Most Hilarious Comedy". LIARS, LIARS ! It is an insult to both Disney's studio and us !! The cat is dull, and most of all incredibly ugly. His presence is awful on screen. The kidnapped woman was creepy, I wonder how the 2 kidnappers didn't die out of the horror of looking to her face ! Frank Gorshin is the best one ever impersonated Richard Burton and Burt Lancaster, the thing is here he gave the worst impersonation of Richard Wedmark. He was overacting with no comedy, and watching him was nothing but PAIN. Roddy McDowall was totally wasted, as much as everybody I think. Dean Jones did one of his worst roles and movies. His comedy as someone who's allergic to saying the word cat (??) was damn pathetic. His sudden cold whenever he faces the cat was there, then wasn't. He seemed unfunny idiot for half of the time, and stiff for the rest ! And how come Hayley Mills talks with a British accent ?! Nobody contributed to give any explanation for that ! Even the title song, sang by Bobby Darin or else, isn't great or entertaining ! This movie suffers from too many unfunny characters (adulator nervous neighbor, elegant FBI agent, chief of police who works as a chief of police, older sister who combs her hair before sleep, ..) I felt bland all over. Look at the old lady next door, played by Elsa Lanchester. According to the way she looked and shot, she was horrendous, and anything but laughable. At one moment she does slap her poor husband. Not a funny thing by any mean ! True there were more amusing characters (noisy landlady, neurotic jeweler, subdued semi-deaf husband), however  sorrowfully  they were all unused ! The main situation is dealt with by shamefully uncreative style. The sketches are dry, and there is absolutely no step goes ahead in the matter of the hostage or the search for her. Simply the comedy and the thrill are beaten to death in this movie. I watched so empty, so talkative, so silly first and second act. Then there was a short third act where some comedy and thrill appeared, yet didn't pay off 2 hours of useless nonentity before it. Being 80 minutes movie should have been more merciful ! There is something greatly sexy about Hayley Mills. I believe that Hollywood, and the life, of today don't have girls of that shape anymore. Her short blond hair reminded me of my obsession; Marilyn Monroe, her type of clothes did seduce me more than looking decent, and with those glasses she oozed special sex appeal. But that too much politeness annoyed me. At times I wanted that crazy-about-surfing boy to give his girl a French kiss, that FBI agent run accidentally into the older sister while she's naked in the shower, I wanted the unforgettably raunchy weather forecast's girl, with the black swimsuit, dance erotically non-stop for as long as she can. Well, I see daydreams such as these only when it concerns a movie with nothing to love or watch ! What I'll remember form it though is some lines. The old "I know what cooks in your tiny little mind". The witty "I didn't come in from Stupidsville on last night's bus!". The expressive "I look yuck in yellow!". And the most funny, rather the only funny, : "Get me the police. I want to report a prowler. Yeah, he's dressed like an old woman. Running around, looking in windows. And tell your men to be careful. He's dangerous!". In other cases I may say "For the nostalgic feel of it.." NO. FORGET IT UTTERLY. THIS TIME I WOULDN'T. Because except very few factors : The bright image, Hayley Mills' presence, some lines, and that unforgettably raunchy weather forecast's girl, this is a movie that fails at achieving its goals. It ends up as bad memory, or  at best  sweet torture. A darn cat, a darn movie !
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A heady mix of Disney-cat cinema and crime drama - say yes!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Dahlia M.
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/1/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is one of the best films I have seen, it's very funny in the sort of whimsical way which you should be aspiring to appreciate--it is also a compelling and well-paced thriller with plenty of menace and mounting tension. Hayley Mills is excellent; the main bloke (the one who is an F.B.I. agent) is very good; the one who is Hayley Mills' boyfriend is fantastic, very very funny; Roddy McDowall is always adequate; the sister is quite good; Elsa Lanchester is great; the one who is Elsa Lanchester's husband is also really good--I don't know his name but I saw him in an episode of The Twilight Zone or one of those shows the other day and he was very good there too; the main baddie is excellent, very scary; Frank Gorshin is the other baddie who is a bit nicer but also dangerous! ...And of course this film is notable because it also features a cat, which is very rare; the cat is actually not that great, it's in some ways the weakest member of the cast and doesn't really pull its weight--it's not a cute cat (which is good): that would have been an elementary error, all the same it gives a lacklustre and disinterested performance reminiscent of recent Robert de Niro roles. Let's not worry about that though, this film is bloody brilliant and you must all try to see it if you haven't already. Yes!!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Much better than the remake by a country mile
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    TheLittleSongbird
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/5/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This film may be unexceptional and not a 5-star masterpiece but goodness isn't it an improvement over the 1997 remake? Even with Christina Ricci in it, that film turned out to be very disappointing if somewhat watchable with one or two decent performances to savour. This 1965 film is a little too long and dated, and there are some parts where it is a little slow, however it is a lively piece of entertainment that is efficiently directed and is further advantaged by an exceptional cast. The script does have some nice, subtle, humorous touches while the music is nice and the plot carefully constructed. The cast elevate this though from a moderately enjoyable film to an entertaining, lively if somewhat unexceptional one. Hayley Mills is just perky enough in the title role, and William Damerest and Elsa Lanchester are fun support. However it is Dean Jones as the FBI agent with a cat allergy and Roddy McDowall as a drip whose ducks are the feline's favourite playmates who are the standouts in the human cast, while it is the cat who steals the film by a considerable whisker. Overall, not always exceptional, but a vast improvement over its remake. 7/10 Bethany Cox
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    great entertainer
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    arun_singh300-1
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/5/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    a little black tom cat on a night prowl ,a kidnapped bank cashier puts her watch around his neck.the cat's owner a teenage girl discovers the watch alerts FBI .FBI follow cat around.ultimately it leads to the kidnappers and bank robbers. Hayley Mills is really good and funny.Dean Jones is much harassed by the girl and her sister and is allergic to cats.he is the one posted at their house. Roddy McDowell too is funny. the drive-in scene is quite hilarious.cat trying to steal duck or trying to steal pigeons.dean Jones trying to get cat's paw prints.cat stealing dog's food and hoodwinking FBI agents.listening intelligibly to human conversation as if understanding everything. this a nice entertainer.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Best Feline Performance in Movie History
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Rob-120 (lindsayrs@msn.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/4/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    If you've ever had a Siamese cat, you will know that they are the wise guys of the cat world. In the history of the movies, there haven't been too many significant cat performances. Cats do not take direction well. On the movie set, they probably spend a lot of time arguing with directors over how to play a scene. If the studio would let them, cats would probably want to direct the movie themselves. "That Darn Cat!" features the best movie performance ever by a cat. The leading man -- or cat, in this case -- is a crafty Siamese named D.C. (Darn Cat). He is the star of the movie, the one who carries the story. And he does it with suave feline sophistication. (Never mind that several cats played the role of D.C. in making the film. They were *all* good.) D.C. is a smooth operator. Like Bogart, he prowls the back streets of his suburban L.A. neighborhood, the king of his territory, his blue eyes observing everything, his nose to the wind, his mind working out all the angles. Throughout the movie, D.C. is performing tricks and stunts that would make Lassie or Rin-Tin-Tin envious. Take the movie's opening scene. D.C. hops up on a backyard fence, attracting the neighbor's dog, a Scottie, who jumps up and down at the fence, barking furiously, trying to get the cat. Then, D.C. hops down and slips into the yard through a crack in the fence. He strolls casually past the barking, leaping dog, and helps himself to the dog's supper dish. Eventually, the dog turns around. He does a double-take and runs at D.C., who calmly slips out through another crack in the fence. It's a classic Siamese trick! I have *owned* Siamese cats who would pull tricks like that on the neighborhood dogs. One night, when he is out for a stroll, D.C. stumbles into the hideout of two bumbling bank robbers (Frank Gorshin; Neville Brand) who took a female bank teller (Grayson Hall) as a hostage in their last robbery. The bank teller puts her wristwatch around D.C.'s neck with a message for "help" on the back, and tosses D.C. out the door. When D.C. returns home, his young owner, Patti Randall (Hayley Mills), finds the watch and the message. Patti is smart enough to figure out what has happened, and contacts F.B.I. agent Zeke Kelso (Dean Jones). The following night, the F.B.I. sets up a unique operation to track D.C. through the neighborhood, hoping the cat will lead them back to the bank robbers' hideout. The movie has a genuinely funny script, co-written by Bill Walsh (screenwriter on "Mary Poppins") and Gordon and Mildred Gordon, authors of the novel, "Undercover Cat," on which the movie was based. I've read the novel, and the Gordons really knew their cats, and how cats relate (or don't relate) to humans. A lot of the humor in the movie comes from D.C. having to deal with "non-cat people," especially Agent Kelso, who is allergic to cats. One of the funniest scenes in the movie comes when Kelso has to take D.C.'s paw print, and can't figure out how to fit D.C.'s prints onto the standard FBI fingerprint card. Needless to say, D.C. does not like having his paw printed. Hayley Mills does well in her last role for Disney. As Patti, she projects a kind of eager, Nancy Drew-like enthusiasm when she finds herself embroiled in a mystery. Even when the FBI starts to doubt her theory that D.C. has found the bank robbers, she still persists in her investigation. She knows she is right! Perhaps that's why she is the only human in the film that D.C. puts up with -- he finds her to be of equal intelligence to himself. There are small but ingenious supporting performances in the movie, little gems of character acting. Dorothy Provine plays Patti's older sister, Ingrid, who can't believe the fuss that occurs. Roddy McDowell is Ingrid's snobbish boyfriend. Elsa Lanchester and William Demarest are a pair of squabbling neighbors who know that something is going on next door. And Tom Lowell plays Patti's dopey boyfriend, Canoe, who is obsessed with surfing movies. (Some of the funniest gags in the movie occur late in the film, when Canoe accidentally gets involved in the FBI's trailing of D.C. through the neighborhood.) There are some funny cameos. Ed Wynn plays a nervous shop owner that Patti cons into helping her with the investigation. Iris Adrian has a great scene as a landlady who bullies the two bank robbers. And Richard Deacon has a funny role as a drive-in manager. But again, it is D.C. the cat who really carries the picture. It is the cat who outwits both the FBI and the bad guys, and saves the day at the end of the film. He probably wouldn't even care that Hayley Mills got star billing in the movie. For D.C., the greatest joy would be in the giving of his performance -- for what greater joy is there for a cat than simply the joy of...being a cat? P.S. The sly opening song, written by the Sherman Brothers, and sung by Bobby Darin, sets the tone of D.C.'s character perfectly. It is the most accurate song ever written about the character of a cat.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    the book was better!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    rosedawson-2
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/12/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The novel, "That Darn Cat," was written by The Gordons and published a few years before the movie came out. I read the book and it's excellent. It's set in Los Angeles and clearly has an adult slant, although people of all ages who like mysteries would enjoy the novel. There was both humor and suspense in the book---but the movie was written like a sitcom and everyone acted too silly and zany. The movie should have been filmed on the streets of Los Angeles rather than the fake-looking backlot of Disney Studios! Obviously The Gordons (husband & wife mystery writers) knew that in order to turn their excellent novel into a Disney film (circa 1965) they had to write a screenplay that was bland and silly. The movie is okay but the novel is much better!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Gosh Darn It
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    fom4life
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/10/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    As I re-watched TDC, I was planning on giving it a recommendation for inclusion in a family library. That was because it has such a talented and wonderful cast and because this film is considered a Disney classic. They even made a remake for Pete's sake. I was only mildly amused in the beginning and somewhere part way through something clicked in the film for me. I noticed all the chases and characters running here and there and everywhere and then realized that 'Hey, this really is worth writing home about. I was busy reading a book on Bob Hope when I was watching it, so I didn't pay as much attention as I should have given the film. Gosh if I'm going to review films I should give them the attention they deserve gosh DARN it. But I have seen it before and should see it again. But despite the non-descriptive review, I can say it is another Disney film that is worth putting in your library because it is a fun harmless picture that little ones can watch without cause to worry.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    just lovely...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    comeonandrock
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/3/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    one of my favorite movies of all times...reminds me of a quiet childhood...sparkly, intelligent script...lovely acting(the way it's supposed to be, not your lame nowadays style)...a treasure...enriched my life. i was so happy to see the DVD in the store... probably seen it fifty times already, since i got it...my daughter liked it too....i'll keep watching it until i know it by heart...it just brings so much joy... well...some movies rock and this is one of them, in my opinion... i also enjoyed the soundtrack....thanks for posting the lyrics, though you can copy them from the subtitles...
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Cute, sweet comedy
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Grann-Bach (Grann-Bach@jubii.dk)
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/7/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    My first thought as the movie started was that it was "a live action Tom & Jerry". The film spends a lot of its time following the title cat, and whilst the cinematography and editing(complete with footage that has been sped up for comedic effect) might not break any new ground, it works really well, and the overall product is entertaining and never really slow or repetitive. The humor remains fresh throughout, and in spite of several changes of perspective and which characters it focuses on, the whole thing runs smoothly. The picture may not be intricate, but it's good for what it is, it's good to watch without having to think, and hey, it never claims to be Shakespeare. This is good, slightly goofy and occasionally overplayed(but never to the point of annoyance) fun, with a Siamese cat in the lead. The score, as my fianc&eacute;e pointed out, surely to fill with just the cat on the screen, is most apparent when, well, it's only the cat on the screen. It works very well, a nice jazz composition(keep your ears open for a Batman-esquire cue(although this precedes the infamous show)). The acting is fitting... some is over the top, some nicely underplayed. Grayson Hall does well with fairly little in amount. The plot is fairly simplistic, and many of the situations come from complications and such. I recommend it to fans of Hayley Mills, cats and Disney. 7/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    What time is it Kitty Kat?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    JohnRouseMerriottChard
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    That Darn Cat! is out of Disney Productions and directed by Robert Stevenson. Collectively written by Bill Walsh and The Gordons (Mildred & Gordon), it stars Hayley Mills, Dean Jones, Dorothy Provine, Roddy McDowall, Neville Brand and Frank Gorshin. Music is by Robert F. Brunner and cinematography by Edward Colman. When DC the Siamese cat is found to have a watch around his neck, one of his owners, Pattii Randall (Mills), alerts the FBI to the possibility it's a clue to a recent kidnapping. Cue much malarkey as humans and cat try to solve the crime whilst staying one step/paw ahead of the criminals... Utterly harmless fluff from the House of the Mouse, That Darn Cat! is basically a live action cartoon. Away from the wonderful cat(s) performance - and the skillful capturing of said cat(s) reactions to situations - there's no great technical genius here. Nothing wrong with that, this is good old fashioned entertainment for the kids to chuckle along with and for the adults to smile at. Yes some of the performances are twee or precious, and the story is silly, but it's honest family fare that's also boosted by Ed Wynn and Elsa Lanchester in secondary support slots. 6.5/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Unthrilling Uncomic Thriller Comedy !
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ahmed elshikh (ahmed_abd_elreheem@yahoo.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/6/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is one of the longest movies in history. It was more boring than watching water vaporizing in a glass under the sun ! And at one of the authentic posters you'll read "Walt Disney's Most Hilarious Comedy". LIARS, LIARS ! It is an insult to both Disney's studio and us !! The cat is dull, and most of all incredibly ugly. His presence is awful on screen. The kidnapped woman was creepy, I wonder how the 2 kidnappers didn't die out of the horror of looking to her face ! Frank Gorshin is the best one ever impersonated Richard Burton and Burt Lancaster, the thing is here he gave the worst impersonation of Richard Wedmark. He was overacting with no comedy, and watching him was nothing but PAIN. Roddy McDowall was totally wasted, as much as everybody I think. Dean Jones did one of his worst roles and movies. His comedy as someone who's allergic to saying the word cat (??) was damn pathetic. His sudden cold whenever he faces the cat was there, then wasn't. He seemed unfunny idiot for half of the time, and stiff for the rest ! And how come Hayley Mills talks with a British accent ?! Nobody contributed to give any explanation for that ! Even the title song, sang by Bobby Darin or else, isn't great or entertaining ! This movie suffers from too many unfunny characters (adulator nervous neighbor, elegant FBI agent, chief of police who works as a chief of police, older sister who combs her hair before sleep, ..) I felt bland all over. Look at the old lady next door, played by Elsa Lanchester. According to the way she looked and shot, she was horrendous, and anything but laughable. At one moment she does slap her poor husband. Not a funny thing by any mean ! True there were more amusing characters (noisy landlady, neurotic jeweler, subdued semi-deaf husband), however  sorrowfully  they were all unused ! The main situation is dealt with by shamefully uncreative style. The sketches are dry, and there is absolutely no step goes ahead in the matter of the hostage or the search for her. Simply the comedy and the thrill are beaten to death in this movie. I watched so empty, so talkative, so silly first and second act. Then there was a short third act where some comedy and thrill appeared, yet didn't pay off 2 hours of useless nonentity before it. Being 80 minutes movie should have been more merciful ! There is something greatly sexy about Hayley Mills. I believe that Hollywood, and the life, of today don't have girls of that shape anymore. Her short blond hair reminded me of my obsession; Marilyn Monroe, her type of clothes did seduce me more than looking decent, and with those glasses she oozed special sex appeal. But that too much politeness annoyed me. At times I wanted that crazy-about-surfing boy to give his girl a French kiss, that FBI agent run accidentally into the older sister while she's naked in the shower, I wanted the unforgettably raunchy weather forecast's girl, with the black swimsuit, dance erotically non-stop for as long as she can. Well, I see daydreams such as these only when it concerns a movie with nothing to love or watch ! What I'll remember form it though is some lines. The old "I know what cooks in your tiny little mind". The witty "I didn't come in from Stupidsville on last night's bus!". The expressive "I look yuck in yellow!". And the most funny, rather the only funny, : "Get me the police. I want to report a prowler. Yeah, he's dressed like an old woman. Running around, looking in windows. And tell your men to be careful. He's dangerous!". In other cases I may say "For the nostalgic feel of it.." NO. FORGET IT UTTERLY. THIS TIME I WOULDN'T. Because except very few factors : The bright image, Hayley Mills' presence, some lines, and that unforgettably raunchy weather forecast's girl, this is a movie that fails at achieving its goals. It ends up as bad memory, or  at best  sweet torture. A darn cat, a darn movie !
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A heady mix of Disney-cat cinema and crime drama - say yes!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Dahlia M.
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/1/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is one of the best films I have seen, it's very funny in the sort of whimsical way which you should be aspiring to appreciate--it is also a compelling and well-paced thriller with plenty of menace and mounting tension. Hayley Mills is excellent; the main bloke (the one who is an F.B.I. agent) is very good; the one who is Hayley Mills' boyfriend is fantastic, very very funny; Roddy McDowall is always adequate; the sister is quite good; Elsa Lanchester is great; the one who is Elsa Lanchester's husband is also really good--I don't know his name but I saw him in an episode of The Twilight Zone or one of those shows the other day and he was very good there too; the main baddie is excellent, very scary; Frank Gorshin is the other baddie who is a bit nicer but also dangerous! ...And of course this film is notable because it also features a cat, which is very rare; the cat is actually not that great, it's in some ways the weakest member of the cast and doesn't really pull its weight--it's not a cute cat (which is good): that would have been an elementary error, all the same it gives a lacklustre and disinterested performance reminiscent of recent Robert de Niro roles. Let's not worry about that though, this film is bloody brilliant and you must all try to see it if you haven't already. Yes!!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Much better than the remake by a country mile
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    TheLittleSongbird
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/5/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This film may be unexceptional and not a 5-star masterpiece but goodness isn't it an improvement over the 1997 remake? Even with Christina Ricci in it, that film turned out to be very disappointing if somewhat watchable with one or two decent performances to savour. This 1965 film is a little too long and dated, and there are some parts where it is a little slow, however it is a lively piece of entertainment that is efficiently directed and is further advantaged by an exceptional cast. The script does have some nice, subtle, humorous touches while the music is nice and the plot carefully constructed. The cast elevate this though from a moderately enjoyable film to an entertaining, lively if somewhat unexceptional one. Hayley Mills is just perky enough in the title role, and William Damerest and Elsa Lanchester are fun support. However it is Dean Jones as the FBI agent with a cat allergy and Roddy McDowall as a drip whose ducks are the feline's favourite playmates who are the standouts in the human cast, while it is the cat who steals the film by a considerable whisker. Overall, not always exceptional, but a vast improvement over its remake. 7/10 Bethany Cox
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    great entertainer
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    arun_singh300-1
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/5/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    a little black tom cat on a night prowl ,a kidnapped bank cashier puts her watch around his neck.the cat's owner a teenage girl discovers the watch alerts FBI .FBI follow cat around.ultimately it leads to the kidnappers and bank robbers. Hayley Mills is really good and funny.Dean Jones is much harassed by the girl and her sister and is allergic to cats.he is the one posted at their house. Roddy McDowell too is funny. the drive-in scene is quite hilarious.cat trying to steal duck or trying to steal pigeons.dean Jones trying to get cat's paw prints.cat stealing dog's food and hoodwinking FBI agents.listening intelligibly to human conversation as if understanding everything. this a nice entertainer.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Best Feline Performance in Movie History
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Rob-120 (lindsayrs@msn.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/4/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    If you've ever had a Siamese cat, you will know that they are the wise guys of the cat world. In the history of the movies, there haven't been too many significant cat performances. Cats do not take direction well. On the movie set, they probably spend a lot of time arguing with directors over how to play a scene. If the studio would let them, cats would probably want to direct the movie themselves. "That Darn Cat!" features the best movie performance ever by a cat. The leading man -- or cat, in this case -- is a crafty Siamese named D.C. (Darn Cat). He is the star of the movie, the one who carries the story. And he does it with suave feline sophistication. (Never mind that several cats played the role of D.C. in making the film. They were *all* good.) D.C. is a smooth operator. Like Bogart, he prowls the back streets of his suburban L.A. neighborhood, the king of his territory, his blue eyes observing everything, his nose to the wind, his mind working out all the angles. Throughout the movie, D.C. is performing tricks and stunts that would make Lassie or Rin-Tin-Tin envious. Take the movie's opening scene. D.C. hops up on a backyard fence, attracting the neighbor's dog, a Scottie, who jumps up and down at the fence, barking furiously, trying to get the cat. Then, D.C. hops down and slips into the yard through a crack in the fence. He strolls casually past the barking, leaping dog, and helps himself to the dog's supper dish. Eventually, the dog turns around. He does a double-take and runs at D.C., who calmly slips out through another crack in the fence. It's a classic Siamese trick! I have *owned* Siamese cats who would pull tricks like that on the neighborhood dogs. One night, when he is out for a stroll, D.C. stumbles into the hideout of two bumbling bank robbers (Frank Gorshin; Neville Brand) who took a female bank teller (Grayson Hall) as a hostage in their last robbery. The bank teller puts her wristwatch around D.C.'s neck with a message for "help" on the back, and tosses D.C. out the door. When D.C. returns home, his young owner, Patti Randall (Hayley Mills), finds the watch and the message. Patti is smart enough to figure out what has happened, and contacts F.B.I. agent Zeke Kelso (Dean Jones). The following night, the F.B.I. sets up a unique operation to track D.C. through the neighborhood, hoping the cat will lead them back to the bank robbers' hideout. The movie has a genuinely funny script, co-written by Bill Walsh (screenwriter on "Mary Poppins") and Gordon and Mildred Gordon, authors of the novel, "Undercover Cat," on which the movie was based. I've read the novel, and the Gordons really knew their cats, and how cats relate (or don't relate) to humans. A lot of the humor in the movie comes from D.C. having to deal with "non-cat people," especially Agent Kelso, who is allergic to cats. One of the funniest scenes in the movie comes when Kelso has to take D.C.'s paw print, and can't figure out how to fit D.C.'s prints onto the standard FBI fingerprint card. Needless to say, D.C. does not like having his paw printed. Hayley Mills does well in her last role for Disney. As Patti, she projects a kind of eager, Nancy Drew-like enthusiasm when she finds herself embroiled in a mystery. Even when the FBI starts to doubt her theory that D.C. has found the bank robbers, she still persists in her investigation. She knows she is right! Perhaps that's why she is the only human in the film that D.C. puts up with -- he finds her to be of equal intelligence to himself. There are small but ingenious supporting performances in the movie, little gems of character acting. Dorothy Provine plays Patti's older sister, Ingrid, who can't believe the fuss that occurs. Roddy McDowell is Ingrid's snobbish boyfriend. Elsa Lanchester and William Demarest are a pair of squabbling neighbors who know that something is going on next door. And Tom Lowell plays Patti's dopey boyfriend, Canoe, who is obsessed with surfing movies. (Some of the funniest gags in the movie occur late in the film, when Canoe accidentally gets involved in the FBI's trailing of D.C. through the neighborhood.) There are some funny cameos. Ed Wynn plays a nervous shop owner that Patti cons into helping her with the investigation. Iris Adrian has a great scene as a landlady who bullies the two bank robbers. And Richard Deacon has a funny role as a drive-in manager. But again, it is D.C. the cat who really carries the picture. It is the cat who outwits both the FBI and the bad guys, and saves the day at the end of the film. He probably wouldn't even care that Hayley Mills got star billing in the movie. For D.C., the greatest joy would be in the giving of his performance -- for what greater joy is there for a cat than simply the joy of...being a cat? P.S. The sly opening song, written by the Sherman Brothers, and sung by Bobby Darin, sets the tone of D.C.'s character perfectly. It is the most accurate song ever written about the character of a cat.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    the book was better!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    rosedawson-2
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/12/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The novel, "That Darn Cat," was written by The Gordons and published a few years before the movie came out. I read the book and it's excellent. It's set in Los Angeles and clearly has an adult slant, although people of all ages who like mysteries would enjoy the novel. There was both humor and suspense in the book---but the movie was written like a sitcom and everyone acted too silly and zany. The movie should have been filmed on the streets of Los Angeles rather than the fake-looking backlot of Disney Studios! Obviously The Gordons (husband & wife mystery writers) knew that in order to turn their excellent novel into a Disney film (circa 1965) they had to write a screenplay that was bland and silly. The movie is okay but the novel is much better!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Gosh Darn It
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    fom4life
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/10/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    As I re-watched TDC, I was planning on giving it a recommendation for inclusion in a family library. That was because it has such a talented and wonderful cast and because this film is considered a Disney classic. They even made a remake for Pete's sake. I was only mildly amused in the beginning and somewhere part way through something clicked in the film for me. I noticed all the chases and characters running here and there and everywhere and then realized that 'Hey, this really is worth writing home about. I was busy reading a book on Bob Hope when I was watching it, so I didn't pay as much attention as I should have given the film. Gosh if I'm going to review films I should give them the attention they deserve gosh DARN it. But I have seen it before and should see it again. But despite the non-descriptive review, I can say it is another Disney film that is worth putting in your library because it is a fun harmless picture that little ones can watch without cause to worry.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    just lovely...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    comeonandrock
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/3/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    one of my favorite movies of all times...reminds me of a quiet childhood...sparkly, intelligent script...lovely acting(the way it's supposed to be, not your lame nowadays style)...a treasure...enriched my life. i was so happy to see the DVD in the store... probably seen it fifty times already, since i got it...my daughter liked it too....i'll keep watching it until i know it by heart...it just brings so much joy... well...some movies rock and this is one of them, in my opinion... i also enjoyed the soundtrack....thanks for posting the lyrics, though you can copy them from the subtitles...
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Cute, sweet comedy
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Grann-Bach (Grann-Bach@jubii.dk)
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/7/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    My first thought as the movie started was that it was "a live action Tom & Jerry". The film spends a lot of its time following the title cat, and whilst the cinematography and editing(complete with footage that has been sped up for comedic effect) might not break any new ground, it works really well, and the overall product is entertaining and never really slow or repetitive. The humor remains fresh throughout, and in spite of several changes of perspective and which characters it focuses on, the whole thing runs smoothly. The picture may not be intricate, but it's good for what it is, it's good to watch without having to think, and hey, it never claims to be Shakespeare. This is good, slightly goofy and occasionally overplayed(but never to the point of annoyance) fun, with a Siamese cat in the lead. The score, as my fianc&eacute;e pointed out, surely to fill with just the cat on the screen, is most apparent when, well, it's only the cat on the screen. It works very well, a nice jazz composition(keep your ears open for a Batman-esquire cue(although this precedes the infamous show)). The acting is fitting... some is over the top, some nicely underplayed. Grayson Hall does well with fairly little in amount. The plot is fairly simplistic, and many of the situations come from complications and such. I recommend it to fans of Hayley Mills, cats and Disney. 7/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
 </reviews>
</filme>
