<filme>
 <id>
  1452
 </id>
 <imdburl>
  http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0036094
 </imdburl>
 <ano>
  1943
 </ano>
 <titulo>
  A Morte Dirige o Espet&aacute;culo
 </titulo>
 <rating>
  6.3
 </rating>
 <sinopse>
  After one member of their group is murdered, the performers at a burlesque house must work together to find out who the killer is before they strike again.
 </sinopse>
 <storyline>
  Sassy Dixie Daisy is the hot new attraction at a former opera house that's been turned into a burlesque theater. She's popular with the customers, although not with Lolita La Verne, a stuck-up diva who was hoping she'd get the top spot. Also complicating matters is the return of the Princess Nirvena, the show's former star who once had a fling with the boss. When the Princess blackmails her way into the top spot, Dixie is none too pleased. When both Lolita and the Princess are murdered, Dixie becomes a prime suspect. She then sets up a trap to nail the real killer.
 </storyline>
 <generos>
  <genero>
   Comedy
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Horror
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Music
  </genero>
 </generos>
 <keywords>
  <keyword>
   burlesque
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   insanity
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   confession
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   comedian
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   photograph
  </keyword>
 </keywords>
 <diretores>
  <diretor>
   William A. Wellman
  </diretor>
 </diretores>
 <escritores>
  <escritor>
   Gypsy Rose Lee
  </escritor>
  <escritor>
   James Gunn
  </escritor>
 </escritores>
 <atores>
  <ator>
   Barbara Stanwyck
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Michael O'Shea
  </ator>
  <ator>
   J. Edward Bromberg
  </ator>
 </atores>
 <reviews>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Did Barbara ever make a bad film?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    earlytalkie
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/10/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Barbara Stanwyck managed to elevate nearly every film and television show she ever did. The earliest film I saw her in was "The Miracle Woman" from 1931. I just saw "Baby Face" and I own copies of "The Thorn Birds", "Stella Dallas" and this film. "Lady of Burlesque" is a wonderful, atmospheric depiction of an bygone era, complete with Stanwyck doing some amazing dance moves. Some people have criticized the music score as being second-rate, but that is what it SUPPOSED to be. Burlesque wasn't Ziegfeld. Men went to see the girls in various stages of undress, not hear Cole Porter or Irving Berlin. The music and the corny jokes were incidental to the "action" on stage, and it was not for nothing that Arthur Lange's musical score was nominated for an Acadamy Award. The mystery story is well-told and the atmosphere is added to by an excellent supporting cast, with Iris Adrian being a standout. After seeing this wonderfully entertaining film you will feel like you have been whisked back in time to an era long-gone.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    In some ways this is just brash and clumsy, and avoidable...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    secondtake
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/5/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Lady of Burlesque (1943) This is a pretty goofy movie with a forced murder plot thrown in. Some of the actors are comedians in this theater group, so there are gags and one liners throughout. Others are dancers, so there's some dancing, though nothing too worked out. It's fascinating to see how Barbara Stanwyck is head and shoulders above the other actors in screen presence (if not in dancing--she's never been elegant, just sharp). The scene is limited to a few rooms in a dingy theater, and it's filmed with the camera usually just sitting there facing one way and the actors sitting or standing facing the other. It didn't help that the print Netflix has streaming is faded out so the shadows are merely grey. But director William Wellman is better than this film would let on--he's one of those working experts of ordinary cinema, cranking out lots of really good if rarely astonishing films over many decades. It's worth noting that the music is routine stuff, too, so if you are in it for the "musical" aspects you might beware. I just happened to finish a couple of hours ago the 1943 "Stormy Weather" which has incredible music (and an even weaker plot). Needless to say, this one is not about the music, per se. This whole scenario is based on the milieu of Gypsy Rose Lee, a famous burlesque dancer from the early 20th Century, and her apparently silly murder mystery "The G-String Murders" was the basis for this movie. But she wrote an autobiography in 1957 which led to a movie actually about her life, "Gypsy." Ethel Merman of all people was the start of that (with Sondheim music). These are the more interesting tidbits here. I really think this movie is best avoided, especially with many other good musicals out there from the 1940s.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Film Strip Tease
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    wes-connors
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/6/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Barbara Stanwyck (as "Dixie Daisy") is a striptease dancer, singing "Take it off the E-String (Play it on the G-String)" while shaking her booty. Stand-up comic Michael O'Shea (as Biff Brannigan) is especially turned on by Ms. Stanwyck, but she likes to steer clear of clowns. Stanwyck thinks comics bring bad vibes. She and the admiring Mr. O'Shea are among the New York City stage performers hit by a series of "G-String Murders" (stripper Gypsy Rose Lee's more titillating title). But, don't expect to see women modeling the equivalent of today's "thong" or "string bikini" - except around their pretty necks. You've got to appreciate Stanwyck putting such energy into an inappropriate part; she approaches acting assignments with admirable professionalism. "Lady of Burlesque" seems more suited to Betty Grable or Rita Hayworth, but Stanwyck goes for it without showing distaste or boredom with the role. O'Shea keeps step, with director William A. Wellman guiding the players. Sexy blondes Iris Adrian (as Gee Gee Graham) and Marion Martin (as Alice Angel) are worth catching. J. Edward Bromberg (as S.B. Foss) manages to stand out in the leggy crowd. And, sophomoric comic Pinky Lee (as Mandy) is fresh. ***** Lady of Burlesque (5/1/43) William A. Wellman ~ Barbara Stanwyck, Michael O'Shea, Iris Adrian, J. Edward Bromberg
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Gypsy Rose
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    n_r_koch
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/6/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie shows how much the director matters in ensemble pieces. Wellman was one of those guys who seemed incapable of making a bad movie, even when stuck with limited resources and censorship, as in this case. This is basically a one-set film and it was shot under more or less double censorship (Code and wartime). But it's highly entertaining, considering what they couldn't show. (If I had been stuck in North Africa or the South Pacific in 1943 I would much sooner have seen this than those dreadful patriotic movies like THOUSANDS CHEER and SO PROUDLY WE HAIL or even CASABLANCA.) It's full of watchable funny girls of the kind that all but vanished (into the kitchen) after Pearl Harbor. The murder-mystery element is played the right way-- completely unseriously. Stanwyck is totally appealing, and Stephanie Bachelor ("Only tramps work in Toledo!") is one bombshell of a funny girl. Iris Adrian, Marion Martin, and Victoria Faust all make a big impression. Pinky Lee gets to do his schtick, including some tricky dancing, and O'Shea is good as the baggy-pants comic who's after Stanwyck. Both the writing (by Gunn) and editing are snappy (and witty: I love that quick cutaway to 'the Princess' reading her fan mail) and nobody just shows up and reads lines. I doubt anyone could have filmed this better in 1943.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Bad
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Alex da Silva
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/6/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The film is set in a theatre and is a backstage "whodunnit?". After 45 minutes, we start to see a story develop when one of the Burlesque girls is murdered, but by that stage I was fed up with the film. After the murder, the film continues to be annoying despite a second murder. The men are mainly portrayed as jokers and the women swap comments at break-neck speed in that "wise-crack" style, ie, too fast. Its just all rather tiresome - the dialogue isn't that funny and sometimes you can't understand what they are saying. Judging from what we see of the show that the guys & girls put on for audiences (Stanwyck singing a very flat song, some lame comedy sketches and some wooden dancing by Stanwyck), this is a very 3rd-rate group of entertainers. Other irritations include the Princess Nirvena (Stephanie Bachelor) who affects a terrible Russian accent throughout her performance and the constant references to the world of burlesque as being wild and crazy by the police inspectors. We see no evidence of this. The only funny moments come from the girls reactions as a whole in the dressing room. Its one to avoid.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Barbara Stanwyck's fans might find some qualities
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Cristi_Ciopron
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/11/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    LADY OF BURLESQUE,an old humble screwball mystery ,very clumsily made, has one thing of real interestMrs. Stanwyck, at her rather hottest, as a sexbomb. As for the rest, it's a quite insipid screwball comedy, unpretentious B slapdash. I find this genre as admissible as the sleazy fancily violent thrillers of the '70s. Mrs. Stanwyck gives a rather standard performance as a wisecracker ;she makes such nice remarks about how men were looking at her ankles when she was 11;today, such confessions would sound utterly unacceptable. But LADY OF  was made in a time when people were having so much more fun . LADY OF BURLESQUE is about a couple of murders in a burlesque theater ; Mrs. Stanwyck is the Colombina, and an Irishman is her Pierrot; hence the screwball. The execution is, as I already stated, silly and clumsy. Balast.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    She wasn't allowed the full Monty
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    free2emailus
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/10/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Couple of things to remember when you're waiting for something to happen (and it does take about thirty minutes for things to get interesting). *This has plenty of skimpy costumes and leg shots for the boys in the war effort. The ladies didn't have to do much to be welcome on a screen for soldiers and Stanwyck's Edith Head hose went as high as they dared. *There's a nostalgia effort going on here - it was 20 years since the best of vaudeville in 1943 and something American culture does brilliantly is look back in twenty year spans. The 40s came into vogue in the 60s and also, briefly, the 20s fashions again. In the 70s, we looked back at the 50s and so on, so some of this was meant to try and capture burlesque, vaudeville's seedier, coarser cousin. *Stanwyck was looking to take on challenging roles that others would turn down. She had also finished two serious roles and wanted something more fun - the chance to dance and sing. She researched and learned some bumps and grinds that were filmed, but when studio heads and the Hays office saw the rushes of her and the COuntess doing them, they were cut. We get the reaction shots instead. Those bumps and grinds would make for very interesting DVD extras. *Stany sang with her own voice in this one - very low and throaty - and they try like mad to make the song a hit by doing two or three reprises. It's somewhat catchy but what person of morals would buy sheet music to a stripper song? Where would you sing it?! *Michael O'Shea, the love interest, really did start in Vaudeville, and this was his big chance (Stany was a hoofer/chorine on Broadway till a featured role in Burlesque(1926) sent her on her way). This was his big year, with Jack London and The Eve of St. Mark also released. He didn't have a strong enough film presence to sustain a career but he's likable enough and had several good supporting roles and a hit 50s TV show, although his role here required him to spit out groaner after groaner. Real Brulesque was full of double entendres and crappy jokes, spun out one after the other; if one was bad, another came along to take your mind off it. There are other Vaudeville/Burlesque stars tucked here and there, notably Pinky Lee (Oh ya make me so mad) but the girls were mostly starlets. I do love Stany, and once Charles Dingle steps in as the Inspector, the mystery and snappy one liners take hold. However, this is one dated film, maybe from the War audience and nostalgia aspects, the ill suited songs or a script that doesn't find its footing until we wonder why we're watching. A lesser actress might've been hurt, but half a year later, she was shooting Double Indemnity with Billy Wilder, no worse for wear.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Dixie Cups
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    writers_reign
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/8/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    If you're looking for authenticity, atmosphere and the stink of flop sweat then this is for you. Gypsy Rose Lee prevailed on room-mate Craig Rice to help whip her memoirs of burlesque into shape and throw in a murder or two for ballast and William A. Wellman does his usual pro job behind the camera. In 1943 there was no way you could show stripping - which was, of course, the main attraction of burlesque - but what we do get is actual Top Banana-Second Banana routines that had been used in burlecue since year One. With hindsight we can compare the atmosphere to Gypsy -both in stage and film form - and Sugar Babies, which revived the format in the eightiesbut this is the next best thing to being there. Don't miss it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Who Is Killing The Great Ladies of Burlesque?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bkoganbing
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/2/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Barbara Stanwyck got to really show her versatility in Lady of Burlesque doing a couple of numbers that did make me wonder why she didn't try to do a full blown musical. Of course she had the best of inspiration in a book that was partially written by the one and only Gypsy Rose Lee. Gypsy needed a ghostwriter, but she certainly knew the world of burlesque as none other. So with Craig Rice's ghostwriting they fashioned a murder mystery set in the burlesque world. Somebody is killing the strippers at a burlesque theater and Barbara isn't sitting around waiting to be the next victim. With the help of comic Michael O'Shea she's going to find the perpetrator before she gets done in with her G String. A lovely group of movie queens help Barbara out in this film. Playing some of her peers are Iris Adrian, Gloria Dickson, Marion Martin, Janis Carter, Stephanie Bachelor, and Victoria Faust. Some of these don't make it to the end of the picture. Playing another of the comics is Pinky Lee who I well remember because I used to watch his kid's television show back in my salad days. Pinky was as frantic as I remember him and he does a mean jitterbug with Stanwyck. William Wellman as director keeps the pace of things going pretty nicely. And if you're a leg man, this picture will leave you nothing to complain about. As for the murderer, here's a hint, it's roughly the equivalent of the butler doing it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    What were they thinking?!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    planktonrules
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/1/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is a truly amazing film. Considering the adult content of the film, it's amazing that it was made during the era where the Production Code was so rigidly enforced AND it's amazing that some major Hollywood talent associated themselves with such a sleazy and silly film. The movie is directed by the very well respected William Wellman--the same man responsible for such classics as ALL QUIET ON THE WESTERN FRONT. In the starring role is Barbara Stanwyck--an A-list actress in a decidedly B-list film! So why is the film so sleazy? Well, the setting is a burlesque house and the original title for the story was THE G-STRING MURDERS! While people are killed in a variety of ways, one is found with a G-string wrapped around her throat. Additionally, the women in the film all look very cheap and act like tramps--with lots of cat fights and juicy dialog! In many ways, this film looks like a 1930s Pre-Code or Exploitation Film--not the product of a mainstream studio during the rather stuffy 1940s! How this actually got made and was allowed to be released is a mystery--as well as how they got very respected talent to appear in a poorly written and shabby production. Had this movie not starred Stanwyck and been directed by Wellman, I really doubt if it would have been widely released, as the film looks very cheap and suffers from a rather dull script. In fact, I doubt that a poverty row studio like Monogram would have been proud of the product! The bottom line is that this is a salacious film and it's a great curiosity piece. However, once you get past seeing talented people doing their best to ruin their careers, there really isn't much this film has to offer as far as entertainment value goes. It isn't sleazy enough to appeal to adult film fans and it's just crude enough to make it a bit of a guilty pleasure--nothing more. A bizarre and sub-par film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Did Barbara ever make a bad film?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    earlytalkie
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/10/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Barbara Stanwyck managed to elevate nearly every film and television show she ever did. The earliest film I saw her in was "The Miracle Woman" from 1931. I just saw "Baby Face" and I own copies of "The Thorn Birds", "Stella Dallas" and this film. "Lady of Burlesque" is a wonderful, atmospheric depiction of an bygone era, complete with Stanwyck doing some amazing dance moves. Some people have criticized the music score as being second-rate, but that is what it SUPPOSED to be. Burlesque wasn't Ziegfeld. Men went to see the girls in various stages of undress, not hear Cole Porter or Irving Berlin. The music and the corny jokes were incidental to the "action" on stage, and it was not for nothing that Arthur Lange's musical score was nominated for an Acadamy Award. The mystery story is well-told and the atmosphere is added to by an excellent supporting cast, with Iris Adrian being a standout. After seeing this wonderfully entertaining film you will feel like you have been whisked back in time to an era long-gone.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    In some ways this is just brash and clumsy, and avoidable...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    secondtake
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/5/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Lady of Burlesque (1943) This is a pretty goofy movie with a forced murder plot thrown in. Some of the actors are comedians in this theater group, so there are gags and one liners throughout. Others are dancers, so there's some dancing, though nothing too worked out. It's fascinating to see how Barbara Stanwyck is head and shoulders above the other actors in screen presence (if not in dancing--she's never been elegant, just sharp). The scene is limited to a few rooms in a dingy theater, and it's filmed with the camera usually just sitting there facing one way and the actors sitting or standing facing the other. It didn't help that the print Netflix has streaming is faded out so the shadows are merely grey. But director William Wellman is better than this film would let on--he's one of those working experts of ordinary cinema, cranking out lots of really good if rarely astonishing films over many decades. It's worth noting that the music is routine stuff, too, so if you are in it for the "musical" aspects you might beware. I just happened to finish a couple of hours ago the 1943 "Stormy Weather" which has incredible music (and an even weaker plot). Needless to say, this one is not about the music, per se. This whole scenario is based on the milieu of Gypsy Rose Lee, a famous burlesque dancer from the early 20th Century, and her apparently silly murder mystery "The G-String Murders" was the basis for this movie. But she wrote an autobiography in 1957 which led to a movie actually about her life, "Gypsy." Ethel Merman of all people was the start of that (with Sondheim music). These are the more interesting tidbits here. I really think this movie is best avoided, especially with many other good musicals out there from the 1940s.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Film Strip Tease
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    wes-connors
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/6/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Barbara Stanwyck (as "Dixie Daisy") is a striptease dancer, singing "Take it off the E-String (Play it on the G-String)" while shaking her booty. Stand-up comic Michael O'Shea (as Biff Brannigan) is especially turned on by Ms. Stanwyck, but she likes to steer clear of clowns. Stanwyck thinks comics bring bad vibes. She and the admiring Mr. O'Shea are among the New York City stage performers hit by a series of "G-String Murders" (stripper Gypsy Rose Lee's more titillating title). But, don't expect to see women modeling the equivalent of today's "thong" or "string bikini" - except around their pretty necks. You've got to appreciate Stanwyck putting such energy into an inappropriate part; she approaches acting assignments with admirable professionalism. "Lady of Burlesque" seems more suited to Betty Grable or Rita Hayworth, but Stanwyck goes for it without showing distaste or boredom with the role. O'Shea keeps step, with director William A. Wellman guiding the players. Sexy blondes Iris Adrian (as Gee Gee Graham) and Marion Martin (as Alice Angel) are worth catching. J. Edward Bromberg (as S.B. Foss) manages to stand out in the leggy crowd. And, sophomoric comic Pinky Lee (as Mandy) is fresh. ***** Lady of Burlesque (5/1/43) William A. Wellman ~ Barbara Stanwyck, Michael O'Shea, Iris Adrian, J. Edward Bromberg
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Gypsy Rose
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    n_r_koch
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/6/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie shows how much the director matters in ensemble pieces. Wellman was one of those guys who seemed incapable of making a bad movie, even when stuck with limited resources and censorship, as in this case. This is basically a one-set film and it was shot under more or less double censorship (Code and wartime). But it's highly entertaining, considering what they couldn't show. (If I had been stuck in North Africa or the South Pacific in 1943 I would much sooner have seen this than those dreadful patriotic movies like THOUSANDS CHEER and SO PROUDLY WE HAIL or even CASABLANCA.) It's full of watchable funny girls of the kind that all but vanished (into the kitchen) after Pearl Harbor. The murder-mystery element is played the right way-- completely unseriously. Stanwyck is totally appealing, and Stephanie Bachelor ("Only tramps work in Toledo!") is one bombshell of a funny girl. Iris Adrian, Marion Martin, and Victoria Faust all make a big impression. Pinky Lee gets to do his schtick, including some tricky dancing, and O'Shea is good as the baggy-pants comic who's after Stanwyck. Both the writing (by Gunn) and editing are snappy (and witty: I love that quick cutaway to 'the Princess' reading her fan mail) and nobody just shows up and reads lines. I doubt anyone could have filmed this better in 1943.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Bad
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Alex da Silva
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/6/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The film is set in a theatre and is a backstage "whodunnit?". After 45 minutes, we start to see a story develop when one of the Burlesque girls is murdered, but by that stage I was fed up with the film. After the murder, the film continues to be annoying despite a second murder. The men are mainly portrayed as jokers and the women swap comments at break-neck speed in that "wise-crack" style, ie, too fast. Its just all rather tiresome - the dialogue isn't that funny and sometimes you can't understand what they are saying. Judging from what we see of the show that the guys & girls put on for audiences (Stanwyck singing a very flat song, some lame comedy sketches and some wooden dancing by Stanwyck), this is a very 3rd-rate group of entertainers. Other irritations include the Princess Nirvena (Stephanie Bachelor) who affects a terrible Russian accent throughout her performance and the constant references to the world of burlesque as being wild and crazy by the police inspectors. We see no evidence of this. The only funny moments come from the girls reactions as a whole in the dressing room. Its one to avoid.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Barbara Stanwyck's fans might find some qualities
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Cristi_Ciopron
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/11/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    LADY OF BURLESQUE,an old humble screwball mystery ,very clumsily made, has one thing of real interestMrs. Stanwyck, at her rather hottest, as a sexbomb. As for the rest, it's a quite insipid screwball comedy, unpretentious B slapdash. I find this genre as admissible as the sleazy fancily violent thrillers of the '70s. Mrs. Stanwyck gives a rather standard performance as a wisecracker ;she makes such nice remarks about how men were looking at her ankles when she was 11;today, such confessions would sound utterly unacceptable. But LADY OF  was made in a time when people were having so much more fun . LADY OF BURLESQUE is about a couple of murders in a burlesque theater ; Mrs. Stanwyck is the Colombina, and an Irishman is her Pierrot; hence the screwball. The execution is, as I already stated, silly and clumsy. Balast.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    She wasn't allowed the full Monty
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    free2emailus
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/10/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Couple of things to remember when you're waiting for something to happen (and it does take about thirty minutes for things to get interesting). *This has plenty of skimpy costumes and leg shots for the boys in the war effort. The ladies didn't have to do much to be welcome on a screen for soldiers and Stanwyck's Edith Head hose went as high as they dared. *There's a nostalgia effort going on here - it was 20 years since the best of vaudeville in 1943 and something American culture does brilliantly is look back in twenty year spans. The 40s came into vogue in the 60s and also, briefly, the 20s fashions again. In the 70s, we looked back at the 50s and so on, so some of this was meant to try and capture burlesque, vaudeville's seedier, coarser cousin. *Stanwyck was looking to take on challenging roles that others would turn down. She had also finished two serious roles and wanted something more fun - the chance to dance and sing. She researched and learned some bumps and grinds that were filmed, but when studio heads and the Hays office saw the rushes of her and the COuntess doing them, they were cut. We get the reaction shots instead. Those bumps and grinds would make for very interesting DVD extras. *Stany sang with her own voice in this one - very low and throaty - and they try like mad to make the song a hit by doing two or three reprises. It's somewhat catchy but what person of morals would buy sheet music to a stripper song? Where would you sing it?! *Michael O'Shea, the love interest, really did start in Vaudeville, and this was his big chance (Stany was a hoofer/chorine on Broadway till a featured role in Burlesque(1926) sent her on her way). This was his big year, with Jack London and The Eve of St. Mark also released. He didn't have a strong enough film presence to sustain a career but he's likable enough and had several good supporting roles and a hit 50s TV show, although his role here required him to spit out groaner after groaner. Real Brulesque was full of double entendres and crappy jokes, spun out one after the other; if one was bad, another came along to take your mind off it. There are other Vaudeville/Burlesque stars tucked here and there, notably Pinky Lee (Oh ya make me so mad) but the girls were mostly starlets. I do love Stany, and once Charles Dingle steps in as the Inspector, the mystery and snappy one liners take hold. However, this is one dated film, maybe from the War audience and nostalgia aspects, the ill suited songs or a script that doesn't find its footing until we wonder why we're watching. A lesser actress might've been hurt, but half a year later, she was shooting Double Indemnity with Billy Wilder, no worse for wear.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Dixie Cups
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    writers_reign
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/8/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    If you're looking for authenticity, atmosphere and the stink of flop sweat then this is for you. Gypsy Rose Lee prevailed on room-mate Craig Rice to help whip her memoirs of burlesque into shape and throw in a murder or two for ballast and William A. Wellman does his usual pro job behind the camera. In 1943 there was no way you could show stripping - which was, of course, the main attraction of burlesque - but what we do get is actual Top Banana-Second Banana routines that had been used in burlecue since year One. With hindsight we can compare the atmosphere to Gypsy -both in stage and film form - and Sugar Babies, which revived the format in the eightiesbut this is the next best thing to being there. Don't miss it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Who Is Killing The Great Ladies of Burlesque?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bkoganbing
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/2/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Barbara Stanwyck got to really show her versatility in Lady of Burlesque doing a couple of numbers that did make me wonder why she didn't try to do a full blown musical. Of course she had the best of inspiration in a book that was partially written by the one and only Gypsy Rose Lee. Gypsy needed a ghostwriter, but she certainly knew the world of burlesque as none other. So with Craig Rice's ghostwriting they fashioned a murder mystery set in the burlesque world. Somebody is killing the strippers at a burlesque theater and Barbara isn't sitting around waiting to be the next victim. With the help of comic Michael O'Shea she's going to find the perpetrator before she gets done in with her G String. A lovely group of movie queens help Barbara out in this film. Playing some of her peers are Iris Adrian, Gloria Dickson, Marion Martin, Janis Carter, Stephanie Bachelor, and Victoria Faust. Some of these don't make it to the end of the picture. Playing another of the comics is Pinky Lee who I well remember because I used to watch his kid's television show back in my salad days. Pinky was as frantic as I remember him and he does a mean jitterbug with Stanwyck. William Wellman as director keeps the pace of things going pretty nicely. And if you're a leg man, this picture will leave you nothing to complain about. As for the murderer, here's a hint, it's roughly the equivalent of the butler doing it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    What were they thinking?!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    planktonrules
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/1/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is a truly amazing film. Considering the adult content of the film, it's amazing that it was made during the era where the Production Code was so rigidly enforced AND it's amazing that some major Hollywood talent associated themselves with such a sleazy and silly film. The movie is directed by the very well respected William Wellman--the same man responsible for such classics as ALL QUIET ON THE WESTERN FRONT. In the starring role is Barbara Stanwyck--an A-list actress in a decidedly B-list film! So why is the film so sleazy? Well, the setting is a burlesque house and the original title for the story was THE G-STRING MURDERS! While people are killed in a variety of ways, one is found with a G-string wrapped around her throat. Additionally, the women in the film all look very cheap and act like tramps--with lots of cat fights and juicy dialog! In many ways, this film looks like a 1930s Pre-Code or Exploitation Film--not the product of a mainstream studio during the rather stuffy 1940s! How this actually got made and was allowed to be released is a mystery--as well as how they got very respected talent to appear in a poorly written and shabby production. Had this movie not starred Stanwyck and been directed by Wellman, I really doubt if it would have been widely released, as the film looks very cheap and suffers from a rather dull script. In fact, I doubt that a poverty row studio like Monogram would have been proud of the product! The bottom line is that this is a salacious film and it's a great curiosity piece. However, once you get past seeing talented people doing their best to ruin their careers, there really isn't much this film has to offer as far as entertainment value goes. It isn't sleazy enough to appeal to adult film fans and it's just crude enough to make it a bit of a guilty pleasure--nothing more. A bizarre and sub-par film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Did Barbara ever make a bad film?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    earlytalkie
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/10/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Barbara Stanwyck managed to elevate nearly every film and television show she ever did. The earliest film I saw her in was "The Miracle Woman" from 1931. I just saw "Baby Face" and I own copies of "The Thorn Birds", "Stella Dallas" and this film. "Lady of Burlesque" is a wonderful, atmospheric depiction of an bygone era, complete with Stanwyck doing some amazing dance moves. Some people have criticized the music score as being second-rate, but that is what it SUPPOSED to be. Burlesque wasn't Ziegfeld. Men went to see the girls in various stages of undress, not hear Cole Porter or Irving Berlin. The music and the corny jokes were incidental to the "action" on stage, and it was not for nothing that Arthur Lange's musical score was nominated for an Acadamy Award. The mystery story is well-told and the atmosphere is added to by an excellent supporting cast, with Iris Adrian being a standout. After seeing this wonderfully entertaining film you will feel like you have been whisked back in time to an era long-gone.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    In some ways this is just brash and clumsy, and avoidable...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    secondtake
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/5/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Lady of Burlesque (1943) This is a pretty goofy movie with a forced murder plot thrown in. Some of the actors are comedians in this theater group, so there are gags and one liners throughout. Others are dancers, so there's some dancing, though nothing too worked out. It's fascinating to see how Barbara Stanwyck is head and shoulders above the other actors in screen presence (if not in dancing--she's never been elegant, just sharp). The scene is limited to a few rooms in a dingy theater, and it's filmed with the camera usually just sitting there facing one way and the actors sitting or standing facing the other. It didn't help that the print Netflix has streaming is faded out so the shadows are merely grey. But director William Wellman is better than this film would let on--he's one of those working experts of ordinary cinema, cranking out lots of really good if rarely astonishing films over many decades. It's worth noting that the music is routine stuff, too, so if you are in it for the "musical" aspects you might beware. I just happened to finish a couple of hours ago the 1943 "Stormy Weather" which has incredible music (and an even weaker plot). Needless to say, this one is not about the music, per se. This whole scenario is based on the milieu of Gypsy Rose Lee, a famous burlesque dancer from the early 20th Century, and her apparently silly murder mystery "The G-String Murders" was the basis for this movie. But she wrote an autobiography in 1957 which led to a movie actually about her life, "Gypsy." Ethel Merman of all people was the start of that (with Sondheim music). These are the more interesting tidbits here. I really think this movie is best avoided, especially with many other good musicals out there from the 1940s.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Film Strip Tease
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    wes-connors
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/6/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Barbara Stanwyck (as "Dixie Daisy") is a striptease dancer, singing "Take it off the E-String (Play it on the G-String)" while shaking her booty. Stand-up comic Michael O'Shea (as Biff Brannigan) is especially turned on by Ms. Stanwyck, but she likes to steer clear of clowns. Stanwyck thinks comics bring bad vibes. She and the admiring Mr. O'Shea are among the New York City stage performers hit by a series of "G-String Murders" (stripper Gypsy Rose Lee's more titillating title). But, don't expect to see women modeling the equivalent of today's "thong" or "string bikini" - except around their pretty necks. You've got to appreciate Stanwyck putting such energy into an inappropriate part; she approaches acting assignments with admirable professionalism. "Lady of Burlesque" seems more suited to Betty Grable or Rita Hayworth, but Stanwyck goes for it without showing distaste or boredom with the role. O'Shea keeps step, with director William A. Wellman guiding the players. Sexy blondes Iris Adrian (as Gee Gee Graham) and Marion Martin (as Alice Angel) are worth catching. J. Edward Bromberg (as S.B. Foss) manages to stand out in the leggy crowd. And, sophomoric comic Pinky Lee (as Mandy) is fresh. ***** Lady of Burlesque (5/1/43) William A. Wellman ~ Barbara Stanwyck, Michael O'Shea, Iris Adrian, J. Edward Bromberg
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Gypsy Rose
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    n_r_koch
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/6/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie shows how much the director matters in ensemble pieces. Wellman was one of those guys who seemed incapable of making a bad movie, even when stuck with limited resources and censorship, as in this case. This is basically a one-set film and it was shot under more or less double censorship (Code and wartime). But it's highly entertaining, considering what they couldn't show. (If I had been stuck in North Africa or the South Pacific in 1943 I would much sooner have seen this than those dreadful patriotic movies like THOUSANDS CHEER and SO PROUDLY WE HAIL or even CASABLANCA.) It's full of watchable funny girls of the kind that all but vanished (into the kitchen) after Pearl Harbor. The murder-mystery element is played the right way-- completely unseriously. Stanwyck is totally appealing, and Stephanie Bachelor ("Only tramps work in Toledo!") is one bombshell of a funny girl. Iris Adrian, Marion Martin, and Victoria Faust all make a big impression. Pinky Lee gets to do his schtick, including some tricky dancing, and O'Shea is good as the baggy-pants comic who's after Stanwyck. Both the writing (by Gunn) and editing are snappy (and witty: I love that quick cutaway to 'the Princess' reading her fan mail) and nobody just shows up and reads lines. I doubt anyone could have filmed this better in 1943.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Bad
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Alex da Silva
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/6/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The film is set in a theatre and is a backstage "whodunnit?". After 45 minutes, we start to see a story develop when one of the Burlesque girls is murdered, but by that stage I was fed up with the film. After the murder, the film continues to be annoying despite a second murder. The men are mainly portrayed as jokers and the women swap comments at break-neck speed in that "wise-crack" style, ie, too fast. Its just all rather tiresome - the dialogue isn't that funny and sometimes you can't understand what they are saying. Judging from what we see of the show that the guys & girls put on for audiences (Stanwyck singing a very flat song, some lame comedy sketches and some wooden dancing by Stanwyck), this is a very 3rd-rate group of entertainers. Other irritations include the Princess Nirvena (Stephanie Bachelor) who affects a terrible Russian accent throughout her performance and the constant references to the world of burlesque as being wild and crazy by the police inspectors. We see no evidence of this. The only funny moments come from the girls reactions as a whole in the dressing room. Its one to avoid.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Barbara Stanwyck's fans might find some qualities
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Cristi_Ciopron
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/11/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    LADY OF BURLESQUE,an old humble screwball mystery ,very clumsily made, has one thing of real interestMrs. Stanwyck, at her rather hottest, as a sexbomb. As for the rest, it's a quite insipid screwball comedy, unpretentious B slapdash. I find this genre as admissible as the sleazy fancily violent thrillers of the '70s. Mrs. Stanwyck gives a rather standard performance as a wisecracker ;she makes such nice remarks about how men were looking at her ankles when she was 11;today, such confessions would sound utterly unacceptable. But LADY OF  was made in a time when people were having so much more fun . LADY OF BURLESQUE is about a couple of murders in a burlesque theater ; Mrs. Stanwyck is the Colombina, and an Irishman is her Pierrot; hence the screwball. The execution is, as I already stated, silly and clumsy. Balast.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    She wasn't allowed the full Monty
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    free2emailus
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/10/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Couple of things to remember when you're waiting for something to happen (and it does take about thirty minutes for things to get interesting). *This has plenty of skimpy costumes and leg shots for the boys in the war effort. The ladies didn't have to do much to be welcome on a screen for soldiers and Stanwyck's Edith Head hose went as high as they dared. *There's a nostalgia effort going on here - it was 20 years since the best of vaudeville in 1943 and something American culture does brilliantly is look back in twenty year spans. The 40s came into vogue in the 60s and also, briefly, the 20s fashions again. In the 70s, we looked back at the 50s and so on, so some of this was meant to try and capture burlesque, vaudeville's seedier, coarser cousin. *Stanwyck was looking to take on challenging roles that others would turn down. She had also finished two serious roles and wanted something more fun - the chance to dance and sing. She researched and learned some bumps and grinds that were filmed, but when studio heads and the Hays office saw the rushes of her and the COuntess doing them, they were cut. We get the reaction shots instead. Those bumps and grinds would make for very interesting DVD extras. *Stany sang with her own voice in this one - very low and throaty - and they try like mad to make the song a hit by doing two or three reprises. It's somewhat catchy but what person of morals would buy sheet music to a stripper song? Where would you sing it?! *Michael O'Shea, the love interest, really did start in Vaudeville, and this was his big chance (Stany was a hoofer/chorine on Broadway till a featured role in Burlesque(1926) sent her on her way). This was his big year, with Jack London and The Eve of St. Mark also released. He didn't have a strong enough film presence to sustain a career but he's likable enough and had several good supporting roles and a hit 50s TV show, although his role here required him to spit out groaner after groaner. Real Brulesque was full of double entendres and crappy jokes, spun out one after the other; if one was bad, another came along to take your mind off it. There are other Vaudeville/Burlesque stars tucked here and there, notably Pinky Lee (Oh ya make me so mad) but the girls were mostly starlets. I do love Stany, and once Charles Dingle steps in as the Inspector, the mystery and snappy one liners take hold. However, this is one dated film, maybe from the War audience and nostalgia aspects, the ill suited songs or a script that doesn't find its footing until we wonder why we're watching. A lesser actress might've been hurt, but half a year later, she was shooting Double Indemnity with Billy Wilder, no worse for wear.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Dixie Cups
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    writers_reign
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/8/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    If you're looking for authenticity, atmosphere and the stink of flop sweat then this is for you. Gypsy Rose Lee prevailed on room-mate Craig Rice to help whip her memoirs of burlesque into shape and throw in a murder or two for ballast and William A. Wellman does his usual pro job behind the camera. In 1943 there was no way you could show stripping - which was, of course, the main attraction of burlesque - but what we do get is actual Top Banana-Second Banana routines that had been used in burlecue since year One. With hindsight we can compare the atmosphere to Gypsy -both in stage and film form - and Sugar Babies, which revived the format in the eightiesbut this is the next best thing to being there. Don't miss it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Who Is Killing The Great Ladies of Burlesque?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bkoganbing
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/2/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Barbara Stanwyck got to really show her versatility in Lady of Burlesque doing a couple of numbers that did make me wonder why she didn't try to do a full blown musical. Of course she had the best of inspiration in a book that was partially written by the one and only Gypsy Rose Lee. Gypsy needed a ghostwriter, but she certainly knew the world of burlesque as none other. So with Craig Rice's ghostwriting they fashioned a murder mystery set in the burlesque world. Somebody is killing the strippers at a burlesque theater and Barbara isn't sitting around waiting to be the next victim. With the help of comic Michael O'Shea she's going to find the perpetrator before she gets done in with her G String. A lovely group of movie queens help Barbara out in this film. Playing some of her peers are Iris Adrian, Gloria Dickson, Marion Martin, Janis Carter, Stephanie Bachelor, and Victoria Faust. Some of these don't make it to the end of the picture. Playing another of the comics is Pinky Lee who I well remember because I used to watch his kid's television show back in my salad days. Pinky was as frantic as I remember him and he does a mean jitterbug with Stanwyck. William Wellman as director keeps the pace of things going pretty nicely. And if you're a leg man, this picture will leave you nothing to complain about. As for the murderer, here's a hint, it's roughly the equivalent of the butler doing it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    What were they thinking?!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    planktonrules
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/1/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is a truly amazing film. Considering the adult content of the film, it's amazing that it was made during the era where the Production Code was so rigidly enforced AND it's amazing that some major Hollywood talent associated themselves with such a sleazy and silly film. The movie is directed by the very well respected William Wellman--the same man responsible for such classics as ALL QUIET ON THE WESTERN FRONT. In the starring role is Barbara Stanwyck--an A-list actress in a decidedly B-list film! So why is the film so sleazy? Well, the setting is a burlesque house and the original title for the story was THE G-STRING MURDERS! While people are killed in a variety of ways, one is found with a G-string wrapped around her throat. Additionally, the women in the film all look very cheap and act like tramps--with lots of cat fights and juicy dialog! In many ways, this film looks like a 1930s Pre-Code or Exploitation Film--not the product of a mainstream studio during the rather stuffy 1940s! How this actually got made and was allowed to be released is a mystery--as well as how they got very respected talent to appear in a poorly written and shabby production. Had this movie not starred Stanwyck and been directed by Wellman, I really doubt if it would have been widely released, as the film looks very cheap and suffers from a rather dull script. In fact, I doubt that a poverty row studio like Monogram would have been proud of the product! The bottom line is that this is a salacious film and it's a great curiosity piece. However, once you get past seeing talented people doing their best to ruin their careers, there really isn't much this film has to offer as far as entertainment value goes. It isn't sleazy enough to appeal to adult film fans and it's just crude enough to make it a bit of a guilty pleasure--nothing more. A bizarre and sub-par film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Did Barbara ever make a bad film?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    earlytalkie
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/10/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Barbara Stanwyck managed to elevate nearly every film and television show she ever did. The earliest film I saw her in was "The Miracle Woman" from 1931. I just saw "Baby Face" and I own copies of "The Thorn Birds", "Stella Dallas" and this film. "Lady of Burlesque" is a wonderful, atmospheric depiction of an bygone era, complete with Stanwyck doing some amazing dance moves. Some people have criticized the music score as being second-rate, but that is what it SUPPOSED to be. Burlesque wasn't Ziegfeld. Men went to see the girls in various stages of undress, not hear Cole Porter or Irving Berlin. The music and the corny jokes were incidental to the "action" on stage, and it was not for nothing that Arthur Lange's musical score was nominated for an Acadamy Award. The mystery story is well-told and the atmosphere is added to by an excellent supporting cast, with Iris Adrian being a standout. After seeing this wonderfully entertaining film you will feel like you have been whisked back in time to an era long-gone.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    In some ways this is just brash and clumsy, and avoidable...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    secondtake
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/5/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Lady of Burlesque (1943) This is a pretty goofy movie with a forced murder plot thrown in. Some of the actors are comedians in this theater group, so there are gags and one liners throughout. Others are dancers, so there's some dancing, though nothing too worked out. It's fascinating to see how Barbara Stanwyck is head and shoulders above the other actors in screen presence (if not in dancing--she's never been elegant, just sharp). The scene is limited to a few rooms in a dingy theater, and it's filmed with the camera usually just sitting there facing one way and the actors sitting or standing facing the other. It didn't help that the print Netflix has streaming is faded out so the shadows are merely grey. But director William Wellman is better than this film would let on--he's one of those working experts of ordinary cinema, cranking out lots of really good if rarely astonishing films over many decades. It's worth noting that the music is routine stuff, too, so if you are in it for the "musical" aspects you might beware. I just happened to finish a couple of hours ago the 1943 "Stormy Weather" which has incredible music (and an even weaker plot). Needless to say, this one is not about the music, per se. This whole scenario is based on the milieu of Gypsy Rose Lee, a famous burlesque dancer from the early 20th Century, and her apparently silly murder mystery "The G-String Murders" was the basis for this movie. But she wrote an autobiography in 1957 which led to a movie actually about her life, "Gypsy." Ethel Merman of all people was the start of that (with Sondheim music). These are the more interesting tidbits here. I really think this movie is best avoided, especially with many other good musicals out there from the 1940s.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Film Strip Tease
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    wes-connors
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/6/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Barbara Stanwyck (as "Dixie Daisy") is a striptease dancer, singing "Take it off the E-String (Play it on the G-String)" while shaking her booty. Stand-up comic Michael O'Shea (as Biff Brannigan) is especially turned on by Ms. Stanwyck, but she likes to steer clear of clowns. Stanwyck thinks comics bring bad vibes. She and the admiring Mr. O'Shea are among the New York City stage performers hit by a series of "G-String Murders" (stripper Gypsy Rose Lee's more titillating title). But, don't expect to see women modeling the equivalent of today's "thong" or "string bikini" - except around their pretty necks. You've got to appreciate Stanwyck putting such energy into an inappropriate part; she approaches acting assignments with admirable professionalism. "Lady of Burlesque" seems more suited to Betty Grable or Rita Hayworth, but Stanwyck goes for it without showing distaste or boredom with the role. O'Shea keeps step, with director William A. Wellman guiding the players. Sexy blondes Iris Adrian (as Gee Gee Graham) and Marion Martin (as Alice Angel) are worth catching. J. Edward Bromberg (as S.B. Foss) manages to stand out in the leggy crowd. And, sophomoric comic Pinky Lee (as Mandy) is fresh. ***** Lady of Burlesque (5/1/43) William A. Wellman ~ Barbara Stanwyck, Michael O'Shea, Iris Adrian, J. Edward Bromberg
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Gypsy Rose
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    n_r_koch
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/6/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie shows how much the director matters in ensemble pieces. Wellman was one of those guys who seemed incapable of making a bad movie, even when stuck with limited resources and censorship, as in this case. This is basically a one-set film and it was shot under more or less double censorship (Code and wartime). But it's highly entertaining, considering what they couldn't show. (If I had been stuck in North Africa or the South Pacific in 1943 I would much sooner have seen this than those dreadful patriotic movies like THOUSANDS CHEER and SO PROUDLY WE HAIL or even CASABLANCA.) It's full of watchable funny girls of the kind that all but vanished (into the kitchen) after Pearl Harbor. The murder-mystery element is played the right way-- completely unseriously. Stanwyck is totally appealing, and Stephanie Bachelor ("Only tramps work in Toledo!") is one bombshell of a funny girl. Iris Adrian, Marion Martin, and Victoria Faust all make a big impression. Pinky Lee gets to do his schtick, including some tricky dancing, and O'Shea is good as the baggy-pants comic who's after Stanwyck. Both the writing (by Gunn) and editing are snappy (and witty: I love that quick cutaway to 'the Princess' reading her fan mail) and nobody just shows up and reads lines. I doubt anyone could have filmed this better in 1943.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Bad
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Alex da Silva
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/6/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The film is set in a theatre and is a backstage "whodunnit?". After 45 minutes, we start to see a story develop when one of the Burlesque girls is murdered, but by that stage I was fed up with the film. After the murder, the film continues to be annoying despite a second murder. The men are mainly portrayed as jokers and the women swap comments at break-neck speed in that "wise-crack" style, ie, too fast. Its just all rather tiresome - the dialogue isn't that funny and sometimes you can't understand what they are saying. Judging from what we see of the show that the guys & girls put on for audiences (Stanwyck singing a very flat song, some lame comedy sketches and some wooden dancing by Stanwyck), this is a very 3rd-rate group of entertainers. Other irritations include the Princess Nirvena (Stephanie Bachelor) who affects a terrible Russian accent throughout her performance and the constant references to the world of burlesque as being wild and crazy by the police inspectors. We see no evidence of this. The only funny moments come from the girls reactions as a whole in the dressing room. Its one to avoid.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Barbara Stanwyck's fans might find some qualities
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Cristi_Ciopron
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/11/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    LADY OF BURLESQUE,an old humble screwball mystery ,very clumsily made, has one thing of real interestMrs. Stanwyck, at her rather hottest, as a sexbomb. As for the rest, it's a quite insipid screwball comedy, unpretentious B slapdash. I find this genre as admissible as the sleazy fancily violent thrillers of the '70s. Mrs. Stanwyck gives a rather standard performance as a wisecracker ;she makes such nice remarks about how men were looking at her ankles when she was 11;today, such confessions would sound utterly unacceptable. But LADY OF  was made in a time when people were having so much more fun . LADY OF BURLESQUE is about a couple of murders in a burlesque theater ; Mrs. Stanwyck is the Colombina, and an Irishman is her Pierrot; hence the screwball. The execution is, as I already stated, silly and clumsy. Balast.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    She wasn't allowed the full Monty
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    free2emailus
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/10/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Couple of things to remember when you're waiting for something to happen (and it does take about thirty minutes for things to get interesting). *This has plenty of skimpy costumes and leg shots for the boys in the war effort. The ladies didn't have to do much to be welcome on a screen for soldiers and Stanwyck's Edith Head hose went as high as they dared. *There's a nostalgia effort going on here - it was 20 years since the best of vaudeville in 1943 and something American culture does brilliantly is look back in twenty year spans. The 40s came into vogue in the 60s and also, briefly, the 20s fashions again. In the 70s, we looked back at the 50s and so on, so some of this was meant to try and capture burlesque, vaudeville's seedier, coarser cousin. *Stanwyck was looking to take on challenging roles that others would turn down. She had also finished two serious roles and wanted something more fun - the chance to dance and sing. She researched and learned some bumps and grinds that were filmed, but when studio heads and the Hays office saw the rushes of her and the COuntess doing them, they were cut. We get the reaction shots instead. Those bumps and grinds would make for very interesting DVD extras. *Stany sang with her own voice in this one - very low and throaty - and they try like mad to make the song a hit by doing two or three reprises. It's somewhat catchy but what person of morals would buy sheet music to a stripper song? Where would you sing it?! *Michael O'Shea, the love interest, really did start in Vaudeville, and this was his big chance (Stany was a hoofer/chorine on Broadway till a featured role in Burlesque(1926) sent her on her way). This was his big year, with Jack London and The Eve of St. Mark also released. He didn't have a strong enough film presence to sustain a career but he's likable enough and had several good supporting roles and a hit 50s TV show, although his role here required him to spit out groaner after groaner. Real Brulesque was full of double entendres and crappy jokes, spun out one after the other; if one was bad, another came along to take your mind off it. There are other Vaudeville/Burlesque stars tucked here and there, notably Pinky Lee (Oh ya make me so mad) but the girls were mostly starlets. I do love Stany, and once Charles Dingle steps in as the Inspector, the mystery and snappy one liners take hold. However, this is one dated film, maybe from the War audience and nostalgia aspects, the ill suited songs or a script that doesn't find its footing until we wonder why we're watching. A lesser actress might've been hurt, but half a year later, she was shooting Double Indemnity with Billy Wilder, no worse for wear.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Dixie Cups
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    writers_reign
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/8/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    If you're looking for authenticity, atmosphere and the stink of flop sweat then this is for you. Gypsy Rose Lee prevailed on room-mate Craig Rice to help whip her memoirs of burlesque into shape and throw in a murder or two for ballast and William A. Wellman does his usual pro job behind the camera. In 1943 there was no way you could show stripping - which was, of course, the main attraction of burlesque - but what we do get is actual Top Banana-Second Banana routines that had been used in burlecue since year One. With hindsight we can compare the atmosphere to Gypsy -both in stage and film form - and Sugar Babies, which revived the format in the eightiesbut this is the next best thing to being there. Don't miss it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Who Is Killing The Great Ladies of Burlesque?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bkoganbing
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/2/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Barbara Stanwyck got to really show her versatility in Lady of Burlesque doing a couple of numbers that did make me wonder why she didn't try to do a full blown musical. Of course she had the best of inspiration in a book that was partially written by the one and only Gypsy Rose Lee. Gypsy needed a ghostwriter, but she certainly knew the world of burlesque as none other. So with Craig Rice's ghostwriting they fashioned a murder mystery set in the burlesque world. Somebody is killing the strippers at a burlesque theater and Barbara isn't sitting around waiting to be the next victim. With the help of comic Michael O'Shea she's going to find the perpetrator before she gets done in with her G String. A lovely group of movie queens help Barbara out in this film. Playing some of her peers are Iris Adrian, Gloria Dickson, Marion Martin, Janis Carter, Stephanie Bachelor, and Victoria Faust. Some of these don't make it to the end of the picture. Playing another of the comics is Pinky Lee who I well remember because I used to watch his kid's television show back in my salad days. Pinky was as frantic as I remember him and he does a mean jitterbug with Stanwyck. William Wellman as director keeps the pace of things going pretty nicely. And if you're a leg man, this picture will leave you nothing to complain about. As for the murderer, here's a hint, it's roughly the equivalent of the butler doing it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    What were they thinking?!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    planktonrules
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/1/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is a truly amazing film. Considering the adult content of the film, it's amazing that it was made during the era where the Production Code was so rigidly enforced AND it's amazing that some major Hollywood talent associated themselves with such a sleazy and silly film. The movie is directed by the very well respected William Wellman--the same man responsible for such classics as ALL QUIET ON THE WESTERN FRONT. In the starring role is Barbara Stanwyck--an A-list actress in a decidedly B-list film! So why is the film so sleazy? Well, the setting is a burlesque house and the original title for the story was THE G-STRING MURDERS! While people are killed in a variety of ways, one is found with a G-string wrapped around her throat. Additionally, the women in the film all look very cheap and act like tramps--with lots of cat fights and juicy dialog! In many ways, this film looks like a 1930s Pre-Code or Exploitation Film--not the product of a mainstream studio during the rather stuffy 1940s! How this actually got made and was allowed to be released is a mystery--as well as how they got very respected talent to appear in a poorly written and shabby production. Had this movie not starred Stanwyck and been directed by Wellman, I really doubt if it would have been widely released, as the film looks very cheap and suffers from a rather dull script. In fact, I doubt that a poverty row studio like Monogram would have been proud of the product! The bottom line is that this is a salacious film and it's a great curiosity piece. However, once you get past seeing talented people doing their best to ruin their careers, there really isn't much this film has to offer as far as entertainment value goes. It isn't sleazy enough to appeal to adult film fans and it's just crude enough to make it a bit of a guilty pleasure--nothing more. A bizarre and sub-par film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
 </reviews>
</filme>
