<filme>
 <id>
  1454
 </id>
 <imdburl>
  http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0039152
 </imdburl>
 <ano>
  1947
 </ano>
 <titulo>
  O Anjo e o Malvado
 </titulo>
 <rating>
  6.7
 </rating>
 <sinopse>
  Quirt Evens an all round bad guy is nursed back to health and sought after by Penelope Worth a quaker girl. He eventually finds himself having to choose between his world and the world Penelope lives in.
 </sinopse>
 <storyline>
  Quirt Evens an all round bad guy is nursed back to health and sought after by Penelope Worth a quaker girl. He eventually finds himself having to choose between his world and the world Penelope lives in.
 </storyline>
 <generos>
  <genero>
   Romance
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Western
  </genero>
 </generos>
 <keywords>
  <keyword>
   quaker
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   shot in the back
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   chase
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   life changing
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   kiss
  </keyword>
 </keywords>
 <diretores>
  <diretor>
   James Edward Grant
  </diretor>
 </diretores>
 <escritores>
  <escritor>
   James Edward Grant
  </escritor>
 </escritores>
 <atores>
  <ator>
   John Wayne
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Gail Russell
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Harry Carey
  </ator>
 </atores>
 <reviews>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    " The Quaker And The Gunslinger "
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    PamelaShort
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Angel and The Badman is a quaint romantic western with a predictable story, but in this case it really works. The film is a perfect blend of an extremely ruthless gunslinger being tamed by the highly moral Quakers. Opposites attract, as the lovely and sweet Quaker girl Penelope Worth, ( Gail Russell ) falls in love with badman Quirt Evans, ( John Wayne ) who tries to resist the tempting gentle beauty for awhile . His rough past follows him though, with the persistent single-minded older sheriff, Wistful McClintock ( Harry Carey ) who was always determined to bring Quirt Evans to justice. But he's not the only nemesis in Quirt's criminal past. As the story builds, it ends superbly with the tender Quaker girl, finally asserting herself, convincing the badman to hang up his weapons for good. With the interesting cast of characters, all finely played by a good first-rate cast, this film is surprisingly impressive. The message of the opposition to violence, is a different and refreshing change for a John Wayne movie. John Wayne was such an important star for Republic Pictures, that they allowed him to produce this film. Although not a classic, the results are still enjoyable and worth a look.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    the Duke
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    kai ringler
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    After years of running our main character a cowboy played by none other than the Duke decides that it's time to lay low for awhile,, after being shot,, he is taken in by a Quaker woman, who he eventualliy falls for,, he has to keep his past from her so he doesn't lose her,, he also has to hope that his past doesn't catch up to him , as one of his former partners is hanging around waiting for his speedy recovery. this movie shows a very different side of John Wayne that you don't get to see very often,, a quite reserved kind of solitude, instead of the gun toting,, angry man we see most of the time. Harry Carey also is very wonderful in this picture as is Gail Russel.. not a bad western at all as there is some action sequences and the Duke returns to form near the end of the movie.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    What about the Bible? You can't throw it away, that would be bad luck.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    JohnRouseMerriottChard
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Angel and the Badman is written and directed by James Edward Grant. It stars John Wayne, Gail Russell, Harry Carey, Bruce Cabot, Irene Rich, Lee Dixon and Stephen Grant. Music is by Richard Hageman and cinematography by Archie J. Stout. Quirt Evans (Wayne), a notorious gunman is hurt and on the run. Taken in by The Worth's, a Quaker family, Quirt forms a "special" bond with daughter Penelope (Russell). With the law and other badmen on his tail, will Quirt change his ways before it's too late? John Wayne's first film as a producer and star is also his most romantic. That's not to say it lacks action or Wayne's fine tuning of his macho image is halted, because that's not the case, but this carries a dreamy like old fashioned value that has helped the film endear over the years. It's a touch too slow at times for its own good and runs for ten minutes longer than was needed, things that no doubt stunted its financial growth at the 1947 box office, but there is much to enjoy here. Technical values are high, from Stout's photography that beautifully realises locations in Sedona, Arizona (Monument Valley standing out, naturally!), to cast performances from Carey, Wayne and the gorgeous Miss Russell (chemistry unbound between the three actors), film never lacks for quality. Memorable scenes are plenty, such as The Duke sitting in a chair facing down three henchmen led by Cabot's Laredo Stevens; his gun empty, a free-for-all punch up in a saloon, and some very tender moments between Wayne and Russell. While narratively there's the deft pitching of Quaker values into a wild west setting. A lovely film which also manages to pump the adrenalin as well. 7.5/10 DVD version viewed was Region 2 taken out of the John Wayne Out West 6 film Box Set. A good quality black and white print.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Awesome Film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    David_Brown
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This film is an absolute masterpiece, and one of John Wayne's best. What people who have reviewed the film, have overlooked is the why behind the relationship behind Quirt Evans (Wayne), and Penelope Worth (Gail Russell), which is essentially she was a woman who was essentially put on Earth by God for Quirt, and vice versa. Without Penelope, he would have been doomed, either from the wounds he received prior to meeting her, or by McClintock (Harry Carey), or by some other means. There was a reviewer who said "She threw herself at Quirk.", which was really not true. She was a woman of tremendous faith and devotion, and thus knew that she and Quirt had been put together for a reason,by a higher authority. So that even when he left, she knew he would return, and in the most pivotal scene of the film (Spoilers ahead) where her after she almost dies, and gets a fever, a miracle occurs, and it goes away (Which Dr. Mangram (Tom Powers) acknowledges) and has her father take her to him, and was able prevent the showdown between Quirt and Laredo Stevens (Bruce Cabot) where MCClintock would have killed Quirt. Quirt essentially knew the same thing, because he got tired of the wild life and came back to her. Finally, he was willing to give up his guns and become a farmer for Penelope. The simple reason is Quirt & Penelope were supposed to be together, and they would do whatever was necessary to remain together.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Teaching an old dog new tricks.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mark.waltz
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/12/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    That's what Quaker Gail Russell sets out to do to gunslinger John Wayne in this light-hearted western. With lawman Harry Carey on Wayne's trail, he doesn't really seem to have a chance, but with Russell's family and friends behind him and the grace of God, he just might. Old rivals also seem to want to see him six feet under, but while recovering from injuries with Russell's family's help, Wayne begins to see life from a different perspective. This interesting but occasionally slow-moving film has some great action sequences and a lot of heart. Very amusing is a church scene where Quaker locals accept Wayne into their lives and present him with a monogrammed bible. Later, this bible falls into the hands of some saloon floozies Wayne encounters which is the first indication that Wayne is changing. Bruce Cabot and Irene Rich offer fine support as Russell's family, while stunt director Yakuma Camut offers two fine action sequences-one a fight scene in a saloon, the other a chase sequence which ends with Wayne and Russell flying off a cliff into the river in a fleeing wagon.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Friendly persuasion
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    dbdumonteil
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/7/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is a quiet western ;there's violence in the first pictures (close shot of a revolver) and towards the end but this is a true story of redemption.These quaker family is some kind of heaven where you can eat the best donuts in the world and their influence radiates on the others : take the scene of the water ;we expect a fight between Wayne and the selfish old man ;but it is not so: not only he lets the waters flow ,but when he comes to his neighbor's farm,the good mom presents him with baskets of food.as in the title of William Wyler's famous movie (1956),friendly persuasion indeed!Gail Russel had wonderful eyes and you should see her in "the night has a thousand eyes" where they merge in the sky.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Pretty good, but can be slow
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Mickey Micklon
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/5/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A wounded "Quirt Evans" (John Wayne) is injured even more as his horse collapses near the house of a Quaker family, who take him in and treat him. He catches the eye of the daughter in the family (Gail Russell), and he is obviously attracted to her. But, he just can't shake his past as outlaws and the law alike try to get them for whatever reason. Now he has to look at himself and try to figure out what to do with his life. I have been watching a lot of movies starring John Wayne lately on Hulu, and this is easily the longest one so far. It is also one of the best ones on the site. For the first time in his career, Wayne is pulling double duty in this film. First, he is the leading man, as well as a first-time producer. Since I have no clue as to a producer's job, all I can do is judge him on his performance in front of the camera. And I have to say he does a pretty good job. What makes this Western unique is that it focuses on the personal conflict of "Evans," while throwing everything familiar to Westerns in. The focus is on "Evan's" personal struggle more than the typical plot of a Western. Violence in this movie is fairly tame in this movie, even by the standards of the time of its release. You get some shooting, and one fist fight (which mostly remains off-screen), and one attack from behind with an object from their surroundings. The violence is tame most likely because of the morality of the plot. I was not impressed with the romance subplot. Actually, not the way it was handled. I found it to be pretty weak, and not given the screen time it should have had. I think that the two involved were rushed in the storyline, and not given time to develop the on-screen relationship. I was also not impressed with the chemistry between Wayne and Russell. They had some chemistry together, but nothing impressive. In fact, I wasn't impressed with much of the chemistry between many cast members. I did not like many of the supporting cast, many of which didn't have time to develop. The child actor in this movie was pretty annoying, and seemed to be there just to throw out some complaints as some poor comic relief that, for me, didn't even produce a chuckle. Unlike other recent movies I've watched starring Wayne, I didn't hear any problems with audio. I did have a problem with the picture going fuzzy at times. It appears that Hulu got a bad print to upload. Also, unlike the other movies I've seen in the last couple of weeks, it appeared there was more music in the film. I didn't find any of the music helping in enhancing scenes, and can't remember any particular piece of music except a song being performed on stage in a bar scene. Parents need not worry about the violence in this film. It's pretty mild. You can watch this movie with no problem. In fact, parents will like the moral of this story.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of John Wayne's Earliest and Best Westerns
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    zardoz-13
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/2/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Former Chicago newspaper reporter James Edward Grant spent most of his career either penning or polishing screenplays for John Wayne, and Grant handed Wayne one of his best and earliest western classics in 1947 with "Angel and the Badman" that Wayne produced as his first film and Grant helmed. This amiable black & white oater about a scrappy saddle tramp befriended by a family of friendly Quakers after he has been wounded in a gunfight with three other men is a conversion saga. The Quakers, particularly their young, starry-eyed daughter, eventually convince the gunslinging hero to change his way, hang up his six-gun, and till the soil. John Wayne is perfectly cast as Quirt Evans, a fast-drawing, crack-shooting cowboy and Gail Russell is Penelope Worth. Clocking in at 100 minutes, "Angel and the Badman" is a top-notch horse opera that never run out of energy and triggers a surprise or two. The rest of the cast is uniformly excellent with Bruce Cabot of "Dodge City" as the evil villain Laredo Stevens and Harry Carey stealing the show every time he sneaks into the picture as Territorial Marshal Wistful McClintock. Carey is really funny, too, especially his dialogue about how he isn't going to hang Quirt with a 'new' rope. "Angel and the Badman" benefits from the chemistry between Wayne and Russell who appear to be genuinely made for each other. Although there is a lot of romance, this western boasts enough action to keep the guys happy. A cattle stampede and a runaway wagon chase are two highlights. "Riders of Destiny" lenser Archie Stout makes this Republic western look sprawling and scenic. The best scene in the movie occurs early in the action as the doctor is struggling to sedate Quirt Evans so that he can remove a bullet in his chest. No matter how much laudanum he administers to Quirt, Quirt refuses to stop thrashing around in the best. Penelope's father Thomas Worth (John Halloran of "Blood on the Sun") scrambles downstairs and retrieves Quirt's six-gun dangling outside their house, empties the cartridges from the cylinder and then sticks it into Quirt's hand and Quirt settles down for the doctor to extract the bullet. The scenes where Quirt gets an unfriendly landowner who has blocked up a stream to the Quakers' farms is memorable, too. Chief comic relief is provided by the beanpole town telegrapher (Olin Howland of "Gone with the Wind") who brags later about how close Quirt and he are after he sends a telegram for him. Actually, "Angel and the Badman" is a precursor of sorts to the Alan Ladd oater "Shane," because Quirt defends the Quakers from their enemies. The surprise ending when Quirt rides out to gun down Laredo and his henchmen is good. Grant's dialogue is good, too. "Angel and the Badman" is a thoroughly entertaining, somewhat predictable, rarely outlandish, but good looking western. The scene between Quirt and Penelope when she tells him about the significance of using "thee" and "thou" is imaginative, too.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Friendly Persuasion by Shane/Wayne
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ptb-8
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/1/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This truly uplifting humane Repubic Pictures western produced by John Wayne in 1946 is a genuinely wonderful film in many ways. As a hilarious fish-out-of-water comedy with surprising romance and outlaw danger, it allows Wayne to develop a masculine character of such admirable qualities via the steadfast Quaker rule that dominates the storyline. Wayne plays gunslinger Quirt who might as well be SHANE a few years later or Gary Cooper in FRIENDLY PERSUASION in 1956. Parts even remind me of WITNESS. Gorgeous Gail Russell is so beautiful I easily understand the cult following she developed even after she died so sadly around 1960. ANGEL AND THE BADMAN is a strong and friendly film with very funny scenes and some great western settings lifted by breathtaking photography. The conflict and the innocence work well together, and Wayne and Russell are believable as opposite who attract. It is a very well designed and decorated film with excellent production values. I would be keen now to see THE WAKE OF THE RED WITCH. We are having a John Wayne festival on TV in Australia this January and ANGEL screened on a Saturday night at 8.30pm for us all to enjoy. I certainly did.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    substandard John Wayne western
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    disdressed12
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/3/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    this western is more of a character study than anything else,and a romance.there isn't a lot of action.it's not the worst movie i have seen,but i do felt it went on too long.i felt it was too tedious.there were several times when i thought it was over,and could/should have been over,but it kept going.i think they could have told just as good a story if they had shortened the film.it's definitely not one of my favourite westerns,nor one my favourite John Wayne westerns.it's certainly no classic,in my opinion.i know many people would disagree with that sentiment,which is fine.i wouldn't likely watch it again,at least for a long time.for me,Angel and the Badman is a 4/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    " The Quaker And The Gunslinger "
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    PamelaShort
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Angel and The Badman is a quaint romantic western with a predictable story, but in this case it really works. The film is a perfect blend of an extremely ruthless gunslinger being tamed by the highly moral Quakers. Opposites attract, as the lovely and sweet Quaker girl Penelope Worth, ( Gail Russell ) falls in love with badman Quirt Evans, ( John Wayne ) who tries to resist the tempting gentle beauty for awhile . His rough past follows him though, with the persistent single-minded older sheriff, Wistful McClintock ( Harry Carey ) who was always determined to bring Quirt Evans to justice. But he's not the only nemesis in Quirt's criminal past. As the story builds, it ends superbly with the tender Quaker girl, finally asserting herself, convincing the badman to hang up his weapons for good. With the interesting cast of characters, all finely played by a good first-rate cast, this film is surprisingly impressive. The message of the opposition to violence, is a different and refreshing change for a John Wayne movie. John Wayne was such an important star for Republic Pictures, that they allowed him to produce this film. Although not a classic, the results are still enjoyable and worth a look.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    the Duke
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    kai ringler
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    After years of running our main character a cowboy played by none other than the Duke decides that it's time to lay low for awhile,, after being shot,, he is taken in by a Quaker woman, who he eventualliy falls for,, he has to keep his past from her so he doesn't lose her,, he also has to hope that his past doesn't catch up to him , as one of his former partners is hanging around waiting for his speedy recovery. this movie shows a very different side of John Wayne that you don't get to see very often,, a quite reserved kind of solitude, instead of the gun toting,, angry man we see most of the time. Harry Carey also is very wonderful in this picture as is Gail Russel.. not a bad western at all as there is some action sequences and the Duke returns to form near the end of the movie.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    What about the Bible? You can't throw it away, that would be bad luck.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    JohnRouseMerriottChard
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Angel and the Badman is written and directed by James Edward Grant. It stars John Wayne, Gail Russell, Harry Carey, Bruce Cabot, Irene Rich, Lee Dixon and Stephen Grant. Music is by Richard Hageman and cinematography by Archie J. Stout. Quirt Evans (Wayne), a notorious gunman is hurt and on the run. Taken in by The Worth's, a Quaker family, Quirt forms a "special" bond with daughter Penelope (Russell). With the law and other badmen on his tail, will Quirt change his ways before it's too late? John Wayne's first film as a producer and star is also his most romantic. That's not to say it lacks action or Wayne's fine tuning of his macho image is halted, because that's not the case, but this carries a dreamy like old fashioned value that has helped the film endear over the years. It's a touch too slow at times for its own good and runs for ten minutes longer than was needed, things that no doubt stunted its financial growth at the 1947 box office, but there is much to enjoy here. Technical values are high, from Stout's photography that beautifully realises locations in Sedona, Arizona (Monument Valley standing out, naturally!), to cast performances from Carey, Wayne and the gorgeous Miss Russell (chemistry unbound between the three actors), film never lacks for quality. Memorable scenes are plenty, such as The Duke sitting in a chair facing down three henchmen led by Cabot's Laredo Stevens; his gun empty, a free-for-all punch up in a saloon, and some very tender moments between Wayne and Russell. While narratively there's the deft pitching of Quaker values into a wild west setting. A lovely film which also manages to pump the adrenalin as well. 7.5/10 DVD version viewed was Region 2 taken out of the John Wayne Out West 6 film Box Set. A good quality black and white print.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Awesome Film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    David_Brown
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This film is an absolute masterpiece, and one of John Wayne's best. What people who have reviewed the film, have overlooked is the why behind the relationship behind Quirt Evans (Wayne), and Penelope Worth (Gail Russell), which is essentially she was a woman who was essentially put on Earth by God for Quirt, and vice versa. Without Penelope, he would have been doomed, either from the wounds he received prior to meeting her, or by McClintock (Harry Carey), or by some other means. There was a reviewer who said "She threw herself at Quirk.", which was really not true. She was a woman of tremendous faith and devotion, and thus knew that she and Quirt had been put together for a reason,by a higher authority. So that even when he left, she knew he would return, and in the most pivotal scene of the film (Spoilers ahead) where her after she almost dies, and gets a fever, a miracle occurs, and it goes away (Which Dr. Mangram (Tom Powers) acknowledges) and has her father take her to him, and was able prevent the showdown between Quirt and Laredo Stevens (Bruce Cabot) where MCClintock would have killed Quirt. Quirt essentially knew the same thing, because he got tired of the wild life and came back to her. Finally, he was willing to give up his guns and become a farmer for Penelope. The simple reason is Quirt & Penelope were supposed to be together, and they would do whatever was necessary to remain together.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Teaching an old dog new tricks.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mark.waltz
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/12/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    That's what Quaker Gail Russell sets out to do to gunslinger John Wayne in this light-hearted western. With lawman Harry Carey on Wayne's trail, he doesn't really seem to have a chance, but with Russell's family and friends behind him and the grace of God, he just might. Old rivals also seem to want to see him six feet under, but while recovering from injuries with Russell's family's help, Wayne begins to see life from a different perspective. This interesting but occasionally slow-moving film has some great action sequences and a lot of heart. Very amusing is a church scene where Quaker locals accept Wayne into their lives and present him with a monogrammed bible. Later, this bible falls into the hands of some saloon floozies Wayne encounters which is the first indication that Wayne is changing. Bruce Cabot and Irene Rich offer fine support as Russell's family, while stunt director Yakuma Camut offers two fine action sequences-one a fight scene in a saloon, the other a chase sequence which ends with Wayne and Russell flying off a cliff into the river in a fleeing wagon.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Friendly persuasion
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    dbdumonteil
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/7/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is a quiet western ;there's violence in the first pictures (close shot of a revolver) and towards the end but this is a true story of redemption.These quaker family is some kind of heaven where you can eat the best donuts in the world and their influence radiates on the others : take the scene of the water ;we expect a fight between Wayne and the selfish old man ;but it is not so: not only he lets the waters flow ,but when he comes to his neighbor's farm,the good mom presents him with baskets of food.as in the title of William Wyler's famous movie (1956),friendly persuasion indeed!Gail Russel had wonderful eyes and you should see her in "the night has a thousand eyes" where they merge in the sky.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Pretty good, but can be slow
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Mickey Micklon
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/5/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A wounded "Quirt Evans" (John Wayne) is injured even more as his horse collapses near the house of a Quaker family, who take him in and treat him. He catches the eye of the daughter in the family (Gail Russell), and he is obviously attracted to her. But, he just can't shake his past as outlaws and the law alike try to get them for whatever reason. Now he has to look at himself and try to figure out what to do with his life. I have been watching a lot of movies starring John Wayne lately on Hulu, and this is easily the longest one so far. It is also one of the best ones on the site. For the first time in his career, Wayne is pulling double duty in this film. First, he is the leading man, as well as a first-time producer. Since I have no clue as to a producer's job, all I can do is judge him on his performance in front of the camera. And I have to say he does a pretty good job. What makes this Western unique is that it focuses on the personal conflict of "Evans," while throwing everything familiar to Westerns in. The focus is on "Evan's" personal struggle more than the typical plot of a Western. Violence in this movie is fairly tame in this movie, even by the standards of the time of its release. You get some shooting, and one fist fight (which mostly remains off-screen), and one attack from behind with an object from their surroundings. The violence is tame most likely because of the morality of the plot. I was not impressed with the romance subplot. Actually, not the way it was handled. I found it to be pretty weak, and not given the screen time it should have had. I think that the two involved were rushed in the storyline, and not given time to develop the on-screen relationship. I was also not impressed with the chemistry between Wayne and Russell. They had some chemistry together, but nothing impressive. In fact, I wasn't impressed with much of the chemistry between many cast members. I did not like many of the supporting cast, many of which didn't have time to develop. The child actor in this movie was pretty annoying, and seemed to be there just to throw out some complaints as some poor comic relief that, for me, didn't even produce a chuckle. Unlike other recent movies I've watched starring Wayne, I didn't hear any problems with audio. I did have a problem with the picture going fuzzy at times. It appears that Hulu got a bad print to upload. Also, unlike the other movies I've seen in the last couple of weeks, it appeared there was more music in the film. I didn't find any of the music helping in enhancing scenes, and can't remember any particular piece of music except a song being performed on stage in a bar scene. Parents need not worry about the violence in this film. It's pretty mild. You can watch this movie with no problem. In fact, parents will like the moral of this story.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of John Wayne's Earliest and Best Westerns
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    zardoz-13
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/2/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Former Chicago newspaper reporter James Edward Grant spent most of his career either penning or polishing screenplays for John Wayne, and Grant handed Wayne one of his best and earliest western classics in 1947 with "Angel and the Badman" that Wayne produced as his first film and Grant helmed. This amiable black & white oater about a scrappy saddle tramp befriended by a family of friendly Quakers after he has been wounded in a gunfight with three other men is a conversion saga. The Quakers, particularly their young, starry-eyed daughter, eventually convince the gunslinging hero to change his way, hang up his six-gun, and till the soil. John Wayne is perfectly cast as Quirt Evans, a fast-drawing, crack-shooting cowboy and Gail Russell is Penelope Worth. Clocking in at 100 minutes, "Angel and the Badman" is a top-notch horse opera that never run out of energy and triggers a surprise or two. The rest of the cast is uniformly excellent with Bruce Cabot of "Dodge City" as the evil villain Laredo Stevens and Harry Carey stealing the show every time he sneaks into the picture as Territorial Marshal Wistful McClintock. Carey is really funny, too, especially his dialogue about how he isn't going to hang Quirt with a 'new' rope. "Angel and the Badman" benefits from the chemistry between Wayne and Russell who appear to be genuinely made for each other. Although there is a lot of romance, this western boasts enough action to keep the guys happy. A cattle stampede and a runaway wagon chase are two highlights. "Riders of Destiny" lenser Archie Stout makes this Republic western look sprawling and scenic. The best scene in the movie occurs early in the action as the doctor is struggling to sedate Quirt Evans so that he can remove a bullet in his chest. No matter how much laudanum he administers to Quirt, Quirt refuses to stop thrashing around in the best. Penelope's father Thomas Worth (John Halloran of "Blood on the Sun") scrambles downstairs and retrieves Quirt's six-gun dangling outside their house, empties the cartridges from the cylinder and then sticks it into Quirt's hand and Quirt settles down for the doctor to extract the bullet. The scenes where Quirt gets an unfriendly landowner who has blocked up a stream to the Quakers' farms is memorable, too. Chief comic relief is provided by the beanpole town telegrapher (Olin Howland of "Gone with the Wind") who brags later about how close Quirt and he are after he sends a telegram for him. Actually, "Angel and the Badman" is a precursor of sorts to the Alan Ladd oater "Shane," because Quirt defends the Quakers from their enemies. The surprise ending when Quirt rides out to gun down Laredo and his henchmen is good. Grant's dialogue is good, too. "Angel and the Badman" is a thoroughly entertaining, somewhat predictable, rarely outlandish, but good looking western. The scene between Quirt and Penelope when she tells him about the significance of using "thee" and "thou" is imaginative, too.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Friendly Persuasion by Shane/Wayne
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ptb-8
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/1/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This truly uplifting humane Repubic Pictures western produced by John Wayne in 1946 is a genuinely wonderful film in many ways. As a hilarious fish-out-of-water comedy with surprising romance and outlaw danger, it allows Wayne to develop a masculine character of such admirable qualities via the steadfast Quaker rule that dominates the storyline. Wayne plays gunslinger Quirt who might as well be SHANE a few years later or Gary Cooper in FRIENDLY PERSUASION in 1956. Parts even remind me of WITNESS. Gorgeous Gail Russell is so beautiful I easily understand the cult following she developed even after she died so sadly around 1960. ANGEL AND THE BADMAN is a strong and friendly film with very funny scenes and some great western settings lifted by breathtaking photography. The conflict and the innocence work well together, and Wayne and Russell are believable as opposite who attract. It is a very well designed and decorated film with excellent production values. I would be keen now to see THE WAKE OF THE RED WITCH. We are having a John Wayne festival on TV in Australia this January and ANGEL screened on a Saturday night at 8.30pm for us all to enjoy. I certainly did.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    substandard John Wayne western
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    disdressed12
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/3/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    this western is more of a character study than anything else,and a romance.there isn't a lot of action.it's not the worst movie i have seen,but i do felt it went on too long.i felt it was too tedious.there were several times when i thought it was over,and could/should have been over,but it kept going.i think they could have told just as good a story if they had shortened the film.it's definitely not one of my favourite westerns,nor one my favourite John Wayne westerns.it's certainly no classic,in my opinion.i know many people would disagree with that sentiment,which is fine.i wouldn't likely watch it again,at least for a long time.for me,Angel and the Badman is a 4/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    " The Quaker And The Gunslinger "
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    PamelaShort
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Angel and The Badman is a quaint romantic western with a predictable story, but in this case it really works. The film is a perfect blend of an extremely ruthless gunslinger being tamed by the highly moral Quakers. Opposites attract, as the lovely and sweet Quaker girl Penelope Worth, ( Gail Russell ) falls in love with badman Quirt Evans, ( John Wayne ) who tries to resist the tempting gentle beauty for awhile . His rough past follows him though, with the persistent single-minded older sheriff, Wistful McClintock ( Harry Carey ) who was always determined to bring Quirt Evans to justice. But he's not the only nemesis in Quirt's criminal past. As the story builds, it ends superbly with the tender Quaker girl, finally asserting herself, convincing the badman to hang up his weapons for good. With the interesting cast of characters, all finely played by a good first-rate cast, this film is surprisingly impressive. The message of the opposition to violence, is a different and refreshing change for a John Wayne movie. John Wayne was such an important star for Republic Pictures, that they allowed him to produce this film. Although not a classic, the results are still enjoyable and worth a look.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    the Duke
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    kai ringler
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    After years of running our main character a cowboy played by none other than the Duke decides that it's time to lay low for awhile,, after being shot,, he is taken in by a Quaker woman, who he eventualliy falls for,, he has to keep his past from her so he doesn't lose her,, he also has to hope that his past doesn't catch up to him , as one of his former partners is hanging around waiting for his speedy recovery. this movie shows a very different side of John Wayne that you don't get to see very often,, a quite reserved kind of solitude, instead of the gun toting,, angry man we see most of the time. Harry Carey also is very wonderful in this picture as is Gail Russel.. not a bad western at all as there is some action sequences and the Duke returns to form near the end of the movie.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    What about the Bible? You can't throw it away, that would be bad luck.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    JohnRouseMerriottChard
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Angel and the Badman is written and directed by James Edward Grant. It stars John Wayne, Gail Russell, Harry Carey, Bruce Cabot, Irene Rich, Lee Dixon and Stephen Grant. Music is by Richard Hageman and cinematography by Archie J. Stout. Quirt Evans (Wayne), a notorious gunman is hurt and on the run. Taken in by The Worth's, a Quaker family, Quirt forms a "special" bond with daughter Penelope (Russell). With the law and other badmen on his tail, will Quirt change his ways before it's too late? John Wayne's first film as a producer and star is also his most romantic. That's not to say it lacks action or Wayne's fine tuning of his macho image is halted, because that's not the case, but this carries a dreamy like old fashioned value that has helped the film endear over the years. It's a touch too slow at times for its own good and runs for ten minutes longer than was needed, things that no doubt stunted its financial growth at the 1947 box office, but there is much to enjoy here. Technical values are high, from Stout's photography that beautifully realises locations in Sedona, Arizona (Monument Valley standing out, naturally!), to cast performances from Carey, Wayne and the gorgeous Miss Russell (chemistry unbound between the three actors), film never lacks for quality. Memorable scenes are plenty, such as The Duke sitting in a chair facing down three henchmen led by Cabot's Laredo Stevens; his gun empty, a free-for-all punch up in a saloon, and some very tender moments between Wayne and Russell. While narratively there's the deft pitching of Quaker values into a wild west setting. A lovely film which also manages to pump the adrenalin as well. 7.5/10 DVD version viewed was Region 2 taken out of the John Wayne Out West 6 film Box Set. A good quality black and white print.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Awesome Film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    David_Brown
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This film is an absolute masterpiece, and one of John Wayne's best. What people who have reviewed the film, have overlooked is the why behind the relationship behind Quirt Evans (Wayne), and Penelope Worth (Gail Russell), which is essentially she was a woman who was essentially put on Earth by God for Quirt, and vice versa. Without Penelope, he would have been doomed, either from the wounds he received prior to meeting her, or by McClintock (Harry Carey), or by some other means. There was a reviewer who said "She threw herself at Quirk.", which was really not true. She was a woman of tremendous faith and devotion, and thus knew that she and Quirt had been put together for a reason,by a higher authority. So that even when he left, she knew he would return, and in the most pivotal scene of the film (Spoilers ahead) where her after she almost dies, and gets a fever, a miracle occurs, and it goes away (Which Dr. Mangram (Tom Powers) acknowledges) and has her father take her to him, and was able prevent the showdown between Quirt and Laredo Stevens (Bruce Cabot) where MCClintock would have killed Quirt. Quirt essentially knew the same thing, because he got tired of the wild life and came back to her. Finally, he was willing to give up his guns and become a farmer for Penelope. The simple reason is Quirt & Penelope were supposed to be together, and they would do whatever was necessary to remain together.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Teaching an old dog new tricks.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mark.waltz
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/12/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    That's what Quaker Gail Russell sets out to do to gunslinger John Wayne in this light-hearted western. With lawman Harry Carey on Wayne's trail, he doesn't really seem to have a chance, but with Russell's family and friends behind him and the grace of God, he just might. Old rivals also seem to want to see him six feet under, but while recovering from injuries with Russell's family's help, Wayne begins to see life from a different perspective. This interesting but occasionally slow-moving film has some great action sequences and a lot of heart. Very amusing is a church scene where Quaker locals accept Wayne into their lives and present him with a monogrammed bible. Later, this bible falls into the hands of some saloon floozies Wayne encounters which is the first indication that Wayne is changing. Bruce Cabot and Irene Rich offer fine support as Russell's family, while stunt director Yakuma Camut offers two fine action sequences-one a fight scene in a saloon, the other a chase sequence which ends with Wayne and Russell flying off a cliff into the river in a fleeing wagon.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Friendly persuasion
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    dbdumonteil
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/7/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is a quiet western ;there's violence in the first pictures (close shot of a revolver) and towards the end but this is a true story of redemption.These quaker family is some kind of heaven where you can eat the best donuts in the world and their influence radiates on the others : take the scene of the water ;we expect a fight between Wayne and the selfish old man ;but it is not so: not only he lets the waters flow ,but when he comes to his neighbor's farm,the good mom presents him with baskets of food.as in the title of William Wyler's famous movie (1956),friendly persuasion indeed!Gail Russel had wonderful eyes and you should see her in "the night has a thousand eyes" where they merge in the sky.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Pretty good, but can be slow
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Mickey Micklon
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/5/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A wounded "Quirt Evans" (John Wayne) is injured even more as his horse collapses near the house of a Quaker family, who take him in and treat him. He catches the eye of the daughter in the family (Gail Russell), and he is obviously attracted to her. But, he just can't shake his past as outlaws and the law alike try to get them for whatever reason. Now he has to look at himself and try to figure out what to do with his life. I have been watching a lot of movies starring John Wayne lately on Hulu, and this is easily the longest one so far. It is also one of the best ones on the site. For the first time in his career, Wayne is pulling double duty in this film. First, he is the leading man, as well as a first-time producer. Since I have no clue as to a producer's job, all I can do is judge him on his performance in front of the camera. And I have to say he does a pretty good job. What makes this Western unique is that it focuses on the personal conflict of "Evans," while throwing everything familiar to Westerns in. The focus is on "Evan's" personal struggle more than the typical plot of a Western. Violence in this movie is fairly tame in this movie, even by the standards of the time of its release. You get some shooting, and one fist fight (which mostly remains off-screen), and one attack from behind with an object from their surroundings. The violence is tame most likely because of the morality of the plot. I was not impressed with the romance subplot. Actually, not the way it was handled. I found it to be pretty weak, and not given the screen time it should have had. I think that the two involved were rushed in the storyline, and not given time to develop the on-screen relationship. I was also not impressed with the chemistry between Wayne and Russell. They had some chemistry together, but nothing impressive. In fact, I wasn't impressed with much of the chemistry between many cast members. I did not like many of the supporting cast, many of which didn't have time to develop. The child actor in this movie was pretty annoying, and seemed to be there just to throw out some complaints as some poor comic relief that, for me, didn't even produce a chuckle. Unlike other recent movies I've watched starring Wayne, I didn't hear any problems with audio. I did have a problem with the picture going fuzzy at times. It appears that Hulu got a bad print to upload. Also, unlike the other movies I've seen in the last couple of weeks, it appeared there was more music in the film. I didn't find any of the music helping in enhancing scenes, and can't remember any particular piece of music except a song being performed on stage in a bar scene. Parents need not worry about the violence in this film. It's pretty mild. You can watch this movie with no problem. In fact, parents will like the moral of this story.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of John Wayne's Earliest and Best Westerns
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    zardoz-13
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/2/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Former Chicago newspaper reporter James Edward Grant spent most of his career either penning or polishing screenplays for John Wayne, and Grant handed Wayne one of his best and earliest western classics in 1947 with "Angel and the Badman" that Wayne produced as his first film and Grant helmed. This amiable black & white oater about a scrappy saddle tramp befriended by a family of friendly Quakers after he has been wounded in a gunfight with three other men is a conversion saga. The Quakers, particularly their young, starry-eyed daughter, eventually convince the gunslinging hero to change his way, hang up his six-gun, and till the soil. John Wayne is perfectly cast as Quirt Evans, a fast-drawing, crack-shooting cowboy and Gail Russell is Penelope Worth. Clocking in at 100 minutes, "Angel and the Badman" is a top-notch horse opera that never run out of energy and triggers a surprise or two. The rest of the cast is uniformly excellent with Bruce Cabot of "Dodge City" as the evil villain Laredo Stevens and Harry Carey stealing the show every time he sneaks into the picture as Territorial Marshal Wistful McClintock. Carey is really funny, too, especially his dialogue about how he isn't going to hang Quirt with a 'new' rope. "Angel and the Badman" benefits from the chemistry between Wayne and Russell who appear to be genuinely made for each other. Although there is a lot of romance, this western boasts enough action to keep the guys happy. A cattle stampede and a runaway wagon chase are two highlights. "Riders of Destiny" lenser Archie Stout makes this Republic western look sprawling and scenic. The best scene in the movie occurs early in the action as the doctor is struggling to sedate Quirt Evans so that he can remove a bullet in his chest. No matter how much laudanum he administers to Quirt, Quirt refuses to stop thrashing around in the best. Penelope's father Thomas Worth (John Halloran of "Blood on the Sun") scrambles downstairs and retrieves Quirt's six-gun dangling outside their house, empties the cartridges from the cylinder and then sticks it into Quirt's hand and Quirt settles down for the doctor to extract the bullet. The scenes where Quirt gets an unfriendly landowner who has blocked up a stream to the Quakers' farms is memorable, too. Chief comic relief is provided by the beanpole town telegrapher (Olin Howland of "Gone with the Wind") who brags later about how close Quirt and he are after he sends a telegram for him. Actually, "Angel and the Badman" is a precursor of sorts to the Alan Ladd oater "Shane," because Quirt defends the Quakers from their enemies. The surprise ending when Quirt rides out to gun down Laredo and his henchmen is good. Grant's dialogue is good, too. "Angel and the Badman" is a thoroughly entertaining, somewhat predictable, rarely outlandish, but good looking western. The scene between Quirt and Penelope when she tells him about the significance of using "thee" and "thou" is imaginative, too.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Friendly Persuasion by Shane/Wayne
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ptb-8
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/1/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This truly uplifting humane Repubic Pictures western produced by John Wayne in 1946 is a genuinely wonderful film in many ways. As a hilarious fish-out-of-water comedy with surprising romance and outlaw danger, it allows Wayne to develop a masculine character of such admirable qualities via the steadfast Quaker rule that dominates the storyline. Wayne plays gunslinger Quirt who might as well be SHANE a few years later or Gary Cooper in FRIENDLY PERSUASION in 1956. Parts even remind me of WITNESS. Gorgeous Gail Russell is so beautiful I easily understand the cult following she developed even after she died so sadly around 1960. ANGEL AND THE BADMAN is a strong and friendly film with very funny scenes and some great western settings lifted by breathtaking photography. The conflict and the innocence work well together, and Wayne and Russell are believable as opposite who attract. It is a very well designed and decorated film with excellent production values. I would be keen now to see THE WAKE OF THE RED WITCH. We are having a John Wayne festival on TV in Australia this January and ANGEL screened on a Saturday night at 8.30pm for us all to enjoy. I certainly did.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    substandard John Wayne western
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    disdressed12
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/3/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    this western is more of a character study than anything else,and a romance.there isn't a lot of action.it's not the worst movie i have seen,but i do felt it went on too long.i felt it was too tedious.there were several times when i thought it was over,and could/should have been over,but it kept going.i think they could have told just as good a story if they had shortened the film.it's definitely not one of my favourite westerns,nor one my favourite John Wayne westerns.it's certainly no classic,in my opinion.i know many people would disagree with that sentiment,which is fine.i wouldn't likely watch it again,at least for a long time.for me,Angel and the Badman is a 4/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    " The Quaker And The Gunslinger "
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    PamelaShort
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Angel and The Badman is a quaint romantic western with a predictable story, but in this case it really works. The film is a perfect blend of an extremely ruthless gunslinger being tamed by the highly moral Quakers. Opposites attract, as the lovely and sweet Quaker girl Penelope Worth, ( Gail Russell ) falls in love with badman Quirt Evans, ( John Wayne ) who tries to resist the tempting gentle beauty for awhile . His rough past follows him though, with the persistent single-minded older sheriff, Wistful McClintock ( Harry Carey ) who was always determined to bring Quirt Evans to justice. But he's not the only nemesis in Quirt's criminal past. As the story builds, it ends superbly with the tender Quaker girl, finally asserting herself, convincing the badman to hang up his weapons for good. With the interesting cast of characters, all finely played by a good first-rate cast, this film is surprisingly impressive. The message of the opposition to violence, is a different and refreshing change for a John Wayne movie. John Wayne was such an important star for Republic Pictures, that they allowed him to produce this film. Although not a classic, the results are still enjoyable and worth a look.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    the Duke
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    kai ringler
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    After years of running our main character a cowboy played by none other than the Duke decides that it's time to lay low for awhile,, after being shot,, he is taken in by a Quaker woman, who he eventualliy falls for,, he has to keep his past from her so he doesn't lose her,, he also has to hope that his past doesn't catch up to him , as one of his former partners is hanging around waiting for his speedy recovery. this movie shows a very different side of John Wayne that you don't get to see very often,, a quite reserved kind of solitude, instead of the gun toting,, angry man we see most of the time. Harry Carey also is very wonderful in this picture as is Gail Russel.. not a bad western at all as there is some action sequences and the Duke returns to form near the end of the movie.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    What about the Bible? You can't throw it away, that would be bad luck.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    JohnRouseMerriottChard
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Angel and the Badman is written and directed by James Edward Grant. It stars John Wayne, Gail Russell, Harry Carey, Bruce Cabot, Irene Rich, Lee Dixon and Stephen Grant. Music is by Richard Hageman and cinematography by Archie J. Stout. Quirt Evans (Wayne), a notorious gunman is hurt and on the run. Taken in by The Worth's, a Quaker family, Quirt forms a "special" bond with daughter Penelope (Russell). With the law and other badmen on his tail, will Quirt change his ways before it's too late? John Wayne's first film as a producer and star is also his most romantic. That's not to say it lacks action or Wayne's fine tuning of his macho image is halted, because that's not the case, but this carries a dreamy like old fashioned value that has helped the film endear over the years. It's a touch too slow at times for its own good and runs for ten minutes longer than was needed, things that no doubt stunted its financial growth at the 1947 box office, but there is much to enjoy here. Technical values are high, from Stout's photography that beautifully realises locations in Sedona, Arizona (Monument Valley standing out, naturally!), to cast performances from Carey, Wayne and the gorgeous Miss Russell (chemistry unbound between the three actors), film never lacks for quality. Memorable scenes are plenty, such as The Duke sitting in a chair facing down three henchmen led by Cabot's Laredo Stevens; his gun empty, a free-for-all punch up in a saloon, and some very tender moments between Wayne and Russell. While narratively there's the deft pitching of Quaker values into a wild west setting. A lovely film which also manages to pump the adrenalin as well. 7.5/10 DVD version viewed was Region 2 taken out of the John Wayne Out West 6 film Box Set. A good quality black and white print.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Awesome Film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    David_Brown
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This film is an absolute masterpiece, and one of John Wayne's best. What people who have reviewed the film, have overlooked is the why behind the relationship behind Quirt Evans (Wayne), and Penelope Worth (Gail Russell), which is essentially she was a woman who was essentially put on Earth by God for Quirt, and vice versa. Without Penelope, he would have been doomed, either from the wounds he received prior to meeting her, or by McClintock (Harry Carey), or by some other means. There was a reviewer who said "She threw herself at Quirk.", which was really not true. She was a woman of tremendous faith and devotion, and thus knew that she and Quirt had been put together for a reason,by a higher authority. So that even when he left, she knew he would return, and in the most pivotal scene of the film (Spoilers ahead) where her after she almost dies, and gets a fever, a miracle occurs, and it goes away (Which Dr. Mangram (Tom Powers) acknowledges) and has her father take her to him, and was able prevent the showdown between Quirt and Laredo Stevens (Bruce Cabot) where MCClintock would have killed Quirt. Quirt essentially knew the same thing, because he got tired of the wild life and came back to her. Finally, he was willing to give up his guns and become a farmer for Penelope. The simple reason is Quirt & Penelope were supposed to be together, and they would do whatever was necessary to remain together.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Teaching an old dog new tricks.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mark.waltz
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/12/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    That's what Quaker Gail Russell sets out to do to gunslinger John Wayne in this light-hearted western. With lawman Harry Carey on Wayne's trail, he doesn't really seem to have a chance, but with Russell's family and friends behind him and the grace of God, he just might. Old rivals also seem to want to see him six feet under, but while recovering from injuries with Russell's family's help, Wayne begins to see life from a different perspective. This interesting but occasionally slow-moving film has some great action sequences and a lot of heart. Very amusing is a church scene where Quaker locals accept Wayne into their lives and present him with a monogrammed bible. Later, this bible falls into the hands of some saloon floozies Wayne encounters which is the first indication that Wayne is changing. Bruce Cabot and Irene Rich offer fine support as Russell's family, while stunt director Yakuma Camut offers two fine action sequences-one a fight scene in a saloon, the other a chase sequence which ends with Wayne and Russell flying off a cliff into the river in a fleeing wagon.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Friendly persuasion
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    dbdumonteil
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/7/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is a quiet western ;there's violence in the first pictures (close shot of a revolver) and towards the end but this is a true story of redemption.These quaker family is some kind of heaven where you can eat the best donuts in the world and their influence radiates on the others : take the scene of the water ;we expect a fight between Wayne and the selfish old man ;but it is not so: not only he lets the waters flow ,but when he comes to his neighbor's farm,the good mom presents him with baskets of food.as in the title of William Wyler's famous movie (1956),friendly persuasion indeed!Gail Russel had wonderful eyes and you should see her in "the night has a thousand eyes" where they merge in the sky.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Pretty good, but can be slow
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Mickey Micklon
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/5/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A wounded "Quirt Evans" (John Wayne) is injured even more as his horse collapses near the house of a Quaker family, who take him in and treat him. He catches the eye of the daughter in the family (Gail Russell), and he is obviously attracted to her. But, he just can't shake his past as outlaws and the law alike try to get them for whatever reason. Now he has to look at himself and try to figure out what to do with his life. I have been watching a lot of movies starring John Wayne lately on Hulu, and this is easily the longest one so far. It is also one of the best ones on the site. For the first time in his career, Wayne is pulling double duty in this film. First, he is the leading man, as well as a first-time producer. Since I have no clue as to a producer's job, all I can do is judge him on his performance in front of the camera. And I have to say he does a pretty good job. What makes this Western unique is that it focuses on the personal conflict of "Evans," while throwing everything familiar to Westerns in. The focus is on "Evan's" personal struggle more than the typical plot of a Western. Violence in this movie is fairly tame in this movie, even by the standards of the time of its release. You get some shooting, and one fist fight (which mostly remains off-screen), and one attack from behind with an object from their surroundings. The violence is tame most likely because of the morality of the plot. I was not impressed with the romance subplot. Actually, not the way it was handled. I found it to be pretty weak, and not given the screen time it should have had. I think that the two involved were rushed in the storyline, and not given time to develop the on-screen relationship. I was also not impressed with the chemistry between Wayne and Russell. They had some chemistry together, but nothing impressive. In fact, I wasn't impressed with much of the chemistry between many cast members. I did not like many of the supporting cast, many of which didn't have time to develop. The child actor in this movie was pretty annoying, and seemed to be there just to throw out some complaints as some poor comic relief that, for me, didn't even produce a chuckle. Unlike other recent movies I've watched starring Wayne, I didn't hear any problems with audio. I did have a problem with the picture going fuzzy at times. It appears that Hulu got a bad print to upload. Also, unlike the other movies I've seen in the last couple of weeks, it appeared there was more music in the film. I didn't find any of the music helping in enhancing scenes, and can't remember any particular piece of music except a song being performed on stage in a bar scene. Parents need not worry about the violence in this film. It's pretty mild. You can watch this movie with no problem. In fact, parents will like the moral of this story.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of John Wayne's Earliest and Best Westerns
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    zardoz-13
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/2/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Former Chicago newspaper reporter James Edward Grant spent most of his career either penning or polishing screenplays for John Wayne, and Grant handed Wayne one of his best and earliest western classics in 1947 with "Angel and the Badman" that Wayne produced as his first film and Grant helmed. This amiable black & white oater about a scrappy saddle tramp befriended by a family of friendly Quakers after he has been wounded in a gunfight with three other men is a conversion saga. The Quakers, particularly their young, starry-eyed daughter, eventually convince the gunslinging hero to change his way, hang up his six-gun, and till the soil. John Wayne is perfectly cast as Quirt Evans, a fast-drawing, crack-shooting cowboy and Gail Russell is Penelope Worth. Clocking in at 100 minutes, "Angel and the Badman" is a top-notch horse opera that never run out of energy and triggers a surprise or two. The rest of the cast is uniformly excellent with Bruce Cabot of "Dodge City" as the evil villain Laredo Stevens and Harry Carey stealing the show every time he sneaks into the picture as Territorial Marshal Wistful McClintock. Carey is really funny, too, especially his dialogue about how he isn't going to hang Quirt with a 'new' rope. "Angel and the Badman" benefits from the chemistry between Wayne and Russell who appear to be genuinely made for each other. Although there is a lot of romance, this western boasts enough action to keep the guys happy. A cattle stampede and a runaway wagon chase are two highlights. "Riders of Destiny" lenser Archie Stout makes this Republic western look sprawling and scenic. The best scene in the movie occurs early in the action as the doctor is struggling to sedate Quirt Evans so that he can remove a bullet in his chest. No matter how much laudanum he administers to Quirt, Quirt refuses to stop thrashing around in the best. Penelope's father Thomas Worth (John Halloran of "Blood on the Sun") scrambles downstairs and retrieves Quirt's six-gun dangling outside their house, empties the cartridges from the cylinder and then sticks it into Quirt's hand and Quirt settles down for the doctor to extract the bullet. The scenes where Quirt gets an unfriendly landowner who has blocked up a stream to the Quakers' farms is memorable, too. Chief comic relief is provided by the beanpole town telegrapher (Olin Howland of "Gone with the Wind") who brags later about how close Quirt and he are after he sends a telegram for him. Actually, "Angel and the Badman" is a precursor of sorts to the Alan Ladd oater "Shane," because Quirt defends the Quakers from their enemies. The surprise ending when Quirt rides out to gun down Laredo and his henchmen is good. Grant's dialogue is good, too. "Angel and the Badman" is a thoroughly entertaining, somewhat predictable, rarely outlandish, but good looking western. The scene between Quirt and Penelope when she tells him about the significance of using "thee" and "thou" is imaginative, too.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Friendly Persuasion by Shane/Wayne
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ptb-8
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/1/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This truly uplifting humane Repubic Pictures western produced by John Wayne in 1946 is a genuinely wonderful film in many ways. As a hilarious fish-out-of-water comedy with surprising romance and outlaw danger, it allows Wayne to develop a masculine character of such admirable qualities via the steadfast Quaker rule that dominates the storyline. Wayne plays gunslinger Quirt who might as well be SHANE a few years later or Gary Cooper in FRIENDLY PERSUASION in 1956. Parts even remind me of WITNESS. Gorgeous Gail Russell is so beautiful I easily understand the cult following she developed even after she died so sadly around 1960. ANGEL AND THE BADMAN is a strong and friendly film with very funny scenes and some great western settings lifted by breathtaking photography. The conflict and the innocence work well together, and Wayne and Russell are believable as opposite who attract. It is a very well designed and decorated film with excellent production values. I would be keen now to see THE WAKE OF THE RED WITCH. We are having a John Wayne festival on TV in Australia this January and ANGEL screened on a Saturday night at 8.30pm for us all to enjoy. I certainly did.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    substandard John Wayne western
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    disdressed12
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/3/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    this western is more of a character study than anything else,and a romance.there isn't a lot of action.it's not the worst movie i have seen,but i do felt it went on too long.i felt it was too tedious.there were several times when i thought it was over,and could/should have been over,but it kept going.i think they could have told just as good a story if they had shortened the film.it's definitely not one of my favourite westerns,nor one my favourite John Wayne westerns.it's certainly no classic,in my opinion.i know many people would disagree with that sentiment,which is fine.i wouldn't likely watch it again,at least for a long time.for me,Angel and the Badman is a 4/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
 </reviews>
</filme>
