<filme>
 <id>
  1470
 </id>
 <imdburl>
  http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0113234
 </imdburl>
 <ano>
  1995
 </ano>
 <titulo>
  Gumby 1
 </titulo>
 <rating>
  5.8
 </rating>
 <sinopse>
  In this offshoot of the 1950s "claymation" cartoon series, the crazy Blockheads threaten to ruin Gumby's benefit concert by replacing the entire city of Clokeytown with robots.
 </sinopse>
 <storyline>
  In this offshoot of the 1950s "claymation" cartoon series, the crazy Blockheads threaten to ruin Gumby's benefit concert by replacing the entire city of Clokeytown with robots.
 </storyline>
 <generos>
  <genero>
   Animation
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Action
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Adventure
  </genero>
 </generos>
 <keywords>
  <keyword>
   1950s
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   claymation
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   dog
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   clone
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   singer
  </keyword>
 </keywords>
 <diretores>
  <diretor>
   Art Clokey
  </diretor>
 </diretores>
 <escritores>
  <escritor>
   Art Clokey
  </escritor>
  <escritor>
   Gloria Clokey
  </escritor>
 </escritores>
 <atores>
  <ator>
   Dal McKennon
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Art Clokey
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Gloria Clokey
  </ator>
 </atores>
 <reviews>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Ultimate Gumby Experience
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    moviefanman76-blogspot-com
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/12/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    As a kid, I always enjoyed how creative Gumby had his adventures on the TV show. So much of it was just for pure fun. When I finally heard that there had been a movie released, I was super excited. And none to my surprise, Gumby: The Movie rocked my world. For any Gumby fan, this movie will be a great hit. Everything in this movie is kept the same and even includes some cultural references. Director Art Clokey, who directs his final Gumby film, has done a magnificent job. Dal McKennon is back as good old Gumby and several other characters. Even Art Clokey is Prickle and some other roles. All the animation is done by clay; how else would a Gumby film be done?! Most of the comedic parts are watching the silent Blockheads fight with each other. They're always doing something foolish. The effects are great in this movie. Since stop motion cinematography allows you to make a special effect over time, much of the creations that are made are really quite stunning. This movie BARELY uses CGI for any part of the film. It's things like these that bring the viewer back to the time where CGI wasn't used very often and was only used if it was available. Now almost if not every movie studio uses CGI for anything they want and its gets tiresome to see the same effects used over and over again. Claymation is a sorely missed special effect that is now extinct in the movie making business at least from what I see now. The music, which was composed by Jerry Gerber, is great listening to. Because this movie uses dated effects, it's great to hear music that belongs from the same era. Unfortunately, the soundtrack to this film is inaccessible. I get flustered over that but it's still good that it used in the movie thank heaven. What's also great to see are the cultural references in this film. The Blockheads make robot duplicates of the main characters; sounds a little like The Terminator (1984). Another scene where Gumby fights his robotic clone with a light saber. Need to say more? As the last film made by Art Clokey, Gumby: The Movie will please its fans and may gain interest in others who are not familiar with Gumby. For anyone who has never seen claymation at its best, this is it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Love it!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    C S
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/5/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Gumby in a movie. I have loved this movie since I was a kid. If you like Gumby, you will surely appreciate this. All the gang is there, and they have their real voices. They live on the farm, and have a band with Gumby and his (new) friends ??buckle, Thin-buckle, and No-buckle. Gumby spends all his time rehearsing and it makes Pokey feel left out. :( Nobody messes with my favorite character!!! Then Low-belly, the favored pet dachshund, cries something strange that Goo notices. Professor Caph does a test on the Low-belly tear, and it turns out to be a pearl! (I know it sounds silly but the movie is really cute and I mean, come on, this is talking clay, we already have some sense of suspension of disbelief!) Anyway, there's also some hint of love interest, as we meet Tara and her friend. (kind of like groupies) Then there's the sinister Blockheads who always have to cause trouble. They are a part of the antagonist, and there are other issues the group has to get through which are quite entertaining, like Gumby robots! I will say the BEST part about this movie is the awesome 90's music, (one song is Still in my head and I love it!) "Oh, Gumby oh, you do something to my chemistry! You're Green, you're clay, you're a cosmic display!" It is a great song! AND my favorite part is when they spoof movies like Star Wars, King Arthur, and even some of the previous Gumby episodes! It is a must-see for Stop-motion fans!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Gumby in a rock band
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Electrified_Voltage
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/10/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    When I was around ten years old, I watched some episodes of "The Gumby Show" on video. Since I liked what I saw, I then watched this full-length feature, which came nearly four decades after the birth of the stop-motion character's original TV show. "Gumby: The Movie" was not a disappointment for me, and the first time I watched it during my childhood wasn't my last. I have watched it again three times, I think all within the past year, and thought it was pretty good the first couple times, but it went slightly downhill for me with my latest viewing. While I watched "Gumby: The Movie" last night, I wasn't quite as impressed. In this movie, Gumby is a member of a rock band called the Clayboys. The band has a studio on a farm, where they rehearse. As the band are on their way to their studio, along with Gumby's friends (Pokey, Goo, and Prickle), they learn that farmers are about to lose their homes, due to the fact that they cannot pay their debts. The Clayboys decide to hold a benefit concert for these troubled farmers. Unfortunately, the evil Blockheads, the ones who delivered the letters to the farmers, informing them of the bad news, are at the concert. When these two notice Gumby's dog, Lowbelly, crying pearls, they begin to record the music. After the show, the Blockheads kidnap Lowbelly, so they can play the recording they have of the Clayboys' music, and have him cry more pearls so they can get rich! However, they discover that Lowbelly will only cry pearls when he hears the music live, so the two villains now intend to kidnap the band members as well! "Gumby: The Movie" may have more for kids than for adults, but it's not strictly for kids. During previous recent viewings, I certainly wasn't blown away, but thought it reasonably entertaining, with some mild excitement, an occasional funny scene (such as the clumsy robot waiter in the caf&eacute;), and some interesting places the characters find themselves in when they enter books. When I last watched the film, I was entertained by these things for a while, but eventually, I found that it got tiring. I also found that some of the voice-overs are poor, although most of them are alright. I don't know, maybe I have now seen it too many times. However, since I liked the film more during previous viewings, and enjoyed a bit of it this time, I have to give it credit, and do recommend it for stop-motion fans of all ages. You just might not want to expect a masterpiece.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Hot 90's Rock Soundtrack??!!!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    hootadbinky
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/2/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The music. Did anyone notice the music? Like ZZTop amped-up with Eddie Van Halen and a little Randy Rhodes thrown in for good measure? The song when Gumby's band is playing al fresco has absolutely killer guitar, and I'm trying to track down the guitarist now. Would anyone have or info. or help me in my quest? I'm a guitarist myself and I'll be transcribing all the electric guitar from this movie. Haven't the faintest what the plot is about, but my 3-year old son enjoyed it, and we love G+P anyway. I have ancient memories of it so I bought a couple DVDs for me and my son; we enjoy it. But by God who is playing guitar? Also the song "Take Me Away" is in a classic power-rock romantic-anthem mode, and sung by the perfect female voice. The bridge is boring but everything else in the song is top-notch. I found the producer's name, David Ozzie Ahlers, and he's associated with Jerry Garcia, but that's as far as I could get. I'm lousy at this kind of research. Could anyone help? And yes, I'm going to buy the DVD!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    For Gumby Fans
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    R Becker
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/2/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Those who grew up with Gumby, like me, will find this a welcome step back into the boundless imagination of Art Clokey and his crew. Anybody else may find their mileage varies, unfortunately, because there really *isn't* anybody quite like Art Clokey. It's not mile-a-minute in its pacing, it's not laugh-a-minute in its comedy, it's not trying to be anything but More Gumby. So if you want more Gumby, this is it! Clokey brings back all your favorites -- Gumby, Pokey, Prickle, Goo, the Blockheads, and even some surprises -- and adds a few new characters on top of that. Nobody should miss the utterly psychedelic claymation of the last few minutes of the film, because it really is beautifully done. If you expect Aardman Animation or something modern, you should adjust my rating down a few points -- this probably isn't for you. But if you remember Gumby and would like just another short while with him and his friends, here's your chance.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not bad, when taken for what it is.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mjj237 (mjj237@nyu.edu)
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/6/2005
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Folks, I'll be straight with you. This is not the greatest film ever made. In fact, it's not the best Gumby film ever made (although it's the best--read: only--full-length Gumby film ever made). I attribute this largely to the fact that Gumby and his secondary characters are intended to be digested in five-minute doses. An hour and a half with them is a little bit like a phone call from an old friend you haven't talked to in years, who stays on the phone long after you remember how much better you liked them when they hadn't been chewing your ear off for hours. In other words, as you watch the movie (if you're over the age of 8 at least), you're glad to see Gumby is doing well--he's got a new band, some new friends, even some groupies. And in fact, if you liked Gumby in normal-size episodes as a kid, you almost feel validated somehow because the slightly weird character you liked finally got his own movie. But as the clock ticks forward, you begin to wonder why there needed to be a Gumby cartoon of this length. In fact, you realize, even if you'd really wanted an hour-and-a-half-long Gumby fix, you'd rather have watched 15 or so regular Gumby shorts. But I must admit, once a Gumby fan, always a shameless Gumby fan. It has its moments, and if you like the little green guy with the pointy head, you'll get a kick out of it. But let me put it this way: I've owned the VHS of it since about 1997 and have watched it twice in the past eight years. It's not a movie you'll be watching again and again if you buy it, no matter how much you like Gumby. That said, a word about the two new characters: I can accept a guy named Gumby. I can accept, even, that his dad's name is Gumbo. I can accept a horse named Pokey, a girl named Goo, a kid sister named Minga, and even a dinosaur named Prickle. Not to mention a red teardrop with a face that has limbs coming directly out of said face, and the fact that said teardrop is a professor of some kind. I can even accept the fact that everyone in the world looks normal, except for Gumby and his pals, who are highly stylized blocks of primary colors. But I draw the line at two guys named Claybert and Fatbuckle. What kind of names are those?
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I watched this a long time ago.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Dandamanya
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/12/2003
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I watched this movie a long time ago, and have to say it was pretty good. I remembered a lot of the characters dying. I can barely remember the film. I couldn't even remember the name for awhile. Most of what I remember was a yellow guy, a dinosaur, a sword fight, the dog that cried pearls, the blockheads, gumby, the clones, and the part where they get stuck together. I would have thought more people would vote for this movie than around 50. 9/10.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    This is one of my daughter's favorite movies
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ragweedfarmer
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/8/2003
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The movie has numerous detailed, but unsophisticated sets that Gumby and his friends enter by going into books. My daughter has loved this movie since she was two, and still watches it now even at seven. I would highly recommend it to anyone with small children.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    My Complains / Comments
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    CaptinCanuck
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/11/2002
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie is the most genious thing I've ever seen. My majors are philiosphy and english, and this is the most intelligent piece of film I've ever had the pleasure of watching. First, it has many layers. Layers upon layer upon layer. It starts as a comment on the American Dream, and slowly creeps into the downfall of Western Civilization as we know it. I was glued to my 52" Plasma tv, I wanted to see up a contraption like in "A Clockwork Orange" so I wouldn't have to blink, in fear of I'd miss a second. When this movie was over, I watched it again the next afternoon. This took the next 3 days of classes off just to let it sink in. I was truly amazed. It made me question the Government, my life, my family, my religion, and everything I held dear and belived it. It was a life changing experience. If you don't watch "Gumby : The Movie" you'll be chating yourself. See it ... see it now
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Gumby 1!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    (robocoptng986127@aol.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/7/2002
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    [CONTAINS SPOILERS] Everybody remembers Gumby from the 1950's kids show. He and his pal Pokey would play with toys and get into all sorts of trouble. But now, they've got their very own movie! Nobody ever imagined the day would come, but by George, it did! After popping out of Art Clokey's satellite dish, Gumby and Pokey sail towards earth. Pokey runs into the Clayboys who play in a band with Gumby and were driving his bulky old car. Pokey was feeling left out, now that Gumby had a new band. Upon his search for Gumby, Pokey ran into Prickle and Goo, or rather, they ran into him after trying out a slide. They were taken to the hospital and were freed. Funny, in an episode of the old Gumby show, "The Gumby League", Pokey, Goo and Professor Kapp all ran into each other and blended together like in the movie, but they didn't need any fancy equipment to separate them. Oh well, this is a movie, might as well stretch the budget high as possible. They soon run into Gumby and the Clayboys. The farmers in the neighborhood were becoming foreclosed. The bankers, The Blockheads, were up to no good. So Gumby decides to throw a benefit concert and Pokey would help. The Clayboys' dog, Lowbelly, would cry pearls when the band played. The Blockheads noticed this and brought him to their computer lab. This could mean big money! They proceed to capture the Clayboys and make robot clones of them. Meanwhile, Gumby receives a gig from an agent, Mr. Claybert (W.C. Fields and Groucho Marx rolled into one) but just then, he's captured. A robot clone of him goes to the farm where Prickle, Goo and Pokey discover Lowbelly is also a robot clone and try to go warn Gumby, but the car won't start! (Why is it that every car Gumby ever owned was a piece of junk?) The friends out smart the robot and free the real Gumby, who battles the clone in Camelot, outer space and in the toy store. Soon the evil is defeated, the Blockheads are foiled again and Gumby and his boys play the ultimate concert on TV. Was this a good movie? Yes, I suppose so. I always wondered what a Gumby movie would be like. It's based on the late '80s Gumby TV show, where Gumby lived on a farm and played in a band. So, if you're a fan of the '50s show or the '80s show, then I recommend Gumby 1. Why is it called that? Did they plan on Gumby 2 or what? -
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Ultimate Gumby Experience
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    moviefanman76-blogspot-com
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/12/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    As a kid, I always enjoyed how creative Gumby had his adventures on the TV show. So much of it was just for pure fun. When I finally heard that there had been a movie released, I was super excited. And none to my surprise, Gumby: The Movie rocked my world. For any Gumby fan, this movie will be a great hit. Everything in this movie is kept the same and even includes some cultural references. Director Art Clokey, who directs his final Gumby film, has done a magnificent job. Dal McKennon is back as good old Gumby and several other characters. Even Art Clokey is Prickle and some other roles. All the animation is done by clay; how else would a Gumby film be done?! Most of the comedic parts are watching the silent Blockheads fight with each other. They're always doing something foolish. The effects are great in this movie. Since stop motion cinematography allows you to make a special effect over time, much of the creations that are made are really quite stunning. This movie BARELY uses CGI for any part of the film. It's things like these that bring the viewer back to the time where CGI wasn't used very often and was only used if it was available. Now almost if not every movie studio uses CGI for anything they want and its gets tiresome to see the same effects used over and over again. Claymation is a sorely missed special effect that is now extinct in the movie making business at least from what I see now. The music, which was composed by Jerry Gerber, is great listening to. Because this movie uses dated effects, it's great to hear music that belongs from the same era. Unfortunately, the soundtrack to this film is inaccessible. I get flustered over that but it's still good that it used in the movie thank heaven. What's also great to see are the cultural references in this film. The Blockheads make robot duplicates of the main characters; sounds a little like The Terminator (1984). Another scene where Gumby fights his robotic clone with a light saber. Need to say more? As the last film made by Art Clokey, Gumby: The Movie will please its fans and may gain interest in others who are not familiar with Gumby. For anyone who has never seen claymation at its best, this is it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Love it!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    C S
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/5/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Gumby in a movie. I have loved this movie since I was a kid. If you like Gumby, you will surely appreciate this. All the gang is there, and they have their real voices. They live on the farm, and have a band with Gumby and his (new) friends ??buckle, Thin-buckle, and No-buckle. Gumby spends all his time rehearsing and it makes Pokey feel left out. :( Nobody messes with my favorite character!!! Then Low-belly, the favored pet dachshund, cries something strange that Goo notices. Professor Caph does a test on the Low-belly tear, and it turns out to be a pearl! (I know it sounds silly but the movie is really cute and I mean, come on, this is talking clay, we already have some sense of suspension of disbelief!) Anyway, there's also some hint of love interest, as we meet Tara and her friend. (kind of like groupies) Then there's the sinister Blockheads who always have to cause trouble. They are a part of the antagonist, and there are other issues the group has to get through which are quite entertaining, like Gumby robots! I will say the BEST part about this movie is the awesome 90's music, (one song is Still in my head and I love it!) "Oh, Gumby oh, you do something to my chemistry! You're Green, you're clay, you're a cosmic display!" It is a great song! AND my favorite part is when they spoof movies like Star Wars, King Arthur, and even some of the previous Gumby episodes! It is a must-see for Stop-motion fans!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Gumby in a rock band
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Electrified_Voltage
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/10/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    When I was around ten years old, I watched some episodes of "The Gumby Show" on video. Since I liked what I saw, I then watched this full-length feature, which came nearly four decades after the birth of the stop-motion character's original TV show. "Gumby: The Movie" was not a disappointment for me, and the first time I watched it during my childhood wasn't my last. I have watched it again three times, I think all within the past year, and thought it was pretty good the first couple times, but it went slightly downhill for me with my latest viewing. While I watched "Gumby: The Movie" last night, I wasn't quite as impressed. In this movie, Gumby is a member of a rock band called the Clayboys. The band has a studio on a farm, where they rehearse. As the band are on their way to their studio, along with Gumby's friends (Pokey, Goo, and Prickle), they learn that farmers are about to lose their homes, due to the fact that they cannot pay their debts. The Clayboys decide to hold a benefit concert for these troubled farmers. Unfortunately, the evil Blockheads, the ones who delivered the letters to the farmers, informing them of the bad news, are at the concert. When these two notice Gumby's dog, Lowbelly, crying pearls, they begin to record the music. After the show, the Blockheads kidnap Lowbelly, so they can play the recording they have of the Clayboys' music, and have him cry more pearls so they can get rich! However, they discover that Lowbelly will only cry pearls when he hears the music live, so the two villains now intend to kidnap the band members as well! "Gumby: The Movie" may have more for kids than for adults, but it's not strictly for kids. During previous recent viewings, I certainly wasn't blown away, but thought it reasonably entertaining, with some mild excitement, an occasional funny scene (such as the clumsy robot waiter in the caf&eacute;), and some interesting places the characters find themselves in when they enter books. When I last watched the film, I was entertained by these things for a while, but eventually, I found that it got tiring. I also found that some of the voice-overs are poor, although most of them are alright. I don't know, maybe I have now seen it too many times. However, since I liked the film more during previous viewings, and enjoyed a bit of it this time, I have to give it credit, and do recommend it for stop-motion fans of all ages. You just might not want to expect a masterpiece.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Hot 90's Rock Soundtrack??!!!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    hootadbinky
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/2/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The music. Did anyone notice the music? Like ZZTop amped-up with Eddie Van Halen and a little Randy Rhodes thrown in for good measure? The song when Gumby's band is playing al fresco has absolutely killer guitar, and I'm trying to track down the guitarist now. Would anyone have or info. or help me in my quest? I'm a guitarist myself and I'll be transcribing all the electric guitar from this movie. Haven't the faintest what the plot is about, but my 3-year old son enjoyed it, and we love G+P anyway. I have ancient memories of it so I bought a couple DVDs for me and my son; we enjoy it. But by God who is playing guitar? Also the song "Take Me Away" is in a classic power-rock romantic-anthem mode, and sung by the perfect female voice. The bridge is boring but everything else in the song is top-notch. I found the producer's name, David Ozzie Ahlers, and he's associated with Jerry Garcia, but that's as far as I could get. I'm lousy at this kind of research. Could anyone help? And yes, I'm going to buy the DVD!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    For Gumby Fans
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    R Becker
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/2/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Those who grew up with Gumby, like me, will find this a welcome step back into the boundless imagination of Art Clokey and his crew. Anybody else may find their mileage varies, unfortunately, because there really *isn't* anybody quite like Art Clokey. It's not mile-a-minute in its pacing, it's not laugh-a-minute in its comedy, it's not trying to be anything but More Gumby. So if you want more Gumby, this is it! Clokey brings back all your favorites -- Gumby, Pokey, Prickle, Goo, the Blockheads, and even some surprises -- and adds a few new characters on top of that. Nobody should miss the utterly psychedelic claymation of the last few minutes of the film, because it really is beautifully done. If you expect Aardman Animation or something modern, you should adjust my rating down a few points -- this probably isn't for you. But if you remember Gumby and would like just another short while with him and his friends, here's your chance.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not bad, when taken for what it is.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mjj237 (mjj237@nyu.edu)
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/6/2005
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Folks, I'll be straight with you. This is not the greatest film ever made. In fact, it's not the best Gumby film ever made (although it's the best--read: only--full-length Gumby film ever made). I attribute this largely to the fact that Gumby and his secondary characters are intended to be digested in five-minute doses. An hour and a half with them is a little bit like a phone call from an old friend you haven't talked to in years, who stays on the phone long after you remember how much better you liked them when they hadn't been chewing your ear off for hours. In other words, as you watch the movie (if you're over the age of 8 at least), you're glad to see Gumby is doing well--he's got a new band, some new friends, even some groupies. And in fact, if you liked Gumby in normal-size episodes as a kid, you almost feel validated somehow because the slightly weird character you liked finally got his own movie. But as the clock ticks forward, you begin to wonder why there needed to be a Gumby cartoon of this length. In fact, you realize, even if you'd really wanted an hour-and-a-half-long Gumby fix, you'd rather have watched 15 or so regular Gumby shorts. But I must admit, once a Gumby fan, always a shameless Gumby fan. It has its moments, and if you like the little green guy with the pointy head, you'll get a kick out of it. But let me put it this way: I've owned the VHS of it since about 1997 and have watched it twice in the past eight years. It's not a movie you'll be watching again and again if you buy it, no matter how much you like Gumby. That said, a word about the two new characters: I can accept a guy named Gumby. I can accept, even, that his dad's name is Gumbo. I can accept a horse named Pokey, a girl named Goo, a kid sister named Minga, and even a dinosaur named Prickle. Not to mention a red teardrop with a face that has limbs coming directly out of said face, and the fact that said teardrop is a professor of some kind. I can even accept the fact that everyone in the world looks normal, except for Gumby and his pals, who are highly stylized blocks of primary colors. But I draw the line at two guys named Claybert and Fatbuckle. What kind of names are those?
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I watched this a long time ago.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Dandamanya
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/12/2003
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I watched this movie a long time ago, and have to say it was pretty good. I remembered a lot of the characters dying. I can barely remember the film. I couldn't even remember the name for awhile. Most of what I remember was a yellow guy, a dinosaur, a sword fight, the dog that cried pearls, the blockheads, gumby, the clones, and the part where they get stuck together. I would have thought more people would vote for this movie than around 50. 9/10.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    This is one of my daughter's favorite movies
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ragweedfarmer
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/8/2003
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The movie has numerous detailed, but unsophisticated sets that Gumby and his friends enter by going into books. My daughter has loved this movie since she was two, and still watches it now even at seven. I would highly recommend it to anyone with small children.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    My Complains / Comments
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    CaptinCanuck
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/11/2002
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie is the most genious thing I've ever seen. My majors are philiosphy and english, and this is the most intelligent piece of film I've ever had the pleasure of watching. First, it has many layers. Layers upon layer upon layer. It starts as a comment on the American Dream, and slowly creeps into the downfall of Western Civilization as we know it. I was glued to my 52" Plasma tv, I wanted to see up a contraption like in "A Clockwork Orange" so I wouldn't have to blink, in fear of I'd miss a second. When this movie was over, I watched it again the next afternoon. This took the next 3 days of classes off just to let it sink in. I was truly amazed. It made me question the Government, my life, my family, my religion, and everything I held dear and belived it. It was a life changing experience. If you don't watch "Gumby : The Movie" you'll be chating yourself. See it ... see it now
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Gumby 1!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    (robocoptng986127@aol.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/7/2002
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    [CONTAINS SPOILERS] Everybody remembers Gumby from the 1950's kids show. He and his pal Pokey would play with toys and get into all sorts of trouble. But now, they've got their very own movie! Nobody ever imagined the day would come, but by George, it did! After popping out of Art Clokey's satellite dish, Gumby and Pokey sail towards earth. Pokey runs into the Clayboys who play in a band with Gumby and were driving his bulky old car. Pokey was feeling left out, now that Gumby had a new band. Upon his search for Gumby, Pokey ran into Prickle and Goo, or rather, they ran into him after trying out a slide. They were taken to the hospital and were freed. Funny, in an episode of the old Gumby show, "The Gumby League", Pokey, Goo and Professor Kapp all ran into each other and blended together like in the movie, but they didn't need any fancy equipment to separate them. Oh well, this is a movie, might as well stretch the budget high as possible. They soon run into Gumby and the Clayboys. The farmers in the neighborhood were becoming foreclosed. The bankers, The Blockheads, were up to no good. So Gumby decides to throw a benefit concert and Pokey would help. The Clayboys' dog, Lowbelly, would cry pearls when the band played. The Blockheads noticed this and brought him to their computer lab. This could mean big money! They proceed to capture the Clayboys and make robot clones of them. Meanwhile, Gumby receives a gig from an agent, Mr. Claybert (W.C. Fields and Groucho Marx rolled into one) but just then, he's captured. A robot clone of him goes to the farm where Prickle, Goo and Pokey discover Lowbelly is also a robot clone and try to go warn Gumby, but the car won't start! (Why is it that every car Gumby ever owned was a piece of junk?) The friends out smart the robot and free the real Gumby, who battles the clone in Camelot, outer space and in the toy store. Soon the evil is defeated, the Blockheads are foiled again and Gumby and his boys play the ultimate concert on TV. Was this a good movie? Yes, I suppose so. I always wondered what a Gumby movie would be like. It's based on the late '80s Gumby TV show, where Gumby lived on a farm and played in a band. So, if you're a fan of the '50s show or the '80s show, then I recommend Gumby 1. Why is it called that? Did they plan on Gumby 2 or what? -
   </conteudo>
  </review>
 </reviews>
</filme>
