<filme>
 <id>
  148
 </id>
 <imdburl>
  http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0116409
 </imdburl>
 <ano>
  1996
 </ano>
 <titulo>
  A Sombra e a Escurid&atilde;o
 </titulo>
 <rating>
  6.7
 </rating>
 <sinopse>
  Set in 1898, this movie is based on the true story of two lions in Africa that killed 35 people over a nine month period, while a bridge engineer and an experienced old hunter tried to kill... &nbsp;&raquo;
 </sinopse>
 <storyline>
  Set in 1898, this movie is based on the true story of two lions in Africa that killed 35 people over a nine month period, while a bridge engineer and an experienced old hunter tried to kill them.
 </storyline>
 <generos>
  <genero>
   Action
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Adventure
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Drama
  </genero>
 </generos>
 <keywords>
  <keyword>
   lion
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   bridge
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   hunter
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   engineer
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   railway
  </keyword>
 </keywords>
 <diretores>
  <diretor>
   Stephen Hopkins
  </diretor>
 </diretores>
 <escritores>
  <escritor>
   William Goldman
  </escritor>
 </escritores>
 <atores>
  <ator>
   Michael Douglas
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Val Kilmer
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Tom Wilkinson
  </ator>
 </atores>
 <reviews>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Jaws in Africa
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Roland Jakobsson (rolandddd)
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The story of how two man-eating lions delayed the construction of a railway bridge in Tsavo, Kenya in 1898, is one that fascinates me. The film is loosely based on the biographical account of Lt Col John Henry Patterson, played by Val Kilmer in the movie. Though the original story is decently written and very exciting to read, it is also clearly a work of its time, and some of the more racist undertones of the original short story has wisely been omitted from the film. Halfway through the story something very strange happens. Being at least reasonably true to Patterson's account until then, the movie transforms into a carbon copy of Jaws! Suddenly throwing aside Patterson's story and all ties to reality, fictitious character Remington is introduced, horribly portrayed by Michael Douglas. This legendary huntsman is clearly the equivalent of Jaws's Quint, but unfortunately Douglas OTT-acting doesn't even come close to matching Robert Shaw's performance. Despite the movie's obvious ambition to be a Jaws set in Africa (even down to the POV shots of the lions stalking their prey), I think lots of things work well. The ambition to emulate Jaws is at least partly successful, and the movie has some great suspenseful scenes. The extensive use of real lions Caesar and Bongo and very little animatronics means that the predator scenes look great, and I think the film benefits from being made in the mid-nineties with basically no CGI. The scenery (South Africa substituting for Kenya) looks stunning and the film is wonderfully shot, and together with the realistic animal this makes the movie look really good. The acting, apart from Douglas, is also solid with Kilmer being backed up by a strong supporting cast of Tom Wilkinson, Bernard Hill and Emily Mortimer to name a few. Overall, I have a soft spot for "monster" movies and even though this has many flaws I think it is really entertaining and well worth watching!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    This movie was terrible.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Tekki Kiraito
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I was forced to watch this piece of garbage in English class and I did not find anything about it enjoyable. It is heavy on the violence and gore which I do not think is acceptable for a high school English course. I do not appreciate being forced to watch something that greatly disturbs me for a course that is mandatory. This movie was filled with lots of historical inaccuracies. Some of the people in this film, such as Remington, didn't even exist! The film just felt like a cheap slasher trying to be something it's not. If you are truly interested in this event, I recommend reading Patterson's book. In short, skip this piece of garbage. It's not worth your time.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "Lion" in Wait
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    flowersflix
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Here I am again, reviewing yet another "man vs. nature" movie. This time, we've got two seemingly demon possessed lions murdering railroad workers in turn of the century Uganda. Our hero is John Patterson (Val Kilmer), a contractor hired by a wealthy (and ruthless) tycoon to oversee construction of a bridge that will bolster commerce in the region. When the murderous lions in question begin terrorizingand maimingJohn's workers, something's got to be done (especially when they all flee at the suspicion that he's brought about a curse on the area). Cue the entrance of Charles Remington (Michael Douglas), a world- renowned hunter who's the embodiment of the old-school, no-holds-barred, shotgun-toting, Hemingway-esque man's man. Director Stephen Hopkins decides the go the route of Jaws, as it's rare that we're given a clean, full frame shot of the "monsters." This turns out to be a great decision, as it adds to the suspense when we see a silhouette (or think we see one) moving stealthily among the rippling, waist high savanna. In that regard, there's no denying that The Ghost and the Darkness delivers the goods in the "suspense" department. Unfortunately, the film does have its problems. First and foremost is the entirely too abrupt conclusion, which, quite honestly, feels sloppy and rushed. After all we've been through with Patterson and Remington, one would expect a grand finale that heightens the tension to unbearable levels. Instead we get something like a watered down version of the velociraptor kitchen scene in Jurassic Park. There's also the lack of satisfaction that could have been delivered if the one person we truly despise in the story got what he had coming to him. Spontenaity is a good thing, but all I could think about as the final act unfolded was how badly I hoped that the greedy businessman would finally come in contact with a beast infinitely more malicious than himself. Then there's the music, which alternates between stirring and grating. Particularly annoying is the decision to work some sort of elephant/hyena noise into what would be an otherwise memorable score. If it weren't for the final half hour and the previously mentioned sub- par musical renderings, it'd be safe to call The Ghost and the Darkness an underrated thriller. Instead it fizzles into a flabby shadow of its former self, much like a long coveted balloon that's held on until there's simply nothing left.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Some Lions, Coward Villagers and a Brave Boy!!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Ankit Dubey
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This title suits the movie well. A predictive and very childish kind of storyline, somewhat like bedtime stories to make children brave, which could have been done by a short 5 minutes story. Directed by Stephen Hopkins and Written By William Godman, this film is all about a character John Patterson an engineer, a bridge builder to be specific, who is the protagonist of the story, who takes a challenge of building a bridge in Africa, very confidently and with his wife pregnant and delivering a baby in six months. The job was assigned by a very rude and demotivating boss. The story moves around building of the bridge and some man-eater lions which created fear in the mind of people working there. And at the end of the movie, as one can predict, the hero killed the lions and thank god, the movie was over!! Despite a bad story, the direction is good. The background music is so real, that it creates such a superb horror effect in the mind of people that even if the movie was over you will feel the lions coming after you!! All the characters acted well, especially the hero. The best part of the movie which i liked the most was; cultural relations have been very beautiful shown in this movie, i.e. how to live and co-operate with people who are not like you. So the final verdict of the movie goes as, it's better to watch 'Man verses wild' on National Geographical than to waste time as well money in cinema hall.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Man-Eaters Of Tsavo
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bruce-wayne074
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie is a based on a true story about the man-eaters of Tsavo i like this movie very much i think story line was great and i think Val Kilmer and Michael Douglas did a great job its a great and 100 percent recommended if u haven't seen it yet go check it out guys its really one the best and have place on the list of my top 50 movies its really great some scenes are pretty scary man-eaters attacking the workers and dragged them out of their tents at night although Michael Douglas character was fictional but he did it very well and Val Kilmer the role Colonel John Patterson very its a great movie and i think best movie ever made about the man-eaters of Tsavo
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Awesome Movie, It's Like Jaws with Lions
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Luke Reeves
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/6/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This film is amazing a real gem. The scenery is spectacular, acting superb, great performances by the lions. A real masterpiece! Even better knowing it's a true story. The sound effects were fantastic, you really get a feel for what it must have been like being close to these dangerous monsters. Even the lions were afraid. On surround sound fairly loud, the roar and growls of the lions really makes an emotional impact. If you liked the film Jaws, you will definitely like this film. I was a bit worried about the killing of lions to be sad and depressing, because I really love lions. That's why it has taken me so long to see this film. However these lions really deserved it! They were nasty scary beasts and would make any vegetarian want to go back to eating meat. :D Anyway great film, another must see before you die type movie.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Safari Thriller with Big Cats
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    zardoz-13
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/5/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Director Stephen Hopkins' safari saga "The Ghost and the Darkness" is based on a true incident. Two bloodthirsty lions feasted on 130 native railroad laborers in Africa in the late 1890s. But it's an adventure tale with more growl than grandeur. Val Kilmer bares a pearly smile in his starring role as idealistic bridge builder Lieutenant Colonel John Patterson. As Patterson, he is assigned by his racist British tycoon boss, Robert Beaumont (Tom Wilkinson) to bridge Africa's Tsavo River within five months. As we learn, the Swahili word for Tsavo translates as "a place of slaughter." When Patterson arrives in Africa, his loyal African guide, Samuel (John Kani), warns him that nothing works in Tsavo. No sooner has work started than the lions strike. Patterson guns down one man-eater, but two more lions replace it. The natives call these savage cats "The Ghost and the Darkness." Michael Douglas co-stars as savvy lion killer Charles Remington. He arrives on the scene to help save the day, but he doesn't make his appearance until nearly halfway into the action. William Goldman's script errs in not bringing Douglas into the fray much earlier. Although confined to a role that is little more than an over-long cameo, Douglas dominates "The Ghost and the Darkness." Douglas' charismatic Remington easily upstages Kilmer's ponderous spit and polish Patterson. Compared to the elegant Patterson, Douglas resembles a shaggy villain from a 1970s era Italian western. Nevertheless, what distinguishes "The Ghost and the Darkness" are its cagey lions. These lions constantly elude and outwit our pair of heroes. If you saw the Robin Williams movie "Jumanji," the special effects here are just as incredible. Director Stephen Hopkins deploys these fantastic digital effects to stage a truly realistic lion attack on a crowd. Many close-up shots of gaping jaws and dark, hypnotic eyes bolster the suspense. An exciting confrontation that sends Kilmer scrambling up a tree with a lion nipping at his heels should get the adrenalin singing in your veins. Altogether, "The Ghost and the Darkness" succeeds more as a horror movie. The action never strays far from the bridge site so the movie seems rather claustrophobic. When "Ghost" isn't frightening, it creeps along with one too many campfire scenes. "Butch Cassidy and the Sundance Kid" scenarist William Goldman literate script sticks closely to the events of this true-life tragedy. Nevertheless, you wonder how they made the mistakes that they made. Patterson, for example, swaps rifles the night before the big hunt. When he confronts a lion, his gun misfires. The death of one character occurs off-screen, forcing you to fill in the gap and deprive both the audience and the characters with a memorable death scene. You can almost guess which character will be chomped because the filmmakers cast a halo around the person's head. Meanwhile, Hopkins and Goldman devise one genuinely shocking scene but cannot sustain this kind of momentum when the lions are on-screen. Hopkins deserves credit for making these lion attacks fully vicious without emphasizing the blood and gore.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A story of two demonic lions
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    david-sarkies
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is one absolutely awesome movie. It is about two man eating lions that plague a construction site of a bridge in Africa. These lions are no ordinary lions, they are vicious man eaters that do not conform to what lions are like. The natives call them demons, and as this is claimed to be a true story, this is biblically possible. But before I go into the theology of this, I wish to look at the movie first. This move is set in Africa at the turn of the century. There is a race with the other European countries, namely Germany, to colonise Africa. A bridge must be built so that the British can move further inland. When Val Kilmer's character first looks at the river he is amazed. He says that the wonder of building bridges is to put land over water. The bridge is also seen as a chain, or a manacle for the river. An unbridged river is an obstacle but a bridge makes this obstacle no more. The bridge tames the land for the river can no longer block the progress of man. But here the land seems to fight back. Right at the beginning, the first lion attacks and is killed with one bullet. Thus Val Kilmer comes out as a hero. Soon after the two lions, the Ghost and the Darkness, come and cause havoc in the campsite. No matter what they do they cannot stop these lions. A great hunter, Remington (Michael Douglas) comes along to help get rid of these lions. He believes them to be simple lions, but when his tribe leaves, he suddenly realises what he is up against. There is a very interesting scene, but to tell you about it would give something away. These lions are considered demons by the natives, and in my mind this is possible. If we look in the Gospels of Matthew, Mark, and Luke, there is the story of the man possessed by the demon legion (he is called legion because he is many). The demon pleads with Christ not to send them back to hell so Christ sends them into a herd of swine. This shows us that demons can manifest themselves in animals as well as in humans. With this in mind, the animal kingdom is not as weak as we make it out to be. These lions were intelligent and would torment their enemies and then turn and indiscriminately kill. If you watch the hospital scene you will note that they kill everybody but do not take anybody away to eat. As Remington says, "they do it for the pleasure of it." Even though they are demons, they are still lions, as the swine were still swine. Just because they were possessed did not mean they were unkillable. The soul cannot be destroyed but the body can. The swine ran into the lake and were drowned, the lions were also vulnerable in the same way. This movie comes out as a horror movie, but it is far more than that. There is not ghosts or demons running about, just two lions. The natives call them evil, and that they are, but the movie is real, or so it claims. This really happened and thus can happen to us. A horror movie comes across as being unreal. We can leave a horror movie at the end and be comforted that it is not real. This was. The only comfort we have is that the lions are dead.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "If you lock eyes with them, you will be afraid."
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Frederick Smith
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Since the film was shot in South Africa, the scenery is exceptional. Like all docudramas, an amount of license was taken. Micheal Douglas' part in the film is fictional, but very well played and adds to the suspense of the movie. Val Kilmer gives a very quiet but determined air to the role and is supported by excellent performances by John Kani, Om Puri, and Henry Cele, all essential character actors who bring the proper balance of ethnicity and culture to the film. Tom Wilkinson plays Robert Beaumont, a man dedicated to advancing his position to the throne ("I care about my Knighthood!"), across the backs of the people he assigns the tasks. He is a self described Monster who can either make or break a career, and has no qualms about either. Overall the film is matter of fact and very ordinary, but what cannot be denied is that this happened. I have been to the Field Museum and seen the Lions of Tsavo. It is as the last line of the movie says. "If you lock eyes with them, you will be afraid." Lots of gory scenes make this unsuitable for the children, but most teens have seen worse on their video games. Not necessarily collectible, but certainly worth a viewing, especially if you enjoy Kilmer and Douglas.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Could have been great if... (possible spoilers)
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ADG999
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/12/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    ...This incredible true story could have been much, much better than it was, but choppy editing, inconsistent direction, less-than-great cinematography,and the questionable plot decision to add a fictional American big game hunter to "help" Patterson hunt the lions, made this movie less than it could have been. The fact is that, in real life, Patterson (SPOILER) killed both lions himself, and frankly I think it would have been a better movie if they had written the script to reflect that. The Remington character always seemed somewhat out of place to me, and when I realized he was just a device added by the writers, for reasons that I still can't fathom, I understood why. Maybe they were afraid Val Kilmer could not carry the movie on his own--frankly, I think he could have with no problem. Maybe it was because Michael Douglas was an executive producer on the film, and wanted to be in the movie. Whatever the reason, this movie goes on my list of "missed opportunities" to make a really great film. Eight stars, only because I love the story, and love what the movie could have been.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Jaws in Africa
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Roland Jakobsson (rolandddd)
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The story of how two man-eating lions delayed the construction of a railway bridge in Tsavo, Kenya in 1898, is one that fascinates me. The film is loosely based on the biographical account of Lt Col John Henry Patterson, played by Val Kilmer in the movie. Though the original story is decently written and very exciting to read, it is also clearly a work of its time, and some of the more racist undertones of the original short story has wisely been omitted from the film. Halfway through the story something very strange happens. Being at least reasonably true to Patterson's account until then, the movie transforms into a carbon copy of Jaws! Suddenly throwing aside Patterson's story and all ties to reality, fictitious character Remington is introduced, horribly portrayed by Michael Douglas. This legendary huntsman is clearly the equivalent of Jaws's Quint, but unfortunately Douglas OTT-acting doesn't even come close to matching Robert Shaw's performance. Despite the movie's obvious ambition to be a Jaws set in Africa (even down to the POV shots of the lions stalking their prey), I think lots of things work well. The ambition to emulate Jaws is at least partly successful, and the movie has some great suspenseful scenes. The extensive use of real lions Caesar and Bongo and very little animatronics means that the predator scenes look great, and I think the film benefits from being made in the mid-nineties with basically no CGI. The scenery (South Africa substituting for Kenya) looks stunning and the film is wonderfully shot, and together with the realistic animal this makes the movie look really good. The acting, apart from Douglas, is also solid with Kilmer being backed up by a strong supporting cast of Tom Wilkinson, Bernard Hill and Emily Mortimer to name a few. Overall, I have a soft spot for "monster" movies and even though this has many flaws I think it is really entertaining and well worth watching!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    This movie was terrible.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Tekki Kiraito
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I was forced to watch this piece of garbage in English class and I did not find anything about it enjoyable. It is heavy on the violence and gore which I do not think is acceptable for a high school English course. I do not appreciate being forced to watch something that greatly disturbs me for a course that is mandatory. This movie was filled with lots of historical inaccuracies. Some of the people in this film, such as Remington, didn't even exist! The film just felt like a cheap slasher trying to be something it's not. If you are truly interested in this event, I recommend reading Patterson's book. In short, skip this piece of garbage. It's not worth your time.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "Lion" in Wait
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    flowersflix
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Here I am again, reviewing yet another "man vs. nature" movie. This time, we've got two seemingly demon possessed lions murdering railroad workers in turn of the century Uganda. Our hero is John Patterson (Val Kilmer), a contractor hired by a wealthy (and ruthless) tycoon to oversee construction of a bridge that will bolster commerce in the region. When the murderous lions in question begin terrorizingand maimingJohn's workers, something's got to be done (especially when they all flee at the suspicion that he's brought about a curse on the area). Cue the entrance of Charles Remington (Michael Douglas), a world- renowned hunter who's the embodiment of the old-school, no-holds-barred, shotgun-toting, Hemingway-esque man's man. Director Stephen Hopkins decides the go the route of Jaws, as it's rare that we're given a clean, full frame shot of the "monsters." This turns out to be a great decision, as it adds to the suspense when we see a silhouette (or think we see one) moving stealthily among the rippling, waist high savanna. In that regard, there's no denying that The Ghost and the Darkness delivers the goods in the "suspense" department. Unfortunately, the film does have its problems. First and foremost is the entirely too abrupt conclusion, which, quite honestly, feels sloppy and rushed. After all we've been through with Patterson and Remington, one would expect a grand finale that heightens the tension to unbearable levels. Instead we get something like a watered down version of the velociraptor kitchen scene in Jurassic Park. There's also the lack of satisfaction that could have been delivered if the one person we truly despise in the story got what he had coming to him. Spontenaity is a good thing, but all I could think about as the final act unfolded was how badly I hoped that the greedy businessman would finally come in contact with a beast infinitely more malicious than himself. Then there's the music, which alternates between stirring and grating. Particularly annoying is the decision to work some sort of elephant/hyena noise into what would be an otherwise memorable score. If it weren't for the final half hour and the previously mentioned sub- par musical renderings, it'd be safe to call The Ghost and the Darkness an underrated thriller. Instead it fizzles into a flabby shadow of its former self, much like a long coveted balloon that's held on until there's simply nothing left.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Some Lions, Coward Villagers and a Brave Boy!!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Ankit Dubey
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This title suits the movie well. A predictive and very childish kind of storyline, somewhat like bedtime stories to make children brave, which could have been done by a short 5 minutes story. Directed by Stephen Hopkins and Written By William Godman, this film is all about a character John Patterson an engineer, a bridge builder to be specific, who is the protagonist of the story, who takes a challenge of building a bridge in Africa, very confidently and with his wife pregnant and delivering a baby in six months. The job was assigned by a very rude and demotivating boss. The story moves around building of the bridge and some man-eater lions which created fear in the mind of people working there. And at the end of the movie, as one can predict, the hero killed the lions and thank god, the movie was over!! Despite a bad story, the direction is good. The background music is so real, that it creates such a superb horror effect in the mind of people that even if the movie was over you will feel the lions coming after you!! All the characters acted well, especially the hero. The best part of the movie which i liked the most was; cultural relations have been very beautiful shown in this movie, i.e. how to live and co-operate with people who are not like you. So the final verdict of the movie goes as, it's better to watch 'Man verses wild' on National Geographical than to waste time as well money in cinema hall.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Man-Eaters Of Tsavo
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bruce-wayne074
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie is a based on a true story about the man-eaters of Tsavo i like this movie very much i think story line was great and i think Val Kilmer and Michael Douglas did a great job its a great and 100 percent recommended if u haven't seen it yet go check it out guys its really one the best and have place on the list of my top 50 movies its really great some scenes are pretty scary man-eaters attacking the workers and dragged them out of their tents at night although Michael Douglas character was fictional but he did it very well and Val Kilmer the role Colonel John Patterson very its a great movie and i think best movie ever made about the man-eaters of Tsavo
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Awesome Movie, It's Like Jaws with Lions
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Luke Reeves
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/6/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This film is amazing a real gem. The scenery is spectacular, acting superb, great performances by the lions. A real masterpiece! Even better knowing it's a true story. The sound effects were fantastic, you really get a feel for what it must have been like being close to these dangerous monsters. Even the lions were afraid. On surround sound fairly loud, the roar and growls of the lions really makes an emotional impact. If you liked the film Jaws, you will definitely like this film. I was a bit worried about the killing of lions to be sad and depressing, because I really love lions. That's why it has taken me so long to see this film. However these lions really deserved it! They were nasty scary beasts and would make any vegetarian want to go back to eating meat. :D Anyway great film, another must see before you die type movie.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Safari Thriller with Big Cats
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    zardoz-13
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/5/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Director Stephen Hopkins' safari saga "The Ghost and the Darkness" is based on a true incident. Two bloodthirsty lions feasted on 130 native railroad laborers in Africa in the late 1890s. But it's an adventure tale with more growl than grandeur. Val Kilmer bares a pearly smile in his starring role as idealistic bridge builder Lieutenant Colonel John Patterson. As Patterson, he is assigned by his racist British tycoon boss, Robert Beaumont (Tom Wilkinson) to bridge Africa's Tsavo River within five months. As we learn, the Swahili word for Tsavo translates as "a place of slaughter." When Patterson arrives in Africa, his loyal African guide, Samuel (John Kani), warns him that nothing works in Tsavo. No sooner has work started than the lions strike. Patterson guns down one man-eater, but two more lions replace it. The natives call these savage cats "The Ghost and the Darkness." Michael Douglas co-stars as savvy lion killer Charles Remington. He arrives on the scene to help save the day, but he doesn't make his appearance until nearly halfway into the action. William Goldman's script errs in not bringing Douglas into the fray much earlier. Although confined to a role that is little more than an over-long cameo, Douglas dominates "The Ghost and the Darkness." Douglas' charismatic Remington easily upstages Kilmer's ponderous spit and polish Patterson. Compared to the elegant Patterson, Douglas resembles a shaggy villain from a 1970s era Italian western. Nevertheless, what distinguishes "The Ghost and the Darkness" are its cagey lions. These lions constantly elude and outwit our pair of heroes. If you saw the Robin Williams movie "Jumanji," the special effects here are just as incredible. Director Stephen Hopkins deploys these fantastic digital effects to stage a truly realistic lion attack on a crowd. Many close-up shots of gaping jaws and dark, hypnotic eyes bolster the suspense. An exciting confrontation that sends Kilmer scrambling up a tree with a lion nipping at his heels should get the adrenalin singing in your veins. Altogether, "The Ghost and the Darkness" succeeds more as a horror movie. The action never strays far from the bridge site so the movie seems rather claustrophobic. When "Ghost" isn't frightening, it creeps along with one too many campfire scenes. "Butch Cassidy and the Sundance Kid" scenarist William Goldman literate script sticks closely to the events of this true-life tragedy. Nevertheless, you wonder how they made the mistakes that they made. Patterson, for example, swaps rifles the night before the big hunt. When he confronts a lion, his gun misfires. The death of one character occurs off-screen, forcing you to fill in the gap and deprive both the audience and the characters with a memorable death scene. You can almost guess which character will be chomped because the filmmakers cast a halo around the person's head. Meanwhile, Hopkins and Goldman devise one genuinely shocking scene but cannot sustain this kind of momentum when the lions are on-screen. Hopkins deserves credit for making these lion attacks fully vicious without emphasizing the blood and gore.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A story of two demonic lions
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    david-sarkies
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is one absolutely awesome movie. It is about two man eating lions that plague a construction site of a bridge in Africa. These lions are no ordinary lions, they are vicious man eaters that do not conform to what lions are like. The natives call them demons, and as this is claimed to be a true story, this is biblically possible. But before I go into the theology of this, I wish to look at the movie first. This move is set in Africa at the turn of the century. There is a race with the other European countries, namely Germany, to colonise Africa. A bridge must be built so that the British can move further inland. When Val Kilmer's character first looks at the river he is amazed. He says that the wonder of building bridges is to put land over water. The bridge is also seen as a chain, or a manacle for the river. An unbridged river is an obstacle but a bridge makes this obstacle no more. The bridge tames the land for the river can no longer block the progress of man. But here the land seems to fight back. Right at the beginning, the first lion attacks and is killed with one bullet. Thus Val Kilmer comes out as a hero. Soon after the two lions, the Ghost and the Darkness, come and cause havoc in the campsite. No matter what they do they cannot stop these lions. A great hunter, Remington (Michael Douglas) comes along to help get rid of these lions. He believes them to be simple lions, but when his tribe leaves, he suddenly realises what he is up against. There is a very interesting scene, but to tell you about it would give something away. These lions are considered demons by the natives, and in my mind this is possible. If we look in the Gospels of Matthew, Mark, and Luke, there is the story of the man possessed by the demon legion (he is called legion because he is many). The demon pleads with Christ not to send them back to hell so Christ sends them into a herd of swine. This shows us that demons can manifest themselves in animals as well as in humans. With this in mind, the animal kingdom is not as weak as we make it out to be. These lions were intelligent and would torment their enemies and then turn and indiscriminately kill. If you watch the hospital scene you will note that they kill everybody but do not take anybody away to eat. As Remington says, "they do it for the pleasure of it." Even though they are demons, they are still lions, as the swine were still swine. Just because they were possessed did not mean they were unkillable. The soul cannot be destroyed but the body can. The swine ran into the lake and were drowned, the lions were also vulnerable in the same way. This movie comes out as a horror movie, but it is far more than that. There is not ghosts or demons running about, just two lions. The natives call them evil, and that they are, but the movie is real, or so it claims. This really happened and thus can happen to us. A horror movie comes across as being unreal. We can leave a horror movie at the end and be comforted that it is not real. This was. The only comfort we have is that the lions are dead.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "If you lock eyes with them, you will be afraid."
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Frederick Smith
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Since the film was shot in South Africa, the scenery is exceptional. Like all docudramas, an amount of license was taken. Micheal Douglas' part in the film is fictional, but very well played and adds to the suspense of the movie. Val Kilmer gives a very quiet but determined air to the role and is supported by excellent performances by John Kani, Om Puri, and Henry Cele, all essential character actors who bring the proper balance of ethnicity and culture to the film. Tom Wilkinson plays Robert Beaumont, a man dedicated to advancing his position to the throne ("I care about my Knighthood!"), across the backs of the people he assigns the tasks. He is a self described Monster who can either make or break a career, and has no qualms about either. Overall the film is matter of fact and very ordinary, but what cannot be denied is that this happened. I have been to the Field Museum and seen the Lions of Tsavo. It is as the last line of the movie says. "If you lock eyes with them, you will be afraid." Lots of gory scenes make this unsuitable for the children, but most teens have seen worse on their video games. Not necessarily collectible, but certainly worth a viewing, especially if you enjoy Kilmer and Douglas.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Could have been great if... (possible spoilers)
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ADG999
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/12/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    ...This incredible true story could have been much, much better than it was, but choppy editing, inconsistent direction, less-than-great cinematography,and the questionable plot decision to add a fictional American big game hunter to "help" Patterson hunt the lions, made this movie less than it could have been. The fact is that, in real life, Patterson (SPOILER) killed both lions himself, and frankly I think it would have been a better movie if they had written the script to reflect that. The Remington character always seemed somewhat out of place to me, and when I realized he was just a device added by the writers, for reasons that I still can't fathom, I understood why. Maybe they were afraid Val Kilmer could not carry the movie on his own--frankly, I think he could have with no problem. Maybe it was because Michael Douglas was an executive producer on the film, and wanted to be in the movie. Whatever the reason, this movie goes on my list of "missed opportunities" to make a really great film. Eight stars, only because I love the story, and love what the movie could have been.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Jaws in Africa
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Roland Jakobsson (rolandddd)
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The story of how two man-eating lions delayed the construction of a railway bridge in Tsavo, Kenya in 1898, is one that fascinates me. The film is loosely based on the biographical account of Lt Col John Henry Patterson, played by Val Kilmer in the movie. Though the original story is decently written and very exciting to read, it is also clearly a work of its time, and some of the more racist undertones of the original short story has wisely been omitted from the film. Halfway through the story something very strange happens. Being at least reasonably true to Patterson's account until then, the movie transforms into a carbon copy of Jaws! Suddenly throwing aside Patterson's story and all ties to reality, fictitious character Remington is introduced, horribly portrayed by Michael Douglas. This legendary huntsman is clearly the equivalent of Jaws's Quint, but unfortunately Douglas OTT-acting doesn't even come close to matching Robert Shaw's performance. Despite the movie's obvious ambition to be a Jaws set in Africa (even down to the POV shots of the lions stalking their prey), I think lots of things work well. The ambition to emulate Jaws is at least partly successful, and the movie has some great suspenseful scenes. The extensive use of real lions Caesar and Bongo and very little animatronics means that the predator scenes look great, and I think the film benefits from being made in the mid-nineties with basically no CGI. The scenery (South Africa substituting for Kenya) looks stunning and the film is wonderfully shot, and together with the realistic animal this makes the movie look really good. The acting, apart from Douglas, is also solid with Kilmer being backed up by a strong supporting cast of Tom Wilkinson, Bernard Hill and Emily Mortimer to name a few. Overall, I have a soft spot for "monster" movies and even though this has many flaws I think it is really entertaining and well worth watching!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    This movie was terrible.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Tekki Kiraito
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I was forced to watch this piece of garbage in English class and I did not find anything about it enjoyable. It is heavy on the violence and gore which I do not think is acceptable for a high school English course. I do not appreciate being forced to watch something that greatly disturbs me for a course that is mandatory. This movie was filled with lots of historical inaccuracies. Some of the people in this film, such as Remington, didn't even exist! The film just felt like a cheap slasher trying to be something it's not. If you are truly interested in this event, I recommend reading Patterson's book. In short, skip this piece of garbage. It's not worth your time.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "Lion" in Wait
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    flowersflix
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Here I am again, reviewing yet another "man vs. nature" movie. This time, we've got two seemingly demon possessed lions murdering railroad workers in turn of the century Uganda. Our hero is John Patterson (Val Kilmer), a contractor hired by a wealthy (and ruthless) tycoon to oversee construction of a bridge that will bolster commerce in the region. When the murderous lions in question begin terrorizingand maimingJohn's workers, something's got to be done (especially when they all flee at the suspicion that he's brought about a curse on the area). Cue the entrance of Charles Remington (Michael Douglas), a world- renowned hunter who's the embodiment of the old-school, no-holds-barred, shotgun-toting, Hemingway-esque man's man. Director Stephen Hopkins decides the go the route of Jaws, as it's rare that we're given a clean, full frame shot of the "monsters." This turns out to be a great decision, as it adds to the suspense when we see a silhouette (or think we see one) moving stealthily among the rippling, waist high savanna. In that regard, there's no denying that The Ghost and the Darkness delivers the goods in the "suspense" department. Unfortunately, the film does have its problems. First and foremost is the entirely too abrupt conclusion, which, quite honestly, feels sloppy and rushed. After all we've been through with Patterson and Remington, one would expect a grand finale that heightens the tension to unbearable levels. Instead we get something like a watered down version of the velociraptor kitchen scene in Jurassic Park. There's also the lack of satisfaction that could have been delivered if the one person we truly despise in the story got what he had coming to him. Spontenaity is a good thing, but all I could think about as the final act unfolded was how badly I hoped that the greedy businessman would finally come in contact with a beast infinitely more malicious than himself. Then there's the music, which alternates between stirring and grating. Particularly annoying is the decision to work some sort of elephant/hyena noise into what would be an otherwise memorable score. If it weren't for the final half hour and the previously mentioned sub- par musical renderings, it'd be safe to call The Ghost and the Darkness an underrated thriller. Instead it fizzles into a flabby shadow of its former self, much like a long coveted balloon that's held on until there's simply nothing left.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Some Lions, Coward Villagers and a Brave Boy!!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Ankit Dubey
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This title suits the movie well. A predictive and very childish kind of storyline, somewhat like bedtime stories to make children brave, which could have been done by a short 5 minutes story. Directed by Stephen Hopkins and Written By William Godman, this film is all about a character John Patterson an engineer, a bridge builder to be specific, who is the protagonist of the story, who takes a challenge of building a bridge in Africa, very confidently and with his wife pregnant and delivering a baby in six months. The job was assigned by a very rude and demotivating boss. The story moves around building of the bridge and some man-eater lions which created fear in the mind of people working there. And at the end of the movie, as one can predict, the hero killed the lions and thank god, the movie was over!! Despite a bad story, the direction is good. The background music is so real, that it creates such a superb horror effect in the mind of people that even if the movie was over you will feel the lions coming after you!! All the characters acted well, especially the hero. The best part of the movie which i liked the most was; cultural relations have been very beautiful shown in this movie, i.e. how to live and co-operate with people who are not like you. So the final verdict of the movie goes as, it's better to watch 'Man verses wild' on National Geographical than to waste time as well money in cinema hall.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Man-Eaters Of Tsavo
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bruce-wayne074
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie is a based on a true story about the man-eaters of Tsavo i like this movie very much i think story line was great and i think Val Kilmer and Michael Douglas did a great job its a great and 100 percent recommended if u haven't seen it yet go check it out guys its really one the best and have place on the list of my top 50 movies its really great some scenes are pretty scary man-eaters attacking the workers and dragged them out of their tents at night although Michael Douglas character was fictional but he did it very well and Val Kilmer the role Colonel John Patterson very its a great movie and i think best movie ever made about the man-eaters of Tsavo
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Awesome Movie, It's Like Jaws with Lions
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Luke Reeves
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/6/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This film is amazing a real gem. The scenery is spectacular, acting superb, great performances by the lions. A real masterpiece! Even better knowing it's a true story. The sound effects were fantastic, you really get a feel for what it must have been like being close to these dangerous monsters. Even the lions were afraid. On surround sound fairly loud, the roar and growls of the lions really makes an emotional impact. If you liked the film Jaws, you will definitely like this film. I was a bit worried about the killing of lions to be sad and depressing, because I really love lions. That's why it has taken me so long to see this film. However these lions really deserved it! They were nasty scary beasts and would make any vegetarian want to go back to eating meat. :D Anyway great film, another must see before you die type movie.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Safari Thriller with Big Cats
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    zardoz-13
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/5/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Director Stephen Hopkins' safari saga "The Ghost and the Darkness" is based on a true incident. Two bloodthirsty lions feasted on 130 native railroad laborers in Africa in the late 1890s. But it's an adventure tale with more growl than grandeur. Val Kilmer bares a pearly smile in his starring role as idealistic bridge builder Lieutenant Colonel John Patterson. As Patterson, he is assigned by his racist British tycoon boss, Robert Beaumont (Tom Wilkinson) to bridge Africa's Tsavo River within five months. As we learn, the Swahili word for Tsavo translates as "a place of slaughter." When Patterson arrives in Africa, his loyal African guide, Samuel (John Kani), warns him that nothing works in Tsavo. No sooner has work started than the lions strike. Patterson guns down one man-eater, but two more lions replace it. The natives call these savage cats "The Ghost and the Darkness." Michael Douglas co-stars as savvy lion killer Charles Remington. He arrives on the scene to help save the day, but he doesn't make his appearance until nearly halfway into the action. William Goldman's script errs in not bringing Douglas into the fray much earlier. Although confined to a role that is little more than an over-long cameo, Douglas dominates "The Ghost and the Darkness." Douglas' charismatic Remington easily upstages Kilmer's ponderous spit and polish Patterson. Compared to the elegant Patterson, Douglas resembles a shaggy villain from a 1970s era Italian western. Nevertheless, what distinguishes "The Ghost and the Darkness" are its cagey lions. These lions constantly elude and outwit our pair of heroes. If you saw the Robin Williams movie "Jumanji," the special effects here are just as incredible. Director Stephen Hopkins deploys these fantastic digital effects to stage a truly realistic lion attack on a crowd. Many close-up shots of gaping jaws and dark, hypnotic eyes bolster the suspense. An exciting confrontation that sends Kilmer scrambling up a tree with a lion nipping at his heels should get the adrenalin singing in your veins. Altogether, "The Ghost and the Darkness" succeeds more as a horror movie. The action never strays far from the bridge site so the movie seems rather claustrophobic. When "Ghost" isn't frightening, it creeps along with one too many campfire scenes. "Butch Cassidy and the Sundance Kid" scenarist William Goldman literate script sticks closely to the events of this true-life tragedy. Nevertheless, you wonder how they made the mistakes that they made. Patterson, for example, swaps rifles the night before the big hunt. When he confronts a lion, his gun misfires. The death of one character occurs off-screen, forcing you to fill in the gap and deprive both the audience and the characters with a memorable death scene. You can almost guess which character will be chomped because the filmmakers cast a halo around the person's head. Meanwhile, Hopkins and Goldman devise one genuinely shocking scene but cannot sustain this kind of momentum when the lions are on-screen. Hopkins deserves credit for making these lion attacks fully vicious without emphasizing the blood and gore.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A story of two demonic lions
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    david-sarkies
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is one absolutely awesome movie. It is about two man eating lions that plague a construction site of a bridge in Africa. These lions are no ordinary lions, they are vicious man eaters that do not conform to what lions are like. The natives call them demons, and as this is claimed to be a true story, this is biblically possible. But before I go into the theology of this, I wish to look at the movie first. This move is set in Africa at the turn of the century. There is a race with the other European countries, namely Germany, to colonise Africa. A bridge must be built so that the British can move further inland. When Val Kilmer's character first looks at the river he is amazed. He says that the wonder of building bridges is to put land over water. The bridge is also seen as a chain, or a manacle for the river. An unbridged river is an obstacle but a bridge makes this obstacle no more. The bridge tames the land for the river can no longer block the progress of man. But here the land seems to fight back. Right at the beginning, the first lion attacks and is killed with one bullet. Thus Val Kilmer comes out as a hero. Soon after the two lions, the Ghost and the Darkness, come and cause havoc in the campsite. No matter what they do they cannot stop these lions. A great hunter, Remington (Michael Douglas) comes along to help get rid of these lions. He believes them to be simple lions, but when his tribe leaves, he suddenly realises what he is up against. There is a very interesting scene, but to tell you about it would give something away. These lions are considered demons by the natives, and in my mind this is possible. If we look in the Gospels of Matthew, Mark, and Luke, there is the story of the man possessed by the demon legion (he is called legion because he is many). The demon pleads with Christ not to send them back to hell so Christ sends them into a herd of swine. This shows us that demons can manifest themselves in animals as well as in humans. With this in mind, the animal kingdom is not as weak as we make it out to be. These lions were intelligent and would torment their enemies and then turn and indiscriminately kill. If you watch the hospital scene you will note that they kill everybody but do not take anybody away to eat. As Remington says, "they do it for the pleasure of it." Even though they are demons, they are still lions, as the swine were still swine. Just because they were possessed did not mean they were unkillable. The soul cannot be destroyed but the body can. The swine ran into the lake and were drowned, the lions were also vulnerable in the same way. This movie comes out as a horror movie, but it is far more than that. There is not ghosts or demons running about, just two lions. The natives call them evil, and that they are, but the movie is real, or so it claims. This really happened and thus can happen to us. A horror movie comes across as being unreal. We can leave a horror movie at the end and be comforted that it is not real. This was. The only comfort we have is that the lions are dead.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "If you lock eyes with them, you will be afraid."
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Frederick Smith
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Since the film was shot in South Africa, the scenery is exceptional. Like all docudramas, an amount of license was taken. Micheal Douglas' part in the film is fictional, but very well played and adds to the suspense of the movie. Val Kilmer gives a very quiet but determined air to the role and is supported by excellent performances by John Kani, Om Puri, and Henry Cele, all essential character actors who bring the proper balance of ethnicity and culture to the film. Tom Wilkinson plays Robert Beaumont, a man dedicated to advancing his position to the throne ("I care about my Knighthood!"), across the backs of the people he assigns the tasks. He is a self described Monster who can either make or break a career, and has no qualms about either. Overall the film is matter of fact and very ordinary, but what cannot be denied is that this happened. I have been to the Field Museum and seen the Lions of Tsavo. It is as the last line of the movie says. "If you lock eyes with them, you will be afraid." Lots of gory scenes make this unsuitable for the children, but most teens have seen worse on their video games. Not necessarily collectible, but certainly worth a viewing, especially if you enjoy Kilmer and Douglas.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Could have been great if... (possible spoilers)
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ADG999
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/12/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    ...This incredible true story could have been much, much better than it was, but choppy editing, inconsistent direction, less-than-great cinematography,and the questionable plot decision to add a fictional American big game hunter to "help" Patterson hunt the lions, made this movie less than it could have been. The fact is that, in real life, Patterson (SPOILER) killed both lions himself, and frankly I think it would have been a better movie if they had written the script to reflect that. The Remington character always seemed somewhat out of place to me, and when I realized he was just a device added by the writers, for reasons that I still can't fathom, I understood why. Maybe they were afraid Val Kilmer could not carry the movie on his own--frankly, I think he could have with no problem. Maybe it was because Michael Douglas was an executive producer on the film, and wanted to be in the movie. Whatever the reason, this movie goes on my list of "missed opportunities" to make a really great film. Eight stars, only because I love the story, and love what the movie could have been.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Jaws in Africa
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Roland Jakobsson (rolandddd)
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The story of how two man-eating lions delayed the construction of a railway bridge in Tsavo, Kenya in 1898, is one that fascinates me. The film is loosely based on the biographical account of Lt Col John Henry Patterson, played by Val Kilmer in the movie. Though the original story is decently written and very exciting to read, it is also clearly a work of its time, and some of the more racist undertones of the original short story has wisely been omitted from the film. Halfway through the story something very strange happens. Being at least reasonably true to Patterson's account until then, the movie transforms into a carbon copy of Jaws! Suddenly throwing aside Patterson's story and all ties to reality, fictitious character Remington is introduced, horribly portrayed by Michael Douglas. This legendary huntsman is clearly the equivalent of Jaws's Quint, but unfortunately Douglas OTT-acting doesn't even come close to matching Robert Shaw's performance. Despite the movie's obvious ambition to be a Jaws set in Africa (even down to the POV shots of the lions stalking their prey), I think lots of things work well. The ambition to emulate Jaws is at least partly successful, and the movie has some great suspenseful scenes. The extensive use of real lions Caesar and Bongo and very little animatronics means that the predator scenes look great, and I think the film benefits from being made in the mid-nineties with basically no CGI. The scenery (South Africa substituting for Kenya) looks stunning and the film is wonderfully shot, and together with the realistic animal this makes the movie look really good. The acting, apart from Douglas, is also solid with Kilmer being backed up by a strong supporting cast of Tom Wilkinson, Bernard Hill and Emily Mortimer to name a few. Overall, I have a soft spot for "monster" movies and even though this has many flaws I think it is really entertaining and well worth watching!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    This movie was terrible.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Tekki Kiraito
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I was forced to watch this piece of garbage in English class and I did not find anything about it enjoyable. It is heavy on the violence and gore which I do not think is acceptable for a high school English course. I do not appreciate being forced to watch something that greatly disturbs me for a course that is mandatory. This movie was filled with lots of historical inaccuracies. Some of the people in this film, such as Remington, didn't even exist! The film just felt like a cheap slasher trying to be something it's not. If you are truly interested in this event, I recommend reading Patterson's book. In short, skip this piece of garbage. It's not worth your time.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "Lion" in Wait
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    flowersflix
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Here I am again, reviewing yet another "man vs. nature" movie. This time, we've got two seemingly demon possessed lions murdering railroad workers in turn of the century Uganda. Our hero is John Patterson (Val Kilmer), a contractor hired by a wealthy (and ruthless) tycoon to oversee construction of a bridge that will bolster commerce in the region. When the murderous lions in question begin terrorizingand maimingJohn's workers, something's got to be done (especially when they all flee at the suspicion that he's brought about a curse on the area). Cue the entrance of Charles Remington (Michael Douglas), a world- renowned hunter who's the embodiment of the old-school, no-holds-barred, shotgun-toting, Hemingway-esque man's man. Director Stephen Hopkins decides the go the route of Jaws, as it's rare that we're given a clean, full frame shot of the "monsters." This turns out to be a great decision, as it adds to the suspense when we see a silhouette (or think we see one) moving stealthily among the rippling, waist high savanna. In that regard, there's no denying that The Ghost and the Darkness delivers the goods in the "suspense" department. Unfortunately, the film does have its problems. First and foremost is the entirely too abrupt conclusion, which, quite honestly, feels sloppy and rushed. After all we've been through with Patterson and Remington, one would expect a grand finale that heightens the tension to unbearable levels. Instead we get something like a watered down version of the velociraptor kitchen scene in Jurassic Park. There's also the lack of satisfaction that could have been delivered if the one person we truly despise in the story got what he had coming to him. Spontenaity is a good thing, but all I could think about as the final act unfolded was how badly I hoped that the greedy businessman would finally come in contact with a beast infinitely more malicious than himself. Then there's the music, which alternates between stirring and grating. Particularly annoying is the decision to work some sort of elephant/hyena noise into what would be an otherwise memorable score. If it weren't for the final half hour and the previously mentioned sub- par musical renderings, it'd be safe to call The Ghost and the Darkness an underrated thriller. Instead it fizzles into a flabby shadow of its former self, much like a long coveted balloon that's held on until there's simply nothing left.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Some Lions, Coward Villagers and a Brave Boy!!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Ankit Dubey
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This title suits the movie well. A predictive and very childish kind of storyline, somewhat like bedtime stories to make children brave, which could have been done by a short 5 minutes story. Directed by Stephen Hopkins and Written By William Godman, this film is all about a character John Patterson an engineer, a bridge builder to be specific, who is the protagonist of the story, who takes a challenge of building a bridge in Africa, very confidently and with his wife pregnant and delivering a baby in six months. The job was assigned by a very rude and demotivating boss. The story moves around building of the bridge and some man-eater lions which created fear in the mind of people working there. And at the end of the movie, as one can predict, the hero killed the lions and thank god, the movie was over!! Despite a bad story, the direction is good. The background music is so real, that it creates such a superb horror effect in the mind of people that even if the movie was over you will feel the lions coming after you!! All the characters acted well, especially the hero. The best part of the movie which i liked the most was; cultural relations have been very beautiful shown in this movie, i.e. how to live and co-operate with people who are not like you. So the final verdict of the movie goes as, it's better to watch 'Man verses wild' on National Geographical than to waste time as well money in cinema hall.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Man-Eaters Of Tsavo
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bruce-wayne074
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie is a based on a true story about the man-eaters of Tsavo i like this movie very much i think story line was great and i think Val Kilmer and Michael Douglas did a great job its a great and 100 percent recommended if u haven't seen it yet go check it out guys its really one the best and have place on the list of my top 50 movies its really great some scenes are pretty scary man-eaters attacking the workers and dragged them out of their tents at night although Michael Douglas character was fictional but he did it very well and Val Kilmer the role Colonel John Patterson very its a great movie and i think best movie ever made about the man-eaters of Tsavo
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Awesome Movie, It's Like Jaws with Lions
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Luke Reeves
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/6/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This film is amazing a real gem. The scenery is spectacular, acting superb, great performances by the lions. A real masterpiece! Even better knowing it's a true story. The sound effects were fantastic, you really get a feel for what it must have been like being close to these dangerous monsters. Even the lions were afraid. On surround sound fairly loud, the roar and growls of the lions really makes an emotional impact. If you liked the film Jaws, you will definitely like this film. I was a bit worried about the killing of lions to be sad and depressing, because I really love lions. That's why it has taken me so long to see this film. However these lions really deserved it! They were nasty scary beasts and would make any vegetarian want to go back to eating meat. :D Anyway great film, another must see before you die type movie.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Safari Thriller with Big Cats
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    zardoz-13
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/5/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Director Stephen Hopkins' safari saga "The Ghost and the Darkness" is based on a true incident. Two bloodthirsty lions feasted on 130 native railroad laborers in Africa in the late 1890s. But it's an adventure tale with more growl than grandeur. Val Kilmer bares a pearly smile in his starring role as idealistic bridge builder Lieutenant Colonel John Patterson. As Patterson, he is assigned by his racist British tycoon boss, Robert Beaumont (Tom Wilkinson) to bridge Africa's Tsavo River within five months. As we learn, the Swahili word for Tsavo translates as "a place of slaughter." When Patterson arrives in Africa, his loyal African guide, Samuel (John Kani), warns him that nothing works in Tsavo. No sooner has work started than the lions strike. Patterson guns down one man-eater, but two more lions replace it. The natives call these savage cats "The Ghost and the Darkness." Michael Douglas co-stars as savvy lion killer Charles Remington. He arrives on the scene to help save the day, but he doesn't make his appearance until nearly halfway into the action. William Goldman's script errs in not bringing Douglas into the fray much earlier. Although confined to a role that is little more than an over-long cameo, Douglas dominates "The Ghost and the Darkness." Douglas' charismatic Remington easily upstages Kilmer's ponderous spit and polish Patterson. Compared to the elegant Patterson, Douglas resembles a shaggy villain from a 1970s era Italian western. Nevertheless, what distinguishes "The Ghost and the Darkness" are its cagey lions. These lions constantly elude and outwit our pair of heroes. If you saw the Robin Williams movie "Jumanji," the special effects here are just as incredible. Director Stephen Hopkins deploys these fantastic digital effects to stage a truly realistic lion attack on a crowd. Many close-up shots of gaping jaws and dark, hypnotic eyes bolster the suspense. An exciting confrontation that sends Kilmer scrambling up a tree with a lion nipping at his heels should get the adrenalin singing in your veins. Altogether, "The Ghost and the Darkness" succeeds more as a horror movie. The action never strays far from the bridge site so the movie seems rather claustrophobic. When "Ghost" isn't frightening, it creeps along with one too many campfire scenes. "Butch Cassidy and the Sundance Kid" scenarist William Goldman literate script sticks closely to the events of this true-life tragedy. Nevertheless, you wonder how they made the mistakes that they made. Patterson, for example, swaps rifles the night before the big hunt. When he confronts a lion, his gun misfires. The death of one character occurs off-screen, forcing you to fill in the gap and deprive both the audience and the characters with a memorable death scene. You can almost guess which character will be chomped because the filmmakers cast a halo around the person's head. Meanwhile, Hopkins and Goldman devise one genuinely shocking scene but cannot sustain this kind of momentum when the lions are on-screen. Hopkins deserves credit for making these lion attacks fully vicious without emphasizing the blood and gore.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A story of two demonic lions
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    david-sarkies
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is one absolutely awesome movie. It is about two man eating lions that plague a construction site of a bridge in Africa. These lions are no ordinary lions, they are vicious man eaters that do not conform to what lions are like. The natives call them demons, and as this is claimed to be a true story, this is biblically possible. But before I go into the theology of this, I wish to look at the movie first. This move is set in Africa at the turn of the century. There is a race with the other European countries, namely Germany, to colonise Africa. A bridge must be built so that the British can move further inland. When Val Kilmer's character first looks at the river he is amazed. He says that the wonder of building bridges is to put land over water. The bridge is also seen as a chain, or a manacle for the river. An unbridged river is an obstacle but a bridge makes this obstacle no more. The bridge tames the land for the river can no longer block the progress of man. But here the land seems to fight back. Right at the beginning, the first lion attacks and is killed with one bullet. Thus Val Kilmer comes out as a hero. Soon after the two lions, the Ghost and the Darkness, come and cause havoc in the campsite. No matter what they do they cannot stop these lions. A great hunter, Remington (Michael Douglas) comes along to help get rid of these lions. He believes them to be simple lions, but when his tribe leaves, he suddenly realises what he is up against. There is a very interesting scene, but to tell you about it would give something away. These lions are considered demons by the natives, and in my mind this is possible. If we look in the Gospels of Matthew, Mark, and Luke, there is the story of the man possessed by the demon legion (he is called legion because he is many). The demon pleads with Christ not to send them back to hell so Christ sends them into a herd of swine. This shows us that demons can manifest themselves in animals as well as in humans. With this in mind, the animal kingdom is not as weak as we make it out to be. These lions were intelligent and would torment their enemies and then turn and indiscriminately kill. If you watch the hospital scene you will note that they kill everybody but do not take anybody away to eat. As Remington says, "they do it for the pleasure of it." Even though they are demons, they are still lions, as the swine were still swine. Just because they were possessed did not mean they were unkillable. The soul cannot be destroyed but the body can. The swine ran into the lake and were drowned, the lions were also vulnerable in the same way. This movie comes out as a horror movie, but it is far more than that. There is not ghosts or demons running about, just two lions. The natives call them evil, and that they are, but the movie is real, or so it claims. This really happened and thus can happen to us. A horror movie comes across as being unreal. We can leave a horror movie at the end and be comforted that it is not real. This was. The only comfort we have is that the lions are dead.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "If you lock eyes with them, you will be afraid."
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Frederick Smith
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Since the film was shot in South Africa, the scenery is exceptional. Like all docudramas, an amount of license was taken. Micheal Douglas' part in the film is fictional, but very well played and adds to the suspense of the movie. Val Kilmer gives a very quiet but determined air to the role and is supported by excellent performances by John Kani, Om Puri, and Henry Cele, all essential character actors who bring the proper balance of ethnicity and culture to the film. Tom Wilkinson plays Robert Beaumont, a man dedicated to advancing his position to the throne ("I care about my Knighthood!"), across the backs of the people he assigns the tasks. He is a self described Monster who can either make or break a career, and has no qualms about either. Overall the film is matter of fact and very ordinary, but what cannot be denied is that this happened. I have been to the Field Museum and seen the Lions of Tsavo. It is as the last line of the movie says. "If you lock eyes with them, you will be afraid." Lots of gory scenes make this unsuitable for the children, but most teens have seen worse on their video games. Not necessarily collectible, but certainly worth a viewing, especially if you enjoy Kilmer and Douglas.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Could have been great if... (possible spoilers)
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ADG999
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/12/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    ...This incredible true story could have been much, much better than it was, but choppy editing, inconsistent direction, less-than-great cinematography,and the questionable plot decision to add a fictional American big game hunter to "help" Patterson hunt the lions, made this movie less than it could have been. The fact is that, in real life, Patterson (SPOILER) killed both lions himself, and frankly I think it would have been a better movie if they had written the script to reflect that. The Remington character always seemed somewhat out of place to me, and when I realized he was just a device added by the writers, for reasons that I still can't fathom, I understood why. Maybe they were afraid Val Kilmer could not carry the movie on his own--frankly, I think he could have with no problem. Maybe it was because Michael Douglas was an executive producer on the film, and wanted to be in the movie. Whatever the reason, this movie goes on my list of "missed opportunities" to make a really great film. Eight stars, only because I love the story, and love what the movie could have been.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Jaws in Africa
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Roland Jakobsson (rolandddd)
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The story of how two man-eating lions delayed the construction of a railway bridge in Tsavo, Kenya in 1898, is one that fascinates me. The film is loosely based on the biographical account of Lt Col John Henry Patterson, played by Val Kilmer in the movie. Though the original story is decently written and very exciting to read, it is also clearly a work of its time, and some of the more racist undertones of the original short story has wisely been omitted from the film. Halfway through the story something very strange happens. Being at least reasonably true to Patterson's account until then, the movie transforms into a carbon copy of Jaws! Suddenly throwing aside Patterson's story and all ties to reality, fictitious character Remington is introduced, horribly portrayed by Michael Douglas. This legendary huntsman is clearly the equivalent of Jaws's Quint, but unfortunately Douglas OTT-acting doesn't even come close to matching Robert Shaw's performance. Despite the movie's obvious ambition to be a Jaws set in Africa (even down to the POV shots of the lions stalking their prey), I think lots of things work well. The ambition to emulate Jaws is at least partly successful, and the movie has some great suspenseful scenes. The extensive use of real lions Caesar and Bongo and very little animatronics means that the predator scenes look great, and I think the film benefits from being made in the mid-nineties with basically no CGI. The scenery (South Africa substituting for Kenya) looks stunning and the film is wonderfully shot, and together with the realistic animal this makes the movie look really good. The acting, apart from Douglas, is also solid with Kilmer being backed up by a strong supporting cast of Tom Wilkinson, Bernard Hill and Emily Mortimer to name a few. Overall, I have a soft spot for "monster" movies and even though this has many flaws I think it is really entertaining and well worth watching!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    This movie was terrible.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Tekki Kiraito
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I was forced to watch this piece of garbage in English class and I did not find anything about it enjoyable. It is heavy on the violence and gore which I do not think is acceptable for a high school English course. I do not appreciate being forced to watch something that greatly disturbs me for a course that is mandatory. This movie was filled with lots of historical inaccuracies. Some of the people in this film, such as Remington, didn't even exist! The film just felt like a cheap slasher trying to be something it's not. If you are truly interested in this event, I recommend reading Patterson's book. In short, skip this piece of garbage. It's not worth your time.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "Lion" in Wait
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    flowersflix
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Here I am again, reviewing yet another "man vs. nature" movie. This time, we've got two seemingly demon possessed lions murdering railroad workers in turn of the century Uganda. Our hero is John Patterson (Val Kilmer), a contractor hired by a wealthy (and ruthless) tycoon to oversee construction of a bridge that will bolster commerce in the region. When the murderous lions in question begin terrorizingand maimingJohn's workers, something's got to be done (especially when they all flee at the suspicion that he's brought about a curse on the area). Cue the entrance of Charles Remington (Michael Douglas), a world- renowned hunter who's the embodiment of the old-school, no-holds-barred, shotgun-toting, Hemingway-esque man's man. Director Stephen Hopkins decides the go the route of Jaws, as it's rare that we're given a clean, full frame shot of the "monsters." This turns out to be a great decision, as it adds to the suspense when we see a silhouette (or think we see one) moving stealthily among the rippling, waist high savanna. In that regard, there's no denying that The Ghost and the Darkness delivers the goods in the "suspense" department. Unfortunately, the film does have its problems. First and foremost is the entirely too abrupt conclusion, which, quite honestly, feels sloppy and rushed. After all we've been through with Patterson and Remington, one would expect a grand finale that heightens the tension to unbearable levels. Instead we get something like a watered down version of the velociraptor kitchen scene in Jurassic Park. There's also the lack of satisfaction that could have been delivered if the one person we truly despise in the story got what he had coming to him. Spontenaity is a good thing, but all I could think about as the final act unfolded was how badly I hoped that the greedy businessman would finally come in contact with a beast infinitely more malicious than himself. Then there's the music, which alternates between stirring and grating. Particularly annoying is the decision to work some sort of elephant/hyena noise into what would be an otherwise memorable score. If it weren't for the final half hour and the previously mentioned sub- par musical renderings, it'd be safe to call The Ghost and the Darkness an underrated thriller. Instead it fizzles into a flabby shadow of its former self, much like a long coveted balloon that's held on until there's simply nothing left.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Some Lions, Coward Villagers and a Brave Boy!!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Ankit Dubey
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This title suits the movie well. A predictive and very childish kind of storyline, somewhat like bedtime stories to make children brave, which could have been done by a short 5 minutes story. Directed by Stephen Hopkins and Written By William Godman, this film is all about a character John Patterson an engineer, a bridge builder to be specific, who is the protagonist of the story, who takes a challenge of building a bridge in Africa, very confidently and with his wife pregnant and delivering a baby in six months. The job was assigned by a very rude and demotivating boss. The story moves around building of the bridge and some man-eater lions which created fear in the mind of people working there. And at the end of the movie, as one can predict, the hero killed the lions and thank god, the movie was over!! Despite a bad story, the direction is good. The background music is so real, that it creates such a superb horror effect in the mind of people that even if the movie was over you will feel the lions coming after you!! All the characters acted well, especially the hero. The best part of the movie which i liked the most was; cultural relations have been very beautiful shown in this movie, i.e. how to live and co-operate with people who are not like you. So the final verdict of the movie goes as, it's better to watch 'Man verses wild' on National Geographical than to waste time as well money in cinema hall.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Man-Eaters Of Tsavo
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bruce-wayne074
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie is a based on a true story about the man-eaters of Tsavo i like this movie very much i think story line was great and i think Val Kilmer and Michael Douglas did a great job its a great and 100 percent recommended if u haven't seen it yet go check it out guys its really one the best and have place on the list of my top 50 movies its really great some scenes are pretty scary man-eaters attacking the workers and dragged them out of their tents at night although Michael Douglas character was fictional but he did it very well and Val Kilmer the role Colonel John Patterson very its a great movie and i think best movie ever made about the man-eaters of Tsavo
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Awesome Movie, It's Like Jaws with Lions
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Luke Reeves
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/6/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This film is amazing a real gem. The scenery is spectacular, acting superb, great performances by the lions. A real masterpiece! Even better knowing it's a true story. The sound effects were fantastic, you really get a feel for what it must have been like being close to these dangerous monsters. Even the lions were afraid. On surround sound fairly loud, the roar and growls of the lions really makes an emotional impact. If you liked the film Jaws, you will definitely like this film. I was a bit worried about the killing of lions to be sad and depressing, because I really love lions. That's why it has taken me so long to see this film. However these lions really deserved it! They were nasty scary beasts and would make any vegetarian want to go back to eating meat. :D Anyway great film, another must see before you die type movie.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Safari Thriller with Big Cats
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    zardoz-13
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/5/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Director Stephen Hopkins' safari saga "The Ghost and the Darkness" is based on a true incident. Two bloodthirsty lions feasted on 130 native railroad laborers in Africa in the late 1890s. But it's an adventure tale with more growl than grandeur. Val Kilmer bares a pearly smile in his starring role as idealistic bridge builder Lieutenant Colonel John Patterson. As Patterson, he is assigned by his racist British tycoon boss, Robert Beaumont (Tom Wilkinson) to bridge Africa's Tsavo River within five months. As we learn, the Swahili word for Tsavo translates as "a place of slaughter." When Patterson arrives in Africa, his loyal African guide, Samuel (John Kani), warns him that nothing works in Tsavo. No sooner has work started than the lions strike. Patterson guns down one man-eater, but two more lions replace it. The natives call these savage cats "The Ghost and the Darkness." Michael Douglas co-stars as savvy lion killer Charles Remington. He arrives on the scene to help save the day, but he doesn't make his appearance until nearly halfway into the action. William Goldman's script errs in not bringing Douglas into the fray much earlier. Although confined to a role that is little more than an over-long cameo, Douglas dominates "The Ghost and the Darkness." Douglas' charismatic Remington easily upstages Kilmer's ponderous spit and polish Patterson. Compared to the elegant Patterson, Douglas resembles a shaggy villain from a 1970s era Italian western. Nevertheless, what distinguishes "The Ghost and the Darkness" are its cagey lions. These lions constantly elude and outwit our pair of heroes. If you saw the Robin Williams movie "Jumanji," the special effects here are just as incredible. Director Stephen Hopkins deploys these fantastic digital effects to stage a truly realistic lion attack on a crowd. Many close-up shots of gaping jaws and dark, hypnotic eyes bolster the suspense. An exciting confrontation that sends Kilmer scrambling up a tree with a lion nipping at his heels should get the adrenalin singing in your veins. Altogether, "The Ghost and the Darkness" succeeds more as a horror movie. The action never strays far from the bridge site so the movie seems rather claustrophobic. When "Ghost" isn't frightening, it creeps along with one too many campfire scenes. "Butch Cassidy and the Sundance Kid" scenarist William Goldman literate script sticks closely to the events of this true-life tragedy. Nevertheless, you wonder how they made the mistakes that they made. Patterson, for example, swaps rifles the night before the big hunt. When he confronts a lion, his gun misfires. The death of one character occurs off-screen, forcing you to fill in the gap and deprive both the audience and the characters with a memorable death scene. You can almost guess which character will be chomped because the filmmakers cast a halo around the person's head. Meanwhile, Hopkins and Goldman devise one genuinely shocking scene but cannot sustain this kind of momentum when the lions are on-screen. Hopkins deserves credit for making these lion attacks fully vicious without emphasizing the blood and gore.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A story of two demonic lions
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    david-sarkies
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is one absolutely awesome movie. It is about two man eating lions that plague a construction site of a bridge in Africa. These lions are no ordinary lions, they are vicious man eaters that do not conform to what lions are like. The natives call them demons, and as this is claimed to be a true story, this is biblically possible. But before I go into the theology of this, I wish to look at the movie first. This move is set in Africa at the turn of the century. There is a race with the other European countries, namely Germany, to colonise Africa. A bridge must be built so that the British can move further inland. When Val Kilmer's character first looks at the river he is amazed. He says that the wonder of building bridges is to put land over water. The bridge is also seen as a chain, or a manacle for the river. An unbridged river is an obstacle but a bridge makes this obstacle no more. The bridge tames the land for the river can no longer block the progress of man. But here the land seems to fight back. Right at the beginning, the first lion attacks and is killed with one bullet. Thus Val Kilmer comes out as a hero. Soon after the two lions, the Ghost and the Darkness, come and cause havoc in the campsite. No matter what they do they cannot stop these lions. A great hunter, Remington (Michael Douglas) comes along to help get rid of these lions. He believes them to be simple lions, but when his tribe leaves, he suddenly realises what he is up against. There is a very interesting scene, but to tell you about it would give something away. These lions are considered demons by the natives, and in my mind this is possible. If we look in the Gospels of Matthew, Mark, and Luke, there is the story of the man possessed by the demon legion (he is called legion because he is many). The demon pleads with Christ not to send them back to hell so Christ sends them into a herd of swine. This shows us that demons can manifest themselves in animals as well as in humans. With this in mind, the animal kingdom is not as weak as we make it out to be. These lions were intelligent and would torment their enemies and then turn and indiscriminately kill. If you watch the hospital scene you will note that they kill everybody but do not take anybody away to eat. As Remington says, "they do it for the pleasure of it." Even though they are demons, they are still lions, as the swine were still swine. Just because they were possessed did not mean they were unkillable. The soul cannot be destroyed but the body can. The swine ran into the lake and were drowned, the lions were also vulnerable in the same way. This movie comes out as a horror movie, but it is far more than that. There is not ghosts or demons running about, just two lions. The natives call them evil, and that they are, but the movie is real, or so it claims. This really happened and thus can happen to us. A horror movie comes across as being unreal. We can leave a horror movie at the end and be comforted that it is not real. This was. The only comfort we have is that the lions are dead.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "If you lock eyes with them, you will be afraid."
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Frederick Smith
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Since the film was shot in South Africa, the scenery is exceptional. Like all docudramas, an amount of license was taken. Micheal Douglas' part in the film is fictional, but very well played and adds to the suspense of the movie. Val Kilmer gives a very quiet but determined air to the role and is supported by excellent performances by John Kani, Om Puri, and Henry Cele, all essential character actors who bring the proper balance of ethnicity and culture to the film. Tom Wilkinson plays Robert Beaumont, a man dedicated to advancing his position to the throne ("I care about my Knighthood!"), across the backs of the people he assigns the tasks. He is a self described Monster who can either make or break a career, and has no qualms about either. Overall the film is matter of fact and very ordinary, but what cannot be denied is that this happened. I have been to the Field Museum and seen the Lions of Tsavo. It is as the last line of the movie says. "If you lock eyes with them, you will be afraid." Lots of gory scenes make this unsuitable for the children, but most teens have seen worse on their video games. Not necessarily collectible, but certainly worth a viewing, especially if you enjoy Kilmer and Douglas.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Could have been great if... (possible spoilers)
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ADG999
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/12/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    ...This incredible true story could have been much, much better than it was, but choppy editing, inconsistent direction, less-than-great cinematography,and the questionable plot decision to add a fictional American big game hunter to "help" Patterson hunt the lions, made this movie less than it could have been. The fact is that, in real life, Patterson (SPOILER) killed both lions himself, and frankly I think it would have been a better movie if they had written the script to reflect that. The Remington character always seemed somewhat out of place to me, and when I realized he was just a device added by the writers, for reasons that I still can't fathom, I understood why. Maybe they were afraid Val Kilmer could not carry the movie on his own--frankly, I think he could have with no problem. Maybe it was because Michael Douglas was an executive producer on the film, and wanted to be in the movie. Whatever the reason, this movie goes on my list of "missed opportunities" to make a really great film. Eight stars, only because I love the story, and love what the movie could have been.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Jaws in Africa
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Roland Jakobsson (rolandddd)
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The story of how two man-eating lions delayed the construction of a railway bridge in Tsavo, Kenya in 1898, is one that fascinates me. The film is loosely based on the biographical account of Lt Col John Henry Patterson, played by Val Kilmer in the movie. Though the original story is decently written and very exciting to read, it is also clearly a work of its time, and some of the more racist undertones of the original short story has wisely been omitted from the film. Halfway through the story something very strange happens. Being at least reasonably true to Patterson's account until then, the movie transforms into a carbon copy of Jaws! Suddenly throwing aside Patterson's story and all ties to reality, fictitious character Remington is introduced, horribly portrayed by Michael Douglas. This legendary huntsman is clearly the equivalent of Jaws's Quint, but unfortunately Douglas OTT-acting doesn't even come close to matching Robert Shaw's performance. Despite the movie's obvious ambition to be a Jaws set in Africa (even down to the POV shots of the lions stalking their prey), I think lots of things work well. The ambition to emulate Jaws is at least partly successful, and the movie has some great suspenseful scenes. The extensive use of real lions Caesar and Bongo and very little animatronics means that the predator scenes look great, and I think the film benefits from being made in the mid-nineties with basically no CGI. The scenery (South Africa substituting for Kenya) looks stunning and the film is wonderfully shot, and together with the realistic animal this makes the movie look really good. The acting, apart from Douglas, is also solid with Kilmer being backed up by a strong supporting cast of Tom Wilkinson, Bernard Hill and Emily Mortimer to name a few. Overall, I have a soft spot for "monster" movies and even though this has many flaws I think it is really entertaining and well worth watching!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    This movie was terrible.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Tekki Kiraito
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I was forced to watch this piece of garbage in English class and I did not find anything about it enjoyable. It is heavy on the violence and gore which I do not think is acceptable for a high school English course. I do not appreciate being forced to watch something that greatly disturbs me for a course that is mandatory. This movie was filled with lots of historical inaccuracies. Some of the people in this film, such as Remington, didn't even exist! The film just felt like a cheap slasher trying to be something it's not. If you are truly interested in this event, I recommend reading Patterson's book. In short, skip this piece of garbage. It's not worth your time.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "Lion" in Wait
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    flowersflix
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Here I am again, reviewing yet another "man vs. nature" movie. This time, we've got two seemingly demon possessed lions murdering railroad workers in turn of the century Uganda. Our hero is John Patterson (Val Kilmer), a contractor hired by a wealthy (and ruthless) tycoon to oversee construction of a bridge that will bolster commerce in the region. When the murderous lions in question begin terrorizingand maimingJohn's workers, something's got to be done (especially when they all flee at the suspicion that he's brought about a curse on the area). Cue the entrance of Charles Remington (Michael Douglas), a world- renowned hunter who's the embodiment of the old-school, no-holds-barred, shotgun-toting, Hemingway-esque man's man. Director Stephen Hopkins decides the go the route of Jaws, as it's rare that we're given a clean, full frame shot of the "monsters." This turns out to be a great decision, as it adds to the suspense when we see a silhouette (or think we see one) moving stealthily among the rippling, waist high savanna. In that regard, there's no denying that The Ghost and the Darkness delivers the goods in the "suspense" department. Unfortunately, the film does have its problems. First and foremost is the entirely too abrupt conclusion, which, quite honestly, feels sloppy and rushed. After all we've been through with Patterson and Remington, one would expect a grand finale that heightens the tension to unbearable levels. Instead we get something like a watered down version of the velociraptor kitchen scene in Jurassic Park. There's also the lack of satisfaction that could have been delivered if the one person we truly despise in the story got what he had coming to him. Spontenaity is a good thing, but all I could think about as the final act unfolded was how badly I hoped that the greedy businessman would finally come in contact with a beast infinitely more malicious than himself. Then there's the music, which alternates between stirring and grating. Particularly annoying is the decision to work some sort of elephant/hyena noise into what would be an otherwise memorable score. If it weren't for the final half hour and the previously mentioned sub- par musical renderings, it'd be safe to call The Ghost and the Darkness an underrated thriller. Instead it fizzles into a flabby shadow of its former self, much like a long coveted balloon that's held on until there's simply nothing left.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Some Lions, Coward Villagers and a Brave Boy!!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Ankit Dubey
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This title suits the movie well. A predictive and very childish kind of storyline, somewhat like bedtime stories to make children brave, which could have been done by a short 5 minutes story. Directed by Stephen Hopkins and Written By William Godman, this film is all about a character John Patterson an engineer, a bridge builder to be specific, who is the protagonist of the story, who takes a challenge of building a bridge in Africa, very confidently and with his wife pregnant and delivering a baby in six months. The job was assigned by a very rude and demotivating boss. The story moves around building of the bridge and some man-eater lions which created fear in the mind of people working there. And at the end of the movie, as one can predict, the hero killed the lions and thank god, the movie was over!! Despite a bad story, the direction is good. The background music is so real, that it creates such a superb horror effect in the mind of people that even if the movie was over you will feel the lions coming after you!! All the characters acted well, especially the hero. The best part of the movie which i liked the most was; cultural relations have been very beautiful shown in this movie, i.e. how to live and co-operate with people who are not like you. So the final verdict of the movie goes as, it's better to watch 'Man verses wild' on National Geographical than to waste time as well money in cinema hall.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Man-Eaters Of Tsavo
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bruce-wayne074
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie is a based on a true story about the man-eaters of Tsavo i like this movie very much i think story line was great and i think Val Kilmer and Michael Douglas did a great job its a great and 100 percent recommended if u haven't seen it yet go check it out guys its really one the best and have place on the list of my top 50 movies its really great some scenes are pretty scary man-eaters attacking the workers and dragged them out of their tents at night although Michael Douglas character was fictional but he did it very well and Val Kilmer the role Colonel John Patterson very its a great movie and i think best movie ever made about the man-eaters of Tsavo
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Awesome Movie, It's Like Jaws with Lions
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Luke Reeves
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/6/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This film is amazing a real gem. The scenery is spectacular, acting superb, great performances by the lions. A real masterpiece! Even better knowing it's a true story. The sound effects were fantastic, you really get a feel for what it must have been like being close to these dangerous monsters. Even the lions were afraid. On surround sound fairly loud, the roar and growls of the lions really makes an emotional impact. If you liked the film Jaws, you will definitely like this film. I was a bit worried about the killing of lions to be sad and depressing, because I really love lions. That's why it has taken me so long to see this film. However these lions really deserved it! They were nasty scary beasts and would make any vegetarian want to go back to eating meat. :D Anyway great film, another must see before you die type movie.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Safari Thriller with Big Cats
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    zardoz-13
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/5/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Director Stephen Hopkins' safari saga "The Ghost and the Darkness" is based on a true incident. Two bloodthirsty lions feasted on 130 native railroad laborers in Africa in the late 1890s. But it's an adventure tale with more growl than grandeur. Val Kilmer bares a pearly smile in his starring role as idealistic bridge builder Lieutenant Colonel John Patterson. As Patterson, he is assigned by his racist British tycoon boss, Robert Beaumont (Tom Wilkinson) to bridge Africa's Tsavo River within five months. As we learn, the Swahili word for Tsavo translates as "a place of slaughter." When Patterson arrives in Africa, his loyal African guide, Samuel (John Kani), warns him that nothing works in Tsavo. No sooner has work started than the lions strike. Patterson guns down one man-eater, but two more lions replace it. The natives call these savage cats "The Ghost and the Darkness." Michael Douglas co-stars as savvy lion killer Charles Remington. He arrives on the scene to help save the day, but he doesn't make his appearance until nearly halfway into the action. William Goldman's script errs in not bringing Douglas into the fray much earlier. Although confined to a role that is little more than an over-long cameo, Douglas dominates "The Ghost and the Darkness." Douglas' charismatic Remington easily upstages Kilmer's ponderous spit and polish Patterson. Compared to the elegant Patterson, Douglas resembles a shaggy villain from a 1970s era Italian western. Nevertheless, what distinguishes "The Ghost and the Darkness" are its cagey lions. These lions constantly elude and outwit our pair of heroes. If you saw the Robin Williams movie "Jumanji," the special effects here are just as incredible. Director Stephen Hopkins deploys these fantastic digital effects to stage a truly realistic lion attack on a crowd. Many close-up shots of gaping jaws and dark, hypnotic eyes bolster the suspense. An exciting confrontation that sends Kilmer scrambling up a tree with a lion nipping at his heels should get the adrenalin singing in your veins. Altogether, "The Ghost and the Darkness" succeeds more as a horror movie. The action never strays far from the bridge site so the movie seems rather claustrophobic. When "Ghost" isn't frightening, it creeps along with one too many campfire scenes. "Butch Cassidy and the Sundance Kid" scenarist William Goldman literate script sticks closely to the events of this true-life tragedy. Nevertheless, you wonder how they made the mistakes that they made. Patterson, for example, swaps rifles the night before the big hunt. When he confronts a lion, his gun misfires. The death of one character occurs off-screen, forcing you to fill in the gap and deprive both the audience and the characters with a memorable death scene. You can almost guess which character will be chomped because the filmmakers cast a halo around the person's head. Meanwhile, Hopkins and Goldman devise one genuinely shocking scene but cannot sustain this kind of momentum when the lions are on-screen. Hopkins deserves credit for making these lion attacks fully vicious without emphasizing the blood and gore.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A story of two demonic lions
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    david-sarkies
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is one absolutely awesome movie. It is about two man eating lions that plague a construction site of a bridge in Africa. These lions are no ordinary lions, they are vicious man eaters that do not conform to what lions are like. The natives call them demons, and as this is claimed to be a true story, this is biblically possible. But before I go into the theology of this, I wish to look at the movie first. This move is set in Africa at the turn of the century. There is a race with the other European countries, namely Germany, to colonise Africa. A bridge must be built so that the British can move further inland. When Val Kilmer's character first looks at the river he is amazed. He says that the wonder of building bridges is to put land over water. The bridge is also seen as a chain, or a manacle for the river. An unbridged river is an obstacle but a bridge makes this obstacle no more. The bridge tames the land for the river can no longer block the progress of man. But here the land seems to fight back. Right at the beginning, the first lion attacks and is killed with one bullet. Thus Val Kilmer comes out as a hero. Soon after the two lions, the Ghost and the Darkness, come and cause havoc in the campsite. No matter what they do they cannot stop these lions. A great hunter, Remington (Michael Douglas) comes along to help get rid of these lions. He believes them to be simple lions, but when his tribe leaves, he suddenly realises what he is up against. There is a very interesting scene, but to tell you about it would give something away. These lions are considered demons by the natives, and in my mind this is possible. If we look in the Gospels of Matthew, Mark, and Luke, there is the story of the man possessed by the demon legion (he is called legion because he is many). The demon pleads with Christ not to send them back to hell so Christ sends them into a herd of swine. This shows us that demons can manifest themselves in animals as well as in humans. With this in mind, the animal kingdom is not as weak as we make it out to be. These lions were intelligent and would torment their enemies and then turn and indiscriminately kill. If you watch the hospital scene you will note that they kill everybody but do not take anybody away to eat. As Remington says, "they do it for the pleasure of it." Even though they are demons, they are still lions, as the swine were still swine. Just because they were possessed did not mean they were unkillable. The soul cannot be destroyed but the body can. The swine ran into the lake and were drowned, the lions were also vulnerable in the same way. This movie comes out as a horror movie, but it is far more than that. There is not ghosts or demons running about, just two lions. The natives call them evil, and that they are, but the movie is real, or so it claims. This really happened and thus can happen to us. A horror movie comes across as being unreal. We can leave a horror movie at the end and be comforted that it is not real. This was. The only comfort we have is that the lions are dead.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "If you lock eyes with them, you will be afraid."
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Frederick Smith
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Since the film was shot in South Africa, the scenery is exceptional. Like all docudramas, an amount of license was taken. Micheal Douglas' part in the film is fictional, but very well played and adds to the suspense of the movie. Val Kilmer gives a very quiet but determined air to the role and is supported by excellent performances by John Kani, Om Puri, and Henry Cele, all essential character actors who bring the proper balance of ethnicity and culture to the film. Tom Wilkinson plays Robert Beaumont, a man dedicated to advancing his position to the throne ("I care about my Knighthood!"), across the backs of the people he assigns the tasks. He is a self described Monster who can either make or break a career, and has no qualms about either. Overall the film is matter of fact and very ordinary, but what cannot be denied is that this happened. I have been to the Field Museum and seen the Lions of Tsavo. It is as the last line of the movie says. "If you lock eyes with them, you will be afraid." Lots of gory scenes make this unsuitable for the children, but most teens have seen worse on their video games. Not necessarily collectible, but certainly worth a viewing, especially if you enjoy Kilmer and Douglas.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Could have been great if... (possible spoilers)
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ADG999
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/12/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    ...This incredible true story could have been much, much better than it was, but choppy editing, inconsistent direction, less-than-great cinematography,and the questionable plot decision to add a fictional American big game hunter to "help" Patterson hunt the lions, made this movie less than it could have been. The fact is that, in real life, Patterson (SPOILER) killed both lions himself, and frankly I think it would have been a better movie if they had written the script to reflect that. The Remington character always seemed somewhat out of place to me, and when I realized he was just a device added by the writers, for reasons that I still can't fathom, I understood why. Maybe they were afraid Val Kilmer could not carry the movie on his own--frankly, I think he could have with no problem. Maybe it was because Michael Douglas was an executive producer on the film, and wanted to be in the movie. Whatever the reason, this movie goes on my list of "missed opportunities" to make a really great film. Eight stars, only because I love the story, and love what the movie could have been.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Jaws in Africa
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Roland Jakobsson (rolandddd)
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The story of how two man-eating lions delayed the construction of a railway bridge in Tsavo, Kenya in 1898, is one that fascinates me. The film is loosely based on the biographical account of Lt Col John Henry Patterson, played by Val Kilmer in the movie. Though the original story is decently written and very exciting to read, it is also clearly a work of its time, and some of the more racist undertones of the original short story has wisely been omitted from the film. Halfway through the story something very strange happens. Being at least reasonably true to Patterson's account until then, the movie transforms into a carbon copy of Jaws! Suddenly throwing aside Patterson's story and all ties to reality, fictitious character Remington is introduced, horribly portrayed by Michael Douglas. This legendary huntsman is clearly the equivalent of Jaws's Quint, but unfortunately Douglas OTT-acting doesn't even come close to matching Robert Shaw's performance. Despite the movie's obvious ambition to be a Jaws set in Africa (even down to the POV shots of the lions stalking their prey), I think lots of things work well. The ambition to emulate Jaws is at least partly successful, and the movie has some great suspenseful scenes. The extensive use of real lions Caesar and Bongo and very little animatronics means that the predator scenes look great, and I think the film benefits from being made in the mid-nineties with basically no CGI. The scenery (South Africa substituting for Kenya) looks stunning and the film is wonderfully shot, and together with the realistic animal this makes the movie look really good. The acting, apart from Douglas, is also solid with Kilmer being backed up by a strong supporting cast of Tom Wilkinson, Bernard Hill and Emily Mortimer to name a few. Overall, I have a soft spot for "monster" movies and even though this has many flaws I think it is really entertaining and well worth watching!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    This movie was terrible.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Tekki Kiraito
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I was forced to watch this piece of garbage in English class and I did not find anything about it enjoyable. It is heavy on the violence and gore which I do not think is acceptable for a high school English course. I do not appreciate being forced to watch something that greatly disturbs me for a course that is mandatory. This movie was filled with lots of historical inaccuracies. Some of the people in this film, such as Remington, didn't even exist! The film just felt like a cheap slasher trying to be something it's not. If you are truly interested in this event, I recommend reading Patterson's book. In short, skip this piece of garbage. It's not worth your time.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "Lion" in Wait
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    flowersflix
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Here I am again, reviewing yet another "man vs. nature" movie. This time, we've got two seemingly demon possessed lions murdering railroad workers in turn of the century Uganda. Our hero is John Patterson (Val Kilmer), a contractor hired by a wealthy (and ruthless) tycoon to oversee construction of a bridge that will bolster commerce in the region. When the murderous lions in question begin terrorizingand maimingJohn's workers, something's got to be done (especially when they all flee at the suspicion that he's brought about a curse on the area). Cue the entrance of Charles Remington (Michael Douglas), a world- renowned hunter who's the embodiment of the old-school, no-holds-barred, shotgun-toting, Hemingway-esque man's man. Director Stephen Hopkins decides the go the route of Jaws, as it's rare that we're given a clean, full frame shot of the "monsters." This turns out to be a great decision, as it adds to the suspense when we see a silhouette (or think we see one) moving stealthily among the rippling, waist high savanna. In that regard, there's no denying that The Ghost and the Darkness delivers the goods in the "suspense" department. Unfortunately, the film does have its problems. First and foremost is the entirely too abrupt conclusion, which, quite honestly, feels sloppy and rushed. After all we've been through with Patterson and Remington, one would expect a grand finale that heightens the tension to unbearable levels. Instead we get something like a watered down version of the velociraptor kitchen scene in Jurassic Park. There's also the lack of satisfaction that could have been delivered if the one person we truly despise in the story got what he had coming to him. Spontenaity is a good thing, but all I could think about as the final act unfolded was how badly I hoped that the greedy businessman would finally come in contact with a beast infinitely more malicious than himself. Then there's the music, which alternates between stirring and grating. Particularly annoying is the decision to work some sort of elephant/hyena noise into what would be an otherwise memorable score. If it weren't for the final half hour and the previously mentioned sub- par musical renderings, it'd be safe to call The Ghost and the Darkness an underrated thriller. Instead it fizzles into a flabby shadow of its former self, much like a long coveted balloon that's held on until there's simply nothing left.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Some Lions, Coward Villagers and a Brave Boy!!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Ankit Dubey
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This title suits the movie well. A predictive and very childish kind of storyline, somewhat like bedtime stories to make children brave, which could have been done by a short 5 minutes story. Directed by Stephen Hopkins and Written By William Godman, this film is all about a character John Patterson an engineer, a bridge builder to be specific, who is the protagonist of the story, who takes a challenge of building a bridge in Africa, very confidently and with his wife pregnant and delivering a baby in six months. The job was assigned by a very rude and demotivating boss. The story moves around building of the bridge and some man-eater lions which created fear in the mind of people working there. And at the end of the movie, as one can predict, the hero killed the lions and thank god, the movie was over!! Despite a bad story, the direction is good. The background music is so real, that it creates such a superb horror effect in the mind of people that even if the movie was over you will feel the lions coming after you!! All the characters acted well, especially the hero. The best part of the movie which i liked the most was; cultural relations have been very beautiful shown in this movie, i.e. how to live and co-operate with people who are not like you. So the final verdict of the movie goes as, it's better to watch 'Man verses wild' on National Geographical than to waste time as well money in cinema hall.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Man-Eaters Of Tsavo
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bruce-wayne074
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie is a based on a true story about the man-eaters of Tsavo i like this movie very much i think story line was great and i think Val Kilmer and Michael Douglas did a great job its a great and 100 percent recommended if u haven't seen it yet go check it out guys its really one the best and have place on the list of my top 50 movies its really great some scenes are pretty scary man-eaters attacking the workers and dragged them out of their tents at night although Michael Douglas character was fictional but he did it very well and Val Kilmer the role Colonel John Patterson very its a great movie and i think best movie ever made about the man-eaters of Tsavo
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Awesome Movie, It's Like Jaws with Lions
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Luke Reeves
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/6/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This film is amazing a real gem. The scenery is spectacular, acting superb, great performances by the lions. A real masterpiece! Even better knowing it's a true story. The sound effects were fantastic, you really get a feel for what it must have been like being close to these dangerous monsters. Even the lions were afraid. On surround sound fairly loud, the roar and growls of the lions really makes an emotional impact. If you liked the film Jaws, you will definitely like this film. I was a bit worried about the killing of lions to be sad and depressing, because I really love lions. That's why it has taken me so long to see this film. However these lions really deserved it! They were nasty scary beasts and would make any vegetarian want to go back to eating meat. :D Anyway great film, another must see before you die type movie.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Safari Thriller with Big Cats
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    zardoz-13
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/5/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Director Stephen Hopkins' safari saga "The Ghost and the Darkness" is based on a true incident. Two bloodthirsty lions feasted on 130 native railroad laborers in Africa in the late 1890s. But it's an adventure tale with more growl than grandeur. Val Kilmer bares a pearly smile in his starring role as idealistic bridge builder Lieutenant Colonel John Patterson. As Patterson, he is assigned by his racist British tycoon boss, Robert Beaumont (Tom Wilkinson) to bridge Africa's Tsavo River within five months. As we learn, the Swahili word for Tsavo translates as "a place of slaughter." When Patterson arrives in Africa, his loyal African guide, Samuel (John Kani), warns him that nothing works in Tsavo. No sooner has work started than the lions strike. Patterson guns down one man-eater, but two more lions replace it. The natives call these savage cats "The Ghost and the Darkness." Michael Douglas co-stars as savvy lion killer Charles Remington. He arrives on the scene to help save the day, but he doesn't make his appearance until nearly halfway into the action. William Goldman's script errs in not bringing Douglas into the fray much earlier. Although confined to a role that is little more than an over-long cameo, Douglas dominates "The Ghost and the Darkness." Douglas' charismatic Remington easily upstages Kilmer's ponderous spit and polish Patterson. Compared to the elegant Patterson, Douglas resembles a shaggy villain from a 1970s era Italian western. Nevertheless, what distinguishes "The Ghost and the Darkness" are its cagey lions. These lions constantly elude and outwit our pair of heroes. If you saw the Robin Williams movie "Jumanji," the special effects here are just as incredible. Director Stephen Hopkins deploys these fantastic digital effects to stage a truly realistic lion attack on a crowd. Many close-up shots of gaping jaws and dark, hypnotic eyes bolster the suspense. An exciting confrontation that sends Kilmer scrambling up a tree with a lion nipping at his heels should get the adrenalin singing in your veins. Altogether, "The Ghost and the Darkness" succeeds more as a horror movie. The action never strays far from the bridge site so the movie seems rather claustrophobic. When "Ghost" isn't frightening, it creeps along with one too many campfire scenes. "Butch Cassidy and the Sundance Kid" scenarist William Goldman literate script sticks closely to the events of this true-life tragedy. Nevertheless, you wonder how they made the mistakes that they made. Patterson, for example, swaps rifles the night before the big hunt. When he confronts a lion, his gun misfires. The death of one character occurs off-screen, forcing you to fill in the gap and deprive both the audience and the characters with a memorable death scene. You can almost guess which character will be chomped because the filmmakers cast a halo around the person's head. Meanwhile, Hopkins and Goldman devise one genuinely shocking scene but cannot sustain this kind of momentum when the lions are on-screen. Hopkins deserves credit for making these lion attacks fully vicious without emphasizing the blood and gore.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A story of two demonic lions
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    david-sarkies
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is one absolutely awesome movie. It is about two man eating lions that plague a construction site of a bridge in Africa. These lions are no ordinary lions, they are vicious man eaters that do not conform to what lions are like. The natives call them demons, and as this is claimed to be a true story, this is biblically possible. But before I go into the theology of this, I wish to look at the movie first. This move is set in Africa at the turn of the century. There is a race with the other European countries, namely Germany, to colonise Africa. A bridge must be built so that the British can move further inland. When Val Kilmer's character first looks at the river he is amazed. He says that the wonder of building bridges is to put land over water. The bridge is also seen as a chain, or a manacle for the river. An unbridged river is an obstacle but a bridge makes this obstacle no more. The bridge tames the land for the river can no longer block the progress of man. But here the land seems to fight back. Right at the beginning, the first lion attacks and is killed with one bullet. Thus Val Kilmer comes out as a hero. Soon after the two lions, the Ghost and the Darkness, come and cause havoc in the campsite. No matter what they do they cannot stop these lions. A great hunter, Remington (Michael Douglas) comes along to help get rid of these lions. He believes them to be simple lions, but when his tribe leaves, he suddenly realises what he is up against. There is a very interesting scene, but to tell you about it would give something away. These lions are considered demons by the natives, and in my mind this is possible. If we look in the Gospels of Matthew, Mark, and Luke, there is the story of the man possessed by the demon legion (he is called legion because he is many). The demon pleads with Christ not to send them back to hell so Christ sends them into a herd of swine. This shows us that demons can manifest themselves in animals as well as in humans. With this in mind, the animal kingdom is not as weak as we make it out to be. These lions were intelligent and would torment their enemies and then turn and indiscriminately kill. If you watch the hospital scene you will note that they kill everybody but do not take anybody away to eat. As Remington says, "they do it for the pleasure of it." Even though they are demons, they are still lions, as the swine were still swine. Just because they were possessed did not mean they were unkillable. The soul cannot be destroyed but the body can. The swine ran into the lake and were drowned, the lions were also vulnerable in the same way. This movie comes out as a horror movie, but it is far more than that. There is not ghosts or demons running about, just two lions. The natives call them evil, and that they are, but the movie is real, or so it claims. This really happened and thus can happen to us. A horror movie comes across as being unreal. We can leave a horror movie at the end and be comforted that it is not real. This was. The only comfort we have is that the lions are dead.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "If you lock eyes with them, you will be afraid."
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Frederick Smith
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Since the film was shot in South Africa, the scenery is exceptional. Like all docudramas, an amount of license was taken. Micheal Douglas' part in the film is fictional, but very well played and adds to the suspense of the movie. Val Kilmer gives a very quiet but determined air to the role and is supported by excellent performances by John Kani, Om Puri, and Henry Cele, all essential character actors who bring the proper balance of ethnicity and culture to the film. Tom Wilkinson plays Robert Beaumont, a man dedicated to advancing his position to the throne ("I care about my Knighthood!"), across the backs of the people he assigns the tasks. He is a self described Monster who can either make or break a career, and has no qualms about either. Overall the film is matter of fact and very ordinary, but what cannot be denied is that this happened. I have been to the Field Museum and seen the Lions of Tsavo. It is as the last line of the movie says. "If you lock eyes with them, you will be afraid." Lots of gory scenes make this unsuitable for the children, but most teens have seen worse on their video games. Not necessarily collectible, but certainly worth a viewing, especially if you enjoy Kilmer and Douglas.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Could have been great if... (possible spoilers)
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ADG999
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/12/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    ...This incredible true story could have been much, much better than it was, but choppy editing, inconsistent direction, less-than-great cinematography,and the questionable plot decision to add a fictional American big game hunter to "help" Patterson hunt the lions, made this movie less than it could have been. The fact is that, in real life, Patterson (SPOILER) killed both lions himself, and frankly I think it would have been a better movie if they had written the script to reflect that. The Remington character always seemed somewhat out of place to me, and when I realized he was just a device added by the writers, for reasons that I still can't fathom, I understood why. Maybe they were afraid Val Kilmer could not carry the movie on his own--frankly, I think he could have with no problem. Maybe it was because Michael Douglas was an executive producer on the film, and wanted to be in the movie. Whatever the reason, this movie goes on my list of "missed opportunities" to make a really great film. Eight stars, only because I love the story, and love what the movie could have been.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Jaws in Africa
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Roland Jakobsson (rolandddd)
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The story of how two man-eating lions delayed the construction of a railway bridge in Tsavo, Kenya in 1898, is one that fascinates me. The film is loosely based on the biographical account of Lt Col John Henry Patterson, played by Val Kilmer in the movie. Though the original story is decently written and very exciting to read, it is also clearly a work of its time, and some of the more racist undertones of the original short story has wisely been omitted from the film. Halfway through the story something very strange happens. Being at least reasonably true to Patterson's account until then, the movie transforms into a carbon copy of Jaws! Suddenly throwing aside Patterson's story and all ties to reality, fictitious character Remington is introduced, horribly portrayed by Michael Douglas. This legendary huntsman is clearly the equivalent of Jaws's Quint, but unfortunately Douglas OTT-acting doesn't even come close to matching Robert Shaw's performance. Despite the movie's obvious ambition to be a Jaws set in Africa (even down to the POV shots of the lions stalking their prey), I think lots of things work well. The ambition to emulate Jaws is at least partly successful, and the movie has some great suspenseful scenes. The extensive use of real lions Caesar and Bongo and very little animatronics means that the predator scenes look great, and I think the film benefits from being made in the mid-nineties with basically no CGI. The scenery (South Africa substituting for Kenya) looks stunning and the film is wonderfully shot, and together with the realistic animal this makes the movie look really good. The acting, apart from Douglas, is also solid with Kilmer being backed up by a strong supporting cast of Tom Wilkinson, Bernard Hill and Emily Mortimer to name a few. Overall, I have a soft spot for "monster" movies and even though this has many flaws I think it is really entertaining and well worth watching!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    This movie was terrible.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Tekki Kiraito
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I was forced to watch this piece of garbage in English class and I did not find anything about it enjoyable. It is heavy on the violence and gore which I do not think is acceptable for a high school English course. I do not appreciate being forced to watch something that greatly disturbs me for a course that is mandatory. This movie was filled with lots of historical inaccuracies. Some of the people in this film, such as Remington, didn't even exist! The film just felt like a cheap slasher trying to be something it's not. If you are truly interested in this event, I recommend reading Patterson's book. In short, skip this piece of garbage. It's not worth your time.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "Lion" in Wait
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    flowersflix
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Here I am again, reviewing yet another "man vs. nature" movie. This time, we've got two seemingly demon possessed lions murdering railroad workers in turn of the century Uganda. Our hero is John Patterson (Val Kilmer), a contractor hired by a wealthy (and ruthless) tycoon to oversee construction of a bridge that will bolster commerce in the region. When the murderous lions in question begin terrorizingand maimingJohn's workers, something's got to be done (especially when they all flee at the suspicion that he's brought about a curse on the area). Cue the entrance of Charles Remington (Michael Douglas), a world- renowned hunter who's the embodiment of the old-school, no-holds-barred, shotgun-toting, Hemingway-esque man's man. Director Stephen Hopkins decides the go the route of Jaws, as it's rare that we're given a clean, full frame shot of the "monsters." This turns out to be a great decision, as it adds to the suspense when we see a silhouette (or think we see one) moving stealthily among the rippling, waist high savanna. In that regard, there's no denying that The Ghost and the Darkness delivers the goods in the "suspense" department. Unfortunately, the film does have its problems. First and foremost is the entirely too abrupt conclusion, which, quite honestly, feels sloppy and rushed. After all we've been through with Patterson and Remington, one would expect a grand finale that heightens the tension to unbearable levels. Instead we get something like a watered down version of the velociraptor kitchen scene in Jurassic Park. There's also the lack of satisfaction that could have been delivered if the one person we truly despise in the story got what he had coming to him. Spontenaity is a good thing, but all I could think about as the final act unfolded was how badly I hoped that the greedy businessman would finally come in contact with a beast infinitely more malicious than himself. Then there's the music, which alternates between stirring and grating. Particularly annoying is the decision to work some sort of elephant/hyena noise into what would be an otherwise memorable score. If it weren't for the final half hour and the previously mentioned sub- par musical renderings, it'd be safe to call The Ghost and the Darkness an underrated thriller. Instead it fizzles into a flabby shadow of its former self, much like a long coveted balloon that's held on until there's simply nothing left.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Some Lions, Coward Villagers and a Brave Boy!!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Ankit Dubey
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This title suits the movie well. A predictive and very childish kind of storyline, somewhat like bedtime stories to make children brave, which could have been done by a short 5 minutes story. Directed by Stephen Hopkins and Written By William Godman, this film is all about a character John Patterson an engineer, a bridge builder to be specific, who is the protagonist of the story, who takes a challenge of building a bridge in Africa, very confidently and with his wife pregnant and delivering a baby in six months. The job was assigned by a very rude and demotivating boss. The story moves around building of the bridge and some man-eater lions which created fear in the mind of people working there. And at the end of the movie, as one can predict, the hero killed the lions and thank god, the movie was over!! Despite a bad story, the direction is good. The background music is so real, that it creates such a superb horror effect in the mind of people that even if the movie was over you will feel the lions coming after you!! All the characters acted well, especially the hero. The best part of the movie which i liked the most was; cultural relations have been very beautiful shown in this movie, i.e. how to live and co-operate with people who are not like you. So the final verdict of the movie goes as, it's better to watch 'Man verses wild' on National Geographical than to waste time as well money in cinema hall.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Man-Eaters Of Tsavo
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bruce-wayne074
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie is a based on a true story about the man-eaters of Tsavo i like this movie very much i think story line was great and i think Val Kilmer and Michael Douglas did a great job its a great and 100 percent recommended if u haven't seen it yet go check it out guys its really one the best and have place on the list of my top 50 movies its really great some scenes are pretty scary man-eaters attacking the workers and dragged them out of their tents at night although Michael Douglas character was fictional but he did it very well and Val Kilmer the role Colonel John Patterson very its a great movie and i think best movie ever made about the man-eaters of Tsavo
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Awesome Movie, It's Like Jaws with Lions
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Luke Reeves
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/6/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This film is amazing a real gem. The scenery is spectacular, acting superb, great performances by the lions. A real masterpiece! Even better knowing it's a true story. The sound effects were fantastic, you really get a feel for what it must have been like being close to these dangerous monsters. Even the lions were afraid. On surround sound fairly loud, the roar and growls of the lions really makes an emotional impact. If you liked the film Jaws, you will definitely like this film. I was a bit worried about the killing of lions to be sad and depressing, because I really love lions. That's why it has taken me so long to see this film. However these lions really deserved it! They were nasty scary beasts and would make any vegetarian want to go back to eating meat. :D Anyway great film, another must see before you die type movie.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Safari Thriller with Big Cats
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    zardoz-13
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/5/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Director Stephen Hopkins' safari saga "The Ghost and the Darkness" is based on a true incident. Two bloodthirsty lions feasted on 130 native railroad laborers in Africa in the late 1890s. But it's an adventure tale with more growl than grandeur. Val Kilmer bares a pearly smile in his starring role as idealistic bridge builder Lieutenant Colonel John Patterson. As Patterson, he is assigned by his racist British tycoon boss, Robert Beaumont (Tom Wilkinson) to bridge Africa's Tsavo River within five months. As we learn, the Swahili word for Tsavo translates as "a place of slaughter." When Patterson arrives in Africa, his loyal African guide, Samuel (John Kani), warns him that nothing works in Tsavo. No sooner has work started than the lions strike. Patterson guns down one man-eater, but two more lions replace it. The natives call these savage cats "The Ghost and the Darkness." Michael Douglas co-stars as savvy lion killer Charles Remington. He arrives on the scene to help save the day, but he doesn't make his appearance until nearly halfway into the action. William Goldman's script errs in not bringing Douglas into the fray much earlier. Although confined to a role that is little more than an over-long cameo, Douglas dominates "The Ghost and the Darkness." Douglas' charismatic Remington easily upstages Kilmer's ponderous spit and polish Patterson. Compared to the elegant Patterson, Douglas resembles a shaggy villain from a 1970s era Italian western. Nevertheless, what distinguishes "The Ghost and the Darkness" are its cagey lions. These lions constantly elude and outwit our pair of heroes. If you saw the Robin Williams movie "Jumanji," the special effects here are just as incredible. Director Stephen Hopkins deploys these fantastic digital effects to stage a truly realistic lion attack on a crowd. Many close-up shots of gaping jaws and dark, hypnotic eyes bolster the suspense. An exciting confrontation that sends Kilmer scrambling up a tree with a lion nipping at his heels should get the adrenalin singing in your veins. Altogether, "The Ghost and the Darkness" succeeds more as a horror movie. The action never strays far from the bridge site so the movie seems rather claustrophobic. When "Ghost" isn't frightening, it creeps along with one too many campfire scenes. "Butch Cassidy and the Sundance Kid" scenarist William Goldman literate script sticks closely to the events of this true-life tragedy. Nevertheless, you wonder how they made the mistakes that they made. Patterson, for example, swaps rifles the night before the big hunt. When he confronts a lion, his gun misfires. The death of one character occurs off-screen, forcing you to fill in the gap and deprive both the audience and the characters with a memorable death scene. You can almost guess which character will be chomped because the filmmakers cast a halo around the person's head. Meanwhile, Hopkins and Goldman devise one genuinely shocking scene but cannot sustain this kind of momentum when the lions are on-screen. Hopkins deserves credit for making these lion attacks fully vicious without emphasizing the blood and gore.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A story of two demonic lions
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    david-sarkies
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is one absolutely awesome movie. It is about two man eating lions that plague a construction site of a bridge in Africa. These lions are no ordinary lions, they are vicious man eaters that do not conform to what lions are like. The natives call them demons, and as this is claimed to be a true story, this is biblically possible. But before I go into the theology of this, I wish to look at the movie first. This move is set in Africa at the turn of the century. There is a race with the other European countries, namely Germany, to colonise Africa. A bridge must be built so that the British can move further inland. When Val Kilmer's character first looks at the river he is amazed. He says that the wonder of building bridges is to put land over water. The bridge is also seen as a chain, or a manacle for the river. An unbridged river is an obstacle but a bridge makes this obstacle no more. The bridge tames the land for the river can no longer block the progress of man. But here the land seems to fight back. Right at the beginning, the first lion attacks and is killed with one bullet. Thus Val Kilmer comes out as a hero. Soon after the two lions, the Ghost and the Darkness, come and cause havoc in the campsite. No matter what they do they cannot stop these lions. A great hunter, Remington (Michael Douglas) comes along to help get rid of these lions. He believes them to be simple lions, but when his tribe leaves, he suddenly realises what he is up against. There is a very interesting scene, but to tell you about it would give something away. These lions are considered demons by the natives, and in my mind this is possible. If we look in the Gospels of Matthew, Mark, and Luke, there is the story of the man possessed by the demon legion (he is called legion because he is many). The demon pleads with Christ not to send them back to hell so Christ sends them into a herd of swine. This shows us that demons can manifest themselves in animals as well as in humans. With this in mind, the animal kingdom is not as weak as we make it out to be. These lions were intelligent and would torment their enemies and then turn and indiscriminately kill. If you watch the hospital scene you will note that they kill everybody but do not take anybody away to eat. As Remington says, "they do it for the pleasure of it." Even though they are demons, they are still lions, as the swine were still swine. Just because they were possessed did not mean they were unkillable. The soul cannot be destroyed but the body can. The swine ran into the lake and were drowned, the lions were also vulnerable in the same way. This movie comes out as a horror movie, but it is far more than that. There is not ghosts or demons running about, just two lions. The natives call them evil, and that they are, but the movie is real, or so it claims. This really happened and thus can happen to us. A horror movie comes across as being unreal. We can leave a horror movie at the end and be comforted that it is not real. This was. The only comfort we have is that the lions are dead.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "If you lock eyes with them, you will be afraid."
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Frederick Smith
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Since the film was shot in South Africa, the scenery is exceptional. Like all docudramas, an amount of license was taken. Micheal Douglas' part in the film is fictional, but very well played and adds to the suspense of the movie. Val Kilmer gives a very quiet but determined air to the role and is supported by excellent performances by John Kani, Om Puri, and Henry Cele, all essential character actors who bring the proper balance of ethnicity and culture to the film. Tom Wilkinson plays Robert Beaumont, a man dedicated to advancing his position to the throne ("I care about my Knighthood!"), across the backs of the people he assigns the tasks. He is a self described Monster who can either make or break a career, and has no qualms about either. Overall the film is matter of fact and very ordinary, but what cannot be denied is that this happened. I have been to the Field Museum and seen the Lions of Tsavo. It is as the last line of the movie says. "If you lock eyes with them, you will be afraid." Lots of gory scenes make this unsuitable for the children, but most teens have seen worse on their video games. Not necessarily collectible, but certainly worth a viewing, especially if you enjoy Kilmer and Douglas.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Could have been great if... (possible spoilers)
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ADG999
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/12/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    ...This incredible true story could have been much, much better than it was, but choppy editing, inconsistent direction, less-than-great cinematography,and the questionable plot decision to add a fictional American big game hunter to "help" Patterson hunt the lions, made this movie less than it could have been. The fact is that, in real life, Patterson (SPOILER) killed both lions himself, and frankly I think it would have been a better movie if they had written the script to reflect that. The Remington character always seemed somewhat out of place to me, and when I realized he was just a device added by the writers, for reasons that I still can't fathom, I understood why. Maybe they were afraid Val Kilmer could not carry the movie on his own--frankly, I think he could have with no problem. Maybe it was because Michael Douglas was an executive producer on the film, and wanted to be in the movie. Whatever the reason, this movie goes on my list of "missed opportunities" to make a really great film. Eight stars, only because I love the story, and love what the movie could have been.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Jaws in Africa
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Roland Jakobsson (rolandddd)
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The story of how two man-eating lions delayed the construction of a railway bridge in Tsavo, Kenya in 1898, is one that fascinates me. The film is loosely based on the biographical account of Lt Col John Henry Patterson, played by Val Kilmer in the movie. Though the original story is decently written and very exciting to read, it is also clearly a work of its time, and some of the more racist undertones of the original short story has wisely been omitted from the film. Halfway through the story something very strange happens. Being at least reasonably true to Patterson's account until then, the movie transforms into a carbon copy of Jaws! Suddenly throwing aside Patterson's story and all ties to reality, fictitious character Remington is introduced, horribly portrayed by Michael Douglas. This legendary huntsman is clearly the equivalent of Jaws's Quint, but unfortunately Douglas OTT-acting doesn't even come close to matching Robert Shaw's performance. Despite the movie's obvious ambition to be a Jaws set in Africa (even down to the POV shots of the lions stalking their prey), I think lots of things work well. The ambition to emulate Jaws is at least partly successful, and the movie has some great suspenseful scenes. The extensive use of real lions Caesar and Bongo and very little animatronics means that the predator scenes look great, and I think the film benefits from being made in the mid-nineties with basically no CGI. The scenery (South Africa substituting for Kenya) looks stunning and the film is wonderfully shot, and together with the realistic animal this makes the movie look really good. The acting, apart from Douglas, is also solid with Kilmer being backed up by a strong supporting cast of Tom Wilkinson, Bernard Hill and Emily Mortimer to name a few. Overall, I have a soft spot for "monster" movies and even though this has many flaws I think it is really entertaining and well worth watching!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    This movie was terrible.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Tekki Kiraito
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I was forced to watch this piece of garbage in English class and I did not find anything about it enjoyable. It is heavy on the violence and gore which I do not think is acceptable for a high school English course. I do not appreciate being forced to watch something that greatly disturbs me for a course that is mandatory. This movie was filled with lots of historical inaccuracies. Some of the people in this film, such as Remington, didn't even exist! The film just felt like a cheap slasher trying to be something it's not. If you are truly interested in this event, I recommend reading Patterson's book. In short, skip this piece of garbage. It's not worth your time.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "Lion" in Wait
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    flowersflix
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Here I am again, reviewing yet another "man vs. nature" movie. This time, we've got two seemingly demon possessed lions murdering railroad workers in turn of the century Uganda. Our hero is John Patterson (Val Kilmer), a contractor hired by a wealthy (and ruthless) tycoon to oversee construction of a bridge that will bolster commerce in the region. When the murderous lions in question begin terrorizingand maimingJohn's workers, something's got to be done (especially when they all flee at the suspicion that he's brought about a curse on the area). Cue the entrance of Charles Remington (Michael Douglas), a world- renowned hunter who's the embodiment of the old-school, no-holds-barred, shotgun-toting, Hemingway-esque man's man. Director Stephen Hopkins decides the go the route of Jaws, as it's rare that we're given a clean, full frame shot of the "monsters." This turns out to be a great decision, as it adds to the suspense when we see a silhouette (or think we see one) moving stealthily among the rippling, waist high savanna. In that regard, there's no denying that The Ghost and the Darkness delivers the goods in the "suspense" department. Unfortunately, the film does have its problems. First and foremost is the entirely too abrupt conclusion, which, quite honestly, feels sloppy and rushed. After all we've been through with Patterson and Remington, one would expect a grand finale that heightens the tension to unbearable levels. Instead we get something like a watered down version of the velociraptor kitchen scene in Jurassic Park. There's also the lack of satisfaction that could have been delivered if the one person we truly despise in the story got what he had coming to him. Spontenaity is a good thing, but all I could think about as the final act unfolded was how badly I hoped that the greedy businessman would finally come in contact with a beast infinitely more malicious than himself. Then there's the music, which alternates between stirring and grating. Particularly annoying is the decision to work some sort of elephant/hyena noise into what would be an otherwise memorable score. If it weren't for the final half hour and the previously mentioned sub- par musical renderings, it'd be safe to call The Ghost and the Darkness an underrated thriller. Instead it fizzles into a flabby shadow of its former self, much like a long coveted balloon that's held on until there's simply nothing left.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Some Lions, Coward Villagers and a Brave Boy!!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Ankit Dubey
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This title suits the movie well. A predictive and very childish kind of storyline, somewhat like bedtime stories to make children brave, which could have been done by a short 5 minutes story. Directed by Stephen Hopkins and Written By William Godman, this film is all about a character John Patterson an engineer, a bridge builder to be specific, who is the protagonist of the story, who takes a challenge of building a bridge in Africa, very confidently and with his wife pregnant and delivering a baby in six months. The job was assigned by a very rude and demotivating boss. The story moves around building of the bridge and some man-eater lions which created fear in the mind of people working there. And at the end of the movie, as one can predict, the hero killed the lions and thank god, the movie was over!! Despite a bad story, the direction is good. The background music is so real, that it creates such a superb horror effect in the mind of people that even if the movie was over you will feel the lions coming after you!! All the characters acted well, especially the hero. The best part of the movie which i liked the most was; cultural relations have been very beautiful shown in this movie, i.e. how to live and co-operate with people who are not like you. So the final verdict of the movie goes as, it's better to watch 'Man verses wild' on National Geographical than to waste time as well money in cinema hall.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Man-Eaters Of Tsavo
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bruce-wayne074
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie is a based on a true story about the man-eaters of Tsavo i like this movie very much i think story line was great and i think Val Kilmer and Michael Douglas did a great job its a great and 100 percent recommended if u haven't seen it yet go check it out guys its really one the best and have place on the list of my top 50 movies its really great some scenes are pretty scary man-eaters attacking the workers and dragged them out of their tents at night although Michael Douglas character was fictional but he did it very well and Val Kilmer the role Colonel John Patterson very its a great movie and i think best movie ever made about the man-eaters of Tsavo
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Awesome Movie, It's Like Jaws with Lions
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Luke Reeves
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/6/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This film is amazing a real gem. The scenery is spectacular, acting superb, great performances by the lions. A real masterpiece! Even better knowing it's a true story. The sound effects were fantastic, you really get a feel for what it must have been like being close to these dangerous monsters. Even the lions were afraid. On surround sound fairly loud, the roar and growls of the lions really makes an emotional impact. If you liked the film Jaws, you will definitely like this film. I was a bit worried about the killing of lions to be sad and depressing, because I really love lions. That's why it has taken me so long to see this film. However these lions really deserved it! They were nasty scary beasts and would make any vegetarian want to go back to eating meat. :D Anyway great film, another must see before you die type movie.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Safari Thriller with Big Cats
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    zardoz-13
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/5/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Director Stephen Hopkins' safari saga "The Ghost and the Darkness" is based on a true incident. Two bloodthirsty lions feasted on 130 native railroad laborers in Africa in the late 1890s. But it's an adventure tale with more growl than grandeur. Val Kilmer bares a pearly smile in his starring role as idealistic bridge builder Lieutenant Colonel John Patterson. As Patterson, he is assigned by his racist British tycoon boss, Robert Beaumont (Tom Wilkinson) to bridge Africa's Tsavo River within five months. As we learn, the Swahili word for Tsavo translates as "a place of slaughter." When Patterson arrives in Africa, his loyal African guide, Samuel (John Kani), warns him that nothing works in Tsavo. No sooner has work started than the lions strike. Patterson guns down one man-eater, but two more lions replace it. The natives call these savage cats "The Ghost and the Darkness." Michael Douglas co-stars as savvy lion killer Charles Remington. He arrives on the scene to help save the day, but he doesn't make his appearance until nearly halfway into the action. William Goldman's script errs in not bringing Douglas into the fray much earlier. Although confined to a role that is little more than an over-long cameo, Douglas dominates "The Ghost and the Darkness." Douglas' charismatic Remington easily upstages Kilmer's ponderous spit and polish Patterson. Compared to the elegant Patterson, Douglas resembles a shaggy villain from a 1970s era Italian western. Nevertheless, what distinguishes "The Ghost and the Darkness" are its cagey lions. These lions constantly elude and outwit our pair of heroes. If you saw the Robin Williams movie "Jumanji," the special effects here are just as incredible. Director Stephen Hopkins deploys these fantastic digital effects to stage a truly realistic lion attack on a crowd. Many close-up shots of gaping jaws and dark, hypnotic eyes bolster the suspense. An exciting confrontation that sends Kilmer scrambling up a tree with a lion nipping at his heels should get the adrenalin singing in your veins. Altogether, "The Ghost and the Darkness" succeeds more as a horror movie. The action never strays far from the bridge site so the movie seems rather claustrophobic. When "Ghost" isn't frightening, it creeps along with one too many campfire scenes. "Butch Cassidy and the Sundance Kid" scenarist William Goldman literate script sticks closely to the events of this true-life tragedy. Nevertheless, you wonder how they made the mistakes that they made. Patterson, for example, swaps rifles the night before the big hunt. When he confronts a lion, his gun misfires. The death of one character occurs off-screen, forcing you to fill in the gap and deprive both the audience and the characters with a memorable death scene. You can almost guess which character will be chomped because the filmmakers cast a halo around the person's head. Meanwhile, Hopkins and Goldman devise one genuinely shocking scene but cannot sustain this kind of momentum when the lions are on-screen. Hopkins deserves credit for making these lion attacks fully vicious without emphasizing the blood and gore.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A story of two demonic lions
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    david-sarkies
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is one absolutely awesome movie. It is about two man eating lions that plague a construction site of a bridge in Africa. These lions are no ordinary lions, they are vicious man eaters that do not conform to what lions are like. The natives call them demons, and as this is claimed to be a true story, this is biblically possible. But before I go into the theology of this, I wish to look at the movie first. This move is set in Africa at the turn of the century. There is a race with the other European countries, namely Germany, to colonise Africa. A bridge must be built so that the British can move further inland. When Val Kilmer's character first looks at the river he is amazed. He says that the wonder of building bridges is to put land over water. The bridge is also seen as a chain, or a manacle for the river. An unbridged river is an obstacle but a bridge makes this obstacle no more. The bridge tames the land for the river can no longer block the progress of man. But here the land seems to fight back. Right at the beginning, the first lion attacks and is killed with one bullet. Thus Val Kilmer comes out as a hero. Soon after the two lions, the Ghost and the Darkness, come and cause havoc in the campsite. No matter what they do they cannot stop these lions. A great hunter, Remington (Michael Douglas) comes along to help get rid of these lions. He believes them to be simple lions, but when his tribe leaves, he suddenly realises what he is up against. There is a very interesting scene, but to tell you about it would give something away. These lions are considered demons by the natives, and in my mind this is possible. If we look in the Gospels of Matthew, Mark, and Luke, there is the story of the man possessed by the demon legion (he is called legion because he is many). The demon pleads with Christ not to send them back to hell so Christ sends them into a herd of swine. This shows us that demons can manifest themselves in animals as well as in humans. With this in mind, the animal kingdom is not as weak as we make it out to be. These lions were intelligent and would torment their enemies and then turn and indiscriminately kill. If you watch the hospital scene you will note that they kill everybody but do not take anybody away to eat. As Remington says, "they do it for the pleasure of it." Even though they are demons, they are still lions, as the swine were still swine. Just because they were possessed did not mean they were unkillable. The soul cannot be destroyed but the body can. The swine ran into the lake and were drowned, the lions were also vulnerable in the same way. This movie comes out as a horror movie, but it is far more than that. There is not ghosts or demons running about, just two lions. The natives call them evil, and that they are, but the movie is real, or so it claims. This really happened and thus can happen to us. A horror movie comes across as being unreal. We can leave a horror movie at the end and be comforted that it is not real. This was. The only comfort we have is that the lions are dead.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "If you lock eyes with them, you will be afraid."
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Frederick Smith
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Since the film was shot in South Africa, the scenery is exceptional. Like all docudramas, an amount of license was taken. Micheal Douglas' part in the film is fictional, but very well played and adds to the suspense of the movie. Val Kilmer gives a very quiet but determined air to the role and is supported by excellent performances by John Kani, Om Puri, and Henry Cele, all essential character actors who bring the proper balance of ethnicity and culture to the film. Tom Wilkinson plays Robert Beaumont, a man dedicated to advancing his position to the throne ("I care about my Knighthood!"), across the backs of the people he assigns the tasks. He is a self described Monster who can either make or break a career, and has no qualms about either. Overall the film is matter of fact and very ordinary, but what cannot be denied is that this happened. I have been to the Field Museum and seen the Lions of Tsavo. It is as the last line of the movie says. "If you lock eyes with them, you will be afraid." Lots of gory scenes make this unsuitable for the children, but most teens have seen worse on their video games. Not necessarily collectible, but certainly worth a viewing, especially if you enjoy Kilmer and Douglas.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Could have been great if... (possible spoilers)
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ADG999
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/12/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    ...This incredible true story could have been much, much better than it was, but choppy editing, inconsistent direction, less-than-great cinematography,and the questionable plot decision to add a fictional American big game hunter to "help" Patterson hunt the lions, made this movie less than it could have been. The fact is that, in real life, Patterson (SPOILER) killed both lions himself, and frankly I think it would have been a better movie if they had written the script to reflect that. The Remington character always seemed somewhat out of place to me, and when I realized he was just a device added by the writers, for reasons that I still can't fathom, I understood why. Maybe they were afraid Val Kilmer could not carry the movie on his own--frankly, I think he could have with no problem. Maybe it was because Michael Douglas was an executive producer on the film, and wanted to be in the movie. Whatever the reason, this movie goes on my list of "missed opportunities" to make a really great film. Eight stars, only because I love the story, and love what the movie could have been.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Jaws in Africa
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Roland Jakobsson (rolandddd)
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The story of how two man-eating lions delayed the construction of a railway bridge in Tsavo, Kenya in 1898, is one that fascinates me. The film is loosely based on the biographical account of Lt Col John Henry Patterson, played by Val Kilmer in the movie. Though the original story is decently written and very exciting to read, it is also clearly a work of its time, and some of the more racist undertones of the original short story has wisely been omitted from the film. Halfway through the story something very strange happens. Being at least reasonably true to Patterson's account until then, the movie transforms into a carbon copy of Jaws! Suddenly throwing aside Patterson's story and all ties to reality, fictitious character Remington is introduced, horribly portrayed by Michael Douglas. This legendary huntsman is clearly the equivalent of Jaws's Quint, but unfortunately Douglas OTT-acting doesn't even come close to matching Robert Shaw's performance. Despite the movie's obvious ambition to be a Jaws set in Africa (even down to the POV shots of the lions stalking their prey), I think lots of things work well. The ambition to emulate Jaws is at least partly successful, and the movie has some great suspenseful scenes. The extensive use of real lions Caesar and Bongo and very little animatronics means that the predator scenes look great, and I think the film benefits from being made in the mid-nineties with basically no CGI. The scenery (South Africa substituting for Kenya) looks stunning and the film is wonderfully shot, and together with the realistic animal this makes the movie look really good. The acting, apart from Douglas, is also solid with Kilmer being backed up by a strong supporting cast of Tom Wilkinson, Bernard Hill and Emily Mortimer to name a few. Overall, I have a soft spot for "monster" movies and even though this has many flaws I think it is really entertaining and well worth watching!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    This movie was terrible.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Tekki Kiraito
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I was forced to watch this piece of garbage in English class and I did not find anything about it enjoyable. It is heavy on the violence and gore which I do not think is acceptable for a high school English course. I do not appreciate being forced to watch something that greatly disturbs me for a course that is mandatory. This movie was filled with lots of historical inaccuracies. Some of the people in this film, such as Remington, didn't even exist! The film just felt like a cheap slasher trying to be something it's not. If you are truly interested in this event, I recommend reading Patterson's book. In short, skip this piece of garbage. It's not worth your time.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "Lion" in Wait
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    flowersflix
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Here I am again, reviewing yet another "man vs. nature" movie. This time, we've got two seemingly demon possessed lions murdering railroad workers in turn of the century Uganda. Our hero is John Patterson (Val Kilmer), a contractor hired by a wealthy (and ruthless) tycoon to oversee construction of a bridge that will bolster commerce in the region. When the murderous lions in question begin terrorizingand maimingJohn's workers, something's got to be done (especially when they all flee at the suspicion that he's brought about a curse on the area). Cue the entrance of Charles Remington (Michael Douglas), a world- renowned hunter who's the embodiment of the old-school, no-holds-barred, shotgun-toting, Hemingway-esque man's man. Director Stephen Hopkins decides the go the route of Jaws, as it's rare that we're given a clean, full frame shot of the "monsters." This turns out to be a great decision, as it adds to the suspense when we see a silhouette (or think we see one) moving stealthily among the rippling, waist high savanna. In that regard, there's no denying that The Ghost and the Darkness delivers the goods in the "suspense" department. Unfortunately, the film does have its problems. First and foremost is the entirely too abrupt conclusion, which, quite honestly, feels sloppy and rushed. After all we've been through with Patterson and Remington, one would expect a grand finale that heightens the tension to unbearable levels. Instead we get something like a watered down version of the velociraptor kitchen scene in Jurassic Park. There's also the lack of satisfaction that could have been delivered if the one person we truly despise in the story got what he had coming to him. Spontenaity is a good thing, but all I could think about as the final act unfolded was how badly I hoped that the greedy businessman would finally come in contact with a beast infinitely more malicious than himself. Then there's the music, which alternates between stirring and grating. Particularly annoying is the decision to work some sort of elephant/hyena noise into what would be an otherwise memorable score. If it weren't for the final half hour and the previously mentioned sub- par musical renderings, it'd be safe to call The Ghost and the Darkness an underrated thriller. Instead it fizzles into a flabby shadow of its former self, much like a long coveted balloon that's held on until there's simply nothing left.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Some Lions, Coward Villagers and a Brave Boy!!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Ankit Dubey
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This title suits the movie well. A predictive and very childish kind of storyline, somewhat like bedtime stories to make children brave, which could have been done by a short 5 minutes story. Directed by Stephen Hopkins and Written By William Godman, this film is all about a character John Patterson an engineer, a bridge builder to be specific, who is the protagonist of the story, who takes a challenge of building a bridge in Africa, very confidently and with his wife pregnant and delivering a baby in six months. The job was assigned by a very rude and demotivating boss. The story moves around building of the bridge and some man-eater lions which created fear in the mind of people working there. And at the end of the movie, as one can predict, the hero killed the lions and thank god, the movie was over!! Despite a bad story, the direction is good. The background music is so real, that it creates such a superb horror effect in the mind of people that even if the movie was over you will feel the lions coming after you!! All the characters acted well, especially the hero. The best part of the movie which i liked the most was; cultural relations have been very beautiful shown in this movie, i.e. how to live and co-operate with people who are not like you. So the final verdict of the movie goes as, it's better to watch 'Man verses wild' on National Geographical than to waste time as well money in cinema hall.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Man-Eaters Of Tsavo
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bruce-wayne074
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie is a based on a true story about the man-eaters of Tsavo i like this movie very much i think story line was great and i think Val Kilmer and Michael Douglas did a great job its a great and 100 percent recommended if u haven't seen it yet go check it out guys its really one the best and have place on the list of my top 50 movies its really great some scenes are pretty scary man-eaters attacking the workers and dragged them out of their tents at night although Michael Douglas character was fictional but he did it very well and Val Kilmer the role Colonel John Patterson very its a great movie and i think best movie ever made about the man-eaters of Tsavo
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Awesome Movie, It's Like Jaws with Lions
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Luke Reeves
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/6/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This film is amazing a real gem. The scenery is spectacular, acting superb, great performances by the lions. A real masterpiece! Even better knowing it's a true story. The sound effects were fantastic, you really get a feel for what it must have been like being close to these dangerous monsters. Even the lions were afraid. On surround sound fairly loud, the roar and growls of the lions really makes an emotional impact. If you liked the film Jaws, you will definitely like this film. I was a bit worried about the killing of lions to be sad and depressing, because I really love lions. That's why it has taken me so long to see this film. However these lions really deserved it! They were nasty scary beasts and would make any vegetarian want to go back to eating meat. :D Anyway great film, another must see before you die type movie.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Safari Thriller with Big Cats
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    zardoz-13
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/5/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Director Stephen Hopkins' safari saga "The Ghost and the Darkness" is based on a true incident. Two bloodthirsty lions feasted on 130 native railroad laborers in Africa in the late 1890s. But it's an adventure tale with more growl than grandeur. Val Kilmer bares a pearly smile in his starring role as idealistic bridge builder Lieutenant Colonel John Patterson. As Patterson, he is assigned by his racist British tycoon boss, Robert Beaumont (Tom Wilkinson) to bridge Africa's Tsavo River within five months. As we learn, the Swahili word for Tsavo translates as "a place of slaughter." When Patterson arrives in Africa, his loyal African guide, Samuel (John Kani), warns him that nothing works in Tsavo. No sooner has work started than the lions strike. Patterson guns down one man-eater, but two more lions replace it. The natives call these savage cats "The Ghost and the Darkness." Michael Douglas co-stars as savvy lion killer Charles Remington. He arrives on the scene to help save the day, but he doesn't make his appearance until nearly halfway into the action. William Goldman's script errs in not bringing Douglas into the fray much earlier. Although confined to a role that is little more than an over-long cameo, Douglas dominates "The Ghost and the Darkness." Douglas' charismatic Remington easily upstages Kilmer's ponderous spit and polish Patterson. Compared to the elegant Patterson, Douglas resembles a shaggy villain from a 1970s era Italian western. Nevertheless, what distinguishes "The Ghost and the Darkness" are its cagey lions. These lions constantly elude and outwit our pair of heroes. If you saw the Robin Williams movie "Jumanji," the special effects here are just as incredible. Director Stephen Hopkins deploys these fantastic digital effects to stage a truly realistic lion attack on a crowd. Many close-up shots of gaping jaws and dark, hypnotic eyes bolster the suspense. An exciting confrontation that sends Kilmer scrambling up a tree with a lion nipping at his heels should get the adrenalin singing in your veins. Altogether, "The Ghost and the Darkness" succeeds more as a horror movie. The action never strays far from the bridge site so the movie seems rather claustrophobic. When "Ghost" isn't frightening, it creeps along with one too many campfire scenes. "Butch Cassidy and the Sundance Kid" scenarist William Goldman literate script sticks closely to the events of this true-life tragedy. Nevertheless, you wonder how they made the mistakes that they made. Patterson, for example, swaps rifles the night before the big hunt. When he confronts a lion, his gun misfires. The death of one character occurs off-screen, forcing you to fill in the gap and deprive both the audience and the characters with a memorable death scene. You can almost guess which character will be chomped because the filmmakers cast a halo around the person's head. Meanwhile, Hopkins and Goldman devise one genuinely shocking scene but cannot sustain this kind of momentum when the lions are on-screen. Hopkins deserves credit for making these lion attacks fully vicious without emphasizing the blood and gore.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A story of two demonic lions
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    david-sarkies
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is one absolutely awesome movie. It is about two man eating lions that plague a construction site of a bridge in Africa. These lions are no ordinary lions, they are vicious man eaters that do not conform to what lions are like. The natives call them demons, and as this is claimed to be a true story, this is biblically possible. But before I go into the theology of this, I wish to look at the movie first. This move is set in Africa at the turn of the century. There is a race with the other European countries, namely Germany, to colonise Africa. A bridge must be built so that the British can move further inland. When Val Kilmer's character first looks at the river he is amazed. He says that the wonder of building bridges is to put land over water. The bridge is also seen as a chain, or a manacle for the river. An unbridged river is an obstacle but a bridge makes this obstacle no more. The bridge tames the land for the river can no longer block the progress of man. But here the land seems to fight back. Right at the beginning, the first lion attacks and is killed with one bullet. Thus Val Kilmer comes out as a hero. Soon after the two lions, the Ghost and the Darkness, come and cause havoc in the campsite. No matter what they do they cannot stop these lions. A great hunter, Remington (Michael Douglas) comes along to help get rid of these lions. He believes them to be simple lions, but when his tribe leaves, he suddenly realises what he is up against. There is a very interesting scene, but to tell you about it would give something away. These lions are considered demons by the natives, and in my mind this is possible. If we look in the Gospels of Matthew, Mark, and Luke, there is the story of the man possessed by the demon legion (he is called legion because he is many). The demon pleads with Christ not to send them back to hell so Christ sends them into a herd of swine. This shows us that demons can manifest themselves in animals as well as in humans. With this in mind, the animal kingdom is not as weak as we make it out to be. These lions were intelligent and would torment their enemies and then turn and indiscriminately kill. If you watch the hospital scene you will note that they kill everybody but do not take anybody away to eat. As Remington says, "they do it for the pleasure of it." Even though they are demons, they are still lions, as the swine were still swine. Just because they were possessed did not mean they were unkillable. The soul cannot be destroyed but the body can. The swine ran into the lake and were drowned, the lions were also vulnerable in the same way. This movie comes out as a horror movie, but it is far more than that. There is not ghosts or demons running about, just two lions. The natives call them evil, and that they are, but the movie is real, or so it claims. This really happened and thus can happen to us. A horror movie comes across as being unreal. We can leave a horror movie at the end and be comforted that it is not real. This was. The only comfort we have is that the lions are dead.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "If you lock eyes with them, you will be afraid."
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Frederick Smith
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Since the film was shot in South Africa, the scenery is exceptional. Like all docudramas, an amount of license was taken. Micheal Douglas' part in the film is fictional, but very well played and adds to the suspense of the movie. Val Kilmer gives a very quiet but determined air to the role and is supported by excellent performances by John Kani, Om Puri, and Henry Cele, all essential character actors who bring the proper balance of ethnicity and culture to the film. Tom Wilkinson plays Robert Beaumont, a man dedicated to advancing his position to the throne ("I care about my Knighthood!"), across the backs of the people he assigns the tasks. He is a self described Monster who can either make or break a career, and has no qualms about either. Overall the film is matter of fact and very ordinary, but what cannot be denied is that this happened. I have been to the Field Museum and seen the Lions of Tsavo. It is as the last line of the movie says. "If you lock eyes with them, you will be afraid." Lots of gory scenes make this unsuitable for the children, but most teens have seen worse on their video games. Not necessarily collectible, but certainly worth a viewing, especially if you enjoy Kilmer and Douglas.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Could have been great if... (possible spoilers)
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ADG999
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/12/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    ...This incredible true story could have been much, much better than it was, but choppy editing, inconsistent direction, less-than-great cinematography,and the questionable plot decision to add a fictional American big game hunter to "help" Patterson hunt the lions, made this movie less than it could have been. The fact is that, in real life, Patterson (SPOILER) killed both lions himself, and frankly I think it would have been a better movie if they had written the script to reflect that. The Remington character always seemed somewhat out of place to me, and when I realized he was just a device added by the writers, for reasons that I still can't fathom, I understood why. Maybe they were afraid Val Kilmer could not carry the movie on his own--frankly, I think he could have with no problem. Maybe it was because Michael Douglas was an executive producer on the film, and wanted to be in the movie. Whatever the reason, this movie goes on my list of "missed opportunities" to make a really great film. Eight stars, only because I love the story, and love what the movie could have been.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
 </reviews>
</filme>
