<filme>
 <id>
  1481
 </id>
 <imdburl>
  http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0111048
 </imdburl>
 <ano>
  1994
 </ano>
 <titulo>
  S.F.W. - Filhos da Viol&ecirc;ncia
 </titulo>
 <rating>
  5.6
 </rating>
 <sinopse>
  An alienated and misanthropic teenager gains sudden and unwanted celebrity status after he's taken hostage by terrorists where his indifference to their threats to kill him makes news headlines.
 </sinopse>
 <storyline>
  Cliff Spab is a guy who doesn't really care about anything. He gets held hostage at a store for 36 days by terrorists, who demand that the entire thing be broadcast on national television. Cliff ends up taking a bullet for fellow hostage Wendy - making him a national hero. The two are the sole survivors of the ordeal, and soon become prisoners of the media. Cliff escapes it all, only to find himself being pushed further away from Wendy when he needs her most.
 </storyline>
 <generos>
  <genero>
   Comedy
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Drama
  </genero>
 </generos>
 <keywords>
  <keyword>
   hostage
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   celebrity
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   television
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   teenager
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   media
  </keyword>
 </keywords>
 <diretores>
  <diretor>
   Jefery Levy
  </diretor>
 </diretores>
 <escritores>
  <escritor>
   Andrew Wellman
  </escritor>
  <escritor>
   Danny Rubin
  </escritor>
 </escritores>
 <atores>
  <ator>
   Stephen Dorff
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Reese Witherspoon
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Jake Busey
  </ator>
 </atores>
 <reviews>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Takes you back to a specific and forgotten style point in the 90's
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    xynphix
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I had high hopes for this movie but was totally disappointed upon seeing it. For how much I didn't like it, something about this movie stuck with me ten years later, looking back I've created a more interesting version of what this movie COULD have been in my head, It put me on the edge of wanting to believe that it was a poor man's Oliver Stone movie. The most intriguing thing about this movie is that watching it puts you in a specific time and place, a short lived style in the early to mid 90's that seems like a twilight zone dream. It captures something about that time that very few movies have done. Other than that quality, the plot, which starts off great slowly rolls down an incline and falls flat off a cliff. The characters almost have depth and catch your interest right from the start but end up over the top annoying, especially the main character Spab. By the end of the movie, he's lost any redeeming quality and Joey Lauren Adams character's continual whining becomes like nails on a chalk board. Having had no background knowledge of this movie upon seeing it, I really thought that Kevin Smith was somehow involved because it has the same feel of his early work and uses a few of the same actors. All in all, this could have been a memorable movie, far ahead of it's time with it's depiction of reality TV and media sensationalism but in reality, was really just a big waste of time.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Real Meaning- A Good/Bad Movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    rjkeenan
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Yes, the acting and directing were a little inconsistent, and some of the lines were sophomoric and occasionally downright lame, but the value of the movie lays in it's overall existentialist theme. Cliff Spab doesn't care about the consequences of anything- he's smokes, he drinks, he curses, doesn't care about bettering himself, doesn't really care about the way he looks, and isn't afraid of anything- not even death. Is it because he was overlooked, abused, etc.? Not really. Cliff doesn't revel in fame or attention when he gets it, but rather treats it as a joke because it simply doesn't matter (even if he half enjoys it), hence the phrase "So Fu.... What." The importance of this phrase points to the notion that nothing really matters in life. Someone can get the best grades, go to the best schools, watch their weight, be good to others, always do right, gain fame and notoriety...or they can be shot in the head in the middle of a store robbery. In the grand scheme of things it really doesn't matter. Quoting Chuck Palahniuk, "On a long enough time-line, the survival rate for everyone drops to zero." Our existence in our solar system, in our galaxy, in the universe is a spec of dust on a spec of dust on a spec of dust, hence SFW (nothing really matters). The black comedy and satire of this movie comes from the doting media and fans of Cliff Spab. It's not that they really love him, they are just looking for an answer- a motto to guide their lives. But, as in real life, something seemingly meaningful to you one moment becomes a useless fad in the next moment. In the conclusion of the movie Barbara Wyler tries to shoot Cliff or something (it's really been years), and states her tag-line "Everything matters!" It's the complete opposite theory of Cliff's. Her essential meaning is that everything we do has an affect on the future, future generations, the overall makeup of things on our planet, etc. Her message could be looked at as kind of good, but the irony lies in the fact that she seems all too excited to step directly into Cliff's shoes and be another meaningless, short-lived role model. In essence Cliff was right when he believed nothing matters and Barbara's time in the spotlight will also fade away. One day neither will be remembered and will have no affect on anything or anyone. Even those that followed them for a brief time will be gone and forgotten. It's a sad story of the media misguiding people to waste their short lives with whatever's popular and meaningless in the moment. But, it also questions, if nothing really matters anyway, SFW.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Does Generation X really matter?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    FlashCallahan
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Cliff Spab doesn't really care about anything. He gets held hostage at a store for 36 days by terrorists, who demand that the entire thing be broadcast on national television. Cliff ends up taking a bullet for fellow hostage Wendy - making him a national hero. The two are the sole survivors of the ordeal, and soon become prisoners of the media. Cliff escapes it all, only to find himself being pushed further away from Wendy when he needs her most.... Once you get past the fact that Dorff sounds uncannily like Christian Slater, you get another one of those films from the mid nineties that tried to define good old 'generation X'. And for the most part, it works. Dorff is great as the guy who is having his fifteen minutes of fame, but cannot decipher why people are not mentioning his friend who was killed. But this was a time when media only really dwelled on the good stuff, to sugar coat the public, to get more money behind their new 'celeb' The film doesn't know what genre it belongs to. One minute it's hilarious, next it's soul searching, and then it goes for a Araki/Solondz hybrid that baffles. But it's good, and all the performances are great, I just wish it didn't get lost in its own smugness every now and again. The last fifteen minutes is great though, showing us how fickle the media were/are, and how fame really slips through your fingers, once a new fad has been found. Everything Matters? S.F.W...
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Disappointed that this isn't a Natural Born Killers re-imagining
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    nathanschubach
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Well what can I say about this? It came out when I was still a teenager, and it had all of the elements of the 1990s that kids were getting into because, according to the majority of media outlets, we were the jaded generation that believed in nothing other than grunge music, being pains in the butt for adults, and rocking out without a care in the world. Every generation does this, but this was our version of "Steal This Movie." And while most of that attitude was true and around at the time, you can see how much the creative lines were blurred when you had movies like "S.F.W." coming out and trying to cash in on these trends. Wayne's World, Tank Girl, Beavis & Butthead, Slacker, Clerks, Mall Rats, Natural Born Killers, Drugstore Cowboy, Pump Up the Volume, Bill & Ted's, Singles, Reality Bites, Empire Records...hell, even Ferris Bueller's Day Off had its similar message in the 80s. So what's one more, right? First off, the movie is ridiculous. The premise (without spoiling it) is thin, unbelievable, and needed a lot of retooling (if the whole screenplay was adapted from a book, and if it was, the book's probably not much better). Even more than "Singles," this movie tries to cram grunge music into every nook and cranny to remind you how street-level Reese Witherspoon and Stephen Dorff's character are (along with their friends), but then they make a weird, Disney-moment every time Dorff's character ("Cliff Spab"...AKA the worst name to be repeated EVER) reminisces about their friend. I'm not going to say what happens, but every time Spab contemplates what went down with his friend, music bussed in from the movie "E.T." gets played, and we're supposed to feel bad for some reason (why, i don't know because Spab wasn't all that close with him in the beginning of the movie or in other scenes either). Secondly, the objective seemed to make sense, that the media and relatives try and cash in from those around them who become famous...but the message easily becomes turned around on the movie itself for cashing in on the attitudes of cynical youths who are biting the bait that this movie produces. Third, it should stay a cult movie and nothing more. It's not Dazed & Confused, and it's not Natural Born Killers. The subjects of this movie became lucky in the film to be celebrities due to a minor news story that realistically would never had happened in real life, and if they would have, people wouldn't give the story more than a week of exposure after-the-fact. I liked the addition of the music to commemorate the times, but as a movie, there isn't a lot of groundbreaking material to lump it into a deeper category of film or re-release it on Criterion or anything. If you're a fan of grunge music or slacker-movies that let you kill 1.5 hours while you're downing a 6-pack, this might be a fun watch once, but I don't think I'll be owning this.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Awesome Rocking Grunge Movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    indydirecta
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/12/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I really love this movie. Dorff is way cool and the soundtrack just rocks your face off. SFW is really more than that, because it really takes the mickey out of news, media and reality TV, and it's cool to think that this came out way before the reality TV craze hit all our channels. Heaps of good acting from the cast, and lots of cool tunes and a really good message in this movie. I don't know why more people haven't seen it but if you love cool 90's movies with awesome soundtracks like Soundgarden, Manson and GWAR , then this is a movie you should really check out! Nine out of Ten, would be more but I was bummed the DVD had no features.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    So what indeed.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Boba_Fett1138
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/8/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    And in the category of most pointless movies; "S.F.W.". A movie that totally fails at trying to make a statement and at leaving a lasting impression. Guess that in potential this still could had been a good movie or at least one that worked out somewhat better with all of its themes. The right ideas seem to be there, which makes some of the choices the film-makers made with this movie seem all the more odd. The story is told real messy. Characters literally pop up out of nowhere and then disappear again and the story is lacking a real point and a good clear main plot line. The movie basically tries to be a social commentary about today's youth (well 1994's youth of course but it's not like much has changed ever since) and the influence and behavior of the media. Problem is that for a commentary the movie isn't either edgy or clever enough. Also as a comedy/parody it falls terribly short. Thing that still kept this movie somewhat going for me was Stephen Dorff, who was perfectly cast for his role. His characters was about still the only good and interesting thing about this movie. Reese Witherspoon and Jake Busey are also in this movie but I wonder why. It's not like their characters get to do much in this movie. Another thing that makes this movie disappointing and lacking is its rushed ending. Basically it's one big long montage and feels terribly out of place. It's as if they were saying; we still have a whole other story to tell but we haven't got the time or money to do it, so here is a fast montage of things. Needless to say, it doesn't work out all that well. I really can't think of any good reason why anyone should ever watch this movie. It's such a pointless and poorly executed one. 5/10 http://bobafett1138.blogspot.com/
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Brilliant.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    leetodman
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/12/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I disagree with some of these analytical idiots. This is a must see for everyone, young and old and yes I do believe the media can be this screwed up especially in America. There were some parts of this movie where I just couldn't stop laughing and it portray's how pathetic people try to feed off someone else's success. Never seen anything like it and it will be a long time before something in this genre will even come close. Performances by Stephen Dorff and Reese Witherspoon are out of this world. Just brilliant.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Was a sad sign of things to come.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Bloodzombie77
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/5/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It's sorry to see this movie get panned by critics, but I can also see why critics hated it, because critics are a part of the media that "S.F.W." tried to make fun of. For every person claiming this to be the worst movie ever, you took it too seriously. The whole point of the film was not to take it too seriously, and focus on what animals people can become when someone they know becomes famous. All his friends and family didn't care what he and the others went through, they wanted whatever dime they could make off of him, and it portrays it very subtly. Joe's (his friend that died) older sister sleeps with him, only to sell his "bedroom stories" to the tabloids, but it's only revealed in a split-second when Spab sees it posted on a tabloid cover on display. His other friend (Jake Busey) takes Spab to a place, where he beats up some kid, then goes to another place, pulls a gun on a girl he slept with, and then takes him to his sister's house (who happens to be a lawyer), all in the name of hiding him from the press. Shortly after she sleeps with him and has him throw Busey's gun in the lake, she starts talking about suing people and splitting the money with her and her brother. He gets disenchanted and runs off, only to hear a radio APB placed on him for beating up the kid that Busey's character roughed up, long story short, they set him up so that if he didn't play ball, they'd frame him for a crime. Long story short, if you were a teenager in the 90's and you watched this then, watch it again and you'd be surprised how it probably went in your memory from being a stoner-drama flick to a decently made indie film that was simply a sign of things to come about the never-ending pseudo-celebrity.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Brilliant flashes of light
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bob_meg
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/12/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I saw this movie on release ages ago and it's not hard to fall in love with it at first. Stephen Dorff's performance is really amazing. You never think for a moment he isn't Cliff Spab, with all the pent-up rage, pain, hostility and hilarity that it entails. For the first half of the movie, it's really "the Cliff Spab/Stephen Dorff Show." He goes on a sort of Jack Kerouac road trip, bumping heads and rubbing noses with a variety of characters (and some wonderful actors who play them): Jake Busey (a good movie for once), Joey Lauren Adams (always terrific and smokin' hot here), and Pamela Gidley (quite a complex little cameo). But after his odyssey ends, there doesn't seem to be much of a place to go...the film just stalls. I think the intent was for it to be completely character driven, so I wasn't expecting, well, a story-line or anything, but still.... I was hoping for more of a connection between the final scene, Spab's revelations, and the rest of the movie leading up to that point, but it didn't happen. Never read the book, but it sounds like that ending would have made more sense. A movie this dark doesn't deserve a happy ending....a little too tidy, in my opinion. But SFW?
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Brilliant
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    lee-todman
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/6/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This has to be the ultimate teenage rebellion movie and it does not get better than this. An attack on the media - I don't think so, the media as usual always turn things upside down. The plot, Directing and acting were top class especially Stephen Dorf. I am 40 years old and can still enjoy watching this movie, it's just so dam good. I bought this movie as soon as it was released on DVD, it's a classic and I think it will remain that way for many years. Anybody who didn't enjoy this movie might want to see it again and get a fresh perspective. The truth it tells about society and the media is brilliant and if you cant see that then you must be blind. Top class movie and well done to everyone involved.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Takes you back to a specific and forgotten style point in the 90's
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    xynphix
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I had high hopes for this movie but was totally disappointed upon seeing it. For how much I didn't like it, something about this movie stuck with me ten years later, looking back I've created a more interesting version of what this movie COULD have been in my head, It put me on the edge of wanting to believe that it was a poor man's Oliver Stone movie. The most intriguing thing about this movie is that watching it puts you in a specific time and place, a short lived style in the early to mid 90's that seems like a twilight zone dream. It captures something about that time that very few movies have done. Other than that quality, the plot, which starts off great slowly rolls down an incline and falls flat off a cliff. The characters almost have depth and catch your interest right from the start but end up over the top annoying, especially the main character Spab. By the end of the movie, he's lost any redeeming quality and Joey Lauren Adams character's continual whining becomes like nails on a chalk board. Having had no background knowledge of this movie upon seeing it, I really thought that Kevin Smith was somehow involved because it has the same feel of his early work and uses a few of the same actors. All in all, this could have been a memorable movie, far ahead of it's time with it's depiction of reality TV and media sensationalism but in reality, was really just a big waste of time.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Real Meaning- A Good/Bad Movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    rjkeenan
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Yes, the acting and directing were a little inconsistent, and some of the lines were sophomoric and occasionally downright lame, but the value of the movie lays in it's overall existentialist theme. Cliff Spab doesn't care about the consequences of anything- he's smokes, he drinks, he curses, doesn't care about bettering himself, doesn't really care about the way he looks, and isn't afraid of anything- not even death. Is it because he was overlooked, abused, etc.? Not really. Cliff doesn't revel in fame or attention when he gets it, but rather treats it as a joke because it simply doesn't matter (even if he half enjoys it), hence the phrase "So Fu.... What." The importance of this phrase points to the notion that nothing really matters in life. Someone can get the best grades, go to the best schools, watch their weight, be good to others, always do right, gain fame and notoriety...or they can be shot in the head in the middle of a store robbery. In the grand scheme of things it really doesn't matter. Quoting Chuck Palahniuk, "On a long enough time-line, the survival rate for everyone drops to zero." Our existence in our solar system, in our galaxy, in the universe is a spec of dust on a spec of dust on a spec of dust, hence SFW (nothing really matters). The black comedy and satire of this movie comes from the doting media and fans of Cliff Spab. It's not that they really love him, they are just looking for an answer- a motto to guide their lives. But, as in real life, something seemingly meaningful to you one moment becomes a useless fad in the next moment. In the conclusion of the movie Barbara Wyler tries to shoot Cliff or something (it's really been years), and states her tag-line "Everything matters!" It's the complete opposite theory of Cliff's. Her essential meaning is that everything we do has an affect on the future, future generations, the overall makeup of things on our planet, etc. Her message could be looked at as kind of good, but the irony lies in the fact that she seems all too excited to step directly into Cliff's shoes and be another meaningless, short-lived role model. In essence Cliff was right when he believed nothing matters and Barbara's time in the spotlight will also fade away. One day neither will be remembered and will have no affect on anything or anyone. Even those that followed them for a brief time will be gone and forgotten. It's a sad story of the media misguiding people to waste their short lives with whatever's popular and meaningless in the moment. But, it also questions, if nothing really matters anyway, SFW.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Does Generation X really matter?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    FlashCallahan
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Cliff Spab doesn't really care about anything. He gets held hostage at a store for 36 days by terrorists, who demand that the entire thing be broadcast on national television. Cliff ends up taking a bullet for fellow hostage Wendy - making him a national hero. The two are the sole survivors of the ordeal, and soon become prisoners of the media. Cliff escapes it all, only to find himself being pushed further away from Wendy when he needs her most.... Once you get past the fact that Dorff sounds uncannily like Christian Slater, you get another one of those films from the mid nineties that tried to define good old 'generation X'. And for the most part, it works. Dorff is great as the guy who is having his fifteen minutes of fame, but cannot decipher why people are not mentioning his friend who was killed. But this was a time when media only really dwelled on the good stuff, to sugar coat the public, to get more money behind their new 'celeb' The film doesn't know what genre it belongs to. One minute it's hilarious, next it's soul searching, and then it goes for a Araki/Solondz hybrid that baffles. But it's good, and all the performances are great, I just wish it didn't get lost in its own smugness every now and again. The last fifteen minutes is great though, showing us how fickle the media were/are, and how fame really slips through your fingers, once a new fad has been found. Everything Matters? S.F.W...
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Disappointed that this isn't a Natural Born Killers re-imagining
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    nathanschubach
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Well what can I say about this? It came out when I was still a teenager, and it had all of the elements of the 1990s that kids were getting into because, according to the majority of media outlets, we were the jaded generation that believed in nothing other than grunge music, being pains in the butt for adults, and rocking out without a care in the world. Every generation does this, but this was our version of "Steal This Movie." And while most of that attitude was true and around at the time, you can see how much the creative lines were blurred when you had movies like "S.F.W." coming out and trying to cash in on these trends. Wayne's World, Tank Girl, Beavis & Butthead, Slacker, Clerks, Mall Rats, Natural Born Killers, Drugstore Cowboy, Pump Up the Volume, Bill & Ted's, Singles, Reality Bites, Empire Records...hell, even Ferris Bueller's Day Off had its similar message in the 80s. So what's one more, right? First off, the movie is ridiculous. The premise (without spoiling it) is thin, unbelievable, and needed a lot of retooling (if the whole screenplay was adapted from a book, and if it was, the book's probably not much better). Even more than "Singles," this movie tries to cram grunge music into every nook and cranny to remind you how street-level Reese Witherspoon and Stephen Dorff's character are (along with their friends), but then they make a weird, Disney-moment every time Dorff's character ("Cliff Spab"...AKA the worst name to be repeated EVER) reminisces about their friend. I'm not going to say what happens, but every time Spab contemplates what went down with his friend, music bussed in from the movie "E.T." gets played, and we're supposed to feel bad for some reason (why, i don't know because Spab wasn't all that close with him in the beginning of the movie or in other scenes either). Secondly, the objective seemed to make sense, that the media and relatives try and cash in from those around them who become famous...but the message easily becomes turned around on the movie itself for cashing in on the attitudes of cynical youths who are biting the bait that this movie produces. Third, it should stay a cult movie and nothing more. It's not Dazed & Confused, and it's not Natural Born Killers. The subjects of this movie became lucky in the film to be celebrities due to a minor news story that realistically would never had happened in real life, and if they would have, people wouldn't give the story more than a week of exposure after-the-fact. I liked the addition of the music to commemorate the times, but as a movie, there isn't a lot of groundbreaking material to lump it into a deeper category of film or re-release it on Criterion or anything. If you're a fan of grunge music or slacker-movies that let you kill 1.5 hours while you're downing a 6-pack, this might be a fun watch once, but I don't think I'll be owning this.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Awesome Rocking Grunge Movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    indydirecta
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/12/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I really love this movie. Dorff is way cool and the soundtrack just rocks your face off. SFW is really more than that, because it really takes the mickey out of news, media and reality TV, and it's cool to think that this came out way before the reality TV craze hit all our channels. Heaps of good acting from the cast, and lots of cool tunes and a really good message in this movie. I don't know why more people haven't seen it but if you love cool 90's movies with awesome soundtracks like Soundgarden, Manson and GWAR , then this is a movie you should really check out! Nine out of Ten, would be more but I was bummed the DVD had no features.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    So what indeed.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Boba_Fett1138
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/8/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    And in the category of most pointless movies; "S.F.W.". A movie that totally fails at trying to make a statement and at leaving a lasting impression. Guess that in potential this still could had been a good movie or at least one that worked out somewhat better with all of its themes. The right ideas seem to be there, which makes some of the choices the film-makers made with this movie seem all the more odd. The story is told real messy. Characters literally pop up out of nowhere and then disappear again and the story is lacking a real point and a good clear main plot line. The movie basically tries to be a social commentary about today's youth (well 1994's youth of course but it's not like much has changed ever since) and the influence and behavior of the media. Problem is that for a commentary the movie isn't either edgy or clever enough. Also as a comedy/parody it falls terribly short. Thing that still kept this movie somewhat going for me was Stephen Dorff, who was perfectly cast for his role. His characters was about still the only good and interesting thing about this movie. Reese Witherspoon and Jake Busey are also in this movie but I wonder why. It's not like their characters get to do much in this movie. Another thing that makes this movie disappointing and lacking is its rushed ending. Basically it's one big long montage and feels terribly out of place. It's as if they were saying; we still have a whole other story to tell but we haven't got the time or money to do it, so here is a fast montage of things. Needless to say, it doesn't work out all that well. I really can't think of any good reason why anyone should ever watch this movie. It's such a pointless and poorly executed one. 5/10 http://bobafett1138.blogspot.com/
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Brilliant.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    leetodman
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/12/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I disagree with some of these analytical idiots. This is a must see for everyone, young and old and yes I do believe the media can be this screwed up especially in America. There were some parts of this movie where I just couldn't stop laughing and it portray's how pathetic people try to feed off someone else's success. Never seen anything like it and it will be a long time before something in this genre will even come close. Performances by Stephen Dorff and Reese Witherspoon are out of this world. Just brilliant.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Was a sad sign of things to come.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Bloodzombie77
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/5/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It's sorry to see this movie get panned by critics, but I can also see why critics hated it, because critics are a part of the media that "S.F.W." tried to make fun of. For every person claiming this to be the worst movie ever, you took it too seriously. The whole point of the film was not to take it too seriously, and focus on what animals people can become when someone they know becomes famous. All his friends and family didn't care what he and the others went through, they wanted whatever dime they could make off of him, and it portrays it very subtly. Joe's (his friend that died) older sister sleeps with him, only to sell his "bedroom stories" to the tabloids, but it's only revealed in a split-second when Spab sees it posted on a tabloid cover on display. His other friend (Jake Busey) takes Spab to a place, where he beats up some kid, then goes to another place, pulls a gun on a girl he slept with, and then takes him to his sister's house (who happens to be a lawyer), all in the name of hiding him from the press. Shortly after she sleeps with him and has him throw Busey's gun in the lake, she starts talking about suing people and splitting the money with her and her brother. He gets disenchanted and runs off, only to hear a radio APB placed on him for beating up the kid that Busey's character roughed up, long story short, they set him up so that if he didn't play ball, they'd frame him for a crime. Long story short, if you were a teenager in the 90's and you watched this then, watch it again and you'd be surprised how it probably went in your memory from being a stoner-drama flick to a decently made indie film that was simply a sign of things to come about the never-ending pseudo-celebrity.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Brilliant flashes of light
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bob_meg
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/12/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I saw this movie on release ages ago and it's not hard to fall in love with it at first. Stephen Dorff's performance is really amazing. You never think for a moment he isn't Cliff Spab, with all the pent-up rage, pain, hostility and hilarity that it entails. For the first half of the movie, it's really "the Cliff Spab/Stephen Dorff Show." He goes on a sort of Jack Kerouac road trip, bumping heads and rubbing noses with a variety of characters (and some wonderful actors who play them): Jake Busey (a good movie for once), Joey Lauren Adams (always terrific and smokin' hot here), and Pamela Gidley (quite a complex little cameo). But after his odyssey ends, there doesn't seem to be much of a place to go...the film just stalls. I think the intent was for it to be completely character driven, so I wasn't expecting, well, a story-line or anything, but still.... I was hoping for more of a connection between the final scene, Spab's revelations, and the rest of the movie leading up to that point, but it didn't happen. Never read the book, but it sounds like that ending would have made more sense. A movie this dark doesn't deserve a happy ending....a little too tidy, in my opinion. But SFW?
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Brilliant
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    lee-todman
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/6/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This has to be the ultimate teenage rebellion movie and it does not get better than this. An attack on the media - I don't think so, the media as usual always turn things upside down. The plot, Directing and acting were top class especially Stephen Dorf. I am 40 years old and can still enjoy watching this movie, it's just so dam good. I bought this movie as soon as it was released on DVD, it's a classic and I think it will remain that way for many years. Anybody who didn't enjoy this movie might want to see it again and get a fresh perspective. The truth it tells about society and the media is brilliant and if you cant see that then you must be blind. Top class movie and well done to everyone involved.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Takes you back to a specific and forgotten style point in the 90's
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    xynphix
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I had high hopes for this movie but was totally disappointed upon seeing it. For how much I didn't like it, something about this movie stuck with me ten years later, looking back I've created a more interesting version of what this movie COULD have been in my head, It put me on the edge of wanting to believe that it was a poor man's Oliver Stone movie. The most intriguing thing about this movie is that watching it puts you in a specific time and place, a short lived style in the early to mid 90's that seems like a twilight zone dream. It captures something about that time that very few movies have done. Other than that quality, the plot, which starts off great slowly rolls down an incline and falls flat off a cliff. The characters almost have depth and catch your interest right from the start but end up over the top annoying, especially the main character Spab. By the end of the movie, he's lost any redeeming quality and Joey Lauren Adams character's continual whining becomes like nails on a chalk board. Having had no background knowledge of this movie upon seeing it, I really thought that Kevin Smith was somehow involved because it has the same feel of his early work and uses a few of the same actors. All in all, this could have been a memorable movie, far ahead of it's time with it's depiction of reality TV and media sensationalism but in reality, was really just a big waste of time.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Real Meaning- A Good/Bad Movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    rjkeenan
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Yes, the acting and directing were a little inconsistent, and some of the lines were sophomoric and occasionally downright lame, but the value of the movie lays in it's overall existentialist theme. Cliff Spab doesn't care about the consequences of anything- he's smokes, he drinks, he curses, doesn't care about bettering himself, doesn't really care about the way he looks, and isn't afraid of anything- not even death. Is it because he was overlooked, abused, etc.? Not really. Cliff doesn't revel in fame or attention when he gets it, but rather treats it as a joke because it simply doesn't matter (even if he half enjoys it), hence the phrase "So Fu.... What." The importance of this phrase points to the notion that nothing really matters in life. Someone can get the best grades, go to the best schools, watch their weight, be good to others, always do right, gain fame and notoriety...or they can be shot in the head in the middle of a store robbery. In the grand scheme of things it really doesn't matter. Quoting Chuck Palahniuk, "On a long enough time-line, the survival rate for everyone drops to zero." Our existence in our solar system, in our galaxy, in the universe is a spec of dust on a spec of dust on a spec of dust, hence SFW (nothing really matters). The black comedy and satire of this movie comes from the doting media and fans of Cliff Spab. It's not that they really love him, they are just looking for an answer- a motto to guide their lives. But, as in real life, something seemingly meaningful to you one moment becomes a useless fad in the next moment. In the conclusion of the movie Barbara Wyler tries to shoot Cliff or something (it's really been years), and states her tag-line "Everything matters!" It's the complete opposite theory of Cliff's. Her essential meaning is that everything we do has an affect on the future, future generations, the overall makeup of things on our planet, etc. Her message could be looked at as kind of good, but the irony lies in the fact that she seems all too excited to step directly into Cliff's shoes and be another meaningless, short-lived role model. In essence Cliff was right when he believed nothing matters and Barbara's time in the spotlight will also fade away. One day neither will be remembered and will have no affect on anything or anyone. Even those that followed them for a brief time will be gone and forgotten. It's a sad story of the media misguiding people to waste their short lives with whatever's popular and meaningless in the moment. But, it also questions, if nothing really matters anyway, SFW.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Does Generation X really matter?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    FlashCallahan
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Cliff Spab doesn't really care about anything. He gets held hostage at a store for 36 days by terrorists, who demand that the entire thing be broadcast on national television. Cliff ends up taking a bullet for fellow hostage Wendy - making him a national hero. The two are the sole survivors of the ordeal, and soon become prisoners of the media. Cliff escapes it all, only to find himself being pushed further away from Wendy when he needs her most.... Once you get past the fact that Dorff sounds uncannily like Christian Slater, you get another one of those films from the mid nineties that tried to define good old 'generation X'. And for the most part, it works. Dorff is great as the guy who is having his fifteen minutes of fame, but cannot decipher why people are not mentioning his friend who was killed. But this was a time when media only really dwelled on the good stuff, to sugar coat the public, to get more money behind their new 'celeb' The film doesn't know what genre it belongs to. One minute it's hilarious, next it's soul searching, and then it goes for a Araki/Solondz hybrid that baffles. But it's good, and all the performances are great, I just wish it didn't get lost in its own smugness every now and again. The last fifteen minutes is great though, showing us how fickle the media were/are, and how fame really slips through your fingers, once a new fad has been found. Everything Matters? S.F.W...
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Disappointed that this isn't a Natural Born Killers re-imagining
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    nathanschubach
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Well what can I say about this? It came out when I was still a teenager, and it had all of the elements of the 1990s that kids were getting into because, according to the majority of media outlets, we were the jaded generation that believed in nothing other than grunge music, being pains in the butt for adults, and rocking out without a care in the world. Every generation does this, but this was our version of "Steal This Movie." And while most of that attitude was true and around at the time, you can see how much the creative lines were blurred when you had movies like "S.F.W." coming out and trying to cash in on these trends. Wayne's World, Tank Girl, Beavis & Butthead, Slacker, Clerks, Mall Rats, Natural Born Killers, Drugstore Cowboy, Pump Up the Volume, Bill & Ted's, Singles, Reality Bites, Empire Records...hell, even Ferris Bueller's Day Off had its similar message in the 80s. So what's one more, right? First off, the movie is ridiculous. The premise (without spoiling it) is thin, unbelievable, and needed a lot of retooling (if the whole screenplay was adapted from a book, and if it was, the book's probably not much better). Even more than "Singles," this movie tries to cram grunge music into every nook and cranny to remind you how street-level Reese Witherspoon and Stephen Dorff's character are (along with their friends), but then they make a weird, Disney-moment every time Dorff's character ("Cliff Spab"...AKA the worst name to be repeated EVER) reminisces about their friend. I'm not going to say what happens, but every time Spab contemplates what went down with his friend, music bussed in from the movie "E.T." gets played, and we're supposed to feel bad for some reason (why, i don't know because Spab wasn't all that close with him in the beginning of the movie or in other scenes either). Secondly, the objective seemed to make sense, that the media and relatives try and cash in from those around them who become famous...but the message easily becomes turned around on the movie itself for cashing in on the attitudes of cynical youths who are biting the bait that this movie produces. Third, it should stay a cult movie and nothing more. It's not Dazed & Confused, and it's not Natural Born Killers. The subjects of this movie became lucky in the film to be celebrities due to a minor news story that realistically would never had happened in real life, and if they would have, people wouldn't give the story more than a week of exposure after-the-fact. I liked the addition of the music to commemorate the times, but as a movie, there isn't a lot of groundbreaking material to lump it into a deeper category of film or re-release it on Criterion or anything. If you're a fan of grunge music or slacker-movies that let you kill 1.5 hours while you're downing a 6-pack, this might be a fun watch once, but I don't think I'll be owning this.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Awesome Rocking Grunge Movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    indydirecta
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/12/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I really love this movie. Dorff is way cool and the soundtrack just rocks your face off. SFW is really more than that, because it really takes the mickey out of news, media and reality TV, and it's cool to think that this came out way before the reality TV craze hit all our channels. Heaps of good acting from the cast, and lots of cool tunes and a really good message in this movie. I don't know why more people haven't seen it but if you love cool 90's movies with awesome soundtracks like Soundgarden, Manson and GWAR , then this is a movie you should really check out! Nine out of Ten, would be more but I was bummed the DVD had no features.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    So what indeed.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Boba_Fett1138
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/8/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    And in the category of most pointless movies; "S.F.W.". A movie that totally fails at trying to make a statement and at leaving a lasting impression. Guess that in potential this still could had been a good movie or at least one that worked out somewhat better with all of its themes. The right ideas seem to be there, which makes some of the choices the film-makers made with this movie seem all the more odd. The story is told real messy. Characters literally pop up out of nowhere and then disappear again and the story is lacking a real point and a good clear main plot line. The movie basically tries to be a social commentary about today's youth (well 1994's youth of course but it's not like much has changed ever since) and the influence and behavior of the media. Problem is that for a commentary the movie isn't either edgy or clever enough. Also as a comedy/parody it falls terribly short. Thing that still kept this movie somewhat going for me was Stephen Dorff, who was perfectly cast for his role. His characters was about still the only good and interesting thing about this movie. Reese Witherspoon and Jake Busey are also in this movie but I wonder why. It's not like their characters get to do much in this movie. Another thing that makes this movie disappointing and lacking is its rushed ending. Basically it's one big long montage and feels terribly out of place. It's as if they were saying; we still have a whole other story to tell but we haven't got the time or money to do it, so here is a fast montage of things. Needless to say, it doesn't work out all that well. I really can't think of any good reason why anyone should ever watch this movie. It's such a pointless and poorly executed one. 5/10 http://bobafett1138.blogspot.com/
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Brilliant.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    leetodman
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/12/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I disagree with some of these analytical idiots. This is a must see for everyone, young and old and yes I do believe the media can be this screwed up especially in America. There were some parts of this movie where I just couldn't stop laughing and it portray's how pathetic people try to feed off someone else's success. Never seen anything like it and it will be a long time before something in this genre will even come close. Performances by Stephen Dorff and Reese Witherspoon are out of this world. Just brilliant.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Was a sad sign of things to come.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Bloodzombie77
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/5/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It's sorry to see this movie get panned by critics, but I can also see why critics hated it, because critics are a part of the media that "S.F.W." tried to make fun of. For every person claiming this to be the worst movie ever, you took it too seriously. The whole point of the film was not to take it too seriously, and focus on what animals people can become when someone they know becomes famous. All his friends and family didn't care what he and the others went through, they wanted whatever dime they could make off of him, and it portrays it very subtly. Joe's (his friend that died) older sister sleeps with him, only to sell his "bedroom stories" to the tabloids, but it's only revealed in a split-second when Spab sees it posted on a tabloid cover on display. His other friend (Jake Busey) takes Spab to a place, where he beats up some kid, then goes to another place, pulls a gun on a girl he slept with, and then takes him to his sister's house (who happens to be a lawyer), all in the name of hiding him from the press. Shortly after she sleeps with him and has him throw Busey's gun in the lake, she starts talking about suing people and splitting the money with her and her brother. He gets disenchanted and runs off, only to hear a radio APB placed on him for beating up the kid that Busey's character roughed up, long story short, they set him up so that if he didn't play ball, they'd frame him for a crime. Long story short, if you were a teenager in the 90's and you watched this then, watch it again and you'd be surprised how it probably went in your memory from being a stoner-drama flick to a decently made indie film that was simply a sign of things to come about the never-ending pseudo-celebrity.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Brilliant flashes of light
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bob_meg
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/12/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I saw this movie on release ages ago and it's not hard to fall in love with it at first. Stephen Dorff's performance is really amazing. You never think for a moment he isn't Cliff Spab, with all the pent-up rage, pain, hostility and hilarity that it entails. For the first half of the movie, it's really "the Cliff Spab/Stephen Dorff Show." He goes on a sort of Jack Kerouac road trip, bumping heads and rubbing noses with a variety of characters (and some wonderful actors who play them): Jake Busey (a good movie for once), Joey Lauren Adams (always terrific and smokin' hot here), and Pamela Gidley (quite a complex little cameo). But after his odyssey ends, there doesn't seem to be much of a place to go...the film just stalls. I think the intent was for it to be completely character driven, so I wasn't expecting, well, a story-line or anything, but still.... I was hoping for more of a connection between the final scene, Spab's revelations, and the rest of the movie leading up to that point, but it didn't happen. Never read the book, but it sounds like that ending would have made more sense. A movie this dark doesn't deserve a happy ending....a little too tidy, in my opinion. But SFW?
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Brilliant
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    lee-todman
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/6/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This has to be the ultimate teenage rebellion movie and it does not get better than this. An attack on the media - I don't think so, the media as usual always turn things upside down. The plot, Directing and acting were top class especially Stephen Dorf. I am 40 years old and can still enjoy watching this movie, it's just so dam good. I bought this movie as soon as it was released on DVD, it's a classic and I think it will remain that way for many years. Anybody who didn't enjoy this movie might want to see it again and get a fresh perspective. The truth it tells about society and the media is brilliant and if you cant see that then you must be blind. Top class movie and well done to everyone involved.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Takes you back to a specific and forgotten style point in the 90's
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    xynphix
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I had high hopes for this movie but was totally disappointed upon seeing it. For how much I didn't like it, something about this movie stuck with me ten years later, looking back I've created a more interesting version of what this movie COULD have been in my head, It put me on the edge of wanting to believe that it was a poor man's Oliver Stone movie. The most intriguing thing about this movie is that watching it puts you in a specific time and place, a short lived style in the early to mid 90's that seems like a twilight zone dream. It captures something about that time that very few movies have done. Other than that quality, the plot, which starts off great slowly rolls down an incline and falls flat off a cliff. The characters almost have depth and catch your interest right from the start but end up over the top annoying, especially the main character Spab. By the end of the movie, he's lost any redeeming quality and Joey Lauren Adams character's continual whining becomes like nails on a chalk board. Having had no background knowledge of this movie upon seeing it, I really thought that Kevin Smith was somehow involved because it has the same feel of his early work and uses a few of the same actors. All in all, this could have been a memorable movie, far ahead of it's time with it's depiction of reality TV and media sensationalism but in reality, was really just a big waste of time.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Real Meaning- A Good/Bad Movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    rjkeenan
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Yes, the acting and directing were a little inconsistent, and some of the lines were sophomoric and occasionally downright lame, but the value of the movie lays in it's overall existentialist theme. Cliff Spab doesn't care about the consequences of anything- he's smokes, he drinks, he curses, doesn't care about bettering himself, doesn't really care about the way he looks, and isn't afraid of anything- not even death. Is it because he was overlooked, abused, etc.? Not really. Cliff doesn't revel in fame or attention when he gets it, but rather treats it as a joke because it simply doesn't matter (even if he half enjoys it), hence the phrase "So Fu.... What." The importance of this phrase points to the notion that nothing really matters in life. Someone can get the best grades, go to the best schools, watch their weight, be good to others, always do right, gain fame and notoriety...or they can be shot in the head in the middle of a store robbery. In the grand scheme of things it really doesn't matter. Quoting Chuck Palahniuk, "On a long enough time-line, the survival rate for everyone drops to zero." Our existence in our solar system, in our galaxy, in the universe is a spec of dust on a spec of dust on a spec of dust, hence SFW (nothing really matters). The black comedy and satire of this movie comes from the doting media and fans of Cliff Spab. It's not that they really love him, they are just looking for an answer- a motto to guide their lives. But, as in real life, something seemingly meaningful to you one moment becomes a useless fad in the next moment. In the conclusion of the movie Barbara Wyler tries to shoot Cliff or something (it's really been years), and states her tag-line "Everything matters!" It's the complete opposite theory of Cliff's. Her essential meaning is that everything we do has an affect on the future, future generations, the overall makeup of things on our planet, etc. Her message could be looked at as kind of good, but the irony lies in the fact that she seems all too excited to step directly into Cliff's shoes and be another meaningless, short-lived role model. In essence Cliff was right when he believed nothing matters and Barbara's time in the spotlight will also fade away. One day neither will be remembered and will have no affect on anything or anyone. Even those that followed them for a brief time will be gone and forgotten. It's a sad story of the media misguiding people to waste their short lives with whatever's popular and meaningless in the moment. But, it also questions, if nothing really matters anyway, SFW.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Does Generation X really matter?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    FlashCallahan
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Cliff Spab doesn't really care about anything. He gets held hostage at a store for 36 days by terrorists, who demand that the entire thing be broadcast on national television. Cliff ends up taking a bullet for fellow hostage Wendy - making him a national hero. The two are the sole survivors of the ordeal, and soon become prisoners of the media. Cliff escapes it all, only to find himself being pushed further away from Wendy when he needs her most.... Once you get past the fact that Dorff sounds uncannily like Christian Slater, you get another one of those films from the mid nineties that tried to define good old 'generation X'. And for the most part, it works. Dorff is great as the guy who is having his fifteen minutes of fame, but cannot decipher why people are not mentioning his friend who was killed. But this was a time when media only really dwelled on the good stuff, to sugar coat the public, to get more money behind their new 'celeb' The film doesn't know what genre it belongs to. One minute it's hilarious, next it's soul searching, and then it goes for a Araki/Solondz hybrid that baffles. But it's good, and all the performances are great, I just wish it didn't get lost in its own smugness every now and again. The last fifteen minutes is great though, showing us how fickle the media were/are, and how fame really slips through your fingers, once a new fad has been found. Everything Matters? S.F.W...
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Disappointed that this isn't a Natural Born Killers re-imagining
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    nathanschubach
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Well what can I say about this? It came out when I was still a teenager, and it had all of the elements of the 1990s that kids were getting into because, according to the majority of media outlets, we were the jaded generation that believed in nothing other than grunge music, being pains in the butt for adults, and rocking out without a care in the world. Every generation does this, but this was our version of "Steal This Movie." And while most of that attitude was true and around at the time, you can see how much the creative lines were blurred when you had movies like "S.F.W." coming out and trying to cash in on these trends. Wayne's World, Tank Girl, Beavis & Butthead, Slacker, Clerks, Mall Rats, Natural Born Killers, Drugstore Cowboy, Pump Up the Volume, Bill & Ted's, Singles, Reality Bites, Empire Records...hell, even Ferris Bueller's Day Off had its similar message in the 80s. So what's one more, right? First off, the movie is ridiculous. The premise (without spoiling it) is thin, unbelievable, and needed a lot of retooling (if the whole screenplay was adapted from a book, and if it was, the book's probably not much better). Even more than "Singles," this movie tries to cram grunge music into every nook and cranny to remind you how street-level Reese Witherspoon and Stephen Dorff's character are (along with their friends), but then they make a weird, Disney-moment every time Dorff's character ("Cliff Spab"...AKA the worst name to be repeated EVER) reminisces about their friend. I'm not going to say what happens, but every time Spab contemplates what went down with his friend, music bussed in from the movie "E.T." gets played, and we're supposed to feel bad for some reason (why, i don't know because Spab wasn't all that close with him in the beginning of the movie or in other scenes either). Secondly, the objective seemed to make sense, that the media and relatives try and cash in from those around them who become famous...but the message easily becomes turned around on the movie itself for cashing in on the attitudes of cynical youths who are biting the bait that this movie produces. Third, it should stay a cult movie and nothing more. It's not Dazed & Confused, and it's not Natural Born Killers. The subjects of this movie became lucky in the film to be celebrities due to a minor news story that realistically would never had happened in real life, and if they would have, people wouldn't give the story more than a week of exposure after-the-fact. I liked the addition of the music to commemorate the times, but as a movie, there isn't a lot of groundbreaking material to lump it into a deeper category of film or re-release it on Criterion or anything. If you're a fan of grunge music or slacker-movies that let you kill 1.5 hours while you're downing a 6-pack, this might be a fun watch once, but I don't think I'll be owning this.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Awesome Rocking Grunge Movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    indydirecta
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/12/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I really love this movie. Dorff is way cool and the soundtrack just rocks your face off. SFW is really more than that, because it really takes the mickey out of news, media and reality TV, and it's cool to think that this came out way before the reality TV craze hit all our channels. Heaps of good acting from the cast, and lots of cool tunes and a really good message in this movie. I don't know why more people haven't seen it but if you love cool 90's movies with awesome soundtracks like Soundgarden, Manson and GWAR , then this is a movie you should really check out! Nine out of Ten, would be more but I was bummed the DVD had no features.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    So what indeed.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Boba_Fett1138
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/8/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    And in the category of most pointless movies; "S.F.W.". A movie that totally fails at trying to make a statement and at leaving a lasting impression. Guess that in potential this still could had been a good movie or at least one that worked out somewhat better with all of its themes. The right ideas seem to be there, which makes some of the choices the film-makers made with this movie seem all the more odd. The story is told real messy. Characters literally pop up out of nowhere and then disappear again and the story is lacking a real point and a good clear main plot line. The movie basically tries to be a social commentary about today's youth (well 1994's youth of course but it's not like much has changed ever since) and the influence and behavior of the media. Problem is that for a commentary the movie isn't either edgy or clever enough. Also as a comedy/parody it falls terribly short. Thing that still kept this movie somewhat going for me was Stephen Dorff, who was perfectly cast for his role. His characters was about still the only good and interesting thing about this movie. Reese Witherspoon and Jake Busey are also in this movie but I wonder why. It's not like their characters get to do much in this movie. Another thing that makes this movie disappointing and lacking is its rushed ending. Basically it's one big long montage and feels terribly out of place. It's as if they were saying; we still have a whole other story to tell but we haven't got the time or money to do it, so here is a fast montage of things. Needless to say, it doesn't work out all that well. I really can't think of any good reason why anyone should ever watch this movie. It's such a pointless and poorly executed one. 5/10 http://bobafett1138.blogspot.com/
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Brilliant.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    leetodman
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/12/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I disagree with some of these analytical idiots. This is a must see for everyone, young and old and yes I do believe the media can be this screwed up especially in America. There were some parts of this movie where I just couldn't stop laughing and it portray's how pathetic people try to feed off someone else's success. Never seen anything like it and it will be a long time before something in this genre will even come close. Performances by Stephen Dorff and Reese Witherspoon are out of this world. Just brilliant.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Was a sad sign of things to come.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Bloodzombie77
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/5/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It's sorry to see this movie get panned by critics, but I can also see why critics hated it, because critics are a part of the media that "S.F.W." tried to make fun of. For every person claiming this to be the worst movie ever, you took it too seriously. The whole point of the film was not to take it too seriously, and focus on what animals people can become when someone they know becomes famous. All his friends and family didn't care what he and the others went through, they wanted whatever dime they could make off of him, and it portrays it very subtly. Joe's (his friend that died) older sister sleeps with him, only to sell his "bedroom stories" to the tabloids, but it's only revealed in a split-second when Spab sees it posted on a tabloid cover on display. His other friend (Jake Busey) takes Spab to a place, where he beats up some kid, then goes to another place, pulls a gun on a girl he slept with, and then takes him to his sister's house (who happens to be a lawyer), all in the name of hiding him from the press. Shortly after she sleeps with him and has him throw Busey's gun in the lake, she starts talking about suing people and splitting the money with her and her brother. He gets disenchanted and runs off, only to hear a radio APB placed on him for beating up the kid that Busey's character roughed up, long story short, they set him up so that if he didn't play ball, they'd frame him for a crime. Long story short, if you were a teenager in the 90's and you watched this then, watch it again and you'd be surprised how it probably went in your memory from being a stoner-drama flick to a decently made indie film that was simply a sign of things to come about the never-ending pseudo-celebrity.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Brilliant flashes of light
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bob_meg
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/12/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I saw this movie on release ages ago and it's not hard to fall in love with it at first. Stephen Dorff's performance is really amazing. You never think for a moment he isn't Cliff Spab, with all the pent-up rage, pain, hostility and hilarity that it entails. For the first half of the movie, it's really "the Cliff Spab/Stephen Dorff Show." He goes on a sort of Jack Kerouac road trip, bumping heads and rubbing noses with a variety of characters (and some wonderful actors who play them): Jake Busey (a good movie for once), Joey Lauren Adams (always terrific and smokin' hot here), and Pamela Gidley (quite a complex little cameo). But after his odyssey ends, there doesn't seem to be much of a place to go...the film just stalls. I think the intent was for it to be completely character driven, so I wasn't expecting, well, a story-line or anything, but still.... I was hoping for more of a connection between the final scene, Spab's revelations, and the rest of the movie leading up to that point, but it didn't happen. Never read the book, but it sounds like that ending would have made more sense. A movie this dark doesn't deserve a happy ending....a little too tidy, in my opinion. But SFW?
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Brilliant
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    lee-todman
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/6/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This has to be the ultimate teenage rebellion movie and it does not get better than this. An attack on the media - I don't think so, the media as usual always turn things upside down. The plot, Directing and acting were top class especially Stephen Dorf. I am 40 years old and can still enjoy watching this movie, it's just so dam good. I bought this movie as soon as it was released on DVD, it's a classic and I think it will remain that way for many years. Anybody who didn't enjoy this movie might want to see it again and get a fresh perspective. The truth it tells about society and the media is brilliant and if you cant see that then you must be blind. Top class movie and well done to everyone involved.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Takes you back to a specific and forgotten style point in the 90's
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    xynphix
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I had high hopes for this movie but was totally disappointed upon seeing it. For how much I didn't like it, something about this movie stuck with me ten years later, looking back I've created a more interesting version of what this movie COULD have been in my head, It put me on the edge of wanting to believe that it was a poor man's Oliver Stone movie. The most intriguing thing about this movie is that watching it puts you in a specific time and place, a short lived style in the early to mid 90's that seems like a twilight zone dream. It captures something about that time that very few movies have done. Other than that quality, the plot, which starts off great slowly rolls down an incline and falls flat off a cliff. The characters almost have depth and catch your interest right from the start but end up over the top annoying, especially the main character Spab. By the end of the movie, he's lost any redeeming quality and Joey Lauren Adams character's continual whining becomes like nails on a chalk board. Having had no background knowledge of this movie upon seeing it, I really thought that Kevin Smith was somehow involved because it has the same feel of his early work and uses a few of the same actors. All in all, this could have been a memorable movie, far ahead of it's time with it's depiction of reality TV and media sensationalism but in reality, was really just a big waste of time.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Real Meaning- A Good/Bad Movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    rjkeenan
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Yes, the acting and directing were a little inconsistent, and some of the lines were sophomoric and occasionally downright lame, but the value of the movie lays in it's overall existentialist theme. Cliff Spab doesn't care about the consequences of anything- he's smokes, he drinks, he curses, doesn't care about bettering himself, doesn't really care about the way he looks, and isn't afraid of anything- not even death. Is it because he was overlooked, abused, etc.? Not really. Cliff doesn't revel in fame or attention when he gets it, but rather treats it as a joke because it simply doesn't matter (even if he half enjoys it), hence the phrase "So Fu.... What." The importance of this phrase points to the notion that nothing really matters in life. Someone can get the best grades, go to the best schools, watch their weight, be good to others, always do right, gain fame and notoriety...or they can be shot in the head in the middle of a store robbery. In the grand scheme of things it really doesn't matter. Quoting Chuck Palahniuk, "On a long enough time-line, the survival rate for everyone drops to zero." Our existence in our solar system, in our galaxy, in the universe is a spec of dust on a spec of dust on a spec of dust, hence SFW (nothing really matters). The black comedy and satire of this movie comes from the doting media and fans of Cliff Spab. It's not that they really love him, they are just looking for an answer- a motto to guide their lives. But, as in real life, something seemingly meaningful to you one moment becomes a useless fad in the next moment. In the conclusion of the movie Barbara Wyler tries to shoot Cliff or something (it's really been years), and states her tag-line "Everything matters!" It's the complete opposite theory of Cliff's. Her essential meaning is that everything we do has an affect on the future, future generations, the overall makeup of things on our planet, etc. Her message could be looked at as kind of good, but the irony lies in the fact that she seems all too excited to step directly into Cliff's shoes and be another meaningless, short-lived role model. In essence Cliff was right when he believed nothing matters and Barbara's time in the spotlight will also fade away. One day neither will be remembered and will have no affect on anything or anyone. Even those that followed them for a brief time will be gone and forgotten. It's a sad story of the media misguiding people to waste their short lives with whatever's popular and meaningless in the moment. But, it also questions, if nothing really matters anyway, SFW.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Does Generation X really matter?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    FlashCallahan
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Cliff Spab doesn't really care about anything. He gets held hostage at a store for 36 days by terrorists, who demand that the entire thing be broadcast on national television. Cliff ends up taking a bullet for fellow hostage Wendy - making him a national hero. The two are the sole survivors of the ordeal, and soon become prisoners of the media. Cliff escapes it all, only to find himself being pushed further away from Wendy when he needs her most.... Once you get past the fact that Dorff sounds uncannily like Christian Slater, you get another one of those films from the mid nineties that tried to define good old 'generation X'. And for the most part, it works. Dorff is great as the guy who is having his fifteen minutes of fame, but cannot decipher why people are not mentioning his friend who was killed. But this was a time when media only really dwelled on the good stuff, to sugar coat the public, to get more money behind their new 'celeb' The film doesn't know what genre it belongs to. One minute it's hilarious, next it's soul searching, and then it goes for a Araki/Solondz hybrid that baffles. But it's good, and all the performances are great, I just wish it didn't get lost in its own smugness every now and again. The last fifteen minutes is great though, showing us how fickle the media were/are, and how fame really slips through your fingers, once a new fad has been found. Everything Matters? S.F.W...
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Disappointed that this isn't a Natural Born Killers re-imagining
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    nathanschubach
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Well what can I say about this? It came out when I was still a teenager, and it had all of the elements of the 1990s that kids were getting into because, according to the majority of media outlets, we were the jaded generation that believed in nothing other than grunge music, being pains in the butt for adults, and rocking out without a care in the world. Every generation does this, but this was our version of "Steal This Movie." And while most of that attitude was true and around at the time, you can see how much the creative lines were blurred when you had movies like "S.F.W." coming out and trying to cash in on these trends. Wayne's World, Tank Girl, Beavis & Butthead, Slacker, Clerks, Mall Rats, Natural Born Killers, Drugstore Cowboy, Pump Up the Volume, Bill & Ted's, Singles, Reality Bites, Empire Records...hell, even Ferris Bueller's Day Off had its similar message in the 80s. So what's one more, right? First off, the movie is ridiculous. The premise (without spoiling it) is thin, unbelievable, and needed a lot of retooling (if the whole screenplay was adapted from a book, and if it was, the book's probably not much better). Even more than "Singles," this movie tries to cram grunge music into every nook and cranny to remind you how street-level Reese Witherspoon and Stephen Dorff's character are (along with their friends), but then they make a weird, Disney-moment every time Dorff's character ("Cliff Spab"...AKA the worst name to be repeated EVER) reminisces about their friend. I'm not going to say what happens, but every time Spab contemplates what went down with his friend, music bussed in from the movie "E.T." gets played, and we're supposed to feel bad for some reason (why, i don't know because Spab wasn't all that close with him in the beginning of the movie or in other scenes either). Secondly, the objective seemed to make sense, that the media and relatives try and cash in from those around them who become famous...but the message easily becomes turned around on the movie itself for cashing in on the attitudes of cynical youths who are biting the bait that this movie produces. Third, it should stay a cult movie and nothing more. It's not Dazed & Confused, and it's not Natural Born Killers. The subjects of this movie became lucky in the film to be celebrities due to a minor news story that realistically would never had happened in real life, and if they would have, people wouldn't give the story more than a week of exposure after-the-fact. I liked the addition of the music to commemorate the times, but as a movie, there isn't a lot of groundbreaking material to lump it into a deeper category of film or re-release it on Criterion or anything. If you're a fan of grunge music or slacker-movies that let you kill 1.5 hours while you're downing a 6-pack, this might be a fun watch once, but I don't think I'll be owning this.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Awesome Rocking Grunge Movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    indydirecta
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/12/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I really love this movie. Dorff is way cool and the soundtrack just rocks your face off. SFW is really more than that, because it really takes the mickey out of news, media and reality TV, and it's cool to think that this came out way before the reality TV craze hit all our channels. Heaps of good acting from the cast, and lots of cool tunes and a really good message in this movie. I don't know why more people haven't seen it but if you love cool 90's movies with awesome soundtracks like Soundgarden, Manson and GWAR , then this is a movie you should really check out! Nine out of Ten, would be more but I was bummed the DVD had no features.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    So what indeed.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Boba_Fett1138
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/8/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    And in the category of most pointless movies; "S.F.W.". A movie that totally fails at trying to make a statement and at leaving a lasting impression. Guess that in potential this still could had been a good movie or at least one that worked out somewhat better with all of its themes. The right ideas seem to be there, which makes some of the choices the film-makers made with this movie seem all the more odd. The story is told real messy. Characters literally pop up out of nowhere and then disappear again and the story is lacking a real point and a good clear main plot line. The movie basically tries to be a social commentary about today's youth (well 1994's youth of course but it's not like much has changed ever since) and the influence and behavior of the media. Problem is that for a commentary the movie isn't either edgy or clever enough. Also as a comedy/parody it falls terribly short. Thing that still kept this movie somewhat going for me was Stephen Dorff, who was perfectly cast for his role. His characters was about still the only good and interesting thing about this movie. Reese Witherspoon and Jake Busey are also in this movie but I wonder why. It's not like their characters get to do much in this movie. Another thing that makes this movie disappointing and lacking is its rushed ending. Basically it's one big long montage and feels terribly out of place. It's as if they were saying; we still have a whole other story to tell but we haven't got the time or money to do it, so here is a fast montage of things. Needless to say, it doesn't work out all that well. I really can't think of any good reason why anyone should ever watch this movie. It's such a pointless and poorly executed one. 5/10 http://bobafett1138.blogspot.com/
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Brilliant.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    leetodman
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/12/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I disagree with some of these analytical idiots. This is a must see for everyone, young and old and yes I do believe the media can be this screwed up especially in America. There were some parts of this movie where I just couldn't stop laughing and it portray's how pathetic people try to feed off someone else's success. Never seen anything like it and it will be a long time before something in this genre will even come close. Performances by Stephen Dorff and Reese Witherspoon are out of this world. Just brilliant.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Was a sad sign of things to come.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Bloodzombie77
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/5/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It's sorry to see this movie get panned by critics, but I can also see why critics hated it, because critics are a part of the media that "S.F.W." tried to make fun of. For every person claiming this to be the worst movie ever, you took it too seriously. The whole point of the film was not to take it too seriously, and focus on what animals people can become when someone they know becomes famous. All his friends and family didn't care what he and the others went through, they wanted whatever dime they could make off of him, and it portrays it very subtly. Joe's (his friend that died) older sister sleeps with him, only to sell his "bedroom stories" to the tabloids, but it's only revealed in a split-second when Spab sees it posted on a tabloid cover on display. His other friend (Jake Busey) takes Spab to a place, where he beats up some kid, then goes to another place, pulls a gun on a girl he slept with, and then takes him to his sister's house (who happens to be a lawyer), all in the name of hiding him from the press. Shortly after she sleeps with him and has him throw Busey's gun in the lake, she starts talking about suing people and splitting the money with her and her brother. He gets disenchanted and runs off, only to hear a radio APB placed on him for beating up the kid that Busey's character roughed up, long story short, they set him up so that if he didn't play ball, they'd frame him for a crime. Long story short, if you were a teenager in the 90's and you watched this then, watch it again and you'd be surprised how it probably went in your memory from being a stoner-drama flick to a decently made indie film that was simply a sign of things to come about the never-ending pseudo-celebrity.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Brilliant flashes of light
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bob_meg
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/12/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I saw this movie on release ages ago and it's not hard to fall in love with it at first. Stephen Dorff's performance is really amazing. You never think for a moment he isn't Cliff Spab, with all the pent-up rage, pain, hostility and hilarity that it entails. For the first half of the movie, it's really "the Cliff Spab/Stephen Dorff Show." He goes on a sort of Jack Kerouac road trip, bumping heads and rubbing noses with a variety of characters (and some wonderful actors who play them): Jake Busey (a good movie for once), Joey Lauren Adams (always terrific and smokin' hot here), and Pamela Gidley (quite a complex little cameo). But after his odyssey ends, there doesn't seem to be much of a place to go...the film just stalls. I think the intent was for it to be completely character driven, so I wasn't expecting, well, a story-line or anything, but still.... I was hoping for more of a connection between the final scene, Spab's revelations, and the rest of the movie leading up to that point, but it didn't happen. Never read the book, but it sounds like that ending would have made more sense. A movie this dark doesn't deserve a happy ending....a little too tidy, in my opinion. But SFW?
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Brilliant
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    lee-todman
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/6/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This has to be the ultimate teenage rebellion movie and it does not get better than this. An attack on the media - I don't think so, the media as usual always turn things upside down. The plot, Directing and acting were top class especially Stephen Dorf. I am 40 years old and can still enjoy watching this movie, it's just so dam good. I bought this movie as soon as it was released on DVD, it's a classic and I think it will remain that way for many years. Anybody who didn't enjoy this movie might want to see it again and get a fresh perspective. The truth it tells about society and the media is brilliant and if you cant see that then you must be blind. Top class movie and well done to everyone involved.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
 </reviews>
</filme>
