<filme>
 <id>
  1487
 </id>
 <imdburl>
  http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0106834
 </imdburl>
 <ano>
  1993
 </ano>
 <titulo>
  At&eacute; as Vaqueiras Ficam Tristes
 </titulo>
 <rating>
  4.1
 </rating>
 <sinopse>
  Sissy Hankshaw is born with enormous thumbs that help her hitchhiking through the US from a young age. She becomes a model in advertising and her NY agent 'the Countess' sends her to his ... &nbsp;&raquo;
 </sinopse>
 <storyline>
  Sissy Hankshaw is born with enormous thumbs that help her hitchhiking through the US from a young age. She becomes a model in advertising and her NY agent 'the Countess' sends her to his ranch in CA to shoot a commercial, set against the background of mating whooping cranes. There, she befriends Bonanza Jellybean, one of the cowgirls at the beauty- ranch. The cowgirls take command of the ranch from the Countess and 'drug' the cranes with 'peyote'. The police besiege the ranch.
 </storyline>
 <generos>
  <genero>
   Comedy
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Drama
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Romance
  </genero>
 </generos>
 <keywords>
  <keyword>
   ranch
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   cowgirl
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   whooping crane
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   thumb
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   peyote
  </keyword>
 </keywords>
 <diretores>
  <diretor>
   Gus Van Sant
  </diretor>
 </diretores>
 <escritores>
  <escritor>
   Tom Robbins
  </escritor>
  <escritor>
   Gus Van Sant
  </escritor>
 </escritores>
 <atores>
  <ator>
   Uma Thurman
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Lorraine Bracco
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Pat Morita
  </ator>
 </atores>
 <reviews>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Unconventional and entertaining film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Olya Ivanova
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Wow, I can't believe that the average rating for this movie is a 4! At first I thought it was rated by closed minded mainstreamers who enjoy The Avengers or Fast and Furious, but after reading the reviews I realized that most of the bad ratings come from the people who read the original novel the movie was based on, and I can totally understand where those people come from. But as a person who has not read the book and just accidentally stumbled upon this film, it turned out to be a pleasant surprise. It was strange, surprising, sexual. It kept me tuned till the end and although the original plot may have been truncated and the details emboldened by the pace of the film, I definitely don't think it deserves a 4. As a new viewer to this story, I was left with a feeling of being entertained.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    WTF is that for a movie!?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Rold-Ickam
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I saw the movie years ago in a small theater in Brussels. Small theater, small crowd, quite comfy to appreciate an independent movie. That movie made a very strong impression on me as I left the place wondering if I had turned completely stupid or if the movie didn't make any sense at all !? Honest, I do appreciate (some) art films for their different view on the world's craziness. But this movie is pure spit in the audience's face. The cast is amazing but the way these poor fellows were directed into this joke is pure bad. I don't know maybe the director was under very strong influence when directing and editing? Which would explain why it makes no sense... I admit I didn't read the book and maybe I should have. But we're talking about the movie here and clearly I couldn't find anything good or appealing in it. It's a shame Uma Thurman started her acting career with that. I'm just glad it didn't stick to her later on... same for Keanu Reeves!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I've got your a spoiler right here: this movie stinks!!!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    RondoHatton
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/8/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Uma Thurman is not a very good actress. She's tall, & reasonably attractive, & sometimes blonde, but she was the poster-girl for the Uber-hip set in the late 80's/early 90's so for that set, she was a perfect choice as Cissy Hankshaw. Having read & loved this book, I knew she was not a good choice, and she was subsequently was named Worst Actress of 1993 for her terrible attempt to portray Cissy. Likewise, Rain aka Rainbow aka Rain Phoenix was also miscast, as well as not being talented enough to pull off what could have been a great role, that of Boss Cowgirl Bonanza Jellybean. Rain Phoenix didn't look as if she was reading off a TelePrompter, she looked like she was A)Wondering what a TelePrompter was & B)Wondering what to to with a TelePrompter once she figured out what it was. I've seen better acting in 1950's Mexican porn. Did I detect her lips moving before she attempted to deliver her lines? The reason she was not named Worst Actress of 1993 was that to win that award, she had to be an actress, which she clearly is not. Sean Young looked so sexy I almost forgot about her psychotic meltdown over James Woods, but she showed less acting ability than in her role in "Blade Runner". Angie Dickinson, that 60's-70's retread hearthrob of teenage males was nearly as bad as Phoenix & Thurman, but she had an excuse, she hadn't worked for many years, & seemed critically hungover. That's the bad news. The good news is, the rest of the cast was a hoot! Batting leadoff, the always weird & wonderful Carol Kane & Buck Henry(why don't those two have children?? What a great idea), John Hurt in drag, Crispin Glover, Pat Morita(as Noryuki)as The Chink("Ha Ha Ho Ho and Hee Hee!!"), Keanu Reeves was entirely adequate as Julian Gitchee, but any one of a number of Native American, Canadian, or Ecuadoran actors would have been a better choice, such as the lovely & talented Gary Farmer. Two other bones to pick: 1) Tom Robbins' favorite Native American tribe, is not pronounced See-Wash, but Sigh-wash and B) Why was the locale moved from the Dakotas to Deschutes County, Oregon, and then accused of being California(rather than just Californicated)? Stupid idea. I really loved Crispin Glover & John Hurt, but their performances are not enough to tempt me to watch this terrible movie again. The personnel not named Phoenix, Young, Dickinson, or Thurman are the reason this piece of crap gets as many as two stars. Like many reviewers, anger is my strongest emotion at this attempt to adapt a really good book.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    What the...???
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bobvend
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/11/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I was torn between watching this "film" or tuning into the Paint Drying Channel. Deciding to watch this train wreck was the obvious wrong choice! Chock full of high-wattage stars that apparently made this on their lunch break, it was shot in Oregon but unfortunately it survived. The characters are so absurdly drawn and the acting is so wretched it is not even enjoyable on a So-Bad-It's-Good level. This is the perfect time-waster to watch if you have no standards and don't like movies which contain such annoying things as coherent narratives or even a point! How this turkey managed NOT to go direct-to-video is one of the amazing mysteries of the universe.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Two Hours Of My Life That I'll Never Gonna Get Back Again
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Rodrigo Amaro (rodrigo882008@hotmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/4/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A respectful director, a talented group of actors and one of the best first ten minutes I ever saw in a motion picture. "Even Cowgirls Get the Blues" lacks humor, talent, and most of all a good plot. And what's left to say? One of the Worst Films ever. I'll say to you don't even bother watching because it's a completely waste of time (for those who are about to rent it a waste of money, I feel sorry for those Gus Van Sant's die hard fans that payed for this nonsense to see this in theaters back in 1994). I mean, not absolutely total waste of time. The first 40 minutes are great, they left a curiosity in see what's going to happen next and then it's all downhill. Uma Thurman plays Sissy, a woman who was born with enormous thumbs that help her hitchhiking through the US. So far so good. When she goes to New York she becomes a model and eventually she starts working with 'the Countess' (John Hurt) an agent who sends her to a ranch in CA to shoot a commercial. In this beauty ranch she becomes friends of a bunch of cowgirls (all of them lesbians) and the movie turn out to be a unfunny piece of wasted moments where actors come and go without no explanation and we're sorry for them. A great list of good actors are present in this movie and they're all wasted: Keanu Reeves, Pat Morita, Udo Kier, Rain Phoenix, Angie Dickinson, Crispin Glover, Lorraine Bracco, Carol Kane, Sean Young, Grace Zabriskie, Ed Begley Jr., Buck Henry, Roseanne, Heather Graham and the uncredited appearances of Edward James Olmos and River Phoenix (I didn't find him through the whole movie so I can't say if he's good or bad, but I trust his enormous talent. This shouldn't be one of his last features). The bottom of line is this: a bad bad movie, without reasons to exist, and Gus van Sant shouldn't in any moment direct this thing. He's the accomplished author of masterpieces like "My Own Private Idaho", "Good Will Hunting", "Finding Forrester", "Milk", and "Drugstore Cowboy". He shouldn't be a part of such a creepy pointless movie. You can see that his name is written differently than in his other movies. Perhaps it's just a way to say how embarrassing this movie was to his career. Holded the record of the Worst Film I've seen until last year when I watched "Freddy Got Fingered", that one was a total disrespect to movie lovers. Anyway, I'm only giving one star to this because the beginning was quite impressive. That's it! 1/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Suuuuuuuuuuuuucked big time
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jaygllwy
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/11/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Why would any legitimate actor having read the script participated in this piece of crap? My god it is actually embarrassing to even watch it. I can't imagine the shame these people must feel for being a part of it. Also, there is apparently some controversy as to whether River Phoenix had a cameo in the movie. He was uncredited but his list of roles here (IMDB) does give him credit. BTW... Rain is his sister for those who have were asking before. This film is proof that no matter how many big "names" you have. Sow's ears don't make silk purses. I love Lorraine Bracco but this was just sad, sad, sad... Maybe somebody someday can explain to me the reason for this kind of film. It has no endearing, entertaining, or even comedic properties in comparison to it's bad everything else.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Poor
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Michael_Elliott
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/3/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Even Cowgirls Get the Blues (1993) * (out of 4) Sissy Hankshaw (Uma Thurman) had a bad joke played on her when she was born and that is the fact she was born with two huge thumbs. Her parents feared she'd never get married or amount to anything in life but one day her father makes a joke that she'd make a good hitchhiker. Sissy takes that advice and heads off in the world thumbing a ride to wherever she can get. As a teenager Sissy finds a modeling job in NYC for feminine hygiene advertisement, which claims she smells as good as she looks. After being the champ of feminine hygiene for five years running, Sissy finds herself back on the road traveling across the country. She eventually gets a phone call from the drag queen known as The Countess (John Hurt) who has managed to get her a new job up in Oregon. This job is working on a ranch, which has been taken over by a group of cowgirls who seem to be fighting exploitation. With Sissy there, the girls have a new fighter as well as possible lover. Even Cowgirls Get the Blues is based on a novel from Tom Robbins, which I haven't read. Perhaps had I read it I would have understood what this film was trying to say or trying to be about but as it is, I really have no idea. My only guess is that director Gun Van Sant was trying to recapture the exploitation films of the 1970's like Beyond the Valley of the Dolls but he fails miserably here and makes a film that's a bigger disgrace than his future remake of Psycho. The biggest joke running throughout the film is the stuff dealing with feminine hygiene and the fact that Sissy smells better than any other woman around. This stuff here is simply unfunny and I'm sure many would be offended by this humor. Since it's doesn't work and manages to be somewhat offensive I've got to wonder who this humor was meant to entertain. The other big joke is the huge thumbs, which lead to various dialogue scenes dealing with the joys of hitchhiking but once again, who in the world is suppose to find that entertaining? I've always enjoyed watching Uma Thurman because she's one of the most enlightening actresses out there. She can certainly handle comedy, which was proved in Mad Dog and Glory but it's clear she has no idea what to do with the material given to her. There's not a single moment in the film where I believed this was a real character and instead of any insight we are given two fake looking props to tell her story. What attracted her to this project is anyone's guess but what's even worse is the fact that the director got an all-star cast to appear in the film. Lorraine Bracco, Keanu Reeves, Crispin Glover, Angie Dickinson, Sean Young, Heather Graham and Roseanne are among the many familiar faces and none of them bring anything to their roles. My only guess is that these folks forgot to read the script and just thought the idea of being in a cameo would be cool. I remember watching this film opening day in Louisville, KY where the theater was fairly packed Before the movie opened you could tell there was a loud buzz about the film due to the director's previous films, which included Drugstore Cowboy. As soon as the film started you could feel that entire buzz leave the theater and for the next two hours there was a complete silence that was rather haunting. No one was fascinated by what they were seeing but instead every single person was in a state of shock. Was this film some kind of job? Did Van Sant make a bad film on purpose? That's my only guess because there's nothing going good for this turkey, which would give anyone the blues.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Worst movie of all time??? What sheltered movie-watching lives you must lead
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mdugan-3
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/3/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Worst movie of all time? Wow, whoa now. You cannot be serious. Maybe it's all about what you expect a movie to do to you. I live in Oregon, so I got to enjoy the beautifully-filmed shots of familiar yet still amazingly beautiful Smith Rocks and other areas in Central Oregon (as well as the sweet cameo of our own Ken Kesey and Ken Babbs looking down on baby Sissy's cradle at the beginning of the movie). Those alone were enough to spur me to give the movie a better than "average" score. Or .... Maybe it's all about what expectations you have. Having read the book AGES ago, and thinking to myself "goodness, no one could ever make a movie out of this interesting, quirky, weird book ... especially 20 years later, when mores (MORAYS -- can't put in the accent mark online) have changed" -- I was actually quite pleasantly surprised when I first watched the movie when it came out in 1994 and even liked it more today watching it again. Sissy was exquisitely cast, and I don't care what you all say, I was also pleasantly surprised at Rain Phoenix's and John Hurt's performances. I am not a lesbian nor bi nor trans, but have met many folks who are similar to the folks they were supposed to portray -- and those "real" folks kinda acted the same way as these actors acted. Stilted a bit, stage-ey -- always a bit "on." Gus Van Sant is one weird native Oregonian but by garsh he done a good job adapting this crazy book, IMHO.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    If you think the movie is weird...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Son_of_Mansfield
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/6/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    you should read the book. I wouldn't call it unfilmable, but it's certainly not a James Patterson or an Ira Levin novel. A girl born with large thumbs becomes a hitchhiker, a model, and a lobbyist for whopping cranes with her lover Bananza Jellybean. I love this book. The movie is not as bad as you may have heard. Uma Thurman is perfectly cast. She is just quirky enough to pull off the thumbs and obviously good looking enough to be a model. The rest of the cast is woefully miscast, mostly due to being too old for the parts, such as Lorraine Bracco and Pat Moriata. But the thing that really drags the movie down is that the spirit is missing. Even Cowgirls Get the Blues was written in the sixties, the time of free love, and man is the love free in the book. There is too much fear now to make a movie like that. Also, there were different ideals about psychiatry, philosophy, and freedom. It's a true product of it's time and could be filmed by someone with guts. Until then, I can always read the book again...
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Decent Movie Version of a Tough Book to translate to screen.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mickeydl
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/1/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    If you have ever read and enjoyed a novel by Tom Robbins you will appreciate this movie as a whole-hearted attempt to translate his outrageously unconventional writing style into a workable piece of big screen art. The actors and the direction of this film are both good. The only trouble with the film, as I can see it, is that Robbins can relate ideas and sentiments with his words that were still beyond Hollywood's capabilities at the time this film was shot. Given both the irreverence of today's movies, as well as the willingness and abilityof today's audiences to delve into the bizarre, I think "Even Cowgirls... would receive a better reception today than it did when it was originally released.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Unconventional and entertaining film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Olya Ivanova
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Wow, I can't believe that the average rating for this movie is a 4! At first I thought it was rated by closed minded mainstreamers who enjoy The Avengers or Fast and Furious, but after reading the reviews I realized that most of the bad ratings come from the people who read the original novel the movie was based on, and I can totally understand where those people come from. But as a person who has not read the book and just accidentally stumbled upon this film, it turned out to be a pleasant surprise. It was strange, surprising, sexual. It kept me tuned till the end and although the original plot may have been truncated and the details emboldened by the pace of the film, I definitely don't think it deserves a 4. As a new viewer to this story, I was left with a feeling of being entertained.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    WTF is that for a movie!?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Rold-Ickam
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I saw the movie years ago in a small theater in Brussels. Small theater, small crowd, quite comfy to appreciate an independent movie. That movie made a very strong impression on me as I left the place wondering if I had turned completely stupid or if the movie didn't make any sense at all !? Honest, I do appreciate (some) art films for their different view on the world's craziness. But this movie is pure spit in the audience's face. The cast is amazing but the way these poor fellows were directed into this joke is pure bad. I don't know maybe the director was under very strong influence when directing and editing? Which would explain why it makes no sense... I admit I didn't read the book and maybe I should have. But we're talking about the movie here and clearly I couldn't find anything good or appealing in it. It's a shame Uma Thurman started her acting career with that. I'm just glad it didn't stick to her later on... same for Keanu Reeves!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I've got your a spoiler right here: this movie stinks!!!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    RondoHatton
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/8/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Uma Thurman is not a very good actress. She's tall, & reasonably attractive, & sometimes blonde, but she was the poster-girl for the Uber-hip set in the late 80's/early 90's so for that set, she was a perfect choice as Cissy Hankshaw. Having read & loved this book, I knew she was not a good choice, and she was subsequently was named Worst Actress of 1993 for her terrible attempt to portray Cissy. Likewise, Rain aka Rainbow aka Rain Phoenix was also miscast, as well as not being talented enough to pull off what could have been a great role, that of Boss Cowgirl Bonanza Jellybean. Rain Phoenix didn't look as if she was reading off a TelePrompter, she looked like she was A)Wondering what a TelePrompter was & B)Wondering what to to with a TelePrompter once she figured out what it was. I've seen better acting in 1950's Mexican porn. Did I detect her lips moving before she attempted to deliver her lines? The reason she was not named Worst Actress of 1993 was that to win that award, she had to be an actress, which she clearly is not. Sean Young looked so sexy I almost forgot about her psychotic meltdown over James Woods, but she showed less acting ability than in her role in "Blade Runner". Angie Dickinson, that 60's-70's retread hearthrob of teenage males was nearly as bad as Phoenix & Thurman, but she had an excuse, she hadn't worked for many years, & seemed critically hungover. That's the bad news. The good news is, the rest of the cast was a hoot! Batting leadoff, the always weird & wonderful Carol Kane & Buck Henry(why don't those two have children?? What a great idea), John Hurt in drag, Crispin Glover, Pat Morita(as Noryuki)as The Chink("Ha Ha Ho Ho and Hee Hee!!"), Keanu Reeves was entirely adequate as Julian Gitchee, but any one of a number of Native American, Canadian, or Ecuadoran actors would have been a better choice, such as the lovely & talented Gary Farmer. Two other bones to pick: 1) Tom Robbins' favorite Native American tribe, is not pronounced See-Wash, but Sigh-wash and B) Why was the locale moved from the Dakotas to Deschutes County, Oregon, and then accused of being California(rather than just Californicated)? Stupid idea. I really loved Crispin Glover & John Hurt, but their performances are not enough to tempt me to watch this terrible movie again. The personnel not named Phoenix, Young, Dickinson, or Thurman are the reason this piece of crap gets as many as two stars. Like many reviewers, anger is my strongest emotion at this attempt to adapt a really good book.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    What the...???
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bobvend
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/11/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I was torn between watching this "film" or tuning into the Paint Drying Channel. Deciding to watch this train wreck was the obvious wrong choice! Chock full of high-wattage stars that apparently made this on their lunch break, it was shot in Oregon but unfortunately it survived. The characters are so absurdly drawn and the acting is so wretched it is not even enjoyable on a So-Bad-It's-Good level. This is the perfect time-waster to watch if you have no standards and don't like movies which contain such annoying things as coherent narratives or even a point! How this turkey managed NOT to go direct-to-video is one of the amazing mysteries of the universe.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Two Hours Of My Life That I'll Never Gonna Get Back Again
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Rodrigo Amaro (rodrigo882008@hotmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/4/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A respectful director, a talented group of actors and one of the best first ten minutes I ever saw in a motion picture. "Even Cowgirls Get the Blues" lacks humor, talent, and most of all a good plot. And what's left to say? One of the Worst Films ever. I'll say to you don't even bother watching because it's a completely waste of time (for those who are about to rent it a waste of money, I feel sorry for those Gus Van Sant's die hard fans that payed for this nonsense to see this in theaters back in 1994). I mean, not absolutely total waste of time. The first 40 minutes are great, they left a curiosity in see what's going to happen next and then it's all downhill. Uma Thurman plays Sissy, a woman who was born with enormous thumbs that help her hitchhiking through the US. So far so good. When she goes to New York she becomes a model and eventually she starts working with 'the Countess' (John Hurt) an agent who sends her to a ranch in CA to shoot a commercial. In this beauty ranch she becomes friends of a bunch of cowgirls (all of them lesbians) and the movie turn out to be a unfunny piece of wasted moments where actors come and go without no explanation and we're sorry for them. A great list of good actors are present in this movie and they're all wasted: Keanu Reeves, Pat Morita, Udo Kier, Rain Phoenix, Angie Dickinson, Crispin Glover, Lorraine Bracco, Carol Kane, Sean Young, Grace Zabriskie, Ed Begley Jr., Buck Henry, Roseanne, Heather Graham and the uncredited appearances of Edward James Olmos and River Phoenix (I didn't find him through the whole movie so I can't say if he's good or bad, but I trust his enormous talent. This shouldn't be one of his last features). The bottom of line is this: a bad bad movie, without reasons to exist, and Gus van Sant shouldn't in any moment direct this thing. He's the accomplished author of masterpieces like "My Own Private Idaho", "Good Will Hunting", "Finding Forrester", "Milk", and "Drugstore Cowboy". He shouldn't be a part of such a creepy pointless movie. You can see that his name is written differently than in his other movies. Perhaps it's just a way to say how embarrassing this movie was to his career. Holded the record of the Worst Film I've seen until last year when I watched "Freddy Got Fingered", that one was a total disrespect to movie lovers. Anyway, I'm only giving one star to this because the beginning was quite impressive. That's it! 1/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Suuuuuuuuuuuuucked big time
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jaygllwy
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/11/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Why would any legitimate actor having read the script participated in this piece of crap? My god it is actually embarrassing to even watch it. I can't imagine the shame these people must feel for being a part of it. Also, there is apparently some controversy as to whether River Phoenix had a cameo in the movie. He was uncredited but his list of roles here (IMDB) does give him credit. BTW... Rain is his sister for those who have were asking before. This film is proof that no matter how many big "names" you have. Sow's ears don't make silk purses. I love Lorraine Bracco but this was just sad, sad, sad... Maybe somebody someday can explain to me the reason for this kind of film. It has no endearing, entertaining, or even comedic properties in comparison to it's bad everything else.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Poor
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Michael_Elliott
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/3/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Even Cowgirls Get the Blues (1993) * (out of 4) Sissy Hankshaw (Uma Thurman) had a bad joke played on her when she was born and that is the fact she was born with two huge thumbs. Her parents feared she'd never get married or amount to anything in life but one day her father makes a joke that she'd make a good hitchhiker. Sissy takes that advice and heads off in the world thumbing a ride to wherever she can get. As a teenager Sissy finds a modeling job in NYC for feminine hygiene advertisement, which claims she smells as good as she looks. After being the champ of feminine hygiene for five years running, Sissy finds herself back on the road traveling across the country. She eventually gets a phone call from the drag queen known as The Countess (John Hurt) who has managed to get her a new job up in Oregon. This job is working on a ranch, which has been taken over by a group of cowgirls who seem to be fighting exploitation. With Sissy there, the girls have a new fighter as well as possible lover. Even Cowgirls Get the Blues is based on a novel from Tom Robbins, which I haven't read. Perhaps had I read it I would have understood what this film was trying to say or trying to be about but as it is, I really have no idea. My only guess is that director Gun Van Sant was trying to recapture the exploitation films of the 1970's like Beyond the Valley of the Dolls but he fails miserably here and makes a film that's a bigger disgrace than his future remake of Psycho. The biggest joke running throughout the film is the stuff dealing with feminine hygiene and the fact that Sissy smells better than any other woman around. This stuff here is simply unfunny and I'm sure many would be offended by this humor. Since it's doesn't work and manages to be somewhat offensive I've got to wonder who this humor was meant to entertain. The other big joke is the huge thumbs, which lead to various dialogue scenes dealing with the joys of hitchhiking but once again, who in the world is suppose to find that entertaining? I've always enjoyed watching Uma Thurman because she's one of the most enlightening actresses out there. She can certainly handle comedy, which was proved in Mad Dog and Glory but it's clear she has no idea what to do with the material given to her. There's not a single moment in the film where I believed this was a real character and instead of any insight we are given two fake looking props to tell her story. What attracted her to this project is anyone's guess but what's even worse is the fact that the director got an all-star cast to appear in the film. Lorraine Bracco, Keanu Reeves, Crispin Glover, Angie Dickinson, Sean Young, Heather Graham and Roseanne are among the many familiar faces and none of them bring anything to their roles. My only guess is that these folks forgot to read the script and just thought the idea of being in a cameo would be cool. I remember watching this film opening day in Louisville, KY where the theater was fairly packed Before the movie opened you could tell there was a loud buzz about the film due to the director's previous films, which included Drugstore Cowboy. As soon as the film started you could feel that entire buzz leave the theater and for the next two hours there was a complete silence that was rather haunting. No one was fascinated by what they were seeing but instead every single person was in a state of shock. Was this film some kind of job? Did Van Sant make a bad film on purpose? That's my only guess because there's nothing going good for this turkey, which would give anyone the blues.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Worst movie of all time??? What sheltered movie-watching lives you must lead
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mdugan-3
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/3/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Worst movie of all time? Wow, whoa now. You cannot be serious. Maybe it's all about what you expect a movie to do to you. I live in Oregon, so I got to enjoy the beautifully-filmed shots of familiar yet still amazingly beautiful Smith Rocks and other areas in Central Oregon (as well as the sweet cameo of our own Ken Kesey and Ken Babbs looking down on baby Sissy's cradle at the beginning of the movie). Those alone were enough to spur me to give the movie a better than "average" score. Or .... Maybe it's all about what expectations you have. Having read the book AGES ago, and thinking to myself "goodness, no one could ever make a movie out of this interesting, quirky, weird book ... especially 20 years later, when mores (MORAYS -- can't put in the accent mark online) have changed" -- I was actually quite pleasantly surprised when I first watched the movie when it came out in 1994 and even liked it more today watching it again. Sissy was exquisitely cast, and I don't care what you all say, I was also pleasantly surprised at Rain Phoenix's and John Hurt's performances. I am not a lesbian nor bi nor trans, but have met many folks who are similar to the folks they were supposed to portray -- and those "real" folks kinda acted the same way as these actors acted. Stilted a bit, stage-ey -- always a bit "on." Gus Van Sant is one weird native Oregonian but by garsh he done a good job adapting this crazy book, IMHO.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    If you think the movie is weird...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Son_of_Mansfield
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/6/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    you should read the book. I wouldn't call it unfilmable, but it's certainly not a James Patterson or an Ira Levin novel. A girl born with large thumbs becomes a hitchhiker, a model, and a lobbyist for whopping cranes with her lover Bananza Jellybean. I love this book. The movie is not as bad as you may have heard. Uma Thurman is perfectly cast. She is just quirky enough to pull off the thumbs and obviously good looking enough to be a model. The rest of the cast is woefully miscast, mostly due to being too old for the parts, such as Lorraine Bracco and Pat Moriata. But the thing that really drags the movie down is that the spirit is missing. Even Cowgirls Get the Blues was written in the sixties, the time of free love, and man is the love free in the book. There is too much fear now to make a movie like that. Also, there were different ideals about psychiatry, philosophy, and freedom. It's a true product of it's time and could be filmed by someone with guts. Until then, I can always read the book again...
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Decent Movie Version of a Tough Book to translate to screen.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mickeydl
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/1/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    If you have ever read and enjoyed a novel by Tom Robbins you will appreciate this movie as a whole-hearted attempt to translate his outrageously unconventional writing style into a workable piece of big screen art. The actors and the direction of this film are both good. The only trouble with the film, as I can see it, is that Robbins can relate ideas and sentiments with his words that were still beyond Hollywood's capabilities at the time this film was shot. Given both the irreverence of today's movies, as well as the willingness and abilityof today's audiences to delve into the bizarre, I think "Even Cowgirls... would receive a better reception today than it did when it was originally released.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Unconventional and entertaining film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Olya Ivanova
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Wow, I can't believe that the average rating for this movie is a 4! At first I thought it was rated by closed minded mainstreamers who enjoy The Avengers or Fast and Furious, but after reading the reviews I realized that most of the bad ratings come from the people who read the original novel the movie was based on, and I can totally understand where those people come from. But as a person who has not read the book and just accidentally stumbled upon this film, it turned out to be a pleasant surprise. It was strange, surprising, sexual. It kept me tuned till the end and although the original plot may have been truncated and the details emboldened by the pace of the film, I definitely don't think it deserves a 4. As a new viewer to this story, I was left with a feeling of being entertained.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    WTF is that for a movie!?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Rold-Ickam
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I saw the movie years ago in a small theater in Brussels. Small theater, small crowd, quite comfy to appreciate an independent movie. That movie made a very strong impression on me as I left the place wondering if I had turned completely stupid or if the movie didn't make any sense at all !? Honest, I do appreciate (some) art films for their different view on the world's craziness. But this movie is pure spit in the audience's face. The cast is amazing but the way these poor fellows were directed into this joke is pure bad. I don't know maybe the director was under very strong influence when directing and editing? Which would explain why it makes no sense... I admit I didn't read the book and maybe I should have. But we're talking about the movie here and clearly I couldn't find anything good or appealing in it. It's a shame Uma Thurman started her acting career with that. I'm just glad it didn't stick to her later on... same for Keanu Reeves!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I've got your a spoiler right here: this movie stinks!!!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    RondoHatton
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/8/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Uma Thurman is not a very good actress. She's tall, & reasonably attractive, & sometimes blonde, but she was the poster-girl for the Uber-hip set in the late 80's/early 90's so for that set, she was a perfect choice as Cissy Hankshaw. Having read & loved this book, I knew she was not a good choice, and she was subsequently was named Worst Actress of 1993 for her terrible attempt to portray Cissy. Likewise, Rain aka Rainbow aka Rain Phoenix was also miscast, as well as not being talented enough to pull off what could have been a great role, that of Boss Cowgirl Bonanza Jellybean. Rain Phoenix didn't look as if she was reading off a TelePrompter, she looked like she was A)Wondering what a TelePrompter was & B)Wondering what to to with a TelePrompter once she figured out what it was. I've seen better acting in 1950's Mexican porn. Did I detect her lips moving before she attempted to deliver her lines? The reason she was not named Worst Actress of 1993 was that to win that award, she had to be an actress, which she clearly is not. Sean Young looked so sexy I almost forgot about her psychotic meltdown over James Woods, but she showed less acting ability than in her role in "Blade Runner". Angie Dickinson, that 60's-70's retread hearthrob of teenage males was nearly as bad as Phoenix & Thurman, but she had an excuse, she hadn't worked for many years, & seemed critically hungover. That's the bad news. The good news is, the rest of the cast was a hoot! Batting leadoff, the always weird & wonderful Carol Kane & Buck Henry(why don't those two have children?? What a great idea), John Hurt in drag, Crispin Glover, Pat Morita(as Noryuki)as The Chink("Ha Ha Ho Ho and Hee Hee!!"), Keanu Reeves was entirely adequate as Julian Gitchee, but any one of a number of Native American, Canadian, or Ecuadoran actors would have been a better choice, such as the lovely & talented Gary Farmer. Two other bones to pick: 1) Tom Robbins' favorite Native American tribe, is not pronounced See-Wash, but Sigh-wash and B) Why was the locale moved from the Dakotas to Deschutes County, Oregon, and then accused of being California(rather than just Californicated)? Stupid idea. I really loved Crispin Glover & John Hurt, but their performances are not enough to tempt me to watch this terrible movie again. The personnel not named Phoenix, Young, Dickinson, or Thurman are the reason this piece of crap gets as many as two stars. Like many reviewers, anger is my strongest emotion at this attempt to adapt a really good book.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    What the...???
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bobvend
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/11/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I was torn between watching this "film" or tuning into the Paint Drying Channel. Deciding to watch this train wreck was the obvious wrong choice! Chock full of high-wattage stars that apparently made this on their lunch break, it was shot in Oregon but unfortunately it survived. The characters are so absurdly drawn and the acting is so wretched it is not even enjoyable on a So-Bad-It's-Good level. This is the perfect time-waster to watch if you have no standards and don't like movies which contain such annoying things as coherent narratives or even a point! How this turkey managed NOT to go direct-to-video is one of the amazing mysteries of the universe.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Two Hours Of My Life That I'll Never Gonna Get Back Again
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Rodrigo Amaro (rodrigo882008@hotmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/4/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A respectful director, a talented group of actors and one of the best first ten minutes I ever saw in a motion picture. "Even Cowgirls Get the Blues" lacks humor, talent, and most of all a good plot. And what's left to say? One of the Worst Films ever. I'll say to you don't even bother watching because it's a completely waste of time (for those who are about to rent it a waste of money, I feel sorry for those Gus Van Sant's die hard fans that payed for this nonsense to see this in theaters back in 1994). I mean, not absolutely total waste of time. The first 40 minutes are great, they left a curiosity in see what's going to happen next and then it's all downhill. Uma Thurman plays Sissy, a woman who was born with enormous thumbs that help her hitchhiking through the US. So far so good. When she goes to New York she becomes a model and eventually she starts working with 'the Countess' (John Hurt) an agent who sends her to a ranch in CA to shoot a commercial. In this beauty ranch she becomes friends of a bunch of cowgirls (all of them lesbians) and the movie turn out to be a unfunny piece of wasted moments where actors come and go without no explanation and we're sorry for them. A great list of good actors are present in this movie and they're all wasted: Keanu Reeves, Pat Morita, Udo Kier, Rain Phoenix, Angie Dickinson, Crispin Glover, Lorraine Bracco, Carol Kane, Sean Young, Grace Zabriskie, Ed Begley Jr., Buck Henry, Roseanne, Heather Graham and the uncredited appearances of Edward James Olmos and River Phoenix (I didn't find him through the whole movie so I can't say if he's good or bad, but I trust his enormous talent. This shouldn't be one of his last features). The bottom of line is this: a bad bad movie, without reasons to exist, and Gus van Sant shouldn't in any moment direct this thing. He's the accomplished author of masterpieces like "My Own Private Idaho", "Good Will Hunting", "Finding Forrester", "Milk", and "Drugstore Cowboy". He shouldn't be a part of such a creepy pointless movie. You can see that his name is written differently than in his other movies. Perhaps it's just a way to say how embarrassing this movie was to his career. Holded the record of the Worst Film I've seen until last year when I watched "Freddy Got Fingered", that one was a total disrespect to movie lovers. Anyway, I'm only giving one star to this because the beginning was quite impressive. That's it! 1/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Suuuuuuuuuuuuucked big time
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jaygllwy
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/11/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Why would any legitimate actor having read the script participated in this piece of crap? My god it is actually embarrassing to even watch it. I can't imagine the shame these people must feel for being a part of it. Also, there is apparently some controversy as to whether River Phoenix had a cameo in the movie. He was uncredited but his list of roles here (IMDB) does give him credit. BTW... Rain is his sister for those who have were asking before. This film is proof that no matter how many big "names" you have. Sow's ears don't make silk purses. I love Lorraine Bracco but this was just sad, sad, sad... Maybe somebody someday can explain to me the reason for this kind of film. It has no endearing, entertaining, or even comedic properties in comparison to it's bad everything else.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Poor
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Michael_Elliott
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/3/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Even Cowgirls Get the Blues (1993) * (out of 4) Sissy Hankshaw (Uma Thurman) had a bad joke played on her when she was born and that is the fact she was born with two huge thumbs. Her parents feared she'd never get married or amount to anything in life but one day her father makes a joke that she'd make a good hitchhiker. Sissy takes that advice and heads off in the world thumbing a ride to wherever she can get. As a teenager Sissy finds a modeling job in NYC for feminine hygiene advertisement, which claims she smells as good as she looks. After being the champ of feminine hygiene for five years running, Sissy finds herself back on the road traveling across the country. She eventually gets a phone call from the drag queen known as The Countess (John Hurt) who has managed to get her a new job up in Oregon. This job is working on a ranch, which has been taken over by a group of cowgirls who seem to be fighting exploitation. With Sissy there, the girls have a new fighter as well as possible lover. Even Cowgirls Get the Blues is based on a novel from Tom Robbins, which I haven't read. Perhaps had I read it I would have understood what this film was trying to say or trying to be about but as it is, I really have no idea. My only guess is that director Gun Van Sant was trying to recapture the exploitation films of the 1970's like Beyond the Valley of the Dolls but he fails miserably here and makes a film that's a bigger disgrace than his future remake of Psycho. The biggest joke running throughout the film is the stuff dealing with feminine hygiene and the fact that Sissy smells better than any other woman around. This stuff here is simply unfunny and I'm sure many would be offended by this humor. Since it's doesn't work and manages to be somewhat offensive I've got to wonder who this humor was meant to entertain. The other big joke is the huge thumbs, which lead to various dialogue scenes dealing with the joys of hitchhiking but once again, who in the world is suppose to find that entertaining? I've always enjoyed watching Uma Thurman because she's one of the most enlightening actresses out there. She can certainly handle comedy, which was proved in Mad Dog and Glory but it's clear she has no idea what to do with the material given to her. There's not a single moment in the film where I believed this was a real character and instead of any insight we are given two fake looking props to tell her story. What attracted her to this project is anyone's guess but what's even worse is the fact that the director got an all-star cast to appear in the film. Lorraine Bracco, Keanu Reeves, Crispin Glover, Angie Dickinson, Sean Young, Heather Graham and Roseanne are among the many familiar faces and none of them bring anything to their roles. My only guess is that these folks forgot to read the script and just thought the idea of being in a cameo would be cool. I remember watching this film opening day in Louisville, KY where the theater was fairly packed Before the movie opened you could tell there was a loud buzz about the film due to the director's previous films, which included Drugstore Cowboy. As soon as the film started you could feel that entire buzz leave the theater and for the next two hours there was a complete silence that was rather haunting. No one was fascinated by what they were seeing but instead every single person was in a state of shock. Was this film some kind of job? Did Van Sant make a bad film on purpose? That's my only guess because there's nothing going good for this turkey, which would give anyone the blues.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Worst movie of all time??? What sheltered movie-watching lives you must lead
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mdugan-3
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/3/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Worst movie of all time? Wow, whoa now. You cannot be serious. Maybe it's all about what you expect a movie to do to you. I live in Oregon, so I got to enjoy the beautifully-filmed shots of familiar yet still amazingly beautiful Smith Rocks and other areas in Central Oregon (as well as the sweet cameo of our own Ken Kesey and Ken Babbs looking down on baby Sissy's cradle at the beginning of the movie). Those alone were enough to spur me to give the movie a better than "average" score. Or .... Maybe it's all about what expectations you have. Having read the book AGES ago, and thinking to myself "goodness, no one could ever make a movie out of this interesting, quirky, weird book ... especially 20 years later, when mores (MORAYS -- can't put in the accent mark online) have changed" -- I was actually quite pleasantly surprised when I first watched the movie when it came out in 1994 and even liked it more today watching it again. Sissy was exquisitely cast, and I don't care what you all say, I was also pleasantly surprised at Rain Phoenix's and John Hurt's performances. I am not a lesbian nor bi nor trans, but have met many folks who are similar to the folks they were supposed to portray -- and those "real" folks kinda acted the same way as these actors acted. Stilted a bit, stage-ey -- always a bit "on." Gus Van Sant is one weird native Oregonian but by garsh he done a good job adapting this crazy book, IMHO.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    If you think the movie is weird...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Son_of_Mansfield
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/6/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    you should read the book. I wouldn't call it unfilmable, but it's certainly not a James Patterson or an Ira Levin novel. A girl born with large thumbs becomes a hitchhiker, a model, and a lobbyist for whopping cranes with her lover Bananza Jellybean. I love this book. The movie is not as bad as you may have heard. Uma Thurman is perfectly cast. She is just quirky enough to pull off the thumbs and obviously good looking enough to be a model. The rest of the cast is woefully miscast, mostly due to being too old for the parts, such as Lorraine Bracco and Pat Moriata. But the thing that really drags the movie down is that the spirit is missing. Even Cowgirls Get the Blues was written in the sixties, the time of free love, and man is the love free in the book. There is too much fear now to make a movie like that. Also, there were different ideals about psychiatry, philosophy, and freedom. It's a true product of it's time and could be filmed by someone with guts. Until then, I can always read the book again...
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Decent Movie Version of a Tough Book to translate to screen.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mickeydl
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/1/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    If you have ever read and enjoyed a novel by Tom Robbins you will appreciate this movie as a whole-hearted attempt to translate his outrageously unconventional writing style into a workable piece of big screen art. The actors and the direction of this film are both good. The only trouble with the film, as I can see it, is that Robbins can relate ideas and sentiments with his words that were still beyond Hollywood's capabilities at the time this film was shot. Given both the irreverence of today's movies, as well as the willingness and abilityof today's audiences to delve into the bizarre, I think "Even Cowgirls... would receive a better reception today than it did when it was originally released.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Unconventional and entertaining film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Olya Ivanova
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Wow, I can't believe that the average rating for this movie is a 4! At first I thought it was rated by closed minded mainstreamers who enjoy The Avengers or Fast and Furious, but after reading the reviews I realized that most of the bad ratings come from the people who read the original novel the movie was based on, and I can totally understand where those people come from. But as a person who has not read the book and just accidentally stumbled upon this film, it turned out to be a pleasant surprise. It was strange, surprising, sexual. It kept me tuned till the end and although the original plot may have been truncated and the details emboldened by the pace of the film, I definitely don't think it deserves a 4. As a new viewer to this story, I was left with a feeling of being entertained.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    WTF is that for a movie!?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Rold-Ickam
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I saw the movie years ago in a small theater in Brussels. Small theater, small crowd, quite comfy to appreciate an independent movie. That movie made a very strong impression on me as I left the place wondering if I had turned completely stupid or if the movie didn't make any sense at all !? Honest, I do appreciate (some) art films for their different view on the world's craziness. But this movie is pure spit in the audience's face. The cast is amazing but the way these poor fellows were directed into this joke is pure bad. I don't know maybe the director was under very strong influence when directing and editing? Which would explain why it makes no sense... I admit I didn't read the book and maybe I should have. But we're talking about the movie here and clearly I couldn't find anything good or appealing in it. It's a shame Uma Thurman started her acting career with that. I'm just glad it didn't stick to her later on... same for Keanu Reeves!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I've got your a spoiler right here: this movie stinks!!!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    RondoHatton
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/8/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Uma Thurman is not a very good actress. She's tall, & reasonably attractive, & sometimes blonde, but she was the poster-girl for the Uber-hip set in the late 80's/early 90's so for that set, she was a perfect choice as Cissy Hankshaw. Having read & loved this book, I knew she was not a good choice, and she was subsequently was named Worst Actress of 1993 for her terrible attempt to portray Cissy. Likewise, Rain aka Rainbow aka Rain Phoenix was also miscast, as well as not being talented enough to pull off what could have been a great role, that of Boss Cowgirl Bonanza Jellybean. Rain Phoenix didn't look as if she was reading off a TelePrompter, she looked like she was A)Wondering what a TelePrompter was & B)Wondering what to to with a TelePrompter once she figured out what it was. I've seen better acting in 1950's Mexican porn. Did I detect her lips moving before she attempted to deliver her lines? The reason she was not named Worst Actress of 1993 was that to win that award, she had to be an actress, which she clearly is not. Sean Young looked so sexy I almost forgot about her psychotic meltdown over James Woods, but she showed less acting ability than in her role in "Blade Runner". Angie Dickinson, that 60's-70's retread hearthrob of teenage males was nearly as bad as Phoenix & Thurman, but she had an excuse, she hadn't worked for many years, & seemed critically hungover. That's the bad news. The good news is, the rest of the cast was a hoot! Batting leadoff, the always weird & wonderful Carol Kane & Buck Henry(why don't those two have children?? What a great idea), John Hurt in drag, Crispin Glover, Pat Morita(as Noryuki)as The Chink("Ha Ha Ho Ho and Hee Hee!!"), Keanu Reeves was entirely adequate as Julian Gitchee, but any one of a number of Native American, Canadian, or Ecuadoran actors would have been a better choice, such as the lovely & talented Gary Farmer. Two other bones to pick: 1) Tom Robbins' favorite Native American tribe, is not pronounced See-Wash, but Sigh-wash and B) Why was the locale moved from the Dakotas to Deschutes County, Oregon, and then accused of being California(rather than just Californicated)? Stupid idea. I really loved Crispin Glover & John Hurt, but their performances are not enough to tempt me to watch this terrible movie again. The personnel not named Phoenix, Young, Dickinson, or Thurman are the reason this piece of crap gets as many as two stars. Like many reviewers, anger is my strongest emotion at this attempt to adapt a really good book.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    What the...???
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bobvend
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/11/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I was torn between watching this "film" or tuning into the Paint Drying Channel. Deciding to watch this train wreck was the obvious wrong choice! Chock full of high-wattage stars that apparently made this on their lunch break, it was shot in Oregon but unfortunately it survived. The characters are so absurdly drawn and the acting is so wretched it is not even enjoyable on a So-Bad-It's-Good level. This is the perfect time-waster to watch if you have no standards and don't like movies which contain such annoying things as coherent narratives or even a point! How this turkey managed NOT to go direct-to-video is one of the amazing mysteries of the universe.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Two Hours Of My Life That I'll Never Gonna Get Back Again
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Rodrigo Amaro (rodrigo882008@hotmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/4/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A respectful director, a talented group of actors and one of the best first ten minutes I ever saw in a motion picture. "Even Cowgirls Get the Blues" lacks humor, talent, and most of all a good plot. And what's left to say? One of the Worst Films ever. I'll say to you don't even bother watching because it's a completely waste of time (for those who are about to rent it a waste of money, I feel sorry for those Gus Van Sant's die hard fans that payed for this nonsense to see this in theaters back in 1994). I mean, not absolutely total waste of time. The first 40 minutes are great, they left a curiosity in see what's going to happen next and then it's all downhill. Uma Thurman plays Sissy, a woman who was born with enormous thumbs that help her hitchhiking through the US. So far so good. When she goes to New York she becomes a model and eventually she starts working with 'the Countess' (John Hurt) an agent who sends her to a ranch in CA to shoot a commercial. In this beauty ranch she becomes friends of a bunch of cowgirls (all of them lesbians) and the movie turn out to be a unfunny piece of wasted moments where actors come and go without no explanation and we're sorry for them. A great list of good actors are present in this movie and they're all wasted: Keanu Reeves, Pat Morita, Udo Kier, Rain Phoenix, Angie Dickinson, Crispin Glover, Lorraine Bracco, Carol Kane, Sean Young, Grace Zabriskie, Ed Begley Jr., Buck Henry, Roseanne, Heather Graham and the uncredited appearances of Edward James Olmos and River Phoenix (I didn't find him through the whole movie so I can't say if he's good or bad, but I trust his enormous talent. This shouldn't be one of his last features). The bottom of line is this: a bad bad movie, without reasons to exist, and Gus van Sant shouldn't in any moment direct this thing. He's the accomplished author of masterpieces like "My Own Private Idaho", "Good Will Hunting", "Finding Forrester", "Milk", and "Drugstore Cowboy". He shouldn't be a part of such a creepy pointless movie. You can see that his name is written differently than in his other movies. Perhaps it's just a way to say how embarrassing this movie was to his career. Holded the record of the Worst Film I've seen until last year when I watched "Freddy Got Fingered", that one was a total disrespect to movie lovers. Anyway, I'm only giving one star to this because the beginning was quite impressive. That's it! 1/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Suuuuuuuuuuuuucked big time
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jaygllwy
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/11/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Why would any legitimate actor having read the script participated in this piece of crap? My god it is actually embarrassing to even watch it. I can't imagine the shame these people must feel for being a part of it. Also, there is apparently some controversy as to whether River Phoenix had a cameo in the movie. He was uncredited but his list of roles here (IMDB) does give him credit. BTW... Rain is his sister for those who have were asking before. This film is proof that no matter how many big "names" you have. Sow's ears don't make silk purses. I love Lorraine Bracco but this was just sad, sad, sad... Maybe somebody someday can explain to me the reason for this kind of film. It has no endearing, entertaining, or even comedic properties in comparison to it's bad everything else.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Poor
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Michael_Elliott
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/3/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Even Cowgirls Get the Blues (1993) * (out of 4) Sissy Hankshaw (Uma Thurman) had a bad joke played on her when she was born and that is the fact she was born with two huge thumbs. Her parents feared she'd never get married or amount to anything in life but one day her father makes a joke that she'd make a good hitchhiker. Sissy takes that advice and heads off in the world thumbing a ride to wherever she can get. As a teenager Sissy finds a modeling job in NYC for feminine hygiene advertisement, which claims she smells as good as she looks. After being the champ of feminine hygiene for five years running, Sissy finds herself back on the road traveling across the country. She eventually gets a phone call from the drag queen known as The Countess (John Hurt) who has managed to get her a new job up in Oregon. This job is working on a ranch, which has been taken over by a group of cowgirls who seem to be fighting exploitation. With Sissy there, the girls have a new fighter as well as possible lover. Even Cowgirls Get the Blues is based on a novel from Tom Robbins, which I haven't read. Perhaps had I read it I would have understood what this film was trying to say or trying to be about but as it is, I really have no idea. My only guess is that director Gun Van Sant was trying to recapture the exploitation films of the 1970's like Beyond the Valley of the Dolls but he fails miserably here and makes a film that's a bigger disgrace than his future remake of Psycho. The biggest joke running throughout the film is the stuff dealing with feminine hygiene and the fact that Sissy smells better than any other woman around. This stuff here is simply unfunny and I'm sure many would be offended by this humor. Since it's doesn't work and manages to be somewhat offensive I've got to wonder who this humor was meant to entertain. The other big joke is the huge thumbs, which lead to various dialogue scenes dealing with the joys of hitchhiking but once again, who in the world is suppose to find that entertaining? I've always enjoyed watching Uma Thurman because she's one of the most enlightening actresses out there. She can certainly handle comedy, which was proved in Mad Dog and Glory but it's clear she has no idea what to do with the material given to her. There's not a single moment in the film where I believed this was a real character and instead of any insight we are given two fake looking props to tell her story. What attracted her to this project is anyone's guess but what's even worse is the fact that the director got an all-star cast to appear in the film. Lorraine Bracco, Keanu Reeves, Crispin Glover, Angie Dickinson, Sean Young, Heather Graham and Roseanne are among the many familiar faces and none of them bring anything to their roles. My only guess is that these folks forgot to read the script and just thought the idea of being in a cameo would be cool. I remember watching this film opening day in Louisville, KY where the theater was fairly packed Before the movie opened you could tell there was a loud buzz about the film due to the director's previous films, which included Drugstore Cowboy. As soon as the film started you could feel that entire buzz leave the theater and for the next two hours there was a complete silence that was rather haunting. No one was fascinated by what they were seeing but instead every single person was in a state of shock. Was this film some kind of job? Did Van Sant make a bad film on purpose? That's my only guess because there's nothing going good for this turkey, which would give anyone the blues.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Worst movie of all time??? What sheltered movie-watching lives you must lead
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mdugan-3
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/3/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Worst movie of all time? Wow, whoa now. You cannot be serious. Maybe it's all about what you expect a movie to do to you. I live in Oregon, so I got to enjoy the beautifully-filmed shots of familiar yet still amazingly beautiful Smith Rocks and other areas in Central Oregon (as well as the sweet cameo of our own Ken Kesey and Ken Babbs looking down on baby Sissy's cradle at the beginning of the movie). Those alone were enough to spur me to give the movie a better than "average" score. Or .... Maybe it's all about what expectations you have. Having read the book AGES ago, and thinking to myself "goodness, no one could ever make a movie out of this interesting, quirky, weird book ... especially 20 years later, when mores (MORAYS -- can't put in the accent mark online) have changed" -- I was actually quite pleasantly surprised when I first watched the movie when it came out in 1994 and even liked it more today watching it again. Sissy was exquisitely cast, and I don't care what you all say, I was also pleasantly surprised at Rain Phoenix's and John Hurt's performances. I am not a lesbian nor bi nor trans, but have met many folks who are similar to the folks they were supposed to portray -- and those "real" folks kinda acted the same way as these actors acted. Stilted a bit, stage-ey -- always a bit "on." Gus Van Sant is one weird native Oregonian but by garsh he done a good job adapting this crazy book, IMHO.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    If you think the movie is weird...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Son_of_Mansfield
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/6/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    you should read the book. I wouldn't call it unfilmable, but it's certainly not a James Patterson or an Ira Levin novel. A girl born with large thumbs becomes a hitchhiker, a model, and a lobbyist for whopping cranes with her lover Bananza Jellybean. I love this book. The movie is not as bad as you may have heard. Uma Thurman is perfectly cast. She is just quirky enough to pull off the thumbs and obviously good looking enough to be a model. The rest of the cast is woefully miscast, mostly due to being too old for the parts, such as Lorraine Bracco and Pat Moriata. But the thing that really drags the movie down is that the spirit is missing. Even Cowgirls Get the Blues was written in the sixties, the time of free love, and man is the love free in the book. There is too much fear now to make a movie like that. Also, there were different ideals about psychiatry, philosophy, and freedom. It's a true product of it's time and could be filmed by someone with guts. Until then, I can always read the book again...
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Decent Movie Version of a Tough Book to translate to screen.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mickeydl
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/1/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    If you have ever read and enjoyed a novel by Tom Robbins you will appreciate this movie as a whole-hearted attempt to translate his outrageously unconventional writing style into a workable piece of big screen art. The actors and the direction of this film are both good. The only trouble with the film, as I can see it, is that Robbins can relate ideas and sentiments with his words that were still beyond Hollywood's capabilities at the time this film was shot. Given both the irreverence of today's movies, as well as the willingness and abilityof today's audiences to delve into the bizarre, I think "Even Cowgirls... would receive a better reception today than it did when it was originally released.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Unconventional and entertaining film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Olya Ivanova
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Wow, I can't believe that the average rating for this movie is a 4! At first I thought it was rated by closed minded mainstreamers who enjoy The Avengers or Fast and Furious, but after reading the reviews I realized that most of the bad ratings come from the people who read the original novel the movie was based on, and I can totally understand where those people come from. But as a person who has not read the book and just accidentally stumbled upon this film, it turned out to be a pleasant surprise. It was strange, surprising, sexual. It kept me tuned till the end and although the original plot may have been truncated and the details emboldened by the pace of the film, I definitely don't think it deserves a 4. As a new viewer to this story, I was left with a feeling of being entertained.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    WTF is that for a movie!?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Rold-Ickam
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I saw the movie years ago in a small theater in Brussels. Small theater, small crowd, quite comfy to appreciate an independent movie. That movie made a very strong impression on me as I left the place wondering if I had turned completely stupid or if the movie didn't make any sense at all !? Honest, I do appreciate (some) art films for their different view on the world's craziness. But this movie is pure spit in the audience's face. The cast is amazing but the way these poor fellows were directed into this joke is pure bad. I don't know maybe the director was under very strong influence when directing and editing? Which would explain why it makes no sense... I admit I didn't read the book and maybe I should have. But we're talking about the movie here and clearly I couldn't find anything good or appealing in it. It's a shame Uma Thurman started her acting career with that. I'm just glad it didn't stick to her later on... same for Keanu Reeves!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I've got your a spoiler right here: this movie stinks!!!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    RondoHatton
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/8/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Uma Thurman is not a very good actress. She's tall, & reasonably attractive, & sometimes blonde, but she was the poster-girl for the Uber-hip set in the late 80's/early 90's so for that set, she was a perfect choice as Cissy Hankshaw. Having read & loved this book, I knew she was not a good choice, and she was subsequently was named Worst Actress of 1993 for her terrible attempt to portray Cissy. Likewise, Rain aka Rainbow aka Rain Phoenix was also miscast, as well as not being talented enough to pull off what could have been a great role, that of Boss Cowgirl Bonanza Jellybean. Rain Phoenix didn't look as if she was reading off a TelePrompter, she looked like she was A)Wondering what a TelePrompter was & B)Wondering what to to with a TelePrompter once she figured out what it was. I've seen better acting in 1950's Mexican porn. Did I detect her lips moving before she attempted to deliver her lines? The reason she was not named Worst Actress of 1993 was that to win that award, she had to be an actress, which she clearly is not. Sean Young looked so sexy I almost forgot about her psychotic meltdown over James Woods, but she showed less acting ability than in her role in "Blade Runner". Angie Dickinson, that 60's-70's retread hearthrob of teenage males was nearly as bad as Phoenix & Thurman, but she had an excuse, she hadn't worked for many years, & seemed critically hungover. That's the bad news. The good news is, the rest of the cast was a hoot! Batting leadoff, the always weird & wonderful Carol Kane & Buck Henry(why don't those two have children?? What a great idea), John Hurt in drag, Crispin Glover, Pat Morita(as Noryuki)as The Chink("Ha Ha Ho Ho and Hee Hee!!"), Keanu Reeves was entirely adequate as Julian Gitchee, but any one of a number of Native American, Canadian, or Ecuadoran actors would have been a better choice, such as the lovely & talented Gary Farmer. Two other bones to pick: 1) Tom Robbins' favorite Native American tribe, is not pronounced See-Wash, but Sigh-wash and B) Why was the locale moved from the Dakotas to Deschutes County, Oregon, and then accused of being California(rather than just Californicated)? Stupid idea. I really loved Crispin Glover & John Hurt, but their performances are not enough to tempt me to watch this terrible movie again. The personnel not named Phoenix, Young, Dickinson, or Thurman are the reason this piece of crap gets as many as two stars. Like many reviewers, anger is my strongest emotion at this attempt to adapt a really good book.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    What the...???
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bobvend
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/11/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I was torn between watching this "film" or tuning into the Paint Drying Channel. Deciding to watch this train wreck was the obvious wrong choice! Chock full of high-wattage stars that apparently made this on their lunch break, it was shot in Oregon but unfortunately it survived. The characters are so absurdly drawn and the acting is so wretched it is not even enjoyable on a So-Bad-It's-Good level. This is the perfect time-waster to watch if you have no standards and don't like movies which contain such annoying things as coherent narratives or even a point! How this turkey managed NOT to go direct-to-video is one of the amazing mysteries of the universe.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Two Hours Of My Life That I'll Never Gonna Get Back Again
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Rodrigo Amaro (rodrigo882008@hotmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/4/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A respectful director, a talented group of actors and one of the best first ten minutes I ever saw in a motion picture. "Even Cowgirls Get the Blues" lacks humor, talent, and most of all a good plot. And what's left to say? One of the Worst Films ever. I'll say to you don't even bother watching because it's a completely waste of time (for those who are about to rent it a waste of money, I feel sorry for those Gus Van Sant's die hard fans that payed for this nonsense to see this in theaters back in 1994). I mean, not absolutely total waste of time. The first 40 minutes are great, they left a curiosity in see what's going to happen next and then it's all downhill. Uma Thurman plays Sissy, a woman who was born with enormous thumbs that help her hitchhiking through the US. So far so good. When she goes to New York she becomes a model and eventually she starts working with 'the Countess' (John Hurt) an agent who sends her to a ranch in CA to shoot a commercial. In this beauty ranch she becomes friends of a bunch of cowgirls (all of them lesbians) and the movie turn out to be a unfunny piece of wasted moments where actors come and go without no explanation and we're sorry for them. A great list of good actors are present in this movie and they're all wasted: Keanu Reeves, Pat Morita, Udo Kier, Rain Phoenix, Angie Dickinson, Crispin Glover, Lorraine Bracco, Carol Kane, Sean Young, Grace Zabriskie, Ed Begley Jr., Buck Henry, Roseanne, Heather Graham and the uncredited appearances of Edward James Olmos and River Phoenix (I didn't find him through the whole movie so I can't say if he's good or bad, but I trust his enormous talent. This shouldn't be one of his last features). The bottom of line is this: a bad bad movie, without reasons to exist, and Gus van Sant shouldn't in any moment direct this thing. He's the accomplished author of masterpieces like "My Own Private Idaho", "Good Will Hunting", "Finding Forrester", "Milk", and "Drugstore Cowboy". He shouldn't be a part of such a creepy pointless movie. You can see that his name is written differently than in his other movies. Perhaps it's just a way to say how embarrassing this movie was to his career. Holded the record of the Worst Film I've seen until last year when I watched "Freddy Got Fingered", that one was a total disrespect to movie lovers. Anyway, I'm only giving one star to this because the beginning was quite impressive. That's it! 1/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Suuuuuuuuuuuuucked big time
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jaygllwy
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/11/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Why would any legitimate actor having read the script participated in this piece of crap? My god it is actually embarrassing to even watch it. I can't imagine the shame these people must feel for being a part of it. Also, there is apparently some controversy as to whether River Phoenix had a cameo in the movie. He was uncredited but his list of roles here (IMDB) does give him credit. BTW... Rain is his sister for those who have were asking before. This film is proof that no matter how many big "names" you have. Sow's ears don't make silk purses. I love Lorraine Bracco but this was just sad, sad, sad... Maybe somebody someday can explain to me the reason for this kind of film. It has no endearing, entertaining, or even comedic properties in comparison to it's bad everything else.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Poor
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Michael_Elliott
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/3/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Even Cowgirls Get the Blues (1993) * (out of 4) Sissy Hankshaw (Uma Thurman) had a bad joke played on her when she was born and that is the fact she was born with two huge thumbs. Her parents feared she'd never get married or amount to anything in life but one day her father makes a joke that she'd make a good hitchhiker. Sissy takes that advice and heads off in the world thumbing a ride to wherever she can get. As a teenager Sissy finds a modeling job in NYC for feminine hygiene advertisement, which claims she smells as good as she looks. After being the champ of feminine hygiene for five years running, Sissy finds herself back on the road traveling across the country. She eventually gets a phone call from the drag queen known as The Countess (John Hurt) who has managed to get her a new job up in Oregon. This job is working on a ranch, which has been taken over by a group of cowgirls who seem to be fighting exploitation. With Sissy there, the girls have a new fighter as well as possible lover. Even Cowgirls Get the Blues is based on a novel from Tom Robbins, which I haven't read. Perhaps had I read it I would have understood what this film was trying to say or trying to be about but as it is, I really have no idea. My only guess is that director Gun Van Sant was trying to recapture the exploitation films of the 1970's like Beyond the Valley of the Dolls but he fails miserably here and makes a film that's a bigger disgrace than his future remake of Psycho. The biggest joke running throughout the film is the stuff dealing with feminine hygiene and the fact that Sissy smells better than any other woman around. This stuff here is simply unfunny and I'm sure many would be offended by this humor. Since it's doesn't work and manages to be somewhat offensive I've got to wonder who this humor was meant to entertain. The other big joke is the huge thumbs, which lead to various dialogue scenes dealing with the joys of hitchhiking but once again, who in the world is suppose to find that entertaining? I've always enjoyed watching Uma Thurman because she's one of the most enlightening actresses out there. She can certainly handle comedy, which was proved in Mad Dog and Glory but it's clear she has no idea what to do with the material given to her. There's not a single moment in the film where I believed this was a real character and instead of any insight we are given two fake looking props to tell her story. What attracted her to this project is anyone's guess but what's even worse is the fact that the director got an all-star cast to appear in the film. Lorraine Bracco, Keanu Reeves, Crispin Glover, Angie Dickinson, Sean Young, Heather Graham and Roseanne are among the many familiar faces and none of them bring anything to their roles. My only guess is that these folks forgot to read the script and just thought the idea of being in a cameo would be cool. I remember watching this film opening day in Louisville, KY where the theater was fairly packed Before the movie opened you could tell there was a loud buzz about the film due to the director's previous films, which included Drugstore Cowboy. As soon as the film started you could feel that entire buzz leave the theater and for the next two hours there was a complete silence that was rather haunting. No one was fascinated by what they were seeing but instead every single person was in a state of shock. Was this film some kind of job? Did Van Sant make a bad film on purpose? That's my only guess because there's nothing going good for this turkey, which would give anyone the blues.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Worst movie of all time??? What sheltered movie-watching lives you must lead
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mdugan-3
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/3/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Worst movie of all time? Wow, whoa now. You cannot be serious. Maybe it's all about what you expect a movie to do to you. I live in Oregon, so I got to enjoy the beautifully-filmed shots of familiar yet still amazingly beautiful Smith Rocks and other areas in Central Oregon (as well as the sweet cameo of our own Ken Kesey and Ken Babbs looking down on baby Sissy's cradle at the beginning of the movie). Those alone were enough to spur me to give the movie a better than "average" score. Or .... Maybe it's all about what expectations you have. Having read the book AGES ago, and thinking to myself "goodness, no one could ever make a movie out of this interesting, quirky, weird book ... especially 20 years later, when mores (MORAYS -- can't put in the accent mark online) have changed" -- I was actually quite pleasantly surprised when I first watched the movie when it came out in 1994 and even liked it more today watching it again. Sissy was exquisitely cast, and I don't care what you all say, I was also pleasantly surprised at Rain Phoenix's and John Hurt's performances. I am not a lesbian nor bi nor trans, but have met many folks who are similar to the folks they were supposed to portray -- and those "real" folks kinda acted the same way as these actors acted. Stilted a bit, stage-ey -- always a bit "on." Gus Van Sant is one weird native Oregonian but by garsh he done a good job adapting this crazy book, IMHO.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    If you think the movie is weird...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Son_of_Mansfield
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/6/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    you should read the book. I wouldn't call it unfilmable, but it's certainly not a James Patterson or an Ira Levin novel. A girl born with large thumbs becomes a hitchhiker, a model, and a lobbyist for whopping cranes with her lover Bananza Jellybean. I love this book. The movie is not as bad as you may have heard. Uma Thurman is perfectly cast. She is just quirky enough to pull off the thumbs and obviously good looking enough to be a model. The rest of the cast is woefully miscast, mostly due to being too old for the parts, such as Lorraine Bracco and Pat Moriata. But the thing that really drags the movie down is that the spirit is missing. Even Cowgirls Get the Blues was written in the sixties, the time of free love, and man is the love free in the book. There is too much fear now to make a movie like that. Also, there were different ideals about psychiatry, philosophy, and freedom. It's a true product of it's time and could be filmed by someone with guts. Until then, I can always read the book again...
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Decent Movie Version of a Tough Book to translate to screen.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mickeydl
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/1/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    If you have ever read and enjoyed a novel by Tom Robbins you will appreciate this movie as a whole-hearted attempt to translate his outrageously unconventional writing style into a workable piece of big screen art. The actors and the direction of this film are both good. The only trouble with the film, as I can see it, is that Robbins can relate ideas and sentiments with his words that were still beyond Hollywood's capabilities at the time this film was shot. Given both the irreverence of today's movies, as well as the willingness and abilityof today's audiences to delve into the bizarre, I think "Even Cowgirls... would receive a better reception today than it did when it was originally released.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
 </reviews>
</filme>
