<filme>
 <id>
  149
 </id>
 <imdburl>
  http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0116722
 </imdburl>
 <ano>
  1996
 </ano>
 <titulo>
  Paix&atilde;o Proibida
 </titulo>
 <rating>
  6.9
 </rating>
 <sinopse>
  A stonemason steadfastly pursues a cousin he loves. However their love is troubled as he is married to a woman who tricked him into marriage and she is married to a man she does not love. ... &nbsp;&raquo;
 </sinopse>
 <storyline>
  A stonemason steadfastly pursues a cousin he loves. However their love is troubled as he is married to a woman who tricked him into marriage and she is married to a man she does not love. Living out of wedlock, the two are rejected by the townspeople leaving them to struggle in abject poverty.
 </storyline>
 <generos>
  <genero>
   Drama
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Romance
  </genero>
 </generos>
 <keywords>
  <keyword>
   love
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   stonemason
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   education
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   female frontal nudity
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   passionate
  </keyword>
 </keywords>
 <diretores>
  <diretor>
   Michael Winterbottom
  </diretor>
 </diretores>
 <escritores>
  <escritor>
   Hossein Amini
  </escritor>
  <escritor>
   Thomas Hardy
  </escritor>
 </escritores>
 <atores>
  <ator>
   Christopher Eccleston
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Kate Winslet
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Liam Cunningham
  </ator>
 </atores>
 <reviews>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Hey Jude, you make it good (web)
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    leplatypus
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It's an excellent movie because it scores in each corner: it has a wonderful, gripping story that can speaks to anyone with heart. As it's an adaptation, you will be interested in reading the novel. Beyond the personal drama, I remember two scandals that are always verified today: 1) education is elitist as it expels those who don't have pedigree 2) Christian congregation is highly hypocritical as they achieve to turn a message of love into one of rejection. It has wonderful locations, between the green pastures and the austere British cities (for those who have seen Spielberg's "War Horse", it has the same ambiance). Winterbottom is inspired to fill his frames and Johnston's soundtrack is just one of the best ever as it gives such poetry to the pictures. As for the cast, it's just an amazing reunion: Eccleston finds his career pick as his Jude is such a good man: always sincere, hardworking, caring, sometimes sad but never quits! Kate is always fascinating by her precocity and by her personal choices for free- spirited characters!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A bitter reflection on non-conformity
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Malcolm Parker
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    With actors of the calibre of Kate Winslet and Christopher Eccleston, this drama could hardly have failed. That said, I felt something was lacking in the characterisation of Sue Bridehead, I haven't read the book, but there is a difficult combination of character traits that stumble between the intellectual and prim and the untethered and vivacious. I felt that we knew Jude, and all the other principle characters, but somehow Sue, despite a magnificent performance by Winslet remained detached and distant as though there was something unexplained in her make up. She was wholly unabashed about her and Jude's marital state, incredibly liberal in her adoption of Jude's son, but yet at times seemed almost uninvolved in her intimacy with Jude. I'm not sure what Hardy wrote, but I think revealing a little more of the motivation behind Sue's character would have clarified and improved the film immensely. Overall though, a very moving and beautifully shot construction, not quite in the same league as Polanski's Tess or Schlesinger's Far from the Madding Crowd, but a great film nevertheless.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "Jude"
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    francescof86
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Jude" is an extraordinary film by one of the most daring and amazing director out there ,as Michael Winterbottom. The original novel("Jude the Obscure") is translated in a brilliant script by Hossein Amini and centers on the aspirations of a lower-class man,Jude Fawley(Christopher Ecclestone),who fights to become a university man. After a quick and wrong marriage with an humble country girl,Arabella(Rachel Griffiths), he met his cousin Sue Bridehead(Kate Winslet)an intelligent,beautiful and apparently as unconventional and brave as him. Their passionate love will end tragically though. The film is from the end to the beginning sad and depressing at his best since we see Jude and Sue fight against the Victorian society's beliefs such as a legalized marriage(they only live as a couple)and the impossible aspirations of a lower-class man who would like to become equal to his peers and study at the university. Ultimately their lives will be destroyed by a cruel destiny. Jude is completely coherent to his ideas but Sue is a tormented and fragile woman who,in the end, is not able to came to terms with what she professed at the beginning. In the end, she turns to religion and accepts a life she rejected because she feels guilty. Christoph Ecclestone and Kate Winslet are just superb. Ecclestone is a serious underrated actor who should be in the spotlight. He never misses a beat and gives an amazing performance. Kate Winslet is completely committed to her role and gives a dramatic performance that is devastating. The director gives the a vivid and crude cut and confirms his uncommon abilities to tell a story set in a different era as we're seeing a modern tragedy.His direction is as tormented as his leads and we can't help but have a feeling that he is not afraid to show the crudest side and the terrible contradictions of the Victorian period. my vote is 10/10.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Suitably depressing piece of Hardy
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    miss_lady_ice-853-608700
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Jude The Obscure is Thomas Hardy's final novel, and his bleakest. It doesn't seem an obvious choice for cinema, hence why it failed at the box office. An air of gloom hangs over the whole proceedings. The story is a little like Tess- a man's chance at love is destroyed by a woman from his past. Jude (Christopher Eccleston) is the man in question- an ambitious country boy whose desire is to become a student at Christminster (Hardy's made-up name for Oxford). He moves to Christminster and falls in love with his clever cousin Sue Brideshead (Kate Winslet). Unfortunately he is already married- to loose country girl Arabella (Rachel Griffiths), who keeps popping up and ruining Jude's chance at happiness. The climax of the film is one of the most tragic and horrific things you will see in a long time. The film is quite well done. It is a bit graphic (this is Michael Winterbottom after all) and anachronistic in places, but there are enough tinges of Hardy to make it a costume drama. He certainly hasn't butchered it as he butchered Tess in his film Trishna. The problem of the film is that Jude is a bit of a ninny, who doesn't seem to have the ruthlessness or the cleverness needed to get into the academic elite and constantly runs back to Arabella. The incestuous aspect is also very off-putting. One feels sorry for Jude and Sue but one can never feel entirely comfortable with their relationship. Another problem, at least adaptation-wise, is that Arabella, who is a horrible sadist in the book from what I've heard, is merely a nuisance here. Perhaps Winterbottom thought that might be too much misery for people but it does mean that the film ends abruptly. Acting-wise, everything is fine. Eccleston convinces as a country boy, although his Northern accent does come out at times. Winslet does well as spirited Sue Brideshead, similar to Rose in Titanic so not much of a stretch for her. EDIT: Having now read the novel- not my favourite Hardy novel but a powerful novel nonetheless- the film gets the sexuality right. Everything that Hardy couldn't show, this film shows, so for those who complain that the film has too much nudity, this is actually quite true to the novel- particularly as none of it is very erotic. Jude's weakness for the flesh is almost animalistic. Leaving aside the hot and steamy, we have that whole spiritual dimension. That part of the novel is quite hard to translate and it doesn't really come through in this film. Jude is meant to be too noble for this world, hindered by his fleshy desires. And the film really does let Arabella off too lightly. In this, she's a typical country wench- a tart with not much of a heart. However in the book, she's not only a tart with no heart, she's a proper butcher, cruel to the point of sadism.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    This was a depressing and disturbing movie.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    rujammin2
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/1/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This was a depressing and disturbing movie. I Couldn't get this movie out of my head for a couple days and in a bad way! I wished I would of turned it off before I was so traumatized by it! It's long, cold , depressing and a waste of 2+ hours. The only reason I hung on was for the actors. Kate and Christopher made the best of a terrible story. The director did a great job of putting you right there in the movie. Unfortunately it's not a great place to be. Some of the scenes were just a little overly disturbing for my taste. This movie could of ended an hour earlier and it wouldn't of mattered. I strongly suggest skipping this unless you really want to fell deflated afterward.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    incompetent, poorly conceived, boring
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    withnail-4
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/1/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    What kind of person is Jude? does he have a love for Latin? Does he really want to be a scholar? What does he think of his wife Arabella? what is she like? Are we supposed to like her, dislike her? because...? because she is sensual? earthy? Is she too ignorant to be a good wife for Jude? Is Jude Smart? We see them have sex..and this means..? Not one scene has any development. Guy walks around in the rain, somebody tells a boy that education is everything...Is this Jude our hero? He is shown trying to memorize some Latin. How far has he progressed ...what does Classical literature mean to him? The viewer's emotions are not guided toward any coherent response ...scenes begin and end without discernible intention. Lazy, incompetent film directing. Not thought through. Watch a film Like Hobson's Choice by David Lean, in comparison, and appreciate how every image, gesture, every object, conveys thoughts, character, intentions. Someone intelligent sat down and thought through what to show and how. Scenes with beginnings, middles, and ends and meanings and direction. This film is, by contrast, a lazy, stupidly unrealized piece of incompetence. Kate Winslet's performance, and the beauty of the locations are the only positive parts.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Excellent!!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    dorothy-tripp
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/12/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    If you like dark dramas, this is your movie. Very true to the book and absolutely engrossing. The locations are beautiful. The acting is superb. The characters are richly brought out, and you can understand their thought processes. This is a moral play, as well as a look at the way society imposes rules of conduct. I stumbled on this wonderful film while watching the romance channel on television in 2000. I came in toward the middle, but was immediately drawn into the story. I searched high and low for the video, and when I want a moody drama, this is where I go. This film will make you think. Obviously, the book is practically required reading after you see this movie. You'll just be compelled to know more. Truly a haunting movie that you will remember for a long time.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Ambitious and anything but tender, but wonderfully acted and well adapted
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    TheLittleSongbird
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/11/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Thomas Hardy's Jude the Obscure is a very complicated and ambitious book, and while heavy-reading it is a fine piece of literature. This 1996 film adaptation is a rock-solid adaptation, that is ambitious and realistic. I will admit some parts like the killing of the pig is anything but tender, but none of the scenes are over-sensationalised. As an adaptation of the book, it works very well. If I had a quibble, the secondary characters could have been developed more than they were depicted. The screenplay is well crafted; the writers and the director have at least some idea how Hardy's work should work on film and stay relatively true to the book. The music both haunting and beautiful at the same time was absolutely outstanding. The direction is very fine, never sluggish and never overdone. It was about right. The cinematography is superb, dark, fluid and sensitive. And the period detail was just as good. It was this element alone that contributed to the mood of the adaptation. The love story here which is dirty and tragic was beautifully realised, and very rarely struck a false note. The performances were just brilliant, no overplaying or underplaying as far as I could see. Special mention must go to the two lead performances. Christopher Ecceleston is a very talented and I think under-appreciated actor, and in the title role he was perfectly cast and showed real versatility. As Sue Brideshead, the beautiful Kate Winslet is positively luminous and is true to her character. Out of the supporting performances, the best is Rachel Griffiths as Arabella, a very modest performance I must say. Overall, has its minor flaws but a very well done adaptation of a complicated book. Always realistic and never overly-sentimental as I feared. Though the ending is heart-rending. 9/10 Bethany Cox
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Hardy's Jude the Obscure faithfully portrayed
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    CountZero313
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/4/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Winterbottom keeps the temperature of the searing original novel in his faithful, brilliantly realised film adaptation. Hardy was sick when writing Jude, out of sorts, and the bleak tale has in some quarters been credited more to bile than his muse. Jude's fate is certainly more damning than other Hardy heroes such as Tess, and the final third of this tale requires a strong heart to get through. Jude Fawley is a self-educated stonemason looking to enter the hallowed halls of (a thinly-disguised) Oxford. Class and snobbery combine to crush that dream, but he fights and wins his other dream, to secure the love of his cousin Sue. Headstrong and independent, a prototype Suffragette, she will face her own stern test and be found wanting. Christopher Eccleston inhabits the character fully. The scene in the pub where he recites the Lord's Creed in Latin, then challenges the undergrads to judge if he got it right, is painful and poignant. Winslet is stunning as the admirable but infuriating Sue Brideshead whose choices in life are oblique but all-too-real. A cold draft of air oozes from her expression every time she shuns Jude. There isn't a missed beat in Winslet's portrayal of a woman who goes from supremely confident to utterly lost. Winterbottom would go on to tinker and experiment, unsuccessfully, with Hardy's Mayor of Casterbridge in The Claim. Here, he keeps it strictly BBC, evoking the early industrial age magnificently in his cobbled streets and fog-shrouded spires. An array of British acting talent fill out the supporting roles superbly, most notably Liam Cunningham as the put-upon Phillotson, and Rachel Griffiths as pig-hugging Arabella, whose rising fortune sways in counter-point to Jude's slow, inexorable decline. In one scene where she encounters her estranged son at a fairground, the interaction between woman and child is both naturalistic and magical. The expression on the face of Little Jude's sister is priceless. Perhaps a happy accident, perhaps genius from the director, but all the more tragic for what follows. One of the most ill-fated couples in British literature are vividly brought to life in this film, designed to satisfy fans of the novel. Hardy, one feels, would approve.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Heartbreaking literary adaptation
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Framescourer
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/11/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A briskly but sensitively shot, well-acted and brutally rendered version of Thomas Hardy's tragic novel. I remember being terribly disappointed though (when I saw this in the cinema) that the grainy, visceral b&w images of the title sequence were discontinued as the movie proper got started. Ecclestone finds a great deal of sympathy and charm with which to play the ambitious but unlucky Jude. Kate Winslet is an arguably bigger draw though, throwing herself headlong into a part that requires... well many of the characteristics that she brought to the successful Austen adaptation Sense and Sensibility the previous year: willfulness, joy and despair. Rachel Griffiths is horrible as Jude's ball and chain but nothing is as nasty as the notorious fate of the incestuous couple's children. Strong stuff from Winterbottom, as usual. 6/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Hey Jude, you make it good (web)
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    leplatypus
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It's an excellent movie because it scores in each corner: it has a wonderful, gripping story that can speaks to anyone with heart. As it's an adaptation, you will be interested in reading the novel. Beyond the personal drama, I remember two scandals that are always verified today: 1) education is elitist as it expels those who don't have pedigree 2) Christian congregation is highly hypocritical as they achieve to turn a message of love into one of rejection. It has wonderful locations, between the green pastures and the austere British cities (for those who have seen Spielberg's "War Horse", it has the same ambiance). Winterbottom is inspired to fill his frames and Johnston's soundtrack is just one of the best ever as it gives such poetry to the pictures. As for the cast, it's just an amazing reunion: Eccleston finds his career pick as his Jude is such a good man: always sincere, hardworking, caring, sometimes sad but never quits! Kate is always fascinating by her precocity and by her personal choices for free- spirited characters!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A bitter reflection on non-conformity
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Malcolm Parker
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    With actors of the calibre of Kate Winslet and Christopher Eccleston, this drama could hardly have failed. That said, I felt something was lacking in the characterisation of Sue Bridehead, I haven't read the book, but there is a difficult combination of character traits that stumble between the intellectual and prim and the untethered and vivacious. I felt that we knew Jude, and all the other principle characters, but somehow Sue, despite a magnificent performance by Winslet remained detached and distant as though there was something unexplained in her make up. She was wholly unabashed about her and Jude's marital state, incredibly liberal in her adoption of Jude's son, but yet at times seemed almost uninvolved in her intimacy with Jude. I'm not sure what Hardy wrote, but I think revealing a little more of the motivation behind Sue's character would have clarified and improved the film immensely. Overall though, a very moving and beautifully shot construction, not quite in the same league as Polanski's Tess or Schlesinger's Far from the Madding Crowd, but a great film nevertheless.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "Jude"
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    francescof86
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Jude" is an extraordinary film by one of the most daring and amazing director out there ,as Michael Winterbottom. The original novel("Jude the Obscure") is translated in a brilliant script by Hossein Amini and centers on the aspirations of a lower-class man,Jude Fawley(Christopher Ecclestone),who fights to become a university man. After a quick and wrong marriage with an humble country girl,Arabella(Rachel Griffiths), he met his cousin Sue Bridehead(Kate Winslet)an intelligent,beautiful and apparently as unconventional and brave as him. Their passionate love will end tragically though. The film is from the end to the beginning sad and depressing at his best since we see Jude and Sue fight against the Victorian society's beliefs such as a legalized marriage(they only live as a couple)and the impossible aspirations of a lower-class man who would like to become equal to his peers and study at the university. Ultimately their lives will be destroyed by a cruel destiny. Jude is completely coherent to his ideas but Sue is a tormented and fragile woman who,in the end, is not able to came to terms with what she professed at the beginning. In the end, she turns to religion and accepts a life she rejected because she feels guilty. Christoph Ecclestone and Kate Winslet are just superb. Ecclestone is a serious underrated actor who should be in the spotlight. He never misses a beat and gives an amazing performance. Kate Winslet is completely committed to her role and gives a dramatic performance that is devastating. The director gives the a vivid and crude cut and confirms his uncommon abilities to tell a story set in a different era as we're seeing a modern tragedy.His direction is as tormented as his leads and we can't help but have a feeling that he is not afraid to show the crudest side and the terrible contradictions of the Victorian period. my vote is 10/10.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Suitably depressing piece of Hardy
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    miss_lady_ice-853-608700
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Jude The Obscure is Thomas Hardy's final novel, and his bleakest. It doesn't seem an obvious choice for cinema, hence why it failed at the box office. An air of gloom hangs over the whole proceedings. The story is a little like Tess- a man's chance at love is destroyed by a woman from his past. Jude (Christopher Eccleston) is the man in question- an ambitious country boy whose desire is to become a student at Christminster (Hardy's made-up name for Oxford). He moves to Christminster and falls in love with his clever cousin Sue Brideshead (Kate Winslet). Unfortunately he is already married- to loose country girl Arabella (Rachel Griffiths), who keeps popping up and ruining Jude's chance at happiness. The climax of the film is one of the most tragic and horrific things you will see in a long time. The film is quite well done. It is a bit graphic (this is Michael Winterbottom after all) and anachronistic in places, but there are enough tinges of Hardy to make it a costume drama. He certainly hasn't butchered it as he butchered Tess in his film Trishna. The problem of the film is that Jude is a bit of a ninny, who doesn't seem to have the ruthlessness or the cleverness needed to get into the academic elite and constantly runs back to Arabella. The incestuous aspect is also very off-putting. One feels sorry for Jude and Sue but one can never feel entirely comfortable with their relationship. Another problem, at least adaptation-wise, is that Arabella, who is a horrible sadist in the book from what I've heard, is merely a nuisance here. Perhaps Winterbottom thought that might be too much misery for people but it does mean that the film ends abruptly. Acting-wise, everything is fine. Eccleston convinces as a country boy, although his Northern accent does come out at times. Winslet does well as spirited Sue Brideshead, similar to Rose in Titanic so not much of a stretch for her. EDIT: Having now read the novel- not my favourite Hardy novel but a powerful novel nonetheless- the film gets the sexuality right. Everything that Hardy couldn't show, this film shows, so for those who complain that the film has too much nudity, this is actually quite true to the novel- particularly as none of it is very erotic. Jude's weakness for the flesh is almost animalistic. Leaving aside the hot and steamy, we have that whole spiritual dimension. That part of the novel is quite hard to translate and it doesn't really come through in this film. Jude is meant to be too noble for this world, hindered by his fleshy desires. And the film really does let Arabella off too lightly. In this, she's a typical country wench- a tart with not much of a heart. However in the book, she's not only a tart with no heart, she's a proper butcher, cruel to the point of sadism.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    This was a depressing and disturbing movie.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    rujammin2
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/1/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This was a depressing and disturbing movie. I Couldn't get this movie out of my head for a couple days and in a bad way! I wished I would of turned it off before I was so traumatized by it! It's long, cold , depressing and a waste of 2+ hours. The only reason I hung on was for the actors. Kate and Christopher made the best of a terrible story. The director did a great job of putting you right there in the movie. Unfortunately it's not a great place to be. Some of the scenes were just a little overly disturbing for my taste. This movie could of ended an hour earlier and it wouldn't of mattered. I strongly suggest skipping this unless you really want to fell deflated afterward.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    incompetent, poorly conceived, boring
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    withnail-4
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/1/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    What kind of person is Jude? does he have a love for Latin? Does he really want to be a scholar? What does he think of his wife Arabella? what is she like? Are we supposed to like her, dislike her? because...? because she is sensual? earthy? Is she too ignorant to be a good wife for Jude? Is Jude Smart? We see them have sex..and this means..? Not one scene has any development. Guy walks around in the rain, somebody tells a boy that education is everything...Is this Jude our hero? He is shown trying to memorize some Latin. How far has he progressed ...what does Classical literature mean to him? The viewer's emotions are not guided toward any coherent response ...scenes begin and end without discernible intention. Lazy, incompetent film directing. Not thought through. Watch a film Like Hobson's Choice by David Lean, in comparison, and appreciate how every image, gesture, every object, conveys thoughts, character, intentions. Someone intelligent sat down and thought through what to show and how. Scenes with beginnings, middles, and ends and meanings and direction. This film is, by contrast, a lazy, stupidly unrealized piece of incompetence. Kate Winslet's performance, and the beauty of the locations are the only positive parts.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Excellent!!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    dorothy-tripp
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/12/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    If you like dark dramas, this is your movie. Very true to the book and absolutely engrossing. The locations are beautiful. The acting is superb. The characters are richly brought out, and you can understand their thought processes. This is a moral play, as well as a look at the way society imposes rules of conduct. I stumbled on this wonderful film while watching the romance channel on television in 2000. I came in toward the middle, but was immediately drawn into the story. I searched high and low for the video, and when I want a moody drama, this is where I go. This film will make you think. Obviously, the book is practically required reading after you see this movie. You'll just be compelled to know more. Truly a haunting movie that you will remember for a long time.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Ambitious and anything but tender, but wonderfully acted and well adapted
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    TheLittleSongbird
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/11/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Thomas Hardy's Jude the Obscure is a very complicated and ambitious book, and while heavy-reading it is a fine piece of literature. This 1996 film adaptation is a rock-solid adaptation, that is ambitious and realistic. I will admit some parts like the killing of the pig is anything but tender, but none of the scenes are over-sensationalised. As an adaptation of the book, it works very well. If I had a quibble, the secondary characters could have been developed more than they were depicted. The screenplay is well crafted; the writers and the director have at least some idea how Hardy's work should work on film and stay relatively true to the book. The music both haunting and beautiful at the same time was absolutely outstanding. The direction is very fine, never sluggish and never overdone. It was about right. The cinematography is superb, dark, fluid and sensitive. And the period detail was just as good. It was this element alone that contributed to the mood of the adaptation. The love story here which is dirty and tragic was beautifully realised, and very rarely struck a false note. The performances were just brilliant, no overplaying or underplaying as far as I could see. Special mention must go to the two lead performances. Christopher Ecceleston is a very talented and I think under-appreciated actor, and in the title role he was perfectly cast and showed real versatility. As Sue Brideshead, the beautiful Kate Winslet is positively luminous and is true to her character. Out of the supporting performances, the best is Rachel Griffiths as Arabella, a very modest performance I must say. Overall, has its minor flaws but a very well done adaptation of a complicated book. Always realistic and never overly-sentimental as I feared. Though the ending is heart-rending. 9/10 Bethany Cox
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Hardy's Jude the Obscure faithfully portrayed
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    CountZero313
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/4/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Winterbottom keeps the temperature of the searing original novel in his faithful, brilliantly realised film adaptation. Hardy was sick when writing Jude, out of sorts, and the bleak tale has in some quarters been credited more to bile than his muse. Jude's fate is certainly more damning than other Hardy heroes such as Tess, and the final third of this tale requires a strong heart to get through. Jude Fawley is a self-educated stonemason looking to enter the hallowed halls of (a thinly-disguised) Oxford. Class and snobbery combine to crush that dream, but he fights and wins his other dream, to secure the love of his cousin Sue. Headstrong and independent, a prototype Suffragette, she will face her own stern test and be found wanting. Christopher Eccleston inhabits the character fully. The scene in the pub where he recites the Lord's Creed in Latin, then challenges the undergrads to judge if he got it right, is painful and poignant. Winslet is stunning as the admirable but infuriating Sue Brideshead whose choices in life are oblique but all-too-real. A cold draft of air oozes from her expression every time she shuns Jude. There isn't a missed beat in Winslet's portrayal of a woman who goes from supremely confident to utterly lost. Winterbottom would go on to tinker and experiment, unsuccessfully, with Hardy's Mayor of Casterbridge in The Claim. Here, he keeps it strictly BBC, evoking the early industrial age magnificently in his cobbled streets and fog-shrouded spires. An array of British acting talent fill out the supporting roles superbly, most notably Liam Cunningham as the put-upon Phillotson, and Rachel Griffiths as pig-hugging Arabella, whose rising fortune sways in counter-point to Jude's slow, inexorable decline. In one scene where she encounters her estranged son at a fairground, the interaction between woman and child is both naturalistic and magical. The expression on the face of Little Jude's sister is priceless. Perhaps a happy accident, perhaps genius from the director, but all the more tragic for what follows. One of the most ill-fated couples in British literature are vividly brought to life in this film, designed to satisfy fans of the novel. Hardy, one feels, would approve.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Heartbreaking literary adaptation
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Framescourer
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/11/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A briskly but sensitively shot, well-acted and brutally rendered version of Thomas Hardy's tragic novel. I remember being terribly disappointed though (when I saw this in the cinema) that the grainy, visceral b&w images of the title sequence were discontinued as the movie proper got started. Ecclestone finds a great deal of sympathy and charm with which to play the ambitious but unlucky Jude. Kate Winslet is an arguably bigger draw though, throwing herself headlong into a part that requires... well many of the characteristics that she brought to the successful Austen adaptation Sense and Sensibility the previous year: willfulness, joy and despair. Rachel Griffiths is horrible as Jude's ball and chain but nothing is as nasty as the notorious fate of the incestuous couple's children. Strong stuff from Winterbottom, as usual. 6/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Hey Jude, you make it good (web)
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    leplatypus
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It's an excellent movie because it scores in each corner: it has a wonderful, gripping story that can speaks to anyone with heart. As it's an adaptation, you will be interested in reading the novel. Beyond the personal drama, I remember two scandals that are always verified today: 1) education is elitist as it expels those who don't have pedigree 2) Christian congregation is highly hypocritical as they achieve to turn a message of love into one of rejection. It has wonderful locations, between the green pastures and the austere British cities (for those who have seen Spielberg's "War Horse", it has the same ambiance). Winterbottom is inspired to fill his frames and Johnston's soundtrack is just one of the best ever as it gives such poetry to the pictures. As for the cast, it's just an amazing reunion: Eccleston finds his career pick as his Jude is such a good man: always sincere, hardworking, caring, sometimes sad but never quits! Kate is always fascinating by her precocity and by her personal choices for free- spirited characters!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A bitter reflection on non-conformity
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Malcolm Parker
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    With actors of the calibre of Kate Winslet and Christopher Eccleston, this drama could hardly have failed. That said, I felt something was lacking in the characterisation of Sue Bridehead, I haven't read the book, but there is a difficult combination of character traits that stumble between the intellectual and prim and the untethered and vivacious. I felt that we knew Jude, and all the other principle characters, but somehow Sue, despite a magnificent performance by Winslet remained detached and distant as though there was something unexplained in her make up. She was wholly unabashed about her and Jude's marital state, incredibly liberal in her adoption of Jude's son, but yet at times seemed almost uninvolved in her intimacy with Jude. I'm not sure what Hardy wrote, but I think revealing a little more of the motivation behind Sue's character would have clarified and improved the film immensely. Overall though, a very moving and beautifully shot construction, not quite in the same league as Polanski's Tess or Schlesinger's Far from the Madding Crowd, but a great film nevertheless.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "Jude"
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    francescof86
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Jude" is an extraordinary film by one of the most daring and amazing director out there ,as Michael Winterbottom. The original novel("Jude the Obscure") is translated in a brilliant script by Hossein Amini and centers on the aspirations of a lower-class man,Jude Fawley(Christopher Ecclestone),who fights to become a university man. After a quick and wrong marriage with an humble country girl,Arabella(Rachel Griffiths), he met his cousin Sue Bridehead(Kate Winslet)an intelligent,beautiful and apparently as unconventional and brave as him. Their passionate love will end tragically though. The film is from the end to the beginning sad and depressing at his best since we see Jude and Sue fight against the Victorian society's beliefs such as a legalized marriage(they only live as a couple)and the impossible aspirations of a lower-class man who would like to become equal to his peers and study at the university. Ultimately their lives will be destroyed by a cruel destiny. Jude is completely coherent to his ideas but Sue is a tormented and fragile woman who,in the end, is not able to came to terms with what she professed at the beginning. In the end, she turns to religion and accepts a life she rejected because she feels guilty. Christoph Ecclestone and Kate Winslet are just superb. Ecclestone is a serious underrated actor who should be in the spotlight. He never misses a beat and gives an amazing performance. Kate Winslet is completely committed to her role and gives a dramatic performance that is devastating. The director gives the a vivid and crude cut and confirms his uncommon abilities to tell a story set in a different era as we're seeing a modern tragedy.His direction is as tormented as his leads and we can't help but have a feeling that he is not afraid to show the crudest side and the terrible contradictions of the Victorian period. my vote is 10/10.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Suitably depressing piece of Hardy
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    miss_lady_ice-853-608700
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Jude The Obscure is Thomas Hardy's final novel, and his bleakest. It doesn't seem an obvious choice for cinema, hence why it failed at the box office. An air of gloom hangs over the whole proceedings. The story is a little like Tess- a man's chance at love is destroyed by a woman from his past. Jude (Christopher Eccleston) is the man in question- an ambitious country boy whose desire is to become a student at Christminster (Hardy's made-up name for Oxford). He moves to Christminster and falls in love with his clever cousin Sue Brideshead (Kate Winslet). Unfortunately he is already married- to loose country girl Arabella (Rachel Griffiths), who keeps popping up and ruining Jude's chance at happiness. The climax of the film is one of the most tragic and horrific things you will see in a long time. The film is quite well done. It is a bit graphic (this is Michael Winterbottom after all) and anachronistic in places, but there are enough tinges of Hardy to make it a costume drama. He certainly hasn't butchered it as he butchered Tess in his film Trishna. The problem of the film is that Jude is a bit of a ninny, who doesn't seem to have the ruthlessness or the cleverness needed to get into the academic elite and constantly runs back to Arabella. The incestuous aspect is also very off-putting. One feels sorry for Jude and Sue but one can never feel entirely comfortable with their relationship. Another problem, at least adaptation-wise, is that Arabella, who is a horrible sadist in the book from what I've heard, is merely a nuisance here. Perhaps Winterbottom thought that might be too much misery for people but it does mean that the film ends abruptly. Acting-wise, everything is fine. Eccleston convinces as a country boy, although his Northern accent does come out at times. Winslet does well as spirited Sue Brideshead, similar to Rose in Titanic so not much of a stretch for her. EDIT: Having now read the novel- not my favourite Hardy novel but a powerful novel nonetheless- the film gets the sexuality right. Everything that Hardy couldn't show, this film shows, so for those who complain that the film has too much nudity, this is actually quite true to the novel- particularly as none of it is very erotic. Jude's weakness for the flesh is almost animalistic. Leaving aside the hot and steamy, we have that whole spiritual dimension. That part of the novel is quite hard to translate and it doesn't really come through in this film. Jude is meant to be too noble for this world, hindered by his fleshy desires. And the film really does let Arabella off too lightly. In this, she's a typical country wench- a tart with not much of a heart. However in the book, she's not only a tart with no heart, she's a proper butcher, cruel to the point of sadism.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    This was a depressing and disturbing movie.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    rujammin2
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/1/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This was a depressing and disturbing movie. I Couldn't get this movie out of my head for a couple days and in a bad way! I wished I would of turned it off before I was so traumatized by it! It's long, cold , depressing and a waste of 2+ hours. The only reason I hung on was for the actors. Kate and Christopher made the best of a terrible story. The director did a great job of putting you right there in the movie. Unfortunately it's not a great place to be. Some of the scenes were just a little overly disturbing for my taste. This movie could of ended an hour earlier and it wouldn't of mattered. I strongly suggest skipping this unless you really want to fell deflated afterward.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    incompetent, poorly conceived, boring
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    withnail-4
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/1/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    What kind of person is Jude? does he have a love for Latin? Does he really want to be a scholar? What does he think of his wife Arabella? what is she like? Are we supposed to like her, dislike her? because...? because she is sensual? earthy? Is she too ignorant to be a good wife for Jude? Is Jude Smart? We see them have sex..and this means..? Not one scene has any development. Guy walks around in the rain, somebody tells a boy that education is everything...Is this Jude our hero? He is shown trying to memorize some Latin. How far has he progressed ...what does Classical literature mean to him? The viewer's emotions are not guided toward any coherent response ...scenes begin and end without discernible intention. Lazy, incompetent film directing. Not thought through. Watch a film Like Hobson's Choice by David Lean, in comparison, and appreciate how every image, gesture, every object, conveys thoughts, character, intentions. Someone intelligent sat down and thought through what to show and how. Scenes with beginnings, middles, and ends and meanings and direction. This film is, by contrast, a lazy, stupidly unrealized piece of incompetence. Kate Winslet's performance, and the beauty of the locations are the only positive parts.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Excellent!!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    dorothy-tripp
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/12/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    If you like dark dramas, this is your movie. Very true to the book and absolutely engrossing. The locations are beautiful. The acting is superb. The characters are richly brought out, and you can understand their thought processes. This is a moral play, as well as a look at the way society imposes rules of conduct. I stumbled on this wonderful film while watching the romance channel on television in 2000. I came in toward the middle, but was immediately drawn into the story. I searched high and low for the video, and when I want a moody drama, this is where I go. This film will make you think. Obviously, the book is practically required reading after you see this movie. You'll just be compelled to know more. Truly a haunting movie that you will remember for a long time.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Ambitious and anything but tender, but wonderfully acted and well adapted
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    TheLittleSongbird
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/11/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Thomas Hardy's Jude the Obscure is a very complicated and ambitious book, and while heavy-reading it is a fine piece of literature. This 1996 film adaptation is a rock-solid adaptation, that is ambitious and realistic. I will admit some parts like the killing of the pig is anything but tender, but none of the scenes are over-sensationalised. As an adaptation of the book, it works very well. If I had a quibble, the secondary characters could have been developed more than they were depicted. The screenplay is well crafted; the writers and the director have at least some idea how Hardy's work should work on film and stay relatively true to the book. The music both haunting and beautiful at the same time was absolutely outstanding. The direction is very fine, never sluggish and never overdone. It was about right. The cinematography is superb, dark, fluid and sensitive. And the period detail was just as good. It was this element alone that contributed to the mood of the adaptation. The love story here which is dirty and tragic was beautifully realised, and very rarely struck a false note. The performances were just brilliant, no overplaying or underplaying as far as I could see. Special mention must go to the two lead performances. Christopher Ecceleston is a very talented and I think under-appreciated actor, and in the title role he was perfectly cast and showed real versatility. As Sue Brideshead, the beautiful Kate Winslet is positively luminous and is true to her character. Out of the supporting performances, the best is Rachel Griffiths as Arabella, a very modest performance I must say. Overall, has its minor flaws but a very well done adaptation of a complicated book. Always realistic and never overly-sentimental as I feared. Though the ending is heart-rending. 9/10 Bethany Cox
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Hardy's Jude the Obscure faithfully portrayed
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    CountZero313
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/4/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Winterbottom keeps the temperature of the searing original novel in his faithful, brilliantly realised film adaptation. Hardy was sick when writing Jude, out of sorts, and the bleak tale has in some quarters been credited more to bile than his muse. Jude's fate is certainly more damning than other Hardy heroes such as Tess, and the final third of this tale requires a strong heart to get through. Jude Fawley is a self-educated stonemason looking to enter the hallowed halls of (a thinly-disguised) Oxford. Class and snobbery combine to crush that dream, but he fights and wins his other dream, to secure the love of his cousin Sue. Headstrong and independent, a prototype Suffragette, she will face her own stern test and be found wanting. Christopher Eccleston inhabits the character fully. The scene in the pub where he recites the Lord's Creed in Latin, then challenges the undergrads to judge if he got it right, is painful and poignant. Winslet is stunning as the admirable but infuriating Sue Brideshead whose choices in life are oblique but all-too-real. A cold draft of air oozes from her expression every time she shuns Jude. There isn't a missed beat in Winslet's portrayal of a woman who goes from supremely confident to utterly lost. Winterbottom would go on to tinker and experiment, unsuccessfully, with Hardy's Mayor of Casterbridge in The Claim. Here, he keeps it strictly BBC, evoking the early industrial age magnificently in his cobbled streets and fog-shrouded spires. An array of British acting talent fill out the supporting roles superbly, most notably Liam Cunningham as the put-upon Phillotson, and Rachel Griffiths as pig-hugging Arabella, whose rising fortune sways in counter-point to Jude's slow, inexorable decline. In one scene where she encounters her estranged son at a fairground, the interaction between woman and child is both naturalistic and magical. The expression on the face of Little Jude's sister is priceless. Perhaps a happy accident, perhaps genius from the director, but all the more tragic for what follows. One of the most ill-fated couples in British literature are vividly brought to life in this film, designed to satisfy fans of the novel. Hardy, one feels, would approve.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Heartbreaking literary adaptation
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Framescourer
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/11/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A briskly but sensitively shot, well-acted and brutally rendered version of Thomas Hardy's tragic novel. I remember being terribly disappointed though (when I saw this in the cinema) that the grainy, visceral b&w images of the title sequence were discontinued as the movie proper got started. Ecclestone finds a great deal of sympathy and charm with which to play the ambitious but unlucky Jude. Kate Winslet is an arguably bigger draw though, throwing herself headlong into a part that requires... well many of the characteristics that she brought to the successful Austen adaptation Sense and Sensibility the previous year: willfulness, joy and despair. Rachel Griffiths is horrible as Jude's ball and chain but nothing is as nasty as the notorious fate of the incestuous couple's children. Strong stuff from Winterbottom, as usual. 6/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Hey Jude, you make it good (web)
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    leplatypus
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It's an excellent movie because it scores in each corner: it has a wonderful, gripping story that can speaks to anyone with heart. As it's an adaptation, you will be interested in reading the novel. Beyond the personal drama, I remember two scandals that are always verified today: 1) education is elitist as it expels those who don't have pedigree 2) Christian congregation is highly hypocritical as they achieve to turn a message of love into one of rejection. It has wonderful locations, between the green pastures and the austere British cities (for those who have seen Spielberg's "War Horse", it has the same ambiance). Winterbottom is inspired to fill his frames and Johnston's soundtrack is just one of the best ever as it gives such poetry to the pictures. As for the cast, it's just an amazing reunion: Eccleston finds his career pick as his Jude is such a good man: always sincere, hardworking, caring, sometimes sad but never quits! Kate is always fascinating by her precocity and by her personal choices for free- spirited characters!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A bitter reflection on non-conformity
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Malcolm Parker
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    With actors of the calibre of Kate Winslet and Christopher Eccleston, this drama could hardly have failed. That said, I felt something was lacking in the characterisation of Sue Bridehead, I haven't read the book, but there is a difficult combination of character traits that stumble between the intellectual and prim and the untethered and vivacious. I felt that we knew Jude, and all the other principle characters, but somehow Sue, despite a magnificent performance by Winslet remained detached and distant as though there was something unexplained in her make up. She was wholly unabashed about her and Jude's marital state, incredibly liberal in her adoption of Jude's son, but yet at times seemed almost uninvolved in her intimacy with Jude. I'm not sure what Hardy wrote, but I think revealing a little more of the motivation behind Sue's character would have clarified and improved the film immensely. Overall though, a very moving and beautifully shot construction, not quite in the same league as Polanski's Tess or Schlesinger's Far from the Madding Crowd, but a great film nevertheless.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "Jude"
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    francescof86
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Jude" is an extraordinary film by one of the most daring and amazing director out there ,as Michael Winterbottom. The original novel("Jude the Obscure") is translated in a brilliant script by Hossein Amini and centers on the aspirations of a lower-class man,Jude Fawley(Christopher Ecclestone),who fights to become a university man. After a quick and wrong marriage with an humble country girl,Arabella(Rachel Griffiths), he met his cousin Sue Bridehead(Kate Winslet)an intelligent,beautiful and apparently as unconventional and brave as him. Their passionate love will end tragically though. The film is from the end to the beginning sad and depressing at his best since we see Jude and Sue fight against the Victorian society's beliefs such as a legalized marriage(they only live as a couple)and the impossible aspirations of a lower-class man who would like to become equal to his peers and study at the university. Ultimately their lives will be destroyed by a cruel destiny. Jude is completely coherent to his ideas but Sue is a tormented and fragile woman who,in the end, is not able to came to terms with what she professed at the beginning. In the end, she turns to religion and accepts a life she rejected because she feels guilty. Christoph Ecclestone and Kate Winslet are just superb. Ecclestone is a serious underrated actor who should be in the spotlight. He never misses a beat and gives an amazing performance. Kate Winslet is completely committed to her role and gives a dramatic performance that is devastating. The director gives the a vivid and crude cut and confirms his uncommon abilities to tell a story set in a different era as we're seeing a modern tragedy.His direction is as tormented as his leads and we can't help but have a feeling that he is not afraid to show the crudest side and the terrible contradictions of the Victorian period. my vote is 10/10.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Suitably depressing piece of Hardy
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    miss_lady_ice-853-608700
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Jude The Obscure is Thomas Hardy's final novel, and his bleakest. It doesn't seem an obvious choice for cinema, hence why it failed at the box office. An air of gloom hangs over the whole proceedings. The story is a little like Tess- a man's chance at love is destroyed by a woman from his past. Jude (Christopher Eccleston) is the man in question- an ambitious country boy whose desire is to become a student at Christminster (Hardy's made-up name for Oxford). He moves to Christminster and falls in love with his clever cousin Sue Brideshead (Kate Winslet). Unfortunately he is already married- to loose country girl Arabella (Rachel Griffiths), who keeps popping up and ruining Jude's chance at happiness. The climax of the film is one of the most tragic and horrific things you will see in a long time. The film is quite well done. It is a bit graphic (this is Michael Winterbottom after all) and anachronistic in places, but there are enough tinges of Hardy to make it a costume drama. He certainly hasn't butchered it as he butchered Tess in his film Trishna. The problem of the film is that Jude is a bit of a ninny, who doesn't seem to have the ruthlessness or the cleverness needed to get into the academic elite and constantly runs back to Arabella. The incestuous aspect is also very off-putting. One feels sorry for Jude and Sue but one can never feel entirely comfortable with their relationship. Another problem, at least adaptation-wise, is that Arabella, who is a horrible sadist in the book from what I've heard, is merely a nuisance here. Perhaps Winterbottom thought that might be too much misery for people but it does mean that the film ends abruptly. Acting-wise, everything is fine. Eccleston convinces as a country boy, although his Northern accent does come out at times. Winslet does well as spirited Sue Brideshead, similar to Rose in Titanic so not much of a stretch for her. EDIT: Having now read the novel- not my favourite Hardy novel but a powerful novel nonetheless- the film gets the sexuality right. Everything that Hardy couldn't show, this film shows, so for those who complain that the film has too much nudity, this is actually quite true to the novel- particularly as none of it is very erotic. Jude's weakness for the flesh is almost animalistic. Leaving aside the hot and steamy, we have that whole spiritual dimension. That part of the novel is quite hard to translate and it doesn't really come through in this film. Jude is meant to be too noble for this world, hindered by his fleshy desires. And the film really does let Arabella off too lightly. In this, she's a typical country wench- a tart with not much of a heart. However in the book, she's not only a tart with no heart, she's a proper butcher, cruel to the point of sadism.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    This was a depressing and disturbing movie.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    rujammin2
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/1/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This was a depressing and disturbing movie. I Couldn't get this movie out of my head for a couple days and in a bad way! I wished I would of turned it off before I was so traumatized by it! It's long, cold , depressing and a waste of 2+ hours. The only reason I hung on was for the actors. Kate and Christopher made the best of a terrible story. The director did a great job of putting you right there in the movie. Unfortunately it's not a great place to be. Some of the scenes were just a little overly disturbing for my taste. This movie could of ended an hour earlier and it wouldn't of mattered. I strongly suggest skipping this unless you really want to fell deflated afterward.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    incompetent, poorly conceived, boring
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    withnail-4
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/1/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    What kind of person is Jude? does he have a love for Latin? Does he really want to be a scholar? What does he think of his wife Arabella? what is she like? Are we supposed to like her, dislike her? because...? because she is sensual? earthy? Is she too ignorant to be a good wife for Jude? Is Jude Smart? We see them have sex..and this means..? Not one scene has any development. Guy walks around in the rain, somebody tells a boy that education is everything...Is this Jude our hero? He is shown trying to memorize some Latin. How far has he progressed ...what does Classical literature mean to him? The viewer's emotions are not guided toward any coherent response ...scenes begin and end without discernible intention. Lazy, incompetent film directing. Not thought through. Watch a film Like Hobson's Choice by David Lean, in comparison, and appreciate how every image, gesture, every object, conveys thoughts, character, intentions. Someone intelligent sat down and thought through what to show and how. Scenes with beginnings, middles, and ends and meanings and direction. This film is, by contrast, a lazy, stupidly unrealized piece of incompetence. Kate Winslet's performance, and the beauty of the locations are the only positive parts.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Excellent!!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    dorothy-tripp
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/12/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    If you like dark dramas, this is your movie. Very true to the book and absolutely engrossing. The locations are beautiful. The acting is superb. The characters are richly brought out, and you can understand their thought processes. This is a moral play, as well as a look at the way society imposes rules of conduct. I stumbled on this wonderful film while watching the romance channel on television in 2000. I came in toward the middle, but was immediately drawn into the story. I searched high and low for the video, and when I want a moody drama, this is where I go. This film will make you think. Obviously, the book is practically required reading after you see this movie. You'll just be compelled to know more. Truly a haunting movie that you will remember for a long time.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Ambitious and anything but tender, but wonderfully acted and well adapted
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    TheLittleSongbird
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/11/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Thomas Hardy's Jude the Obscure is a very complicated and ambitious book, and while heavy-reading it is a fine piece of literature. This 1996 film adaptation is a rock-solid adaptation, that is ambitious and realistic. I will admit some parts like the killing of the pig is anything but tender, but none of the scenes are over-sensationalised. As an adaptation of the book, it works very well. If I had a quibble, the secondary characters could have been developed more than they were depicted. The screenplay is well crafted; the writers and the director have at least some idea how Hardy's work should work on film and stay relatively true to the book. The music both haunting and beautiful at the same time was absolutely outstanding. The direction is very fine, never sluggish and never overdone. It was about right. The cinematography is superb, dark, fluid and sensitive. And the period detail was just as good. It was this element alone that contributed to the mood of the adaptation. The love story here which is dirty and tragic was beautifully realised, and very rarely struck a false note. The performances were just brilliant, no overplaying or underplaying as far as I could see. Special mention must go to the two lead performances. Christopher Ecceleston is a very talented and I think under-appreciated actor, and in the title role he was perfectly cast and showed real versatility. As Sue Brideshead, the beautiful Kate Winslet is positively luminous and is true to her character. Out of the supporting performances, the best is Rachel Griffiths as Arabella, a very modest performance I must say. Overall, has its minor flaws but a very well done adaptation of a complicated book. Always realistic and never overly-sentimental as I feared. Though the ending is heart-rending. 9/10 Bethany Cox
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Hardy's Jude the Obscure faithfully portrayed
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    CountZero313
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/4/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Winterbottom keeps the temperature of the searing original novel in his faithful, brilliantly realised film adaptation. Hardy was sick when writing Jude, out of sorts, and the bleak tale has in some quarters been credited more to bile than his muse. Jude's fate is certainly more damning than other Hardy heroes such as Tess, and the final third of this tale requires a strong heart to get through. Jude Fawley is a self-educated stonemason looking to enter the hallowed halls of (a thinly-disguised) Oxford. Class and snobbery combine to crush that dream, but he fights and wins his other dream, to secure the love of his cousin Sue. Headstrong and independent, a prototype Suffragette, she will face her own stern test and be found wanting. Christopher Eccleston inhabits the character fully. The scene in the pub where he recites the Lord's Creed in Latin, then challenges the undergrads to judge if he got it right, is painful and poignant. Winslet is stunning as the admirable but infuriating Sue Brideshead whose choices in life are oblique but all-too-real. A cold draft of air oozes from her expression every time she shuns Jude. There isn't a missed beat in Winslet's portrayal of a woman who goes from supremely confident to utterly lost. Winterbottom would go on to tinker and experiment, unsuccessfully, with Hardy's Mayor of Casterbridge in The Claim. Here, he keeps it strictly BBC, evoking the early industrial age magnificently in his cobbled streets and fog-shrouded spires. An array of British acting talent fill out the supporting roles superbly, most notably Liam Cunningham as the put-upon Phillotson, and Rachel Griffiths as pig-hugging Arabella, whose rising fortune sways in counter-point to Jude's slow, inexorable decline. In one scene where she encounters her estranged son at a fairground, the interaction between woman and child is both naturalistic and magical. The expression on the face of Little Jude's sister is priceless. Perhaps a happy accident, perhaps genius from the director, but all the more tragic for what follows. One of the most ill-fated couples in British literature are vividly brought to life in this film, designed to satisfy fans of the novel. Hardy, one feels, would approve.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Heartbreaking literary adaptation
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Framescourer
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/11/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A briskly but sensitively shot, well-acted and brutally rendered version of Thomas Hardy's tragic novel. I remember being terribly disappointed though (when I saw this in the cinema) that the grainy, visceral b&w images of the title sequence were discontinued as the movie proper got started. Ecclestone finds a great deal of sympathy and charm with which to play the ambitious but unlucky Jude. Kate Winslet is an arguably bigger draw though, throwing herself headlong into a part that requires... well many of the characteristics that she brought to the successful Austen adaptation Sense and Sensibility the previous year: willfulness, joy and despair. Rachel Griffiths is horrible as Jude's ball and chain but nothing is as nasty as the notorious fate of the incestuous couple's children. Strong stuff from Winterbottom, as usual. 6/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Hey Jude, you make it good (web)
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    leplatypus
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It's an excellent movie because it scores in each corner: it has a wonderful, gripping story that can speaks to anyone with heart. As it's an adaptation, you will be interested in reading the novel. Beyond the personal drama, I remember two scandals that are always verified today: 1) education is elitist as it expels those who don't have pedigree 2) Christian congregation is highly hypocritical as they achieve to turn a message of love into one of rejection. It has wonderful locations, between the green pastures and the austere British cities (for those who have seen Spielberg's "War Horse", it has the same ambiance). Winterbottom is inspired to fill his frames and Johnston's soundtrack is just one of the best ever as it gives such poetry to the pictures. As for the cast, it's just an amazing reunion: Eccleston finds his career pick as his Jude is such a good man: always sincere, hardworking, caring, sometimes sad but never quits! Kate is always fascinating by her precocity and by her personal choices for free- spirited characters!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A bitter reflection on non-conformity
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Malcolm Parker
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    With actors of the calibre of Kate Winslet and Christopher Eccleston, this drama could hardly have failed. That said, I felt something was lacking in the characterisation of Sue Bridehead, I haven't read the book, but there is a difficult combination of character traits that stumble between the intellectual and prim and the untethered and vivacious. I felt that we knew Jude, and all the other principle characters, but somehow Sue, despite a magnificent performance by Winslet remained detached and distant as though there was something unexplained in her make up. She was wholly unabashed about her and Jude's marital state, incredibly liberal in her adoption of Jude's son, but yet at times seemed almost uninvolved in her intimacy with Jude. I'm not sure what Hardy wrote, but I think revealing a little more of the motivation behind Sue's character would have clarified and improved the film immensely. Overall though, a very moving and beautifully shot construction, not quite in the same league as Polanski's Tess or Schlesinger's Far from the Madding Crowd, but a great film nevertheless.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "Jude"
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    francescof86
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Jude" is an extraordinary film by one of the most daring and amazing director out there ,as Michael Winterbottom. The original novel("Jude the Obscure") is translated in a brilliant script by Hossein Amini and centers on the aspirations of a lower-class man,Jude Fawley(Christopher Ecclestone),who fights to become a university man. After a quick and wrong marriage with an humble country girl,Arabella(Rachel Griffiths), he met his cousin Sue Bridehead(Kate Winslet)an intelligent,beautiful and apparently as unconventional and brave as him. Their passionate love will end tragically though. The film is from the end to the beginning sad and depressing at his best since we see Jude and Sue fight against the Victorian society's beliefs such as a legalized marriage(they only live as a couple)and the impossible aspirations of a lower-class man who would like to become equal to his peers and study at the university. Ultimately their lives will be destroyed by a cruel destiny. Jude is completely coherent to his ideas but Sue is a tormented and fragile woman who,in the end, is not able to came to terms with what she professed at the beginning. In the end, she turns to religion and accepts a life she rejected because she feels guilty. Christoph Ecclestone and Kate Winslet are just superb. Ecclestone is a serious underrated actor who should be in the spotlight. He never misses a beat and gives an amazing performance. Kate Winslet is completely committed to her role and gives a dramatic performance that is devastating. The director gives the a vivid and crude cut and confirms his uncommon abilities to tell a story set in a different era as we're seeing a modern tragedy.His direction is as tormented as his leads and we can't help but have a feeling that he is not afraid to show the crudest side and the terrible contradictions of the Victorian period. my vote is 10/10.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Suitably depressing piece of Hardy
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    miss_lady_ice-853-608700
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Jude The Obscure is Thomas Hardy's final novel, and his bleakest. It doesn't seem an obvious choice for cinema, hence why it failed at the box office. An air of gloom hangs over the whole proceedings. The story is a little like Tess- a man's chance at love is destroyed by a woman from his past. Jude (Christopher Eccleston) is the man in question- an ambitious country boy whose desire is to become a student at Christminster (Hardy's made-up name for Oxford). He moves to Christminster and falls in love with his clever cousin Sue Brideshead (Kate Winslet). Unfortunately he is already married- to loose country girl Arabella (Rachel Griffiths), who keeps popping up and ruining Jude's chance at happiness. The climax of the film is one of the most tragic and horrific things you will see in a long time. The film is quite well done. It is a bit graphic (this is Michael Winterbottom after all) and anachronistic in places, but there are enough tinges of Hardy to make it a costume drama. He certainly hasn't butchered it as he butchered Tess in his film Trishna. The problem of the film is that Jude is a bit of a ninny, who doesn't seem to have the ruthlessness or the cleverness needed to get into the academic elite and constantly runs back to Arabella. The incestuous aspect is also very off-putting. One feels sorry for Jude and Sue but one can never feel entirely comfortable with their relationship. Another problem, at least adaptation-wise, is that Arabella, who is a horrible sadist in the book from what I've heard, is merely a nuisance here. Perhaps Winterbottom thought that might be too much misery for people but it does mean that the film ends abruptly. Acting-wise, everything is fine. Eccleston convinces as a country boy, although his Northern accent does come out at times. Winslet does well as spirited Sue Brideshead, similar to Rose in Titanic so not much of a stretch for her. EDIT: Having now read the novel- not my favourite Hardy novel but a powerful novel nonetheless- the film gets the sexuality right. Everything that Hardy couldn't show, this film shows, so for those who complain that the film has too much nudity, this is actually quite true to the novel- particularly as none of it is very erotic. Jude's weakness for the flesh is almost animalistic. Leaving aside the hot and steamy, we have that whole spiritual dimension. That part of the novel is quite hard to translate and it doesn't really come through in this film. Jude is meant to be too noble for this world, hindered by his fleshy desires. And the film really does let Arabella off too lightly. In this, she's a typical country wench- a tart with not much of a heart. However in the book, she's not only a tart with no heart, she's a proper butcher, cruel to the point of sadism.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    This was a depressing and disturbing movie.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    rujammin2
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/1/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This was a depressing and disturbing movie. I Couldn't get this movie out of my head for a couple days and in a bad way! I wished I would of turned it off before I was so traumatized by it! It's long, cold , depressing and a waste of 2+ hours. The only reason I hung on was for the actors. Kate and Christopher made the best of a terrible story. The director did a great job of putting you right there in the movie. Unfortunately it's not a great place to be. Some of the scenes were just a little overly disturbing for my taste. This movie could of ended an hour earlier and it wouldn't of mattered. I strongly suggest skipping this unless you really want to fell deflated afterward.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    incompetent, poorly conceived, boring
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    withnail-4
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/1/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    What kind of person is Jude? does he have a love for Latin? Does he really want to be a scholar? What does he think of his wife Arabella? what is she like? Are we supposed to like her, dislike her? because...? because she is sensual? earthy? Is she too ignorant to be a good wife for Jude? Is Jude Smart? We see them have sex..and this means..? Not one scene has any development. Guy walks around in the rain, somebody tells a boy that education is everything...Is this Jude our hero? He is shown trying to memorize some Latin. How far has he progressed ...what does Classical literature mean to him? The viewer's emotions are not guided toward any coherent response ...scenes begin and end without discernible intention. Lazy, incompetent film directing. Not thought through. Watch a film Like Hobson's Choice by David Lean, in comparison, and appreciate how every image, gesture, every object, conveys thoughts, character, intentions. Someone intelligent sat down and thought through what to show and how. Scenes with beginnings, middles, and ends and meanings and direction. This film is, by contrast, a lazy, stupidly unrealized piece of incompetence. Kate Winslet's performance, and the beauty of the locations are the only positive parts.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Excellent!!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    dorothy-tripp
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/12/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    If you like dark dramas, this is your movie. Very true to the book and absolutely engrossing. The locations are beautiful. The acting is superb. The characters are richly brought out, and you can understand their thought processes. This is a moral play, as well as a look at the way society imposes rules of conduct. I stumbled on this wonderful film while watching the romance channel on television in 2000. I came in toward the middle, but was immediately drawn into the story. I searched high and low for the video, and when I want a moody drama, this is where I go. This film will make you think. Obviously, the book is practically required reading after you see this movie. You'll just be compelled to know more. Truly a haunting movie that you will remember for a long time.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Ambitious and anything but tender, but wonderfully acted and well adapted
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    TheLittleSongbird
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/11/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Thomas Hardy's Jude the Obscure is a very complicated and ambitious book, and while heavy-reading it is a fine piece of literature. This 1996 film adaptation is a rock-solid adaptation, that is ambitious and realistic. I will admit some parts like the killing of the pig is anything but tender, but none of the scenes are over-sensationalised. As an adaptation of the book, it works very well. If I had a quibble, the secondary characters could have been developed more than they were depicted. The screenplay is well crafted; the writers and the director have at least some idea how Hardy's work should work on film and stay relatively true to the book. The music both haunting and beautiful at the same time was absolutely outstanding. The direction is very fine, never sluggish and never overdone. It was about right. The cinematography is superb, dark, fluid and sensitive. And the period detail was just as good. It was this element alone that contributed to the mood of the adaptation. The love story here which is dirty and tragic was beautifully realised, and very rarely struck a false note. The performances were just brilliant, no overplaying or underplaying as far as I could see. Special mention must go to the two lead performances. Christopher Ecceleston is a very talented and I think under-appreciated actor, and in the title role he was perfectly cast and showed real versatility. As Sue Brideshead, the beautiful Kate Winslet is positively luminous and is true to her character. Out of the supporting performances, the best is Rachel Griffiths as Arabella, a very modest performance I must say. Overall, has its minor flaws but a very well done adaptation of a complicated book. Always realistic and never overly-sentimental as I feared. Though the ending is heart-rending. 9/10 Bethany Cox
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Hardy's Jude the Obscure faithfully portrayed
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    CountZero313
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/4/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Winterbottom keeps the temperature of the searing original novel in his faithful, brilliantly realised film adaptation. Hardy was sick when writing Jude, out of sorts, and the bleak tale has in some quarters been credited more to bile than his muse. Jude's fate is certainly more damning than other Hardy heroes such as Tess, and the final third of this tale requires a strong heart to get through. Jude Fawley is a self-educated stonemason looking to enter the hallowed halls of (a thinly-disguised) Oxford. Class and snobbery combine to crush that dream, but he fights and wins his other dream, to secure the love of his cousin Sue. Headstrong and independent, a prototype Suffragette, she will face her own stern test and be found wanting. Christopher Eccleston inhabits the character fully. The scene in the pub where he recites the Lord's Creed in Latin, then challenges the undergrads to judge if he got it right, is painful and poignant. Winslet is stunning as the admirable but infuriating Sue Brideshead whose choices in life are oblique but all-too-real. A cold draft of air oozes from her expression every time she shuns Jude. There isn't a missed beat in Winslet's portrayal of a woman who goes from supremely confident to utterly lost. Winterbottom would go on to tinker and experiment, unsuccessfully, with Hardy's Mayor of Casterbridge in The Claim. Here, he keeps it strictly BBC, evoking the early industrial age magnificently in his cobbled streets and fog-shrouded spires. An array of British acting talent fill out the supporting roles superbly, most notably Liam Cunningham as the put-upon Phillotson, and Rachel Griffiths as pig-hugging Arabella, whose rising fortune sways in counter-point to Jude's slow, inexorable decline. In one scene where she encounters her estranged son at a fairground, the interaction between woman and child is both naturalistic and magical. The expression on the face of Little Jude's sister is priceless. Perhaps a happy accident, perhaps genius from the director, but all the more tragic for what follows. One of the most ill-fated couples in British literature are vividly brought to life in this film, designed to satisfy fans of the novel. Hardy, one feels, would approve.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Heartbreaking literary adaptation
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Framescourer
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/11/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A briskly but sensitively shot, well-acted and brutally rendered version of Thomas Hardy's tragic novel. I remember being terribly disappointed though (when I saw this in the cinema) that the grainy, visceral b&w images of the title sequence were discontinued as the movie proper got started. Ecclestone finds a great deal of sympathy and charm with which to play the ambitious but unlucky Jude. Kate Winslet is an arguably bigger draw though, throwing herself headlong into a part that requires... well many of the characteristics that she brought to the successful Austen adaptation Sense and Sensibility the previous year: willfulness, joy and despair. Rachel Griffiths is horrible as Jude's ball and chain but nothing is as nasty as the notorious fate of the incestuous couple's children. Strong stuff from Winterbottom, as usual. 6/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Hey Jude, you make it good (web)
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    leplatypus
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It's an excellent movie because it scores in each corner: it has a wonderful, gripping story that can speaks to anyone with heart. As it's an adaptation, you will be interested in reading the novel. Beyond the personal drama, I remember two scandals that are always verified today: 1) education is elitist as it expels those who don't have pedigree 2) Christian congregation is highly hypocritical as they achieve to turn a message of love into one of rejection. It has wonderful locations, between the green pastures and the austere British cities (for those who have seen Spielberg's "War Horse", it has the same ambiance). Winterbottom is inspired to fill his frames and Johnston's soundtrack is just one of the best ever as it gives such poetry to the pictures. As for the cast, it's just an amazing reunion: Eccleston finds his career pick as his Jude is such a good man: always sincere, hardworking, caring, sometimes sad but never quits! Kate is always fascinating by her precocity and by her personal choices for free- spirited characters!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A bitter reflection on non-conformity
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Malcolm Parker
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    With actors of the calibre of Kate Winslet and Christopher Eccleston, this drama could hardly have failed. That said, I felt something was lacking in the characterisation of Sue Bridehead, I haven't read the book, but there is a difficult combination of character traits that stumble between the intellectual and prim and the untethered and vivacious. I felt that we knew Jude, and all the other principle characters, but somehow Sue, despite a magnificent performance by Winslet remained detached and distant as though there was something unexplained in her make up. She was wholly unabashed about her and Jude's marital state, incredibly liberal in her adoption of Jude's son, but yet at times seemed almost uninvolved in her intimacy with Jude. I'm not sure what Hardy wrote, but I think revealing a little more of the motivation behind Sue's character would have clarified and improved the film immensely. Overall though, a very moving and beautifully shot construction, not quite in the same league as Polanski's Tess or Schlesinger's Far from the Madding Crowd, but a great film nevertheless.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "Jude"
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    francescof86
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Jude" is an extraordinary film by one of the most daring and amazing director out there ,as Michael Winterbottom. The original novel("Jude the Obscure") is translated in a brilliant script by Hossein Amini and centers on the aspirations of a lower-class man,Jude Fawley(Christopher Ecclestone),who fights to become a university man. After a quick and wrong marriage with an humble country girl,Arabella(Rachel Griffiths), he met his cousin Sue Bridehead(Kate Winslet)an intelligent,beautiful and apparently as unconventional and brave as him. Their passionate love will end tragically though. The film is from the end to the beginning sad and depressing at his best since we see Jude and Sue fight against the Victorian society's beliefs such as a legalized marriage(they only live as a couple)and the impossible aspirations of a lower-class man who would like to become equal to his peers and study at the university. Ultimately their lives will be destroyed by a cruel destiny. Jude is completely coherent to his ideas but Sue is a tormented and fragile woman who,in the end, is not able to came to terms with what she professed at the beginning. In the end, she turns to religion and accepts a life she rejected because she feels guilty. Christoph Ecclestone and Kate Winslet are just superb. Ecclestone is a serious underrated actor who should be in the spotlight. He never misses a beat and gives an amazing performance. Kate Winslet is completely committed to her role and gives a dramatic performance that is devastating. The director gives the a vivid and crude cut and confirms his uncommon abilities to tell a story set in a different era as we're seeing a modern tragedy.His direction is as tormented as his leads and we can't help but have a feeling that he is not afraid to show the crudest side and the terrible contradictions of the Victorian period. my vote is 10/10.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Suitably depressing piece of Hardy
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    miss_lady_ice-853-608700
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Jude The Obscure is Thomas Hardy's final novel, and his bleakest. It doesn't seem an obvious choice for cinema, hence why it failed at the box office. An air of gloom hangs over the whole proceedings. The story is a little like Tess- a man's chance at love is destroyed by a woman from his past. Jude (Christopher Eccleston) is the man in question- an ambitious country boy whose desire is to become a student at Christminster (Hardy's made-up name for Oxford). He moves to Christminster and falls in love with his clever cousin Sue Brideshead (Kate Winslet). Unfortunately he is already married- to loose country girl Arabella (Rachel Griffiths), who keeps popping up and ruining Jude's chance at happiness. The climax of the film is one of the most tragic and horrific things you will see in a long time. The film is quite well done. It is a bit graphic (this is Michael Winterbottom after all) and anachronistic in places, but there are enough tinges of Hardy to make it a costume drama. He certainly hasn't butchered it as he butchered Tess in his film Trishna. The problem of the film is that Jude is a bit of a ninny, who doesn't seem to have the ruthlessness or the cleverness needed to get into the academic elite and constantly runs back to Arabella. The incestuous aspect is also very off-putting. One feels sorry for Jude and Sue but one can never feel entirely comfortable with their relationship. Another problem, at least adaptation-wise, is that Arabella, who is a horrible sadist in the book from what I've heard, is merely a nuisance here. Perhaps Winterbottom thought that might be too much misery for people but it does mean that the film ends abruptly. Acting-wise, everything is fine. Eccleston convinces as a country boy, although his Northern accent does come out at times. Winslet does well as spirited Sue Brideshead, similar to Rose in Titanic so not much of a stretch for her. EDIT: Having now read the novel- not my favourite Hardy novel but a powerful novel nonetheless- the film gets the sexuality right. Everything that Hardy couldn't show, this film shows, so for those who complain that the film has too much nudity, this is actually quite true to the novel- particularly as none of it is very erotic. Jude's weakness for the flesh is almost animalistic. Leaving aside the hot and steamy, we have that whole spiritual dimension. That part of the novel is quite hard to translate and it doesn't really come through in this film. Jude is meant to be too noble for this world, hindered by his fleshy desires. And the film really does let Arabella off too lightly. In this, she's a typical country wench- a tart with not much of a heart. However in the book, she's not only a tart with no heart, she's a proper butcher, cruel to the point of sadism.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    This was a depressing and disturbing movie.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    rujammin2
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/1/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This was a depressing and disturbing movie. I Couldn't get this movie out of my head for a couple days and in a bad way! I wished I would of turned it off before I was so traumatized by it! It's long, cold , depressing and a waste of 2+ hours. The only reason I hung on was for the actors. Kate and Christopher made the best of a terrible story. The director did a great job of putting you right there in the movie. Unfortunately it's not a great place to be. Some of the scenes were just a little overly disturbing for my taste. This movie could of ended an hour earlier and it wouldn't of mattered. I strongly suggest skipping this unless you really want to fell deflated afterward.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    incompetent, poorly conceived, boring
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    withnail-4
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/1/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    What kind of person is Jude? does he have a love for Latin? Does he really want to be a scholar? What does he think of his wife Arabella? what is she like? Are we supposed to like her, dislike her? because...? because she is sensual? earthy? Is she too ignorant to be a good wife for Jude? Is Jude Smart? We see them have sex..and this means..? Not one scene has any development. Guy walks around in the rain, somebody tells a boy that education is everything...Is this Jude our hero? He is shown trying to memorize some Latin. How far has he progressed ...what does Classical literature mean to him? The viewer's emotions are not guided toward any coherent response ...scenes begin and end without discernible intention. Lazy, incompetent film directing. Not thought through. Watch a film Like Hobson's Choice by David Lean, in comparison, and appreciate how every image, gesture, every object, conveys thoughts, character, intentions. Someone intelligent sat down and thought through what to show and how. Scenes with beginnings, middles, and ends and meanings and direction. This film is, by contrast, a lazy, stupidly unrealized piece of incompetence. Kate Winslet's performance, and the beauty of the locations are the only positive parts.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Excellent!!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    dorothy-tripp
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/12/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    If you like dark dramas, this is your movie. Very true to the book and absolutely engrossing. The locations are beautiful. The acting is superb. The characters are richly brought out, and you can understand their thought processes. This is a moral play, as well as a look at the way society imposes rules of conduct. I stumbled on this wonderful film while watching the romance channel on television in 2000. I came in toward the middle, but was immediately drawn into the story. I searched high and low for the video, and when I want a moody drama, this is where I go. This film will make you think. Obviously, the book is practically required reading after you see this movie. You'll just be compelled to know more. Truly a haunting movie that you will remember for a long time.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Ambitious and anything but tender, but wonderfully acted and well adapted
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    TheLittleSongbird
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/11/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Thomas Hardy's Jude the Obscure is a very complicated and ambitious book, and while heavy-reading it is a fine piece of literature. This 1996 film adaptation is a rock-solid adaptation, that is ambitious and realistic. I will admit some parts like the killing of the pig is anything but tender, but none of the scenes are over-sensationalised. As an adaptation of the book, it works very well. If I had a quibble, the secondary characters could have been developed more than they were depicted. The screenplay is well crafted; the writers and the director have at least some idea how Hardy's work should work on film and stay relatively true to the book. The music both haunting and beautiful at the same time was absolutely outstanding. The direction is very fine, never sluggish and never overdone. It was about right. The cinematography is superb, dark, fluid and sensitive. And the period detail was just as good. It was this element alone that contributed to the mood of the adaptation. The love story here which is dirty and tragic was beautifully realised, and very rarely struck a false note. The performances were just brilliant, no overplaying or underplaying as far as I could see. Special mention must go to the two lead performances. Christopher Ecceleston is a very talented and I think under-appreciated actor, and in the title role he was perfectly cast and showed real versatility. As Sue Brideshead, the beautiful Kate Winslet is positively luminous and is true to her character. Out of the supporting performances, the best is Rachel Griffiths as Arabella, a very modest performance I must say. Overall, has its minor flaws but a very well done adaptation of a complicated book. Always realistic and never overly-sentimental as I feared. Though the ending is heart-rending. 9/10 Bethany Cox
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Hardy's Jude the Obscure faithfully portrayed
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    CountZero313
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/4/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Winterbottom keeps the temperature of the searing original novel in his faithful, brilliantly realised film adaptation. Hardy was sick when writing Jude, out of sorts, and the bleak tale has in some quarters been credited more to bile than his muse. Jude's fate is certainly more damning than other Hardy heroes such as Tess, and the final third of this tale requires a strong heart to get through. Jude Fawley is a self-educated stonemason looking to enter the hallowed halls of (a thinly-disguised) Oxford. Class and snobbery combine to crush that dream, but he fights and wins his other dream, to secure the love of his cousin Sue. Headstrong and independent, a prototype Suffragette, she will face her own stern test and be found wanting. Christopher Eccleston inhabits the character fully. The scene in the pub where he recites the Lord's Creed in Latin, then challenges the undergrads to judge if he got it right, is painful and poignant. Winslet is stunning as the admirable but infuriating Sue Brideshead whose choices in life are oblique but all-too-real. A cold draft of air oozes from her expression every time she shuns Jude. There isn't a missed beat in Winslet's portrayal of a woman who goes from supremely confident to utterly lost. Winterbottom would go on to tinker and experiment, unsuccessfully, with Hardy's Mayor of Casterbridge in The Claim. Here, he keeps it strictly BBC, evoking the early industrial age magnificently in his cobbled streets and fog-shrouded spires. An array of British acting talent fill out the supporting roles superbly, most notably Liam Cunningham as the put-upon Phillotson, and Rachel Griffiths as pig-hugging Arabella, whose rising fortune sways in counter-point to Jude's slow, inexorable decline. In one scene where she encounters her estranged son at a fairground, the interaction between woman and child is both naturalistic and magical. The expression on the face of Little Jude's sister is priceless. Perhaps a happy accident, perhaps genius from the director, but all the more tragic for what follows. One of the most ill-fated couples in British literature are vividly brought to life in this film, designed to satisfy fans of the novel. Hardy, one feels, would approve.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Heartbreaking literary adaptation
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Framescourer
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/11/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A briskly but sensitively shot, well-acted and brutally rendered version of Thomas Hardy's tragic novel. I remember being terribly disappointed though (when I saw this in the cinema) that the grainy, visceral b&w images of the title sequence were discontinued as the movie proper got started. Ecclestone finds a great deal of sympathy and charm with which to play the ambitious but unlucky Jude. Kate Winslet is an arguably bigger draw though, throwing herself headlong into a part that requires... well many of the characteristics that she brought to the successful Austen adaptation Sense and Sensibility the previous year: willfulness, joy and despair. Rachel Griffiths is horrible as Jude's ball and chain but nothing is as nasty as the notorious fate of the incestuous couple's children. Strong stuff from Winterbottom, as usual. 6/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Hey Jude, you make it good (web)
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    leplatypus
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It's an excellent movie because it scores in each corner: it has a wonderful, gripping story that can speaks to anyone with heart. As it's an adaptation, you will be interested in reading the novel. Beyond the personal drama, I remember two scandals that are always verified today: 1) education is elitist as it expels those who don't have pedigree 2) Christian congregation is highly hypocritical as they achieve to turn a message of love into one of rejection. It has wonderful locations, between the green pastures and the austere British cities (for those who have seen Spielberg's "War Horse", it has the same ambiance). Winterbottom is inspired to fill his frames and Johnston's soundtrack is just one of the best ever as it gives such poetry to the pictures. As for the cast, it's just an amazing reunion: Eccleston finds his career pick as his Jude is such a good man: always sincere, hardworking, caring, sometimes sad but never quits! Kate is always fascinating by her precocity and by her personal choices for free- spirited characters!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A bitter reflection on non-conformity
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Malcolm Parker
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    With actors of the calibre of Kate Winslet and Christopher Eccleston, this drama could hardly have failed. That said, I felt something was lacking in the characterisation of Sue Bridehead, I haven't read the book, but there is a difficult combination of character traits that stumble between the intellectual and prim and the untethered and vivacious. I felt that we knew Jude, and all the other principle characters, but somehow Sue, despite a magnificent performance by Winslet remained detached and distant as though there was something unexplained in her make up. She was wholly unabashed about her and Jude's marital state, incredibly liberal in her adoption of Jude's son, but yet at times seemed almost uninvolved in her intimacy with Jude. I'm not sure what Hardy wrote, but I think revealing a little more of the motivation behind Sue's character would have clarified and improved the film immensely. Overall though, a very moving and beautifully shot construction, not quite in the same league as Polanski's Tess or Schlesinger's Far from the Madding Crowd, but a great film nevertheless.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "Jude"
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    francescof86
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Jude" is an extraordinary film by one of the most daring and amazing director out there ,as Michael Winterbottom. The original novel("Jude the Obscure") is translated in a brilliant script by Hossein Amini and centers on the aspirations of a lower-class man,Jude Fawley(Christopher Ecclestone),who fights to become a university man. After a quick and wrong marriage with an humble country girl,Arabella(Rachel Griffiths), he met his cousin Sue Bridehead(Kate Winslet)an intelligent,beautiful and apparently as unconventional and brave as him. Their passionate love will end tragically though. The film is from the end to the beginning sad and depressing at his best since we see Jude and Sue fight against the Victorian society's beliefs such as a legalized marriage(they only live as a couple)and the impossible aspirations of a lower-class man who would like to become equal to his peers and study at the university. Ultimately their lives will be destroyed by a cruel destiny. Jude is completely coherent to his ideas but Sue is a tormented and fragile woman who,in the end, is not able to came to terms with what she professed at the beginning. In the end, she turns to religion and accepts a life she rejected because she feels guilty. Christoph Ecclestone and Kate Winslet are just superb. Ecclestone is a serious underrated actor who should be in the spotlight. He never misses a beat and gives an amazing performance. Kate Winslet is completely committed to her role and gives a dramatic performance that is devastating. The director gives the a vivid and crude cut and confirms his uncommon abilities to tell a story set in a different era as we're seeing a modern tragedy.His direction is as tormented as his leads and we can't help but have a feeling that he is not afraid to show the crudest side and the terrible contradictions of the Victorian period. my vote is 10/10.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Suitably depressing piece of Hardy
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    miss_lady_ice-853-608700
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Jude The Obscure is Thomas Hardy's final novel, and his bleakest. It doesn't seem an obvious choice for cinema, hence why it failed at the box office. An air of gloom hangs over the whole proceedings. The story is a little like Tess- a man's chance at love is destroyed by a woman from his past. Jude (Christopher Eccleston) is the man in question- an ambitious country boy whose desire is to become a student at Christminster (Hardy's made-up name for Oxford). He moves to Christminster and falls in love with his clever cousin Sue Brideshead (Kate Winslet). Unfortunately he is already married- to loose country girl Arabella (Rachel Griffiths), who keeps popping up and ruining Jude's chance at happiness. The climax of the film is one of the most tragic and horrific things you will see in a long time. The film is quite well done. It is a bit graphic (this is Michael Winterbottom after all) and anachronistic in places, but there are enough tinges of Hardy to make it a costume drama. He certainly hasn't butchered it as he butchered Tess in his film Trishna. The problem of the film is that Jude is a bit of a ninny, who doesn't seem to have the ruthlessness or the cleverness needed to get into the academic elite and constantly runs back to Arabella. The incestuous aspect is also very off-putting. One feels sorry for Jude and Sue but one can never feel entirely comfortable with their relationship. Another problem, at least adaptation-wise, is that Arabella, who is a horrible sadist in the book from what I've heard, is merely a nuisance here. Perhaps Winterbottom thought that might be too much misery for people but it does mean that the film ends abruptly. Acting-wise, everything is fine. Eccleston convinces as a country boy, although his Northern accent does come out at times. Winslet does well as spirited Sue Brideshead, similar to Rose in Titanic so not much of a stretch for her. EDIT: Having now read the novel- not my favourite Hardy novel but a powerful novel nonetheless- the film gets the sexuality right. Everything that Hardy couldn't show, this film shows, so for those who complain that the film has too much nudity, this is actually quite true to the novel- particularly as none of it is very erotic. Jude's weakness for the flesh is almost animalistic. Leaving aside the hot and steamy, we have that whole spiritual dimension. That part of the novel is quite hard to translate and it doesn't really come through in this film. Jude is meant to be too noble for this world, hindered by his fleshy desires. And the film really does let Arabella off too lightly. In this, she's a typical country wench- a tart with not much of a heart. However in the book, she's not only a tart with no heart, she's a proper butcher, cruel to the point of sadism.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    This was a depressing and disturbing movie.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    rujammin2
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/1/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This was a depressing and disturbing movie. I Couldn't get this movie out of my head for a couple days and in a bad way! I wished I would of turned it off before I was so traumatized by it! It's long, cold , depressing and a waste of 2+ hours. The only reason I hung on was for the actors. Kate and Christopher made the best of a terrible story. The director did a great job of putting you right there in the movie. Unfortunately it's not a great place to be. Some of the scenes were just a little overly disturbing for my taste. This movie could of ended an hour earlier and it wouldn't of mattered. I strongly suggest skipping this unless you really want to fell deflated afterward.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    incompetent, poorly conceived, boring
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    withnail-4
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/1/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    What kind of person is Jude? does he have a love for Latin? Does he really want to be a scholar? What does he think of his wife Arabella? what is she like? Are we supposed to like her, dislike her? because...? because she is sensual? earthy? Is she too ignorant to be a good wife for Jude? Is Jude Smart? We see them have sex..and this means..? Not one scene has any development. Guy walks around in the rain, somebody tells a boy that education is everything...Is this Jude our hero? He is shown trying to memorize some Latin. How far has he progressed ...what does Classical literature mean to him? The viewer's emotions are not guided toward any coherent response ...scenes begin and end without discernible intention. Lazy, incompetent film directing. Not thought through. Watch a film Like Hobson's Choice by David Lean, in comparison, and appreciate how every image, gesture, every object, conveys thoughts, character, intentions. Someone intelligent sat down and thought through what to show and how. Scenes with beginnings, middles, and ends and meanings and direction. This film is, by contrast, a lazy, stupidly unrealized piece of incompetence. Kate Winslet's performance, and the beauty of the locations are the only positive parts.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Excellent!!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    dorothy-tripp
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/12/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    If you like dark dramas, this is your movie. Very true to the book and absolutely engrossing. The locations are beautiful. The acting is superb. The characters are richly brought out, and you can understand their thought processes. This is a moral play, as well as a look at the way society imposes rules of conduct. I stumbled on this wonderful film while watching the romance channel on television in 2000. I came in toward the middle, but was immediately drawn into the story. I searched high and low for the video, and when I want a moody drama, this is where I go. This film will make you think. Obviously, the book is practically required reading after you see this movie. You'll just be compelled to know more. Truly a haunting movie that you will remember for a long time.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Ambitious and anything but tender, but wonderfully acted and well adapted
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    TheLittleSongbird
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/11/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Thomas Hardy's Jude the Obscure is a very complicated and ambitious book, and while heavy-reading it is a fine piece of literature. This 1996 film adaptation is a rock-solid adaptation, that is ambitious and realistic. I will admit some parts like the killing of the pig is anything but tender, but none of the scenes are over-sensationalised. As an adaptation of the book, it works very well. If I had a quibble, the secondary characters could have been developed more than they were depicted. The screenplay is well crafted; the writers and the director have at least some idea how Hardy's work should work on film and stay relatively true to the book. The music both haunting and beautiful at the same time was absolutely outstanding. The direction is very fine, never sluggish and never overdone. It was about right. The cinematography is superb, dark, fluid and sensitive. And the period detail was just as good. It was this element alone that contributed to the mood of the adaptation. The love story here which is dirty and tragic was beautifully realised, and very rarely struck a false note. The performances were just brilliant, no overplaying or underplaying as far as I could see. Special mention must go to the two lead performances. Christopher Ecceleston is a very talented and I think under-appreciated actor, and in the title role he was perfectly cast and showed real versatility. As Sue Brideshead, the beautiful Kate Winslet is positively luminous and is true to her character. Out of the supporting performances, the best is Rachel Griffiths as Arabella, a very modest performance I must say. Overall, has its minor flaws but a very well done adaptation of a complicated book. Always realistic and never overly-sentimental as I feared. Though the ending is heart-rending. 9/10 Bethany Cox
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Hardy's Jude the Obscure faithfully portrayed
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    CountZero313
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/4/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Winterbottom keeps the temperature of the searing original novel in his faithful, brilliantly realised film adaptation. Hardy was sick when writing Jude, out of sorts, and the bleak tale has in some quarters been credited more to bile than his muse. Jude's fate is certainly more damning than other Hardy heroes such as Tess, and the final third of this tale requires a strong heart to get through. Jude Fawley is a self-educated stonemason looking to enter the hallowed halls of (a thinly-disguised) Oxford. Class and snobbery combine to crush that dream, but he fights and wins his other dream, to secure the love of his cousin Sue. Headstrong and independent, a prototype Suffragette, she will face her own stern test and be found wanting. Christopher Eccleston inhabits the character fully. The scene in the pub where he recites the Lord's Creed in Latin, then challenges the undergrads to judge if he got it right, is painful and poignant. Winslet is stunning as the admirable but infuriating Sue Brideshead whose choices in life are oblique but all-too-real. A cold draft of air oozes from her expression every time she shuns Jude. There isn't a missed beat in Winslet's portrayal of a woman who goes from supremely confident to utterly lost. Winterbottom would go on to tinker and experiment, unsuccessfully, with Hardy's Mayor of Casterbridge in The Claim. Here, he keeps it strictly BBC, evoking the early industrial age magnificently in his cobbled streets and fog-shrouded spires. An array of British acting talent fill out the supporting roles superbly, most notably Liam Cunningham as the put-upon Phillotson, and Rachel Griffiths as pig-hugging Arabella, whose rising fortune sways in counter-point to Jude's slow, inexorable decline. In one scene where she encounters her estranged son at a fairground, the interaction between woman and child is both naturalistic and magical. The expression on the face of Little Jude's sister is priceless. Perhaps a happy accident, perhaps genius from the director, but all the more tragic for what follows. One of the most ill-fated couples in British literature are vividly brought to life in this film, designed to satisfy fans of the novel. Hardy, one feels, would approve.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Heartbreaking literary adaptation
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Framescourer
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/11/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A briskly but sensitively shot, well-acted and brutally rendered version of Thomas Hardy's tragic novel. I remember being terribly disappointed though (when I saw this in the cinema) that the grainy, visceral b&w images of the title sequence were discontinued as the movie proper got started. Ecclestone finds a great deal of sympathy and charm with which to play the ambitious but unlucky Jude. Kate Winslet is an arguably bigger draw though, throwing herself headlong into a part that requires... well many of the characteristics that she brought to the successful Austen adaptation Sense and Sensibility the previous year: willfulness, joy and despair. Rachel Griffiths is horrible as Jude's ball and chain but nothing is as nasty as the notorious fate of the incestuous couple's children. Strong stuff from Winterbottom, as usual. 6/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Hey Jude, you make it good (web)
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    leplatypus
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It's an excellent movie because it scores in each corner: it has a wonderful, gripping story that can speaks to anyone with heart. As it's an adaptation, you will be interested in reading the novel. Beyond the personal drama, I remember two scandals that are always verified today: 1) education is elitist as it expels those who don't have pedigree 2) Christian congregation is highly hypocritical as they achieve to turn a message of love into one of rejection. It has wonderful locations, between the green pastures and the austere British cities (for those who have seen Spielberg's "War Horse", it has the same ambiance). Winterbottom is inspired to fill his frames and Johnston's soundtrack is just one of the best ever as it gives such poetry to the pictures. As for the cast, it's just an amazing reunion: Eccleston finds his career pick as his Jude is such a good man: always sincere, hardworking, caring, sometimes sad but never quits! Kate is always fascinating by her precocity and by her personal choices for free- spirited characters!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A bitter reflection on non-conformity
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Malcolm Parker
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    With actors of the calibre of Kate Winslet and Christopher Eccleston, this drama could hardly have failed. That said, I felt something was lacking in the characterisation of Sue Bridehead, I haven't read the book, but there is a difficult combination of character traits that stumble between the intellectual and prim and the untethered and vivacious. I felt that we knew Jude, and all the other principle characters, but somehow Sue, despite a magnificent performance by Winslet remained detached and distant as though there was something unexplained in her make up. She was wholly unabashed about her and Jude's marital state, incredibly liberal in her adoption of Jude's son, but yet at times seemed almost uninvolved in her intimacy with Jude. I'm not sure what Hardy wrote, but I think revealing a little more of the motivation behind Sue's character would have clarified and improved the film immensely. Overall though, a very moving and beautifully shot construction, not quite in the same league as Polanski's Tess or Schlesinger's Far from the Madding Crowd, but a great film nevertheless.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "Jude"
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    francescof86
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Jude" is an extraordinary film by one of the most daring and amazing director out there ,as Michael Winterbottom. The original novel("Jude the Obscure") is translated in a brilliant script by Hossein Amini and centers on the aspirations of a lower-class man,Jude Fawley(Christopher Ecclestone),who fights to become a university man. After a quick and wrong marriage with an humble country girl,Arabella(Rachel Griffiths), he met his cousin Sue Bridehead(Kate Winslet)an intelligent,beautiful and apparently as unconventional and brave as him. Their passionate love will end tragically though. The film is from the end to the beginning sad and depressing at his best since we see Jude and Sue fight against the Victorian society's beliefs such as a legalized marriage(they only live as a couple)and the impossible aspirations of a lower-class man who would like to become equal to his peers and study at the university. Ultimately their lives will be destroyed by a cruel destiny. Jude is completely coherent to his ideas but Sue is a tormented and fragile woman who,in the end, is not able to came to terms with what she professed at the beginning. In the end, she turns to religion and accepts a life she rejected because she feels guilty. Christoph Ecclestone and Kate Winslet are just superb. Ecclestone is a serious underrated actor who should be in the spotlight. He never misses a beat and gives an amazing performance. Kate Winslet is completely committed to her role and gives a dramatic performance that is devastating. The director gives the a vivid and crude cut and confirms his uncommon abilities to tell a story set in a different era as we're seeing a modern tragedy.His direction is as tormented as his leads and we can't help but have a feeling that he is not afraid to show the crudest side and the terrible contradictions of the Victorian period. my vote is 10/10.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Suitably depressing piece of Hardy
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    miss_lady_ice-853-608700
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Jude The Obscure is Thomas Hardy's final novel, and his bleakest. It doesn't seem an obvious choice for cinema, hence why it failed at the box office. An air of gloom hangs over the whole proceedings. The story is a little like Tess- a man's chance at love is destroyed by a woman from his past. Jude (Christopher Eccleston) is the man in question- an ambitious country boy whose desire is to become a student at Christminster (Hardy's made-up name for Oxford). He moves to Christminster and falls in love with his clever cousin Sue Brideshead (Kate Winslet). Unfortunately he is already married- to loose country girl Arabella (Rachel Griffiths), who keeps popping up and ruining Jude's chance at happiness. The climax of the film is one of the most tragic and horrific things you will see in a long time. The film is quite well done. It is a bit graphic (this is Michael Winterbottom after all) and anachronistic in places, but there are enough tinges of Hardy to make it a costume drama. He certainly hasn't butchered it as he butchered Tess in his film Trishna. The problem of the film is that Jude is a bit of a ninny, who doesn't seem to have the ruthlessness or the cleverness needed to get into the academic elite and constantly runs back to Arabella. The incestuous aspect is also very off-putting. One feels sorry for Jude and Sue but one can never feel entirely comfortable with their relationship. Another problem, at least adaptation-wise, is that Arabella, who is a horrible sadist in the book from what I've heard, is merely a nuisance here. Perhaps Winterbottom thought that might be too much misery for people but it does mean that the film ends abruptly. Acting-wise, everything is fine. Eccleston convinces as a country boy, although his Northern accent does come out at times. Winslet does well as spirited Sue Brideshead, similar to Rose in Titanic so not much of a stretch for her. EDIT: Having now read the novel- not my favourite Hardy novel but a powerful novel nonetheless- the film gets the sexuality right. Everything that Hardy couldn't show, this film shows, so for those who complain that the film has too much nudity, this is actually quite true to the novel- particularly as none of it is very erotic. Jude's weakness for the flesh is almost animalistic. Leaving aside the hot and steamy, we have that whole spiritual dimension. That part of the novel is quite hard to translate and it doesn't really come through in this film. Jude is meant to be too noble for this world, hindered by his fleshy desires. And the film really does let Arabella off too lightly. In this, she's a typical country wench- a tart with not much of a heart. However in the book, she's not only a tart with no heart, she's a proper butcher, cruel to the point of sadism.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    This was a depressing and disturbing movie.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    rujammin2
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/1/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This was a depressing and disturbing movie. I Couldn't get this movie out of my head for a couple days and in a bad way! I wished I would of turned it off before I was so traumatized by it! It's long, cold , depressing and a waste of 2+ hours. The only reason I hung on was for the actors. Kate and Christopher made the best of a terrible story. The director did a great job of putting you right there in the movie. Unfortunately it's not a great place to be. Some of the scenes were just a little overly disturbing for my taste. This movie could of ended an hour earlier and it wouldn't of mattered. I strongly suggest skipping this unless you really want to fell deflated afterward.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    incompetent, poorly conceived, boring
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    withnail-4
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/1/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    What kind of person is Jude? does he have a love for Latin? Does he really want to be a scholar? What does he think of his wife Arabella? what is she like? Are we supposed to like her, dislike her? because...? because she is sensual? earthy? Is she too ignorant to be a good wife for Jude? Is Jude Smart? We see them have sex..and this means..? Not one scene has any development. Guy walks around in the rain, somebody tells a boy that education is everything...Is this Jude our hero? He is shown trying to memorize some Latin. How far has he progressed ...what does Classical literature mean to him? The viewer's emotions are not guided toward any coherent response ...scenes begin and end without discernible intention. Lazy, incompetent film directing. Not thought through. Watch a film Like Hobson's Choice by David Lean, in comparison, and appreciate how every image, gesture, every object, conveys thoughts, character, intentions. Someone intelligent sat down and thought through what to show and how. Scenes with beginnings, middles, and ends and meanings and direction. This film is, by contrast, a lazy, stupidly unrealized piece of incompetence. Kate Winslet's performance, and the beauty of the locations are the only positive parts.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Excellent!!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    dorothy-tripp
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/12/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    If you like dark dramas, this is your movie. Very true to the book and absolutely engrossing. The locations are beautiful. The acting is superb. The characters are richly brought out, and you can understand their thought processes. This is a moral play, as well as a look at the way society imposes rules of conduct. I stumbled on this wonderful film while watching the romance channel on television in 2000. I came in toward the middle, but was immediately drawn into the story. I searched high and low for the video, and when I want a moody drama, this is where I go. This film will make you think. Obviously, the book is practically required reading after you see this movie. You'll just be compelled to know more. Truly a haunting movie that you will remember for a long time.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Ambitious and anything but tender, but wonderfully acted and well adapted
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    TheLittleSongbird
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/11/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Thomas Hardy's Jude the Obscure is a very complicated and ambitious book, and while heavy-reading it is a fine piece of literature. This 1996 film adaptation is a rock-solid adaptation, that is ambitious and realistic. I will admit some parts like the killing of the pig is anything but tender, but none of the scenes are over-sensationalised. As an adaptation of the book, it works very well. If I had a quibble, the secondary characters could have been developed more than they were depicted. The screenplay is well crafted; the writers and the director have at least some idea how Hardy's work should work on film and stay relatively true to the book. The music both haunting and beautiful at the same time was absolutely outstanding. The direction is very fine, never sluggish and never overdone. It was about right. The cinematography is superb, dark, fluid and sensitive. And the period detail was just as good. It was this element alone that contributed to the mood of the adaptation. The love story here which is dirty and tragic was beautifully realised, and very rarely struck a false note. The performances were just brilliant, no overplaying or underplaying as far as I could see. Special mention must go to the two lead performances. Christopher Ecceleston is a very talented and I think under-appreciated actor, and in the title role he was perfectly cast and showed real versatility. As Sue Brideshead, the beautiful Kate Winslet is positively luminous and is true to her character. Out of the supporting performances, the best is Rachel Griffiths as Arabella, a very modest performance I must say. Overall, has its minor flaws but a very well done adaptation of a complicated book. Always realistic and never overly-sentimental as I feared. Though the ending is heart-rending. 9/10 Bethany Cox
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Hardy's Jude the Obscure faithfully portrayed
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    CountZero313
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/4/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Winterbottom keeps the temperature of the searing original novel in his faithful, brilliantly realised film adaptation. Hardy was sick when writing Jude, out of sorts, and the bleak tale has in some quarters been credited more to bile than his muse. Jude's fate is certainly more damning than other Hardy heroes such as Tess, and the final third of this tale requires a strong heart to get through. Jude Fawley is a self-educated stonemason looking to enter the hallowed halls of (a thinly-disguised) Oxford. Class and snobbery combine to crush that dream, but he fights and wins his other dream, to secure the love of his cousin Sue. Headstrong and independent, a prototype Suffragette, she will face her own stern test and be found wanting. Christopher Eccleston inhabits the character fully. The scene in the pub where he recites the Lord's Creed in Latin, then challenges the undergrads to judge if he got it right, is painful and poignant. Winslet is stunning as the admirable but infuriating Sue Brideshead whose choices in life are oblique but all-too-real. A cold draft of air oozes from her expression every time she shuns Jude. There isn't a missed beat in Winslet's portrayal of a woman who goes from supremely confident to utterly lost. Winterbottom would go on to tinker and experiment, unsuccessfully, with Hardy's Mayor of Casterbridge in The Claim. Here, he keeps it strictly BBC, evoking the early industrial age magnificently in his cobbled streets and fog-shrouded spires. An array of British acting talent fill out the supporting roles superbly, most notably Liam Cunningham as the put-upon Phillotson, and Rachel Griffiths as pig-hugging Arabella, whose rising fortune sways in counter-point to Jude's slow, inexorable decline. In one scene where she encounters her estranged son at a fairground, the interaction between woman and child is both naturalistic and magical. The expression on the face of Little Jude's sister is priceless. Perhaps a happy accident, perhaps genius from the director, but all the more tragic for what follows. One of the most ill-fated couples in British literature are vividly brought to life in this film, designed to satisfy fans of the novel. Hardy, one feels, would approve.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Heartbreaking literary adaptation
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Framescourer
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/11/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A briskly but sensitively shot, well-acted and brutally rendered version of Thomas Hardy's tragic novel. I remember being terribly disappointed though (when I saw this in the cinema) that the grainy, visceral b&w images of the title sequence were discontinued as the movie proper got started. Ecclestone finds a great deal of sympathy and charm with which to play the ambitious but unlucky Jude. Kate Winslet is an arguably bigger draw though, throwing herself headlong into a part that requires... well many of the characteristics that she brought to the successful Austen adaptation Sense and Sensibility the previous year: willfulness, joy and despair. Rachel Griffiths is horrible as Jude's ball and chain but nothing is as nasty as the notorious fate of the incestuous couple's children. Strong stuff from Winterbottom, as usual. 6/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Hey Jude, you make it good (web)
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    leplatypus
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It's an excellent movie because it scores in each corner: it has a wonderful, gripping story that can speaks to anyone with heart. As it's an adaptation, you will be interested in reading the novel. Beyond the personal drama, I remember two scandals that are always verified today: 1) education is elitist as it expels those who don't have pedigree 2) Christian congregation is highly hypocritical as they achieve to turn a message of love into one of rejection. It has wonderful locations, between the green pastures and the austere British cities (for those who have seen Spielberg's "War Horse", it has the same ambiance). Winterbottom is inspired to fill his frames and Johnston's soundtrack is just one of the best ever as it gives such poetry to the pictures. As for the cast, it's just an amazing reunion: Eccleston finds his career pick as his Jude is such a good man: always sincere, hardworking, caring, sometimes sad but never quits! Kate is always fascinating by her precocity and by her personal choices for free- spirited characters!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A bitter reflection on non-conformity
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Malcolm Parker
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    With actors of the calibre of Kate Winslet and Christopher Eccleston, this drama could hardly have failed. That said, I felt something was lacking in the characterisation of Sue Bridehead, I haven't read the book, but there is a difficult combination of character traits that stumble between the intellectual and prim and the untethered and vivacious. I felt that we knew Jude, and all the other principle characters, but somehow Sue, despite a magnificent performance by Winslet remained detached and distant as though there was something unexplained in her make up. She was wholly unabashed about her and Jude's marital state, incredibly liberal in her adoption of Jude's son, but yet at times seemed almost uninvolved in her intimacy with Jude. I'm not sure what Hardy wrote, but I think revealing a little more of the motivation behind Sue's character would have clarified and improved the film immensely. Overall though, a very moving and beautifully shot construction, not quite in the same league as Polanski's Tess or Schlesinger's Far from the Madding Crowd, but a great film nevertheless.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "Jude"
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    francescof86
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Jude" is an extraordinary film by one of the most daring and amazing director out there ,as Michael Winterbottom. The original novel("Jude the Obscure") is translated in a brilliant script by Hossein Amini and centers on the aspirations of a lower-class man,Jude Fawley(Christopher Ecclestone),who fights to become a university man. After a quick and wrong marriage with an humble country girl,Arabella(Rachel Griffiths), he met his cousin Sue Bridehead(Kate Winslet)an intelligent,beautiful and apparently as unconventional and brave as him. Their passionate love will end tragically though. The film is from the end to the beginning sad and depressing at his best since we see Jude and Sue fight against the Victorian society's beliefs such as a legalized marriage(they only live as a couple)and the impossible aspirations of a lower-class man who would like to become equal to his peers and study at the university. Ultimately their lives will be destroyed by a cruel destiny. Jude is completely coherent to his ideas but Sue is a tormented and fragile woman who,in the end, is not able to came to terms with what she professed at the beginning. In the end, she turns to religion and accepts a life she rejected because she feels guilty. Christoph Ecclestone and Kate Winslet are just superb. Ecclestone is a serious underrated actor who should be in the spotlight. He never misses a beat and gives an amazing performance. Kate Winslet is completely committed to her role and gives a dramatic performance that is devastating. The director gives the a vivid and crude cut and confirms his uncommon abilities to tell a story set in a different era as we're seeing a modern tragedy.His direction is as tormented as his leads and we can't help but have a feeling that he is not afraid to show the crudest side and the terrible contradictions of the Victorian period. my vote is 10/10.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Suitably depressing piece of Hardy
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    miss_lady_ice-853-608700
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Jude The Obscure is Thomas Hardy's final novel, and his bleakest. It doesn't seem an obvious choice for cinema, hence why it failed at the box office. An air of gloom hangs over the whole proceedings. The story is a little like Tess- a man's chance at love is destroyed by a woman from his past. Jude (Christopher Eccleston) is the man in question- an ambitious country boy whose desire is to become a student at Christminster (Hardy's made-up name for Oxford). He moves to Christminster and falls in love with his clever cousin Sue Brideshead (Kate Winslet). Unfortunately he is already married- to loose country girl Arabella (Rachel Griffiths), who keeps popping up and ruining Jude's chance at happiness. The climax of the film is one of the most tragic and horrific things you will see in a long time. The film is quite well done. It is a bit graphic (this is Michael Winterbottom after all) and anachronistic in places, but there are enough tinges of Hardy to make it a costume drama. He certainly hasn't butchered it as he butchered Tess in his film Trishna. The problem of the film is that Jude is a bit of a ninny, who doesn't seem to have the ruthlessness or the cleverness needed to get into the academic elite and constantly runs back to Arabella. The incestuous aspect is also very off-putting. One feels sorry for Jude and Sue but one can never feel entirely comfortable with their relationship. Another problem, at least adaptation-wise, is that Arabella, who is a horrible sadist in the book from what I've heard, is merely a nuisance here. Perhaps Winterbottom thought that might be too much misery for people but it does mean that the film ends abruptly. Acting-wise, everything is fine. Eccleston convinces as a country boy, although his Northern accent does come out at times. Winslet does well as spirited Sue Brideshead, similar to Rose in Titanic so not much of a stretch for her. EDIT: Having now read the novel- not my favourite Hardy novel but a powerful novel nonetheless- the film gets the sexuality right. Everything that Hardy couldn't show, this film shows, so for those who complain that the film has too much nudity, this is actually quite true to the novel- particularly as none of it is very erotic. Jude's weakness for the flesh is almost animalistic. Leaving aside the hot and steamy, we have that whole spiritual dimension. That part of the novel is quite hard to translate and it doesn't really come through in this film. Jude is meant to be too noble for this world, hindered by his fleshy desires. And the film really does let Arabella off too lightly. In this, she's a typical country wench- a tart with not much of a heart. However in the book, she's not only a tart with no heart, she's a proper butcher, cruel to the point of sadism.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    This was a depressing and disturbing movie.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    rujammin2
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/1/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This was a depressing and disturbing movie. I Couldn't get this movie out of my head for a couple days and in a bad way! I wished I would of turned it off before I was so traumatized by it! It's long, cold , depressing and a waste of 2+ hours. The only reason I hung on was for the actors. Kate and Christopher made the best of a terrible story. The director did a great job of putting you right there in the movie. Unfortunately it's not a great place to be. Some of the scenes were just a little overly disturbing for my taste. This movie could of ended an hour earlier and it wouldn't of mattered. I strongly suggest skipping this unless you really want to fell deflated afterward.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    incompetent, poorly conceived, boring
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    withnail-4
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/1/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    What kind of person is Jude? does he have a love for Latin? Does he really want to be a scholar? What does he think of his wife Arabella? what is she like? Are we supposed to like her, dislike her? because...? because she is sensual? earthy? Is she too ignorant to be a good wife for Jude? Is Jude Smart? We see them have sex..and this means..? Not one scene has any development. Guy walks around in the rain, somebody tells a boy that education is everything...Is this Jude our hero? He is shown trying to memorize some Latin. How far has he progressed ...what does Classical literature mean to him? The viewer's emotions are not guided toward any coherent response ...scenes begin and end without discernible intention. Lazy, incompetent film directing. Not thought through. Watch a film Like Hobson's Choice by David Lean, in comparison, and appreciate how every image, gesture, every object, conveys thoughts, character, intentions. Someone intelligent sat down and thought through what to show and how. Scenes with beginnings, middles, and ends and meanings and direction. This film is, by contrast, a lazy, stupidly unrealized piece of incompetence. Kate Winslet's performance, and the beauty of the locations are the only positive parts.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Excellent!!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    dorothy-tripp
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/12/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    If you like dark dramas, this is your movie. Very true to the book and absolutely engrossing. The locations are beautiful. The acting is superb. The characters are richly brought out, and you can understand their thought processes. This is a moral play, as well as a look at the way society imposes rules of conduct. I stumbled on this wonderful film while watching the romance channel on television in 2000. I came in toward the middle, but was immediately drawn into the story. I searched high and low for the video, and when I want a moody drama, this is where I go. This film will make you think. Obviously, the book is practically required reading after you see this movie. You'll just be compelled to know more. Truly a haunting movie that you will remember for a long time.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Ambitious and anything but tender, but wonderfully acted and well adapted
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    TheLittleSongbird
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/11/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Thomas Hardy's Jude the Obscure is a very complicated and ambitious book, and while heavy-reading it is a fine piece of literature. This 1996 film adaptation is a rock-solid adaptation, that is ambitious and realistic. I will admit some parts like the killing of the pig is anything but tender, but none of the scenes are over-sensationalised. As an adaptation of the book, it works very well. If I had a quibble, the secondary characters could have been developed more than they were depicted. The screenplay is well crafted; the writers and the director have at least some idea how Hardy's work should work on film and stay relatively true to the book. The music both haunting and beautiful at the same time was absolutely outstanding. The direction is very fine, never sluggish and never overdone. It was about right. The cinematography is superb, dark, fluid and sensitive. And the period detail was just as good. It was this element alone that contributed to the mood of the adaptation. The love story here which is dirty and tragic was beautifully realised, and very rarely struck a false note. The performances were just brilliant, no overplaying or underplaying as far as I could see. Special mention must go to the two lead performances. Christopher Ecceleston is a very talented and I think under-appreciated actor, and in the title role he was perfectly cast and showed real versatility. As Sue Brideshead, the beautiful Kate Winslet is positively luminous and is true to her character. Out of the supporting performances, the best is Rachel Griffiths as Arabella, a very modest performance I must say. Overall, has its minor flaws but a very well done adaptation of a complicated book. Always realistic and never overly-sentimental as I feared. Though the ending is heart-rending. 9/10 Bethany Cox
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Hardy's Jude the Obscure faithfully portrayed
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    CountZero313
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/4/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Winterbottom keeps the temperature of the searing original novel in his faithful, brilliantly realised film adaptation. Hardy was sick when writing Jude, out of sorts, and the bleak tale has in some quarters been credited more to bile than his muse. Jude's fate is certainly more damning than other Hardy heroes such as Tess, and the final third of this tale requires a strong heart to get through. Jude Fawley is a self-educated stonemason looking to enter the hallowed halls of (a thinly-disguised) Oxford. Class and snobbery combine to crush that dream, but he fights and wins his other dream, to secure the love of his cousin Sue. Headstrong and independent, a prototype Suffragette, she will face her own stern test and be found wanting. Christopher Eccleston inhabits the character fully. The scene in the pub where he recites the Lord's Creed in Latin, then challenges the undergrads to judge if he got it right, is painful and poignant. Winslet is stunning as the admirable but infuriating Sue Brideshead whose choices in life are oblique but all-too-real. A cold draft of air oozes from her expression every time she shuns Jude. There isn't a missed beat in Winslet's portrayal of a woman who goes from supremely confident to utterly lost. Winterbottom would go on to tinker and experiment, unsuccessfully, with Hardy's Mayor of Casterbridge in The Claim. Here, he keeps it strictly BBC, evoking the early industrial age magnificently in his cobbled streets and fog-shrouded spires. An array of British acting talent fill out the supporting roles superbly, most notably Liam Cunningham as the put-upon Phillotson, and Rachel Griffiths as pig-hugging Arabella, whose rising fortune sways in counter-point to Jude's slow, inexorable decline. In one scene where she encounters her estranged son at a fairground, the interaction between woman and child is both naturalistic and magical. The expression on the face of Little Jude's sister is priceless. Perhaps a happy accident, perhaps genius from the director, but all the more tragic for what follows. One of the most ill-fated couples in British literature are vividly brought to life in this film, designed to satisfy fans of the novel. Hardy, one feels, would approve.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Heartbreaking literary adaptation
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Framescourer
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/11/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A briskly but sensitively shot, well-acted and brutally rendered version of Thomas Hardy's tragic novel. I remember being terribly disappointed though (when I saw this in the cinema) that the grainy, visceral b&w images of the title sequence were discontinued as the movie proper got started. Ecclestone finds a great deal of sympathy and charm with which to play the ambitious but unlucky Jude. Kate Winslet is an arguably bigger draw though, throwing herself headlong into a part that requires... well many of the characteristics that she brought to the successful Austen adaptation Sense and Sensibility the previous year: willfulness, joy and despair. Rachel Griffiths is horrible as Jude's ball and chain but nothing is as nasty as the notorious fate of the incestuous couple's children. Strong stuff from Winterbottom, as usual. 6/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
 </reviews>
</filme>
