<filme>
 <id>
  1490
 </id>
 <imdburl>
  http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0105226
 </imdburl>
 <ano>
  1993
 </ano>
 <titulo>
  Morte Por Encomenda
 </titulo>
 <rating>
  6.9
 </rating>
 <sinopse>
  When a promised job for Texan Michael fails to materialise in Wyoming, Mike is mistaken by Wayne to be the hitman he hired to kill his unfaithful wife, Suzanne. Mike takes full advantage of... &nbsp;&raquo;
 </sinopse>
 <storyline>
  When a promised job for Texan Michael fails to materialise in Wyoming, Mike is mistaken by Wayne to be the hitman he hired to kill his unfaithful wife, Suzanne. Mike takes full advantage of the situation, collects the money and runs. During his getaway, things go wrong, and soon get worse when he runs into the real hitman, Lyle.
 </storyline>
 <generos>
  <genero>
   Crime
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Drama
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Thriller
  </genero>
 </generos>
 <keywords>
  <keyword>
   hitman
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   money
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   wyoming
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   texan
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   ex marine
  </keyword>
 </keywords>
 <diretores>
  <diretor>
   John Dahl
  </diretor>
 </diretores>
 <escritores>
  <escritor>
   John Dahl
  </escritor>
  <escritor>
   Rick Dahl
  </escritor>
 </escritores>
 <atores>
  <ator>
   Nicolas Cage
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Dennis Hopper
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Lara Flynn Boyle
  </ator>
 </atores>
 <reviews>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A lonesome drifter, low on money, finds himself suddenly in a deadly rat race for money.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Caged Cinema
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Red Rock West is a beautiful film. It is a film made by movie lovers, for movie lovers, with clearly lots of fun and enthusiasm. It is as much a film-noir as it is a western, a thriller or perhaps a black comedy. Set in middle-of-nowhere Wyoming the film starts with the masculine ex-marine Michael Williams (Cage), with his muscle car on the side of the road. He has almost no gas, only some peanuts as food, and little money. He is on his way to apply for a job at an oilfield. Seemingly a friend told him this job would be a definitive. Williams, however, doesn't get hired due to a war injury. Williams hits the road again, searching for a job in another place. He stops at a local gas station, where he wants to fill his tank and ask for advice. The gas station seems abandoned and at the cash register some cash is exposed This is one of the first in many moments where William's moral stance is put to the test. Steal the much needed money or leave it alone and stay broke? Luckily, Williams doesn't have to make a choice; the owner unexpectedly appears. Williams asks for gas and a place where he can find a job. "You can try Red Rock" says the man, while he fills the tank for five dollars the last of William's money. "Welcome to Red Rock" reads a somewhat unsettling- metal sign on the side of the road when Williams enters the town. It is a sign that he will encounter many more times, for it seems that leaving Red Rock isn't as easy as entering it. It is here where it all goes downhill He asks for a job in the local bar, which results in a strange twist of fate. The bartender (J.T. Marsh) thinks Williams is the killer he had hired to murder his cheating wife! The pay for it is big and Williams can't resist the temptation; he accepts the offer. Instead of killing the bartender's wife though, he explains her the whole situation, She, however doesn't seem impressed. She actually wants him to do the reverse and kill her husband for double the money! Williams, now full on cash, tries to avoid problems and take a leave from Red Rock, but by bad luck (or fate?), he keeps finding his way back to the diabolical town. When the real killer (a brilliant Dennis Hopper) shows up and the existence of even more money is discovered, Williams' search for money turns into a rat race, where lust, greed, obsession and violence are no exceptions. As you can read, Red Rock West is a dark film. Every character has its own secret agenda and even Williams'' moral is sometimes quite ambiguous. Although the film is quite funny sometimes, with enough irony and black humor, it is still one of the more serious films starring Nicolas Cage. Cage plays his character quite natural and even has few of his famous freak-outs. The atmosphere of this film is just brilliant. The film is well shot, the music is amazing (too bad I couldn't find it anywhere on the internet), the cast is great, the pace is fast and the plot is gripping. It has many great and exciting scenes and the way the thriller and western genres are combined is very entertaining. Still, somehow, the film never really delivers a form of profoundness, which more memorable and canonical films do provide. It is as if something is missing. Nonetheless, I think Red Rock West is an extremely underrated and overslept film. Don't expect a full blown masterpiece here. Rather expect a very good and entertaining thriller/western with a great role for Nicolas Cage. As Roger Ebert fittingly concluded his review of the film: "In a sense, we've been in Red Rock many times before: It's a town where plots lie in wait for unsuspecting visitors, where hatred runs deep, where love is never enough of a motive for doing anything when cash is available." And we love it there.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Wayne's Place.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    morrison-dylan-fan
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Taking a look at a poll that was held on the IMDb Classic Film board for the best movies of 1993,I found myself getting constantly drawn towards a Neo-Noir called Red Rock West,due to having heard a large amount of praise for the title over the year.Sadly,with the price of the DVD being pretty expensive,I regrettably decided to push any plans to take a look at this tantalising Neo-Noir to the side. 2 weeks later: Being happily caught completely by surprise,I recently received an offer from a very kind IMDb'er ,who asked if I would be interested in borrowing the DVD of the film,which led to me excitingly getting ready to pay a long over due visit to Red Rock West. The plot: Angered over getting turned down for a construction job due to having an injury which he picked up in the Vietnam war,Michael Williams drives towards a small town called Red Rock West,after getting advised by a gas station worker to pay a visit to a bar in the town called Wayne's Place,where there is a good chance that Williams will be able to pick up a bar staff job. Finding Wayne Brown at the front of the bar,Michael decides to not reveal his full background details to Brown,when Wayne asks Williams if he is "The Lyle who has come here for a job?".Pretending to be Lyle,Williams expectations of being given a bar job by Brown are left in ruins,when Wayne reveals to him that "Lyle" has not been hired to work at the bar,but has in fact been chosen by Brown to be a hit-man for his wife. View on the film: Placing the dark heart of this Neo-Noir in a full to the brim whisky bottle,co-writer/ (along with his brother Rick) director John Dahl and cinematography Marc Reshovsky soak the film in a warm Neo-Noir Western atmosphere,with Dahl and Reshovsky shooting the movie in brilliant sun setting colours,which along with allowing every member of the cast face's to have a world weary quality about them,also allows Reschovsky and Dahl to show the dark secrets that all the residence of Red Rock West are desperately trying to keep out of the light. Continuing with the underlying Western theme in the excellent screenplay,John and Rick Dahl show the Wyoming town of Red Rock West to be a fading sun-lit Neo-Noir world,where everyone knows each others secrets and deals on how the town is run are made by secret drinks,and beer stained back-hander's,which is seriously threatened of being buckled,by the arrival of two "outlaws" from Texas,one being an unlucky soul who is at the wrong place,at the very worst time,and the other one being a black-clad wearing gunslinger,who wants to take the power of the town all for himself. Being given the chance to sizzle on the screen as this Neo-Noir's sole Femme Fatale,I was disappointed to find Lara Flynn Boyle give a rather frozen performance as Suzanne Brown,with Boyle failing to blend into John Dahl wonderful shadowy world,and also being unable to give the dialogue the fizzle that it richly deserves. Whilst Boyle sadly fails from setting the fuse off,the rest of the cast thankfully attack the movie with a burning hot,ten ton hammer,with J.T. Walsh giving an tremendous performance as Wayne Brown,thanks to Walsh showing Brown to go gradually more desperate for the killing of his wife to take place,and Walsh also taking full advantage of Dahl's stylish directing,by using the close ups to reveal the darkened lies and dirty deals that lay behind the scar's on Wayne's face. Entering this Neo-Noir like a fire breathing dragon,Dennis Hooper gives a fiery performance as the "real" Lyle,with Hooper showing Lyle's initially well meaning first appearance to be quickly slashed away and replaced by an outlaw whose only language is increasing the dirty money that is placed in his hands. Kept right at the centre for the whole of the film,Nicolas Cage gives an extremely strong performance,which carefully balances Michael Williams being a down to earth.down on his luck guy,with an increasing,potential deadly desire to get hold of the cash and the woman that are both just out of William's reach,which leads to Red Rock West being a gravel road that is defiantly worth travelling down.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    All Roads Lead To Intrigue.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    JohnRouseMerriottChard
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Red Rock West is directed by John Dahl who also co-wrote the screenplay with his brother Rick. It stars Nicolas Cage, Dennis Hopper, Lara Flynn Boyle, J. T. Walsh and Timothy Carhart. Music is by William Olvis and cinematography by Marc Reshovsky. When a promised job in Wyoming fails to materialise on account of an injury sustained in combat, Michael Williams (Cage) drifts into the town of Red Rock and is mistaken in a bar for a hit-man hired to kill an unfaithful wife. Tempted by the high cash on offer, Michael plays along and promptly finds himself in a web of intrigue from which escape is looking unlikely Welcome To Red Rock/You Are Now Leaving Red Rock. The studio didn't know what to do with it, a neo-noir flavoured with contemporary Western spices. Put out on cable in America and thriving on its limited release in Europe, it started to gain a cult fan-base. More so after a theatre in the Frisco Bay area started showing it and it made considerable coinage. Today it still remains more of a cult piece than anything else, which while it deserves more accolades and exposure, is still kind of nice for the fans, because it's like we have our own little neo-noir treasure all to ourselves. Red Rock West is essential for the neo-noir heads and well worthy of inspection by the average modern day crime film fan. Plot wise it's a bit, shall we say iffy? Yet the twists, turns and characterisations are so deftly constructed and performed, it matters not a jot. Cage's ex- marine is an honest and decent guy who whilst down on his luck - punished for his honesty - finds himself in a vortex of mystery and murder that he can't escape from. His companions in this scenario are film noir staples, the femme fatale (Boyle) with a smoulder as big as her secret, the hit-man (Hopper) with a glint in his eye to accompany his callous leanings, and the shifty bar owner (Walsh) trying to off his wife whilst keeping his shady cards close to his chest. As the tricksy plot unfolds in a haze of bad judgements and untruths, further pulsed by the vagaries of fate, it becomes apparent that Dahl wants us to know it isn't taking itself too seriously. There's a glorious scent of dark humour hanging in the air, an unpretentiousness about the whole thing that's refreshing. The look and feel is perfect for the narrative, the colour is stripped back to create a moody atmospheric surround, while the score and sound-tracking immediately brings to mind country and western tales of woe. Dahl knows his noir onions, but this is not just a homage hat tipper to the past, he understands what works in noir, be it the blending of the quirky with the edgy, or scene setting in locales such as a colourless bar and a foggy cemetery, Dahl gets the key ingredients right to deliver the goods wholesale. The small cast come up trumps. Boyle as Suzanne Brown is weak if her femme fatale is pitted against the likes of Matty Walker or Bridget Gregory, but it's an adequate performance that doesn't hinder the picture. She is helped enormously, though, by having to share most scenes with Cage who brings his "A" game. Consistently inconsistent throughout his career, Cage, when on form is a joy to watch, here he gets to thrive as a put upon hero, shifting seamlessly between confusion and boldness, where incredulous looks are the order of the day with a side order of eccentric intensity. Hopper does what he does so well, amusing villainy, while Walsh is effortlessly menacing and suspicious. In small secondary support Carhart and country star Dwight Yoakam leave favourable impressions. This is not an edge of your seat thriller, or a cranium bothering piece of dramedy, it's neo-noir done right. Where morality is grey at best and money is the root of all evil, it's slick, playful, cold blooded and absorbing. Hooray! 9/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Dial H for honesty
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    cmoyton
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/4/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    John Dahls opening salvo as director ranks among the best compared to his fellow contemporary directors. Sandwiched between Kill Me Again and The Last Seduction, Red Rock West was one of three "neo noirs" directed by Dahl who now finds himself marooned in TV land. It has a cast to die for and Nicholas Cage at the peak of his career. It is fantastic to see that the late J.T. Walsh is given a substantial role as bar owner/sheriff Wayne and shares as much screen time as Cage, Hopper and Boyle. Cage plays an out of work jobless drifter who in desperation pretends to be someone else to secure employment. Unfortunately the "job" requires him to murder the wife of a small town bar owner. Although he takes the money and runs from the town of Red Rock his own honesty sucks him back into the town into a shed load of trouble. Being in noir territory plot twists and deception abound. Denniis Hopper excels as hit-man Lyle. His acting is a joy to behold - all the usual Hopper mannerisms are present and the razor sharp dialogue flows from his lips in a unique style that no other actor is ever likely to replicate again. A true one off. Having said that the movies sharpest line is given to bit part actor Dwight Yoakam. My only beef is how they made sexy actress Lara Flynn Boyle look so frumpy in her rural cowgirl clothing but her acting is first class as usual. Of course there are the usual plot contrivances only found in movies in order to move the story along - the worst possibly being Cage being rescued by Hopper (the man he happens to be impersonating) just after he escapes the clutches of J.T. Walsh's crooked sheriff. I am always amazed at the blank expressions i receive when i name check this movie to others. Do yourself a favour and rent/buy this movie immediately.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Bizarre Love Quadriangle
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Raul Faust
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/10/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Well, "Red Rock West" isn't a very original or innovative film, since it repeats many of the western's clich&eacute;s from the eighties. Also, it may not have a great scenario or photography direction-- because of that, it seems to be much older than it actually is. However, the film is extremely entertaining; the story develops quickly, with an engaging and professional cast-- Nicolas Cage himself hasn't aged a day since this was released, he now looks exactly the same. The story has some interesting twists that help the film not become boring-- which is the worst element a film can have. See it without commitment and you'll have a good time.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Serpentine thriller
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Neil Welch
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/4/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    There are certain people who scream out to be typecast. Looing for a small-town bigwig with an air of corruption and a nasty streak? How about the late (and much lamented) JT Walsh? How about a contract killer with superficial charm and a centre of pure viciousness? Has to be the late (and even more lamented) Dennis Hopper. Penniless drifter with a hard luck story? Nicolas Cage, who else? Only femme fatale wife of small-town bigwig doesn't immediately scream Lara Flynn Boyle, but she does a perfectly adequate job in the role. Red Rock West is a noir movie, updated for modern audiences. The plot involves murder plots, opportunism, corruption, double-dealing, and assorted twists and turns, and is splendid fun. The performances are all dark, and all the principals get their teeth into the piece. Highly recommended, if you're in the mood for some dark fun.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    More twists and turns than a Chubby Checker concert.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    oneguyrambling
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/10/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Love him or hate him (and since he named his kid after Superman he's dropped a peg in my book), Nicolas Cage at least takes chances with his films. Sometimes this is disastrous and sometimes worthwhile, and realistically he hasn't appeared in a really good movie since "Adaptation" in 2002. But Cage ruled the 90's, in between the commercial stuff like Con Air, The Rock and Face/Off he continued taking chances with his choices with Wild At Heart and Leaving Las Vegas. Red Rock West was made in between his indie period of the late 80's and the blockbuster guy of the mid to late 90's, it's a pretty good movie but you can see why articles don't say things like "Nicolas Cage, of Leaving Las Vegas and Red Rock West fame." Strongly reminiscent of some of the Coen brothers early stuff, Red Rock West has more twists and turns than 12 garden variety whodunit thrillers combined. Cage stars as Michael, a man down to his last few dollars that is coming to an end of a long trek to start a new job on an oil drilling site, only due to a military service injury he is knocked back by the boss. So now he is still broke, out of fuel and disenchanted, Michael heads into the nearest town hoping to find work. A couple of early incidents show us he's an honest and ethical guy, the kind of guy that calls a woman "Ma'am". Now the next bit can be described, but after the movie is half over the plot becomes impossible to explain simply without major spoilers as reality changes from one minute to the next. So, Michael heads to the local pub and orders a coffee, the barman sees his car parked outside and because of the Texas license plate decides he is the man he is waiting for "Lyle from Texas". As the mistaken identity involves paid employment Michael goes along with the mistake, until he finds out that the job is to kill Wayne the barman's wife. Rather than straight out saying No Michael takes the cash and heads to Wayne's home. Somehow Michael happens upon the wife riding a horse to where she is having some hanky-panky with another farmhand, it's never really explained how he knew she would be there but who cares? Michael then goes to the house and waits for her return, when they meet he explains why he is there, and Suzanne (played by 25 kg Lara Flynn-Boyle) calmly counter offers Michael, at double the rate, to kill Wayne instead. Again Michael agrees, only this time he says enough and decides to "Lock it in Eddie", taking the cash with the sole intention of buggering off. Now in non-Hollywood this would be the end of it, but because a movie can't be over in 45 minutes we follow Michael as he leaves town in the rain. Here's where the twists get hectic, I'll summarise the next 15 minutes: - Michael hits someone in his car and takes them to the local hospital. (He's a nice guy remember?) - The Sheriff turns out to be the last person Michael needs to see, Wayne. - Wayne is a bit miffed at the perceived double cross and decides to off Michael. - Michael escapes, runs off and is picked up by Dennis Hopper, who is, you guessed it: Lyle from Texas! I can't explain much more without spoilers and confusion, only from here on in the remainder of the film revolves around Suzanne, Wayne, Michael and Lyle, and includes a myriad of twists and turns, deception, betrayal and double crossing galore. Everything a grown movie needs really. Wayne is played by JT Walsh, usually a bit player in other movies and I have always felt he is a bit over the top. Dennis Hopper is always ultra-hammy, and is almost cartoonish here. Lara Flynn-Boyle is surprisingly low key through most of the film, and has flawless skin regardless of the circumstances. Cage plays the troubled hero part to the hilt, he's the prototype for the nice guy in a situation that he wants to avoid but can't. The finale is in keeping with the rest of the film and is fairly satisfying. If I might digress momentarily, at one stage Michael walks into a bar and says "Give me a beer", now I have walked into many bars and know if I ever say that the bartender will say something along the lines of "Which one d**khead?" Since the dawn of time even the most low key bar stocks more than one brand, in fact most have literally dozens to choose from. Dunno why this bothers me but it does. If you're worried about the perception of product placement do what Tarantino does and make up a brand. Final Rating  7 / 10. "We twist. And turn. And twist and twist and turn. Twist, twist, twist. Turn, turn, turn. The Itchy and Scratchy Show." I mean Red Rock West. (That means it's a pretty good movie.) If you liked this review (or even if you didn't) check out oneguyrambling.com
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Another gem starring Cage that slipped under my radar
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    thekyles99
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/7/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Like i said in previous reviews, recently i have been going through Nic Cage's IMDb list of projects he has done to see if there was anything i hadn't seen that he's been in. And low and behold i found a bunch of em. So far out of three watched i liked 2 of em . 2-1 not a bad ratio so far. Just goes to show to show Nic Cage although one of the busiest actors is also careful of the scripts he chooses to work on. Red Rock West is another gem of his that must've slipped under my radar in 93. Great storyline however i found the ending a little on the cheesy side that being said it was a pretty good thriller. This time round Nic portrays Michael Williams a down and out Texan who resides in his car and tries to get jobs but fails to an injury he took while serving in the marines. Apon driving into a little town of red rock he enters the red rock tavern to see about a job and in a serious judgement error ends up taking a job that belonged to a professional hit-man (Dennis Hopper) needless to say all hell breaks loose and the moral of the story is number one money is never easy and number two...watch who's life you try to impersonate as the grass is always greener on the other side of the fence. Good casting featuring the late great Jt Walsh who was always a pleasure to watch work and a very underrated actor to say the least. Another great and recently passed Dennis Hopper portrays the hit-man that was originally intended for the hit but was a little later then mike at arriving to the bar. Dennis hopper in my books was awesome in portraying villains. Lara Flynn Boyle rounds off the cast with a less then believable performance as the sheriffs wife who the hit is to be delivered upon. Nic Cage's character in this spends the rest of the movie digging the hole he has made himself further and further. To get out is the question.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Enthralling criminal goings-on in a small Western town, as the lead is caught between a Red Rock and a hard place.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    johnnyboyz (j_l_h_m@yahoo.co.uk)
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/6/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    John Dahl's Red Rock West is a neat, taut, stripped down piece of cut-and-thrust film-making without gimmickry nor a single false string attached. In a current contemporary world of American film-making, and one that was almost certainly predominant at the time of Red Rock West's inception, how wonderful it is to uncover a film that refrains from the over indulgence of extravagance and the ideology that awe is built on a foundation of overkill and visuals. That's not to say Red Rock West is without extravagance nor awe, such is Dahl's ability, that the film is full of a number of various incidences and twists that are exactly these things and gotten across by way of little more than a glance from one of the character's or an individual cut of the camera. When we hark back to America's independent cinematic boom of the late 1980s and going on into the early 1990s, certainly a boom that saw a number of films and individual directors both honoured and recognised on the European film circuit at the top level in a series of Golden Palm nominations, the displaying of Red Rock West shows we must not glance over the name of Dahl when speaking of both the films and directors of that era, namely: the Coen Brothers; Steven Soderburgh; Spike Lee and Tarantino, et al. The film revolves around Nicolas Cage's character named Michael Williams, an ex-Marine of American nationality down on his luck and strapped for money in the dusty outback of Wyoming. He lives out of his car; uses random road side troughs full of water as makeshift sinks and struggles to find work, the latest failing being a construction site job that doesn't come through, although later on, he'll find ample opportunity at constructing something: a monstrosity of a scenario for himself. Unbeknownst to us at the time, he's going into the misadventure he'll come to have with a prior tragedy of having served time in the Vietnam War, but suffering during this stretch at the hands of a missile attack on a base in Lebanon he was positioned at which forced him into enduring a glut of both chaos and death. The event that may very well lend itself to Williams' dishevelled and down-beat tone and attitude, something Cage pulls off in that naturalistic manner he's done so on occasion since, shares eerie parallels with what will come to unfold around him as another glut of death and chaos unfolds around a man who has signed up for something you only realise you don't want to be anywhere near when it gets ugly as 'wrong place  wrong time' scenario once again kicks in. The devilish premise sees Williams pretend to be the Texan hit-man an apparent bar owner named Wayne (Walsh) called for some days ago so as to do some local dirty-work he wants taken care of. His looming over a seated Cage whilst in the office an early establishing of power, the sort of power that he'll come to have over him as Williams is forced throughout into proverbially dancing to the tune of others. But rather than eliminate the target, Wayne's wife played by Lara Flynn Boyle, Williams warns her of the predicament and that her marriage ought quite clearly be an item of concern form here on in. Once all is said and done, the real hit-man in Dennis Hopper's Lyle shows up in jet black Texan attire and similarly coloured car more resembling a hearse than anything else, whilst developments and complications in exactly who it is the chief of police is in the whole area open up. For Cage's character, and like in most good film noir when dealing with the down-trodden lead whom treads a fine line between right and wrong, the persistent idea of torn morals floats to the surface relatively quickly and consistently in Red Rock West. In just observing the premise, the notion of Williams illegally accepting the offer of being paid to kill someone before refraining from doing it when confronted with the innocent figure of Wayne's wife, Dahl highlights his character's soon-to-be prominent ever shifting; ever changing attitudes to what crime infused activity is playing out around him. Throughout, Williams lies; shoots; kills and steals but additionally saves; offers salvation and actually avoids violence on several occasions when straight forward murder would have offered a simple way out of a predicament. Given this, Dahl expertly manoeuvres Williams from one town in the form of Red Rock to another and then back over the border again, a sort of physical flitting from one place to another in what is a physical manifestation of both the above theories of a film noir's male lead as well as Cage's character's constantly ambiguous hopping from justified in his actions to not as so. Red Rock West moulds a fascinating, and quite terrifying at times, tale out of all these elements; combining a number of items such as double-crosses; multiple identities and intense connections characters have with one another, the sorts that they're forced into forging before later being asked what they truly mean to them. Dahl additionally, and in a very basic sense, taps into a certain idea of post-war disillusionment through his lead in Williams' disconnection from the rest of society seeing him inhabit a desolate and often incomprehensible rural locale in which he just about scrapes by. This, as an old war injury refrains him from making any true advancement in a chosen field of work. Red Rock West is a tight, gripping piece; the sort that arrives with a steady and effective eye on a variety of items all the while under the control of a steady, focused hand.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    western-noir at its near finest
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    MisterWhiplash
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/6/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    John Dahl knows his film-noir, and he knows his westerns. This should be assumed from seeing Red Rock West, though his 'noir' influence comes through in other films as well (Kill Me Again and to a degree Joy Ride). He knows how to write a lone average-Joe type of character, and the shady villain, and a sexy Femme Fatale. He knows this, but he also fills his story of a drifter coming to a small Wyoming town and being (accidentally?) hired to kill a man's wife with some top-shelf talent. Or, at least, the best actors that could make the parts their own. It's a cold little movie where you realize pretty quickly that despite Michael's "nice-guy" quality, he's still a potential thief and is the comparatively not so bad. Not so bad compared to Wayne the "bartender" or "Sheriff", if that is indeed his name, and his wife who wants to escape to Mexico with all of the money she "inherited" (please note the quotations). An extra slice of danger comes with the appearance of the actual man hired to kill the woman, Lyle from Dallas played by the late Dennis Hopper. His character and performance is far less aggressive than in Blue Velvet, though this is like comparing a Tasmanian Devil to a bull at a fight. I liked the suspense, of not knowing who might double-cross who next or where the story might go depending on who is alive, and I also liked that they gave each character something to them. Michael and Lyle meet up the first time under unusual circumstances and he gives Michael a ride, where they each find out they were marines, Michael formerly a fighter in a botched mission in Lebanon. This is mentioned about halfway into the film, but it helps to set up this guy as a somewhat tragic figure, without a home and without a job but all of those memories he'd rather not take with him. Certainly not to Mexico, where he has nice ones with his father. Again, the casting and the writing is what makes the film. Lara Flynn Boyle works just about perfect as the female figure of desire and greed, and even if we've seen something like her before she's still fresh because of her performance. JT Walsh is also good but in a different way, where he's a lot more careful with his words, but one can see the look of panic when it surely comes. And Nicolas Cage, at first seemingly a little bored with the part in the opening scenes, really makes it his own as a reluctant hero with nothing to lose. Dialog is used in the film only so much to keep things moving along, but I mean this as a compliment; it's not minimalism, but economy of speech if that makes sense. Dahl knows exactly what he wants in his B-movie premise, and it's like he's taken material sitting on a shelf for years and dusted it and made it vital again.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A lonesome drifter, low on money, finds himself suddenly in a deadly rat race for money.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Caged Cinema
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Red Rock West is a beautiful film. It is a film made by movie lovers, for movie lovers, with clearly lots of fun and enthusiasm. It is as much a film-noir as it is a western, a thriller or perhaps a black comedy. Set in middle-of-nowhere Wyoming the film starts with the masculine ex-marine Michael Williams (Cage), with his muscle car on the side of the road. He has almost no gas, only some peanuts as food, and little money. He is on his way to apply for a job at an oilfield. Seemingly a friend told him this job would be a definitive. Williams, however, doesn't get hired due to a war injury. Williams hits the road again, searching for a job in another place. He stops at a local gas station, where he wants to fill his tank and ask for advice. The gas station seems abandoned and at the cash register some cash is exposed This is one of the first in many moments where William's moral stance is put to the test. Steal the much needed money or leave it alone and stay broke? Luckily, Williams doesn't have to make a choice; the owner unexpectedly appears. Williams asks for gas and a place where he can find a job. "You can try Red Rock" says the man, while he fills the tank for five dollars the last of William's money. "Welcome to Red Rock" reads a somewhat unsettling- metal sign on the side of the road when Williams enters the town. It is a sign that he will encounter many more times, for it seems that leaving Red Rock isn't as easy as entering it. It is here where it all goes downhill He asks for a job in the local bar, which results in a strange twist of fate. The bartender (J.T. Marsh) thinks Williams is the killer he had hired to murder his cheating wife! The pay for it is big and Williams can't resist the temptation; he accepts the offer. Instead of killing the bartender's wife though, he explains her the whole situation, She, however doesn't seem impressed. She actually wants him to do the reverse and kill her husband for double the money! Williams, now full on cash, tries to avoid problems and take a leave from Red Rock, but by bad luck (or fate?), he keeps finding his way back to the diabolical town. When the real killer (a brilliant Dennis Hopper) shows up and the existence of even more money is discovered, Williams' search for money turns into a rat race, where lust, greed, obsession and violence are no exceptions. As you can read, Red Rock West is a dark film. Every character has its own secret agenda and even Williams'' moral is sometimes quite ambiguous. Although the film is quite funny sometimes, with enough irony and black humor, it is still one of the more serious films starring Nicolas Cage. Cage plays his character quite natural and even has few of his famous freak-outs. The atmosphere of this film is just brilliant. The film is well shot, the music is amazing (too bad I couldn't find it anywhere on the internet), the cast is great, the pace is fast and the plot is gripping. It has many great and exciting scenes and the way the thriller and western genres are combined is very entertaining. Still, somehow, the film never really delivers a form of profoundness, which more memorable and canonical films do provide. It is as if something is missing. Nonetheless, I think Red Rock West is an extremely underrated and overslept film. Don't expect a full blown masterpiece here. Rather expect a very good and entertaining thriller/western with a great role for Nicolas Cage. As Roger Ebert fittingly concluded his review of the film: "In a sense, we've been in Red Rock many times before: It's a town where plots lie in wait for unsuspecting visitors, where hatred runs deep, where love is never enough of a motive for doing anything when cash is available." And we love it there.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Wayne's Place.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    morrison-dylan-fan
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Taking a look at a poll that was held on the IMDb Classic Film board for the best movies of 1993,I found myself getting constantly drawn towards a Neo-Noir called Red Rock West,due to having heard a large amount of praise for the title over the year.Sadly,with the price of the DVD being pretty expensive,I regrettably decided to push any plans to take a look at this tantalising Neo-Noir to the side. 2 weeks later: Being happily caught completely by surprise,I recently received an offer from a very kind IMDb'er ,who asked if I would be interested in borrowing the DVD of the film,which led to me excitingly getting ready to pay a long over due visit to Red Rock West. The plot: Angered over getting turned down for a construction job due to having an injury which he picked up in the Vietnam war,Michael Williams drives towards a small town called Red Rock West,after getting advised by a gas station worker to pay a visit to a bar in the town called Wayne's Place,where there is a good chance that Williams will be able to pick up a bar staff job. Finding Wayne Brown at the front of the bar,Michael decides to not reveal his full background details to Brown,when Wayne asks Williams if he is "The Lyle who has come here for a job?".Pretending to be Lyle,Williams expectations of being given a bar job by Brown are left in ruins,when Wayne reveals to him that "Lyle" has not been hired to work at the bar,but has in fact been chosen by Brown to be a hit-man for his wife. View on the film: Placing the dark heart of this Neo-Noir in a full to the brim whisky bottle,co-writer/ (along with his brother Rick) director John Dahl and cinematography Marc Reshovsky soak the film in a warm Neo-Noir Western atmosphere,with Dahl and Reshovsky shooting the movie in brilliant sun setting colours,which along with allowing every member of the cast face's to have a world weary quality about them,also allows Reschovsky and Dahl to show the dark secrets that all the residence of Red Rock West are desperately trying to keep out of the light. Continuing with the underlying Western theme in the excellent screenplay,John and Rick Dahl show the Wyoming town of Red Rock West to be a fading sun-lit Neo-Noir world,where everyone knows each others secrets and deals on how the town is run are made by secret drinks,and beer stained back-hander's,which is seriously threatened of being buckled,by the arrival of two "outlaws" from Texas,one being an unlucky soul who is at the wrong place,at the very worst time,and the other one being a black-clad wearing gunslinger,who wants to take the power of the town all for himself. Being given the chance to sizzle on the screen as this Neo-Noir's sole Femme Fatale,I was disappointed to find Lara Flynn Boyle give a rather frozen performance as Suzanne Brown,with Boyle failing to blend into John Dahl wonderful shadowy world,and also being unable to give the dialogue the fizzle that it richly deserves. Whilst Boyle sadly fails from setting the fuse off,the rest of the cast thankfully attack the movie with a burning hot,ten ton hammer,with J.T. Walsh giving an tremendous performance as Wayne Brown,thanks to Walsh showing Brown to go gradually more desperate for the killing of his wife to take place,and Walsh also taking full advantage of Dahl's stylish directing,by using the close ups to reveal the darkened lies and dirty deals that lay behind the scar's on Wayne's face. Entering this Neo-Noir like a fire breathing dragon,Dennis Hooper gives a fiery performance as the "real" Lyle,with Hooper showing Lyle's initially well meaning first appearance to be quickly slashed away and replaced by an outlaw whose only language is increasing the dirty money that is placed in his hands. Kept right at the centre for the whole of the film,Nicolas Cage gives an extremely strong performance,which carefully balances Michael Williams being a down to earth.down on his luck guy,with an increasing,potential deadly desire to get hold of the cash and the woman that are both just out of William's reach,which leads to Red Rock West being a gravel road that is defiantly worth travelling down.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    All Roads Lead To Intrigue.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    JohnRouseMerriottChard
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Red Rock West is directed by John Dahl who also co-wrote the screenplay with his brother Rick. It stars Nicolas Cage, Dennis Hopper, Lara Flynn Boyle, J. T. Walsh and Timothy Carhart. Music is by William Olvis and cinematography by Marc Reshovsky. When a promised job in Wyoming fails to materialise on account of an injury sustained in combat, Michael Williams (Cage) drifts into the town of Red Rock and is mistaken in a bar for a hit-man hired to kill an unfaithful wife. Tempted by the high cash on offer, Michael plays along and promptly finds himself in a web of intrigue from which escape is looking unlikely Welcome To Red Rock/You Are Now Leaving Red Rock. The studio didn't know what to do with it, a neo-noir flavoured with contemporary Western spices. Put out on cable in America and thriving on its limited release in Europe, it started to gain a cult fan-base. More so after a theatre in the Frisco Bay area started showing it and it made considerable coinage. Today it still remains more of a cult piece than anything else, which while it deserves more accolades and exposure, is still kind of nice for the fans, because it's like we have our own little neo-noir treasure all to ourselves. Red Rock West is essential for the neo-noir heads and well worthy of inspection by the average modern day crime film fan. Plot wise it's a bit, shall we say iffy? Yet the twists, turns and characterisations are so deftly constructed and performed, it matters not a jot. Cage's ex- marine is an honest and decent guy who whilst down on his luck - punished for his honesty - finds himself in a vortex of mystery and murder that he can't escape from. His companions in this scenario are film noir staples, the femme fatale (Boyle) with a smoulder as big as her secret, the hit-man (Hopper) with a glint in his eye to accompany his callous leanings, and the shifty bar owner (Walsh) trying to off his wife whilst keeping his shady cards close to his chest. As the tricksy plot unfolds in a haze of bad judgements and untruths, further pulsed by the vagaries of fate, it becomes apparent that Dahl wants us to know it isn't taking itself too seriously. There's a glorious scent of dark humour hanging in the air, an unpretentiousness about the whole thing that's refreshing. The look and feel is perfect for the narrative, the colour is stripped back to create a moody atmospheric surround, while the score and sound-tracking immediately brings to mind country and western tales of woe. Dahl knows his noir onions, but this is not just a homage hat tipper to the past, he understands what works in noir, be it the blending of the quirky with the edgy, or scene setting in locales such as a colourless bar and a foggy cemetery, Dahl gets the key ingredients right to deliver the goods wholesale. The small cast come up trumps. Boyle as Suzanne Brown is weak if her femme fatale is pitted against the likes of Matty Walker or Bridget Gregory, but it's an adequate performance that doesn't hinder the picture. She is helped enormously, though, by having to share most scenes with Cage who brings his "A" game. Consistently inconsistent throughout his career, Cage, when on form is a joy to watch, here he gets to thrive as a put upon hero, shifting seamlessly between confusion and boldness, where incredulous looks are the order of the day with a side order of eccentric intensity. Hopper does what he does so well, amusing villainy, while Walsh is effortlessly menacing and suspicious. In small secondary support Carhart and country star Dwight Yoakam leave favourable impressions. This is not an edge of your seat thriller, or a cranium bothering piece of dramedy, it's neo-noir done right. Where morality is grey at best and money is the root of all evil, it's slick, playful, cold blooded and absorbing. Hooray! 9/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Dial H for honesty
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    cmoyton
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/4/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    John Dahls opening salvo as director ranks among the best compared to his fellow contemporary directors. Sandwiched between Kill Me Again and The Last Seduction, Red Rock West was one of three "neo noirs" directed by Dahl who now finds himself marooned in TV land. It has a cast to die for and Nicholas Cage at the peak of his career. It is fantastic to see that the late J.T. Walsh is given a substantial role as bar owner/sheriff Wayne and shares as much screen time as Cage, Hopper and Boyle. Cage plays an out of work jobless drifter who in desperation pretends to be someone else to secure employment. Unfortunately the "job" requires him to murder the wife of a small town bar owner. Although he takes the money and runs from the town of Red Rock his own honesty sucks him back into the town into a shed load of trouble. Being in noir territory plot twists and deception abound. Denniis Hopper excels as hit-man Lyle. His acting is a joy to behold - all the usual Hopper mannerisms are present and the razor sharp dialogue flows from his lips in a unique style that no other actor is ever likely to replicate again. A true one off. Having said that the movies sharpest line is given to bit part actor Dwight Yoakam. My only beef is how they made sexy actress Lara Flynn Boyle look so frumpy in her rural cowgirl clothing but her acting is first class as usual. Of course there are the usual plot contrivances only found in movies in order to move the story along - the worst possibly being Cage being rescued by Hopper (the man he happens to be impersonating) just after he escapes the clutches of J.T. Walsh's crooked sheriff. I am always amazed at the blank expressions i receive when i name check this movie to others. Do yourself a favour and rent/buy this movie immediately.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Bizarre Love Quadriangle
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Raul Faust
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/10/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Well, "Red Rock West" isn't a very original or innovative film, since it repeats many of the western's clich&eacute;s from the eighties. Also, it may not have a great scenario or photography direction-- because of that, it seems to be much older than it actually is. However, the film is extremely entertaining; the story develops quickly, with an engaging and professional cast-- Nicolas Cage himself hasn't aged a day since this was released, he now looks exactly the same. The story has some interesting twists that help the film not become boring-- which is the worst element a film can have. See it without commitment and you'll have a good time.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Serpentine thriller
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Neil Welch
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/4/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    There are certain people who scream out to be typecast. Looing for a small-town bigwig with an air of corruption and a nasty streak? How about the late (and much lamented) JT Walsh? How about a contract killer with superficial charm and a centre of pure viciousness? Has to be the late (and even more lamented) Dennis Hopper. Penniless drifter with a hard luck story? Nicolas Cage, who else? Only femme fatale wife of small-town bigwig doesn't immediately scream Lara Flynn Boyle, but she does a perfectly adequate job in the role. Red Rock West is a noir movie, updated for modern audiences. The plot involves murder plots, opportunism, corruption, double-dealing, and assorted twists and turns, and is splendid fun. The performances are all dark, and all the principals get their teeth into the piece. Highly recommended, if you're in the mood for some dark fun.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    More twists and turns than a Chubby Checker concert.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    oneguyrambling
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/10/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Love him or hate him (and since he named his kid after Superman he's dropped a peg in my book), Nicolas Cage at least takes chances with his films. Sometimes this is disastrous and sometimes worthwhile, and realistically he hasn't appeared in a really good movie since "Adaptation" in 2002. But Cage ruled the 90's, in between the commercial stuff like Con Air, The Rock and Face/Off he continued taking chances with his choices with Wild At Heart and Leaving Las Vegas. Red Rock West was made in between his indie period of the late 80's and the blockbuster guy of the mid to late 90's, it's a pretty good movie but you can see why articles don't say things like "Nicolas Cage, of Leaving Las Vegas and Red Rock West fame." Strongly reminiscent of some of the Coen brothers early stuff, Red Rock West has more twists and turns than 12 garden variety whodunit thrillers combined. Cage stars as Michael, a man down to his last few dollars that is coming to an end of a long trek to start a new job on an oil drilling site, only due to a military service injury he is knocked back by the boss. So now he is still broke, out of fuel and disenchanted, Michael heads into the nearest town hoping to find work. A couple of early incidents show us he's an honest and ethical guy, the kind of guy that calls a woman "Ma'am". Now the next bit can be described, but after the movie is half over the plot becomes impossible to explain simply without major spoilers as reality changes from one minute to the next. So, Michael heads to the local pub and orders a coffee, the barman sees his car parked outside and because of the Texas license plate decides he is the man he is waiting for "Lyle from Texas". As the mistaken identity involves paid employment Michael goes along with the mistake, until he finds out that the job is to kill Wayne the barman's wife. Rather than straight out saying No Michael takes the cash and heads to Wayne's home. Somehow Michael happens upon the wife riding a horse to where she is having some hanky-panky with another farmhand, it's never really explained how he knew she would be there but who cares? Michael then goes to the house and waits for her return, when they meet he explains why he is there, and Suzanne (played by 25 kg Lara Flynn-Boyle) calmly counter offers Michael, at double the rate, to kill Wayne instead. Again Michael agrees, only this time he says enough and decides to "Lock it in Eddie", taking the cash with the sole intention of buggering off. Now in non-Hollywood this would be the end of it, but because a movie can't be over in 45 minutes we follow Michael as he leaves town in the rain. Here's where the twists get hectic, I'll summarise the next 15 minutes: - Michael hits someone in his car and takes them to the local hospital. (He's a nice guy remember?) - The Sheriff turns out to be the last person Michael needs to see, Wayne. - Wayne is a bit miffed at the perceived double cross and decides to off Michael. - Michael escapes, runs off and is picked up by Dennis Hopper, who is, you guessed it: Lyle from Texas! I can't explain much more without spoilers and confusion, only from here on in the remainder of the film revolves around Suzanne, Wayne, Michael and Lyle, and includes a myriad of twists and turns, deception, betrayal and double crossing galore. Everything a grown movie needs really. Wayne is played by JT Walsh, usually a bit player in other movies and I have always felt he is a bit over the top. Dennis Hopper is always ultra-hammy, and is almost cartoonish here. Lara Flynn-Boyle is surprisingly low key through most of the film, and has flawless skin regardless of the circumstances. Cage plays the troubled hero part to the hilt, he's the prototype for the nice guy in a situation that he wants to avoid but can't. The finale is in keeping with the rest of the film and is fairly satisfying. If I might digress momentarily, at one stage Michael walks into a bar and says "Give me a beer", now I have walked into many bars and know if I ever say that the bartender will say something along the lines of "Which one d**khead?" Since the dawn of time even the most low key bar stocks more than one brand, in fact most have literally dozens to choose from. Dunno why this bothers me but it does. If you're worried about the perception of product placement do what Tarantino does and make up a brand. Final Rating  7 / 10. "We twist. And turn. And twist and twist and turn. Twist, twist, twist. Turn, turn, turn. The Itchy and Scratchy Show." I mean Red Rock West. (That means it's a pretty good movie.) If you liked this review (or even if you didn't) check out oneguyrambling.com
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Another gem starring Cage that slipped under my radar
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    thekyles99
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/7/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Like i said in previous reviews, recently i have been going through Nic Cage's IMDb list of projects he has done to see if there was anything i hadn't seen that he's been in. And low and behold i found a bunch of em. So far out of three watched i liked 2 of em . 2-1 not a bad ratio so far. Just goes to show to show Nic Cage although one of the busiest actors is also careful of the scripts he chooses to work on. Red Rock West is another gem of his that must've slipped under my radar in 93. Great storyline however i found the ending a little on the cheesy side that being said it was a pretty good thriller. This time round Nic portrays Michael Williams a down and out Texan who resides in his car and tries to get jobs but fails to an injury he took while serving in the marines. Apon driving into a little town of red rock he enters the red rock tavern to see about a job and in a serious judgement error ends up taking a job that belonged to a professional hit-man (Dennis Hopper) needless to say all hell breaks loose and the moral of the story is number one money is never easy and number two...watch who's life you try to impersonate as the grass is always greener on the other side of the fence. Good casting featuring the late great Jt Walsh who was always a pleasure to watch work and a very underrated actor to say the least. Another great and recently passed Dennis Hopper portrays the hit-man that was originally intended for the hit but was a little later then mike at arriving to the bar. Dennis hopper in my books was awesome in portraying villains. Lara Flynn Boyle rounds off the cast with a less then believable performance as the sheriffs wife who the hit is to be delivered upon. Nic Cage's character in this spends the rest of the movie digging the hole he has made himself further and further. To get out is the question.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Enthralling criminal goings-on in a small Western town, as the lead is caught between a Red Rock and a hard place.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    johnnyboyz (j_l_h_m@yahoo.co.uk)
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/6/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    John Dahl's Red Rock West is a neat, taut, stripped down piece of cut-and-thrust film-making without gimmickry nor a single false string attached. In a current contemporary world of American film-making, and one that was almost certainly predominant at the time of Red Rock West's inception, how wonderful it is to uncover a film that refrains from the over indulgence of extravagance and the ideology that awe is built on a foundation of overkill and visuals. That's not to say Red Rock West is without extravagance nor awe, such is Dahl's ability, that the film is full of a number of various incidences and twists that are exactly these things and gotten across by way of little more than a glance from one of the character's or an individual cut of the camera. When we hark back to America's independent cinematic boom of the late 1980s and going on into the early 1990s, certainly a boom that saw a number of films and individual directors both honoured and recognised on the European film circuit at the top level in a series of Golden Palm nominations, the displaying of Red Rock West shows we must not glance over the name of Dahl when speaking of both the films and directors of that era, namely: the Coen Brothers; Steven Soderburgh; Spike Lee and Tarantino, et al. The film revolves around Nicolas Cage's character named Michael Williams, an ex-Marine of American nationality down on his luck and strapped for money in the dusty outback of Wyoming. He lives out of his car; uses random road side troughs full of water as makeshift sinks and struggles to find work, the latest failing being a construction site job that doesn't come through, although later on, he'll find ample opportunity at constructing something: a monstrosity of a scenario for himself. Unbeknownst to us at the time, he's going into the misadventure he'll come to have with a prior tragedy of having served time in the Vietnam War, but suffering during this stretch at the hands of a missile attack on a base in Lebanon he was positioned at which forced him into enduring a glut of both chaos and death. The event that may very well lend itself to Williams' dishevelled and down-beat tone and attitude, something Cage pulls off in that naturalistic manner he's done so on occasion since, shares eerie parallels with what will come to unfold around him as another glut of death and chaos unfolds around a man who has signed up for something you only realise you don't want to be anywhere near when it gets ugly as 'wrong place  wrong time' scenario once again kicks in. The devilish premise sees Williams pretend to be the Texan hit-man an apparent bar owner named Wayne (Walsh) called for some days ago so as to do some local dirty-work he wants taken care of. His looming over a seated Cage whilst in the office an early establishing of power, the sort of power that he'll come to have over him as Williams is forced throughout into proverbially dancing to the tune of others. But rather than eliminate the target, Wayne's wife played by Lara Flynn Boyle, Williams warns her of the predicament and that her marriage ought quite clearly be an item of concern form here on in. Once all is said and done, the real hit-man in Dennis Hopper's Lyle shows up in jet black Texan attire and similarly coloured car more resembling a hearse than anything else, whilst developments and complications in exactly who it is the chief of police is in the whole area open up. For Cage's character, and like in most good film noir when dealing with the down-trodden lead whom treads a fine line between right and wrong, the persistent idea of torn morals floats to the surface relatively quickly and consistently in Red Rock West. In just observing the premise, the notion of Williams illegally accepting the offer of being paid to kill someone before refraining from doing it when confronted with the innocent figure of Wayne's wife, Dahl highlights his character's soon-to-be prominent ever shifting; ever changing attitudes to what crime infused activity is playing out around him. Throughout, Williams lies; shoots; kills and steals but additionally saves; offers salvation and actually avoids violence on several occasions when straight forward murder would have offered a simple way out of a predicament. Given this, Dahl expertly manoeuvres Williams from one town in the form of Red Rock to another and then back over the border again, a sort of physical flitting from one place to another in what is a physical manifestation of both the above theories of a film noir's male lead as well as Cage's character's constantly ambiguous hopping from justified in his actions to not as so. Red Rock West moulds a fascinating, and quite terrifying at times, tale out of all these elements; combining a number of items such as double-crosses; multiple identities and intense connections characters have with one another, the sorts that they're forced into forging before later being asked what they truly mean to them. Dahl additionally, and in a very basic sense, taps into a certain idea of post-war disillusionment through his lead in Williams' disconnection from the rest of society seeing him inhabit a desolate and often incomprehensible rural locale in which he just about scrapes by. This, as an old war injury refrains him from making any true advancement in a chosen field of work. Red Rock West is a tight, gripping piece; the sort that arrives with a steady and effective eye on a variety of items all the while under the control of a steady, focused hand.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    western-noir at its near finest
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    MisterWhiplash
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/6/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    John Dahl knows his film-noir, and he knows his westerns. This should be assumed from seeing Red Rock West, though his 'noir' influence comes through in other films as well (Kill Me Again and to a degree Joy Ride). He knows how to write a lone average-Joe type of character, and the shady villain, and a sexy Femme Fatale. He knows this, but he also fills his story of a drifter coming to a small Wyoming town and being (accidentally?) hired to kill a man's wife with some top-shelf talent. Or, at least, the best actors that could make the parts their own. It's a cold little movie where you realize pretty quickly that despite Michael's "nice-guy" quality, he's still a potential thief and is the comparatively not so bad. Not so bad compared to Wayne the "bartender" or "Sheriff", if that is indeed his name, and his wife who wants to escape to Mexico with all of the money she "inherited" (please note the quotations). An extra slice of danger comes with the appearance of the actual man hired to kill the woman, Lyle from Dallas played by the late Dennis Hopper. His character and performance is far less aggressive than in Blue Velvet, though this is like comparing a Tasmanian Devil to a bull at a fight. I liked the suspense, of not knowing who might double-cross who next or where the story might go depending on who is alive, and I also liked that they gave each character something to them. Michael and Lyle meet up the first time under unusual circumstances and he gives Michael a ride, where they each find out they were marines, Michael formerly a fighter in a botched mission in Lebanon. This is mentioned about halfway into the film, but it helps to set up this guy as a somewhat tragic figure, without a home and without a job but all of those memories he'd rather not take with him. Certainly not to Mexico, where he has nice ones with his father. Again, the casting and the writing is what makes the film. Lara Flynn Boyle works just about perfect as the female figure of desire and greed, and even if we've seen something like her before she's still fresh because of her performance. JT Walsh is also good but in a different way, where he's a lot more careful with his words, but one can see the look of panic when it surely comes. And Nicolas Cage, at first seemingly a little bored with the part in the opening scenes, really makes it his own as a reluctant hero with nothing to lose. Dialog is used in the film only so much to keep things moving along, but I mean this as a compliment; it's not minimalism, but economy of speech if that makes sense. Dahl knows exactly what he wants in his B-movie premise, and it's like he's taken material sitting on a shelf for years and dusted it and made it vital again.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A lonesome drifter, low on money, finds himself suddenly in a deadly rat race for money.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Caged Cinema
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Red Rock West is a beautiful film. It is a film made by movie lovers, for movie lovers, with clearly lots of fun and enthusiasm. It is as much a film-noir as it is a western, a thriller or perhaps a black comedy. Set in middle-of-nowhere Wyoming the film starts with the masculine ex-marine Michael Williams (Cage), with his muscle car on the side of the road. He has almost no gas, only some peanuts as food, and little money. He is on his way to apply for a job at an oilfield. Seemingly a friend told him this job would be a definitive. Williams, however, doesn't get hired due to a war injury. Williams hits the road again, searching for a job in another place. He stops at a local gas station, where he wants to fill his tank and ask for advice. The gas station seems abandoned and at the cash register some cash is exposed This is one of the first in many moments where William's moral stance is put to the test. Steal the much needed money or leave it alone and stay broke? Luckily, Williams doesn't have to make a choice; the owner unexpectedly appears. Williams asks for gas and a place where he can find a job. "You can try Red Rock" says the man, while he fills the tank for five dollars the last of William's money. "Welcome to Red Rock" reads a somewhat unsettling- metal sign on the side of the road when Williams enters the town. It is a sign that he will encounter many more times, for it seems that leaving Red Rock isn't as easy as entering it. It is here where it all goes downhill He asks for a job in the local bar, which results in a strange twist of fate. The bartender (J.T. Marsh) thinks Williams is the killer he had hired to murder his cheating wife! The pay for it is big and Williams can't resist the temptation; he accepts the offer. Instead of killing the bartender's wife though, he explains her the whole situation, She, however doesn't seem impressed. She actually wants him to do the reverse and kill her husband for double the money! Williams, now full on cash, tries to avoid problems and take a leave from Red Rock, but by bad luck (or fate?), he keeps finding his way back to the diabolical town. When the real killer (a brilliant Dennis Hopper) shows up and the existence of even more money is discovered, Williams' search for money turns into a rat race, where lust, greed, obsession and violence are no exceptions. As you can read, Red Rock West is a dark film. Every character has its own secret agenda and even Williams'' moral is sometimes quite ambiguous. Although the film is quite funny sometimes, with enough irony and black humor, it is still one of the more serious films starring Nicolas Cage. Cage plays his character quite natural and even has few of his famous freak-outs. The atmosphere of this film is just brilliant. The film is well shot, the music is amazing (too bad I couldn't find it anywhere on the internet), the cast is great, the pace is fast and the plot is gripping. It has many great and exciting scenes and the way the thriller and western genres are combined is very entertaining. Still, somehow, the film never really delivers a form of profoundness, which more memorable and canonical films do provide. It is as if something is missing. Nonetheless, I think Red Rock West is an extremely underrated and overslept film. Don't expect a full blown masterpiece here. Rather expect a very good and entertaining thriller/western with a great role for Nicolas Cage. As Roger Ebert fittingly concluded his review of the film: "In a sense, we've been in Red Rock many times before: It's a town where plots lie in wait for unsuspecting visitors, where hatred runs deep, where love is never enough of a motive for doing anything when cash is available." And we love it there.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Wayne's Place.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    morrison-dylan-fan
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Taking a look at a poll that was held on the IMDb Classic Film board for the best movies of 1993,I found myself getting constantly drawn towards a Neo-Noir called Red Rock West,due to having heard a large amount of praise for the title over the year.Sadly,with the price of the DVD being pretty expensive,I regrettably decided to push any plans to take a look at this tantalising Neo-Noir to the side. 2 weeks later: Being happily caught completely by surprise,I recently received an offer from a very kind IMDb'er ,who asked if I would be interested in borrowing the DVD of the film,which led to me excitingly getting ready to pay a long over due visit to Red Rock West. The plot: Angered over getting turned down for a construction job due to having an injury which he picked up in the Vietnam war,Michael Williams drives towards a small town called Red Rock West,after getting advised by a gas station worker to pay a visit to a bar in the town called Wayne's Place,where there is a good chance that Williams will be able to pick up a bar staff job. Finding Wayne Brown at the front of the bar,Michael decides to not reveal his full background details to Brown,when Wayne asks Williams if he is "The Lyle who has come here for a job?".Pretending to be Lyle,Williams expectations of being given a bar job by Brown are left in ruins,when Wayne reveals to him that "Lyle" has not been hired to work at the bar,but has in fact been chosen by Brown to be a hit-man for his wife. View on the film: Placing the dark heart of this Neo-Noir in a full to the brim whisky bottle,co-writer/ (along with his brother Rick) director John Dahl and cinematography Marc Reshovsky soak the film in a warm Neo-Noir Western atmosphere,with Dahl and Reshovsky shooting the movie in brilliant sun setting colours,which along with allowing every member of the cast face's to have a world weary quality about them,also allows Reschovsky and Dahl to show the dark secrets that all the residence of Red Rock West are desperately trying to keep out of the light. Continuing with the underlying Western theme in the excellent screenplay,John and Rick Dahl show the Wyoming town of Red Rock West to be a fading sun-lit Neo-Noir world,where everyone knows each others secrets and deals on how the town is run are made by secret drinks,and beer stained back-hander's,which is seriously threatened of being buckled,by the arrival of two "outlaws" from Texas,one being an unlucky soul who is at the wrong place,at the very worst time,and the other one being a black-clad wearing gunslinger,who wants to take the power of the town all for himself. Being given the chance to sizzle on the screen as this Neo-Noir's sole Femme Fatale,I was disappointed to find Lara Flynn Boyle give a rather frozen performance as Suzanne Brown,with Boyle failing to blend into John Dahl wonderful shadowy world,and also being unable to give the dialogue the fizzle that it richly deserves. Whilst Boyle sadly fails from setting the fuse off,the rest of the cast thankfully attack the movie with a burning hot,ten ton hammer,with J.T. Walsh giving an tremendous performance as Wayne Brown,thanks to Walsh showing Brown to go gradually more desperate for the killing of his wife to take place,and Walsh also taking full advantage of Dahl's stylish directing,by using the close ups to reveal the darkened lies and dirty deals that lay behind the scar's on Wayne's face. Entering this Neo-Noir like a fire breathing dragon,Dennis Hooper gives a fiery performance as the "real" Lyle,with Hooper showing Lyle's initially well meaning first appearance to be quickly slashed away and replaced by an outlaw whose only language is increasing the dirty money that is placed in his hands. Kept right at the centre for the whole of the film,Nicolas Cage gives an extremely strong performance,which carefully balances Michael Williams being a down to earth.down on his luck guy,with an increasing,potential deadly desire to get hold of the cash and the woman that are both just out of William's reach,which leads to Red Rock West being a gravel road that is defiantly worth travelling down.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    All Roads Lead To Intrigue.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    JohnRouseMerriottChard
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Red Rock West is directed by John Dahl who also co-wrote the screenplay with his brother Rick. It stars Nicolas Cage, Dennis Hopper, Lara Flynn Boyle, J. T. Walsh and Timothy Carhart. Music is by William Olvis and cinematography by Marc Reshovsky. When a promised job in Wyoming fails to materialise on account of an injury sustained in combat, Michael Williams (Cage) drifts into the town of Red Rock and is mistaken in a bar for a hit-man hired to kill an unfaithful wife. Tempted by the high cash on offer, Michael plays along and promptly finds himself in a web of intrigue from which escape is looking unlikely Welcome To Red Rock/You Are Now Leaving Red Rock. The studio didn't know what to do with it, a neo-noir flavoured with contemporary Western spices. Put out on cable in America and thriving on its limited release in Europe, it started to gain a cult fan-base. More so after a theatre in the Frisco Bay area started showing it and it made considerable coinage. Today it still remains more of a cult piece than anything else, which while it deserves more accolades and exposure, is still kind of nice for the fans, because it's like we have our own little neo-noir treasure all to ourselves. Red Rock West is essential for the neo-noir heads and well worthy of inspection by the average modern day crime film fan. Plot wise it's a bit, shall we say iffy? Yet the twists, turns and characterisations are so deftly constructed and performed, it matters not a jot. Cage's ex- marine is an honest and decent guy who whilst down on his luck - punished for his honesty - finds himself in a vortex of mystery and murder that he can't escape from. His companions in this scenario are film noir staples, the femme fatale (Boyle) with a smoulder as big as her secret, the hit-man (Hopper) with a glint in his eye to accompany his callous leanings, and the shifty bar owner (Walsh) trying to off his wife whilst keeping his shady cards close to his chest. As the tricksy plot unfolds in a haze of bad judgements and untruths, further pulsed by the vagaries of fate, it becomes apparent that Dahl wants us to know it isn't taking itself too seriously. There's a glorious scent of dark humour hanging in the air, an unpretentiousness about the whole thing that's refreshing. The look and feel is perfect for the narrative, the colour is stripped back to create a moody atmospheric surround, while the score and sound-tracking immediately brings to mind country and western tales of woe. Dahl knows his noir onions, but this is not just a homage hat tipper to the past, he understands what works in noir, be it the blending of the quirky with the edgy, or scene setting in locales such as a colourless bar and a foggy cemetery, Dahl gets the key ingredients right to deliver the goods wholesale. The small cast come up trumps. Boyle as Suzanne Brown is weak if her femme fatale is pitted against the likes of Matty Walker or Bridget Gregory, but it's an adequate performance that doesn't hinder the picture. She is helped enormously, though, by having to share most scenes with Cage who brings his "A" game. Consistently inconsistent throughout his career, Cage, when on form is a joy to watch, here he gets to thrive as a put upon hero, shifting seamlessly between confusion and boldness, where incredulous looks are the order of the day with a side order of eccentric intensity. Hopper does what he does so well, amusing villainy, while Walsh is effortlessly menacing and suspicious. In small secondary support Carhart and country star Dwight Yoakam leave favourable impressions. This is not an edge of your seat thriller, or a cranium bothering piece of dramedy, it's neo-noir done right. Where morality is grey at best and money is the root of all evil, it's slick, playful, cold blooded and absorbing. Hooray! 9/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Dial H for honesty
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    cmoyton
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/4/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    John Dahls opening salvo as director ranks among the best compared to his fellow contemporary directors. Sandwiched between Kill Me Again and The Last Seduction, Red Rock West was one of three "neo noirs" directed by Dahl who now finds himself marooned in TV land. It has a cast to die for and Nicholas Cage at the peak of his career. It is fantastic to see that the late J.T. Walsh is given a substantial role as bar owner/sheriff Wayne and shares as much screen time as Cage, Hopper and Boyle. Cage plays an out of work jobless drifter who in desperation pretends to be someone else to secure employment. Unfortunately the "job" requires him to murder the wife of a small town bar owner. Although he takes the money and runs from the town of Red Rock his own honesty sucks him back into the town into a shed load of trouble. Being in noir territory plot twists and deception abound. Denniis Hopper excels as hit-man Lyle. His acting is a joy to behold - all the usual Hopper mannerisms are present and the razor sharp dialogue flows from his lips in a unique style that no other actor is ever likely to replicate again. A true one off. Having said that the movies sharpest line is given to bit part actor Dwight Yoakam. My only beef is how they made sexy actress Lara Flynn Boyle look so frumpy in her rural cowgirl clothing but her acting is first class as usual. Of course there are the usual plot contrivances only found in movies in order to move the story along - the worst possibly being Cage being rescued by Hopper (the man he happens to be impersonating) just after he escapes the clutches of J.T. Walsh's crooked sheriff. I am always amazed at the blank expressions i receive when i name check this movie to others. Do yourself a favour and rent/buy this movie immediately.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Bizarre Love Quadriangle
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Raul Faust
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/10/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Well, "Red Rock West" isn't a very original or innovative film, since it repeats many of the western's clich&eacute;s from the eighties. Also, it may not have a great scenario or photography direction-- because of that, it seems to be much older than it actually is. However, the film is extremely entertaining; the story develops quickly, with an engaging and professional cast-- Nicolas Cage himself hasn't aged a day since this was released, he now looks exactly the same. The story has some interesting twists that help the film not become boring-- which is the worst element a film can have. See it without commitment and you'll have a good time.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Serpentine thriller
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Neil Welch
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/4/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    There are certain people who scream out to be typecast. Looing for a small-town bigwig with an air of corruption and a nasty streak? How about the late (and much lamented) JT Walsh? How about a contract killer with superficial charm and a centre of pure viciousness? Has to be the late (and even more lamented) Dennis Hopper. Penniless drifter with a hard luck story? Nicolas Cage, who else? Only femme fatale wife of small-town bigwig doesn't immediately scream Lara Flynn Boyle, but she does a perfectly adequate job in the role. Red Rock West is a noir movie, updated for modern audiences. The plot involves murder plots, opportunism, corruption, double-dealing, and assorted twists and turns, and is splendid fun. The performances are all dark, and all the principals get their teeth into the piece. Highly recommended, if you're in the mood for some dark fun.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    More twists and turns than a Chubby Checker concert.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    oneguyrambling
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/10/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Love him or hate him (and since he named his kid after Superman he's dropped a peg in my book), Nicolas Cage at least takes chances with his films. Sometimes this is disastrous and sometimes worthwhile, and realistically he hasn't appeared in a really good movie since "Adaptation" in 2002. But Cage ruled the 90's, in between the commercial stuff like Con Air, The Rock and Face/Off he continued taking chances with his choices with Wild At Heart and Leaving Las Vegas. Red Rock West was made in between his indie period of the late 80's and the blockbuster guy of the mid to late 90's, it's a pretty good movie but you can see why articles don't say things like "Nicolas Cage, of Leaving Las Vegas and Red Rock West fame." Strongly reminiscent of some of the Coen brothers early stuff, Red Rock West has more twists and turns than 12 garden variety whodunit thrillers combined. Cage stars as Michael, a man down to his last few dollars that is coming to an end of a long trek to start a new job on an oil drilling site, only due to a military service injury he is knocked back by the boss. So now he is still broke, out of fuel and disenchanted, Michael heads into the nearest town hoping to find work. A couple of early incidents show us he's an honest and ethical guy, the kind of guy that calls a woman "Ma'am". Now the next bit can be described, but after the movie is half over the plot becomes impossible to explain simply without major spoilers as reality changes from one minute to the next. So, Michael heads to the local pub and orders a coffee, the barman sees his car parked outside and because of the Texas license plate decides he is the man he is waiting for "Lyle from Texas". As the mistaken identity involves paid employment Michael goes along with the mistake, until he finds out that the job is to kill Wayne the barman's wife. Rather than straight out saying No Michael takes the cash and heads to Wayne's home. Somehow Michael happens upon the wife riding a horse to where she is having some hanky-panky with another farmhand, it's never really explained how he knew she would be there but who cares? Michael then goes to the house and waits for her return, when they meet he explains why he is there, and Suzanne (played by 25 kg Lara Flynn-Boyle) calmly counter offers Michael, at double the rate, to kill Wayne instead. Again Michael agrees, only this time he says enough and decides to "Lock it in Eddie", taking the cash with the sole intention of buggering off. Now in non-Hollywood this would be the end of it, but because a movie can't be over in 45 minutes we follow Michael as he leaves town in the rain. Here's where the twists get hectic, I'll summarise the next 15 minutes: - Michael hits someone in his car and takes them to the local hospital. (He's a nice guy remember?) - The Sheriff turns out to be the last person Michael needs to see, Wayne. - Wayne is a bit miffed at the perceived double cross and decides to off Michael. - Michael escapes, runs off and is picked up by Dennis Hopper, who is, you guessed it: Lyle from Texas! I can't explain much more without spoilers and confusion, only from here on in the remainder of the film revolves around Suzanne, Wayne, Michael and Lyle, and includes a myriad of twists and turns, deception, betrayal and double crossing galore. Everything a grown movie needs really. Wayne is played by JT Walsh, usually a bit player in other movies and I have always felt he is a bit over the top. Dennis Hopper is always ultra-hammy, and is almost cartoonish here. Lara Flynn-Boyle is surprisingly low key through most of the film, and has flawless skin regardless of the circumstances. Cage plays the troubled hero part to the hilt, he's the prototype for the nice guy in a situation that he wants to avoid but can't. The finale is in keeping with the rest of the film and is fairly satisfying. If I might digress momentarily, at one stage Michael walks into a bar and says "Give me a beer", now I have walked into many bars and know if I ever say that the bartender will say something along the lines of "Which one d**khead?" Since the dawn of time even the most low key bar stocks more than one brand, in fact most have literally dozens to choose from. Dunno why this bothers me but it does. If you're worried about the perception of product placement do what Tarantino does and make up a brand. Final Rating  7 / 10. "We twist. And turn. And twist and twist and turn. Twist, twist, twist. Turn, turn, turn. The Itchy and Scratchy Show." I mean Red Rock West. (That means it's a pretty good movie.) If you liked this review (or even if you didn't) check out oneguyrambling.com
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Another gem starring Cage that slipped under my radar
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    thekyles99
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/7/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Like i said in previous reviews, recently i have been going through Nic Cage's IMDb list of projects he has done to see if there was anything i hadn't seen that he's been in. And low and behold i found a bunch of em. So far out of three watched i liked 2 of em . 2-1 not a bad ratio so far. Just goes to show to show Nic Cage although one of the busiest actors is also careful of the scripts he chooses to work on. Red Rock West is another gem of his that must've slipped under my radar in 93. Great storyline however i found the ending a little on the cheesy side that being said it was a pretty good thriller. This time round Nic portrays Michael Williams a down and out Texan who resides in his car and tries to get jobs but fails to an injury he took while serving in the marines. Apon driving into a little town of red rock he enters the red rock tavern to see about a job and in a serious judgement error ends up taking a job that belonged to a professional hit-man (Dennis Hopper) needless to say all hell breaks loose and the moral of the story is number one money is never easy and number two...watch who's life you try to impersonate as the grass is always greener on the other side of the fence. Good casting featuring the late great Jt Walsh who was always a pleasure to watch work and a very underrated actor to say the least. Another great and recently passed Dennis Hopper portrays the hit-man that was originally intended for the hit but was a little later then mike at arriving to the bar. Dennis hopper in my books was awesome in portraying villains. Lara Flynn Boyle rounds off the cast with a less then believable performance as the sheriffs wife who the hit is to be delivered upon. Nic Cage's character in this spends the rest of the movie digging the hole he has made himself further and further. To get out is the question.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Enthralling criminal goings-on in a small Western town, as the lead is caught between a Red Rock and a hard place.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    johnnyboyz (j_l_h_m@yahoo.co.uk)
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/6/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    John Dahl's Red Rock West is a neat, taut, stripped down piece of cut-and-thrust film-making without gimmickry nor a single false string attached. In a current contemporary world of American film-making, and one that was almost certainly predominant at the time of Red Rock West's inception, how wonderful it is to uncover a film that refrains from the over indulgence of extravagance and the ideology that awe is built on a foundation of overkill and visuals. That's not to say Red Rock West is without extravagance nor awe, such is Dahl's ability, that the film is full of a number of various incidences and twists that are exactly these things and gotten across by way of little more than a glance from one of the character's or an individual cut of the camera. When we hark back to America's independent cinematic boom of the late 1980s and going on into the early 1990s, certainly a boom that saw a number of films and individual directors both honoured and recognised on the European film circuit at the top level in a series of Golden Palm nominations, the displaying of Red Rock West shows we must not glance over the name of Dahl when speaking of both the films and directors of that era, namely: the Coen Brothers; Steven Soderburgh; Spike Lee and Tarantino, et al. The film revolves around Nicolas Cage's character named Michael Williams, an ex-Marine of American nationality down on his luck and strapped for money in the dusty outback of Wyoming. He lives out of his car; uses random road side troughs full of water as makeshift sinks and struggles to find work, the latest failing being a construction site job that doesn't come through, although later on, he'll find ample opportunity at constructing something: a monstrosity of a scenario for himself. Unbeknownst to us at the time, he's going into the misadventure he'll come to have with a prior tragedy of having served time in the Vietnam War, but suffering during this stretch at the hands of a missile attack on a base in Lebanon he was positioned at which forced him into enduring a glut of both chaos and death. The event that may very well lend itself to Williams' dishevelled and down-beat tone and attitude, something Cage pulls off in that naturalistic manner he's done so on occasion since, shares eerie parallels with what will come to unfold around him as another glut of death and chaos unfolds around a man who has signed up for something you only realise you don't want to be anywhere near when it gets ugly as 'wrong place  wrong time' scenario once again kicks in. The devilish premise sees Williams pretend to be the Texan hit-man an apparent bar owner named Wayne (Walsh) called for some days ago so as to do some local dirty-work he wants taken care of. His looming over a seated Cage whilst in the office an early establishing of power, the sort of power that he'll come to have over him as Williams is forced throughout into proverbially dancing to the tune of others. But rather than eliminate the target, Wayne's wife played by Lara Flynn Boyle, Williams warns her of the predicament and that her marriage ought quite clearly be an item of concern form here on in. Once all is said and done, the real hit-man in Dennis Hopper's Lyle shows up in jet black Texan attire and similarly coloured car more resembling a hearse than anything else, whilst developments and complications in exactly who it is the chief of police is in the whole area open up. For Cage's character, and like in most good film noir when dealing with the down-trodden lead whom treads a fine line between right and wrong, the persistent idea of torn morals floats to the surface relatively quickly and consistently in Red Rock West. In just observing the premise, the notion of Williams illegally accepting the offer of being paid to kill someone before refraining from doing it when confronted with the innocent figure of Wayne's wife, Dahl highlights his character's soon-to-be prominent ever shifting; ever changing attitudes to what crime infused activity is playing out around him. Throughout, Williams lies; shoots; kills and steals but additionally saves; offers salvation and actually avoids violence on several occasions when straight forward murder would have offered a simple way out of a predicament. Given this, Dahl expertly manoeuvres Williams from one town in the form of Red Rock to another and then back over the border again, a sort of physical flitting from one place to another in what is a physical manifestation of both the above theories of a film noir's male lead as well as Cage's character's constantly ambiguous hopping from justified in his actions to not as so. Red Rock West moulds a fascinating, and quite terrifying at times, tale out of all these elements; combining a number of items such as double-crosses; multiple identities and intense connections characters have with one another, the sorts that they're forced into forging before later being asked what they truly mean to them. Dahl additionally, and in a very basic sense, taps into a certain idea of post-war disillusionment through his lead in Williams' disconnection from the rest of society seeing him inhabit a desolate and often incomprehensible rural locale in which he just about scrapes by. This, as an old war injury refrains him from making any true advancement in a chosen field of work. Red Rock West is a tight, gripping piece; the sort that arrives with a steady and effective eye on a variety of items all the while under the control of a steady, focused hand.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    western-noir at its near finest
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    MisterWhiplash
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/6/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    John Dahl knows his film-noir, and he knows his westerns. This should be assumed from seeing Red Rock West, though his 'noir' influence comes through in other films as well (Kill Me Again and to a degree Joy Ride). He knows how to write a lone average-Joe type of character, and the shady villain, and a sexy Femme Fatale. He knows this, but he also fills his story of a drifter coming to a small Wyoming town and being (accidentally?) hired to kill a man's wife with some top-shelf talent. Or, at least, the best actors that could make the parts their own. It's a cold little movie where you realize pretty quickly that despite Michael's "nice-guy" quality, he's still a potential thief and is the comparatively not so bad. Not so bad compared to Wayne the "bartender" or "Sheriff", if that is indeed his name, and his wife who wants to escape to Mexico with all of the money she "inherited" (please note the quotations). An extra slice of danger comes with the appearance of the actual man hired to kill the woman, Lyle from Dallas played by the late Dennis Hopper. His character and performance is far less aggressive than in Blue Velvet, though this is like comparing a Tasmanian Devil to a bull at a fight. I liked the suspense, of not knowing who might double-cross who next or where the story might go depending on who is alive, and I also liked that they gave each character something to them. Michael and Lyle meet up the first time under unusual circumstances and he gives Michael a ride, where they each find out they were marines, Michael formerly a fighter in a botched mission in Lebanon. This is mentioned about halfway into the film, but it helps to set up this guy as a somewhat tragic figure, without a home and without a job but all of those memories he'd rather not take with him. Certainly not to Mexico, where he has nice ones with his father. Again, the casting and the writing is what makes the film. Lara Flynn Boyle works just about perfect as the female figure of desire and greed, and even if we've seen something like her before she's still fresh because of her performance. JT Walsh is also good but in a different way, where he's a lot more careful with his words, but one can see the look of panic when it surely comes. And Nicolas Cage, at first seemingly a little bored with the part in the opening scenes, really makes it his own as a reluctant hero with nothing to lose. Dialog is used in the film only so much to keep things moving along, but I mean this as a compliment; it's not minimalism, but economy of speech if that makes sense. Dahl knows exactly what he wants in his B-movie premise, and it's like he's taken material sitting on a shelf for years and dusted it and made it vital again.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A lonesome drifter, low on money, finds himself suddenly in a deadly rat race for money.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Caged Cinema
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Red Rock West is a beautiful film. It is a film made by movie lovers, for movie lovers, with clearly lots of fun and enthusiasm. It is as much a film-noir as it is a western, a thriller or perhaps a black comedy. Set in middle-of-nowhere Wyoming the film starts with the masculine ex-marine Michael Williams (Cage), with his muscle car on the side of the road. He has almost no gas, only some peanuts as food, and little money. He is on his way to apply for a job at an oilfield. Seemingly a friend told him this job would be a definitive. Williams, however, doesn't get hired due to a war injury. Williams hits the road again, searching for a job in another place. He stops at a local gas station, where he wants to fill his tank and ask for advice. The gas station seems abandoned and at the cash register some cash is exposed This is one of the first in many moments where William's moral stance is put to the test. Steal the much needed money or leave it alone and stay broke? Luckily, Williams doesn't have to make a choice; the owner unexpectedly appears. Williams asks for gas and a place where he can find a job. "You can try Red Rock" says the man, while he fills the tank for five dollars the last of William's money. "Welcome to Red Rock" reads a somewhat unsettling- metal sign on the side of the road when Williams enters the town. It is a sign that he will encounter many more times, for it seems that leaving Red Rock isn't as easy as entering it. It is here where it all goes downhill He asks for a job in the local bar, which results in a strange twist of fate. The bartender (J.T. Marsh) thinks Williams is the killer he had hired to murder his cheating wife! The pay for it is big and Williams can't resist the temptation; he accepts the offer. Instead of killing the bartender's wife though, he explains her the whole situation, She, however doesn't seem impressed. She actually wants him to do the reverse and kill her husband for double the money! Williams, now full on cash, tries to avoid problems and take a leave from Red Rock, but by bad luck (or fate?), he keeps finding his way back to the diabolical town. When the real killer (a brilliant Dennis Hopper) shows up and the existence of even more money is discovered, Williams' search for money turns into a rat race, where lust, greed, obsession and violence are no exceptions. As you can read, Red Rock West is a dark film. Every character has its own secret agenda and even Williams'' moral is sometimes quite ambiguous. Although the film is quite funny sometimes, with enough irony and black humor, it is still one of the more serious films starring Nicolas Cage. Cage plays his character quite natural and even has few of his famous freak-outs. The atmosphere of this film is just brilliant. The film is well shot, the music is amazing (too bad I couldn't find it anywhere on the internet), the cast is great, the pace is fast and the plot is gripping. It has many great and exciting scenes and the way the thriller and western genres are combined is very entertaining. Still, somehow, the film never really delivers a form of profoundness, which more memorable and canonical films do provide. It is as if something is missing. Nonetheless, I think Red Rock West is an extremely underrated and overslept film. Don't expect a full blown masterpiece here. Rather expect a very good and entertaining thriller/western with a great role for Nicolas Cage. As Roger Ebert fittingly concluded his review of the film: "In a sense, we've been in Red Rock many times before: It's a town where plots lie in wait for unsuspecting visitors, where hatred runs deep, where love is never enough of a motive for doing anything when cash is available." And we love it there.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Wayne's Place.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    morrison-dylan-fan
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Taking a look at a poll that was held on the IMDb Classic Film board for the best movies of 1993,I found myself getting constantly drawn towards a Neo-Noir called Red Rock West,due to having heard a large amount of praise for the title over the year.Sadly,with the price of the DVD being pretty expensive,I regrettably decided to push any plans to take a look at this tantalising Neo-Noir to the side. 2 weeks later: Being happily caught completely by surprise,I recently received an offer from a very kind IMDb'er ,who asked if I would be interested in borrowing the DVD of the film,which led to me excitingly getting ready to pay a long over due visit to Red Rock West. The plot: Angered over getting turned down for a construction job due to having an injury which he picked up in the Vietnam war,Michael Williams drives towards a small town called Red Rock West,after getting advised by a gas station worker to pay a visit to a bar in the town called Wayne's Place,where there is a good chance that Williams will be able to pick up a bar staff job. Finding Wayne Brown at the front of the bar,Michael decides to not reveal his full background details to Brown,when Wayne asks Williams if he is "The Lyle who has come here for a job?".Pretending to be Lyle,Williams expectations of being given a bar job by Brown are left in ruins,when Wayne reveals to him that "Lyle" has not been hired to work at the bar,but has in fact been chosen by Brown to be a hit-man for his wife. View on the film: Placing the dark heart of this Neo-Noir in a full to the brim whisky bottle,co-writer/ (along with his brother Rick) director John Dahl and cinematography Marc Reshovsky soak the film in a warm Neo-Noir Western atmosphere,with Dahl and Reshovsky shooting the movie in brilliant sun setting colours,which along with allowing every member of the cast face's to have a world weary quality about them,also allows Reschovsky and Dahl to show the dark secrets that all the residence of Red Rock West are desperately trying to keep out of the light. Continuing with the underlying Western theme in the excellent screenplay,John and Rick Dahl show the Wyoming town of Red Rock West to be a fading sun-lit Neo-Noir world,where everyone knows each others secrets and deals on how the town is run are made by secret drinks,and beer stained back-hander's,which is seriously threatened of being buckled,by the arrival of two "outlaws" from Texas,one being an unlucky soul who is at the wrong place,at the very worst time,and the other one being a black-clad wearing gunslinger,who wants to take the power of the town all for himself. Being given the chance to sizzle on the screen as this Neo-Noir's sole Femme Fatale,I was disappointed to find Lara Flynn Boyle give a rather frozen performance as Suzanne Brown,with Boyle failing to blend into John Dahl wonderful shadowy world,and also being unable to give the dialogue the fizzle that it richly deserves. Whilst Boyle sadly fails from setting the fuse off,the rest of the cast thankfully attack the movie with a burning hot,ten ton hammer,with J.T. Walsh giving an tremendous performance as Wayne Brown,thanks to Walsh showing Brown to go gradually more desperate for the killing of his wife to take place,and Walsh also taking full advantage of Dahl's stylish directing,by using the close ups to reveal the darkened lies and dirty deals that lay behind the scar's on Wayne's face. Entering this Neo-Noir like a fire breathing dragon,Dennis Hooper gives a fiery performance as the "real" Lyle,with Hooper showing Lyle's initially well meaning first appearance to be quickly slashed away and replaced by an outlaw whose only language is increasing the dirty money that is placed in his hands. Kept right at the centre for the whole of the film,Nicolas Cage gives an extremely strong performance,which carefully balances Michael Williams being a down to earth.down on his luck guy,with an increasing,potential deadly desire to get hold of the cash and the woman that are both just out of William's reach,which leads to Red Rock West being a gravel road that is defiantly worth travelling down.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    All Roads Lead To Intrigue.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    JohnRouseMerriottChard
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Red Rock West is directed by John Dahl who also co-wrote the screenplay with his brother Rick. It stars Nicolas Cage, Dennis Hopper, Lara Flynn Boyle, J. T. Walsh and Timothy Carhart. Music is by William Olvis and cinematography by Marc Reshovsky. When a promised job in Wyoming fails to materialise on account of an injury sustained in combat, Michael Williams (Cage) drifts into the town of Red Rock and is mistaken in a bar for a hit-man hired to kill an unfaithful wife. Tempted by the high cash on offer, Michael plays along and promptly finds himself in a web of intrigue from which escape is looking unlikely Welcome To Red Rock/You Are Now Leaving Red Rock. The studio didn't know what to do with it, a neo-noir flavoured with contemporary Western spices. Put out on cable in America and thriving on its limited release in Europe, it started to gain a cult fan-base. More so after a theatre in the Frisco Bay area started showing it and it made considerable coinage. Today it still remains more of a cult piece than anything else, which while it deserves more accolades and exposure, is still kind of nice for the fans, because it's like we have our own little neo-noir treasure all to ourselves. Red Rock West is essential for the neo-noir heads and well worthy of inspection by the average modern day crime film fan. Plot wise it's a bit, shall we say iffy? Yet the twists, turns and characterisations are so deftly constructed and performed, it matters not a jot. Cage's ex- marine is an honest and decent guy who whilst down on his luck - punished for his honesty - finds himself in a vortex of mystery and murder that he can't escape from. His companions in this scenario are film noir staples, the femme fatale (Boyle) with a smoulder as big as her secret, the hit-man (Hopper) with a glint in his eye to accompany his callous leanings, and the shifty bar owner (Walsh) trying to off his wife whilst keeping his shady cards close to his chest. As the tricksy plot unfolds in a haze of bad judgements and untruths, further pulsed by the vagaries of fate, it becomes apparent that Dahl wants us to know it isn't taking itself too seriously. There's a glorious scent of dark humour hanging in the air, an unpretentiousness about the whole thing that's refreshing. The look and feel is perfect for the narrative, the colour is stripped back to create a moody atmospheric surround, while the score and sound-tracking immediately brings to mind country and western tales of woe. Dahl knows his noir onions, but this is not just a homage hat tipper to the past, he understands what works in noir, be it the blending of the quirky with the edgy, or scene setting in locales such as a colourless bar and a foggy cemetery, Dahl gets the key ingredients right to deliver the goods wholesale. The small cast come up trumps. Boyle as Suzanne Brown is weak if her femme fatale is pitted against the likes of Matty Walker or Bridget Gregory, but it's an adequate performance that doesn't hinder the picture. She is helped enormously, though, by having to share most scenes with Cage who brings his "A" game. Consistently inconsistent throughout his career, Cage, when on form is a joy to watch, here he gets to thrive as a put upon hero, shifting seamlessly between confusion and boldness, where incredulous looks are the order of the day with a side order of eccentric intensity. Hopper does what he does so well, amusing villainy, while Walsh is effortlessly menacing and suspicious. In small secondary support Carhart and country star Dwight Yoakam leave favourable impressions. This is not an edge of your seat thriller, or a cranium bothering piece of dramedy, it's neo-noir done right. Where morality is grey at best and money is the root of all evil, it's slick, playful, cold blooded and absorbing. Hooray! 9/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Dial H for honesty
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    cmoyton
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/4/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    John Dahls opening salvo as director ranks among the best compared to his fellow contemporary directors. Sandwiched between Kill Me Again and The Last Seduction, Red Rock West was one of three "neo noirs" directed by Dahl who now finds himself marooned in TV land. It has a cast to die for and Nicholas Cage at the peak of his career. It is fantastic to see that the late J.T. Walsh is given a substantial role as bar owner/sheriff Wayne and shares as much screen time as Cage, Hopper and Boyle. Cage plays an out of work jobless drifter who in desperation pretends to be someone else to secure employment. Unfortunately the "job" requires him to murder the wife of a small town bar owner. Although he takes the money and runs from the town of Red Rock his own honesty sucks him back into the town into a shed load of trouble. Being in noir territory plot twists and deception abound. Denniis Hopper excels as hit-man Lyle. His acting is a joy to behold - all the usual Hopper mannerisms are present and the razor sharp dialogue flows from his lips in a unique style that no other actor is ever likely to replicate again. A true one off. Having said that the movies sharpest line is given to bit part actor Dwight Yoakam. My only beef is how they made sexy actress Lara Flynn Boyle look so frumpy in her rural cowgirl clothing but her acting is first class as usual. Of course there are the usual plot contrivances only found in movies in order to move the story along - the worst possibly being Cage being rescued by Hopper (the man he happens to be impersonating) just after he escapes the clutches of J.T. Walsh's crooked sheriff. I am always amazed at the blank expressions i receive when i name check this movie to others. Do yourself a favour and rent/buy this movie immediately.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Bizarre Love Quadriangle
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Raul Faust
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/10/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Well, "Red Rock West" isn't a very original or innovative film, since it repeats many of the western's clich&eacute;s from the eighties. Also, it may not have a great scenario or photography direction-- because of that, it seems to be much older than it actually is. However, the film is extremely entertaining; the story develops quickly, with an engaging and professional cast-- Nicolas Cage himself hasn't aged a day since this was released, he now looks exactly the same. The story has some interesting twists that help the film not become boring-- which is the worst element a film can have. See it without commitment and you'll have a good time.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Serpentine thriller
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Neil Welch
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/4/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    There are certain people who scream out to be typecast. Looing for a small-town bigwig with an air of corruption and a nasty streak? How about the late (and much lamented) JT Walsh? How about a contract killer with superficial charm and a centre of pure viciousness? Has to be the late (and even more lamented) Dennis Hopper. Penniless drifter with a hard luck story? Nicolas Cage, who else? Only femme fatale wife of small-town bigwig doesn't immediately scream Lara Flynn Boyle, but she does a perfectly adequate job in the role. Red Rock West is a noir movie, updated for modern audiences. The plot involves murder plots, opportunism, corruption, double-dealing, and assorted twists and turns, and is splendid fun. The performances are all dark, and all the principals get their teeth into the piece. Highly recommended, if you're in the mood for some dark fun.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    More twists and turns than a Chubby Checker concert.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    oneguyrambling
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/10/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Love him or hate him (and since he named his kid after Superman he's dropped a peg in my book), Nicolas Cage at least takes chances with his films. Sometimes this is disastrous and sometimes worthwhile, and realistically he hasn't appeared in a really good movie since "Adaptation" in 2002. But Cage ruled the 90's, in between the commercial stuff like Con Air, The Rock and Face/Off he continued taking chances with his choices with Wild At Heart and Leaving Las Vegas. Red Rock West was made in between his indie period of the late 80's and the blockbuster guy of the mid to late 90's, it's a pretty good movie but you can see why articles don't say things like "Nicolas Cage, of Leaving Las Vegas and Red Rock West fame." Strongly reminiscent of some of the Coen brothers early stuff, Red Rock West has more twists and turns than 12 garden variety whodunit thrillers combined. Cage stars as Michael, a man down to his last few dollars that is coming to an end of a long trek to start a new job on an oil drilling site, only due to a military service injury he is knocked back by the boss. So now he is still broke, out of fuel and disenchanted, Michael heads into the nearest town hoping to find work. A couple of early incidents show us he's an honest and ethical guy, the kind of guy that calls a woman "Ma'am". Now the next bit can be described, but after the movie is half over the plot becomes impossible to explain simply without major spoilers as reality changes from one minute to the next. So, Michael heads to the local pub and orders a coffee, the barman sees his car parked outside and because of the Texas license plate decides he is the man he is waiting for "Lyle from Texas". As the mistaken identity involves paid employment Michael goes along with the mistake, until he finds out that the job is to kill Wayne the barman's wife. Rather than straight out saying No Michael takes the cash and heads to Wayne's home. Somehow Michael happens upon the wife riding a horse to where she is having some hanky-panky with another farmhand, it's never really explained how he knew she would be there but who cares? Michael then goes to the house and waits for her return, when they meet he explains why he is there, and Suzanne (played by 25 kg Lara Flynn-Boyle) calmly counter offers Michael, at double the rate, to kill Wayne instead. Again Michael agrees, only this time he says enough and decides to "Lock it in Eddie", taking the cash with the sole intention of buggering off. Now in non-Hollywood this would be the end of it, but because a movie can't be over in 45 minutes we follow Michael as he leaves town in the rain. Here's where the twists get hectic, I'll summarise the next 15 minutes: - Michael hits someone in his car and takes them to the local hospital. (He's a nice guy remember?) - The Sheriff turns out to be the last person Michael needs to see, Wayne. - Wayne is a bit miffed at the perceived double cross and decides to off Michael. - Michael escapes, runs off and is picked up by Dennis Hopper, who is, you guessed it: Lyle from Texas! I can't explain much more without spoilers and confusion, only from here on in the remainder of the film revolves around Suzanne, Wayne, Michael and Lyle, and includes a myriad of twists and turns, deception, betrayal and double crossing galore. Everything a grown movie needs really. Wayne is played by JT Walsh, usually a bit player in other movies and I have always felt he is a bit over the top. Dennis Hopper is always ultra-hammy, and is almost cartoonish here. Lara Flynn-Boyle is surprisingly low key through most of the film, and has flawless skin regardless of the circumstances. Cage plays the troubled hero part to the hilt, he's the prototype for the nice guy in a situation that he wants to avoid but can't. The finale is in keeping with the rest of the film and is fairly satisfying. If I might digress momentarily, at one stage Michael walks into a bar and says "Give me a beer", now I have walked into many bars and know if I ever say that the bartender will say something along the lines of "Which one d**khead?" Since the dawn of time even the most low key bar stocks more than one brand, in fact most have literally dozens to choose from. Dunno why this bothers me but it does. If you're worried about the perception of product placement do what Tarantino does and make up a brand. Final Rating  7 / 10. "We twist. And turn. And twist and twist and turn. Twist, twist, twist. Turn, turn, turn. The Itchy and Scratchy Show." I mean Red Rock West. (That means it's a pretty good movie.) If you liked this review (or even if you didn't) check out oneguyrambling.com
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Another gem starring Cage that slipped under my radar
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    thekyles99
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/7/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Like i said in previous reviews, recently i have been going through Nic Cage's IMDb list of projects he has done to see if there was anything i hadn't seen that he's been in. And low and behold i found a bunch of em. So far out of three watched i liked 2 of em . 2-1 not a bad ratio so far. Just goes to show to show Nic Cage although one of the busiest actors is also careful of the scripts he chooses to work on. Red Rock West is another gem of his that must've slipped under my radar in 93. Great storyline however i found the ending a little on the cheesy side that being said it was a pretty good thriller. This time round Nic portrays Michael Williams a down and out Texan who resides in his car and tries to get jobs but fails to an injury he took while serving in the marines. Apon driving into a little town of red rock he enters the red rock tavern to see about a job and in a serious judgement error ends up taking a job that belonged to a professional hit-man (Dennis Hopper) needless to say all hell breaks loose and the moral of the story is number one money is never easy and number two...watch who's life you try to impersonate as the grass is always greener on the other side of the fence. Good casting featuring the late great Jt Walsh who was always a pleasure to watch work and a very underrated actor to say the least. Another great and recently passed Dennis Hopper portrays the hit-man that was originally intended for the hit but was a little later then mike at arriving to the bar. Dennis hopper in my books was awesome in portraying villains. Lara Flynn Boyle rounds off the cast with a less then believable performance as the sheriffs wife who the hit is to be delivered upon. Nic Cage's character in this spends the rest of the movie digging the hole he has made himself further and further. To get out is the question.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Enthralling criminal goings-on in a small Western town, as the lead is caught between a Red Rock and a hard place.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    johnnyboyz (j_l_h_m@yahoo.co.uk)
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/6/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    John Dahl's Red Rock West is a neat, taut, stripped down piece of cut-and-thrust film-making without gimmickry nor a single false string attached. In a current contemporary world of American film-making, and one that was almost certainly predominant at the time of Red Rock West's inception, how wonderful it is to uncover a film that refrains from the over indulgence of extravagance and the ideology that awe is built on a foundation of overkill and visuals. That's not to say Red Rock West is without extravagance nor awe, such is Dahl's ability, that the film is full of a number of various incidences and twists that are exactly these things and gotten across by way of little more than a glance from one of the character's or an individual cut of the camera. When we hark back to America's independent cinematic boom of the late 1980s and going on into the early 1990s, certainly a boom that saw a number of films and individual directors both honoured and recognised on the European film circuit at the top level in a series of Golden Palm nominations, the displaying of Red Rock West shows we must not glance over the name of Dahl when speaking of both the films and directors of that era, namely: the Coen Brothers; Steven Soderburgh; Spike Lee and Tarantino, et al. The film revolves around Nicolas Cage's character named Michael Williams, an ex-Marine of American nationality down on his luck and strapped for money in the dusty outback of Wyoming. He lives out of his car; uses random road side troughs full of water as makeshift sinks and struggles to find work, the latest failing being a construction site job that doesn't come through, although later on, he'll find ample opportunity at constructing something: a monstrosity of a scenario for himself. Unbeknownst to us at the time, he's going into the misadventure he'll come to have with a prior tragedy of having served time in the Vietnam War, but suffering during this stretch at the hands of a missile attack on a base in Lebanon he was positioned at which forced him into enduring a glut of both chaos and death. The event that may very well lend itself to Williams' dishevelled and down-beat tone and attitude, something Cage pulls off in that naturalistic manner he's done so on occasion since, shares eerie parallels with what will come to unfold around him as another glut of death and chaos unfolds around a man who has signed up for something you only realise you don't want to be anywhere near when it gets ugly as 'wrong place  wrong time' scenario once again kicks in. The devilish premise sees Williams pretend to be the Texan hit-man an apparent bar owner named Wayne (Walsh) called for some days ago so as to do some local dirty-work he wants taken care of. His looming over a seated Cage whilst in the office an early establishing of power, the sort of power that he'll come to have over him as Williams is forced throughout into proverbially dancing to the tune of others. But rather than eliminate the target, Wayne's wife played by Lara Flynn Boyle, Williams warns her of the predicament and that her marriage ought quite clearly be an item of concern form here on in. Once all is said and done, the real hit-man in Dennis Hopper's Lyle shows up in jet black Texan attire and similarly coloured car more resembling a hearse than anything else, whilst developments and complications in exactly who it is the chief of police is in the whole area open up. For Cage's character, and like in most good film noir when dealing with the down-trodden lead whom treads a fine line between right and wrong, the persistent idea of torn morals floats to the surface relatively quickly and consistently in Red Rock West. In just observing the premise, the notion of Williams illegally accepting the offer of being paid to kill someone before refraining from doing it when confronted with the innocent figure of Wayne's wife, Dahl highlights his character's soon-to-be prominent ever shifting; ever changing attitudes to what crime infused activity is playing out around him. Throughout, Williams lies; shoots; kills and steals but additionally saves; offers salvation and actually avoids violence on several occasions when straight forward murder would have offered a simple way out of a predicament. Given this, Dahl expertly manoeuvres Williams from one town in the form of Red Rock to another and then back over the border again, a sort of physical flitting from one place to another in what is a physical manifestation of both the above theories of a film noir's male lead as well as Cage's character's constantly ambiguous hopping from justified in his actions to not as so. Red Rock West moulds a fascinating, and quite terrifying at times, tale out of all these elements; combining a number of items such as double-crosses; multiple identities and intense connections characters have with one another, the sorts that they're forced into forging before later being asked what they truly mean to them. Dahl additionally, and in a very basic sense, taps into a certain idea of post-war disillusionment through his lead in Williams' disconnection from the rest of society seeing him inhabit a desolate and often incomprehensible rural locale in which he just about scrapes by. This, as an old war injury refrains him from making any true advancement in a chosen field of work. Red Rock West is a tight, gripping piece; the sort that arrives with a steady and effective eye on a variety of items all the while under the control of a steady, focused hand.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    western-noir at its near finest
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    MisterWhiplash
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/6/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    John Dahl knows his film-noir, and he knows his westerns. This should be assumed from seeing Red Rock West, though his 'noir' influence comes through in other films as well (Kill Me Again and to a degree Joy Ride). He knows how to write a lone average-Joe type of character, and the shady villain, and a sexy Femme Fatale. He knows this, but he also fills his story of a drifter coming to a small Wyoming town and being (accidentally?) hired to kill a man's wife with some top-shelf talent. Or, at least, the best actors that could make the parts their own. It's a cold little movie where you realize pretty quickly that despite Michael's "nice-guy" quality, he's still a potential thief and is the comparatively not so bad. Not so bad compared to Wayne the "bartender" or "Sheriff", if that is indeed his name, and his wife who wants to escape to Mexico with all of the money she "inherited" (please note the quotations). An extra slice of danger comes with the appearance of the actual man hired to kill the woman, Lyle from Dallas played by the late Dennis Hopper. His character and performance is far less aggressive than in Blue Velvet, though this is like comparing a Tasmanian Devil to a bull at a fight. I liked the suspense, of not knowing who might double-cross who next or where the story might go depending on who is alive, and I also liked that they gave each character something to them. Michael and Lyle meet up the first time under unusual circumstances and he gives Michael a ride, where they each find out they were marines, Michael formerly a fighter in a botched mission in Lebanon. This is mentioned about halfway into the film, but it helps to set up this guy as a somewhat tragic figure, without a home and without a job but all of those memories he'd rather not take with him. Certainly not to Mexico, where he has nice ones with his father. Again, the casting and the writing is what makes the film. Lara Flynn Boyle works just about perfect as the female figure of desire and greed, and even if we've seen something like her before she's still fresh because of her performance. JT Walsh is also good but in a different way, where he's a lot more careful with his words, but one can see the look of panic when it surely comes. And Nicolas Cage, at first seemingly a little bored with the part in the opening scenes, really makes it his own as a reluctant hero with nothing to lose. Dialog is used in the film only so much to keep things moving along, but I mean this as a compliment; it's not minimalism, but economy of speech if that makes sense. Dahl knows exactly what he wants in his B-movie premise, and it's like he's taken material sitting on a shelf for years and dusted it and made it vital again.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A lonesome drifter, low on money, finds himself suddenly in a deadly rat race for money.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Caged Cinema
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Red Rock West is a beautiful film. It is a film made by movie lovers, for movie lovers, with clearly lots of fun and enthusiasm. It is as much a film-noir as it is a western, a thriller or perhaps a black comedy. Set in middle-of-nowhere Wyoming the film starts with the masculine ex-marine Michael Williams (Cage), with his muscle car on the side of the road. He has almost no gas, only some peanuts as food, and little money. He is on his way to apply for a job at an oilfield. Seemingly a friend told him this job would be a definitive. Williams, however, doesn't get hired due to a war injury. Williams hits the road again, searching for a job in another place. He stops at a local gas station, where he wants to fill his tank and ask for advice. The gas station seems abandoned and at the cash register some cash is exposed This is one of the first in many moments where William's moral stance is put to the test. Steal the much needed money or leave it alone and stay broke? Luckily, Williams doesn't have to make a choice; the owner unexpectedly appears. Williams asks for gas and a place where he can find a job. "You can try Red Rock" says the man, while he fills the tank for five dollars the last of William's money. "Welcome to Red Rock" reads a somewhat unsettling- metal sign on the side of the road when Williams enters the town. It is a sign that he will encounter many more times, for it seems that leaving Red Rock isn't as easy as entering it. It is here where it all goes downhill He asks for a job in the local bar, which results in a strange twist of fate. The bartender (J.T. Marsh) thinks Williams is the killer he had hired to murder his cheating wife! The pay for it is big and Williams can't resist the temptation; he accepts the offer. Instead of killing the bartender's wife though, he explains her the whole situation, She, however doesn't seem impressed. She actually wants him to do the reverse and kill her husband for double the money! Williams, now full on cash, tries to avoid problems and take a leave from Red Rock, but by bad luck (or fate?), he keeps finding his way back to the diabolical town. When the real killer (a brilliant Dennis Hopper) shows up and the existence of even more money is discovered, Williams' search for money turns into a rat race, where lust, greed, obsession and violence are no exceptions. As you can read, Red Rock West is a dark film. Every character has its own secret agenda and even Williams'' moral is sometimes quite ambiguous. Although the film is quite funny sometimes, with enough irony and black humor, it is still one of the more serious films starring Nicolas Cage. Cage plays his character quite natural and even has few of his famous freak-outs. The atmosphere of this film is just brilliant. The film is well shot, the music is amazing (too bad I couldn't find it anywhere on the internet), the cast is great, the pace is fast and the plot is gripping. It has many great and exciting scenes and the way the thriller and western genres are combined is very entertaining. Still, somehow, the film never really delivers a form of profoundness, which more memorable and canonical films do provide. It is as if something is missing. Nonetheless, I think Red Rock West is an extremely underrated and overslept film. Don't expect a full blown masterpiece here. Rather expect a very good and entertaining thriller/western with a great role for Nicolas Cage. As Roger Ebert fittingly concluded his review of the film: "In a sense, we've been in Red Rock many times before: It's a town where plots lie in wait for unsuspecting visitors, where hatred runs deep, where love is never enough of a motive for doing anything when cash is available." And we love it there.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Wayne's Place.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    morrison-dylan-fan
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Taking a look at a poll that was held on the IMDb Classic Film board for the best movies of 1993,I found myself getting constantly drawn towards a Neo-Noir called Red Rock West,due to having heard a large amount of praise for the title over the year.Sadly,with the price of the DVD being pretty expensive,I regrettably decided to push any plans to take a look at this tantalising Neo-Noir to the side. 2 weeks later: Being happily caught completely by surprise,I recently received an offer from a very kind IMDb'er ,who asked if I would be interested in borrowing the DVD of the film,which led to me excitingly getting ready to pay a long over due visit to Red Rock West. The plot: Angered over getting turned down for a construction job due to having an injury which he picked up in the Vietnam war,Michael Williams drives towards a small town called Red Rock West,after getting advised by a gas station worker to pay a visit to a bar in the town called Wayne's Place,where there is a good chance that Williams will be able to pick up a bar staff job. Finding Wayne Brown at the front of the bar,Michael decides to not reveal his full background details to Brown,when Wayne asks Williams if he is "The Lyle who has come here for a job?".Pretending to be Lyle,Williams expectations of being given a bar job by Brown are left in ruins,when Wayne reveals to him that "Lyle" has not been hired to work at the bar,but has in fact been chosen by Brown to be a hit-man for his wife. View on the film: Placing the dark heart of this Neo-Noir in a full to the brim whisky bottle,co-writer/ (along with his brother Rick) director John Dahl and cinematography Marc Reshovsky soak the film in a warm Neo-Noir Western atmosphere,with Dahl and Reshovsky shooting the movie in brilliant sun setting colours,which along with allowing every member of the cast face's to have a world weary quality about them,also allows Reschovsky and Dahl to show the dark secrets that all the residence of Red Rock West are desperately trying to keep out of the light. Continuing with the underlying Western theme in the excellent screenplay,John and Rick Dahl show the Wyoming town of Red Rock West to be a fading sun-lit Neo-Noir world,where everyone knows each others secrets and deals on how the town is run are made by secret drinks,and beer stained back-hander's,which is seriously threatened of being buckled,by the arrival of two "outlaws" from Texas,one being an unlucky soul who is at the wrong place,at the very worst time,and the other one being a black-clad wearing gunslinger,who wants to take the power of the town all for himself. Being given the chance to sizzle on the screen as this Neo-Noir's sole Femme Fatale,I was disappointed to find Lara Flynn Boyle give a rather frozen performance as Suzanne Brown,with Boyle failing to blend into John Dahl wonderful shadowy world,and also being unable to give the dialogue the fizzle that it richly deserves. Whilst Boyle sadly fails from setting the fuse off,the rest of the cast thankfully attack the movie with a burning hot,ten ton hammer,with J.T. Walsh giving an tremendous performance as Wayne Brown,thanks to Walsh showing Brown to go gradually more desperate for the killing of his wife to take place,and Walsh also taking full advantage of Dahl's stylish directing,by using the close ups to reveal the darkened lies and dirty deals that lay behind the scar's on Wayne's face. Entering this Neo-Noir like a fire breathing dragon,Dennis Hooper gives a fiery performance as the "real" Lyle,with Hooper showing Lyle's initially well meaning first appearance to be quickly slashed away and replaced by an outlaw whose only language is increasing the dirty money that is placed in his hands. Kept right at the centre for the whole of the film,Nicolas Cage gives an extremely strong performance,which carefully balances Michael Williams being a down to earth.down on his luck guy,with an increasing,potential deadly desire to get hold of the cash and the woman that are both just out of William's reach,which leads to Red Rock West being a gravel road that is defiantly worth travelling down.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    All Roads Lead To Intrigue.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    JohnRouseMerriottChard
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Red Rock West is directed by John Dahl who also co-wrote the screenplay with his brother Rick. It stars Nicolas Cage, Dennis Hopper, Lara Flynn Boyle, J. T. Walsh and Timothy Carhart. Music is by William Olvis and cinematography by Marc Reshovsky. When a promised job in Wyoming fails to materialise on account of an injury sustained in combat, Michael Williams (Cage) drifts into the town of Red Rock and is mistaken in a bar for a hit-man hired to kill an unfaithful wife. Tempted by the high cash on offer, Michael plays along and promptly finds himself in a web of intrigue from which escape is looking unlikely Welcome To Red Rock/You Are Now Leaving Red Rock. The studio didn't know what to do with it, a neo-noir flavoured with contemporary Western spices. Put out on cable in America and thriving on its limited release in Europe, it started to gain a cult fan-base. More so after a theatre in the Frisco Bay area started showing it and it made considerable coinage. Today it still remains more of a cult piece than anything else, which while it deserves more accolades and exposure, is still kind of nice for the fans, because it's like we have our own little neo-noir treasure all to ourselves. Red Rock West is essential for the neo-noir heads and well worthy of inspection by the average modern day crime film fan. Plot wise it's a bit, shall we say iffy? Yet the twists, turns and characterisations are so deftly constructed and performed, it matters not a jot. Cage's ex- marine is an honest and decent guy who whilst down on his luck - punished for his honesty - finds himself in a vortex of mystery and murder that he can't escape from. His companions in this scenario are film noir staples, the femme fatale (Boyle) with a smoulder as big as her secret, the hit-man (Hopper) with a glint in his eye to accompany his callous leanings, and the shifty bar owner (Walsh) trying to off his wife whilst keeping his shady cards close to his chest. As the tricksy plot unfolds in a haze of bad judgements and untruths, further pulsed by the vagaries of fate, it becomes apparent that Dahl wants us to know it isn't taking itself too seriously. There's a glorious scent of dark humour hanging in the air, an unpretentiousness about the whole thing that's refreshing. The look and feel is perfect for the narrative, the colour is stripped back to create a moody atmospheric surround, while the score and sound-tracking immediately brings to mind country and western tales of woe. Dahl knows his noir onions, but this is not just a homage hat tipper to the past, he understands what works in noir, be it the blending of the quirky with the edgy, or scene setting in locales such as a colourless bar and a foggy cemetery, Dahl gets the key ingredients right to deliver the goods wholesale. The small cast come up trumps. Boyle as Suzanne Brown is weak if her femme fatale is pitted against the likes of Matty Walker or Bridget Gregory, but it's an adequate performance that doesn't hinder the picture. She is helped enormously, though, by having to share most scenes with Cage who brings his "A" game. Consistently inconsistent throughout his career, Cage, when on form is a joy to watch, here he gets to thrive as a put upon hero, shifting seamlessly between confusion and boldness, where incredulous looks are the order of the day with a side order of eccentric intensity. Hopper does what he does so well, amusing villainy, while Walsh is effortlessly menacing and suspicious. In small secondary support Carhart and country star Dwight Yoakam leave favourable impressions. This is not an edge of your seat thriller, or a cranium bothering piece of dramedy, it's neo-noir done right. Where morality is grey at best and money is the root of all evil, it's slick, playful, cold blooded and absorbing. Hooray! 9/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Dial H for honesty
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    cmoyton
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/4/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    John Dahls opening salvo as director ranks among the best compared to his fellow contemporary directors. Sandwiched between Kill Me Again and The Last Seduction, Red Rock West was one of three "neo noirs" directed by Dahl who now finds himself marooned in TV land. It has a cast to die for and Nicholas Cage at the peak of his career. It is fantastic to see that the late J.T. Walsh is given a substantial role as bar owner/sheriff Wayne and shares as much screen time as Cage, Hopper and Boyle. Cage plays an out of work jobless drifter who in desperation pretends to be someone else to secure employment. Unfortunately the "job" requires him to murder the wife of a small town bar owner. Although he takes the money and runs from the town of Red Rock his own honesty sucks him back into the town into a shed load of trouble. Being in noir territory plot twists and deception abound. Denniis Hopper excels as hit-man Lyle. His acting is a joy to behold - all the usual Hopper mannerisms are present and the razor sharp dialogue flows from his lips in a unique style that no other actor is ever likely to replicate again. A true one off. Having said that the movies sharpest line is given to bit part actor Dwight Yoakam. My only beef is how they made sexy actress Lara Flynn Boyle look so frumpy in her rural cowgirl clothing but her acting is first class as usual. Of course there are the usual plot contrivances only found in movies in order to move the story along - the worst possibly being Cage being rescued by Hopper (the man he happens to be impersonating) just after he escapes the clutches of J.T. Walsh's crooked sheriff. I am always amazed at the blank expressions i receive when i name check this movie to others. Do yourself a favour and rent/buy this movie immediately.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Bizarre Love Quadriangle
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Raul Faust
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/10/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Well, "Red Rock West" isn't a very original or innovative film, since it repeats many of the western's clich&eacute;s from the eighties. Also, it may not have a great scenario or photography direction-- because of that, it seems to be much older than it actually is. However, the film is extremely entertaining; the story develops quickly, with an engaging and professional cast-- Nicolas Cage himself hasn't aged a day since this was released, he now looks exactly the same. The story has some interesting twists that help the film not become boring-- which is the worst element a film can have. See it without commitment and you'll have a good time.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Serpentine thriller
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Neil Welch
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/4/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    There are certain people who scream out to be typecast. Looing for a small-town bigwig with an air of corruption and a nasty streak? How about the late (and much lamented) JT Walsh? How about a contract killer with superficial charm and a centre of pure viciousness? Has to be the late (and even more lamented) Dennis Hopper. Penniless drifter with a hard luck story? Nicolas Cage, who else? Only femme fatale wife of small-town bigwig doesn't immediately scream Lara Flynn Boyle, but she does a perfectly adequate job in the role. Red Rock West is a noir movie, updated for modern audiences. The plot involves murder plots, opportunism, corruption, double-dealing, and assorted twists and turns, and is splendid fun. The performances are all dark, and all the principals get their teeth into the piece. Highly recommended, if you're in the mood for some dark fun.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    More twists and turns than a Chubby Checker concert.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    oneguyrambling
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/10/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Love him or hate him (and since he named his kid after Superman he's dropped a peg in my book), Nicolas Cage at least takes chances with his films. Sometimes this is disastrous and sometimes worthwhile, and realistically he hasn't appeared in a really good movie since "Adaptation" in 2002. But Cage ruled the 90's, in between the commercial stuff like Con Air, The Rock and Face/Off he continued taking chances with his choices with Wild At Heart and Leaving Las Vegas. Red Rock West was made in between his indie period of the late 80's and the blockbuster guy of the mid to late 90's, it's a pretty good movie but you can see why articles don't say things like "Nicolas Cage, of Leaving Las Vegas and Red Rock West fame." Strongly reminiscent of some of the Coen brothers early stuff, Red Rock West has more twists and turns than 12 garden variety whodunit thrillers combined. Cage stars as Michael, a man down to his last few dollars that is coming to an end of a long trek to start a new job on an oil drilling site, only due to a military service injury he is knocked back by the boss. So now he is still broke, out of fuel and disenchanted, Michael heads into the nearest town hoping to find work. A couple of early incidents show us he's an honest and ethical guy, the kind of guy that calls a woman "Ma'am". Now the next bit can be described, but after the movie is half over the plot becomes impossible to explain simply without major spoilers as reality changes from one minute to the next. So, Michael heads to the local pub and orders a coffee, the barman sees his car parked outside and because of the Texas license plate decides he is the man he is waiting for "Lyle from Texas". As the mistaken identity involves paid employment Michael goes along with the mistake, until he finds out that the job is to kill Wayne the barman's wife. Rather than straight out saying No Michael takes the cash and heads to Wayne's home. Somehow Michael happens upon the wife riding a horse to where she is having some hanky-panky with another farmhand, it's never really explained how he knew she would be there but who cares? Michael then goes to the house and waits for her return, when they meet he explains why he is there, and Suzanne (played by 25 kg Lara Flynn-Boyle) calmly counter offers Michael, at double the rate, to kill Wayne instead. Again Michael agrees, only this time he says enough and decides to "Lock it in Eddie", taking the cash with the sole intention of buggering off. Now in non-Hollywood this would be the end of it, but because a movie can't be over in 45 minutes we follow Michael as he leaves town in the rain. Here's where the twists get hectic, I'll summarise the next 15 minutes: - Michael hits someone in his car and takes them to the local hospital. (He's a nice guy remember?) - The Sheriff turns out to be the last person Michael needs to see, Wayne. - Wayne is a bit miffed at the perceived double cross and decides to off Michael. - Michael escapes, runs off and is picked up by Dennis Hopper, who is, you guessed it: Lyle from Texas! I can't explain much more without spoilers and confusion, only from here on in the remainder of the film revolves around Suzanne, Wayne, Michael and Lyle, and includes a myriad of twists and turns, deception, betrayal and double crossing galore. Everything a grown movie needs really. Wayne is played by JT Walsh, usually a bit player in other movies and I have always felt he is a bit over the top. Dennis Hopper is always ultra-hammy, and is almost cartoonish here. Lara Flynn-Boyle is surprisingly low key through most of the film, and has flawless skin regardless of the circumstances. Cage plays the troubled hero part to the hilt, he's the prototype for the nice guy in a situation that he wants to avoid but can't. The finale is in keeping with the rest of the film and is fairly satisfying. If I might digress momentarily, at one stage Michael walks into a bar and says "Give me a beer", now I have walked into many bars and know if I ever say that the bartender will say something along the lines of "Which one d**khead?" Since the dawn of time even the most low key bar stocks more than one brand, in fact most have literally dozens to choose from. Dunno why this bothers me but it does. If you're worried about the perception of product placement do what Tarantino does and make up a brand. Final Rating  7 / 10. "We twist. And turn. And twist and twist and turn. Twist, twist, twist. Turn, turn, turn. The Itchy and Scratchy Show." I mean Red Rock West. (That means it's a pretty good movie.) If you liked this review (or even if you didn't) check out oneguyrambling.com
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Another gem starring Cage that slipped under my radar
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    thekyles99
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/7/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Like i said in previous reviews, recently i have been going through Nic Cage's IMDb list of projects he has done to see if there was anything i hadn't seen that he's been in. And low and behold i found a bunch of em. So far out of three watched i liked 2 of em . 2-1 not a bad ratio so far. Just goes to show to show Nic Cage although one of the busiest actors is also careful of the scripts he chooses to work on. Red Rock West is another gem of his that must've slipped under my radar in 93. Great storyline however i found the ending a little on the cheesy side that being said it was a pretty good thriller. This time round Nic portrays Michael Williams a down and out Texan who resides in his car and tries to get jobs but fails to an injury he took while serving in the marines. Apon driving into a little town of red rock he enters the red rock tavern to see about a job and in a serious judgement error ends up taking a job that belonged to a professional hit-man (Dennis Hopper) needless to say all hell breaks loose and the moral of the story is number one money is never easy and number two...watch who's life you try to impersonate as the grass is always greener on the other side of the fence. Good casting featuring the late great Jt Walsh who was always a pleasure to watch work and a very underrated actor to say the least. Another great and recently passed Dennis Hopper portrays the hit-man that was originally intended for the hit but was a little later then mike at arriving to the bar. Dennis hopper in my books was awesome in portraying villains. Lara Flynn Boyle rounds off the cast with a less then believable performance as the sheriffs wife who the hit is to be delivered upon. Nic Cage's character in this spends the rest of the movie digging the hole he has made himself further and further. To get out is the question.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Enthralling criminal goings-on in a small Western town, as the lead is caught between a Red Rock and a hard place.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    johnnyboyz (j_l_h_m@yahoo.co.uk)
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/6/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    John Dahl's Red Rock West is a neat, taut, stripped down piece of cut-and-thrust film-making without gimmickry nor a single false string attached. In a current contemporary world of American film-making, and one that was almost certainly predominant at the time of Red Rock West's inception, how wonderful it is to uncover a film that refrains from the over indulgence of extravagance and the ideology that awe is built on a foundation of overkill and visuals. That's not to say Red Rock West is without extravagance nor awe, such is Dahl's ability, that the film is full of a number of various incidences and twists that are exactly these things and gotten across by way of little more than a glance from one of the character's or an individual cut of the camera. When we hark back to America's independent cinematic boom of the late 1980s and going on into the early 1990s, certainly a boom that saw a number of films and individual directors both honoured and recognised on the European film circuit at the top level in a series of Golden Palm nominations, the displaying of Red Rock West shows we must not glance over the name of Dahl when speaking of both the films and directors of that era, namely: the Coen Brothers; Steven Soderburgh; Spike Lee and Tarantino, et al. The film revolves around Nicolas Cage's character named Michael Williams, an ex-Marine of American nationality down on his luck and strapped for money in the dusty outback of Wyoming. He lives out of his car; uses random road side troughs full of water as makeshift sinks and struggles to find work, the latest failing being a construction site job that doesn't come through, although later on, he'll find ample opportunity at constructing something: a monstrosity of a scenario for himself. Unbeknownst to us at the time, he's going into the misadventure he'll come to have with a prior tragedy of having served time in the Vietnam War, but suffering during this stretch at the hands of a missile attack on a base in Lebanon he was positioned at which forced him into enduring a glut of both chaos and death. The event that may very well lend itself to Williams' dishevelled and down-beat tone and attitude, something Cage pulls off in that naturalistic manner he's done so on occasion since, shares eerie parallels with what will come to unfold around him as another glut of death and chaos unfolds around a man who has signed up for something you only realise you don't want to be anywhere near when it gets ugly as 'wrong place  wrong time' scenario once again kicks in. The devilish premise sees Williams pretend to be the Texan hit-man an apparent bar owner named Wayne (Walsh) called for some days ago so as to do some local dirty-work he wants taken care of. His looming over a seated Cage whilst in the office an early establishing of power, the sort of power that he'll come to have over him as Williams is forced throughout into proverbially dancing to the tune of others. But rather than eliminate the target, Wayne's wife played by Lara Flynn Boyle, Williams warns her of the predicament and that her marriage ought quite clearly be an item of concern form here on in. Once all is said and done, the real hit-man in Dennis Hopper's Lyle shows up in jet black Texan attire and similarly coloured car more resembling a hearse than anything else, whilst developments and complications in exactly who it is the chief of police is in the whole area open up. For Cage's character, and like in most good film noir when dealing with the down-trodden lead whom treads a fine line between right and wrong, the persistent idea of torn morals floats to the surface relatively quickly and consistently in Red Rock West. In just observing the premise, the notion of Williams illegally accepting the offer of being paid to kill someone before refraining from doing it when confronted with the innocent figure of Wayne's wife, Dahl highlights his character's soon-to-be prominent ever shifting; ever changing attitudes to what crime infused activity is playing out around him. Throughout, Williams lies; shoots; kills and steals but additionally saves; offers salvation and actually avoids violence on several occasions when straight forward murder would have offered a simple way out of a predicament. Given this, Dahl expertly manoeuvres Williams from one town in the form of Red Rock to another and then back over the border again, a sort of physical flitting from one place to another in what is a physical manifestation of both the above theories of a film noir's male lead as well as Cage's character's constantly ambiguous hopping from justified in his actions to not as so. Red Rock West moulds a fascinating, and quite terrifying at times, tale out of all these elements; combining a number of items such as double-crosses; multiple identities and intense connections characters have with one another, the sorts that they're forced into forging before later being asked what they truly mean to them. Dahl additionally, and in a very basic sense, taps into a certain idea of post-war disillusionment through his lead in Williams' disconnection from the rest of society seeing him inhabit a desolate and often incomprehensible rural locale in which he just about scrapes by. This, as an old war injury refrains him from making any true advancement in a chosen field of work. Red Rock West is a tight, gripping piece; the sort that arrives with a steady and effective eye on a variety of items all the while under the control of a steady, focused hand.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    western-noir at its near finest
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    MisterWhiplash
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/6/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    John Dahl knows his film-noir, and he knows his westerns. This should be assumed from seeing Red Rock West, though his 'noir' influence comes through in other films as well (Kill Me Again and to a degree Joy Ride). He knows how to write a lone average-Joe type of character, and the shady villain, and a sexy Femme Fatale. He knows this, but he also fills his story of a drifter coming to a small Wyoming town and being (accidentally?) hired to kill a man's wife with some top-shelf talent. Or, at least, the best actors that could make the parts their own. It's a cold little movie where you realize pretty quickly that despite Michael's "nice-guy" quality, he's still a potential thief and is the comparatively not so bad. Not so bad compared to Wayne the "bartender" or "Sheriff", if that is indeed his name, and his wife who wants to escape to Mexico with all of the money she "inherited" (please note the quotations). An extra slice of danger comes with the appearance of the actual man hired to kill the woman, Lyle from Dallas played by the late Dennis Hopper. His character and performance is far less aggressive than in Blue Velvet, though this is like comparing a Tasmanian Devil to a bull at a fight. I liked the suspense, of not knowing who might double-cross who next or where the story might go depending on who is alive, and I also liked that they gave each character something to them. Michael and Lyle meet up the first time under unusual circumstances and he gives Michael a ride, where they each find out they were marines, Michael formerly a fighter in a botched mission in Lebanon. This is mentioned about halfway into the film, but it helps to set up this guy as a somewhat tragic figure, without a home and without a job but all of those memories he'd rather not take with him. Certainly not to Mexico, where he has nice ones with his father. Again, the casting and the writing is what makes the film. Lara Flynn Boyle works just about perfect as the female figure of desire and greed, and even if we've seen something like her before she's still fresh because of her performance. JT Walsh is also good but in a different way, where he's a lot more careful with his words, but one can see the look of panic when it surely comes. And Nicolas Cage, at first seemingly a little bored with the part in the opening scenes, really makes it his own as a reluctant hero with nothing to lose. Dialog is used in the film only so much to keep things moving along, but I mean this as a compliment; it's not minimalism, but economy of speech if that makes sense. Dahl knows exactly what he wants in his B-movie premise, and it's like he's taken material sitting on a shelf for years and dusted it and made it vital again.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A lonesome drifter, low on money, finds himself suddenly in a deadly rat race for money.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Caged Cinema
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Red Rock West is a beautiful film. It is a film made by movie lovers, for movie lovers, with clearly lots of fun and enthusiasm. It is as much a film-noir as it is a western, a thriller or perhaps a black comedy. Set in middle-of-nowhere Wyoming the film starts with the masculine ex-marine Michael Williams (Cage), with his muscle car on the side of the road. He has almost no gas, only some peanuts as food, and little money. He is on his way to apply for a job at an oilfield. Seemingly a friend told him this job would be a definitive. Williams, however, doesn't get hired due to a war injury. Williams hits the road again, searching for a job in another place. He stops at a local gas station, where he wants to fill his tank and ask for advice. The gas station seems abandoned and at the cash register some cash is exposed This is one of the first in many moments where William's moral stance is put to the test. Steal the much needed money or leave it alone and stay broke? Luckily, Williams doesn't have to make a choice; the owner unexpectedly appears. Williams asks for gas and a place where he can find a job. "You can try Red Rock" says the man, while he fills the tank for five dollars the last of William's money. "Welcome to Red Rock" reads a somewhat unsettling- metal sign on the side of the road when Williams enters the town. It is a sign that he will encounter many more times, for it seems that leaving Red Rock isn't as easy as entering it. It is here where it all goes downhill He asks for a job in the local bar, which results in a strange twist of fate. The bartender (J.T. Marsh) thinks Williams is the killer he had hired to murder his cheating wife! The pay for it is big and Williams can't resist the temptation; he accepts the offer. Instead of killing the bartender's wife though, he explains her the whole situation, She, however doesn't seem impressed. She actually wants him to do the reverse and kill her husband for double the money! Williams, now full on cash, tries to avoid problems and take a leave from Red Rock, but by bad luck (or fate?), he keeps finding his way back to the diabolical town. When the real killer (a brilliant Dennis Hopper) shows up and the existence of even more money is discovered, Williams' search for money turns into a rat race, where lust, greed, obsession and violence are no exceptions. As you can read, Red Rock West is a dark film. Every character has its own secret agenda and even Williams'' moral is sometimes quite ambiguous. Although the film is quite funny sometimes, with enough irony and black humor, it is still one of the more serious films starring Nicolas Cage. Cage plays his character quite natural and even has few of his famous freak-outs. The atmosphere of this film is just brilliant. The film is well shot, the music is amazing (too bad I couldn't find it anywhere on the internet), the cast is great, the pace is fast and the plot is gripping. It has many great and exciting scenes and the way the thriller and western genres are combined is very entertaining. Still, somehow, the film never really delivers a form of profoundness, which more memorable and canonical films do provide. It is as if something is missing. Nonetheless, I think Red Rock West is an extremely underrated and overslept film. Don't expect a full blown masterpiece here. Rather expect a very good and entertaining thriller/western with a great role for Nicolas Cage. As Roger Ebert fittingly concluded his review of the film: "In a sense, we've been in Red Rock many times before: It's a town where plots lie in wait for unsuspecting visitors, where hatred runs deep, where love is never enough of a motive for doing anything when cash is available." And we love it there.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Wayne's Place.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    morrison-dylan-fan
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Taking a look at a poll that was held on the IMDb Classic Film board for the best movies of 1993,I found myself getting constantly drawn towards a Neo-Noir called Red Rock West,due to having heard a large amount of praise for the title over the year.Sadly,with the price of the DVD being pretty expensive,I regrettably decided to push any plans to take a look at this tantalising Neo-Noir to the side. 2 weeks later: Being happily caught completely by surprise,I recently received an offer from a very kind IMDb'er ,who asked if I would be interested in borrowing the DVD of the film,which led to me excitingly getting ready to pay a long over due visit to Red Rock West. The plot: Angered over getting turned down for a construction job due to having an injury which he picked up in the Vietnam war,Michael Williams drives towards a small town called Red Rock West,after getting advised by a gas station worker to pay a visit to a bar in the town called Wayne's Place,where there is a good chance that Williams will be able to pick up a bar staff job. Finding Wayne Brown at the front of the bar,Michael decides to not reveal his full background details to Brown,when Wayne asks Williams if he is "The Lyle who has come here for a job?".Pretending to be Lyle,Williams expectations of being given a bar job by Brown are left in ruins,when Wayne reveals to him that "Lyle" has not been hired to work at the bar,but has in fact been chosen by Brown to be a hit-man for his wife. View on the film: Placing the dark heart of this Neo-Noir in a full to the brim whisky bottle,co-writer/ (along with his brother Rick) director John Dahl and cinematography Marc Reshovsky soak the film in a warm Neo-Noir Western atmosphere,with Dahl and Reshovsky shooting the movie in brilliant sun setting colours,which along with allowing every member of the cast face's to have a world weary quality about them,also allows Reschovsky and Dahl to show the dark secrets that all the residence of Red Rock West are desperately trying to keep out of the light. Continuing with the underlying Western theme in the excellent screenplay,John and Rick Dahl show the Wyoming town of Red Rock West to be a fading sun-lit Neo-Noir world,where everyone knows each others secrets and deals on how the town is run are made by secret drinks,and beer stained back-hander's,which is seriously threatened of being buckled,by the arrival of two "outlaws" from Texas,one being an unlucky soul who is at the wrong place,at the very worst time,and the other one being a black-clad wearing gunslinger,who wants to take the power of the town all for himself. Being given the chance to sizzle on the screen as this Neo-Noir's sole Femme Fatale,I was disappointed to find Lara Flynn Boyle give a rather frozen performance as Suzanne Brown,with Boyle failing to blend into John Dahl wonderful shadowy world,and also being unable to give the dialogue the fizzle that it richly deserves. Whilst Boyle sadly fails from setting the fuse off,the rest of the cast thankfully attack the movie with a burning hot,ten ton hammer,with J.T. Walsh giving an tremendous performance as Wayne Brown,thanks to Walsh showing Brown to go gradually more desperate for the killing of his wife to take place,and Walsh also taking full advantage of Dahl's stylish directing,by using the close ups to reveal the darkened lies and dirty deals that lay behind the scar's on Wayne's face. Entering this Neo-Noir like a fire breathing dragon,Dennis Hooper gives a fiery performance as the "real" Lyle,with Hooper showing Lyle's initially well meaning first appearance to be quickly slashed away and replaced by an outlaw whose only language is increasing the dirty money that is placed in his hands. Kept right at the centre for the whole of the film,Nicolas Cage gives an extremely strong performance,which carefully balances Michael Williams being a down to earth.down on his luck guy,with an increasing,potential deadly desire to get hold of the cash and the woman that are both just out of William's reach,which leads to Red Rock West being a gravel road that is defiantly worth travelling down.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    All Roads Lead To Intrigue.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    JohnRouseMerriottChard
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Red Rock West is directed by John Dahl who also co-wrote the screenplay with his brother Rick. It stars Nicolas Cage, Dennis Hopper, Lara Flynn Boyle, J. T. Walsh and Timothy Carhart. Music is by William Olvis and cinematography by Marc Reshovsky. When a promised job in Wyoming fails to materialise on account of an injury sustained in combat, Michael Williams (Cage) drifts into the town of Red Rock and is mistaken in a bar for a hit-man hired to kill an unfaithful wife. Tempted by the high cash on offer, Michael plays along and promptly finds himself in a web of intrigue from which escape is looking unlikely Welcome To Red Rock/You Are Now Leaving Red Rock. The studio didn't know what to do with it, a neo-noir flavoured with contemporary Western spices. Put out on cable in America and thriving on its limited release in Europe, it started to gain a cult fan-base. More so after a theatre in the Frisco Bay area started showing it and it made considerable coinage. Today it still remains more of a cult piece than anything else, which while it deserves more accolades and exposure, is still kind of nice for the fans, because it's like we have our own little neo-noir treasure all to ourselves. Red Rock West is essential for the neo-noir heads and well worthy of inspection by the average modern day crime film fan. Plot wise it's a bit, shall we say iffy? Yet the twists, turns and characterisations are so deftly constructed and performed, it matters not a jot. Cage's ex- marine is an honest and decent guy who whilst down on his luck - punished for his honesty - finds himself in a vortex of mystery and murder that he can't escape from. His companions in this scenario are film noir staples, the femme fatale (Boyle) with a smoulder as big as her secret, the hit-man (Hopper) with a glint in his eye to accompany his callous leanings, and the shifty bar owner (Walsh) trying to off his wife whilst keeping his shady cards close to his chest. As the tricksy plot unfolds in a haze of bad judgements and untruths, further pulsed by the vagaries of fate, it becomes apparent that Dahl wants us to know it isn't taking itself too seriously. There's a glorious scent of dark humour hanging in the air, an unpretentiousness about the whole thing that's refreshing. The look and feel is perfect for the narrative, the colour is stripped back to create a moody atmospheric surround, while the score and sound-tracking immediately brings to mind country and western tales of woe. Dahl knows his noir onions, but this is not just a homage hat tipper to the past, he understands what works in noir, be it the blending of the quirky with the edgy, or scene setting in locales such as a colourless bar and a foggy cemetery, Dahl gets the key ingredients right to deliver the goods wholesale. The small cast come up trumps. Boyle as Suzanne Brown is weak if her femme fatale is pitted against the likes of Matty Walker or Bridget Gregory, but it's an adequate performance that doesn't hinder the picture. She is helped enormously, though, by having to share most scenes with Cage who brings his "A" game. Consistently inconsistent throughout his career, Cage, when on form is a joy to watch, here he gets to thrive as a put upon hero, shifting seamlessly between confusion and boldness, where incredulous looks are the order of the day with a side order of eccentric intensity. Hopper does what he does so well, amusing villainy, while Walsh is effortlessly menacing and suspicious. In small secondary support Carhart and country star Dwight Yoakam leave favourable impressions. This is not an edge of your seat thriller, or a cranium bothering piece of dramedy, it's neo-noir done right. Where morality is grey at best and money is the root of all evil, it's slick, playful, cold blooded and absorbing. Hooray! 9/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Dial H for honesty
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    cmoyton
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/4/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    John Dahls opening salvo as director ranks among the best compared to his fellow contemporary directors. Sandwiched between Kill Me Again and The Last Seduction, Red Rock West was one of three "neo noirs" directed by Dahl who now finds himself marooned in TV land. It has a cast to die for and Nicholas Cage at the peak of his career. It is fantastic to see that the late J.T. Walsh is given a substantial role as bar owner/sheriff Wayne and shares as much screen time as Cage, Hopper and Boyle. Cage plays an out of work jobless drifter who in desperation pretends to be someone else to secure employment. Unfortunately the "job" requires him to murder the wife of a small town bar owner. Although he takes the money and runs from the town of Red Rock his own honesty sucks him back into the town into a shed load of trouble. Being in noir territory plot twists and deception abound. Denniis Hopper excels as hit-man Lyle. His acting is a joy to behold - all the usual Hopper mannerisms are present and the razor sharp dialogue flows from his lips in a unique style that no other actor is ever likely to replicate again. A true one off. Having said that the movies sharpest line is given to bit part actor Dwight Yoakam. My only beef is how they made sexy actress Lara Flynn Boyle look so frumpy in her rural cowgirl clothing but her acting is first class as usual. Of course there are the usual plot contrivances only found in movies in order to move the story along - the worst possibly being Cage being rescued by Hopper (the man he happens to be impersonating) just after he escapes the clutches of J.T. Walsh's crooked sheriff. I am always amazed at the blank expressions i receive when i name check this movie to others. Do yourself a favour and rent/buy this movie immediately.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Bizarre Love Quadriangle
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Raul Faust
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/10/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Well, "Red Rock West" isn't a very original or innovative film, since it repeats many of the western's clich&eacute;s from the eighties. Also, it may not have a great scenario or photography direction-- because of that, it seems to be much older than it actually is. However, the film is extremely entertaining; the story develops quickly, with an engaging and professional cast-- Nicolas Cage himself hasn't aged a day since this was released, he now looks exactly the same. The story has some interesting twists that help the film not become boring-- which is the worst element a film can have. See it without commitment and you'll have a good time.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Serpentine thriller
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Neil Welch
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/4/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    There are certain people who scream out to be typecast. Looing for a small-town bigwig with an air of corruption and a nasty streak? How about the late (and much lamented) JT Walsh? How about a contract killer with superficial charm and a centre of pure viciousness? Has to be the late (and even more lamented) Dennis Hopper. Penniless drifter with a hard luck story? Nicolas Cage, who else? Only femme fatale wife of small-town bigwig doesn't immediately scream Lara Flynn Boyle, but she does a perfectly adequate job in the role. Red Rock West is a noir movie, updated for modern audiences. The plot involves murder plots, opportunism, corruption, double-dealing, and assorted twists and turns, and is splendid fun. The performances are all dark, and all the principals get their teeth into the piece. Highly recommended, if you're in the mood for some dark fun.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    More twists and turns than a Chubby Checker concert.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    oneguyrambling
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/10/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Love him or hate him (and since he named his kid after Superman he's dropped a peg in my book), Nicolas Cage at least takes chances with his films. Sometimes this is disastrous and sometimes worthwhile, and realistically he hasn't appeared in a really good movie since "Adaptation" in 2002. But Cage ruled the 90's, in between the commercial stuff like Con Air, The Rock and Face/Off he continued taking chances with his choices with Wild At Heart and Leaving Las Vegas. Red Rock West was made in between his indie period of the late 80's and the blockbuster guy of the mid to late 90's, it's a pretty good movie but you can see why articles don't say things like "Nicolas Cage, of Leaving Las Vegas and Red Rock West fame." Strongly reminiscent of some of the Coen brothers early stuff, Red Rock West has more twists and turns than 12 garden variety whodunit thrillers combined. Cage stars as Michael, a man down to his last few dollars that is coming to an end of a long trek to start a new job on an oil drilling site, only due to a military service injury he is knocked back by the boss. So now he is still broke, out of fuel and disenchanted, Michael heads into the nearest town hoping to find work. A couple of early incidents show us he's an honest and ethical guy, the kind of guy that calls a woman "Ma'am". Now the next bit can be described, but after the movie is half over the plot becomes impossible to explain simply without major spoilers as reality changes from one minute to the next. So, Michael heads to the local pub and orders a coffee, the barman sees his car parked outside and because of the Texas license plate decides he is the man he is waiting for "Lyle from Texas". As the mistaken identity involves paid employment Michael goes along with the mistake, until he finds out that the job is to kill Wayne the barman's wife. Rather than straight out saying No Michael takes the cash and heads to Wayne's home. Somehow Michael happens upon the wife riding a horse to where she is having some hanky-panky with another farmhand, it's never really explained how he knew she would be there but who cares? Michael then goes to the house and waits for her return, when they meet he explains why he is there, and Suzanne (played by 25 kg Lara Flynn-Boyle) calmly counter offers Michael, at double the rate, to kill Wayne instead. Again Michael agrees, only this time he says enough and decides to "Lock it in Eddie", taking the cash with the sole intention of buggering off. Now in non-Hollywood this would be the end of it, but because a movie can't be over in 45 minutes we follow Michael as he leaves town in the rain. Here's where the twists get hectic, I'll summarise the next 15 minutes: - Michael hits someone in his car and takes them to the local hospital. (He's a nice guy remember?) - The Sheriff turns out to be the last person Michael needs to see, Wayne. - Wayne is a bit miffed at the perceived double cross and decides to off Michael. - Michael escapes, runs off and is picked up by Dennis Hopper, who is, you guessed it: Lyle from Texas! I can't explain much more without spoilers and confusion, only from here on in the remainder of the film revolves around Suzanne, Wayne, Michael and Lyle, and includes a myriad of twists and turns, deception, betrayal and double crossing galore. Everything a grown movie needs really. Wayne is played by JT Walsh, usually a bit player in other movies and I have always felt he is a bit over the top. Dennis Hopper is always ultra-hammy, and is almost cartoonish here. Lara Flynn-Boyle is surprisingly low key through most of the film, and has flawless skin regardless of the circumstances. Cage plays the troubled hero part to the hilt, he's the prototype for the nice guy in a situation that he wants to avoid but can't. The finale is in keeping with the rest of the film and is fairly satisfying. If I might digress momentarily, at one stage Michael walks into a bar and says "Give me a beer", now I have walked into many bars and know if I ever say that the bartender will say something along the lines of "Which one d**khead?" Since the dawn of time even the most low key bar stocks more than one brand, in fact most have literally dozens to choose from. Dunno why this bothers me but it does. If you're worried about the perception of product placement do what Tarantino does and make up a brand. Final Rating  7 / 10. "We twist. And turn. And twist and twist and turn. Twist, twist, twist. Turn, turn, turn. The Itchy and Scratchy Show." I mean Red Rock West. (That means it's a pretty good movie.) If you liked this review (or even if you didn't) check out oneguyrambling.com
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Another gem starring Cage that slipped under my radar
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    thekyles99
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/7/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Like i said in previous reviews, recently i have been going through Nic Cage's IMDb list of projects he has done to see if there was anything i hadn't seen that he's been in. And low and behold i found a bunch of em. So far out of three watched i liked 2 of em . 2-1 not a bad ratio so far. Just goes to show to show Nic Cage although one of the busiest actors is also careful of the scripts he chooses to work on. Red Rock West is another gem of his that must've slipped under my radar in 93. Great storyline however i found the ending a little on the cheesy side that being said it was a pretty good thriller. This time round Nic portrays Michael Williams a down and out Texan who resides in his car and tries to get jobs but fails to an injury he took while serving in the marines. Apon driving into a little town of red rock he enters the red rock tavern to see about a job and in a serious judgement error ends up taking a job that belonged to a professional hit-man (Dennis Hopper) needless to say all hell breaks loose and the moral of the story is number one money is never easy and number two...watch who's life you try to impersonate as the grass is always greener on the other side of the fence. Good casting featuring the late great Jt Walsh who was always a pleasure to watch work and a very underrated actor to say the least. Another great and recently passed Dennis Hopper portrays the hit-man that was originally intended for the hit but was a little later then mike at arriving to the bar. Dennis hopper in my books was awesome in portraying villains. Lara Flynn Boyle rounds off the cast with a less then believable performance as the sheriffs wife who the hit is to be delivered upon. Nic Cage's character in this spends the rest of the movie digging the hole he has made himself further and further. To get out is the question.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Enthralling criminal goings-on in a small Western town, as the lead is caught between a Red Rock and a hard place.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    johnnyboyz (j_l_h_m@yahoo.co.uk)
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/6/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    John Dahl's Red Rock West is a neat, taut, stripped down piece of cut-and-thrust film-making without gimmickry nor a single false string attached. In a current contemporary world of American film-making, and one that was almost certainly predominant at the time of Red Rock West's inception, how wonderful it is to uncover a film that refrains from the over indulgence of extravagance and the ideology that awe is built on a foundation of overkill and visuals. That's not to say Red Rock West is without extravagance nor awe, such is Dahl's ability, that the film is full of a number of various incidences and twists that are exactly these things and gotten across by way of little more than a glance from one of the character's or an individual cut of the camera. When we hark back to America's independent cinematic boom of the late 1980s and going on into the early 1990s, certainly a boom that saw a number of films and individual directors both honoured and recognised on the European film circuit at the top level in a series of Golden Palm nominations, the displaying of Red Rock West shows we must not glance over the name of Dahl when speaking of both the films and directors of that era, namely: the Coen Brothers; Steven Soderburgh; Spike Lee and Tarantino, et al. The film revolves around Nicolas Cage's character named Michael Williams, an ex-Marine of American nationality down on his luck and strapped for money in the dusty outback of Wyoming. He lives out of his car; uses random road side troughs full of water as makeshift sinks and struggles to find work, the latest failing being a construction site job that doesn't come through, although later on, he'll find ample opportunity at constructing something: a monstrosity of a scenario for himself. Unbeknownst to us at the time, he's going into the misadventure he'll come to have with a prior tragedy of having served time in the Vietnam War, but suffering during this stretch at the hands of a missile attack on a base in Lebanon he was positioned at which forced him into enduring a glut of both chaos and death. The event that may very well lend itself to Williams' dishevelled and down-beat tone and attitude, something Cage pulls off in that naturalistic manner he's done so on occasion since, shares eerie parallels with what will come to unfold around him as another glut of death and chaos unfolds around a man who has signed up for something you only realise you don't want to be anywhere near when it gets ugly as 'wrong place  wrong time' scenario once again kicks in. The devilish premise sees Williams pretend to be the Texan hit-man an apparent bar owner named Wayne (Walsh) called for some days ago so as to do some local dirty-work he wants taken care of. His looming over a seated Cage whilst in the office an early establishing of power, the sort of power that he'll come to have over him as Williams is forced throughout into proverbially dancing to the tune of others. But rather than eliminate the target, Wayne's wife played by Lara Flynn Boyle, Williams warns her of the predicament and that her marriage ought quite clearly be an item of concern form here on in. Once all is said and done, the real hit-man in Dennis Hopper's Lyle shows up in jet black Texan attire and similarly coloured car more resembling a hearse than anything else, whilst developments and complications in exactly who it is the chief of police is in the whole area open up. For Cage's character, and like in most good film noir when dealing with the down-trodden lead whom treads a fine line between right and wrong, the persistent idea of torn morals floats to the surface relatively quickly and consistently in Red Rock West. In just observing the premise, the notion of Williams illegally accepting the offer of being paid to kill someone before refraining from doing it when confronted with the innocent figure of Wayne's wife, Dahl highlights his character's soon-to-be prominent ever shifting; ever changing attitudes to what crime infused activity is playing out around him. Throughout, Williams lies; shoots; kills and steals but additionally saves; offers salvation and actually avoids violence on several occasions when straight forward murder would have offered a simple way out of a predicament. Given this, Dahl expertly manoeuvres Williams from one town in the form of Red Rock to another and then back over the border again, a sort of physical flitting from one place to another in what is a physical manifestation of both the above theories of a film noir's male lead as well as Cage's character's constantly ambiguous hopping from justified in his actions to not as so. Red Rock West moulds a fascinating, and quite terrifying at times, tale out of all these elements; combining a number of items such as double-crosses; multiple identities and intense connections characters have with one another, the sorts that they're forced into forging before later being asked what they truly mean to them. Dahl additionally, and in a very basic sense, taps into a certain idea of post-war disillusionment through his lead in Williams' disconnection from the rest of society seeing him inhabit a desolate and often incomprehensible rural locale in which he just about scrapes by. This, as an old war injury refrains him from making any true advancement in a chosen field of work. Red Rock West is a tight, gripping piece; the sort that arrives with a steady and effective eye on a variety of items all the while under the control of a steady, focused hand.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    western-noir at its near finest
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    MisterWhiplash
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/6/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    John Dahl knows his film-noir, and he knows his westerns. This should be assumed from seeing Red Rock West, though his 'noir' influence comes through in other films as well (Kill Me Again and to a degree Joy Ride). He knows how to write a lone average-Joe type of character, and the shady villain, and a sexy Femme Fatale. He knows this, but he also fills his story of a drifter coming to a small Wyoming town and being (accidentally?) hired to kill a man's wife with some top-shelf talent. Or, at least, the best actors that could make the parts their own. It's a cold little movie where you realize pretty quickly that despite Michael's "nice-guy" quality, he's still a potential thief and is the comparatively not so bad. Not so bad compared to Wayne the "bartender" or "Sheriff", if that is indeed his name, and his wife who wants to escape to Mexico with all of the money she "inherited" (please note the quotations). An extra slice of danger comes with the appearance of the actual man hired to kill the woman, Lyle from Dallas played by the late Dennis Hopper. His character and performance is far less aggressive than in Blue Velvet, though this is like comparing a Tasmanian Devil to a bull at a fight. I liked the suspense, of not knowing who might double-cross who next or where the story might go depending on who is alive, and I also liked that they gave each character something to them. Michael and Lyle meet up the first time under unusual circumstances and he gives Michael a ride, where they each find out they were marines, Michael formerly a fighter in a botched mission in Lebanon. This is mentioned about halfway into the film, but it helps to set up this guy as a somewhat tragic figure, without a home and without a job but all of those memories he'd rather not take with him. Certainly not to Mexico, where he has nice ones with his father. Again, the casting and the writing is what makes the film. Lara Flynn Boyle works just about perfect as the female figure of desire and greed, and even if we've seen something like her before she's still fresh because of her performance. JT Walsh is also good but in a different way, where he's a lot more careful with his words, but one can see the look of panic when it surely comes. And Nicolas Cage, at first seemingly a little bored with the part in the opening scenes, really makes it his own as a reluctant hero with nothing to lose. Dialog is used in the film only so much to keep things moving along, but I mean this as a compliment; it's not minimalism, but economy of speech if that makes sense. Dahl knows exactly what he wants in his B-movie premise, and it's like he's taken material sitting on a shelf for years and dusted it and made it vital again.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A lonesome drifter, low on money, finds himself suddenly in a deadly rat race for money.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Caged Cinema
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Red Rock West is a beautiful film. It is a film made by movie lovers, for movie lovers, with clearly lots of fun and enthusiasm. It is as much a film-noir as it is a western, a thriller or perhaps a black comedy. Set in middle-of-nowhere Wyoming the film starts with the masculine ex-marine Michael Williams (Cage), with his muscle car on the side of the road. He has almost no gas, only some peanuts as food, and little money. He is on his way to apply for a job at an oilfield. Seemingly a friend told him this job would be a definitive. Williams, however, doesn't get hired due to a war injury. Williams hits the road again, searching for a job in another place. He stops at a local gas station, where he wants to fill his tank and ask for advice. The gas station seems abandoned and at the cash register some cash is exposed This is one of the first in many moments where William's moral stance is put to the test. Steal the much needed money or leave it alone and stay broke? Luckily, Williams doesn't have to make a choice; the owner unexpectedly appears. Williams asks for gas and a place where he can find a job. "You can try Red Rock" says the man, while he fills the tank for five dollars the last of William's money. "Welcome to Red Rock" reads a somewhat unsettling- metal sign on the side of the road when Williams enters the town. It is a sign that he will encounter many more times, for it seems that leaving Red Rock isn't as easy as entering it. It is here where it all goes downhill He asks for a job in the local bar, which results in a strange twist of fate. The bartender (J.T. Marsh) thinks Williams is the killer he had hired to murder his cheating wife! The pay for it is big and Williams can't resist the temptation; he accepts the offer. Instead of killing the bartender's wife though, he explains her the whole situation, She, however doesn't seem impressed. She actually wants him to do the reverse and kill her husband for double the money! Williams, now full on cash, tries to avoid problems and take a leave from Red Rock, but by bad luck (or fate?), he keeps finding his way back to the diabolical town. When the real killer (a brilliant Dennis Hopper) shows up and the existence of even more money is discovered, Williams' search for money turns into a rat race, where lust, greed, obsession and violence are no exceptions. As you can read, Red Rock West is a dark film. Every character has its own secret agenda and even Williams'' moral is sometimes quite ambiguous. Although the film is quite funny sometimes, with enough irony and black humor, it is still one of the more serious films starring Nicolas Cage. Cage plays his character quite natural and even has few of his famous freak-outs. The atmosphere of this film is just brilliant. The film is well shot, the music is amazing (too bad I couldn't find it anywhere on the internet), the cast is great, the pace is fast and the plot is gripping. It has many great and exciting scenes and the way the thriller and western genres are combined is very entertaining. Still, somehow, the film never really delivers a form of profoundness, which more memorable and canonical films do provide. It is as if something is missing. Nonetheless, I think Red Rock West is an extremely underrated and overslept film. Don't expect a full blown masterpiece here. Rather expect a very good and entertaining thriller/western with a great role for Nicolas Cage. As Roger Ebert fittingly concluded his review of the film: "In a sense, we've been in Red Rock many times before: It's a town where plots lie in wait for unsuspecting visitors, where hatred runs deep, where love is never enough of a motive for doing anything when cash is available." And we love it there.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Wayne's Place.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    morrison-dylan-fan
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Taking a look at a poll that was held on the IMDb Classic Film board for the best movies of 1993,I found myself getting constantly drawn towards a Neo-Noir called Red Rock West,due to having heard a large amount of praise for the title over the year.Sadly,with the price of the DVD being pretty expensive,I regrettably decided to push any plans to take a look at this tantalising Neo-Noir to the side. 2 weeks later: Being happily caught completely by surprise,I recently received an offer from a very kind IMDb'er ,who asked if I would be interested in borrowing the DVD of the film,which led to me excitingly getting ready to pay a long over due visit to Red Rock West. The plot: Angered over getting turned down for a construction job due to having an injury which he picked up in the Vietnam war,Michael Williams drives towards a small town called Red Rock West,after getting advised by a gas station worker to pay a visit to a bar in the town called Wayne's Place,where there is a good chance that Williams will be able to pick up a bar staff job. Finding Wayne Brown at the front of the bar,Michael decides to not reveal his full background details to Brown,when Wayne asks Williams if he is "The Lyle who has come here for a job?".Pretending to be Lyle,Williams expectations of being given a bar job by Brown are left in ruins,when Wayne reveals to him that "Lyle" has not been hired to work at the bar,but has in fact been chosen by Brown to be a hit-man for his wife. View on the film: Placing the dark heart of this Neo-Noir in a full to the brim whisky bottle,co-writer/ (along with his brother Rick) director John Dahl and cinematography Marc Reshovsky soak the film in a warm Neo-Noir Western atmosphere,with Dahl and Reshovsky shooting the movie in brilliant sun setting colours,which along with allowing every member of the cast face's to have a world weary quality about them,also allows Reschovsky and Dahl to show the dark secrets that all the residence of Red Rock West are desperately trying to keep out of the light. Continuing with the underlying Western theme in the excellent screenplay,John and Rick Dahl show the Wyoming town of Red Rock West to be a fading sun-lit Neo-Noir world,where everyone knows each others secrets and deals on how the town is run are made by secret drinks,and beer stained back-hander's,which is seriously threatened of being buckled,by the arrival of two "outlaws" from Texas,one being an unlucky soul who is at the wrong place,at the very worst time,and the other one being a black-clad wearing gunslinger,who wants to take the power of the town all for himself. Being given the chance to sizzle on the screen as this Neo-Noir's sole Femme Fatale,I was disappointed to find Lara Flynn Boyle give a rather frozen performance as Suzanne Brown,with Boyle failing to blend into John Dahl wonderful shadowy world,and also being unable to give the dialogue the fizzle that it richly deserves. Whilst Boyle sadly fails from setting the fuse off,the rest of the cast thankfully attack the movie with a burning hot,ten ton hammer,with J.T. Walsh giving an tremendous performance as Wayne Brown,thanks to Walsh showing Brown to go gradually more desperate for the killing of his wife to take place,and Walsh also taking full advantage of Dahl's stylish directing,by using the close ups to reveal the darkened lies and dirty deals that lay behind the scar's on Wayne's face. Entering this Neo-Noir like a fire breathing dragon,Dennis Hooper gives a fiery performance as the "real" Lyle,with Hooper showing Lyle's initially well meaning first appearance to be quickly slashed away and replaced by an outlaw whose only language is increasing the dirty money that is placed in his hands. Kept right at the centre for the whole of the film,Nicolas Cage gives an extremely strong performance,which carefully balances Michael Williams being a down to earth.down on his luck guy,with an increasing,potential deadly desire to get hold of the cash and the woman that are both just out of William's reach,which leads to Red Rock West being a gravel road that is defiantly worth travelling down.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    All Roads Lead To Intrigue.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    JohnRouseMerriottChard
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Red Rock West is directed by John Dahl who also co-wrote the screenplay with his brother Rick. It stars Nicolas Cage, Dennis Hopper, Lara Flynn Boyle, J. T. Walsh and Timothy Carhart. Music is by William Olvis and cinematography by Marc Reshovsky. When a promised job in Wyoming fails to materialise on account of an injury sustained in combat, Michael Williams (Cage) drifts into the town of Red Rock and is mistaken in a bar for a hit-man hired to kill an unfaithful wife. Tempted by the high cash on offer, Michael plays along and promptly finds himself in a web of intrigue from which escape is looking unlikely Welcome To Red Rock/You Are Now Leaving Red Rock. The studio didn't know what to do with it, a neo-noir flavoured with contemporary Western spices. Put out on cable in America and thriving on its limited release in Europe, it started to gain a cult fan-base. More so after a theatre in the Frisco Bay area started showing it and it made considerable coinage. Today it still remains more of a cult piece than anything else, which while it deserves more accolades and exposure, is still kind of nice for the fans, because it's like we have our own little neo-noir treasure all to ourselves. Red Rock West is essential for the neo-noir heads and well worthy of inspection by the average modern day crime film fan. Plot wise it's a bit, shall we say iffy? Yet the twists, turns and characterisations are so deftly constructed and performed, it matters not a jot. Cage's ex- marine is an honest and decent guy who whilst down on his luck - punished for his honesty - finds himself in a vortex of mystery and murder that he can't escape from. His companions in this scenario are film noir staples, the femme fatale (Boyle) with a smoulder as big as her secret, the hit-man (Hopper) with a glint in his eye to accompany his callous leanings, and the shifty bar owner (Walsh) trying to off his wife whilst keeping his shady cards close to his chest. As the tricksy plot unfolds in a haze of bad judgements and untruths, further pulsed by the vagaries of fate, it becomes apparent that Dahl wants us to know it isn't taking itself too seriously. There's a glorious scent of dark humour hanging in the air, an unpretentiousness about the whole thing that's refreshing. The look and feel is perfect for the narrative, the colour is stripped back to create a moody atmospheric surround, while the score and sound-tracking immediately brings to mind country and western tales of woe. Dahl knows his noir onions, but this is not just a homage hat tipper to the past, he understands what works in noir, be it the blending of the quirky with the edgy, or scene setting in locales such as a colourless bar and a foggy cemetery, Dahl gets the key ingredients right to deliver the goods wholesale. The small cast come up trumps. Boyle as Suzanne Brown is weak if her femme fatale is pitted against the likes of Matty Walker or Bridget Gregory, but it's an adequate performance that doesn't hinder the picture. She is helped enormously, though, by having to share most scenes with Cage who brings his "A" game. Consistently inconsistent throughout his career, Cage, when on form is a joy to watch, here he gets to thrive as a put upon hero, shifting seamlessly between confusion and boldness, where incredulous looks are the order of the day with a side order of eccentric intensity. Hopper does what he does so well, amusing villainy, while Walsh is effortlessly menacing and suspicious. In small secondary support Carhart and country star Dwight Yoakam leave favourable impressions. This is not an edge of your seat thriller, or a cranium bothering piece of dramedy, it's neo-noir done right. Where morality is grey at best and money is the root of all evil, it's slick, playful, cold blooded and absorbing. Hooray! 9/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Dial H for honesty
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    cmoyton
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/4/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    John Dahls opening salvo as director ranks among the best compared to his fellow contemporary directors. Sandwiched between Kill Me Again and The Last Seduction, Red Rock West was one of three "neo noirs" directed by Dahl who now finds himself marooned in TV land. It has a cast to die for and Nicholas Cage at the peak of his career. It is fantastic to see that the late J.T. Walsh is given a substantial role as bar owner/sheriff Wayne and shares as much screen time as Cage, Hopper and Boyle. Cage plays an out of work jobless drifter who in desperation pretends to be someone else to secure employment. Unfortunately the "job" requires him to murder the wife of a small town bar owner. Although he takes the money and runs from the town of Red Rock his own honesty sucks him back into the town into a shed load of trouble. Being in noir territory plot twists and deception abound. Denniis Hopper excels as hit-man Lyle. His acting is a joy to behold - all the usual Hopper mannerisms are present and the razor sharp dialogue flows from his lips in a unique style that no other actor is ever likely to replicate again. A true one off. Having said that the movies sharpest line is given to bit part actor Dwight Yoakam. My only beef is how they made sexy actress Lara Flynn Boyle look so frumpy in her rural cowgirl clothing but her acting is first class as usual. Of course there are the usual plot contrivances only found in movies in order to move the story along - the worst possibly being Cage being rescued by Hopper (the man he happens to be impersonating) just after he escapes the clutches of J.T. Walsh's crooked sheriff. I am always amazed at the blank expressions i receive when i name check this movie to others. Do yourself a favour and rent/buy this movie immediately.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Bizarre Love Quadriangle
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Raul Faust
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/10/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Well, "Red Rock West" isn't a very original or innovative film, since it repeats many of the western's clich&eacute;s from the eighties. Also, it may not have a great scenario or photography direction-- because of that, it seems to be much older than it actually is. However, the film is extremely entertaining; the story develops quickly, with an engaging and professional cast-- Nicolas Cage himself hasn't aged a day since this was released, he now looks exactly the same. The story has some interesting twists that help the film not become boring-- which is the worst element a film can have. See it without commitment and you'll have a good time.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Serpentine thriller
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Neil Welch
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/4/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    There are certain people who scream out to be typecast. Looing for a small-town bigwig with an air of corruption and a nasty streak? How about the late (and much lamented) JT Walsh? How about a contract killer with superficial charm and a centre of pure viciousness? Has to be the late (and even more lamented) Dennis Hopper. Penniless drifter with a hard luck story? Nicolas Cage, who else? Only femme fatale wife of small-town bigwig doesn't immediately scream Lara Flynn Boyle, but she does a perfectly adequate job in the role. Red Rock West is a noir movie, updated for modern audiences. The plot involves murder plots, opportunism, corruption, double-dealing, and assorted twists and turns, and is splendid fun. The performances are all dark, and all the principals get their teeth into the piece. Highly recommended, if you're in the mood for some dark fun.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    More twists and turns than a Chubby Checker concert.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    oneguyrambling
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/10/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Love him or hate him (and since he named his kid after Superman he's dropped a peg in my book), Nicolas Cage at least takes chances with his films. Sometimes this is disastrous and sometimes worthwhile, and realistically he hasn't appeared in a really good movie since "Adaptation" in 2002. But Cage ruled the 90's, in between the commercial stuff like Con Air, The Rock and Face/Off he continued taking chances with his choices with Wild At Heart and Leaving Las Vegas. Red Rock West was made in between his indie period of the late 80's and the blockbuster guy of the mid to late 90's, it's a pretty good movie but you can see why articles don't say things like "Nicolas Cage, of Leaving Las Vegas and Red Rock West fame." Strongly reminiscent of some of the Coen brothers early stuff, Red Rock West has more twists and turns than 12 garden variety whodunit thrillers combined. Cage stars as Michael, a man down to his last few dollars that is coming to an end of a long trek to start a new job on an oil drilling site, only due to a military service injury he is knocked back by the boss. So now he is still broke, out of fuel and disenchanted, Michael heads into the nearest town hoping to find work. A couple of early incidents show us he's an honest and ethical guy, the kind of guy that calls a woman "Ma'am". Now the next bit can be described, but after the movie is half over the plot becomes impossible to explain simply without major spoilers as reality changes from one minute to the next. So, Michael heads to the local pub and orders a coffee, the barman sees his car parked outside and because of the Texas license plate decides he is the man he is waiting for "Lyle from Texas". As the mistaken identity involves paid employment Michael goes along with the mistake, until he finds out that the job is to kill Wayne the barman's wife. Rather than straight out saying No Michael takes the cash and heads to Wayne's home. Somehow Michael happens upon the wife riding a horse to where she is having some hanky-panky with another farmhand, it's never really explained how he knew she would be there but who cares? Michael then goes to the house and waits for her return, when they meet he explains why he is there, and Suzanne (played by 25 kg Lara Flynn-Boyle) calmly counter offers Michael, at double the rate, to kill Wayne instead. Again Michael agrees, only this time he says enough and decides to "Lock it in Eddie", taking the cash with the sole intention of buggering off. Now in non-Hollywood this would be the end of it, but because a movie can't be over in 45 minutes we follow Michael as he leaves town in the rain. Here's where the twists get hectic, I'll summarise the next 15 minutes: - Michael hits someone in his car and takes them to the local hospital. (He's a nice guy remember?) - The Sheriff turns out to be the last person Michael needs to see, Wayne. - Wayne is a bit miffed at the perceived double cross and decides to off Michael. - Michael escapes, runs off and is picked up by Dennis Hopper, who is, you guessed it: Lyle from Texas! I can't explain much more without spoilers and confusion, only from here on in the remainder of the film revolves around Suzanne, Wayne, Michael and Lyle, and includes a myriad of twists and turns, deception, betrayal and double crossing galore. Everything a grown movie needs really. Wayne is played by JT Walsh, usually a bit player in other movies and I have always felt he is a bit over the top. Dennis Hopper is always ultra-hammy, and is almost cartoonish here. Lara Flynn-Boyle is surprisingly low key through most of the film, and has flawless skin regardless of the circumstances. Cage plays the troubled hero part to the hilt, he's the prototype for the nice guy in a situation that he wants to avoid but can't. The finale is in keeping with the rest of the film and is fairly satisfying. If I might digress momentarily, at one stage Michael walks into a bar and says "Give me a beer", now I have walked into many bars and know if I ever say that the bartender will say something along the lines of "Which one d**khead?" Since the dawn of time even the most low key bar stocks more than one brand, in fact most have literally dozens to choose from. Dunno why this bothers me but it does. If you're worried about the perception of product placement do what Tarantino does and make up a brand. Final Rating  7 / 10. "We twist. And turn. And twist and twist and turn. Twist, twist, twist. Turn, turn, turn. The Itchy and Scratchy Show." I mean Red Rock West. (That means it's a pretty good movie.) If you liked this review (or even if you didn't) check out oneguyrambling.com
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Another gem starring Cage that slipped under my radar
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    thekyles99
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/7/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Like i said in previous reviews, recently i have been going through Nic Cage's IMDb list of projects he has done to see if there was anything i hadn't seen that he's been in. And low and behold i found a bunch of em. So far out of three watched i liked 2 of em . 2-1 not a bad ratio so far. Just goes to show to show Nic Cage although one of the busiest actors is also careful of the scripts he chooses to work on. Red Rock West is another gem of his that must've slipped under my radar in 93. Great storyline however i found the ending a little on the cheesy side that being said it was a pretty good thriller. This time round Nic portrays Michael Williams a down and out Texan who resides in his car and tries to get jobs but fails to an injury he took while serving in the marines. Apon driving into a little town of red rock he enters the red rock tavern to see about a job and in a serious judgement error ends up taking a job that belonged to a professional hit-man (Dennis Hopper) needless to say all hell breaks loose and the moral of the story is number one money is never easy and number two...watch who's life you try to impersonate as the grass is always greener on the other side of the fence. Good casting featuring the late great Jt Walsh who was always a pleasure to watch work and a very underrated actor to say the least. Another great and recently passed Dennis Hopper portrays the hit-man that was originally intended for the hit but was a little later then mike at arriving to the bar. Dennis hopper in my books was awesome in portraying villains. Lara Flynn Boyle rounds off the cast with a less then believable performance as the sheriffs wife who the hit is to be delivered upon. Nic Cage's character in this spends the rest of the movie digging the hole he has made himself further and further. To get out is the question.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Enthralling criminal goings-on in a small Western town, as the lead is caught between a Red Rock and a hard place.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    johnnyboyz (j_l_h_m@yahoo.co.uk)
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/6/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    John Dahl's Red Rock West is a neat, taut, stripped down piece of cut-and-thrust film-making without gimmickry nor a single false string attached. In a current contemporary world of American film-making, and one that was almost certainly predominant at the time of Red Rock West's inception, how wonderful it is to uncover a film that refrains from the over indulgence of extravagance and the ideology that awe is built on a foundation of overkill and visuals. That's not to say Red Rock West is without extravagance nor awe, such is Dahl's ability, that the film is full of a number of various incidences and twists that are exactly these things and gotten across by way of little more than a glance from one of the character's or an individual cut of the camera. When we hark back to America's independent cinematic boom of the late 1980s and going on into the early 1990s, certainly a boom that saw a number of films and individual directors both honoured and recognised on the European film circuit at the top level in a series of Golden Palm nominations, the displaying of Red Rock West shows we must not glance over the name of Dahl when speaking of both the films and directors of that era, namely: the Coen Brothers; Steven Soderburgh; Spike Lee and Tarantino, et al. The film revolves around Nicolas Cage's character named Michael Williams, an ex-Marine of American nationality down on his luck and strapped for money in the dusty outback of Wyoming. He lives out of his car; uses random road side troughs full of water as makeshift sinks and struggles to find work, the latest failing being a construction site job that doesn't come through, although later on, he'll find ample opportunity at constructing something: a monstrosity of a scenario for himself. Unbeknownst to us at the time, he's going into the misadventure he'll come to have with a prior tragedy of having served time in the Vietnam War, but suffering during this stretch at the hands of a missile attack on a base in Lebanon he was positioned at which forced him into enduring a glut of both chaos and death. The event that may very well lend itself to Williams' dishevelled and down-beat tone and attitude, something Cage pulls off in that naturalistic manner he's done so on occasion since, shares eerie parallels with what will come to unfold around him as another glut of death and chaos unfolds around a man who has signed up for something you only realise you don't want to be anywhere near when it gets ugly as 'wrong place  wrong time' scenario once again kicks in. The devilish premise sees Williams pretend to be the Texan hit-man an apparent bar owner named Wayne (Walsh) called for some days ago so as to do some local dirty-work he wants taken care of. His looming over a seated Cage whilst in the office an early establishing of power, the sort of power that he'll come to have over him as Williams is forced throughout into proverbially dancing to the tune of others. But rather than eliminate the target, Wayne's wife played by Lara Flynn Boyle, Williams warns her of the predicament and that her marriage ought quite clearly be an item of concern form here on in. Once all is said and done, the real hit-man in Dennis Hopper's Lyle shows up in jet black Texan attire and similarly coloured car more resembling a hearse than anything else, whilst developments and complications in exactly who it is the chief of police is in the whole area open up. For Cage's character, and like in most good film noir when dealing with the down-trodden lead whom treads a fine line between right and wrong, the persistent idea of torn morals floats to the surface relatively quickly and consistently in Red Rock West. In just observing the premise, the notion of Williams illegally accepting the offer of being paid to kill someone before refraining from doing it when confronted with the innocent figure of Wayne's wife, Dahl highlights his character's soon-to-be prominent ever shifting; ever changing attitudes to what crime infused activity is playing out around him. Throughout, Williams lies; shoots; kills and steals but additionally saves; offers salvation and actually avoids violence on several occasions when straight forward murder would have offered a simple way out of a predicament. Given this, Dahl expertly manoeuvres Williams from one town in the form of Red Rock to another and then back over the border again, a sort of physical flitting from one place to another in what is a physical manifestation of both the above theories of a film noir's male lead as well as Cage's character's constantly ambiguous hopping from justified in his actions to not as so. Red Rock West moulds a fascinating, and quite terrifying at times, tale out of all these elements; combining a number of items such as double-crosses; multiple identities and intense connections characters have with one another, the sorts that they're forced into forging before later being asked what they truly mean to them. Dahl additionally, and in a very basic sense, taps into a certain idea of post-war disillusionment through his lead in Williams' disconnection from the rest of society seeing him inhabit a desolate and often incomprehensible rural locale in which he just about scrapes by. This, as an old war injury refrains him from making any true advancement in a chosen field of work. Red Rock West is a tight, gripping piece; the sort that arrives with a steady and effective eye on a variety of items all the while under the control of a steady, focused hand.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    western-noir at its near finest
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    MisterWhiplash
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/6/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    John Dahl knows his film-noir, and he knows his westerns. This should be assumed from seeing Red Rock West, though his 'noir' influence comes through in other films as well (Kill Me Again and to a degree Joy Ride). He knows how to write a lone average-Joe type of character, and the shady villain, and a sexy Femme Fatale. He knows this, but he also fills his story of a drifter coming to a small Wyoming town and being (accidentally?) hired to kill a man's wife with some top-shelf talent. Or, at least, the best actors that could make the parts their own. It's a cold little movie where you realize pretty quickly that despite Michael's "nice-guy" quality, he's still a potential thief and is the comparatively not so bad. Not so bad compared to Wayne the "bartender" or "Sheriff", if that is indeed his name, and his wife who wants to escape to Mexico with all of the money she "inherited" (please note the quotations). An extra slice of danger comes with the appearance of the actual man hired to kill the woman, Lyle from Dallas played by the late Dennis Hopper. His character and performance is far less aggressive than in Blue Velvet, though this is like comparing a Tasmanian Devil to a bull at a fight. I liked the suspense, of not knowing who might double-cross who next or where the story might go depending on who is alive, and I also liked that they gave each character something to them. Michael and Lyle meet up the first time under unusual circumstances and he gives Michael a ride, where they each find out they were marines, Michael formerly a fighter in a botched mission in Lebanon. This is mentioned about halfway into the film, but it helps to set up this guy as a somewhat tragic figure, without a home and without a job but all of those memories he'd rather not take with him. Certainly not to Mexico, where he has nice ones with his father. Again, the casting and the writing is what makes the film. Lara Flynn Boyle works just about perfect as the female figure of desire and greed, and even if we've seen something like her before she's still fresh because of her performance. JT Walsh is also good but in a different way, where he's a lot more careful with his words, but one can see the look of panic when it surely comes. And Nicolas Cage, at first seemingly a little bored with the part in the opening scenes, really makes it his own as a reluctant hero with nothing to lose. Dialog is used in the film only so much to keep things moving along, but I mean this as a compliment; it's not minimalism, but economy of speech if that makes sense. Dahl knows exactly what he wants in his B-movie premise, and it's like he's taken material sitting on a shelf for years and dusted it and made it vital again.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
 </reviews>
</filme>
