<filme>
 <id>
  1500
 </id>
 <imdburl>
  http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0117550
 </imdburl>
 <ano>
  1996
 </ano>
 <titulo>
  Her&oacute;i por Engano
 </titulo>
 <rating>
  2.2
 </rating>
 <sinopse>
  An evil millionaire (Hulk Hogan) gets amnesia and then belives that he is Santa Claus.
 </sinopse>
 <storyline>
  An evil millionaire (Hulk Hogan) gets amnesia and then belives that he is Santa Claus.
 </storyline>
 <generos>
  <genero>
   Family
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Comedy
  </genero>
 </generos>
 <keywords>
  <keyword>
   amnesia
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   santa claus
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   millionaire
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   orphan
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   orphanage
  </keyword>
 </keywords>
 <diretores>
  <diretor>
   John Murlowski
  </diretor>
 </diretores>
 <escritores>
  <escritor>
   Jonathan Bond
  </escritor>
  <escritor>
   Fred Mata
  </escritor>
 </escritores>
 <atores>
  <ator>
   Hulk Hogan
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Don Stark
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Robin Curtis
  </ator>
 </atores>
 <reviews>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Just because it's a kids film doesn't mean you can get away with poor quality.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Anders Twetman
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is actually not that bad. Don't get me wrong here, it is by no means a good movie but compare to some some of it's neighbors on the bottom #100 list, Santa with Muscles is pretty watchable. It has a consistent narrative, all be it an inane one. There are well defined characters, flat as cardboard they may be, but at least they act consistently throughout the film. And best of all, the humor comes naturally, the jokes don't feel as forced as they do in Epic Movie or other bad comedies. I have some nitpicks though. First, the bad guy is having people tortured in his back yard, how is he not in prison already? The henchmen destroy property, threaten people an nearly kill a guy, why does no one call the police? When trying to catch the hero for speeding, the police try to shoot him with a rocket launcher, why is internal affairs not there arresting these murderous coppers? Not to mention, why does the police even have a rocket launcher? Questions like this keep popping up but that just makes the film more entertaining Now, this a children's movie and as such less effort has gone into the details of making it, thus the plot is too simplistic, the characters, especially the bad guys are just ridiculous and the acting leaves a lot to ask. Given that there are good, well made children's films out there, having a younger audience is no excuse for making a bad film. Good enough for children maybe, but not good.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    To those who wonder why Hulk Hogan's acting career never got off the ground...watch "Santa with Muscles".
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Boba_Fett1138
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/7/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    You know that a movie is really bad when it makes you feel psychically ill. This for me was really the case with "Santa with Muscles". It's amazing how many bad Christmas/Santa Claus movies for kids are around. But this movie is even below the normal level of Santa Claus movies, that are made for kids. It's very obviously a movie that got aimed toward young children but just because it's a kids movie doesn't mean it can get away just with everything. But also on top of that; I really can't see how kids could ever enjoy watching this movie. It really isn't that entertaining or humorous to watch because of some serious bad writing. If I had seen this movie as kid it probably wouldn't had annoyed me as much as it did now but I probably would still had been bored out of my skull while watching it. I don't even know what this movie is supposed to be all about. It's such an huge mess to watch and it feels like the script got put together from a couple of other different Santa Claus scripts they had floating around somewhere in a dark corner. The movie too often doesn't make sense and it's a very inconsistent one to watch, since the story jumps all over the place and doesn't seem to know what it wants. What the story is also lacking is a good Christmas message in it. This movie has absolutely none and isn't even about the Christmas spirit at all. Who wants to watch a Santa Claus movie that isn't even somewhat remotely Christmas related. It always has been sort of a mystery as to why Hulk Hogan's acting career never took off. He had the right looks and charisma and was and still is incredibly popular and well known, all over the world, due to his wrestling career. And hey, if Dwayne Johnson and Arnold Schwarzenegger have a big acting career, with similar backgrounds, than why couldn't he? The answer is in movies like this. He made some bad choices with his picks for movies and the highlights of his acting career are cameos in some well known movies, in which he only spoofs himself. So Hulk Hogan doesn't impress much with this movie but so does nobody else in this. The movie made some weird casting choices, by making Steve Valentine and Ed Begley Jr. the main villains. When you have Hulk Hogan as your main hero, you need a strong and way more threatening villain opposing him, not two lab-geeks. It still gets points for having Clint Howard and a very young Mila Kunis in it though. What also puzzles me is if this is supposed to be a Christmas movie than why does this movie look all the time like it got shot in the middle of the summer? Couldn't they at least somewhat tried to fake it. To be honest, I don't think I'll ever put this movie on any of my worst movie lists but that is simply because I have seen so many bad movies, that are even in one way or another worse than this one. But of course that really doesn't make "Santa with Muscles" somewhat of a good or a remotely entertaining watch. Just avoid, it's not even watchable for its cult-value. 3/10 http://bobafett1138.blogspot.com/
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Worse than an evening with bin Laden, Michael Jackson and Hitler.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    LoonyAaron
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/12/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    What can really be said about a film like this? Well, let's start with a little background information about the leading man. Terry 'Hulk Hogan' Boella is the most selfish man in the wrestling business. He never put over anyone, he can't sell whatsoever and he tried to sabotage Bret Hart's career. He even disrespect Shawn Michaels - SHAWN FREAKING MICHAELS. The Heart-Break Kid! The Icon! The Showstoppa'! MR. WRESTLEMANIA! So when the Hulkster is tasked with playing an obnoxious, egotistical, vapid, sexually confused plutocrat it is by far the most convincing part of this abortion of a movie. He hires his buddy Ed Leslie to play an Asian doctor - correct, an EVIL Asian doctor. Ed Leslie, the man who couldn't get over playing a stripper/barber. Ed Leslie, the man who caused a terrorist scare when people mistook his COCAINE for anthrax. The fact that this man was in the wrestling business for so long is bad enough, but for the love of God and Scorsese, blacklist him from cinema! This movie is awful, truly awful in every way. You see, there's an orphanage and it's going to get blown up. And when the poor children need someone to rely on, who do they turn to? The cops? A responsible grown up? No, poor old steroid-addict Hulk Hogan. He rambles through the script like a diabetic monkey, delivering dialogue so hideous it would make Vince Price (God rest his soul) blanch. And then, at the end of the movie, this disturbed mental patient, makes a bunch of orphans live alone with him in his secluded mansion. Everything about this film is wrong, everything about this film should be buried in the Nevada desert alongside Jimmy Hoffa and those copies of the ET video game. Do not watch this movie. No, not even if you are told to do so by your Mother on her death bed. This is tripe of the highest order and will actually make you question your sexual orientation. At one part, Hogan begins wearing a fetish Santa suit complete with tight leather boots and an S&M belt. I wish I was making this up. Please, just let this film die a slow and painful death.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Grinch did not steal Christmas...this film did!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    planktonrules
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/1/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    If ever there was a family holiday film that could kill the holiday spirit, this film is it. It makes "Jingle All the Way" and even "Santa Claus Conquers the Martians" seem GOOD in comparison! And, if you ever meet anyone who hates Christmas, chances are that they saw this film! This movie is a cloying, annoying dud...the sort of contrived mess of a film that makes you want to tell Hollywood to STOP making holiday movies if this is the sort of crap they think the public could want! The film begins with Hulk Hogan playing some sort of combination rich guy, superhero, GI Joe wannabe and ninja. I am glad that his impressions of himself and his abilities are not in any way over-ambitious or egocentric! In a stupid freak accident, the Hulkster now thinks he's Santa and comes to the aid...I kid you not...of a home for orphans!! Folks, it just doesn't get any worse than this--or does it?! Well, in fact it does. You see, the evil man behind this is, naturally, Ed Begley, Jr. and I assume he wanted this property to build an electric car dealership. But, in a bizarre twist, it's to get a whole bunch of neon-like power crystals hidden in an underground vault! Say what?!?!? Begley's crew of evil villains look like the sort of baddies that might attack Barney the dinosaur. They are all really, really lame and are about as threatening as a mild case of dandruff. And, it's up to Hulk to kick some butt (wow, not a tough thing in this case), win the hearts of a whole bunch of cute moppets AND manage to make a family-friendly movie that involves lots of punching, kicking and other forms of violence! The film has absolutely nothing going for it other than Hogan's massive ego. The acting is crap, the script is crap, the action is crap and there is nothing...I repeat, NOTHING of any value to this steaming pile of....movie. What makes it worse is the 'surprise' twist concerning the villain and Hulk's childhood--which, oddly, neither seemed to remember! Sadly, anyone seeing this turkey of a film will not have the same thing occur--they'll never forget having wasted nearly an hour and a half on this snot-fest. This film easily deserves to be on IMDb's Bottom 100 list, as it's the worst vanity project I've seen in ages--and a family film which is too violent and stupid for kids and just about impossible for any adult to sit through without massive amounts of liquor. My favorite part of the film? Towards the end, one of the lame villains yells "It's gonna blow!!". He couldn't have been more right, though he probably should have said this at the beginning in order to warn people what they were in for seeing! I think I'd have rather seen "Chitty, Chitty Bang, Bang", "The Adventures of Pippi Longstocking" or even "Son of the Mask" instead of this movie--it was that bad! By the way, there is a worse Christmas film. The 1959 Mexican film "Santa Claus" is in the Bottom 100 as well and it is light-years worse! But, for a big-budget Hollywood Christmas story, "Santa With Muscles" takes the prize!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Only in a movie this awful...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ij-holmes
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/11/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    ...could you find a wrestler playing a millionaire who thinks he's Santa Claus sword fighting a guy in an astronaut suit with a crystal broken off from a mine underneath a church. When you have that picture in your mind, you've already seen the only part of this movie worth watching, if you can even call it that. Don't watch this movie. Don't rent this movie. Don't stay on the channel on which this movie is playing. Forget this movie exists. If you must see it, make sure you are compensated financially for your trouble. If you can avoid seeing it, AVOID IT. You'll be doing your brain a favor.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    What the Hell was this?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jts0405
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/8/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Santa With Muscles is supposed to be a comedy, I guess, but it really doesn't bring the laughs at all. You don't find yourself laughing with the movie, but instead laughing at it and how incredibly cheesy it is. Hulk Hogan really needed to take his name off the project, because it would've done him a lot of good in his shortly lived acting career. I don't even get the plot to all of this, he is a millionaire that thinks he's Santa Claus, wow a preschooler could come up with that idea and make this whole movie look a lot better in the process. I am not bashing Hogan, because I did like him as a wrestler but as an actor the stuff he has done has really sucked. This belongs on the bottom 100. 1/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Best, Movie, Ever.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    James Miller
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/7/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Well now, this was probably one of the most fantastic pieces of movie literature to ever be produced within this day and age of cinematography Hulk Hogan is the greatest actor of all time, and he is also, the greatest wrestler to ever, take foot within the wrestling ring. Now, I am a hulkamaniac. Best movie ever Best movie ever Best movie ever. 10/10b Nothing beats seeing a movie about Santa, with fight scenes, thieves trying to steal crystals from an orphanage with Hulk Hogan, the man with a plan, coming in and desecrating the enemies ! pewpew !
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Santa, you sleigh me!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    lastliberal
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/12/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    OK, this is probably the absolutely worst Christmas program ever! No, it is not as bad as Feeders 2: Slay Bells, but for a Christmas show it is pretty bad. Hulk Hogan may have been a good wrestler, but he certainly cannot act. Here he bumps his head and thinks he's Santa. He is up against a group of real clowns led by Ed Begley, Jr. Steve Valentine from "Crossing Jordan" and more Grade Z actors. The only redeeming performance was little Aria Noelle Curzon, who was nine at the time. Cross this one off your Christmas list.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Hulkster must smoke rock
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    lodi_70005
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/8/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I am sure most of the posters here are not wrestling fans. Therefore, I will clue you in on a couple of things. Hulk Hogan is an ego maniacal jackass that demands creative control over anything he is involved in. This movie might not have been a classic when it was first written, but I will be fair and say it had average potential(a rating of 5). The movie probably had a different title at first until......Hulkamania arrived. Hulk Hogan has this remarkable ability to turn something good or average into unwatchable garbage. Original title may have been "When Santa got Rich" or "Santa CEO" or something slightly stupid. Hogan looks at the title and says "no way brother, my fans don't know nothing about no CEO(the first true words to come out of the mouth of the Hulkster in twenty years). So he called it "Santa with Muscles" because no project involving Hogan is allowed to go 5 seconds without referring to the "24 inch pythons" After adding scenes where blow up candy canes are used by Hogan with results comparable to the bomb dropped on Hiroshima, Hogan finally has gotten his wish. He ruined what might have been an enjoyable movie experience for two year olds and those who are "mentally challenged" or retards as Hogan's faithful redneck fans may call them. I am not surprised at how bad this film turned out. Wrestling fans with half a brain have hated Hogan for years. He exercises creative control when he is told that he is going to lose and this ends up boring anyone with a below average iq on up to tears. Hogan may have turned wrestling into a million dollar industry with a lot of help from the master marketing machine named Vince Mcmahon. Many good people sacrificed their wrestling careers by falling prey to Hogan's trademark "leg drop of doom" and now some poor director is probably living under a bridge in Los Angeles damning the day he got involved with Hulk Hogan. Hogan may have helped turn wrestling into mainstream entertainment, but he also singlehandedly destroyed the same industry(his tired act help put WCW into the ground) he helped build by never learning more than three moves. Punch, back scratch, high boot and leg drop. Oops that is four moves. Some things never change. In the ring the bad guy always loses to Hulk via leg drop. In the movies, Hogan expands his creative horizons by having the bad guy lose via Plastic candy Kane.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Watch out, he's got laughter and smiles!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Seth Nelson
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/2/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "He" referring to Hulk Hogan, which I consider the America's Tor Johnson. Tor starred in many bad movies; so does Hulk. Both are very funny in each of their performances! In my opinion, "Santa with Muscles" is where all the fun and the laughs are! Hearing that "Eegah"-like "Watch out, he's got a candy cane!" makes me laugh until I cry! And I laugh so much, I cry until I can do neither of those things anymore! That's the secret recipe for a great family holiday film: Laughs + Good Clean Family Fun (none of that "Bad Santa" stuff, please!) = The Best Holiday Family Film In The History Of The Universe! Let "Santa with Muscles" be the centerpiece of your entertainment next Christmas!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Just because it's a kids film doesn't mean you can get away with poor quality.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Anders Twetman
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is actually not that bad. Don't get me wrong here, it is by no means a good movie but compare to some some of it's neighbors on the bottom #100 list, Santa with Muscles is pretty watchable. It has a consistent narrative, all be it an inane one. There are well defined characters, flat as cardboard they may be, but at least they act consistently throughout the film. And best of all, the humor comes naturally, the jokes don't feel as forced as they do in Epic Movie or other bad comedies. I have some nitpicks though. First, the bad guy is having people tortured in his back yard, how is he not in prison already? The henchmen destroy property, threaten people an nearly kill a guy, why does no one call the police? When trying to catch the hero for speeding, the police try to shoot him with a rocket launcher, why is internal affairs not there arresting these murderous coppers? Not to mention, why does the police even have a rocket launcher? Questions like this keep popping up but that just makes the film more entertaining Now, this a children's movie and as such less effort has gone into the details of making it, thus the plot is too simplistic, the characters, especially the bad guys are just ridiculous and the acting leaves a lot to ask. Given that there are good, well made children's films out there, having a younger audience is no excuse for making a bad film. Good enough for children maybe, but not good.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    To those who wonder why Hulk Hogan's acting career never got off the ground...watch "Santa with Muscles".
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Boba_Fett1138
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/7/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    You know that a movie is really bad when it makes you feel psychically ill. This for me was really the case with "Santa with Muscles". It's amazing how many bad Christmas/Santa Claus movies for kids are around. But this movie is even below the normal level of Santa Claus movies, that are made for kids. It's very obviously a movie that got aimed toward young children but just because it's a kids movie doesn't mean it can get away just with everything. But also on top of that; I really can't see how kids could ever enjoy watching this movie. It really isn't that entertaining or humorous to watch because of some serious bad writing. If I had seen this movie as kid it probably wouldn't had annoyed me as much as it did now but I probably would still had been bored out of my skull while watching it. I don't even know what this movie is supposed to be all about. It's such an huge mess to watch and it feels like the script got put together from a couple of other different Santa Claus scripts they had floating around somewhere in a dark corner. The movie too often doesn't make sense and it's a very inconsistent one to watch, since the story jumps all over the place and doesn't seem to know what it wants. What the story is also lacking is a good Christmas message in it. This movie has absolutely none and isn't even about the Christmas spirit at all. Who wants to watch a Santa Claus movie that isn't even somewhat remotely Christmas related. It always has been sort of a mystery as to why Hulk Hogan's acting career never took off. He had the right looks and charisma and was and still is incredibly popular and well known, all over the world, due to his wrestling career. And hey, if Dwayne Johnson and Arnold Schwarzenegger have a big acting career, with similar backgrounds, than why couldn't he? The answer is in movies like this. He made some bad choices with his picks for movies and the highlights of his acting career are cameos in some well known movies, in which he only spoofs himself. So Hulk Hogan doesn't impress much with this movie but so does nobody else in this. The movie made some weird casting choices, by making Steve Valentine and Ed Begley Jr. the main villains. When you have Hulk Hogan as your main hero, you need a strong and way more threatening villain opposing him, not two lab-geeks. It still gets points for having Clint Howard and a very young Mila Kunis in it though. What also puzzles me is if this is supposed to be a Christmas movie than why does this movie look all the time like it got shot in the middle of the summer? Couldn't they at least somewhat tried to fake it. To be honest, I don't think I'll ever put this movie on any of my worst movie lists but that is simply because I have seen so many bad movies, that are even in one way or another worse than this one. But of course that really doesn't make "Santa with Muscles" somewhat of a good or a remotely entertaining watch. Just avoid, it's not even watchable for its cult-value. 3/10 http://bobafett1138.blogspot.com/
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Worse than an evening with bin Laden, Michael Jackson and Hitler.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    LoonyAaron
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/12/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    What can really be said about a film like this? Well, let's start with a little background information about the leading man. Terry 'Hulk Hogan' Boella is the most selfish man in the wrestling business. He never put over anyone, he can't sell whatsoever and he tried to sabotage Bret Hart's career. He even disrespect Shawn Michaels - SHAWN FREAKING MICHAELS. The Heart-Break Kid! The Icon! The Showstoppa'! MR. WRESTLEMANIA! So when the Hulkster is tasked with playing an obnoxious, egotistical, vapid, sexually confused plutocrat it is by far the most convincing part of this abortion of a movie. He hires his buddy Ed Leslie to play an Asian doctor - correct, an EVIL Asian doctor. Ed Leslie, the man who couldn't get over playing a stripper/barber. Ed Leslie, the man who caused a terrorist scare when people mistook his COCAINE for anthrax. The fact that this man was in the wrestling business for so long is bad enough, but for the love of God and Scorsese, blacklist him from cinema! This movie is awful, truly awful in every way. You see, there's an orphanage and it's going to get blown up. And when the poor children need someone to rely on, who do they turn to? The cops? A responsible grown up? No, poor old steroid-addict Hulk Hogan. He rambles through the script like a diabetic monkey, delivering dialogue so hideous it would make Vince Price (God rest his soul) blanch. And then, at the end of the movie, this disturbed mental patient, makes a bunch of orphans live alone with him in his secluded mansion. Everything about this film is wrong, everything about this film should be buried in the Nevada desert alongside Jimmy Hoffa and those copies of the ET video game. Do not watch this movie. No, not even if you are told to do so by your Mother on her death bed. This is tripe of the highest order and will actually make you question your sexual orientation. At one part, Hogan begins wearing a fetish Santa suit complete with tight leather boots and an S&M belt. I wish I was making this up. Please, just let this film die a slow and painful death.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Grinch did not steal Christmas...this film did!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    planktonrules
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/1/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    If ever there was a family holiday film that could kill the holiday spirit, this film is it. It makes "Jingle All the Way" and even "Santa Claus Conquers the Martians" seem GOOD in comparison! And, if you ever meet anyone who hates Christmas, chances are that they saw this film! This movie is a cloying, annoying dud...the sort of contrived mess of a film that makes you want to tell Hollywood to STOP making holiday movies if this is the sort of crap they think the public could want! The film begins with Hulk Hogan playing some sort of combination rich guy, superhero, GI Joe wannabe and ninja. I am glad that his impressions of himself and his abilities are not in any way over-ambitious or egocentric! In a stupid freak accident, the Hulkster now thinks he's Santa and comes to the aid...I kid you not...of a home for orphans!! Folks, it just doesn't get any worse than this--or does it?! Well, in fact it does. You see, the evil man behind this is, naturally, Ed Begley, Jr. and I assume he wanted this property to build an electric car dealership. But, in a bizarre twist, it's to get a whole bunch of neon-like power crystals hidden in an underground vault! Say what?!?!? Begley's crew of evil villains look like the sort of baddies that might attack Barney the dinosaur. They are all really, really lame and are about as threatening as a mild case of dandruff. And, it's up to Hulk to kick some butt (wow, not a tough thing in this case), win the hearts of a whole bunch of cute moppets AND manage to make a family-friendly movie that involves lots of punching, kicking and other forms of violence! The film has absolutely nothing going for it other than Hogan's massive ego. The acting is crap, the script is crap, the action is crap and there is nothing...I repeat, NOTHING of any value to this steaming pile of....movie. What makes it worse is the 'surprise' twist concerning the villain and Hulk's childhood--which, oddly, neither seemed to remember! Sadly, anyone seeing this turkey of a film will not have the same thing occur--they'll never forget having wasted nearly an hour and a half on this snot-fest. This film easily deserves to be on IMDb's Bottom 100 list, as it's the worst vanity project I've seen in ages--and a family film which is too violent and stupid for kids and just about impossible for any adult to sit through without massive amounts of liquor. My favorite part of the film? Towards the end, one of the lame villains yells "It's gonna blow!!". He couldn't have been more right, though he probably should have said this at the beginning in order to warn people what they were in for seeing! I think I'd have rather seen "Chitty, Chitty Bang, Bang", "The Adventures of Pippi Longstocking" or even "Son of the Mask" instead of this movie--it was that bad! By the way, there is a worse Christmas film. The 1959 Mexican film "Santa Claus" is in the Bottom 100 as well and it is light-years worse! But, for a big-budget Hollywood Christmas story, "Santa With Muscles" takes the prize!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Only in a movie this awful...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ij-holmes
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/11/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    ...could you find a wrestler playing a millionaire who thinks he's Santa Claus sword fighting a guy in an astronaut suit with a crystal broken off from a mine underneath a church. When you have that picture in your mind, you've already seen the only part of this movie worth watching, if you can even call it that. Don't watch this movie. Don't rent this movie. Don't stay on the channel on which this movie is playing. Forget this movie exists. If you must see it, make sure you are compensated financially for your trouble. If you can avoid seeing it, AVOID IT. You'll be doing your brain a favor.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    What the Hell was this?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jts0405
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/8/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Santa With Muscles is supposed to be a comedy, I guess, but it really doesn't bring the laughs at all. You don't find yourself laughing with the movie, but instead laughing at it and how incredibly cheesy it is. Hulk Hogan really needed to take his name off the project, because it would've done him a lot of good in his shortly lived acting career. I don't even get the plot to all of this, he is a millionaire that thinks he's Santa Claus, wow a preschooler could come up with that idea and make this whole movie look a lot better in the process. I am not bashing Hogan, because I did like him as a wrestler but as an actor the stuff he has done has really sucked. This belongs on the bottom 100. 1/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Best, Movie, Ever.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    James Miller
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/7/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Well now, this was probably one of the most fantastic pieces of movie literature to ever be produced within this day and age of cinematography Hulk Hogan is the greatest actor of all time, and he is also, the greatest wrestler to ever, take foot within the wrestling ring. Now, I am a hulkamaniac. Best movie ever Best movie ever Best movie ever. 10/10b Nothing beats seeing a movie about Santa, with fight scenes, thieves trying to steal crystals from an orphanage with Hulk Hogan, the man with a plan, coming in and desecrating the enemies ! pewpew !
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Santa, you sleigh me!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    lastliberal
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/12/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    OK, this is probably the absolutely worst Christmas program ever! No, it is not as bad as Feeders 2: Slay Bells, but for a Christmas show it is pretty bad. Hulk Hogan may have been a good wrestler, but he certainly cannot act. Here he bumps his head and thinks he's Santa. He is up against a group of real clowns led by Ed Begley, Jr. Steve Valentine from "Crossing Jordan" and more Grade Z actors. The only redeeming performance was little Aria Noelle Curzon, who was nine at the time. Cross this one off your Christmas list.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Hulkster must smoke rock
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    lodi_70005
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/8/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I am sure most of the posters here are not wrestling fans. Therefore, I will clue you in on a couple of things. Hulk Hogan is an ego maniacal jackass that demands creative control over anything he is involved in. This movie might not have been a classic when it was first written, but I will be fair and say it had average potential(a rating of 5). The movie probably had a different title at first until......Hulkamania arrived. Hulk Hogan has this remarkable ability to turn something good or average into unwatchable garbage. Original title may have been "When Santa got Rich" or "Santa CEO" or something slightly stupid. Hogan looks at the title and says "no way brother, my fans don't know nothing about no CEO(the first true words to come out of the mouth of the Hulkster in twenty years). So he called it "Santa with Muscles" because no project involving Hogan is allowed to go 5 seconds without referring to the "24 inch pythons" After adding scenes where blow up candy canes are used by Hogan with results comparable to the bomb dropped on Hiroshima, Hogan finally has gotten his wish. He ruined what might have been an enjoyable movie experience for two year olds and those who are "mentally challenged" or retards as Hogan's faithful redneck fans may call them. I am not surprised at how bad this film turned out. Wrestling fans with half a brain have hated Hogan for years. He exercises creative control when he is told that he is going to lose and this ends up boring anyone with a below average iq on up to tears. Hogan may have turned wrestling into a million dollar industry with a lot of help from the master marketing machine named Vince Mcmahon. Many good people sacrificed their wrestling careers by falling prey to Hogan's trademark "leg drop of doom" and now some poor director is probably living under a bridge in Los Angeles damning the day he got involved with Hulk Hogan. Hogan may have helped turn wrestling into mainstream entertainment, but he also singlehandedly destroyed the same industry(his tired act help put WCW into the ground) he helped build by never learning more than three moves. Punch, back scratch, high boot and leg drop. Oops that is four moves. Some things never change. In the ring the bad guy always loses to Hulk via leg drop. In the movies, Hogan expands his creative horizons by having the bad guy lose via Plastic candy Kane.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Watch out, he's got laughter and smiles!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Seth Nelson
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/2/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "He" referring to Hulk Hogan, which I consider the America's Tor Johnson. Tor starred in many bad movies; so does Hulk. Both are very funny in each of their performances! In my opinion, "Santa with Muscles" is where all the fun and the laughs are! Hearing that "Eegah"-like "Watch out, he's got a candy cane!" makes me laugh until I cry! And I laugh so much, I cry until I can do neither of those things anymore! That's the secret recipe for a great family holiday film: Laughs + Good Clean Family Fun (none of that "Bad Santa" stuff, please!) = The Best Holiday Family Film In The History Of The Universe! Let "Santa with Muscles" be the centerpiece of your entertainment next Christmas!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Just because it's a kids film doesn't mean you can get away with poor quality.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Anders Twetman
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is actually not that bad. Don't get me wrong here, it is by no means a good movie but compare to some some of it's neighbors on the bottom #100 list, Santa with Muscles is pretty watchable. It has a consistent narrative, all be it an inane one. There are well defined characters, flat as cardboard they may be, but at least they act consistently throughout the film. And best of all, the humor comes naturally, the jokes don't feel as forced as they do in Epic Movie or other bad comedies. I have some nitpicks though. First, the bad guy is having people tortured in his back yard, how is he not in prison already? The henchmen destroy property, threaten people an nearly kill a guy, why does no one call the police? When trying to catch the hero for speeding, the police try to shoot him with a rocket launcher, why is internal affairs not there arresting these murderous coppers? Not to mention, why does the police even have a rocket launcher? Questions like this keep popping up but that just makes the film more entertaining Now, this a children's movie and as such less effort has gone into the details of making it, thus the plot is too simplistic, the characters, especially the bad guys are just ridiculous and the acting leaves a lot to ask. Given that there are good, well made children's films out there, having a younger audience is no excuse for making a bad film. Good enough for children maybe, but not good.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    To those who wonder why Hulk Hogan's acting career never got off the ground...watch "Santa with Muscles".
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Boba_Fett1138
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/7/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    You know that a movie is really bad when it makes you feel psychically ill. This for me was really the case with "Santa with Muscles". It's amazing how many bad Christmas/Santa Claus movies for kids are around. But this movie is even below the normal level of Santa Claus movies, that are made for kids. It's very obviously a movie that got aimed toward young children but just because it's a kids movie doesn't mean it can get away just with everything. But also on top of that; I really can't see how kids could ever enjoy watching this movie. It really isn't that entertaining or humorous to watch because of some serious bad writing. If I had seen this movie as kid it probably wouldn't had annoyed me as much as it did now but I probably would still had been bored out of my skull while watching it. I don't even know what this movie is supposed to be all about. It's such an huge mess to watch and it feels like the script got put together from a couple of other different Santa Claus scripts they had floating around somewhere in a dark corner. The movie too often doesn't make sense and it's a very inconsistent one to watch, since the story jumps all over the place and doesn't seem to know what it wants. What the story is also lacking is a good Christmas message in it. This movie has absolutely none and isn't even about the Christmas spirit at all. Who wants to watch a Santa Claus movie that isn't even somewhat remotely Christmas related. It always has been sort of a mystery as to why Hulk Hogan's acting career never took off. He had the right looks and charisma and was and still is incredibly popular and well known, all over the world, due to his wrestling career. And hey, if Dwayne Johnson and Arnold Schwarzenegger have a big acting career, with similar backgrounds, than why couldn't he? The answer is in movies like this. He made some bad choices with his picks for movies and the highlights of his acting career are cameos in some well known movies, in which he only spoofs himself. So Hulk Hogan doesn't impress much with this movie but so does nobody else in this. The movie made some weird casting choices, by making Steve Valentine and Ed Begley Jr. the main villains. When you have Hulk Hogan as your main hero, you need a strong and way more threatening villain opposing him, not two lab-geeks. It still gets points for having Clint Howard and a very young Mila Kunis in it though. What also puzzles me is if this is supposed to be a Christmas movie than why does this movie look all the time like it got shot in the middle of the summer? Couldn't they at least somewhat tried to fake it. To be honest, I don't think I'll ever put this movie on any of my worst movie lists but that is simply because I have seen so many bad movies, that are even in one way or another worse than this one. But of course that really doesn't make "Santa with Muscles" somewhat of a good or a remotely entertaining watch. Just avoid, it's not even watchable for its cult-value. 3/10 http://bobafett1138.blogspot.com/
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Worse than an evening with bin Laden, Michael Jackson and Hitler.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    LoonyAaron
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/12/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    What can really be said about a film like this? Well, let's start with a little background information about the leading man. Terry 'Hulk Hogan' Boella is the most selfish man in the wrestling business. He never put over anyone, he can't sell whatsoever and he tried to sabotage Bret Hart's career. He even disrespect Shawn Michaels - SHAWN FREAKING MICHAELS. The Heart-Break Kid! The Icon! The Showstoppa'! MR. WRESTLEMANIA! So when the Hulkster is tasked with playing an obnoxious, egotistical, vapid, sexually confused plutocrat it is by far the most convincing part of this abortion of a movie. He hires his buddy Ed Leslie to play an Asian doctor - correct, an EVIL Asian doctor. Ed Leslie, the man who couldn't get over playing a stripper/barber. Ed Leslie, the man who caused a terrorist scare when people mistook his COCAINE for anthrax. The fact that this man was in the wrestling business for so long is bad enough, but for the love of God and Scorsese, blacklist him from cinema! This movie is awful, truly awful in every way. You see, there's an orphanage and it's going to get blown up. And when the poor children need someone to rely on, who do they turn to? The cops? A responsible grown up? No, poor old steroid-addict Hulk Hogan. He rambles through the script like a diabetic monkey, delivering dialogue so hideous it would make Vince Price (God rest his soul) blanch. And then, at the end of the movie, this disturbed mental patient, makes a bunch of orphans live alone with him in his secluded mansion. Everything about this film is wrong, everything about this film should be buried in the Nevada desert alongside Jimmy Hoffa and those copies of the ET video game. Do not watch this movie. No, not even if you are told to do so by your Mother on her death bed. This is tripe of the highest order and will actually make you question your sexual orientation. At one part, Hogan begins wearing a fetish Santa suit complete with tight leather boots and an S&M belt. I wish I was making this up. Please, just let this film die a slow and painful death.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Grinch did not steal Christmas...this film did!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    planktonrules
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/1/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    If ever there was a family holiday film that could kill the holiday spirit, this film is it. It makes "Jingle All the Way" and even "Santa Claus Conquers the Martians" seem GOOD in comparison! And, if you ever meet anyone who hates Christmas, chances are that they saw this film! This movie is a cloying, annoying dud...the sort of contrived mess of a film that makes you want to tell Hollywood to STOP making holiday movies if this is the sort of crap they think the public could want! The film begins with Hulk Hogan playing some sort of combination rich guy, superhero, GI Joe wannabe and ninja. I am glad that his impressions of himself and his abilities are not in any way over-ambitious or egocentric! In a stupid freak accident, the Hulkster now thinks he's Santa and comes to the aid...I kid you not...of a home for orphans!! Folks, it just doesn't get any worse than this--or does it?! Well, in fact it does. You see, the evil man behind this is, naturally, Ed Begley, Jr. and I assume he wanted this property to build an electric car dealership. But, in a bizarre twist, it's to get a whole bunch of neon-like power crystals hidden in an underground vault! Say what?!?!? Begley's crew of evil villains look like the sort of baddies that might attack Barney the dinosaur. They are all really, really lame and are about as threatening as a mild case of dandruff. And, it's up to Hulk to kick some butt (wow, not a tough thing in this case), win the hearts of a whole bunch of cute moppets AND manage to make a family-friendly movie that involves lots of punching, kicking and other forms of violence! The film has absolutely nothing going for it other than Hogan's massive ego. The acting is crap, the script is crap, the action is crap and there is nothing...I repeat, NOTHING of any value to this steaming pile of....movie. What makes it worse is the 'surprise' twist concerning the villain and Hulk's childhood--which, oddly, neither seemed to remember! Sadly, anyone seeing this turkey of a film will not have the same thing occur--they'll never forget having wasted nearly an hour and a half on this snot-fest. This film easily deserves to be on IMDb's Bottom 100 list, as it's the worst vanity project I've seen in ages--and a family film which is too violent and stupid for kids and just about impossible for any adult to sit through without massive amounts of liquor. My favorite part of the film? Towards the end, one of the lame villains yells "It's gonna blow!!". He couldn't have been more right, though he probably should have said this at the beginning in order to warn people what they were in for seeing! I think I'd have rather seen "Chitty, Chitty Bang, Bang", "The Adventures of Pippi Longstocking" or even "Son of the Mask" instead of this movie--it was that bad! By the way, there is a worse Christmas film. The 1959 Mexican film "Santa Claus" is in the Bottom 100 as well and it is light-years worse! But, for a big-budget Hollywood Christmas story, "Santa With Muscles" takes the prize!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Only in a movie this awful...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ij-holmes
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/11/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    ...could you find a wrestler playing a millionaire who thinks he's Santa Claus sword fighting a guy in an astronaut suit with a crystal broken off from a mine underneath a church. When you have that picture in your mind, you've already seen the only part of this movie worth watching, if you can even call it that. Don't watch this movie. Don't rent this movie. Don't stay on the channel on which this movie is playing. Forget this movie exists. If you must see it, make sure you are compensated financially for your trouble. If you can avoid seeing it, AVOID IT. You'll be doing your brain a favor.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    What the Hell was this?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jts0405
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/8/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Santa With Muscles is supposed to be a comedy, I guess, but it really doesn't bring the laughs at all. You don't find yourself laughing with the movie, but instead laughing at it and how incredibly cheesy it is. Hulk Hogan really needed to take his name off the project, because it would've done him a lot of good in his shortly lived acting career. I don't even get the plot to all of this, he is a millionaire that thinks he's Santa Claus, wow a preschooler could come up with that idea and make this whole movie look a lot better in the process. I am not bashing Hogan, because I did like him as a wrestler but as an actor the stuff he has done has really sucked. This belongs on the bottom 100. 1/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Best, Movie, Ever.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    James Miller
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/7/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Well now, this was probably one of the most fantastic pieces of movie literature to ever be produced within this day and age of cinematography Hulk Hogan is the greatest actor of all time, and he is also, the greatest wrestler to ever, take foot within the wrestling ring. Now, I am a hulkamaniac. Best movie ever Best movie ever Best movie ever. 10/10b Nothing beats seeing a movie about Santa, with fight scenes, thieves trying to steal crystals from an orphanage with Hulk Hogan, the man with a plan, coming in and desecrating the enemies ! pewpew !
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Santa, you sleigh me!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    lastliberal
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/12/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    OK, this is probably the absolutely worst Christmas program ever! No, it is not as bad as Feeders 2: Slay Bells, but for a Christmas show it is pretty bad. Hulk Hogan may have been a good wrestler, but he certainly cannot act. Here he bumps his head and thinks he's Santa. He is up against a group of real clowns led by Ed Begley, Jr. Steve Valentine from "Crossing Jordan" and more Grade Z actors. The only redeeming performance was little Aria Noelle Curzon, who was nine at the time. Cross this one off your Christmas list.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Hulkster must smoke rock
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    lodi_70005
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/8/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I am sure most of the posters here are not wrestling fans. Therefore, I will clue you in on a couple of things. Hulk Hogan is an ego maniacal jackass that demands creative control over anything he is involved in. This movie might not have been a classic when it was first written, but I will be fair and say it had average potential(a rating of 5). The movie probably had a different title at first until......Hulkamania arrived. Hulk Hogan has this remarkable ability to turn something good or average into unwatchable garbage. Original title may have been "When Santa got Rich" or "Santa CEO" or something slightly stupid. Hogan looks at the title and says "no way brother, my fans don't know nothing about no CEO(the first true words to come out of the mouth of the Hulkster in twenty years). So he called it "Santa with Muscles" because no project involving Hogan is allowed to go 5 seconds without referring to the "24 inch pythons" After adding scenes where blow up candy canes are used by Hogan with results comparable to the bomb dropped on Hiroshima, Hogan finally has gotten his wish. He ruined what might have been an enjoyable movie experience for two year olds and those who are "mentally challenged" or retards as Hogan's faithful redneck fans may call them. I am not surprised at how bad this film turned out. Wrestling fans with half a brain have hated Hogan for years. He exercises creative control when he is told that he is going to lose and this ends up boring anyone with a below average iq on up to tears. Hogan may have turned wrestling into a million dollar industry with a lot of help from the master marketing machine named Vince Mcmahon. Many good people sacrificed their wrestling careers by falling prey to Hogan's trademark "leg drop of doom" and now some poor director is probably living under a bridge in Los Angeles damning the day he got involved with Hulk Hogan. Hogan may have helped turn wrestling into mainstream entertainment, but he also singlehandedly destroyed the same industry(his tired act help put WCW into the ground) he helped build by never learning more than three moves. Punch, back scratch, high boot and leg drop. Oops that is four moves. Some things never change. In the ring the bad guy always loses to Hulk via leg drop. In the movies, Hogan expands his creative horizons by having the bad guy lose via Plastic candy Kane.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Watch out, he's got laughter and smiles!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Seth Nelson
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/2/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "He" referring to Hulk Hogan, which I consider the America's Tor Johnson. Tor starred in many bad movies; so does Hulk. Both are very funny in each of their performances! In my opinion, "Santa with Muscles" is where all the fun and the laughs are! Hearing that "Eegah"-like "Watch out, he's got a candy cane!" makes me laugh until I cry! And I laugh so much, I cry until I can do neither of those things anymore! That's the secret recipe for a great family holiday film: Laughs + Good Clean Family Fun (none of that "Bad Santa" stuff, please!) = The Best Holiday Family Film In The History Of The Universe! Let "Santa with Muscles" be the centerpiece of your entertainment next Christmas!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Just because it's a kids film doesn't mean you can get away with poor quality.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Anders Twetman
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is actually not that bad. Don't get me wrong here, it is by no means a good movie but compare to some some of it's neighbors on the bottom #100 list, Santa with Muscles is pretty watchable. It has a consistent narrative, all be it an inane one. There are well defined characters, flat as cardboard they may be, but at least they act consistently throughout the film. And best of all, the humor comes naturally, the jokes don't feel as forced as they do in Epic Movie or other bad comedies. I have some nitpicks though. First, the bad guy is having people tortured in his back yard, how is he not in prison already? The henchmen destroy property, threaten people an nearly kill a guy, why does no one call the police? When trying to catch the hero for speeding, the police try to shoot him with a rocket launcher, why is internal affairs not there arresting these murderous coppers? Not to mention, why does the police even have a rocket launcher? Questions like this keep popping up but that just makes the film more entertaining Now, this a children's movie and as such less effort has gone into the details of making it, thus the plot is too simplistic, the characters, especially the bad guys are just ridiculous and the acting leaves a lot to ask. Given that there are good, well made children's films out there, having a younger audience is no excuse for making a bad film. Good enough for children maybe, but not good.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    To those who wonder why Hulk Hogan's acting career never got off the ground...watch "Santa with Muscles".
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Boba_Fett1138
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/7/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    You know that a movie is really bad when it makes you feel psychically ill. This for me was really the case with "Santa with Muscles". It's amazing how many bad Christmas/Santa Claus movies for kids are around. But this movie is even below the normal level of Santa Claus movies, that are made for kids. It's very obviously a movie that got aimed toward young children but just because it's a kids movie doesn't mean it can get away just with everything. But also on top of that; I really can't see how kids could ever enjoy watching this movie. It really isn't that entertaining or humorous to watch because of some serious bad writing. If I had seen this movie as kid it probably wouldn't had annoyed me as much as it did now but I probably would still had been bored out of my skull while watching it. I don't even know what this movie is supposed to be all about. It's such an huge mess to watch and it feels like the script got put together from a couple of other different Santa Claus scripts they had floating around somewhere in a dark corner. The movie too often doesn't make sense and it's a very inconsistent one to watch, since the story jumps all over the place and doesn't seem to know what it wants. What the story is also lacking is a good Christmas message in it. This movie has absolutely none and isn't even about the Christmas spirit at all. Who wants to watch a Santa Claus movie that isn't even somewhat remotely Christmas related. It always has been sort of a mystery as to why Hulk Hogan's acting career never took off. He had the right looks and charisma and was and still is incredibly popular and well known, all over the world, due to his wrestling career. And hey, if Dwayne Johnson and Arnold Schwarzenegger have a big acting career, with similar backgrounds, than why couldn't he? The answer is in movies like this. He made some bad choices with his picks for movies and the highlights of his acting career are cameos in some well known movies, in which he only spoofs himself. So Hulk Hogan doesn't impress much with this movie but so does nobody else in this. The movie made some weird casting choices, by making Steve Valentine and Ed Begley Jr. the main villains. When you have Hulk Hogan as your main hero, you need a strong and way more threatening villain opposing him, not two lab-geeks. It still gets points for having Clint Howard and a very young Mila Kunis in it though. What also puzzles me is if this is supposed to be a Christmas movie than why does this movie look all the time like it got shot in the middle of the summer? Couldn't they at least somewhat tried to fake it. To be honest, I don't think I'll ever put this movie on any of my worst movie lists but that is simply because I have seen so many bad movies, that are even in one way or another worse than this one. But of course that really doesn't make "Santa with Muscles" somewhat of a good or a remotely entertaining watch. Just avoid, it's not even watchable for its cult-value. 3/10 http://bobafett1138.blogspot.com/
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Worse than an evening with bin Laden, Michael Jackson and Hitler.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    LoonyAaron
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/12/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    What can really be said about a film like this? Well, let's start with a little background information about the leading man. Terry 'Hulk Hogan' Boella is the most selfish man in the wrestling business. He never put over anyone, he can't sell whatsoever and he tried to sabotage Bret Hart's career. He even disrespect Shawn Michaels - SHAWN FREAKING MICHAELS. The Heart-Break Kid! The Icon! The Showstoppa'! MR. WRESTLEMANIA! So when the Hulkster is tasked with playing an obnoxious, egotistical, vapid, sexually confused plutocrat it is by far the most convincing part of this abortion of a movie. He hires his buddy Ed Leslie to play an Asian doctor - correct, an EVIL Asian doctor. Ed Leslie, the man who couldn't get over playing a stripper/barber. Ed Leslie, the man who caused a terrorist scare when people mistook his COCAINE for anthrax. The fact that this man was in the wrestling business for so long is bad enough, but for the love of God and Scorsese, blacklist him from cinema! This movie is awful, truly awful in every way. You see, there's an orphanage and it's going to get blown up. And when the poor children need someone to rely on, who do they turn to? The cops? A responsible grown up? No, poor old steroid-addict Hulk Hogan. He rambles through the script like a diabetic monkey, delivering dialogue so hideous it would make Vince Price (God rest his soul) blanch. And then, at the end of the movie, this disturbed mental patient, makes a bunch of orphans live alone with him in his secluded mansion. Everything about this film is wrong, everything about this film should be buried in the Nevada desert alongside Jimmy Hoffa and those copies of the ET video game. Do not watch this movie. No, not even if you are told to do so by your Mother on her death bed. This is tripe of the highest order and will actually make you question your sexual orientation. At one part, Hogan begins wearing a fetish Santa suit complete with tight leather boots and an S&M belt. I wish I was making this up. Please, just let this film die a slow and painful death.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Grinch did not steal Christmas...this film did!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    planktonrules
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/1/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    If ever there was a family holiday film that could kill the holiday spirit, this film is it. It makes "Jingle All the Way" and even "Santa Claus Conquers the Martians" seem GOOD in comparison! And, if you ever meet anyone who hates Christmas, chances are that they saw this film! This movie is a cloying, annoying dud...the sort of contrived mess of a film that makes you want to tell Hollywood to STOP making holiday movies if this is the sort of crap they think the public could want! The film begins with Hulk Hogan playing some sort of combination rich guy, superhero, GI Joe wannabe and ninja. I am glad that his impressions of himself and his abilities are not in any way over-ambitious or egocentric! In a stupid freak accident, the Hulkster now thinks he's Santa and comes to the aid...I kid you not...of a home for orphans!! Folks, it just doesn't get any worse than this--or does it?! Well, in fact it does. You see, the evil man behind this is, naturally, Ed Begley, Jr. and I assume he wanted this property to build an electric car dealership. But, in a bizarre twist, it's to get a whole bunch of neon-like power crystals hidden in an underground vault! Say what?!?!? Begley's crew of evil villains look like the sort of baddies that might attack Barney the dinosaur. They are all really, really lame and are about as threatening as a mild case of dandruff. And, it's up to Hulk to kick some butt (wow, not a tough thing in this case), win the hearts of a whole bunch of cute moppets AND manage to make a family-friendly movie that involves lots of punching, kicking and other forms of violence! The film has absolutely nothing going for it other than Hogan's massive ego. The acting is crap, the script is crap, the action is crap and there is nothing...I repeat, NOTHING of any value to this steaming pile of....movie. What makes it worse is the 'surprise' twist concerning the villain and Hulk's childhood--which, oddly, neither seemed to remember! Sadly, anyone seeing this turkey of a film will not have the same thing occur--they'll never forget having wasted nearly an hour and a half on this snot-fest. This film easily deserves to be on IMDb's Bottom 100 list, as it's the worst vanity project I've seen in ages--and a family film which is too violent and stupid for kids and just about impossible for any adult to sit through without massive amounts of liquor. My favorite part of the film? Towards the end, one of the lame villains yells "It's gonna blow!!". He couldn't have been more right, though he probably should have said this at the beginning in order to warn people what they were in for seeing! I think I'd have rather seen "Chitty, Chitty Bang, Bang", "The Adventures of Pippi Longstocking" or even "Son of the Mask" instead of this movie--it was that bad! By the way, there is a worse Christmas film. The 1959 Mexican film "Santa Claus" is in the Bottom 100 as well and it is light-years worse! But, for a big-budget Hollywood Christmas story, "Santa With Muscles" takes the prize!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Only in a movie this awful...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ij-holmes
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/11/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    ...could you find a wrestler playing a millionaire who thinks he's Santa Claus sword fighting a guy in an astronaut suit with a crystal broken off from a mine underneath a church. When you have that picture in your mind, you've already seen the only part of this movie worth watching, if you can even call it that. Don't watch this movie. Don't rent this movie. Don't stay on the channel on which this movie is playing. Forget this movie exists. If you must see it, make sure you are compensated financially for your trouble. If you can avoid seeing it, AVOID IT. You'll be doing your brain a favor.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    What the Hell was this?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jts0405
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/8/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Santa With Muscles is supposed to be a comedy, I guess, but it really doesn't bring the laughs at all. You don't find yourself laughing with the movie, but instead laughing at it and how incredibly cheesy it is. Hulk Hogan really needed to take his name off the project, because it would've done him a lot of good in his shortly lived acting career. I don't even get the plot to all of this, he is a millionaire that thinks he's Santa Claus, wow a preschooler could come up with that idea and make this whole movie look a lot better in the process. I am not bashing Hogan, because I did like him as a wrestler but as an actor the stuff he has done has really sucked. This belongs on the bottom 100. 1/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Best, Movie, Ever.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    James Miller
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/7/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Well now, this was probably one of the most fantastic pieces of movie literature to ever be produced within this day and age of cinematography Hulk Hogan is the greatest actor of all time, and he is also, the greatest wrestler to ever, take foot within the wrestling ring. Now, I am a hulkamaniac. Best movie ever Best movie ever Best movie ever. 10/10b Nothing beats seeing a movie about Santa, with fight scenes, thieves trying to steal crystals from an orphanage with Hulk Hogan, the man with a plan, coming in and desecrating the enemies ! pewpew !
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Santa, you sleigh me!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    lastliberal
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/12/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    OK, this is probably the absolutely worst Christmas program ever! No, it is not as bad as Feeders 2: Slay Bells, but for a Christmas show it is pretty bad. Hulk Hogan may have been a good wrestler, but he certainly cannot act. Here he bumps his head and thinks he's Santa. He is up against a group of real clowns led by Ed Begley, Jr. Steve Valentine from "Crossing Jordan" and more Grade Z actors. The only redeeming performance was little Aria Noelle Curzon, who was nine at the time. Cross this one off your Christmas list.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Hulkster must smoke rock
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    lodi_70005
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/8/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I am sure most of the posters here are not wrestling fans. Therefore, I will clue you in on a couple of things. Hulk Hogan is an ego maniacal jackass that demands creative control over anything he is involved in. This movie might not have been a classic when it was first written, but I will be fair and say it had average potential(a rating of 5). The movie probably had a different title at first until......Hulkamania arrived. Hulk Hogan has this remarkable ability to turn something good or average into unwatchable garbage. Original title may have been "When Santa got Rich" or "Santa CEO" or something slightly stupid. Hogan looks at the title and says "no way brother, my fans don't know nothing about no CEO(the first true words to come out of the mouth of the Hulkster in twenty years). So he called it "Santa with Muscles" because no project involving Hogan is allowed to go 5 seconds without referring to the "24 inch pythons" After adding scenes where blow up candy canes are used by Hogan with results comparable to the bomb dropped on Hiroshima, Hogan finally has gotten his wish. He ruined what might have been an enjoyable movie experience for two year olds and those who are "mentally challenged" or retards as Hogan's faithful redneck fans may call them. I am not surprised at how bad this film turned out. Wrestling fans with half a brain have hated Hogan for years. He exercises creative control when he is told that he is going to lose and this ends up boring anyone with a below average iq on up to tears. Hogan may have turned wrestling into a million dollar industry with a lot of help from the master marketing machine named Vince Mcmahon. Many good people sacrificed their wrestling careers by falling prey to Hogan's trademark "leg drop of doom" and now some poor director is probably living under a bridge in Los Angeles damning the day he got involved with Hulk Hogan. Hogan may have helped turn wrestling into mainstream entertainment, but he also singlehandedly destroyed the same industry(his tired act help put WCW into the ground) he helped build by never learning more than three moves. Punch, back scratch, high boot and leg drop. Oops that is four moves. Some things never change. In the ring the bad guy always loses to Hulk via leg drop. In the movies, Hogan expands his creative horizons by having the bad guy lose via Plastic candy Kane.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Watch out, he's got laughter and smiles!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Seth Nelson
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/2/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "He" referring to Hulk Hogan, which I consider the America's Tor Johnson. Tor starred in many bad movies; so does Hulk. Both are very funny in each of their performances! In my opinion, "Santa with Muscles" is where all the fun and the laughs are! Hearing that "Eegah"-like "Watch out, he's got a candy cane!" makes me laugh until I cry! And I laugh so much, I cry until I can do neither of those things anymore! That's the secret recipe for a great family holiday film: Laughs + Good Clean Family Fun (none of that "Bad Santa" stuff, please!) = The Best Holiday Family Film In The History Of The Universe! Let "Santa with Muscles" be the centerpiece of your entertainment next Christmas!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Just because it's a kids film doesn't mean you can get away with poor quality.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Anders Twetman
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is actually not that bad. Don't get me wrong here, it is by no means a good movie but compare to some some of it's neighbors on the bottom #100 list, Santa with Muscles is pretty watchable. It has a consistent narrative, all be it an inane one. There are well defined characters, flat as cardboard they may be, but at least they act consistently throughout the film. And best of all, the humor comes naturally, the jokes don't feel as forced as they do in Epic Movie or other bad comedies. I have some nitpicks though. First, the bad guy is having people tortured in his back yard, how is he not in prison already? The henchmen destroy property, threaten people an nearly kill a guy, why does no one call the police? When trying to catch the hero for speeding, the police try to shoot him with a rocket launcher, why is internal affairs not there arresting these murderous coppers? Not to mention, why does the police even have a rocket launcher? Questions like this keep popping up but that just makes the film more entertaining Now, this a children's movie and as such less effort has gone into the details of making it, thus the plot is too simplistic, the characters, especially the bad guys are just ridiculous and the acting leaves a lot to ask. Given that there are good, well made children's films out there, having a younger audience is no excuse for making a bad film. Good enough for children maybe, but not good.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    To those who wonder why Hulk Hogan's acting career never got off the ground...watch "Santa with Muscles".
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Boba_Fett1138
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/7/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    You know that a movie is really bad when it makes you feel psychically ill. This for me was really the case with "Santa with Muscles". It's amazing how many bad Christmas/Santa Claus movies for kids are around. But this movie is even below the normal level of Santa Claus movies, that are made for kids. It's very obviously a movie that got aimed toward young children but just because it's a kids movie doesn't mean it can get away just with everything. But also on top of that; I really can't see how kids could ever enjoy watching this movie. It really isn't that entertaining or humorous to watch because of some serious bad writing. If I had seen this movie as kid it probably wouldn't had annoyed me as much as it did now but I probably would still had been bored out of my skull while watching it. I don't even know what this movie is supposed to be all about. It's such an huge mess to watch and it feels like the script got put together from a couple of other different Santa Claus scripts they had floating around somewhere in a dark corner. The movie too often doesn't make sense and it's a very inconsistent one to watch, since the story jumps all over the place and doesn't seem to know what it wants. What the story is also lacking is a good Christmas message in it. This movie has absolutely none and isn't even about the Christmas spirit at all. Who wants to watch a Santa Claus movie that isn't even somewhat remotely Christmas related. It always has been sort of a mystery as to why Hulk Hogan's acting career never took off. He had the right looks and charisma and was and still is incredibly popular and well known, all over the world, due to his wrestling career. And hey, if Dwayne Johnson and Arnold Schwarzenegger have a big acting career, with similar backgrounds, than why couldn't he? The answer is in movies like this. He made some bad choices with his picks for movies and the highlights of his acting career are cameos in some well known movies, in which he only spoofs himself. So Hulk Hogan doesn't impress much with this movie but so does nobody else in this. The movie made some weird casting choices, by making Steve Valentine and Ed Begley Jr. the main villains. When you have Hulk Hogan as your main hero, you need a strong and way more threatening villain opposing him, not two lab-geeks. It still gets points for having Clint Howard and a very young Mila Kunis in it though. What also puzzles me is if this is supposed to be a Christmas movie than why does this movie look all the time like it got shot in the middle of the summer? Couldn't they at least somewhat tried to fake it. To be honest, I don't think I'll ever put this movie on any of my worst movie lists but that is simply because I have seen so many bad movies, that are even in one way or another worse than this one. But of course that really doesn't make "Santa with Muscles" somewhat of a good or a remotely entertaining watch. Just avoid, it's not even watchable for its cult-value. 3/10 http://bobafett1138.blogspot.com/
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Worse than an evening with bin Laden, Michael Jackson and Hitler.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    LoonyAaron
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/12/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    What can really be said about a film like this? Well, let's start with a little background information about the leading man. Terry 'Hulk Hogan' Boella is the most selfish man in the wrestling business. He never put over anyone, he can't sell whatsoever and he tried to sabotage Bret Hart's career. He even disrespect Shawn Michaels - SHAWN FREAKING MICHAELS. The Heart-Break Kid! The Icon! The Showstoppa'! MR. WRESTLEMANIA! So when the Hulkster is tasked with playing an obnoxious, egotistical, vapid, sexually confused plutocrat it is by far the most convincing part of this abortion of a movie. He hires his buddy Ed Leslie to play an Asian doctor - correct, an EVIL Asian doctor. Ed Leslie, the man who couldn't get over playing a stripper/barber. Ed Leslie, the man who caused a terrorist scare when people mistook his COCAINE for anthrax. The fact that this man was in the wrestling business for so long is bad enough, but for the love of God and Scorsese, blacklist him from cinema! This movie is awful, truly awful in every way. You see, there's an orphanage and it's going to get blown up. And when the poor children need someone to rely on, who do they turn to? The cops? A responsible grown up? No, poor old steroid-addict Hulk Hogan. He rambles through the script like a diabetic monkey, delivering dialogue so hideous it would make Vince Price (God rest his soul) blanch. And then, at the end of the movie, this disturbed mental patient, makes a bunch of orphans live alone with him in his secluded mansion. Everything about this film is wrong, everything about this film should be buried in the Nevada desert alongside Jimmy Hoffa and those copies of the ET video game. Do not watch this movie. No, not even if you are told to do so by your Mother on her death bed. This is tripe of the highest order and will actually make you question your sexual orientation. At one part, Hogan begins wearing a fetish Santa suit complete with tight leather boots and an S&M belt. I wish I was making this up. Please, just let this film die a slow and painful death.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Grinch did not steal Christmas...this film did!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    planktonrules
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/1/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    If ever there was a family holiday film that could kill the holiday spirit, this film is it. It makes "Jingle All the Way" and even "Santa Claus Conquers the Martians" seem GOOD in comparison! And, if you ever meet anyone who hates Christmas, chances are that they saw this film! This movie is a cloying, annoying dud...the sort of contrived mess of a film that makes you want to tell Hollywood to STOP making holiday movies if this is the sort of crap they think the public could want! The film begins with Hulk Hogan playing some sort of combination rich guy, superhero, GI Joe wannabe and ninja. I am glad that his impressions of himself and his abilities are not in any way over-ambitious or egocentric! In a stupid freak accident, the Hulkster now thinks he's Santa and comes to the aid...I kid you not...of a home for orphans!! Folks, it just doesn't get any worse than this--or does it?! Well, in fact it does. You see, the evil man behind this is, naturally, Ed Begley, Jr. and I assume he wanted this property to build an electric car dealership. But, in a bizarre twist, it's to get a whole bunch of neon-like power crystals hidden in an underground vault! Say what?!?!? Begley's crew of evil villains look like the sort of baddies that might attack Barney the dinosaur. They are all really, really lame and are about as threatening as a mild case of dandruff. And, it's up to Hulk to kick some butt (wow, not a tough thing in this case), win the hearts of a whole bunch of cute moppets AND manage to make a family-friendly movie that involves lots of punching, kicking and other forms of violence! The film has absolutely nothing going for it other than Hogan's massive ego. The acting is crap, the script is crap, the action is crap and there is nothing...I repeat, NOTHING of any value to this steaming pile of....movie. What makes it worse is the 'surprise' twist concerning the villain and Hulk's childhood--which, oddly, neither seemed to remember! Sadly, anyone seeing this turkey of a film will not have the same thing occur--they'll never forget having wasted nearly an hour and a half on this snot-fest. This film easily deserves to be on IMDb's Bottom 100 list, as it's the worst vanity project I've seen in ages--and a family film which is too violent and stupid for kids and just about impossible for any adult to sit through without massive amounts of liquor. My favorite part of the film? Towards the end, one of the lame villains yells "It's gonna blow!!". He couldn't have been more right, though he probably should have said this at the beginning in order to warn people what they were in for seeing! I think I'd have rather seen "Chitty, Chitty Bang, Bang", "The Adventures of Pippi Longstocking" or even "Son of the Mask" instead of this movie--it was that bad! By the way, there is a worse Christmas film. The 1959 Mexican film "Santa Claus" is in the Bottom 100 as well and it is light-years worse! But, for a big-budget Hollywood Christmas story, "Santa With Muscles" takes the prize!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Only in a movie this awful...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ij-holmes
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/11/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    ...could you find a wrestler playing a millionaire who thinks he's Santa Claus sword fighting a guy in an astronaut suit with a crystal broken off from a mine underneath a church. When you have that picture in your mind, you've already seen the only part of this movie worth watching, if you can even call it that. Don't watch this movie. Don't rent this movie. Don't stay on the channel on which this movie is playing. Forget this movie exists. If you must see it, make sure you are compensated financially for your trouble. If you can avoid seeing it, AVOID IT. You'll be doing your brain a favor.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    What the Hell was this?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jts0405
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/8/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Santa With Muscles is supposed to be a comedy, I guess, but it really doesn't bring the laughs at all. You don't find yourself laughing with the movie, but instead laughing at it and how incredibly cheesy it is. Hulk Hogan really needed to take his name off the project, because it would've done him a lot of good in his shortly lived acting career. I don't even get the plot to all of this, he is a millionaire that thinks he's Santa Claus, wow a preschooler could come up with that idea and make this whole movie look a lot better in the process. I am not bashing Hogan, because I did like him as a wrestler but as an actor the stuff he has done has really sucked. This belongs on the bottom 100. 1/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Best, Movie, Ever.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    James Miller
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/7/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Well now, this was probably one of the most fantastic pieces of movie literature to ever be produced within this day and age of cinematography Hulk Hogan is the greatest actor of all time, and he is also, the greatest wrestler to ever, take foot within the wrestling ring. Now, I am a hulkamaniac. Best movie ever Best movie ever Best movie ever. 10/10b Nothing beats seeing a movie about Santa, with fight scenes, thieves trying to steal crystals from an orphanage with Hulk Hogan, the man with a plan, coming in and desecrating the enemies ! pewpew !
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Santa, you sleigh me!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    lastliberal
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/12/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    OK, this is probably the absolutely worst Christmas program ever! No, it is not as bad as Feeders 2: Slay Bells, but for a Christmas show it is pretty bad. Hulk Hogan may have been a good wrestler, but he certainly cannot act. Here he bumps his head and thinks he's Santa. He is up against a group of real clowns led by Ed Begley, Jr. Steve Valentine from "Crossing Jordan" and more Grade Z actors. The only redeeming performance was little Aria Noelle Curzon, who was nine at the time. Cross this one off your Christmas list.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Hulkster must smoke rock
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    lodi_70005
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/8/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I am sure most of the posters here are not wrestling fans. Therefore, I will clue you in on a couple of things. Hulk Hogan is an ego maniacal jackass that demands creative control over anything he is involved in. This movie might not have been a classic when it was first written, but I will be fair and say it had average potential(a rating of 5). The movie probably had a different title at first until......Hulkamania arrived. Hulk Hogan has this remarkable ability to turn something good or average into unwatchable garbage. Original title may have been "When Santa got Rich" or "Santa CEO" or something slightly stupid. Hogan looks at the title and says "no way brother, my fans don't know nothing about no CEO(the first true words to come out of the mouth of the Hulkster in twenty years). So he called it "Santa with Muscles" because no project involving Hogan is allowed to go 5 seconds without referring to the "24 inch pythons" After adding scenes where blow up candy canes are used by Hogan with results comparable to the bomb dropped on Hiroshima, Hogan finally has gotten his wish. He ruined what might have been an enjoyable movie experience for two year olds and those who are "mentally challenged" or retards as Hogan's faithful redneck fans may call them. I am not surprised at how bad this film turned out. Wrestling fans with half a brain have hated Hogan for years. He exercises creative control when he is told that he is going to lose and this ends up boring anyone with a below average iq on up to tears. Hogan may have turned wrestling into a million dollar industry with a lot of help from the master marketing machine named Vince Mcmahon. Many good people sacrificed their wrestling careers by falling prey to Hogan's trademark "leg drop of doom" and now some poor director is probably living under a bridge in Los Angeles damning the day he got involved with Hulk Hogan. Hogan may have helped turn wrestling into mainstream entertainment, but he also singlehandedly destroyed the same industry(his tired act help put WCW into the ground) he helped build by never learning more than three moves. Punch, back scratch, high boot and leg drop. Oops that is four moves. Some things never change. In the ring the bad guy always loses to Hulk via leg drop. In the movies, Hogan expands his creative horizons by having the bad guy lose via Plastic candy Kane.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Watch out, he's got laughter and smiles!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Seth Nelson
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/2/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "He" referring to Hulk Hogan, which I consider the America's Tor Johnson. Tor starred in many bad movies; so does Hulk. Both are very funny in each of their performances! In my opinion, "Santa with Muscles" is where all the fun and the laughs are! Hearing that "Eegah"-like "Watch out, he's got a candy cane!" makes me laugh until I cry! And I laugh so much, I cry until I can do neither of those things anymore! That's the secret recipe for a great family holiday film: Laughs + Good Clean Family Fun (none of that "Bad Santa" stuff, please!) = The Best Holiday Family Film In The History Of The Universe! Let "Santa with Muscles" be the centerpiece of your entertainment next Christmas!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Just because it's a kids film doesn't mean you can get away with poor quality.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Anders Twetman
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is actually not that bad. Don't get me wrong here, it is by no means a good movie but compare to some some of it's neighbors on the bottom #100 list, Santa with Muscles is pretty watchable. It has a consistent narrative, all be it an inane one. There are well defined characters, flat as cardboard they may be, but at least they act consistently throughout the film. And best of all, the humor comes naturally, the jokes don't feel as forced as they do in Epic Movie or other bad comedies. I have some nitpicks though. First, the bad guy is having people tortured in his back yard, how is he not in prison already? The henchmen destroy property, threaten people an nearly kill a guy, why does no one call the police? When trying to catch the hero for speeding, the police try to shoot him with a rocket launcher, why is internal affairs not there arresting these murderous coppers? Not to mention, why does the police even have a rocket launcher? Questions like this keep popping up but that just makes the film more entertaining Now, this a children's movie and as such less effort has gone into the details of making it, thus the plot is too simplistic, the characters, especially the bad guys are just ridiculous and the acting leaves a lot to ask. Given that there are good, well made children's films out there, having a younger audience is no excuse for making a bad film. Good enough for children maybe, but not good.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    To those who wonder why Hulk Hogan's acting career never got off the ground...watch "Santa with Muscles".
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Boba_Fett1138
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/7/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    You know that a movie is really bad when it makes you feel psychically ill. This for me was really the case with "Santa with Muscles". It's amazing how many bad Christmas/Santa Claus movies for kids are around. But this movie is even below the normal level of Santa Claus movies, that are made for kids. It's very obviously a movie that got aimed toward young children but just because it's a kids movie doesn't mean it can get away just with everything. But also on top of that; I really can't see how kids could ever enjoy watching this movie. It really isn't that entertaining or humorous to watch because of some serious bad writing. If I had seen this movie as kid it probably wouldn't had annoyed me as much as it did now but I probably would still had been bored out of my skull while watching it. I don't even know what this movie is supposed to be all about. It's such an huge mess to watch and it feels like the script got put together from a couple of other different Santa Claus scripts they had floating around somewhere in a dark corner. The movie too often doesn't make sense and it's a very inconsistent one to watch, since the story jumps all over the place and doesn't seem to know what it wants. What the story is also lacking is a good Christmas message in it. This movie has absolutely none and isn't even about the Christmas spirit at all. Who wants to watch a Santa Claus movie that isn't even somewhat remotely Christmas related. It always has been sort of a mystery as to why Hulk Hogan's acting career never took off. He had the right looks and charisma and was and still is incredibly popular and well known, all over the world, due to his wrestling career. And hey, if Dwayne Johnson and Arnold Schwarzenegger have a big acting career, with similar backgrounds, than why couldn't he? The answer is in movies like this. He made some bad choices with his picks for movies and the highlights of his acting career are cameos in some well known movies, in which he only spoofs himself. So Hulk Hogan doesn't impress much with this movie but so does nobody else in this. The movie made some weird casting choices, by making Steve Valentine and Ed Begley Jr. the main villains. When you have Hulk Hogan as your main hero, you need a strong and way more threatening villain opposing him, not two lab-geeks. It still gets points for having Clint Howard and a very young Mila Kunis in it though. What also puzzles me is if this is supposed to be a Christmas movie than why does this movie look all the time like it got shot in the middle of the summer? Couldn't they at least somewhat tried to fake it. To be honest, I don't think I'll ever put this movie on any of my worst movie lists but that is simply because I have seen so many bad movies, that are even in one way or another worse than this one. But of course that really doesn't make "Santa with Muscles" somewhat of a good or a remotely entertaining watch. Just avoid, it's not even watchable for its cult-value. 3/10 http://bobafett1138.blogspot.com/
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Worse than an evening with bin Laden, Michael Jackson and Hitler.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    LoonyAaron
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/12/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    What can really be said about a film like this? Well, let's start with a little background information about the leading man. Terry 'Hulk Hogan' Boella is the most selfish man in the wrestling business. He never put over anyone, he can't sell whatsoever and he tried to sabotage Bret Hart's career. He even disrespect Shawn Michaels - SHAWN FREAKING MICHAELS. The Heart-Break Kid! The Icon! The Showstoppa'! MR. WRESTLEMANIA! So when the Hulkster is tasked with playing an obnoxious, egotistical, vapid, sexually confused plutocrat it is by far the most convincing part of this abortion of a movie. He hires his buddy Ed Leslie to play an Asian doctor - correct, an EVIL Asian doctor. Ed Leslie, the man who couldn't get over playing a stripper/barber. Ed Leslie, the man who caused a terrorist scare when people mistook his COCAINE for anthrax. The fact that this man was in the wrestling business for so long is bad enough, but for the love of God and Scorsese, blacklist him from cinema! This movie is awful, truly awful in every way. You see, there's an orphanage and it's going to get blown up. And when the poor children need someone to rely on, who do they turn to? The cops? A responsible grown up? No, poor old steroid-addict Hulk Hogan. He rambles through the script like a diabetic monkey, delivering dialogue so hideous it would make Vince Price (God rest his soul) blanch. And then, at the end of the movie, this disturbed mental patient, makes a bunch of orphans live alone with him in his secluded mansion. Everything about this film is wrong, everything about this film should be buried in the Nevada desert alongside Jimmy Hoffa and those copies of the ET video game. Do not watch this movie. No, not even if you are told to do so by your Mother on her death bed. This is tripe of the highest order and will actually make you question your sexual orientation. At one part, Hogan begins wearing a fetish Santa suit complete with tight leather boots and an S&M belt. I wish I was making this up. Please, just let this film die a slow and painful death.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Grinch did not steal Christmas...this film did!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    planktonrules
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/1/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    If ever there was a family holiday film that could kill the holiday spirit, this film is it. It makes "Jingle All the Way" and even "Santa Claus Conquers the Martians" seem GOOD in comparison! And, if you ever meet anyone who hates Christmas, chances are that they saw this film! This movie is a cloying, annoying dud...the sort of contrived mess of a film that makes you want to tell Hollywood to STOP making holiday movies if this is the sort of crap they think the public could want! The film begins with Hulk Hogan playing some sort of combination rich guy, superhero, GI Joe wannabe and ninja. I am glad that his impressions of himself and his abilities are not in any way over-ambitious or egocentric! In a stupid freak accident, the Hulkster now thinks he's Santa and comes to the aid...I kid you not...of a home for orphans!! Folks, it just doesn't get any worse than this--or does it?! Well, in fact it does. You see, the evil man behind this is, naturally, Ed Begley, Jr. and I assume he wanted this property to build an electric car dealership. But, in a bizarre twist, it's to get a whole bunch of neon-like power crystals hidden in an underground vault! Say what?!?!? Begley's crew of evil villains look like the sort of baddies that might attack Barney the dinosaur. They are all really, really lame and are about as threatening as a mild case of dandruff. And, it's up to Hulk to kick some butt (wow, not a tough thing in this case), win the hearts of a whole bunch of cute moppets AND manage to make a family-friendly movie that involves lots of punching, kicking and other forms of violence! The film has absolutely nothing going for it other than Hogan's massive ego. The acting is crap, the script is crap, the action is crap and there is nothing...I repeat, NOTHING of any value to this steaming pile of....movie. What makes it worse is the 'surprise' twist concerning the villain and Hulk's childhood--which, oddly, neither seemed to remember! Sadly, anyone seeing this turkey of a film will not have the same thing occur--they'll never forget having wasted nearly an hour and a half on this snot-fest. This film easily deserves to be on IMDb's Bottom 100 list, as it's the worst vanity project I've seen in ages--and a family film which is too violent and stupid for kids and just about impossible for any adult to sit through without massive amounts of liquor. My favorite part of the film? Towards the end, one of the lame villains yells "It's gonna blow!!". He couldn't have been more right, though he probably should have said this at the beginning in order to warn people what they were in for seeing! I think I'd have rather seen "Chitty, Chitty Bang, Bang", "The Adventures of Pippi Longstocking" or even "Son of the Mask" instead of this movie--it was that bad! By the way, there is a worse Christmas film. The 1959 Mexican film "Santa Claus" is in the Bottom 100 as well and it is light-years worse! But, for a big-budget Hollywood Christmas story, "Santa With Muscles" takes the prize!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Only in a movie this awful...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ij-holmes
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/11/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    ...could you find a wrestler playing a millionaire who thinks he's Santa Claus sword fighting a guy in an astronaut suit with a crystal broken off from a mine underneath a church. When you have that picture in your mind, you've already seen the only part of this movie worth watching, if you can even call it that. Don't watch this movie. Don't rent this movie. Don't stay on the channel on which this movie is playing. Forget this movie exists. If you must see it, make sure you are compensated financially for your trouble. If you can avoid seeing it, AVOID IT. You'll be doing your brain a favor.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    What the Hell was this?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jts0405
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/8/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Santa With Muscles is supposed to be a comedy, I guess, but it really doesn't bring the laughs at all. You don't find yourself laughing with the movie, but instead laughing at it and how incredibly cheesy it is. Hulk Hogan really needed to take his name off the project, because it would've done him a lot of good in his shortly lived acting career. I don't even get the plot to all of this, he is a millionaire that thinks he's Santa Claus, wow a preschooler could come up with that idea and make this whole movie look a lot better in the process. I am not bashing Hogan, because I did like him as a wrestler but as an actor the stuff he has done has really sucked. This belongs on the bottom 100. 1/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Best, Movie, Ever.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    James Miller
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/7/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Well now, this was probably one of the most fantastic pieces of movie literature to ever be produced within this day and age of cinematography Hulk Hogan is the greatest actor of all time, and he is also, the greatest wrestler to ever, take foot within the wrestling ring. Now, I am a hulkamaniac. Best movie ever Best movie ever Best movie ever. 10/10b Nothing beats seeing a movie about Santa, with fight scenes, thieves trying to steal crystals from an orphanage with Hulk Hogan, the man with a plan, coming in and desecrating the enemies ! pewpew !
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Santa, you sleigh me!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    lastliberal
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/12/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    OK, this is probably the absolutely worst Christmas program ever! No, it is not as bad as Feeders 2: Slay Bells, but for a Christmas show it is pretty bad. Hulk Hogan may have been a good wrestler, but he certainly cannot act. Here he bumps his head and thinks he's Santa. He is up against a group of real clowns led by Ed Begley, Jr. Steve Valentine from "Crossing Jordan" and more Grade Z actors. The only redeeming performance was little Aria Noelle Curzon, who was nine at the time. Cross this one off your Christmas list.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Hulkster must smoke rock
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    lodi_70005
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/8/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I am sure most of the posters here are not wrestling fans. Therefore, I will clue you in on a couple of things. Hulk Hogan is an ego maniacal jackass that demands creative control over anything he is involved in. This movie might not have been a classic when it was first written, but I will be fair and say it had average potential(a rating of 5). The movie probably had a different title at first until......Hulkamania arrived. Hulk Hogan has this remarkable ability to turn something good or average into unwatchable garbage. Original title may have been "When Santa got Rich" or "Santa CEO" or something slightly stupid. Hogan looks at the title and says "no way brother, my fans don't know nothing about no CEO(the first true words to come out of the mouth of the Hulkster in twenty years). So he called it "Santa with Muscles" because no project involving Hogan is allowed to go 5 seconds without referring to the "24 inch pythons" After adding scenes where blow up candy canes are used by Hogan with results comparable to the bomb dropped on Hiroshima, Hogan finally has gotten his wish. He ruined what might have been an enjoyable movie experience for two year olds and those who are "mentally challenged" or retards as Hogan's faithful redneck fans may call them. I am not surprised at how bad this film turned out. Wrestling fans with half a brain have hated Hogan for years. He exercises creative control when he is told that he is going to lose and this ends up boring anyone with a below average iq on up to tears. Hogan may have turned wrestling into a million dollar industry with a lot of help from the master marketing machine named Vince Mcmahon. Many good people sacrificed their wrestling careers by falling prey to Hogan's trademark "leg drop of doom" and now some poor director is probably living under a bridge in Los Angeles damning the day he got involved with Hulk Hogan. Hogan may have helped turn wrestling into mainstream entertainment, but he also singlehandedly destroyed the same industry(his tired act help put WCW into the ground) he helped build by never learning more than three moves. Punch, back scratch, high boot and leg drop. Oops that is four moves. Some things never change. In the ring the bad guy always loses to Hulk via leg drop. In the movies, Hogan expands his creative horizons by having the bad guy lose via Plastic candy Kane.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Watch out, he's got laughter and smiles!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Seth Nelson
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/2/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "He" referring to Hulk Hogan, which I consider the America's Tor Johnson. Tor starred in many bad movies; so does Hulk. Both are very funny in each of their performances! In my opinion, "Santa with Muscles" is where all the fun and the laughs are! Hearing that "Eegah"-like "Watch out, he's got a candy cane!" makes me laugh until I cry! And I laugh so much, I cry until I can do neither of those things anymore! That's the secret recipe for a great family holiday film: Laughs + Good Clean Family Fun (none of that "Bad Santa" stuff, please!) = The Best Holiday Family Film In The History Of The Universe! Let "Santa with Muscles" be the centerpiece of your entertainment next Christmas!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Just because it's a kids film doesn't mean you can get away with poor quality.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Anders Twetman
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is actually not that bad. Don't get me wrong here, it is by no means a good movie but compare to some some of it's neighbors on the bottom #100 list, Santa with Muscles is pretty watchable. It has a consistent narrative, all be it an inane one. There are well defined characters, flat as cardboard they may be, but at least they act consistently throughout the film. And best of all, the humor comes naturally, the jokes don't feel as forced as they do in Epic Movie or other bad comedies. I have some nitpicks though. First, the bad guy is having people tortured in his back yard, how is he not in prison already? The henchmen destroy property, threaten people an nearly kill a guy, why does no one call the police? When trying to catch the hero for speeding, the police try to shoot him with a rocket launcher, why is internal affairs not there arresting these murderous coppers? Not to mention, why does the police even have a rocket launcher? Questions like this keep popping up but that just makes the film more entertaining Now, this a children's movie and as such less effort has gone into the details of making it, thus the plot is too simplistic, the characters, especially the bad guys are just ridiculous and the acting leaves a lot to ask. Given that there are good, well made children's films out there, having a younger audience is no excuse for making a bad film. Good enough for children maybe, but not good.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    To those who wonder why Hulk Hogan's acting career never got off the ground...watch "Santa with Muscles".
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Boba_Fett1138
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/7/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    You know that a movie is really bad when it makes you feel psychically ill. This for me was really the case with "Santa with Muscles". It's amazing how many bad Christmas/Santa Claus movies for kids are around. But this movie is even below the normal level of Santa Claus movies, that are made for kids. It's very obviously a movie that got aimed toward young children but just because it's a kids movie doesn't mean it can get away just with everything. But also on top of that; I really can't see how kids could ever enjoy watching this movie. It really isn't that entertaining or humorous to watch because of some serious bad writing. If I had seen this movie as kid it probably wouldn't had annoyed me as much as it did now but I probably would still had been bored out of my skull while watching it. I don't even know what this movie is supposed to be all about. It's such an huge mess to watch and it feels like the script got put together from a couple of other different Santa Claus scripts they had floating around somewhere in a dark corner. The movie too often doesn't make sense and it's a very inconsistent one to watch, since the story jumps all over the place and doesn't seem to know what it wants. What the story is also lacking is a good Christmas message in it. This movie has absolutely none and isn't even about the Christmas spirit at all. Who wants to watch a Santa Claus movie that isn't even somewhat remotely Christmas related. It always has been sort of a mystery as to why Hulk Hogan's acting career never took off. He had the right looks and charisma and was and still is incredibly popular and well known, all over the world, due to his wrestling career. And hey, if Dwayne Johnson and Arnold Schwarzenegger have a big acting career, with similar backgrounds, than why couldn't he? The answer is in movies like this. He made some bad choices with his picks for movies and the highlights of his acting career are cameos in some well known movies, in which he only spoofs himself. So Hulk Hogan doesn't impress much with this movie but so does nobody else in this. The movie made some weird casting choices, by making Steve Valentine and Ed Begley Jr. the main villains. When you have Hulk Hogan as your main hero, you need a strong and way more threatening villain opposing him, not two lab-geeks. It still gets points for having Clint Howard and a very young Mila Kunis in it though. What also puzzles me is if this is supposed to be a Christmas movie than why does this movie look all the time like it got shot in the middle of the summer? Couldn't they at least somewhat tried to fake it. To be honest, I don't think I'll ever put this movie on any of my worst movie lists but that is simply because I have seen so many bad movies, that are even in one way or another worse than this one. But of course that really doesn't make "Santa with Muscles" somewhat of a good or a remotely entertaining watch. Just avoid, it's not even watchable for its cult-value. 3/10 http://bobafett1138.blogspot.com/
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Worse than an evening with bin Laden, Michael Jackson and Hitler.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    LoonyAaron
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/12/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    What can really be said about a film like this? Well, let's start with a little background information about the leading man. Terry 'Hulk Hogan' Boella is the most selfish man in the wrestling business. He never put over anyone, he can't sell whatsoever and he tried to sabotage Bret Hart's career. He even disrespect Shawn Michaels - SHAWN FREAKING MICHAELS. The Heart-Break Kid! The Icon! The Showstoppa'! MR. WRESTLEMANIA! So when the Hulkster is tasked with playing an obnoxious, egotistical, vapid, sexually confused plutocrat it is by far the most convincing part of this abortion of a movie. He hires his buddy Ed Leslie to play an Asian doctor - correct, an EVIL Asian doctor. Ed Leslie, the man who couldn't get over playing a stripper/barber. Ed Leslie, the man who caused a terrorist scare when people mistook his COCAINE for anthrax. The fact that this man was in the wrestling business for so long is bad enough, but for the love of God and Scorsese, blacklist him from cinema! This movie is awful, truly awful in every way. You see, there's an orphanage and it's going to get blown up. And when the poor children need someone to rely on, who do they turn to? The cops? A responsible grown up? No, poor old steroid-addict Hulk Hogan. He rambles through the script like a diabetic monkey, delivering dialogue so hideous it would make Vince Price (God rest his soul) blanch. And then, at the end of the movie, this disturbed mental patient, makes a bunch of orphans live alone with him in his secluded mansion. Everything about this film is wrong, everything about this film should be buried in the Nevada desert alongside Jimmy Hoffa and those copies of the ET video game. Do not watch this movie. No, not even if you are told to do so by your Mother on her death bed. This is tripe of the highest order and will actually make you question your sexual orientation. At one part, Hogan begins wearing a fetish Santa suit complete with tight leather boots and an S&M belt. I wish I was making this up. Please, just let this film die a slow and painful death.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Grinch did not steal Christmas...this film did!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    planktonrules
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/1/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    If ever there was a family holiday film that could kill the holiday spirit, this film is it. It makes "Jingle All the Way" and even "Santa Claus Conquers the Martians" seem GOOD in comparison! And, if you ever meet anyone who hates Christmas, chances are that they saw this film! This movie is a cloying, annoying dud...the sort of contrived mess of a film that makes you want to tell Hollywood to STOP making holiday movies if this is the sort of crap they think the public could want! The film begins with Hulk Hogan playing some sort of combination rich guy, superhero, GI Joe wannabe and ninja. I am glad that his impressions of himself and his abilities are not in any way over-ambitious or egocentric! In a stupid freak accident, the Hulkster now thinks he's Santa and comes to the aid...I kid you not...of a home for orphans!! Folks, it just doesn't get any worse than this--or does it?! Well, in fact it does. You see, the evil man behind this is, naturally, Ed Begley, Jr. and I assume he wanted this property to build an electric car dealership. But, in a bizarre twist, it's to get a whole bunch of neon-like power crystals hidden in an underground vault! Say what?!?!? Begley's crew of evil villains look like the sort of baddies that might attack Barney the dinosaur. They are all really, really lame and are about as threatening as a mild case of dandruff. And, it's up to Hulk to kick some butt (wow, not a tough thing in this case), win the hearts of a whole bunch of cute moppets AND manage to make a family-friendly movie that involves lots of punching, kicking and other forms of violence! The film has absolutely nothing going for it other than Hogan's massive ego. The acting is crap, the script is crap, the action is crap and there is nothing...I repeat, NOTHING of any value to this steaming pile of....movie. What makes it worse is the 'surprise' twist concerning the villain and Hulk's childhood--which, oddly, neither seemed to remember! Sadly, anyone seeing this turkey of a film will not have the same thing occur--they'll never forget having wasted nearly an hour and a half on this snot-fest. This film easily deserves to be on IMDb's Bottom 100 list, as it's the worst vanity project I've seen in ages--and a family film which is too violent and stupid for kids and just about impossible for any adult to sit through without massive amounts of liquor. My favorite part of the film? Towards the end, one of the lame villains yells "It's gonna blow!!". He couldn't have been more right, though he probably should have said this at the beginning in order to warn people what they were in for seeing! I think I'd have rather seen "Chitty, Chitty Bang, Bang", "The Adventures of Pippi Longstocking" or even "Son of the Mask" instead of this movie--it was that bad! By the way, there is a worse Christmas film. The 1959 Mexican film "Santa Claus" is in the Bottom 100 as well and it is light-years worse! But, for a big-budget Hollywood Christmas story, "Santa With Muscles" takes the prize!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Only in a movie this awful...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ij-holmes
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/11/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    ...could you find a wrestler playing a millionaire who thinks he's Santa Claus sword fighting a guy in an astronaut suit with a crystal broken off from a mine underneath a church. When you have that picture in your mind, you've already seen the only part of this movie worth watching, if you can even call it that. Don't watch this movie. Don't rent this movie. Don't stay on the channel on which this movie is playing. Forget this movie exists. If you must see it, make sure you are compensated financially for your trouble. If you can avoid seeing it, AVOID IT. You'll be doing your brain a favor.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    What the Hell was this?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jts0405
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/8/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Santa With Muscles is supposed to be a comedy, I guess, but it really doesn't bring the laughs at all. You don't find yourself laughing with the movie, but instead laughing at it and how incredibly cheesy it is. Hulk Hogan really needed to take his name off the project, because it would've done him a lot of good in his shortly lived acting career. I don't even get the plot to all of this, he is a millionaire that thinks he's Santa Claus, wow a preschooler could come up with that idea and make this whole movie look a lot better in the process. I am not bashing Hogan, because I did like him as a wrestler but as an actor the stuff he has done has really sucked. This belongs on the bottom 100. 1/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Best, Movie, Ever.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    James Miller
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/7/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Well now, this was probably one of the most fantastic pieces of movie literature to ever be produced within this day and age of cinematography Hulk Hogan is the greatest actor of all time, and he is also, the greatest wrestler to ever, take foot within the wrestling ring. Now, I am a hulkamaniac. Best movie ever Best movie ever Best movie ever. 10/10b Nothing beats seeing a movie about Santa, with fight scenes, thieves trying to steal crystals from an orphanage with Hulk Hogan, the man with a plan, coming in and desecrating the enemies ! pewpew !
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Santa, you sleigh me!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    lastliberal
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/12/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    OK, this is probably the absolutely worst Christmas program ever! No, it is not as bad as Feeders 2: Slay Bells, but for a Christmas show it is pretty bad. Hulk Hogan may have been a good wrestler, but he certainly cannot act. Here he bumps his head and thinks he's Santa. He is up against a group of real clowns led by Ed Begley, Jr. Steve Valentine from "Crossing Jordan" and more Grade Z actors. The only redeeming performance was little Aria Noelle Curzon, who was nine at the time. Cross this one off your Christmas list.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Hulkster must smoke rock
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    lodi_70005
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/8/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I am sure most of the posters here are not wrestling fans. Therefore, I will clue you in on a couple of things. Hulk Hogan is an ego maniacal jackass that demands creative control over anything he is involved in. This movie might not have been a classic when it was first written, but I will be fair and say it had average potential(a rating of 5). The movie probably had a different title at first until......Hulkamania arrived. Hulk Hogan has this remarkable ability to turn something good or average into unwatchable garbage. Original title may have been "When Santa got Rich" or "Santa CEO" or something slightly stupid. Hogan looks at the title and says "no way brother, my fans don't know nothing about no CEO(the first true words to come out of the mouth of the Hulkster in twenty years). So he called it "Santa with Muscles" because no project involving Hogan is allowed to go 5 seconds without referring to the "24 inch pythons" After adding scenes where blow up candy canes are used by Hogan with results comparable to the bomb dropped on Hiroshima, Hogan finally has gotten his wish. He ruined what might have been an enjoyable movie experience for two year olds and those who are "mentally challenged" or retards as Hogan's faithful redneck fans may call them. I am not surprised at how bad this film turned out. Wrestling fans with half a brain have hated Hogan for years. He exercises creative control when he is told that he is going to lose and this ends up boring anyone with a below average iq on up to tears. Hogan may have turned wrestling into a million dollar industry with a lot of help from the master marketing machine named Vince Mcmahon. Many good people sacrificed their wrestling careers by falling prey to Hogan's trademark "leg drop of doom" and now some poor director is probably living under a bridge in Los Angeles damning the day he got involved with Hulk Hogan. Hogan may have helped turn wrestling into mainstream entertainment, but he also singlehandedly destroyed the same industry(his tired act help put WCW into the ground) he helped build by never learning more than three moves. Punch, back scratch, high boot and leg drop. Oops that is four moves. Some things never change. In the ring the bad guy always loses to Hulk via leg drop. In the movies, Hogan expands his creative horizons by having the bad guy lose via Plastic candy Kane.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Watch out, he's got laughter and smiles!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Seth Nelson
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/2/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "He" referring to Hulk Hogan, which I consider the America's Tor Johnson. Tor starred in many bad movies; so does Hulk. Both are very funny in each of their performances! In my opinion, "Santa with Muscles" is where all the fun and the laughs are! Hearing that "Eegah"-like "Watch out, he's got a candy cane!" makes me laugh until I cry! And I laugh so much, I cry until I can do neither of those things anymore! That's the secret recipe for a great family holiday film: Laughs + Good Clean Family Fun (none of that "Bad Santa" stuff, please!) = The Best Holiday Family Film In The History Of The Universe! Let "Santa with Muscles" be the centerpiece of your entertainment next Christmas!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
 </reviews>
</filme>
