<filme>
 <id>
  1522
 </id>
 <imdburl>
  http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0111488
 </imdburl>
 <ano>
  1994
 </ano>
 <titulo>
  Tribunal Sob Suspeita
 </titulo>
 <rating>
  5.3
 </rating>
 <sinopse>
  Valerie is a juror in the trail of a mob boss. When her young son's life is threatened, she has no option other than to see that justice isn't done.
 </sinopse>
 <storyline>
  Valerie is a juror in the trail of a mob boss. When her young son's life is threatened, she has no option other than to see that justice isn't done.
 </storyline>
 <generos>
  <genero>
   Thriller
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Crime
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Drama
  </genero>
 </generos>
 <keywords>
  <keyword>
   mob boss
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   organized crime
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   female killer
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   wig
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   public phone
  </keyword>
 </keywords>
 <diretores>
  <diretor>
   Heywood Gould
  </diretor>
 </diretores>
 <escritores>
  <escritor>
   Jordan Katz
  </escritor>
  <escritor>
   Heywood Gould
  </escritor>
 </escritores>
 <atores>
  <ator>
   Joanne Whalley
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Armand Assante
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Gabriel Byrne
  </ator>
 </atores>
 <reviews>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An Underrated Film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    rhill-770-504848
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This film is so much better than The Juror. William Hurt is outstanding as a conflicted man, Kathleen Quinlan is amazingly creepy in her role, the tension between Joanne Whalley-Kilmer and the others, Armand Assante in particular, is emotional and well done. You will feel her isolation and fear. You will feel Gabriel Byrne's frustration as he tries to catch the mob boss and and work within the law only to have the legal system perverted by the influence of that mob. You will see how his character, who grew up with the mobster (Assante) could easily have gone in that direction. It has a great supporting cast with people like Joe Santos, Ed Lauter and Margaret Whitton. The film is also done in a film noir style. If you like classy films, you'll love it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Film badly miscast but still good
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    lahagensen
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/6/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I thought the movie was good, but felt all the leading characters (with the exception of Armand Assante as the mob boss) were badly miscast. One of the essential elements of the plot was the mob boss's obsession for the juror, because he had a thing for classy women who looked like movie stars from the 1940s. Although Joanne Whalley is an excellent actress and always a beautiful on-screen presence, I don't feel she fit the 1940s mold, and didn't seem to have much on-screen chemistry with Assante. Another actress such as Kim Basinger (in a pre-LA Confidential Veronica Lake type of performance) might have made that plot element more believable. William Hurt was also miscast as the crooked cop. After seeing Tom Berenger in "Breaking Point" he would have been a much better choice. Gabriel Byrne and Kathleen Quinlan's roles could have been played by Treat Williams and Kelly Preston. Other than the casting of the lead actors, I liked the look of the film (photography, set design, costumes, etc.) and enjoyed watching it. I thought it was a much better film than "The Juror" (with Demi Moore and Alec Baldwin) that had a similar theme and was released the same year.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Underrated Crime-Courtroom Story
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ccthemovieman-1
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/9/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    More often that not, I'll call a movie overrated, but this one, I think, is underrated. It features solid acting and a very involving story. There isn't as much violence as most modern-day crime movies and that's fine because this story doesn't need it. The profanity is also lower-than-normal. All that's missing is better cinematography. Joanne Whalley-Kilmer, Armand Assante, Gabirel Byrne and William Hurt all make this interesting and provide good performances. This is a good attention-diverting movie that is a good "date movie," too. It's tense without a ton of the usual overdone violence and profanity.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Could Have Been a Great Film-Noir
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Claudio Carvalho
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/5/2005
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    In New York, Valerie Alston (Joanne Whalley-Kilmer) is a single woman, who has a small son and is the owner of a store of clothes. She is convoked to participate of the jury of the trial of the mobster Rusty Pirone (Armand Assante), who will be judged for several murders. In the eve, the key witness of the prosecutor Daniel Graham (Gabriel Byrne) was executed with the four police officers that were protecting him by Pirone's men. Meanwhile, the ex-cop Tommy Vesey (William Hurt), who also works for Pirone, threatens Valerie, menacing to kill her son if she does not claim that Pirone is not guilty. "Trial by Jury" is not a bad movie, but it could have been a great film-noir. The first three-quarters of the story are indeed excellent. But there are two weaknesses in this film: the first one is the performance of Joanne Whalley-Kilmer. The character of Valerie lives a terrible dramatic dilemma and a very conflictive situation between her consciousness and the request of the mobster, and demanded a more expressive actress. Unfortunately, Joanne Whalley-Kilmer keeps the same expression in the most different situations along the story. The second weak point is the conclusion of the story, which is too much "Hollywoodian" to be credible. Anyway, this film is a good entertainment. My vote is seven. Title (Brazil): "Tribunal Sob Suspeita" ("Tribunal Under Suspicion")
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Overdone courtroom drama with a boilerplate mobster twist
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ebogan4
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/8/2004
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A antique shop-owner in NYC, played by Joanne Whalley(Valerie Alston)gets put on a US District Court jury, on a trial of a known Mafioso Armand Asante(Rusty Pirone), and most of this very slow-paced film revolves around attempts of Pirone attempting to get Whalley to acquit him of murder, by threatening to kill her son, and herself. Much action ensues, involving gruesome mob-rub outs, interspread with Willam Hurt as the go-between. Much of this silly, disjointed mess surrounds Hurt and Asante's obsession with Whalley, courtroom scenes that we've all seen time and again, and an ending that is unbelievable. 3/10 is probably going easy on this waste of time.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The remake is better.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bri4daz
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/5/2004
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Two years after this movie was made, "The Juror" came out. Don't waste your time on this one. See "The Juror" instead. "The Juror" is essentially the same story as "Trial By Jury," with better acting, better directing and a far more gripping aura about it. William Hurt was not believable as a cop-gone-bad, and Armand Assante couldn't be more unlike a mob boss if they had dressed him in a clown outfit. You didn't become involved enough with Joann Whalley's character to be that upset by what was happening to her. Also, the way in which she interacted with the jury wasn't compelling or interesting in any way. Kathleen Quinlan's role as a hooker/killer wasn't fleshed out enough and quite frankly was unnecessary for to the plot.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    familiar? maybe a spoiler.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    rodneyxiii7
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/10/2003
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Am I the only person that thinks this movie is waaaaay to similar to "The Juror" with Demi Moore? Let's see, let's start with jury intimidation, young son threatened, rape. I always thought this movie was a very good movie but I'm amazed that there is not a stronger association of the two movies in IMDB.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Part court drama, part thriller.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    triple8
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/8/2003
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Trial By Jury isn't a bad movie or anything but it's fairly predictable and isn't really a must see. The best thing about the movie is Joane Whaley in the lead role. The similarities to "The Juror" have been noted here so I won't get into that. This movie is part court drama part wanna be thriller. I say "wanna be" because it's not that original. I'm not saying the movie doesn't scare because it does. I mean there are some genuinely creepy moments. But it's that try to scare type of fear, the type where you kind of respond automatically. I saw it on television and it does hold your Attention so it's not a bad pick for a lazy Sunday. Trial By Jury also, at least to me, felt a bit like a movie one would find on the lifetime network. (Not that I'm putting down the lifetime channel-I actually dig many of their movies.) But it has that feel. The acting is actually quite good and Whaley brings a Special something to the role. She's a very CLASSY actress and that does kind of elevate the movie. Her being in the lead role is definitely a strong point of the movie. The movie Trial By Jury is not a must see.(I'd rate it about a 5.5) but not unwatchable and good for watching on a rainy day or if you like courtroom dramas.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Very disappointing
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Luigi Di Pilla
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/8/2002
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It&acute;s long time that I and my wife didn&acute;t see such a boring thriller. It&acute;s definitively NOT a gripping story and it is paced so slowly that we nearly fell asleep. This could be instead a very low budget TV crime series. There are some ridiculous scenes like the one where mafia boss Pirano wants to see the jury lady in a red clothes or another mafioso cannot stop to think about her and so on. Okay perhaps this should have been a romantic thriller but believe me you really don&acute;t miss anything. We gave 4/10.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Entertaining but cliched
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    JoeytheBrit
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/5/2002
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A good cast and entertaining plot find themselves foiled by a pedestrian script and ludicrous conclusion in this rather old-fashioned pot-boiler. Joanne Whalley-Kilmer looks ravishing as the whiter-than-white single mum who, upon being called to jury duty, finds herself terrorised by the henchmen of the mobster defendant. Armand Assante plays the blacker-than-black gangster - a slick, sharply-dressed caricature if ever there was one - but manages to add some sparks of individuality to the role. Gabriel Byrne is the fiery-tempered, driven state prosecutor who is largely ineffectual throughout the picture (character, not actor)  think about it: he achieves nothing he sets out to do. Only William Hurt really makes a mark as Assante's ex-cop henchman assigned to put the frighteners on Whalley-Kilmer. Plagued by a nagging conscience, and a major case of the hots for JW-K, he is the only interesting character. Mind you, William Hurt makes every role he plays interesting. Although the plot is entertaining it is also filled with huge holes and some really silly twists that require a superhuman suspension of disbelief on the part of the viewer. If you can manage it, though, you may find some enjoyment in this hokey thriller.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An Underrated Film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    rhill-770-504848
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This film is so much better than The Juror. William Hurt is outstanding as a conflicted man, Kathleen Quinlan is amazingly creepy in her role, the tension between Joanne Whalley-Kilmer and the others, Armand Assante in particular, is emotional and well done. You will feel her isolation and fear. You will feel Gabriel Byrne's frustration as he tries to catch the mob boss and and work within the law only to have the legal system perverted by the influence of that mob. You will see how his character, who grew up with the mobster (Assante) could easily have gone in that direction. It has a great supporting cast with people like Joe Santos, Ed Lauter and Margaret Whitton. The film is also done in a film noir style. If you like classy films, you'll love it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Film badly miscast but still good
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    lahagensen
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/6/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I thought the movie was good, but felt all the leading characters (with the exception of Armand Assante as the mob boss) were badly miscast. One of the essential elements of the plot was the mob boss's obsession for the juror, because he had a thing for classy women who looked like movie stars from the 1940s. Although Joanne Whalley is an excellent actress and always a beautiful on-screen presence, I don't feel she fit the 1940s mold, and didn't seem to have much on-screen chemistry with Assante. Another actress such as Kim Basinger (in a pre-LA Confidential Veronica Lake type of performance) might have made that plot element more believable. William Hurt was also miscast as the crooked cop. After seeing Tom Berenger in "Breaking Point" he would have been a much better choice. Gabriel Byrne and Kathleen Quinlan's roles could have been played by Treat Williams and Kelly Preston. Other than the casting of the lead actors, I liked the look of the film (photography, set design, costumes, etc.) and enjoyed watching it. I thought it was a much better film than "The Juror" (with Demi Moore and Alec Baldwin) that had a similar theme and was released the same year.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Underrated Crime-Courtroom Story
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ccthemovieman-1
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/9/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    More often that not, I'll call a movie overrated, but this one, I think, is underrated. It features solid acting and a very involving story. There isn't as much violence as most modern-day crime movies and that's fine because this story doesn't need it. The profanity is also lower-than-normal. All that's missing is better cinematography. Joanne Whalley-Kilmer, Armand Assante, Gabirel Byrne and William Hurt all make this interesting and provide good performances. This is a good attention-diverting movie that is a good "date movie," too. It's tense without a ton of the usual overdone violence and profanity.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Could Have Been a Great Film-Noir
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Claudio Carvalho
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/5/2005
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    In New York, Valerie Alston (Joanne Whalley-Kilmer) is a single woman, who has a small son and is the owner of a store of clothes. She is convoked to participate of the jury of the trial of the mobster Rusty Pirone (Armand Assante), who will be judged for several murders. In the eve, the key witness of the prosecutor Daniel Graham (Gabriel Byrne) was executed with the four police officers that were protecting him by Pirone's men. Meanwhile, the ex-cop Tommy Vesey (William Hurt), who also works for Pirone, threatens Valerie, menacing to kill her son if she does not claim that Pirone is not guilty. "Trial by Jury" is not a bad movie, but it could have been a great film-noir. The first three-quarters of the story are indeed excellent. But there are two weaknesses in this film: the first one is the performance of Joanne Whalley-Kilmer. The character of Valerie lives a terrible dramatic dilemma and a very conflictive situation between her consciousness and the request of the mobster, and demanded a more expressive actress. Unfortunately, Joanne Whalley-Kilmer keeps the same expression in the most different situations along the story. The second weak point is the conclusion of the story, which is too much "Hollywoodian" to be credible. Anyway, this film is a good entertainment. My vote is seven. Title (Brazil): "Tribunal Sob Suspeita" ("Tribunal Under Suspicion")
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Overdone courtroom drama with a boilerplate mobster twist
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ebogan4
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/8/2004
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A antique shop-owner in NYC, played by Joanne Whalley(Valerie Alston)gets put on a US District Court jury, on a trial of a known Mafioso Armand Asante(Rusty Pirone), and most of this very slow-paced film revolves around attempts of Pirone attempting to get Whalley to acquit him of murder, by threatening to kill her son, and herself. Much action ensues, involving gruesome mob-rub outs, interspread with Willam Hurt as the go-between. Much of this silly, disjointed mess surrounds Hurt and Asante's obsession with Whalley, courtroom scenes that we've all seen time and again, and an ending that is unbelievable. 3/10 is probably going easy on this waste of time.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The remake is better.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bri4daz
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/5/2004
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Two years after this movie was made, "The Juror" came out. Don't waste your time on this one. See "The Juror" instead. "The Juror" is essentially the same story as "Trial By Jury," with better acting, better directing and a far more gripping aura about it. William Hurt was not believable as a cop-gone-bad, and Armand Assante couldn't be more unlike a mob boss if they had dressed him in a clown outfit. You didn't become involved enough with Joann Whalley's character to be that upset by what was happening to her. Also, the way in which she interacted with the jury wasn't compelling or interesting in any way. Kathleen Quinlan's role as a hooker/killer wasn't fleshed out enough and quite frankly was unnecessary for to the plot.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    familiar? maybe a spoiler.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    rodneyxiii7
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/10/2003
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Am I the only person that thinks this movie is waaaaay to similar to "The Juror" with Demi Moore? Let's see, let's start with jury intimidation, young son threatened, rape. I always thought this movie was a very good movie but I'm amazed that there is not a stronger association of the two movies in IMDB.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Part court drama, part thriller.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    triple8
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/8/2003
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Trial By Jury isn't a bad movie or anything but it's fairly predictable and isn't really a must see. The best thing about the movie is Joane Whaley in the lead role. The similarities to "The Juror" have been noted here so I won't get into that. This movie is part court drama part wanna be thriller. I say "wanna be" because it's not that original. I'm not saying the movie doesn't scare because it does. I mean there are some genuinely creepy moments. But it's that try to scare type of fear, the type where you kind of respond automatically. I saw it on television and it does hold your Attention so it's not a bad pick for a lazy Sunday. Trial By Jury also, at least to me, felt a bit like a movie one would find on the lifetime network. (Not that I'm putting down the lifetime channel-I actually dig many of their movies.) But it has that feel. The acting is actually quite good and Whaley brings a Special something to the role. She's a very CLASSY actress and that does kind of elevate the movie. Her being in the lead role is definitely a strong point of the movie. The movie Trial By Jury is not a must see.(I'd rate it about a 5.5) but not unwatchable and good for watching on a rainy day or if you like courtroom dramas.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Very disappointing
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Luigi Di Pilla
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/8/2002
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It&acute;s long time that I and my wife didn&acute;t see such a boring thriller. It&acute;s definitively NOT a gripping story and it is paced so slowly that we nearly fell asleep. This could be instead a very low budget TV crime series. There are some ridiculous scenes like the one where mafia boss Pirano wants to see the jury lady in a red clothes or another mafioso cannot stop to think about her and so on. Okay perhaps this should have been a romantic thriller but believe me you really don&acute;t miss anything. We gave 4/10.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Entertaining but cliched
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    JoeytheBrit
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/5/2002
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A good cast and entertaining plot find themselves foiled by a pedestrian script and ludicrous conclusion in this rather old-fashioned pot-boiler. Joanne Whalley-Kilmer looks ravishing as the whiter-than-white single mum who, upon being called to jury duty, finds herself terrorised by the henchmen of the mobster defendant. Armand Assante plays the blacker-than-black gangster - a slick, sharply-dressed caricature if ever there was one - but manages to add some sparks of individuality to the role. Gabriel Byrne is the fiery-tempered, driven state prosecutor who is largely ineffectual throughout the picture (character, not actor)  think about it: he achieves nothing he sets out to do. Only William Hurt really makes a mark as Assante's ex-cop henchman assigned to put the frighteners on Whalley-Kilmer. Plagued by a nagging conscience, and a major case of the hots for JW-K, he is the only interesting character. Mind you, William Hurt makes every role he plays interesting. Although the plot is entertaining it is also filled with huge holes and some really silly twists that require a superhuman suspension of disbelief on the part of the viewer. If you can manage it, though, you may find some enjoyment in this hokey thriller.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
 </reviews>
</filme>
