<filme>
 <id>
  1526
 </id>
 <imdburl>
  http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0090329
 </imdburl>
 <ano>
  1985
 </ano>
 <titulo>
  A Testemunha
 </titulo>
 <rating>
  7.5
 </rating>
 <sinopse>
  A young Amish boy is sole witness to a murder; policeman John Book goes into hiding in Amish country to protect him until the trial.
 </sinopse>
 <storyline>
  Samuel Lap is a young Amish boy who witnesses a murder in Philadelphia while traveling with his mother Rachel. A good cop named John Book must go with them into hiding when the killers come after them. All three retreat to Amish country and Book has to adjust to the new life style, and his feelings for the boy's mother. Of course the killers are still on their trail.
 </storyline>
 <generos>
  <genero>
   Crime
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Drama
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Romance
  </genero>
 </generos>
 <keywords>
  <keyword>
   amish
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   murder
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   police
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   love
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   train
  </keyword>
 </keywords>
 <diretores>
  <diretor>
   Peter Weir
  </diretor>
 </diretores>
 <escritores>
  <escritor>
   William Kelley
  </escritor>
  <escritor>
   Pamela Wallace
  </escritor>
 </escritores>
 <atores>
  <ator>
   Harrison Ford
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Kelly McGillis
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Lukas Haas
  </ator>
 </atores>
 <reviews>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A classic thriller with a great setting
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Jellybeansucker
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Great thriller story and setting. Not sure if the child witness angle was new but certainly his background was, the Amish community, and that's the main pleasure of this movie. The film's pace slows down but the interest and drama is heightened when Book is holed up at the farm. That's well worked by the writers and the love interest is nicely done, and there is real chemistry between Ford and McGillis, what a match! For the ending, the natural thriller pace comes back, it's intense too because we know Book is a good guy who's protective of his hosts. They could have overdone this with a DePalma style OTT shoot out, but this was just right for the movie. The only flaw is a pretty incredible decision by Book just to go into hiding at the Amish farm, putting them all at risk. In reality he'd be shopping his bent police chief to the FBI, the press and anyone else who'd listen and seeking witness protection for the boy. A major flaw, but the creators wanted to finish the movie at the Amish community as well, which is understandable. Overall a real breath of fresh air for the thriller genre, a well rounded movie with something for everyone, an original setting and a fantastic lead link up with Ford at his best and an almost unknown McGillis proving sex appeal doesn't need glamour at all! One of my favourites, a little gem of a thriller.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Genuine Thriller with a Heart!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    g-bodyl
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Witness is a very good thriller with great moments of characterization and that is what sets it apart from other thrillers. Also, you really cannot classify this as thriller for the entire film because the middle portion is a haunting study on a group of peaceful people living away from technology. Harrison Ford gets out of his action movies to have one of the best roles of his career playing John Book. Peter Weir's film is about a hard-nosed detective named John Book who investigates a murder that a small Amish boy witnessed. Thanks to some betrayal, John is forced to live with the Amish and away from being a cop, he forbiddenly falls in love with Rachel, a beautiful Amish woman. As mentioned before, Harrison gives one of his better roles and is full of heartfelt emotion. Kelly McGillis, in her second ever movie, rises to great heights with her shy performance. I also find it ironic how Danny Glover plays a villain who murders cops right before his famed Lethal Weapon series. Overall, Witness is a beautifully shot film that has some intense scenes especially in the beginning and the end. We get to meet a group of people that stay away from society. The music by Maurice Jarre is wonderful and fits well with the themes of the movie. I find it funny how an award-winning thriller like this was released in February. I rate this film 9/10.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "You be careful out among the English."
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    romanorum1
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    After her husband's premature death, a young Amish woman, Rachel Lapp (Kelley McGillis), takes her son Samuel (Lukas Haas) on a train trip to Baltimore. While in the men's washroom at the Philadelphia station, young Samuel witnesses a brutal murder. By his own wits he saves himself from the scary murderer McFee (Danny Glover). Detective John Book (Harrison Ford), summoned to the murder scene, perceives that the dead man is an undercover cop. He questions Rachel and Samuel. From a photograph, Samuel fingers McFee, among others a corrupt cop. McFee had stolen large quantities of a chemical substance used in the manufacture of methamphetamine. The bad guys try to set up Book for a hit, but fail (although he is wounded by McFee). Now searched by the bad guys, Book goes into hiding in Pennsylvania German (Amish) country (Lancaster County, PA) to blend in with the religious sect. The middle part of the movie, and by far the greater segment overall, is the focus on the Amish community. This section is almost a documentary. We learn that the Amish shun the new ways, and live much as they did in the eighteenth century. Unlike the nearby Mennonites, the Amish reject automobiles, electricity, and telephones. Gas lamps are used. The Amish ride in traditional horse and buggy units while heavy traffic passes them by (when they can). They wear plain clothes and use hooks and eyes, rather than buttons or zippers, which they consider proud and vain. There is a nice barn-raising scene, where the Amish people together erect a barn within one day for a newly married couple. We see how the tourists think about the Amish, and Book's reaction to human pests. There is the obvious clash between the modern (Book-urban) and the olden (Rachel-rural) ways. Nevertheless, as Book outwardly becomes part of the Amish community, Rachel and he begin to draw closer. The sponge bath scene is probably the most notable one in the movie. If John and Rachel decide to come together, one of them will have to give up his/her ways, for there is no middle ground. What will happen? Meanwhile three bad cops, including corrupt Chief Schaeffer (played by Josef Sommer) and McFee, track down their quarry and arrive in Amish country to do in Book. So the final scenario is the shootout between the good and the bad. What will the peaceful Amish people do? Perhaps not what you may expect! The acting is very good all-around. Harrison Ford may have given us his best performance here as a decent cop (who does not overact), although others may opt with justification for "The Fugitive" or the "Indiana Jones" series. Kelley McGillis makes a fine and dedicated Amish lady. Jan Rubes plays moral kingpin Eli Lapp, while Danny Glover is indeed chilling as a bad cop. The subtleties / expressions of the actors work so well. For instance, Lukas Haas's bewildered face when he spots McFee's photo in the police station speaks volumes. Of course, the looks of Mc Gillis and Ford during the famous sponge bath scene do not require a word of dialog. See this movie more than once.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An Interesting Look At The Amish
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gavin6942
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A young Amish boy is sole witness to a murder; policeman John Book (Harrison Ford) goes into hiding in Amish country to protect him until the trial. First of all, I have to point out that this was the first big screen role for Viggo Mortensen. Well done, sir. Although they did not know it then, you went on to be a big man in Hollywood. Great to see you here. More importantly, how to judge this film? From an entertainment point of view, it is pretty darn good. I loved Harrison Ford, and I think this is one of Peter Weir's more "fun" films. I am sure more people enjoyed this than "Picnic at Hanging Rock" (which is probably the better film, but not a fun movie by any means). And yet, is this a fair portrayal of the Amish? Is it accurate? Is it exploitation? Were they consulted on how they would be shown here? I suppose in some sense it does not matter because the strict Amish would never see the movie, but it does not do them any favors if they are presented as being something they are not...
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Witness (1985)
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ashish sood (ashistrong@gmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It is a film about adults, whose lives have dignity and whose choices matter to them. The story focuses on a detective (Harrison Ford) protecting a young Amish boy who becomes the target of a ruthless killer after he witnesses a brutal murder. Witness is as much about the meeting of cultures as about cops and robbers, this is one of those lucky movies which works out well on all counts and shows that there are still craftsmen lurking in Hollywood. The film is powerful, assured, full of beautiful imagery and devoid of easy moralising, which is good. Ford is Chicago Detective John Book, assigned to investigate a murder that was committed by crooked cop Danny Glover. The only witness is the son of an Amish widow, played by Kelly McGillis. When Book gets too close to the truth, the crooked cops try to kill him, forcing Book to take it on the lamb and hide out in the Amish country. There, he slowly makes a transition into their society, their way of life, and of course, he starts to fall for Kelly McGillis. (who would later star with pretty boy Cruise in "Top Gun"). Alexander Godunov, who later played the murderous Karl in "Die Hard", makes his debut here as an Amish farmer who is, Ford's romantic rival for Kelly. Also making his debut here is a much younger Viggo Mortensen as another Amish father. Mortensen's barely evident in the role out here,although had his eventual success as Aragorn in "Lord of the Rings" ........ After Star Wars & Indiana Jones,Ford succeeded in a serious role and his multi-layered performance earned him his only Oscar Nomination till date.Well directed Romantic Thriller by Peter Weir (Director of Dead poet's Society and Truman Show) that earned him his first Academy Award Nomination. Do watch this one for great Cinematography and Artwork My Rating - 8/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Wonderfully Poignant, Suspenseful Film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Helio Copter
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I only just recently watched this film for the first time by catching it on television. I had been aware of it in terms of the title and Harrison Ford, but had never actually read up on the plot. I am very glad that I watched it. This film is so much more than the crime/legal drama that I had imagined it to be. The directing, cinematography, screenplay and acting are all wonderfully executed. The contrast between the overt, aggressive world of police and murder investigations in the city with the subdued, understated world of the Amish, is exceptionally well portrayed. Harrison Ford does a fine job in his role. The single most beautiful performance, though, is Kelly McGillis. As other reviews have noted, she does not have an excess of spoken dialog, but her physical acting, in particular her eyes and face, is incredibly evocative and moving. If anyone should have gotten a nomination, it should have been her. Watching her play this role was a revelation to me. One also has to credit the great performance of the then-very-young Lukas Haas. His impressive turn may be as much a true key to this film's success as any other single element. The rest of the characters are well-cast themselves. I greatly admired the ending to this film. I think that it speaks to Peter Weir's directatorial sensibilities. In the hands of a lesser director, it could have been far more clich&eacute;d, but far less powerful. I was nearly thirty years late seeing WITNESS, but I think that it is a timelessly poignant example of excellent storytelling.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Never get tired of the 'barn-raising' scene
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Andreapworth
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Whenever I happen upon this movie (cable), I get sucked in, although I've seen it enough times. It's just a good story with it's own suspense. We all are rooting for little Lucas and the fact that John Book has to hide him and his mother away from the 'bad guys'. So many scenes are worth seeing again, especially when John Book gets hurt and must rely on the the Amish people to heal him - no doctors, of course. And of course, when Rachel's father wakes him up at the crack of dawn for milking. And when Radhel gives him some clothes that were her late husband's and explains that zippers and buttons are 'too proud'. And as mentioned, if you once see the barn raising scene, it will stay with you forever. Truly moving and a real example of community and what can be done by all people.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Maybe it had a point at the time...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Andrew Werling (awerling)
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Okay, so John Book is in dire straits, and so is a kid and probably his mother, but he seems to feel none of this urgency, and we watch irritating scenes of him falling in love, drinking lemonade, barn-raising, milking a cow...just not very well crafted in my opinion. And the soundtrack was cheesy. Great acting, cinematography, I'll give it that. I think the film took on too much. I just found it nearly impossible to believe his calmness in the face of one of the worst realities a cop can face: the corruption of his friends and mentors. And maybe I'm just jaded by better films on this topic which were made later: L.A. Confidential, 13 Blocks, even Copland. But I just felt antsy watching this in 2012, and I usually really dig Peter Weir films, even the cheesy ones.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Murder, Corruption & Doomed Love
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    seymourblack-1
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Witness" is a subtle, thoughtful and intelligently directed film which is both a crime thriller and an extraordinary love story. A police investigation into a brutal murder provides this drama with its momentum and drive and a tragic romantic tale adds the intensity, warmth and poignancy that elevates this movie to a higher level than that normally achieved by more routine thrillers. The story about two people from different backgrounds who fall in love, but know that their love can't transcend their circumstances, has a timeless and universal appeal which explains why this movie has retained its popularity so consistently since it was first released in 1985. When a recently widowed young Amish woman and her son are in a train station in Philadelphia, the 8-year-old boy witnesses the murder of an undercover cop. Detective Captain John Book (Harrison Ford) is put in charge of the investigation and questions Samuel Lapp (Lukas Haas), but even after showing him mug shots and arranging line-ups of suspects, the boy isn't able to finger the culprit. A little while later, however, Samuel is looking around the police office when he notices the killer's picture on a newspaper clipping that's pinned up inside a glass cabinet. When he brings this to Book's attention, it's quite a shock because the man in the photograph is the highly decorated Detective Lieutenant McFee (Danny Glover) of the Narcotics Division. Detective Book tells his superior officer Detective Chief Schaeffer (Josef Sommer) about this development and Schaeffer asks him to keep the information confidential. Shortly after, when he's shot at and injured by McFee, it becomes obvious to Book that McFee and Schaeffer are both corrupt and Samuel and his mother Rachel (Kelly McGillis) are in mortal danger. In order to protect them, Book drives them back to their Amish community but after his arrival there, he collapses and has to remain with the Amish where Rachel gradually nurses him back to health. During Book's period of recuperation, he and Rachel fall in love but he soon realises that neither of them could survive indefinitely in the other's world. Book adapts well to living with the Amish and earns their respect as he readily helps with milking cows and building a barn, but his presence in their community places them in danger, as becomes all too clear when the story reaches its action-packed conclusion. Non-verbal communication is used frequently in this movie and provides the action with an extremely natural feel. A couple of the stand-out sequences are those in which Samuel looks at Book in a way that immediately signifies that he's seen something important (when he sees McFee's photograph) and another is when Book and Rachel dance together in a barn to Sam Cooke's "What A Wonderful World". The power to convey their thoughts and feelings so clearly in this way is very touching at times and also testifies strongly to the quality of the acting. The differences between the worlds that Book and Rachel inhabit couldn't be greater as the Amish reside in rural surroundings and live a quiet, non-violent existence in which it's normal for everyone to help everyone else. These people embrace old fashioned values and don't use modern conveniences such as cars and refrigerators etc. By contrast, Book's existence as a city cop is far less serene and regularly brings him into contact with violence, corruption and various other forms of errant human behaviour. "Witness", with its interesting characters, its absorbing story of murder, corruption and doomed love and its marvellous acting performances, is tremendously enjoyable to watch and leaves a lasting impression.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "One Of Ford's Best!"
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gwnightscream
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/9/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Harrison Ford, Kelly McGillis, Lucas Haas, Jan Rubes, Danny Glover, Josef Sommer, Patti LuPone, and Alexander Godunov star in this 1985 thriller. This film begins in Pennsylvania in a small Amish town where a widow, Rachel Lapp (McGillis) attends her late husband's funeral with her family and friends. Soon, Rachel and her young son, Samuel (Haas) head to Baltimore to visit her sister until Samuel witnesses a cop's murder in Philadelphia. Ford plays John Book, a cop who investigates the case and tries to protect Rachel and Samuel. When he's almost killed by crooked cops, John takes Rachel and Samuel home, but hides there with them learning their Amish ways. Rubes plays Rachel's father-in-law, Eli, Glover plays cop, McFee, Sommer plays John's mentor, Schaeffer, LuPone plays John's sister, Elaine and Godunov (Die Hard) plays Daniel, an Amish friend of Rachel's family. This is one of Ford's best and he and McGillis are great together. Maurice Jarre's score is also excellent and I recommend this.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A classic thriller with a great setting
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Jellybeansucker
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Great thriller story and setting. Not sure if the child witness angle was new but certainly his background was, the Amish community, and that's the main pleasure of this movie. The film's pace slows down but the interest and drama is heightened when Book is holed up at the farm. That's well worked by the writers and the love interest is nicely done, and there is real chemistry between Ford and McGillis, what a match! For the ending, the natural thriller pace comes back, it's intense too because we know Book is a good guy who's protective of his hosts. They could have overdone this with a DePalma style OTT shoot out, but this was just right for the movie. The only flaw is a pretty incredible decision by Book just to go into hiding at the Amish farm, putting them all at risk. In reality he'd be shopping his bent police chief to the FBI, the press and anyone else who'd listen and seeking witness protection for the boy. A major flaw, but the creators wanted to finish the movie at the Amish community as well, which is understandable. Overall a real breath of fresh air for the thriller genre, a well rounded movie with something for everyone, an original setting and a fantastic lead link up with Ford at his best and an almost unknown McGillis proving sex appeal doesn't need glamour at all! One of my favourites, a little gem of a thriller.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Genuine Thriller with a Heart!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    g-bodyl
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Witness is a very good thriller with great moments of characterization and that is what sets it apart from other thrillers. Also, you really cannot classify this as thriller for the entire film because the middle portion is a haunting study on a group of peaceful people living away from technology. Harrison Ford gets out of his action movies to have one of the best roles of his career playing John Book. Peter Weir's film is about a hard-nosed detective named John Book who investigates a murder that a small Amish boy witnessed. Thanks to some betrayal, John is forced to live with the Amish and away from being a cop, he forbiddenly falls in love with Rachel, a beautiful Amish woman. As mentioned before, Harrison gives one of his better roles and is full of heartfelt emotion. Kelly McGillis, in her second ever movie, rises to great heights with her shy performance. I also find it ironic how Danny Glover plays a villain who murders cops right before his famed Lethal Weapon series. Overall, Witness is a beautifully shot film that has some intense scenes especially in the beginning and the end. We get to meet a group of people that stay away from society. The music by Maurice Jarre is wonderful and fits well with the themes of the movie. I find it funny how an award-winning thriller like this was released in February. I rate this film 9/10.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "You be careful out among the English."
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    romanorum1
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    After her husband's premature death, a young Amish woman, Rachel Lapp (Kelley McGillis), takes her son Samuel (Lukas Haas) on a train trip to Baltimore. While in the men's washroom at the Philadelphia station, young Samuel witnesses a brutal murder. By his own wits he saves himself from the scary murderer McFee (Danny Glover). Detective John Book (Harrison Ford), summoned to the murder scene, perceives that the dead man is an undercover cop. He questions Rachel and Samuel. From a photograph, Samuel fingers McFee, among others a corrupt cop. McFee had stolen large quantities of a chemical substance used in the manufacture of methamphetamine. The bad guys try to set up Book for a hit, but fail (although he is wounded by McFee). Now searched by the bad guys, Book goes into hiding in Pennsylvania German (Amish) country (Lancaster County, PA) to blend in with the religious sect. The middle part of the movie, and by far the greater segment overall, is the focus on the Amish community. This section is almost a documentary. We learn that the Amish shun the new ways, and live much as they did in the eighteenth century. Unlike the nearby Mennonites, the Amish reject automobiles, electricity, and telephones. Gas lamps are used. The Amish ride in traditional horse and buggy units while heavy traffic passes them by (when they can). They wear plain clothes and use hooks and eyes, rather than buttons or zippers, which they consider proud and vain. There is a nice barn-raising scene, where the Amish people together erect a barn within one day for a newly married couple. We see how the tourists think about the Amish, and Book's reaction to human pests. There is the obvious clash between the modern (Book-urban) and the olden (Rachel-rural) ways. Nevertheless, as Book outwardly becomes part of the Amish community, Rachel and he begin to draw closer. The sponge bath scene is probably the most notable one in the movie. If John and Rachel decide to come together, one of them will have to give up his/her ways, for there is no middle ground. What will happen? Meanwhile three bad cops, including corrupt Chief Schaeffer (played by Josef Sommer) and McFee, track down their quarry and arrive in Amish country to do in Book. So the final scenario is the shootout between the good and the bad. What will the peaceful Amish people do? Perhaps not what you may expect! The acting is very good all-around. Harrison Ford may have given us his best performance here as a decent cop (who does not overact), although others may opt with justification for "The Fugitive" or the "Indiana Jones" series. Kelley McGillis makes a fine and dedicated Amish lady. Jan Rubes plays moral kingpin Eli Lapp, while Danny Glover is indeed chilling as a bad cop. The subtleties / expressions of the actors work so well. For instance, Lukas Haas's bewildered face when he spots McFee's photo in the police station speaks volumes. Of course, the looks of Mc Gillis and Ford during the famous sponge bath scene do not require a word of dialog. See this movie more than once.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An Interesting Look At The Amish
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gavin6942
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A young Amish boy is sole witness to a murder; policeman John Book (Harrison Ford) goes into hiding in Amish country to protect him until the trial. First of all, I have to point out that this was the first big screen role for Viggo Mortensen. Well done, sir. Although they did not know it then, you went on to be a big man in Hollywood. Great to see you here. More importantly, how to judge this film? From an entertainment point of view, it is pretty darn good. I loved Harrison Ford, and I think this is one of Peter Weir's more "fun" films. I am sure more people enjoyed this than "Picnic at Hanging Rock" (which is probably the better film, but not a fun movie by any means). And yet, is this a fair portrayal of the Amish? Is it accurate? Is it exploitation? Were they consulted on how they would be shown here? I suppose in some sense it does not matter because the strict Amish would never see the movie, but it does not do them any favors if they are presented as being something they are not...
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Witness (1985)
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ashish sood (ashistrong@gmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It is a film about adults, whose lives have dignity and whose choices matter to them. The story focuses on a detective (Harrison Ford) protecting a young Amish boy who becomes the target of a ruthless killer after he witnesses a brutal murder. Witness is as much about the meeting of cultures as about cops and robbers, this is one of those lucky movies which works out well on all counts and shows that there are still craftsmen lurking in Hollywood. The film is powerful, assured, full of beautiful imagery and devoid of easy moralising, which is good. Ford is Chicago Detective John Book, assigned to investigate a murder that was committed by crooked cop Danny Glover. The only witness is the son of an Amish widow, played by Kelly McGillis. When Book gets too close to the truth, the crooked cops try to kill him, forcing Book to take it on the lamb and hide out in the Amish country. There, he slowly makes a transition into their society, their way of life, and of course, he starts to fall for Kelly McGillis. (who would later star with pretty boy Cruise in "Top Gun"). Alexander Godunov, who later played the murderous Karl in "Die Hard", makes his debut here as an Amish farmer who is, Ford's romantic rival for Kelly. Also making his debut here is a much younger Viggo Mortensen as another Amish father. Mortensen's barely evident in the role out here,although had his eventual success as Aragorn in "Lord of the Rings" ........ After Star Wars & Indiana Jones,Ford succeeded in a serious role and his multi-layered performance earned him his only Oscar Nomination till date.Well directed Romantic Thriller by Peter Weir (Director of Dead poet's Society and Truman Show) that earned him his first Academy Award Nomination. Do watch this one for great Cinematography and Artwork My Rating - 8/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Wonderfully Poignant, Suspenseful Film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Helio Copter
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I only just recently watched this film for the first time by catching it on television. I had been aware of it in terms of the title and Harrison Ford, but had never actually read up on the plot. I am very glad that I watched it. This film is so much more than the crime/legal drama that I had imagined it to be. The directing, cinematography, screenplay and acting are all wonderfully executed. The contrast between the overt, aggressive world of police and murder investigations in the city with the subdued, understated world of the Amish, is exceptionally well portrayed. Harrison Ford does a fine job in his role. The single most beautiful performance, though, is Kelly McGillis. As other reviews have noted, she does not have an excess of spoken dialog, but her physical acting, in particular her eyes and face, is incredibly evocative and moving. If anyone should have gotten a nomination, it should have been her. Watching her play this role was a revelation to me. One also has to credit the great performance of the then-very-young Lukas Haas. His impressive turn may be as much a true key to this film's success as any other single element. The rest of the characters are well-cast themselves. I greatly admired the ending to this film. I think that it speaks to Peter Weir's directatorial sensibilities. In the hands of a lesser director, it could have been far more clich&eacute;d, but far less powerful. I was nearly thirty years late seeing WITNESS, but I think that it is a timelessly poignant example of excellent storytelling.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Never get tired of the 'barn-raising' scene
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Andreapworth
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Whenever I happen upon this movie (cable), I get sucked in, although I've seen it enough times. It's just a good story with it's own suspense. We all are rooting for little Lucas and the fact that John Book has to hide him and his mother away from the 'bad guys'. So many scenes are worth seeing again, especially when John Book gets hurt and must rely on the the Amish people to heal him - no doctors, of course. And of course, when Rachel's father wakes him up at the crack of dawn for milking. And when Radhel gives him some clothes that were her late husband's and explains that zippers and buttons are 'too proud'. And as mentioned, if you once see the barn raising scene, it will stay with you forever. Truly moving and a real example of community and what can be done by all people.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Maybe it had a point at the time...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Andrew Werling (awerling)
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Okay, so John Book is in dire straits, and so is a kid and probably his mother, but he seems to feel none of this urgency, and we watch irritating scenes of him falling in love, drinking lemonade, barn-raising, milking a cow...just not very well crafted in my opinion. And the soundtrack was cheesy. Great acting, cinematography, I'll give it that. I think the film took on too much. I just found it nearly impossible to believe his calmness in the face of one of the worst realities a cop can face: the corruption of his friends and mentors. And maybe I'm just jaded by better films on this topic which were made later: L.A. Confidential, 13 Blocks, even Copland. But I just felt antsy watching this in 2012, and I usually really dig Peter Weir films, even the cheesy ones.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Murder, Corruption & Doomed Love
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    seymourblack-1
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Witness" is a subtle, thoughtful and intelligently directed film which is both a crime thriller and an extraordinary love story. A police investigation into a brutal murder provides this drama with its momentum and drive and a tragic romantic tale adds the intensity, warmth and poignancy that elevates this movie to a higher level than that normally achieved by more routine thrillers. The story about two people from different backgrounds who fall in love, but know that their love can't transcend their circumstances, has a timeless and universal appeal which explains why this movie has retained its popularity so consistently since it was first released in 1985. When a recently widowed young Amish woman and her son are in a train station in Philadelphia, the 8-year-old boy witnesses the murder of an undercover cop. Detective Captain John Book (Harrison Ford) is put in charge of the investigation and questions Samuel Lapp (Lukas Haas), but even after showing him mug shots and arranging line-ups of suspects, the boy isn't able to finger the culprit. A little while later, however, Samuel is looking around the police office when he notices the killer's picture on a newspaper clipping that's pinned up inside a glass cabinet. When he brings this to Book's attention, it's quite a shock because the man in the photograph is the highly decorated Detective Lieutenant McFee (Danny Glover) of the Narcotics Division. Detective Book tells his superior officer Detective Chief Schaeffer (Josef Sommer) about this development and Schaeffer asks him to keep the information confidential. Shortly after, when he's shot at and injured by McFee, it becomes obvious to Book that McFee and Schaeffer are both corrupt and Samuel and his mother Rachel (Kelly McGillis) are in mortal danger. In order to protect them, Book drives them back to their Amish community but after his arrival there, he collapses and has to remain with the Amish where Rachel gradually nurses him back to health. During Book's period of recuperation, he and Rachel fall in love but he soon realises that neither of them could survive indefinitely in the other's world. Book adapts well to living with the Amish and earns their respect as he readily helps with milking cows and building a barn, but his presence in their community places them in danger, as becomes all too clear when the story reaches its action-packed conclusion. Non-verbal communication is used frequently in this movie and provides the action with an extremely natural feel. A couple of the stand-out sequences are those in which Samuel looks at Book in a way that immediately signifies that he's seen something important (when he sees McFee's photograph) and another is when Book and Rachel dance together in a barn to Sam Cooke's "What A Wonderful World". The power to convey their thoughts and feelings so clearly in this way is very touching at times and also testifies strongly to the quality of the acting. The differences between the worlds that Book and Rachel inhabit couldn't be greater as the Amish reside in rural surroundings and live a quiet, non-violent existence in which it's normal for everyone to help everyone else. These people embrace old fashioned values and don't use modern conveniences such as cars and refrigerators etc. By contrast, Book's existence as a city cop is far less serene and regularly brings him into contact with violence, corruption and various other forms of errant human behaviour. "Witness", with its interesting characters, its absorbing story of murder, corruption and doomed love and its marvellous acting performances, is tremendously enjoyable to watch and leaves a lasting impression.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "One Of Ford's Best!"
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gwnightscream
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/9/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Harrison Ford, Kelly McGillis, Lucas Haas, Jan Rubes, Danny Glover, Josef Sommer, Patti LuPone, and Alexander Godunov star in this 1985 thriller. This film begins in Pennsylvania in a small Amish town where a widow, Rachel Lapp (McGillis) attends her late husband's funeral with her family and friends. Soon, Rachel and her young son, Samuel (Haas) head to Baltimore to visit her sister until Samuel witnesses a cop's murder in Philadelphia. Ford plays John Book, a cop who investigates the case and tries to protect Rachel and Samuel. When he's almost killed by crooked cops, John takes Rachel and Samuel home, but hides there with them learning their Amish ways. Rubes plays Rachel's father-in-law, Eli, Glover plays cop, McFee, Sommer plays John's mentor, Schaeffer, LuPone plays John's sister, Elaine and Godunov (Die Hard) plays Daniel, an Amish friend of Rachel's family. This is one of Ford's best and he and McGillis are great together. Maurice Jarre's score is also excellent and I recommend this.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A classic thriller with a great setting
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Jellybeansucker
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Great thriller story and setting. Not sure if the child witness angle was new but certainly his background was, the Amish community, and that's the main pleasure of this movie. The film's pace slows down but the interest and drama is heightened when Book is holed up at the farm. That's well worked by the writers and the love interest is nicely done, and there is real chemistry between Ford and McGillis, what a match! For the ending, the natural thriller pace comes back, it's intense too because we know Book is a good guy who's protective of his hosts. They could have overdone this with a DePalma style OTT shoot out, but this was just right for the movie. The only flaw is a pretty incredible decision by Book just to go into hiding at the Amish farm, putting them all at risk. In reality he'd be shopping his bent police chief to the FBI, the press and anyone else who'd listen and seeking witness protection for the boy. A major flaw, but the creators wanted to finish the movie at the Amish community as well, which is understandable. Overall a real breath of fresh air for the thriller genre, a well rounded movie with something for everyone, an original setting and a fantastic lead link up with Ford at his best and an almost unknown McGillis proving sex appeal doesn't need glamour at all! One of my favourites, a little gem of a thriller.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Genuine Thriller with a Heart!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    g-bodyl
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Witness is a very good thriller with great moments of characterization and that is what sets it apart from other thrillers. Also, you really cannot classify this as thriller for the entire film because the middle portion is a haunting study on a group of peaceful people living away from technology. Harrison Ford gets out of his action movies to have one of the best roles of his career playing John Book. Peter Weir's film is about a hard-nosed detective named John Book who investigates a murder that a small Amish boy witnessed. Thanks to some betrayal, John is forced to live with the Amish and away from being a cop, he forbiddenly falls in love with Rachel, a beautiful Amish woman. As mentioned before, Harrison gives one of his better roles and is full of heartfelt emotion. Kelly McGillis, in her second ever movie, rises to great heights with her shy performance. I also find it ironic how Danny Glover plays a villain who murders cops right before his famed Lethal Weapon series. Overall, Witness is a beautifully shot film that has some intense scenes especially in the beginning and the end. We get to meet a group of people that stay away from society. The music by Maurice Jarre is wonderful and fits well with the themes of the movie. I find it funny how an award-winning thriller like this was released in February. I rate this film 9/10.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "You be careful out among the English."
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    romanorum1
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    After her husband's premature death, a young Amish woman, Rachel Lapp (Kelley McGillis), takes her son Samuel (Lukas Haas) on a train trip to Baltimore. While in the men's washroom at the Philadelphia station, young Samuel witnesses a brutal murder. By his own wits he saves himself from the scary murderer McFee (Danny Glover). Detective John Book (Harrison Ford), summoned to the murder scene, perceives that the dead man is an undercover cop. He questions Rachel and Samuel. From a photograph, Samuel fingers McFee, among others a corrupt cop. McFee had stolen large quantities of a chemical substance used in the manufacture of methamphetamine. The bad guys try to set up Book for a hit, but fail (although he is wounded by McFee). Now searched by the bad guys, Book goes into hiding in Pennsylvania German (Amish) country (Lancaster County, PA) to blend in with the religious sect. The middle part of the movie, and by far the greater segment overall, is the focus on the Amish community. This section is almost a documentary. We learn that the Amish shun the new ways, and live much as they did in the eighteenth century. Unlike the nearby Mennonites, the Amish reject automobiles, electricity, and telephones. Gas lamps are used. The Amish ride in traditional horse and buggy units while heavy traffic passes them by (when they can). They wear plain clothes and use hooks and eyes, rather than buttons or zippers, which they consider proud and vain. There is a nice barn-raising scene, where the Amish people together erect a barn within one day for a newly married couple. We see how the tourists think about the Amish, and Book's reaction to human pests. There is the obvious clash between the modern (Book-urban) and the olden (Rachel-rural) ways. Nevertheless, as Book outwardly becomes part of the Amish community, Rachel and he begin to draw closer. The sponge bath scene is probably the most notable one in the movie. If John and Rachel decide to come together, one of them will have to give up his/her ways, for there is no middle ground. What will happen? Meanwhile three bad cops, including corrupt Chief Schaeffer (played by Josef Sommer) and McFee, track down their quarry and arrive in Amish country to do in Book. So the final scenario is the shootout between the good and the bad. What will the peaceful Amish people do? Perhaps not what you may expect! The acting is very good all-around. Harrison Ford may have given us his best performance here as a decent cop (who does not overact), although others may opt with justification for "The Fugitive" or the "Indiana Jones" series. Kelley McGillis makes a fine and dedicated Amish lady. Jan Rubes plays moral kingpin Eli Lapp, while Danny Glover is indeed chilling as a bad cop. The subtleties / expressions of the actors work so well. For instance, Lukas Haas's bewildered face when he spots McFee's photo in the police station speaks volumes. Of course, the looks of Mc Gillis and Ford during the famous sponge bath scene do not require a word of dialog. See this movie more than once.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An Interesting Look At The Amish
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gavin6942
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A young Amish boy is sole witness to a murder; policeman John Book (Harrison Ford) goes into hiding in Amish country to protect him until the trial. First of all, I have to point out that this was the first big screen role for Viggo Mortensen. Well done, sir. Although they did not know it then, you went on to be a big man in Hollywood. Great to see you here. More importantly, how to judge this film? From an entertainment point of view, it is pretty darn good. I loved Harrison Ford, and I think this is one of Peter Weir's more "fun" films. I am sure more people enjoyed this than "Picnic at Hanging Rock" (which is probably the better film, but not a fun movie by any means). And yet, is this a fair portrayal of the Amish? Is it accurate? Is it exploitation? Were they consulted on how they would be shown here? I suppose in some sense it does not matter because the strict Amish would never see the movie, but it does not do them any favors if they are presented as being something they are not...
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Witness (1985)
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ashish sood (ashistrong@gmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It is a film about adults, whose lives have dignity and whose choices matter to them. The story focuses on a detective (Harrison Ford) protecting a young Amish boy who becomes the target of a ruthless killer after he witnesses a brutal murder. Witness is as much about the meeting of cultures as about cops and robbers, this is one of those lucky movies which works out well on all counts and shows that there are still craftsmen lurking in Hollywood. The film is powerful, assured, full of beautiful imagery and devoid of easy moralising, which is good. Ford is Chicago Detective John Book, assigned to investigate a murder that was committed by crooked cop Danny Glover. The only witness is the son of an Amish widow, played by Kelly McGillis. When Book gets too close to the truth, the crooked cops try to kill him, forcing Book to take it on the lamb and hide out in the Amish country. There, he slowly makes a transition into their society, their way of life, and of course, he starts to fall for Kelly McGillis. (who would later star with pretty boy Cruise in "Top Gun"). Alexander Godunov, who later played the murderous Karl in "Die Hard", makes his debut here as an Amish farmer who is, Ford's romantic rival for Kelly. Also making his debut here is a much younger Viggo Mortensen as another Amish father. Mortensen's barely evident in the role out here,although had his eventual success as Aragorn in "Lord of the Rings" ........ After Star Wars & Indiana Jones,Ford succeeded in a serious role and his multi-layered performance earned him his only Oscar Nomination till date.Well directed Romantic Thriller by Peter Weir (Director of Dead poet's Society and Truman Show) that earned him his first Academy Award Nomination. Do watch this one for great Cinematography and Artwork My Rating - 8/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Wonderfully Poignant, Suspenseful Film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Helio Copter
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I only just recently watched this film for the first time by catching it on television. I had been aware of it in terms of the title and Harrison Ford, but had never actually read up on the plot. I am very glad that I watched it. This film is so much more than the crime/legal drama that I had imagined it to be. The directing, cinematography, screenplay and acting are all wonderfully executed. The contrast between the overt, aggressive world of police and murder investigations in the city with the subdued, understated world of the Amish, is exceptionally well portrayed. Harrison Ford does a fine job in his role. The single most beautiful performance, though, is Kelly McGillis. As other reviews have noted, she does not have an excess of spoken dialog, but her physical acting, in particular her eyes and face, is incredibly evocative and moving. If anyone should have gotten a nomination, it should have been her. Watching her play this role was a revelation to me. One also has to credit the great performance of the then-very-young Lukas Haas. His impressive turn may be as much a true key to this film's success as any other single element. The rest of the characters are well-cast themselves. I greatly admired the ending to this film. I think that it speaks to Peter Weir's directatorial sensibilities. In the hands of a lesser director, it could have been far more clich&eacute;d, but far less powerful. I was nearly thirty years late seeing WITNESS, but I think that it is a timelessly poignant example of excellent storytelling.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Never get tired of the 'barn-raising' scene
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Andreapworth
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Whenever I happen upon this movie (cable), I get sucked in, although I've seen it enough times. It's just a good story with it's own suspense. We all are rooting for little Lucas and the fact that John Book has to hide him and his mother away from the 'bad guys'. So many scenes are worth seeing again, especially when John Book gets hurt and must rely on the the Amish people to heal him - no doctors, of course. And of course, when Rachel's father wakes him up at the crack of dawn for milking. And when Radhel gives him some clothes that were her late husband's and explains that zippers and buttons are 'too proud'. And as mentioned, if you once see the barn raising scene, it will stay with you forever. Truly moving and a real example of community and what can be done by all people.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Maybe it had a point at the time...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Andrew Werling (awerling)
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Okay, so John Book is in dire straits, and so is a kid and probably his mother, but he seems to feel none of this urgency, and we watch irritating scenes of him falling in love, drinking lemonade, barn-raising, milking a cow...just not very well crafted in my opinion. And the soundtrack was cheesy. Great acting, cinematography, I'll give it that. I think the film took on too much. I just found it nearly impossible to believe his calmness in the face of one of the worst realities a cop can face: the corruption of his friends and mentors. And maybe I'm just jaded by better films on this topic which were made later: L.A. Confidential, 13 Blocks, even Copland. But I just felt antsy watching this in 2012, and I usually really dig Peter Weir films, even the cheesy ones.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Murder, Corruption & Doomed Love
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    seymourblack-1
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Witness" is a subtle, thoughtful and intelligently directed film which is both a crime thriller and an extraordinary love story. A police investigation into a brutal murder provides this drama with its momentum and drive and a tragic romantic tale adds the intensity, warmth and poignancy that elevates this movie to a higher level than that normally achieved by more routine thrillers. The story about two people from different backgrounds who fall in love, but know that their love can't transcend their circumstances, has a timeless and universal appeal which explains why this movie has retained its popularity so consistently since it was first released in 1985. When a recently widowed young Amish woman and her son are in a train station in Philadelphia, the 8-year-old boy witnesses the murder of an undercover cop. Detective Captain John Book (Harrison Ford) is put in charge of the investigation and questions Samuel Lapp (Lukas Haas), but even after showing him mug shots and arranging line-ups of suspects, the boy isn't able to finger the culprit. A little while later, however, Samuel is looking around the police office when he notices the killer's picture on a newspaper clipping that's pinned up inside a glass cabinet. When he brings this to Book's attention, it's quite a shock because the man in the photograph is the highly decorated Detective Lieutenant McFee (Danny Glover) of the Narcotics Division. Detective Book tells his superior officer Detective Chief Schaeffer (Josef Sommer) about this development and Schaeffer asks him to keep the information confidential. Shortly after, when he's shot at and injured by McFee, it becomes obvious to Book that McFee and Schaeffer are both corrupt and Samuel and his mother Rachel (Kelly McGillis) are in mortal danger. In order to protect them, Book drives them back to their Amish community but after his arrival there, he collapses and has to remain with the Amish where Rachel gradually nurses him back to health. During Book's period of recuperation, he and Rachel fall in love but he soon realises that neither of them could survive indefinitely in the other's world. Book adapts well to living with the Amish and earns their respect as he readily helps with milking cows and building a barn, but his presence in their community places them in danger, as becomes all too clear when the story reaches its action-packed conclusion. Non-verbal communication is used frequently in this movie and provides the action with an extremely natural feel. A couple of the stand-out sequences are those in which Samuel looks at Book in a way that immediately signifies that he's seen something important (when he sees McFee's photograph) and another is when Book and Rachel dance together in a barn to Sam Cooke's "What A Wonderful World". The power to convey their thoughts and feelings so clearly in this way is very touching at times and also testifies strongly to the quality of the acting. The differences between the worlds that Book and Rachel inhabit couldn't be greater as the Amish reside in rural surroundings and live a quiet, non-violent existence in which it's normal for everyone to help everyone else. These people embrace old fashioned values and don't use modern conveniences such as cars and refrigerators etc. By contrast, Book's existence as a city cop is far less serene and regularly brings him into contact with violence, corruption and various other forms of errant human behaviour. "Witness", with its interesting characters, its absorbing story of murder, corruption and doomed love and its marvellous acting performances, is tremendously enjoyable to watch and leaves a lasting impression.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "One Of Ford's Best!"
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gwnightscream
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/9/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Harrison Ford, Kelly McGillis, Lucas Haas, Jan Rubes, Danny Glover, Josef Sommer, Patti LuPone, and Alexander Godunov star in this 1985 thriller. This film begins in Pennsylvania in a small Amish town where a widow, Rachel Lapp (McGillis) attends her late husband's funeral with her family and friends. Soon, Rachel and her young son, Samuel (Haas) head to Baltimore to visit her sister until Samuel witnesses a cop's murder in Philadelphia. Ford plays John Book, a cop who investigates the case and tries to protect Rachel and Samuel. When he's almost killed by crooked cops, John takes Rachel and Samuel home, but hides there with them learning their Amish ways. Rubes plays Rachel's father-in-law, Eli, Glover plays cop, McFee, Sommer plays John's mentor, Schaeffer, LuPone plays John's sister, Elaine and Godunov (Die Hard) plays Daniel, an Amish friend of Rachel's family. This is one of Ford's best and he and McGillis are great together. Maurice Jarre's score is also excellent and I recommend this.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A classic thriller with a great setting
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Jellybeansucker
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Great thriller story and setting. Not sure if the child witness angle was new but certainly his background was, the Amish community, and that's the main pleasure of this movie. The film's pace slows down but the interest and drama is heightened when Book is holed up at the farm. That's well worked by the writers and the love interest is nicely done, and there is real chemistry between Ford and McGillis, what a match! For the ending, the natural thriller pace comes back, it's intense too because we know Book is a good guy who's protective of his hosts. They could have overdone this with a DePalma style OTT shoot out, but this was just right for the movie. The only flaw is a pretty incredible decision by Book just to go into hiding at the Amish farm, putting them all at risk. In reality he'd be shopping his bent police chief to the FBI, the press and anyone else who'd listen and seeking witness protection for the boy. A major flaw, but the creators wanted to finish the movie at the Amish community as well, which is understandable. Overall a real breath of fresh air for the thriller genre, a well rounded movie with something for everyone, an original setting and a fantastic lead link up with Ford at his best and an almost unknown McGillis proving sex appeal doesn't need glamour at all! One of my favourites, a little gem of a thriller.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Genuine Thriller with a Heart!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    g-bodyl
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Witness is a very good thriller with great moments of characterization and that is what sets it apart from other thrillers. Also, you really cannot classify this as thriller for the entire film because the middle portion is a haunting study on a group of peaceful people living away from technology. Harrison Ford gets out of his action movies to have one of the best roles of his career playing John Book. Peter Weir's film is about a hard-nosed detective named John Book who investigates a murder that a small Amish boy witnessed. Thanks to some betrayal, John is forced to live with the Amish and away from being a cop, he forbiddenly falls in love with Rachel, a beautiful Amish woman. As mentioned before, Harrison gives one of his better roles and is full of heartfelt emotion. Kelly McGillis, in her second ever movie, rises to great heights with her shy performance. I also find it ironic how Danny Glover plays a villain who murders cops right before his famed Lethal Weapon series. Overall, Witness is a beautifully shot film that has some intense scenes especially in the beginning and the end. We get to meet a group of people that stay away from society. The music by Maurice Jarre is wonderful and fits well with the themes of the movie. I find it funny how an award-winning thriller like this was released in February. I rate this film 9/10.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "You be careful out among the English."
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    romanorum1
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    After her husband's premature death, a young Amish woman, Rachel Lapp (Kelley McGillis), takes her son Samuel (Lukas Haas) on a train trip to Baltimore. While in the men's washroom at the Philadelphia station, young Samuel witnesses a brutal murder. By his own wits he saves himself from the scary murderer McFee (Danny Glover). Detective John Book (Harrison Ford), summoned to the murder scene, perceives that the dead man is an undercover cop. He questions Rachel and Samuel. From a photograph, Samuel fingers McFee, among others a corrupt cop. McFee had stolen large quantities of a chemical substance used in the manufacture of methamphetamine. The bad guys try to set up Book for a hit, but fail (although he is wounded by McFee). Now searched by the bad guys, Book goes into hiding in Pennsylvania German (Amish) country (Lancaster County, PA) to blend in with the religious sect. The middle part of the movie, and by far the greater segment overall, is the focus on the Amish community. This section is almost a documentary. We learn that the Amish shun the new ways, and live much as they did in the eighteenth century. Unlike the nearby Mennonites, the Amish reject automobiles, electricity, and telephones. Gas lamps are used. The Amish ride in traditional horse and buggy units while heavy traffic passes them by (when they can). They wear plain clothes and use hooks and eyes, rather than buttons or zippers, which they consider proud and vain. There is a nice barn-raising scene, where the Amish people together erect a barn within one day for a newly married couple. We see how the tourists think about the Amish, and Book's reaction to human pests. There is the obvious clash between the modern (Book-urban) and the olden (Rachel-rural) ways. Nevertheless, as Book outwardly becomes part of the Amish community, Rachel and he begin to draw closer. The sponge bath scene is probably the most notable one in the movie. If John and Rachel decide to come together, one of them will have to give up his/her ways, for there is no middle ground. What will happen? Meanwhile three bad cops, including corrupt Chief Schaeffer (played by Josef Sommer) and McFee, track down their quarry and arrive in Amish country to do in Book. So the final scenario is the shootout between the good and the bad. What will the peaceful Amish people do? Perhaps not what you may expect! The acting is very good all-around. Harrison Ford may have given us his best performance here as a decent cop (who does not overact), although others may opt with justification for "The Fugitive" or the "Indiana Jones" series. Kelley McGillis makes a fine and dedicated Amish lady. Jan Rubes plays moral kingpin Eli Lapp, while Danny Glover is indeed chilling as a bad cop. The subtleties / expressions of the actors work so well. For instance, Lukas Haas's bewildered face when he spots McFee's photo in the police station speaks volumes. Of course, the looks of Mc Gillis and Ford during the famous sponge bath scene do not require a word of dialog. See this movie more than once.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An Interesting Look At The Amish
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gavin6942
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A young Amish boy is sole witness to a murder; policeman John Book (Harrison Ford) goes into hiding in Amish country to protect him until the trial. First of all, I have to point out that this was the first big screen role for Viggo Mortensen. Well done, sir. Although they did not know it then, you went on to be a big man in Hollywood. Great to see you here. More importantly, how to judge this film? From an entertainment point of view, it is pretty darn good. I loved Harrison Ford, and I think this is one of Peter Weir's more "fun" films. I am sure more people enjoyed this than "Picnic at Hanging Rock" (which is probably the better film, but not a fun movie by any means). And yet, is this a fair portrayal of the Amish? Is it accurate? Is it exploitation? Were they consulted on how they would be shown here? I suppose in some sense it does not matter because the strict Amish would never see the movie, but it does not do them any favors if they are presented as being something they are not...
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Witness (1985)
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ashish sood (ashistrong@gmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It is a film about adults, whose lives have dignity and whose choices matter to them. The story focuses on a detective (Harrison Ford) protecting a young Amish boy who becomes the target of a ruthless killer after he witnesses a brutal murder. Witness is as much about the meeting of cultures as about cops and robbers, this is one of those lucky movies which works out well on all counts and shows that there are still craftsmen lurking in Hollywood. The film is powerful, assured, full of beautiful imagery and devoid of easy moralising, which is good. Ford is Chicago Detective John Book, assigned to investigate a murder that was committed by crooked cop Danny Glover. The only witness is the son of an Amish widow, played by Kelly McGillis. When Book gets too close to the truth, the crooked cops try to kill him, forcing Book to take it on the lamb and hide out in the Amish country. There, he slowly makes a transition into their society, their way of life, and of course, he starts to fall for Kelly McGillis. (who would later star with pretty boy Cruise in "Top Gun"). Alexander Godunov, who later played the murderous Karl in "Die Hard", makes his debut here as an Amish farmer who is, Ford's romantic rival for Kelly. Also making his debut here is a much younger Viggo Mortensen as another Amish father. Mortensen's barely evident in the role out here,although had his eventual success as Aragorn in "Lord of the Rings" ........ After Star Wars & Indiana Jones,Ford succeeded in a serious role and his multi-layered performance earned him his only Oscar Nomination till date.Well directed Romantic Thriller by Peter Weir (Director of Dead poet's Society and Truman Show) that earned him his first Academy Award Nomination. Do watch this one for great Cinematography and Artwork My Rating - 8/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Wonderfully Poignant, Suspenseful Film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Helio Copter
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I only just recently watched this film for the first time by catching it on television. I had been aware of it in terms of the title and Harrison Ford, but had never actually read up on the plot. I am very glad that I watched it. This film is so much more than the crime/legal drama that I had imagined it to be. The directing, cinematography, screenplay and acting are all wonderfully executed. The contrast between the overt, aggressive world of police and murder investigations in the city with the subdued, understated world of the Amish, is exceptionally well portrayed. Harrison Ford does a fine job in his role. The single most beautiful performance, though, is Kelly McGillis. As other reviews have noted, she does not have an excess of spoken dialog, but her physical acting, in particular her eyes and face, is incredibly evocative and moving. If anyone should have gotten a nomination, it should have been her. Watching her play this role was a revelation to me. One also has to credit the great performance of the then-very-young Lukas Haas. His impressive turn may be as much a true key to this film's success as any other single element. The rest of the characters are well-cast themselves. I greatly admired the ending to this film. I think that it speaks to Peter Weir's directatorial sensibilities. In the hands of a lesser director, it could have been far more clich&eacute;d, but far less powerful. I was nearly thirty years late seeing WITNESS, but I think that it is a timelessly poignant example of excellent storytelling.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Never get tired of the 'barn-raising' scene
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Andreapworth
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Whenever I happen upon this movie (cable), I get sucked in, although I've seen it enough times. It's just a good story with it's own suspense. We all are rooting for little Lucas and the fact that John Book has to hide him and his mother away from the 'bad guys'. So many scenes are worth seeing again, especially when John Book gets hurt and must rely on the the Amish people to heal him - no doctors, of course. And of course, when Rachel's father wakes him up at the crack of dawn for milking. And when Radhel gives him some clothes that were her late husband's and explains that zippers and buttons are 'too proud'. And as mentioned, if you once see the barn raising scene, it will stay with you forever. Truly moving and a real example of community and what can be done by all people.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Maybe it had a point at the time...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Andrew Werling (awerling)
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Okay, so John Book is in dire straits, and so is a kid and probably his mother, but he seems to feel none of this urgency, and we watch irritating scenes of him falling in love, drinking lemonade, barn-raising, milking a cow...just not very well crafted in my opinion. And the soundtrack was cheesy. Great acting, cinematography, I'll give it that. I think the film took on too much. I just found it nearly impossible to believe his calmness in the face of one of the worst realities a cop can face: the corruption of his friends and mentors. And maybe I'm just jaded by better films on this topic which were made later: L.A. Confidential, 13 Blocks, even Copland. But I just felt antsy watching this in 2012, and I usually really dig Peter Weir films, even the cheesy ones.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Murder, Corruption & Doomed Love
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    seymourblack-1
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Witness" is a subtle, thoughtful and intelligently directed film which is both a crime thriller and an extraordinary love story. A police investigation into a brutal murder provides this drama with its momentum and drive and a tragic romantic tale adds the intensity, warmth and poignancy that elevates this movie to a higher level than that normally achieved by more routine thrillers. The story about two people from different backgrounds who fall in love, but know that their love can't transcend their circumstances, has a timeless and universal appeal which explains why this movie has retained its popularity so consistently since it was first released in 1985. When a recently widowed young Amish woman and her son are in a train station in Philadelphia, the 8-year-old boy witnesses the murder of an undercover cop. Detective Captain John Book (Harrison Ford) is put in charge of the investigation and questions Samuel Lapp (Lukas Haas), but even after showing him mug shots and arranging line-ups of suspects, the boy isn't able to finger the culprit. A little while later, however, Samuel is looking around the police office when he notices the killer's picture on a newspaper clipping that's pinned up inside a glass cabinet. When he brings this to Book's attention, it's quite a shock because the man in the photograph is the highly decorated Detective Lieutenant McFee (Danny Glover) of the Narcotics Division. Detective Book tells his superior officer Detective Chief Schaeffer (Josef Sommer) about this development and Schaeffer asks him to keep the information confidential. Shortly after, when he's shot at and injured by McFee, it becomes obvious to Book that McFee and Schaeffer are both corrupt and Samuel and his mother Rachel (Kelly McGillis) are in mortal danger. In order to protect them, Book drives them back to their Amish community but after his arrival there, he collapses and has to remain with the Amish where Rachel gradually nurses him back to health. During Book's period of recuperation, he and Rachel fall in love but he soon realises that neither of them could survive indefinitely in the other's world. Book adapts well to living with the Amish and earns their respect as he readily helps with milking cows and building a barn, but his presence in their community places them in danger, as becomes all too clear when the story reaches its action-packed conclusion. Non-verbal communication is used frequently in this movie and provides the action with an extremely natural feel. A couple of the stand-out sequences are those in which Samuel looks at Book in a way that immediately signifies that he's seen something important (when he sees McFee's photograph) and another is when Book and Rachel dance together in a barn to Sam Cooke's "What A Wonderful World". The power to convey their thoughts and feelings so clearly in this way is very touching at times and also testifies strongly to the quality of the acting. The differences between the worlds that Book and Rachel inhabit couldn't be greater as the Amish reside in rural surroundings and live a quiet, non-violent existence in which it's normal for everyone to help everyone else. These people embrace old fashioned values and don't use modern conveniences such as cars and refrigerators etc. By contrast, Book's existence as a city cop is far less serene and regularly brings him into contact with violence, corruption and various other forms of errant human behaviour. "Witness", with its interesting characters, its absorbing story of murder, corruption and doomed love and its marvellous acting performances, is tremendously enjoyable to watch and leaves a lasting impression.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "One Of Ford's Best!"
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gwnightscream
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/9/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Harrison Ford, Kelly McGillis, Lucas Haas, Jan Rubes, Danny Glover, Josef Sommer, Patti LuPone, and Alexander Godunov star in this 1985 thriller. This film begins in Pennsylvania in a small Amish town where a widow, Rachel Lapp (McGillis) attends her late husband's funeral with her family and friends. Soon, Rachel and her young son, Samuel (Haas) head to Baltimore to visit her sister until Samuel witnesses a cop's murder in Philadelphia. Ford plays John Book, a cop who investigates the case and tries to protect Rachel and Samuel. When he's almost killed by crooked cops, John takes Rachel and Samuel home, but hides there with them learning their Amish ways. Rubes plays Rachel's father-in-law, Eli, Glover plays cop, McFee, Sommer plays John's mentor, Schaeffer, LuPone plays John's sister, Elaine and Godunov (Die Hard) plays Daniel, an Amish friend of Rachel's family. This is one of Ford's best and he and McGillis are great together. Maurice Jarre's score is also excellent and I recommend this.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A classic thriller with a great setting
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Jellybeansucker
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Great thriller story and setting. Not sure if the child witness angle was new but certainly his background was, the Amish community, and that's the main pleasure of this movie. The film's pace slows down but the interest and drama is heightened when Book is holed up at the farm. That's well worked by the writers and the love interest is nicely done, and there is real chemistry between Ford and McGillis, what a match! For the ending, the natural thriller pace comes back, it's intense too because we know Book is a good guy who's protective of his hosts. They could have overdone this with a DePalma style OTT shoot out, but this was just right for the movie. The only flaw is a pretty incredible decision by Book just to go into hiding at the Amish farm, putting them all at risk. In reality he'd be shopping his bent police chief to the FBI, the press and anyone else who'd listen and seeking witness protection for the boy. A major flaw, but the creators wanted to finish the movie at the Amish community as well, which is understandable. Overall a real breath of fresh air for the thriller genre, a well rounded movie with something for everyone, an original setting and a fantastic lead link up with Ford at his best and an almost unknown McGillis proving sex appeal doesn't need glamour at all! One of my favourites, a little gem of a thriller.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Genuine Thriller with a Heart!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    g-bodyl
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Witness is a very good thriller with great moments of characterization and that is what sets it apart from other thrillers. Also, you really cannot classify this as thriller for the entire film because the middle portion is a haunting study on a group of peaceful people living away from technology. Harrison Ford gets out of his action movies to have one of the best roles of his career playing John Book. Peter Weir's film is about a hard-nosed detective named John Book who investigates a murder that a small Amish boy witnessed. Thanks to some betrayal, John is forced to live with the Amish and away from being a cop, he forbiddenly falls in love with Rachel, a beautiful Amish woman. As mentioned before, Harrison gives one of his better roles and is full of heartfelt emotion. Kelly McGillis, in her second ever movie, rises to great heights with her shy performance. I also find it ironic how Danny Glover plays a villain who murders cops right before his famed Lethal Weapon series. Overall, Witness is a beautifully shot film that has some intense scenes especially in the beginning and the end. We get to meet a group of people that stay away from society. The music by Maurice Jarre is wonderful and fits well with the themes of the movie. I find it funny how an award-winning thriller like this was released in February. I rate this film 9/10.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "You be careful out among the English."
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    romanorum1
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    After her husband's premature death, a young Amish woman, Rachel Lapp (Kelley McGillis), takes her son Samuel (Lukas Haas) on a train trip to Baltimore. While in the men's washroom at the Philadelphia station, young Samuel witnesses a brutal murder. By his own wits he saves himself from the scary murderer McFee (Danny Glover). Detective John Book (Harrison Ford), summoned to the murder scene, perceives that the dead man is an undercover cop. He questions Rachel and Samuel. From a photograph, Samuel fingers McFee, among others a corrupt cop. McFee had stolen large quantities of a chemical substance used in the manufacture of methamphetamine. The bad guys try to set up Book for a hit, but fail (although he is wounded by McFee). Now searched by the bad guys, Book goes into hiding in Pennsylvania German (Amish) country (Lancaster County, PA) to blend in with the religious sect. The middle part of the movie, and by far the greater segment overall, is the focus on the Amish community. This section is almost a documentary. We learn that the Amish shun the new ways, and live much as they did in the eighteenth century. Unlike the nearby Mennonites, the Amish reject automobiles, electricity, and telephones. Gas lamps are used. The Amish ride in traditional horse and buggy units while heavy traffic passes them by (when they can). They wear plain clothes and use hooks and eyes, rather than buttons or zippers, which they consider proud and vain. There is a nice barn-raising scene, where the Amish people together erect a barn within one day for a newly married couple. We see how the tourists think about the Amish, and Book's reaction to human pests. There is the obvious clash between the modern (Book-urban) and the olden (Rachel-rural) ways. Nevertheless, as Book outwardly becomes part of the Amish community, Rachel and he begin to draw closer. The sponge bath scene is probably the most notable one in the movie. If John and Rachel decide to come together, one of them will have to give up his/her ways, for there is no middle ground. What will happen? Meanwhile three bad cops, including corrupt Chief Schaeffer (played by Josef Sommer) and McFee, track down their quarry and arrive in Amish country to do in Book. So the final scenario is the shootout between the good and the bad. What will the peaceful Amish people do? Perhaps not what you may expect! The acting is very good all-around. Harrison Ford may have given us his best performance here as a decent cop (who does not overact), although others may opt with justification for "The Fugitive" or the "Indiana Jones" series. Kelley McGillis makes a fine and dedicated Amish lady. Jan Rubes plays moral kingpin Eli Lapp, while Danny Glover is indeed chilling as a bad cop. The subtleties / expressions of the actors work so well. For instance, Lukas Haas's bewildered face when he spots McFee's photo in the police station speaks volumes. Of course, the looks of Mc Gillis and Ford during the famous sponge bath scene do not require a word of dialog. See this movie more than once.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An Interesting Look At The Amish
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gavin6942
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A young Amish boy is sole witness to a murder; policeman John Book (Harrison Ford) goes into hiding in Amish country to protect him until the trial. First of all, I have to point out that this was the first big screen role for Viggo Mortensen. Well done, sir. Although they did not know it then, you went on to be a big man in Hollywood. Great to see you here. More importantly, how to judge this film? From an entertainment point of view, it is pretty darn good. I loved Harrison Ford, and I think this is one of Peter Weir's more "fun" films. I am sure more people enjoyed this than "Picnic at Hanging Rock" (which is probably the better film, but not a fun movie by any means). And yet, is this a fair portrayal of the Amish? Is it accurate? Is it exploitation? Were they consulted on how they would be shown here? I suppose in some sense it does not matter because the strict Amish would never see the movie, but it does not do them any favors if they are presented as being something they are not...
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Witness (1985)
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ashish sood (ashistrong@gmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It is a film about adults, whose lives have dignity and whose choices matter to them. The story focuses on a detective (Harrison Ford) protecting a young Amish boy who becomes the target of a ruthless killer after he witnesses a brutal murder. Witness is as much about the meeting of cultures as about cops and robbers, this is one of those lucky movies which works out well on all counts and shows that there are still craftsmen lurking in Hollywood. The film is powerful, assured, full of beautiful imagery and devoid of easy moralising, which is good. Ford is Chicago Detective John Book, assigned to investigate a murder that was committed by crooked cop Danny Glover. The only witness is the son of an Amish widow, played by Kelly McGillis. When Book gets too close to the truth, the crooked cops try to kill him, forcing Book to take it on the lamb and hide out in the Amish country. There, he slowly makes a transition into their society, their way of life, and of course, he starts to fall for Kelly McGillis. (who would later star with pretty boy Cruise in "Top Gun"). Alexander Godunov, who later played the murderous Karl in "Die Hard", makes his debut here as an Amish farmer who is, Ford's romantic rival for Kelly. Also making his debut here is a much younger Viggo Mortensen as another Amish father. Mortensen's barely evident in the role out here,although had his eventual success as Aragorn in "Lord of the Rings" ........ After Star Wars & Indiana Jones,Ford succeeded in a serious role and his multi-layered performance earned him his only Oscar Nomination till date.Well directed Romantic Thriller by Peter Weir (Director of Dead poet's Society and Truman Show) that earned him his first Academy Award Nomination. Do watch this one for great Cinematography and Artwork My Rating - 8/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Wonderfully Poignant, Suspenseful Film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Helio Copter
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I only just recently watched this film for the first time by catching it on television. I had been aware of it in terms of the title and Harrison Ford, but had never actually read up on the plot. I am very glad that I watched it. This film is so much more than the crime/legal drama that I had imagined it to be. The directing, cinematography, screenplay and acting are all wonderfully executed. The contrast between the overt, aggressive world of police and murder investigations in the city with the subdued, understated world of the Amish, is exceptionally well portrayed. Harrison Ford does a fine job in his role. The single most beautiful performance, though, is Kelly McGillis. As other reviews have noted, she does not have an excess of spoken dialog, but her physical acting, in particular her eyes and face, is incredibly evocative and moving. If anyone should have gotten a nomination, it should have been her. Watching her play this role was a revelation to me. One also has to credit the great performance of the then-very-young Lukas Haas. His impressive turn may be as much a true key to this film's success as any other single element. The rest of the characters are well-cast themselves. I greatly admired the ending to this film. I think that it speaks to Peter Weir's directatorial sensibilities. In the hands of a lesser director, it could have been far more clich&eacute;d, but far less powerful. I was nearly thirty years late seeing WITNESS, but I think that it is a timelessly poignant example of excellent storytelling.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Never get tired of the 'barn-raising' scene
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Andreapworth
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Whenever I happen upon this movie (cable), I get sucked in, although I've seen it enough times. It's just a good story with it's own suspense. We all are rooting for little Lucas and the fact that John Book has to hide him and his mother away from the 'bad guys'. So many scenes are worth seeing again, especially when John Book gets hurt and must rely on the the Amish people to heal him - no doctors, of course. And of course, when Rachel's father wakes him up at the crack of dawn for milking. And when Radhel gives him some clothes that were her late husband's and explains that zippers and buttons are 'too proud'. And as mentioned, if you once see the barn raising scene, it will stay with you forever. Truly moving and a real example of community and what can be done by all people.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Maybe it had a point at the time...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Andrew Werling (awerling)
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Okay, so John Book is in dire straits, and so is a kid and probably his mother, but he seems to feel none of this urgency, and we watch irritating scenes of him falling in love, drinking lemonade, barn-raising, milking a cow...just not very well crafted in my opinion. And the soundtrack was cheesy. Great acting, cinematography, I'll give it that. I think the film took on too much. I just found it nearly impossible to believe his calmness in the face of one of the worst realities a cop can face: the corruption of his friends and mentors. And maybe I'm just jaded by better films on this topic which were made later: L.A. Confidential, 13 Blocks, even Copland. But I just felt antsy watching this in 2012, and I usually really dig Peter Weir films, even the cheesy ones.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Murder, Corruption & Doomed Love
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    seymourblack-1
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Witness" is a subtle, thoughtful and intelligently directed film which is both a crime thriller and an extraordinary love story. A police investigation into a brutal murder provides this drama with its momentum and drive and a tragic romantic tale adds the intensity, warmth and poignancy that elevates this movie to a higher level than that normally achieved by more routine thrillers. The story about two people from different backgrounds who fall in love, but know that their love can't transcend their circumstances, has a timeless and universal appeal which explains why this movie has retained its popularity so consistently since it was first released in 1985. When a recently widowed young Amish woman and her son are in a train station in Philadelphia, the 8-year-old boy witnesses the murder of an undercover cop. Detective Captain John Book (Harrison Ford) is put in charge of the investigation and questions Samuel Lapp (Lukas Haas), but even after showing him mug shots and arranging line-ups of suspects, the boy isn't able to finger the culprit. A little while later, however, Samuel is looking around the police office when he notices the killer's picture on a newspaper clipping that's pinned up inside a glass cabinet. When he brings this to Book's attention, it's quite a shock because the man in the photograph is the highly decorated Detective Lieutenant McFee (Danny Glover) of the Narcotics Division. Detective Book tells his superior officer Detective Chief Schaeffer (Josef Sommer) about this development and Schaeffer asks him to keep the information confidential. Shortly after, when he's shot at and injured by McFee, it becomes obvious to Book that McFee and Schaeffer are both corrupt and Samuel and his mother Rachel (Kelly McGillis) are in mortal danger. In order to protect them, Book drives them back to their Amish community but after his arrival there, he collapses and has to remain with the Amish where Rachel gradually nurses him back to health. During Book's period of recuperation, he and Rachel fall in love but he soon realises that neither of them could survive indefinitely in the other's world. Book adapts well to living with the Amish and earns their respect as he readily helps with milking cows and building a barn, but his presence in their community places them in danger, as becomes all too clear when the story reaches its action-packed conclusion. Non-verbal communication is used frequently in this movie and provides the action with an extremely natural feel. A couple of the stand-out sequences are those in which Samuel looks at Book in a way that immediately signifies that he's seen something important (when he sees McFee's photograph) and another is when Book and Rachel dance together in a barn to Sam Cooke's "What A Wonderful World". The power to convey their thoughts and feelings so clearly in this way is very touching at times and also testifies strongly to the quality of the acting. The differences between the worlds that Book and Rachel inhabit couldn't be greater as the Amish reside in rural surroundings and live a quiet, non-violent existence in which it's normal for everyone to help everyone else. These people embrace old fashioned values and don't use modern conveniences such as cars and refrigerators etc. By contrast, Book's existence as a city cop is far less serene and regularly brings him into contact with violence, corruption and various other forms of errant human behaviour. "Witness", with its interesting characters, its absorbing story of murder, corruption and doomed love and its marvellous acting performances, is tremendously enjoyable to watch and leaves a lasting impression.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "One Of Ford's Best!"
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gwnightscream
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/9/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Harrison Ford, Kelly McGillis, Lucas Haas, Jan Rubes, Danny Glover, Josef Sommer, Patti LuPone, and Alexander Godunov star in this 1985 thriller. This film begins in Pennsylvania in a small Amish town where a widow, Rachel Lapp (McGillis) attends her late husband's funeral with her family and friends. Soon, Rachel and her young son, Samuel (Haas) head to Baltimore to visit her sister until Samuel witnesses a cop's murder in Philadelphia. Ford plays John Book, a cop who investigates the case and tries to protect Rachel and Samuel. When he's almost killed by crooked cops, John takes Rachel and Samuel home, but hides there with them learning their Amish ways. Rubes plays Rachel's father-in-law, Eli, Glover plays cop, McFee, Sommer plays John's mentor, Schaeffer, LuPone plays John's sister, Elaine and Godunov (Die Hard) plays Daniel, an Amish friend of Rachel's family. This is one of Ford's best and he and McGillis are great together. Maurice Jarre's score is also excellent and I recommend this.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A classic thriller with a great setting
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Jellybeansucker
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Great thriller story and setting. Not sure if the child witness angle was new but certainly his background was, the Amish community, and that's the main pleasure of this movie. The film's pace slows down but the interest and drama is heightened when Book is holed up at the farm. That's well worked by the writers and the love interest is nicely done, and there is real chemistry between Ford and McGillis, what a match! For the ending, the natural thriller pace comes back, it's intense too because we know Book is a good guy who's protective of his hosts. They could have overdone this with a DePalma style OTT shoot out, but this was just right for the movie. The only flaw is a pretty incredible decision by Book just to go into hiding at the Amish farm, putting them all at risk. In reality he'd be shopping his bent police chief to the FBI, the press and anyone else who'd listen and seeking witness protection for the boy. A major flaw, but the creators wanted to finish the movie at the Amish community as well, which is understandable. Overall a real breath of fresh air for the thriller genre, a well rounded movie with something for everyone, an original setting and a fantastic lead link up with Ford at his best and an almost unknown McGillis proving sex appeal doesn't need glamour at all! One of my favourites, a little gem of a thriller.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Genuine Thriller with a Heart!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    g-bodyl
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Witness is a very good thriller with great moments of characterization and that is what sets it apart from other thrillers. Also, you really cannot classify this as thriller for the entire film because the middle portion is a haunting study on a group of peaceful people living away from technology. Harrison Ford gets out of his action movies to have one of the best roles of his career playing John Book. Peter Weir's film is about a hard-nosed detective named John Book who investigates a murder that a small Amish boy witnessed. Thanks to some betrayal, John is forced to live with the Amish and away from being a cop, he forbiddenly falls in love with Rachel, a beautiful Amish woman. As mentioned before, Harrison gives one of his better roles and is full of heartfelt emotion. Kelly McGillis, in her second ever movie, rises to great heights with her shy performance. I also find it ironic how Danny Glover plays a villain who murders cops right before his famed Lethal Weapon series. Overall, Witness is a beautifully shot film that has some intense scenes especially in the beginning and the end. We get to meet a group of people that stay away from society. The music by Maurice Jarre is wonderful and fits well with the themes of the movie. I find it funny how an award-winning thriller like this was released in February. I rate this film 9/10.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "You be careful out among the English."
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    romanorum1
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    After her husband's premature death, a young Amish woman, Rachel Lapp (Kelley McGillis), takes her son Samuel (Lukas Haas) on a train trip to Baltimore. While in the men's washroom at the Philadelphia station, young Samuel witnesses a brutal murder. By his own wits he saves himself from the scary murderer McFee (Danny Glover). Detective John Book (Harrison Ford), summoned to the murder scene, perceives that the dead man is an undercover cop. He questions Rachel and Samuel. From a photograph, Samuel fingers McFee, among others a corrupt cop. McFee had stolen large quantities of a chemical substance used in the manufacture of methamphetamine. The bad guys try to set up Book for a hit, but fail (although he is wounded by McFee). Now searched by the bad guys, Book goes into hiding in Pennsylvania German (Amish) country (Lancaster County, PA) to blend in with the religious sect. The middle part of the movie, and by far the greater segment overall, is the focus on the Amish community. This section is almost a documentary. We learn that the Amish shun the new ways, and live much as they did in the eighteenth century. Unlike the nearby Mennonites, the Amish reject automobiles, electricity, and telephones. Gas lamps are used. The Amish ride in traditional horse and buggy units while heavy traffic passes them by (when they can). They wear plain clothes and use hooks and eyes, rather than buttons or zippers, which they consider proud and vain. There is a nice barn-raising scene, where the Amish people together erect a barn within one day for a newly married couple. We see how the tourists think about the Amish, and Book's reaction to human pests. There is the obvious clash between the modern (Book-urban) and the olden (Rachel-rural) ways. Nevertheless, as Book outwardly becomes part of the Amish community, Rachel and he begin to draw closer. The sponge bath scene is probably the most notable one in the movie. If John and Rachel decide to come together, one of them will have to give up his/her ways, for there is no middle ground. What will happen? Meanwhile three bad cops, including corrupt Chief Schaeffer (played by Josef Sommer) and McFee, track down their quarry and arrive in Amish country to do in Book. So the final scenario is the shootout between the good and the bad. What will the peaceful Amish people do? Perhaps not what you may expect! The acting is very good all-around. Harrison Ford may have given us his best performance here as a decent cop (who does not overact), although others may opt with justification for "The Fugitive" or the "Indiana Jones" series. Kelley McGillis makes a fine and dedicated Amish lady. Jan Rubes plays moral kingpin Eli Lapp, while Danny Glover is indeed chilling as a bad cop. The subtleties / expressions of the actors work so well. For instance, Lukas Haas's bewildered face when he spots McFee's photo in the police station speaks volumes. Of course, the looks of Mc Gillis and Ford during the famous sponge bath scene do not require a word of dialog. See this movie more than once.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An Interesting Look At The Amish
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gavin6942
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A young Amish boy is sole witness to a murder; policeman John Book (Harrison Ford) goes into hiding in Amish country to protect him until the trial. First of all, I have to point out that this was the first big screen role for Viggo Mortensen. Well done, sir. Although they did not know it then, you went on to be a big man in Hollywood. Great to see you here. More importantly, how to judge this film? From an entertainment point of view, it is pretty darn good. I loved Harrison Ford, and I think this is one of Peter Weir's more "fun" films. I am sure more people enjoyed this than "Picnic at Hanging Rock" (which is probably the better film, but not a fun movie by any means). And yet, is this a fair portrayal of the Amish? Is it accurate? Is it exploitation? Were they consulted on how they would be shown here? I suppose in some sense it does not matter because the strict Amish would never see the movie, but it does not do them any favors if they are presented as being something they are not...
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Witness (1985)
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ashish sood (ashistrong@gmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It is a film about adults, whose lives have dignity and whose choices matter to them. The story focuses on a detective (Harrison Ford) protecting a young Amish boy who becomes the target of a ruthless killer after he witnesses a brutal murder. Witness is as much about the meeting of cultures as about cops and robbers, this is one of those lucky movies which works out well on all counts and shows that there are still craftsmen lurking in Hollywood. The film is powerful, assured, full of beautiful imagery and devoid of easy moralising, which is good. Ford is Chicago Detective John Book, assigned to investigate a murder that was committed by crooked cop Danny Glover. The only witness is the son of an Amish widow, played by Kelly McGillis. When Book gets too close to the truth, the crooked cops try to kill him, forcing Book to take it on the lamb and hide out in the Amish country. There, he slowly makes a transition into their society, their way of life, and of course, he starts to fall for Kelly McGillis. (who would later star with pretty boy Cruise in "Top Gun"). Alexander Godunov, who later played the murderous Karl in "Die Hard", makes his debut here as an Amish farmer who is, Ford's romantic rival for Kelly. Also making his debut here is a much younger Viggo Mortensen as another Amish father. Mortensen's barely evident in the role out here,although had his eventual success as Aragorn in "Lord of the Rings" ........ After Star Wars & Indiana Jones,Ford succeeded in a serious role and his multi-layered performance earned him his only Oscar Nomination till date.Well directed Romantic Thriller by Peter Weir (Director of Dead poet's Society and Truman Show) that earned him his first Academy Award Nomination. Do watch this one for great Cinematography and Artwork My Rating - 8/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Wonderfully Poignant, Suspenseful Film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Helio Copter
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I only just recently watched this film for the first time by catching it on television. I had been aware of it in terms of the title and Harrison Ford, but had never actually read up on the plot. I am very glad that I watched it. This film is so much more than the crime/legal drama that I had imagined it to be. The directing, cinematography, screenplay and acting are all wonderfully executed. The contrast between the overt, aggressive world of police and murder investigations in the city with the subdued, understated world of the Amish, is exceptionally well portrayed. Harrison Ford does a fine job in his role. The single most beautiful performance, though, is Kelly McGillis. As other reviews have noted, she does not have an excess of spoken dialog, but her physical acting, in particular her eyes and face, is incredibly evocative and moving. If anyone should have gotten a nomination, it should have been her. Watching her play this role was a revelation to me. One also has to credit the great performance of the then-very-young Lukas Haas. His impressive turn may be as much a true key to this film's success as any other single element. The rest of the characters are well-cast themselves. I greatly admired the ending to this film. I think that it speaks to Peter Weir's directatorial sensibilities. In the hands of a lesser director, it could have been far more clich&eacute;d, but far less powerful. I was nearly thirty years late seeing WITNESS, but I think that it is a timelessly poignant example of excellent storytelling.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Never get tired of the 'barn-raising' scene
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Andreapworth
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Whenever I happen upon this movie (cable), I get sucked in, although I've seen it enough times. It's just a good story with it's own suspense. We all are rooting for little Lucas and the fact that John Book has to hide him and his mother away from the 'bad guys'. So many scenes are worth seeing again, especially when John Book gets hurt and must rely on the the Amish people to heal him - no doctors, of course. And of course, when Rachel's father wakes him up at the crack of dawn for milking. And when Radhel gives him some clothes that were her late husband's and explains that zippers and buttons are 'too proud'. And as mentioned, if you once see the barn raising scene, it will stay with you forever. Truly moving and a real example of community and what can be done by all people.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Maybe it had a point at the time...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Andrew Werling (awerling)
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Okay, so John Book is in dire straits, and so is a kid and probably his mother, but he seems to feel none of this urgency, and we watch irritating scenes of him falling in love, drinking lemonade, barn-raising, milking a cow...just not very well crafted in my opinion. And the soundtrack was cheesy. Great acting, cinematography, I'll give it that. I think the film took on too much. I just found it nearly impossible to believe his calmness in the face of one of the worst realities a cop can face: the corruption of his friends and mentors. And maybe I'm just jaded by better films on this topic which were made later: L.A. Confidential, 13 Blocks, even Copland. But I just felt antsy watching this in 2012, and I usually really dig Peter Weir films, even the cheesy ones.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Murder, Corruption & Doomed Love
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    seymourblack-1
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Witness" is a subtle, thoughtful and intelligently directed film which is both a crime thriller and an extraordinary love story. A police investigation into a brutal murder provides this drama with its momentum and drive and a tragic romantic tale adds the intensity, warmth and poignancy that elevates this movie to a higher level than that normally achieved by more routine thrillers. The story about two people from different backgrounds who fall in love, but know that their love can't transcend their circumstances, has a timeless and universal appeal which explains why this movie has retained its popularity so consistently since it was first released in 1985. When a recently widowed young Amish woman and her son are in a train station in Philadelphia, the 8-year-old boy witnesses the murder of an undercover cop. Detective Captain John Book (Harrison Ford) is put in charge of the investigation and questions Samuel Lapp (Lukas Haas), but even after showing him mug shots and arranging line-ups of suspects, the boy isn't able to finger the culprit. A little while later, however, Samuel is looking around the police office when he notices the killer's picture on a newspaper clipping that's pinned up inside a glass cabinet. When he brings this to Book's attention, it's quite a shock because the man in the photograph is the highly decorated Detective Lieutenant McFee (Danny Glover) of the Narcotics Division. Detective Book tells his superior officer Detective Chief Schaeffer (Josef Sommer) about this development and Schaeffer asks him to keep the information confidential. Shortly after, when he's shot at and injured by McFee, it becomes obvious to Book that McFee and Schaeffer are both corrupt and Samuel and his mother Rachel (Kelly McGillis) are in mortal danger. In order to protect them, Book drives them back to their Amish community but after his arrival there, he collapses and has to remain with the Amish where Rachel gradually nurses him back to health. During Book's period of recuperation, he and Rachel fall in love but he soon realises that neither of them could survive indefinitely in the other's world. Book adapts well to living with the Amish and earns their respect as he readily helps with milking cows and building a barn, but his presence in their community places them in danger, as becomes all too clear when the story reaches its action-packed conclusion. Non-verbal communication is used frequently in this movie and provides the action with an extremely natural feel. A couple of the stand-out sequences are those in which Samuel looks at Book in a way that immediately signifies that he's seen something important (when he sees McFee's photograph) and another is when Book and Rachel dance together in a barn to Sam Cooke's "What A Wonderful World". The power to convey their thoughts and feelings so clearly in this way is very touching at times and also testifies strongly to the quality of the acting. The differences between the worlds that Book and Rachel inhabit couldn't be greater as the Amish reside in rural surroundings and live a quiet, non-violent existence in which it's normal for everyone to help everyone else. These people embrace old fashioned values and don't use modern conveniences such as cars and refrigerators etc. By contrast, Book's existence as a city cop is far less serene and regularly brings him into contact with violence, corruption and various other forms of errant human behaviour. "Witness", with its interesting characters, its absorbing story of murder, corruption and doomed love and its marvellous acting performances, is tremendously enjoyable to watch and leaves a lasting impression.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "One Of Ford's Best!"
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gwnightscream
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/9/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Harrison Ford, Kelly McGillis, Lucas Haas, Jan Rubes, Danny Glover, Josef Sommer, Patti LuPone, and Alexander Godunov star in this 1985 thriller. This film begins in Pennsylvania in a small Amish town where a widow, Rachel Lapp (McGillis) attends her late husband's funeral with her family and friends. Soon, Rachel and her young son, Samuel (Haas) head to Baltimore to visit her sister until Samuel witnesses a cop's murder in Philadelphia. Ford plays John Book, a cop who investigates the case and tries to protect Rachel and Samuel. When he's almost killed by crooked cops, John takes Rachel and Samuel home, but hides there with them learning their Amish ways. Rubes plays Rachel's father-in-law, Eli, Glover plays cop, McFee, Sommer plays John's mentor, Schaeffer, LuPone plays John's sister, Elaine and Godunov (Die Hard) plays Daniel, an Amish friend of Rachel's family. This is one of Ford's best and he and McGillis are great together. Maurice Jarre's score is also excellent and I recommend this.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A classic thriller with a great setting
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Jellybeansucker
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Great thriller story and setting. Not sure if the child witness angle was new but certainly his background was, the Amish community, and that's the main pleasure of this movie. The film's pace slows down but the interest and drama is heightened when Book is holed up at the farm. That's well worked by the writers and the love interest is nicely done, and there is real chemistry between Ford and McGillis, what a match! For the ending, the natural thriller pace comes back, it's intense too because we know Book is a good guy who's protective of his hosts. They could have overdone this with a DePalma style OTT shoot out, but this was just right for the movie. The only flaw is a pretty incredible decision by Book just to go into hiding at the Amish farm, putting them all at risk. In reality he'd be shopping his bent police chief to the FBI, the press and anyone else who'd listen and seeking witness protection for the boy. A major flaw, but the creators wanted to finish the movie at the Amish community as well, which is understandable. Overall a real breath of fresh air for the thriller genre, a well rounded movie with something for everyone, an original setting and a fantastic lead link up with Ford at his best and an almost unknown McGillis proving sex appeal doesn't need glamour at all! One of my favourites, a little gem of a thriller.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Genuine Thriller with a Heart!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    g-bodyl
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Witness is a very good thriller with great moments of characterization and that is what sets it apart from other thrillers. Also, you really cannot classify this as thriller for the entire film because the middle portion is a haunting study on a group of peaceful people living away from technology. Harrison Ford gets out of his action movies to have one of the best roles of his career playing John Book. Peter Weir's film is about a hard-nosed detective named John Book who investigates a murder that a small Amish boy witnessed. Thanks to some betrayal, John is forced to live with the Amish and away from being a cop, he forbiddenly falls in love with Rachel, a beautiful Amish woman. As mentioned before, Harrison gives one of his better roles and is full of heartfelt emotion. Kelly McGillis, in her second ever movie, rises to great heights with her shy performance. I also find it ironic how Danny Glover plays a villain who murders cops right before his famed Lethal Weapon series. Overall, Witness is a beautifully shot film that has some intense scenes especially in the beginning and the end. We get to meet a group of people that stay away from society. The music by Maurice Jarre is wonderful and fits well with the themes of the movie. I find it funny how an award-winning thriller like this was released in February. I rate this film 9/10.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "You be careful out among the English."
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    romanorum1
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    After her husband's premature death, a young Amish woman, Rachel Lapp (Kelley McGillis), takes her son Samuel (Lukas Haas) on a train trip to Baltimore. While in the men's washroom at the Philadelphia station, young Samuel witnesses a brutal murder. By his own wits he saves himself from the scary murderer McFee (Danny Glover). Detective John Book (Harrison Ford), summoned to the murder scene, perceives that the dead man is an undercover cop. He questions Rachel and Samuel. From a photograph, Samuel fingers McFee, among others a corrupt cop. McFee had stolen large quantities of a chemical substance used in the manufacture of methamphetamine. The bad guys try to set up Book for a hit, but fail (although he is wounded by McFee). Now searched by the bad guys, Book goes into hiding in Pennsylvania German (Amish) country (Lancaster County, PA) to blend in with the religious sect. The middle part of the movie, and by far the greater segment overall, is the focus on the Amish community. This section is almost a documentary. We learn that the Amish shun the new ways, and live much as they did in the eighteenth century. Unlike the nearby Mennonites, the Amish reject automobiles, electricity, and telephones. Gas lamps are used. The Amish ride in traditional horse and buggy units while heavy traffic passes them by (when they can). They wear plain clothes and use hooks and eyes, rather than buttons or zippers, which they consider proud and vain. There is a nice barn-raising scene, where the Amish people together erect a barn within one day for a newly married couple. We see how the tourists think about the Amish, and Book's reaction to human pests. There is the obvious clash between the modern (Book-urban) and the olden (Rachel-rural) ways. Nevertheless, as Book outwardly becomes part of the Amish community, Rachel and he begin to draw closer. The sponge bath scene is probably the most notable one in the movie. If John and Rachel decide to come together, one of them will have to give up his/her ways, for there is no middle ground. What will happen? Meanwhile three bad cops, including corrupt Chief Schaeffer (played by Josef Sommer) and McFee, track down their quarry and arrive in Amish country to do in Book. So the final scenario is the shootout between the good and the bad. What will the peaceful Amish people do? Perhaps not what you may expect! The acting is very good all-around. Harrison Ford may have given us his best performance here as a decent cop (who does not overact), although others may opt with justification for "The Fugitive" or the "Indiana Jones" series. Kelley McGillis makes a fine and dedicated Amish lady. Jan Rubes plays moral kingpin Eli Lapp, while Danny Glover is indeed chilling as a bad cop. The subtleties / expressions of the actors work so well. For instance, Lukas Haas's bewildered face when he spots McFee's photo in the police station speaks volumes. Of course, the looks of Mc Gillis and Ford during the famous sponge bath scene do not require a word of dialog. See this movie more than once.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An Interesting Look At The Amish
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gavin6942
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A young Amish boy is sole witness to a murder; policeman John Book (Harrison Ford) goes into hiding in Amish country to protect him until the trial. First of all, I have to point out that this was the first big screen role for Viggo Mortensen. Well done, sir. Although they did not know it then, you went on to be a big man in Hollywood. Great to see you here. More importantly, how to judge this film? From an entertainment point of view, it is pretty darn good. I loved Harrison Ford, and I think this is one of Peter Weir's more "fun" films. I am sure more people enjoyed this than "Picnic at Hanging Rock" (which is probably the better film, but not a fun movie by any means). And yet, is this a fair portrayal of the Amish? Is it accurate? Is it exploitation? Were they consulted on how they would be shown here? I suppose in some sense it does not matter because the strict Amish would never see the movie, but it does not do them any favors if they are presented as being something they are not...
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Witness (1985)
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ashish sood (ashistrong@gmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It is a film about adults, whose lives have dignity and whose choices matter to them. The story focuses on a detective (Harrison Ford) protecting a young Amish boy who becomes the target of a ruthless killer after he witnesses a brutal murder. Witness is as much about the meeting of cultures as about cops and robbers, this is one of those lucky movies which works out well on all counts and shows that there are still craftsmen lurking in Hollywood. The film is powerful, assured, full of beautiful imagery and devoid of easy moralising, which is good. Ford is Chicago Detective John Book, assigned to investigate a murder that was committed by crooked cop Danny Glover. The only witness is the son of an Amish widow, played by Kelly McGillis. When Book gets too close to the truth, the crooked cops try to kill him, forcing Book to take it on the lamb and hide out in the Amish country. There, he slowly makes a transition into their society, their way of life, and of course, he starts to fall for Kelly McGillis. (who would later star with pretty boy Cruise in "Top Gun"). Alexander Godunov, who later played the murderous Karl in "Die Hard", makes his debut here as an Amish farmer who is, Ford's romantic rival for Kelly. Also making his debut here is a much younger Viggo Mortensen as another Amish father. Mortensen's barely evident in the role out here,although had his eventual success as Aragorn in "Lord of the Rings" ........ After Star Wars & Indiana Jones,Ford succeeded in a serious role and his multi-layered performance earned him his only Oscar Nomination till date.Well directed Romantic Thriller by Peter Weir (Director of Dead poet's Society and Truman Show) that earned him his first Academy Award Nomination. Do watch this one for great Cinematography and Artwork My Rating - 8/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Wonderfully Poignant, Suspenseful Film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Helio Copter
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I only just recently watched this film for the first time by catching it on television. I had been aware of it in terms of the title and Harrison Ford, but had never actually read up on the plot. I am very glad that I watched it. This film is so much more than the crime/legal drama that I had imagined it to be. The directing, cinematography, screenplay and acting are all wonderfully executed. The contrast between the overt, aggressive world of police and murder investigations in the city with the subdued, understated world of the Amish, is exceptionally well portrayed. Harrison Ford does a fine job in his role. The single most beautiful performance, though, is Kelly McGillis. As other reviews have noted, she does not have an excess of spoken dialog, but her physical acting, in particular her eyes and face, is incredibly evocative and moving. If anyone should have gotten a nomination, it should have been her. Watching her play this role was a revelation to me. One also has to credit the great performance of the then-very-young Lukas Haas. His impressive turn may be as much a true key to this film's success as any other single element. The rest of the characters are well-cast themselves. I greatly admired the ending to this film. I think that it speaks to Peter Weir's directatorial sensibilities. In the hands of a lesser director, it could have been far more clich&eacute;d, but far less powerful. I was nearly thirty years late seeing WITNESS, but I think that it is a timelessly poignant example of excellent storytelling.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Never get tired of the 'barn-raising' scene
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Andreapworth
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Whenever I happen upon this movie (cable), I get sucked in, although I've seen it enough times. It's just a good story with it's own suspense. We all are rooting for little Lucas and the fact that John Book has to hide him and his mother away from the 'bad guys'. So many scenes are worth seeing again, especially when John Book gets hurt and must rely on the the Amish people to heal him - no doctors, of course. And of course, when Rachel's father wakes him up at the crack of dawn for milking. And when Radhel gives him some clothes that were her late husband's and explains that zippers and buttons are 'too proud'. And as mentioned, if you once see the barn raising scene, it will stay with you forever. Truly moving and a real example of community and what can be done by all people.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Maybe it had a point at the time...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Andrew Werling (awerling)
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Okay, so John Book is in dire straits, and so is a kid and probably his mother, but he seems to feel none of this urgency, and we watch irritating scenes of him falling in love, drinking lemonade, barn-raising, milking a cow...just not very well crafted in my opinion. And the soundtrack was cheesy. Great acting, cinematography, I'll give it that. I think the film took on too much. I just found it nearly impossible to believe his calmness in the face of one of the worst realities a cop can face: the corruption of his friends and mentors. And maybe I'm just jaded by better films on this topic which were made later: L.A. Confidential, 13 Blocks, even Copland. But I just felt antsy watching this in 2012, and I usually really dig Peter Weir films, even the cheesy ones.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Murder, Corruption & Doomed Love
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    seymourblack-1
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Witness" is a subtle, thoughtful and intelligently directed film which is both a crime thriller and an extraordinary love story. A police investigation into a brutal murder provides this drama with its momentum and drive and a tragic romantic tale adds the intensity, warmth and poignancy that elevates this movie to a higher level than that normally achieved by more routine thrillers. The story about two people from different backgrounds who fall in love, but know that their love can't transcend their circumstances, has a timeless and universal appeal which explains why this movie has retained its popularity so consistently since it was first released in 1985. When a recently widowed young Amish woman and her son are in a train station in Philadelphia, the 8-year-old boy witnesses the murder of an undercover cop. Detective Captain John Book (Harrison Ford) is put in charge of the investigation and questions Samuel Lapp (Lukas Haas), but even after showing him mug shots and arranging line-ups of suspects, the boy isn't able to finger the culprit. A little while later, however, Samuel is looking around the police office when he notices the killer's picture on a newspaper clipping that's pinned up inside a glass cabinet. When he brings this to Book's attention, it's quite a shock because the man in the photograph is the highly decorated Detective Lieutenant McFee (Danny Glover) of the Narcotics Division. Detective Book tells his superior officer Detective Chief Schaeffer (Josef Sommer) about this development and Schaeffer asks him to keep the information confidential. Shortly after, when he's shot at and injured by McFee, it becomes obvious to Book that McFee and Schaeffer are both corrupt and Samuel and his mother Rachel (Kelly McGillis) are in mortal danger. In order to protect them, Book drives them back to their Amish community but after his arrival there, he collapses and has to remain with the Amish where Rachel gradually nurses him back to health. During Book's period of recuperation, he and Rachel fall in love but he soon realises that neither of them could survive indefinitely in the other's world. Book adapts well to living with the Amish and earns their respect as he readily helps with milking cows and building a barn, but his presence in their community places them in danger, as becomes all too clear when the story reaches its action-packed conclusion. Non-verbal communication is used frequently in this movie and provides the action with an extremely natural feel. A couple of the stand-out sequences are those in which Samuel looks at Book in a way that immediately signifies that he's seen something important (when he sees McFee's photograph) and another is when Book and Rachel dance together in a barn to Sam Cooke's "What A Wonderful World". The power to convey their thoughts and feelings so clearly in this way is very touching at times and also testifies strongly to the quality of the acting. The differences between the worlds that Book and Rachel inhabit couldn't be greater as the Amish reside in rural surroundings and live a quiet, non-violent existence in which it's normal for everyone to help everyone else. These people embrace old fashioned values and don't use modern conveniences such as cars and refrigerators etc. By contrast, Book's existence as a city cop is far less serene and regularly brings him into contact with violence, corruption and various other forms of errant human behaviour. "Witness", with its interesting characters, its absorbing story of murder, corruption and doomed love and its marvellous acting performances, is tremendously enjoyable to watch and leaves a lasting impression.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "One Of Ford's Best!"
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gwnightscream
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/9/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Harrison Ford, Kelly McGillis, Lucas Haas, Jan Rubes, Danny Glover, Josef Sommer, Patti LuPone, and Alexander Godunov star in this 1985 thriller. This film begins in Pennsylvania in a small Amish town where a widow, Rachel Lapp (McGillis) attends her late husband's funeral with her family and friends. Soon, Rachel and her young son, Samuel (Haas) head to Baltimore to visit her sister until Samuel witnesses a cop's murder in Philadelphia. Ford plays John Book, a cop who investigates the case and tries to protect Rachel and Samuel. When he's almost killed by crooked cops, John takes Rachel and Samuel home, but hides there with them learning their Amish ways. Rubes plays Rachel's father-in-law, Eli, Glover plays cop, McFee, Sommer plays John's mentor, Schaeffer, LuPone plays John's sister, Elaine and Godunov (Die Hard) plays Daniel, an Amish friend of Rachel's family. This is one of Ford's best and he and McGillis are great together. Maurice Jarre's score is also excellent and I recommend this.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A classic thriller with a great setting
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Jellybeansucker
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Great thriller story and setting. Not sure if the child witness angle was new but certainly his background was, the Amish community, and that's the main pleasure of this movie. The film's pace slows down but the interest and drama is heightened when Book is holed up at the farm. That's well worked by the writers and the love interest is nicely done, and there is real chemistry between Ford and McGillis, what a match! For the ending, the natural thriller pace comes back, it's intense too because we know Book is a good guy who's protective of his hosts. They could have overdone this with a DePalma style OTT shoot out, but this was just right for the movie. The only flaw is a pretty incredible decision by Book just to go into hiding at the Amish farm, putting them all at risk. In reality he'd be shopping his bent police chief to the FBI, the press and anyone else who'd listen and seeking witness protection for the boy. A major flaw, but the creators wanted to finish the movie at the Amish community as well, which is understandable. Overall a real breath of fresh air for the thriller genre, a well rounded movie with something for everyone, an original setting and a fantastic lead link up with Ford at his best and an almost unknown McGillis proving sex appeal doesn't need glamour at all! One of my favourites, a little gem of a thriller.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Genuine Thriller with a Heart!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    g-bodyl
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Witness is a very good thriller with great moments of characterization and that is what sets it apart from other thrillers. Also, you really cannot classify this as thriller for the entire film because the middle portion is a haunting study on a group of peaceful people living away from technology. Harrison Ford gets out of his action movies to have one of the best roles of his career playing John Book. Peter Weir's film is about a hard-nosed detective named John Book who investigates a murder that a small Amish boy witnessed. Thanks to some betrayal, John is forced to live with the Amish and away from being a cop, he forbiddenly falls in love with Rachel, a beautiful Amish woman. As mentioned before, Harrison gives one of his better roles and is full of heartfelt emotion. Kelly McGillis, in her second ever movie, rises to great heights with her shy performance. I also find it ironic how Danny Glover plays a villain who murders cops right before his famed Lethal Weapon series. Overall, Witness is a beautifully shot film that has some intense scenes especially in the beginning and the end. We get to meet a group of people that stay away from society. The music by Maurice Jarre is wonderful and fits well with the themes of the movie. I find it funny how an award-winning thriller like this was released in February. I rate this film 9/10.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "You be careful out among the English."
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    romanorum1
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    After her husband's premature death, a young Amish woman, Rachel Lapp (Kelley McGillis), takes her son Samuel (Lukas Haas) on a train trip to Baltimore. While in the men's washroom at the Philadelphia station, young Samuel witnesses a brutal murder. By his own wits he saves himself from the scary murderer McFee (Danny Glover). Detective John Book (Harrison Ford), summoned to the murder scene, perceives that the dead man is an undercover cop. He questions Rachel and Samuel. From a photograph, Samuel fingers McFee, among others a corrupt cop. McFee had stolen large quantities of a chemical substance used in the manufacture of methamphetamine. The bad guys try to set up Book for a hit, but fail (although he is wounded by McFee). Now searched by the bad guys, Book goes into hiding in Pennsylvania German (Amish) country (Lancaster County, PA) to blend in with the religious sect. The middle part of the movie, and by far the greater segment overall, is the focus on the Amish community. This section is almost a documentary. We learn that the Amish shun the new ways, and live much as they did in the eighteenth century. Unlike the nearby Mennonites, the Amish reject automobiles, electricity, and telephones. Gas lamps are used. The Amish ride in traditional horse and buggy units while heavy traffic passes them by (when they can). They wear plain clothes and use hooks and eyes, rather than buttons or zippers, which they consider proud and vain. There is a nice barn-raising scene, where the Amish people together erect a barn within one day for a newly married couple. We see how the tourists think about the Amish, and Book's reaction to human pests. There is the obvious clash between the modern (Book-urban) and the olden (Rachel-rural) ways. Nevertheless, as Book outwardly becomes part of the Amish community, Rachel and he begin to draw closer. The sponge bath scene is probably the most notable one in the movie. If John and Rachel decide to come together, one of them will have to give up his/her ways, for there is no middle ground. What will happen? Meanwhile three bad cops, including corrupt Chief Schaeffer (played by Josef Sommer) and McFee, track down their quarry and arrive in Amish country to do in Book. So the final scenario is the shootout between the good and the bad. What will the peaceful Amish people do? Perhaps not what you may expect! The acting is very good all-around. Harrison Ford may have given us his best performance here as a decent cop (who does not overact), although others may opt with justification for "The Fugitive" or the "Indiana Jones" series. Kelley McGillis makes a fine and dedicated Amish lady. Jan Rubes plays moral kingpin Eli Lapp, while Danny Glover is indeed chilling as a bad cop. The subtleties / expressions of the actors work so well. For instance, Lukas Haas's bewildered face when he spots McFee's photo in the police station speaks volumes. Of course, the looks of Mc Gillis and Ford during the famous sponge bath scene do not require a word of dialog. See this movie more than once.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An Interesting Look At The Amish
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gavin6942
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A young Amish boy is sole witness to a murder; policeman John Book (Harrison Ford) goes into hiding in Amish country to protect him until the trial. First of all, I have to point out that this was the first big screen role for Viggo Mortensen. Well done, sir. Although they did not know it then, you went on to be a big man in Hollywood. Great to see you here. More importantly, how to judge this film? From an entertainment point of view, it is pretty darn good. I loved Harrison Ford, and I think this is one of Peter Weir's more "fun" films. I am sure more people enjoyed this than "Picnic at Hanging Rock" (which is probably the better film, but not a fun movie by any means). And yet, is this a fair portrayal of the Amish? Is it accurate? Is it exploitation? Were they consulted on how they would be shown here? I suppose in some sense it does not matter because the strict Amish would never see the movie, but it does not do them any favors if they are presented as being something they are not...
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Witness (1985)
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ashish sood (ashistrong@gmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It is a film about adults, whose lives have dignity and whose choices matter to them. The story focuses on a detective (Harrison Ford) protecting a young Amish boy who becomes the target of a ruthless killer after he witnesses a brutal murder. Witness is as much about the meeting of cultures as about cops and robbers, this is one of those lucky movies which works out well on all counts and shows that there are still craftsmen lurking in Hollywood. The film is powerful, assured, full of beautiful imagery and devoid of easy moralising, which is good. Ford is Chicago Detective John Book, assigned to investigate a murder that was committed by crooked cop Danny Glover. The only witness is the son of an Amish widow, played by Kelly McGillis. When Book gets too close to the truth, the crooked cops try to kill him, forcing Book to take it on the lamb and hide out in the Amish country. There, he slowly makes a transition into their society, their way of life, and of course, he starts to fall for Kelly McGillis. (who would later star with pretty boy Cruise in "Top Gun"). Alexander Godunov, who later played the murderous Karl in "Die Hard", makes his debut here as an Amish farmer who is, Ford's romantic rival for Kelly. Also making his debut here is a much younger Viggo Mortensen as another Amish father. Mortensen's barely evident in the role out here,although had his eventual success as Aragorn in "Lord of the Rings" ........ After Star Wars & Indiana Jones,Ford succeeded in a serious role and his multi-layered performance earned him his only Oscar Nomination till date.Well directed Romantic Thriller by Peter Weir (Director of Dead poet's Society and Truman Show) that earned him his first Academy Award Nomination. Do watch this one for great Cinematography and Artwork My Rating - 8/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Wonderfully Poignant, Suspenseful Film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Helio Copter
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I only just recently watched this film for the first time by catching it on television. I had been aware of it in terms of the title and Harrison Ford, but had never actually read up on the plot. I am very glad that I watched it. This film is so much more than the crime/legal drama that I had imagined it to be. The directing, cinematography, screenplay and acting are all wonderfully executed. The contrast between the overt, aggressive world of police and murder investigations in the city with the subdued, understated world of the Amish, is exceptionally well portrayed. Harrison Ford does a fine job in his role. The single most beautiful performance, though, is Kelly McGillis. As other reviews have noted, she does not have an excess of spoken dialog, but her physical acting, in particular her eyes and face, is incredibly evocative and moving. If anyone should have gotten a nomination, it should have been her. Watching her play this role was a revelation to me. One also has to credit the great performance of the then-very-young Lukas Haas. His impressive turn may be as much a true key to this film's success as any other single element. The rest of the characters are well-cast themselves. I greatly admired the ending to this film. I think that it speaks to Peter Weir's directatorial sensibilities. In the hands of a lesser director, it could have been far more clich&eacute;d, but far less powerful. I was nearly thirty years late seeing WITNESS, but I think that it is a timelessly poignant example of excellent storytelling.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Never get tired of the 'barn-raising' scene
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Andreapworth
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Whenever I happen upon this movie (cable), I get sucked in, although I've seen it enough times. It's just a good story with it's own suspense. We all are rooting for little Lucas and the fact that John Book has to hide him and his mother away from the 'bad guys'. So many scenes are worth seeing again, especially when John Book gets hurt and must rely on the the Amish people to heal him - no doctors, of course. And of course, when Rachel's father wakes him up at the crack of dawn for milking. And when Radhel gives him some clothes that were her late husband's and explains that zippers and buttons are 'too proud'. And as mentioned, if you once see the barn raising scene, it will stay with you forever. Truly moving and a real example of community and what can be done by all people.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Maybe it had a point at the time...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Andrew Werling (awerling)
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Okay, so John Book is in dire straits, and so is a kid and probably his mother, but he seems to feel none of this urgency, and we watch irritating scenes of him falling in love, drinking lemonade, barn-raising, milking a cow...just not very well crafted in my opinion. And the soundtrack was cheesy. Great acting, cinematography, I'll give it that. I think the film took on too much. I just found it nearly impossible to believe his calmness in the face of one of the worst realities a cop can face: the corruption of his friends and mentors. And maybe I'm just jaded by better films on this topic which were made later: L.A. Confidential, 13 Blocks, even Copland. But I just felt antsy watching this in 2012, and I usually really dig Peter Weir films, even the cheesy ones.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Murder, Corruption & Doomed Love
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    seymourblack-1
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Witness" is a subtle, thoughtful and intelligently directed film which is both a crime thriller and an extraordinary love story. A police investigation into a brutal murder provides this drama with its momentum and drive and a tragic romantic tale adds the intensity, warmth and poignancy that elevates this movie to a higher level than that normally achieved by more routine thrillers. The story about two people from different backgrounds who fall in love, but know that their love can't transcend their circumstances, has a timeless and universal appeal which explains why this movie has retained its popularity so consistently since it was first released in 1985. When a recently widowed young Amish woman and her son are in a train station in Philadelphia, the 8-year-old boy witnesses the murder of an undercover cop. Detective Captain John Book (Harrison Ford) is put in charge of the investigation and questions Samuel Lapp (Lukas Haas), but even after showing him mug shots and arranging line-ups of suspects, the boy isn't able to finger the culprit. A little while later, however, Samuel is looking around the police office when he notices the killer's picture on a newspaper clipping that's pinned up inside a glass cabinet. When he brings this to Book's attention, it's quite a shock because the man in the photograph is the highly decorated Detective Lieutenant McFee (Danny Glover) of the Narcotics Division. Detective Book tells his superior officer Detective Chief Schaeffer (Josef Sommer) about this development and Schaeffer asks him to keep the information confidential. Shortly after, when he's shot at and injured by McFee, it becomes obvious to Book that McFee and Schaeffer are both corrupt and Samuel and his mother Rachel (Kelly McGillis) are in mortal danger. In order to protect them, Book drives them back to their Amish community but after his arrival there, he collapses and has to remain with the Amish where Rachel gradually nurses him back to health. During Book's period of recuperation, he and Rachel fall in love but he soon realises that neither of them could survive indefinitely in the other's world. Book adapts well to living with the Amish and earns their respect as he readily helps with milking cows and building a barn, but his presence in their community places them in danger, as becomes all too clear when the story reaches its action-packed conclusion. Non-verbal communication is used frequently in this movie and provides the action with an extremely natural feel. A couple of the stand-out sequences are those in which Samuel looks at Book in a way that immediately signifies that he's seen something important (when he sees McFee's photograph) and another is when Book and Rachel dance together in a barn to Sam Cooke's "What A Wonderful World". The power to convey their thoughts and feelings so clearly in this way is very touching at times and also testifies strongly to the quality of the acting. The differences between the worlds that Book and Rachel inhabit couldn't be greater as the Amish reside in rural surroundings and live a quiet, non-violent existence in which it's normal for everyone to help everyone else. These people embrace old fashioned values and don't use modern conveniences such as cars and refrigerators etc. By contrast, Book's existence as a city cop is far less serene and regularly brings him into contact with violence, corruption and various other forms of errant human behaviour. "Witness", with its interesting characters, its absorbing story of murder, corruption and doomed love and its marvellous acting performances, is tremendously enjoyable to watch and leaves a lasting impression.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "One Of Ford's Best!"
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gwnightscream
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/9/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Harrison Ford, Kelly McGillis, Lucas Haas, Jan Rubes, Danny Glover, Josef Sommer, Patti LuPone, and Alexander Godunov star in this 1985 thriller. This film begins in Pennsylvania in a small Amish town where a widow, Rachel Lapp (McGillis) attends her late husband's funeral with her family and friends. Soon, Rachel and her young son, Samuel (Haas) head to Baltimore to visit her sister until Samuel witnesses a cop's murder in Philadelphia. Ford plays John Book, a cop who investigates the case and tries to protect Rachel and Samuel. When he's almost killed by crooked cops, John takes Rachel and Samuel home, but hides there with them learning their Amish ways. Rubes plays Rachel's father-in-law, Eli, Glover plays cop, McFee, Sommer plays John's mentor, Schaeffer, LuPone plays John's sister, Elaine and Godunov (Die Hard) plays Daniel, an Amish friend of Rachel's family. This is one of Ford's best and he and McGillis are great together. Maurice Jarre's score is also excellent and I recommend this.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A classic thriller with a great setting
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Jellybeansucker
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Great thriller story and setting. Not sure if the child witness angle was new but certainly his background was, the Amish community, and that's the main pleasure of this movie. The film's pace slows down but the interest and drama is heightened when Book is holed up at the farm. That's well worked by the writers and the love interest is nicely done, and there is real chemistry between Ford and McGillis, what a match! For the ending, the natural thriller pace comes back, it's intense too because we know Book is a good guy who's protective of his hosts. They could have overdone this with a DePalma style OTT shoot out, but this was just right for the movie. The only flaw is a pretty incredible decision by Book just to go into hiding at the Amish farm, putting them all at risk. In reality he'd be shopping his bent police chief to the FBI, the press and anyone else who'd listen and seeking witness protection for the boy. A major flaw, but the creators wanted to finish the movie at the Amish community as well, which is understandable. Overall a real breath of fresh air for the thriller genre, a well rounded movie with something for everyone, an original setting and a fantastic lead link up with Ford at his best and an almost unknown McGillis proving sex appeal doesn't need glamour at all! One of my favourites, a little gem of a thriller.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Genuine Thriller with a Heart!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    g-bodyl
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Witness is a very good thriller with great moments of characterization and that is what sets it apart from other thrillers. Also, you really cannot classify this as thriller for the entire film because the middle portion is a haunting study on a group of peaceful people living away from technology. Harrison Ford gets out of his action movies to have one of the best roles of his career playing John Book. Peter Weir's film is about a hard-nosed detective named John Book who investigates a murder that a small Amish boy witnessed. Thanks to some betrayal, John is forced to live with the Amish and away from being a cop, he forbiddenly falls in love with Rachel, a beautiful Amish woman. As mentioned before, Harrison gives one of his better roles and is full of heartfelt emotion. Kelly McGillis, in her second ever movie, rises to great heights with her shy performance. I also find it ironic how Danny Glover plays a villain who murders cops right before his famed Lethal Weapon series. Overall, Witness is a beautifully shot film that has some intense scenes especially in the beginning and the end. We get to meet a group of people that stay away from society. The music by Maurice Jarre is wonderful and fits well with the themes of the movie. I find it funny how an award-winning thriller like this was released in February. I rate this film 9/10.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "You be careful out among the English."
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    romanorum1
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    After her husband's premature death, a young Amish woman, Rachel Lapp (Kelley McGillis), takes her son Samuel (Lukas Haas) on a train trip to Baltimore. While in the men's washroom at the Philadelphia station, young Samuel witnesses a brutal murder. By his own wits he saves himself from the scary murderer McFee (Danny Glover). Detective John Book (Harrison Ford), summoned to the murder scene, perceives that the dead man is an undercover cop. He questions Rachel and Samuel. From a photograph, Samuel fingers McFee, among others a corrupt cop. McFee had stolen large quantities of a chemical substance used in the manufacture of methamphetamine. The bad guys try to set up Book for a hit, but fail (although he is wounded by McFee). Now searched by the bad guys, Book goes into hiding in Pennsylvania German (Amish) country (Lancaster County, PA) to blend in with the religious sect. The middle part of the movie, and by far the greater segment overall, is the focus on the Amish community. This section is almost a documentary. We learn that the Amish shun the new ways, and live much as they did in the eighteenth century. Unlike the nearby Mennonites, the Amish reject automobiles, electricity, and telephones. Gas lamps are used. The Amish ride in traditional horse and buggy units while heavy traffic passes them by (when they can). They wear plain clothes and use hooks and eyes, rather than buttons or zippers, which they consider proud and vain. There is a nice barn-raising scene, where the Amish people together erect a barn within one day for a newly married couple. We see how the tourists think about the Amish, and Book's reaction to human pests. There is the obvious clash between the modern (Book-urban) and the olden (Rachel-rural) ways. Nevertheless, as Book outwardly becomes part of the Amish community, Rachel and he begin to draw closer. The sponge bath scene is probably the most notable one in the movie. If John and Rachel decide to come together, one of them will have to give up his/her ways, for there is no middle ground. What will happen? Meanwhile three bad cops, including corrupt Chief Schaeffer (played by Josef Sommer) and McFee, track down their quarry and arrive in Amish country to do in Book. So the final scenario is the shootout between the good and the bad. What will the peaceful Amish people do? Perhaps not what you may expect! The acting is very good all-around. Harrison Ford may have given us his best performance here as a decent cop (who does not overact), although others may opt with justification for "The Fugitive" or the "Indiana Jones" series. Kelley McGillis makes a fine and dedicated Amish lady. Jan Rubes plays moral kingpin Eli Lapp, while Danny Glover is indeed chilling as a bad cop. The subtleties / expressions of the actors work so well. For instance, Lukas Haas's bewildered face when he spots McFee's photo in the police station speaks volumes. Of course, the looks of Mc Gillis and Ford during the famous sponge bath scene do not require a word of dialog. See this movie more than once.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An Interesting Look At The Amish
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gavin6942
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A young Amish boy is sole witness to a murder; policeman John Book (Harrison Ford) goes into hiding in Amish country to protect him until the trial. First of all, I have to point out that this was the first big screen role for Viggo Mortensen. Well done, sir. Although they did not know it then, you went on to be a big man in Hollywood. Great to see you here. More importantly, how to judge this film? From an entertainment point of view, it is pretty darn good. I loved Harrison Ford, and I think this is one of Peter Weir's more "fun" films. I am sure more people enjoyed this than "Picnic at Hanging Rock" (which is probably the better film, but not a fun movie by any means). And yet, is this a fair portrayal of the Amish? Is it accurate? Is it exploitation? Were they consulted on how they would be shown here? I suppose in some sense it does not matter because the strict Amish would never see the movie, but it does not do them any favors if they are presented as being something they are not...
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Witness (1985)
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ashish sood (ashistrong@gmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It is a film about adults, whose lives have dignity and whose choices matter to them. The story focuses on a detective (Harrison Ford) protecting a young Amish boy who becomes the target of a ruthless killer after he witnesses a brutal murder. Witness is as much about the meeting of cultures as about cops and robbers, this is one of those lucky movies which works out well on all counts and shows that there are still craftsmen lurking in Hollywood. The film is powerful, assured, full of beautiful imagery and devoid of easy moralising, which is good. Ford is Chicago Detective John Book, assigned to investigate a murder that was committed by crooked cop Danny Glover. The only witness is the son of an Amish widow, played by Kelly McGillis. When Book gets too close to the truth, the crooked cops try to kill him, forcing Book to take it on the lamb and hide out in the Amish country. There, he slowly makes a transition into their society, their way of life, and of course, he starts to fall for Kelly McGillis. (who would later star with pretty boy Cruise in "Top Gun"). Alexander Godunov, who later played the murderous Karl in "Die Hard", makes his debut here as an Amish farmer who is, Ford's romantic rival for Kelly. Also making his debut here is a much younger Viggo Mortensen as another Amish father. Mortensen's barely evident in the role out here,although had his eventual success as Aragorn in "Lord of the Rings" ........ After Star Wars & Indiana Jones,Ford succeeded in a serious role and his multi-layered performance earned him his only Oscar Nomination till date.Well directed Romantic Thriller by Peter Weir (Director of Dead poet's Society and Truman Show) that earned him his first Academy Award Nomination. Do watch this one for great Cinematography and Artwork My Rating - 8/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Wonderfully Poignant, Suspenseful Film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Helio Copter
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I only just recently watched this film for the first time by catching it on television. I had been aware of it in terms of the title and Harrison Ford, but had never actually read up on the plot. I am very glad that I watched it. This film is so much more than the crime/legal drama that I had imagined it to be. The directing, cinematography, screenplay and acting are all wonderfully executed. The contrast between the overt, aggressive world of police and murder investigations in the city with the subdued, understated world of the Amish, is exceptionally well portrayed. Harrison Ford does a fine job in his role. The single most beautiful performance, though, is Kelly McGillis. As other reviews have noted, she does not have an excess of spoken dialog, but her physical acting, in particular her eyes and face, is incredibly evocative and moving. If anyone should have gotten a nomination, it should have been her. Watching her play this role was a revelation to me. One also has to credit the great performance of the then-very-young Lukas Haas. His impressive turn may be as much a true key to this film's success as any other single element. The rest of the characters are well-cast themselves. I greatly admired the ending to this film. I think that it speaks to Peter Weir's directatorial sensibilities. In the hands of a lesser director, it could have been far more clich&eacute;d, but far less powerful. I was nearly thirty years late seeing WITNESS, but I think that it is a timelessly poignant example of excellent storytelling.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Never get tired of the 'barn-raising' scene
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Andreapworth
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Whenever I happen upon this movie (cable), I get sucked in, although I've seen it enough times. It's just a good story with it's own suspense. We all are rooting for little Lucas and the fact that John Book has to hide him and his mother away from the 'bad guys'. So many scenes are worth seeing again, especially when John Book gets hurt and must rely on the the Amish people to heal him - no doctors, of course. And of course, when Rachel's father wakes him up at the crack of dawn for milking. And when Radhel gives him some clothes that were her late husband's and explains that zippers and buttons are 'too proud'. And as mentioned, if you once see the barn raising scene, it will stay with you forever. Truly moving and a real example of community and what can be done by all people.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Maybe it had a point at the time...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Andrew Werling (awerling)
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Okay, so John Book is in dire straits, and so is a kid and probably his mother, but he seems to feel none of this urgency, and we watch irritating scenes of him falling in love, drinking lemonade, barn-raising, milking a cow...just not very well crafted in my opinion. And the soundtrack was cheesy. Great acting, cinematography, I'll give it that. I think the film took on too much. I just found it nearly impossible to believe his calmness in the face of one of the worst realities a cop can face: the corruption of his friends and mentors. And maybe I'm just jaded by better films on this topic which were made later: L.A. Confidential, 13 Blocks, even Copland. But I just felt antsy watching this in 2012, and I usually really dig Peter Weir films, even the cheesy ones.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Murder, Corruption & Doomed Love
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    seymourblack-1
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Witness" is a subtle, thoughtful and intelligently directed film which is both a crime thriller and an extraordinary love story. A police investigation into a brutal murder provides this drama with its momentum and drive and a tragic romantic tale adds the intensity, warmth and poignancy that elevates this movie to a higher level than that normally achieved by more routine thrillers. The story about two people from different backgrounds who fall in love, but know that their love can't transcend their circumstances, has a timeless and universal appeal which explains why this movie has retained its popularity so consistently since it was first released in 1985. When a recently widowed young Amish woman and her son are in a train station in Philadelphia, the 8-year-old boy witnesses the murder of an undercover cop. Detective Captain John Book (Harrison Ford) is put in charge of the investigation and questions Samuel Lapp (Lukas Haas), but even after showing him mug shots and arranging line-ups of suspects, the boy isn't able to finger the culprit. A little while later, however, Samuel is looking around the police office when he notices the killer's picture on a newspaper clipping that's pinned up inside a glass cabinet. When he brings this to Book's attention, it's quite a shock because the man in the photograph is the highly decorated Detective Lieutenant McFee (Danny Glover) of the Narcotics Division. Detective Book tells his superior officer Detective Chief Schaeffer (Josef Sommer) about this development and Schaeffer asks him to keep the information confidential. Shortly after, when he's shot at and injured by McFee, it becomes obvious to Book that McFee and Schaeffer are both corrupt and Samuel and his mother Rachel (Kelly McGillis) are in mortal danger. In order to protect them, Book drives them back to their Amish community but after his arrival there, he collapses and has to remain with the Amish where Rachel gradually nurses him back to health. During Book's period of recuperation, he and Rachel fall in love but he soon realises that neither of them could survive indefinitely in the other's world. Book adapts well to living with the Amish and earns their respect as he readily helps with milking cows and building a barn, but his presence in their community places them in danger, as becomes all too clear when the story reaches its action-packed conclusion. Non-verbal communication is used frequently in this movie and provides the action with an extremely natural feel. A couple of the stand-out sequences are those in which Samuel looks at Book in a way that immediately signifies that he's seen something important (when he sees McFee's photograph) and another is when Book and Rachel dance together in a barn to Sam Cooke's "What A Wonderful World". The power to convey their thoughts and feelings so clearly in this way is very touching at times and also testifies strongly to the quality of the acting. The differences between the worlds that Book and Rachel inhabit couldn't be greater as the Amish reside in rural surroundings and live a quiet, non-violent existence in which it's normal for everyone to help everyone else. These people embrace old fashioned values and don't use modern conveniences such as cars and refrigerators etc. By contrast, Book's existence as a city cop is far less serene and regularly brings him into contact with violence, corruption and various other forms of errant human behaviour. "Witness", with its interesting characters, its absorbing story of murder, corruption and doomed love and its marvellous acting performances, is tremendously enjoyable to watch and leaves a lasting impression.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "One Of Ford's Best!"
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gwnightscream
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/9/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Harrison Ford, Kelly McGillis, Lucas Haas, Jan Rubes, Danny Glover, Josef Sommer, Patti LuPone, and Alexander Godunov star in this 1985 thriller. This film begins in Pennsylvania in a small Amish town where a widow, Rachel Lapp (McGillis) attends her late husband's funeral with her family and friends. Soon, Rachel and her young son, Samuel (Haas) head to Baltimore to visit her sister until Samuel witnesses a cop's murder in Philadelphia. Ford plays John Book, a cop who investigates the case and tries to protect Rachel and Samuel. When he's almost killed by crooked cops, John takes Rachel and Samuel home, but hides there with them learning their Amish ways. Rubes plays Rachel's father-in-law, Eli, Glover plays cop, McFee, Sommer plays John's mentor, Schaeffer, LuPone plays John's sister, Elaine and Godunov (Die Hard) plays Daniel, an Amish friend of Rachel's family. This is one of Ford's best and he and McGillis are great together. Maurice Jarre's score is also excellent and I recommend this.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A classic thriller with a great setting
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Jellybeansucker
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Great thriller story and setting. Not sure if the child witness angle was new but certainly his background was, the Amish community, and that's the main pleasure of this movie. The film's pace slows down but the interest and drama is heightened when Book is holed up at the farm. That's well worked by the writers and the love interest is nicely done, and there is real chemistry between Ford and McGillis, what a match! For the ending, the natural thriller pace comes back, it's intense too because we know Book is a good guy who's protective of his hosts. They could have overdone this with a DePalma style OTT shoot out, but this was just right for the movie. The only flaw is a pretty incredible decision by Book just to go into hiding at the Amish farm, putting them all at risk. In reality he'd be shopping his bent police chief to the FBI, the press and anyone else who'd listen and seeking witness protection for the boy. A major flaw, but the creators wanted to finish the movie at the Amish community as well, which is understandable. Overall a real breath of fresh air for the thriller genre, a well rounded movie with something for everyone, an original setting and a fantastic lead link up with Ford at his best and an almost unknown McGillis proving sex appeal doesn't need glamour at all! One of my favourites, a little gem of a thriller.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Genuine Thriller with a Heart!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    g-bodyl
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Witness is a very good thriller with great moments of characterization and that is what sets it apart from other thrillers. Also, you really cannot classify this as thriller for the entire film because the middle portion is a haunting study on a group of peaceful people living away from technology. Harrison Ford gets out of his action movies to have one of the best roles of his career playing John Book. Peter Weir's film is about a hard-nosed detective named John Book who investigates a murder that a small Amish boy witnessed. Thanks to some betrayal, John is forced to live with the Amish and away from being a cop, he forbiddenly falls in love with Rachel, a beautiful Amish woman. As mentioned before, Harrison gives one of his better roles and is full of heartfelt emotion. Kelly McGillis, in her second ever movie, rises to great heights with her shy performance. I also find it ironic how Danny Glover plays a villain who murders cops right before his famed Lethal Weapon series. Overall, Witness is a beautifully shot film that has some intense scenes especially in the beginning and the end. We get to meet a group of people that stay away from society. The music by Maurice Jarre is wonderful and fits well with the themes of the movie. I find it funny how an award-winning thriller like this was released in February. I rate this film 9/10.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "You be careful out among the English."
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    romanorum1
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    After her husband's premature death, a young Amish woman, Rachel Lapp (Kelley McGillis), takes her son Samuel (Lukas Haas) on a train trip to Baltimore. While in the men's washroom at the Philadelphia station, young Samuel witnesses a brutal murder. By his own wits he saves himself from the scary murderer McFee (Danny Glover). Detective John Book (Harrison Ford), summoned to the murder scene, perceives that the dead man is an undercover cop. He questions Rachel and Samuel. From a photograph, Samuel fingers McFee, among others a corrupt cop. McFee had stolen large quantities of a chemical substance used in the manufacture of methamphetamine. The bad guys try to set up Book for a hit, but fail (although he is wounded by McFee). Now searched by the bad guys, Book goes into hiding in Pennsylvania German (Amish) country (Lancaster County, PA) to blend in with the religious sect. The middle part of the movie, and by far the greater segment overall, is the focus on the Amish community. This section is almost a documentary. We learn that the Amish shun the new ways, and live much as they did in the eighteenth century. Unlike the nearby Mennonites, the Amish reject automobiles, electricity, and telephones. Gas lamps are used. The Amish ride in traditional horse and buggy units while heavy traffic passes them by (when they can). They wear plain clothes and use hooks and eyes, rather than buttons or zippers, which they consider proud and vain. There is a nice barn-raising scene, where the Amish people together erect a barn within one day for a newly married couple. We see how the tourists think about the Amish, and Book's reaction to human pests. There is the obvious clash between the modern (Book-urban) and the olden (Rachel-rural) ways. Nevertheless, as Book outwardly becomes part of the Amish community, Rachel and he begin to draw closer. The sponge bath scene is probably the most notable one in the movie. If John and Rachel decide to come together, one of them will have to give up his/her ways, for there is no middle ground. What will happen? Meanwhile three bad cops, including corrupt Chief Schaeffer (played by Josef Sommer) and McFee, track down their quarry and arrive in Amish country to do in Book. So the final scenario is the shootout between the good and the bad. What will the peaceful Amish people do? Perhaps not what you may expect! The acting is very good all-around. Harrison Ford may have given us his best performance here as a decent cop (who does not overact), although others may opt with justification for "The Fugitive" or the "Indiana Jones" series. Kelley McGillis makes a fine and dedicated Amish lady. Jan Rubes plays moral kingpin Eli Lapp, while Danny Glover is indeed chilling as a bad cop. The subtleties / expressions of the actors work so well. For instance, Lukas Haas's bewildered face when he spots McFee's photo in the police station speaks volumes. Of course, the looks of Mc Gillis and Ford during the famous sponge bath scene do not require a word of dialog. See this movie more than once.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An Interesting Look At The Amish
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gavin6942
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A young Amish boy is sole witness to a murder; policeman John Book (Harrison Ford) goes into hiding in Amish country to protect him until the trial. First of all, I have to point out that this was the first big screen role for Viggo Mortensen. Well done, sir. Although they did not know it then, you went on to be a big man in Hollywood. Great to see you here. More importantly, how to judge this film? From an entertainment point of view, it is pretty darn good. I loved Harrison Ford, and I think this is one of Peter Weir's more "fun" films. I am sure more people enjoyed this than "Picnic at Hanging Rock" (which is probably the better film, but not a fun movie by any means). And yet, is this a fair portrayal of the Amish? Is it accurate? Is it exploitation? Were they consulted on how they would be shown here? I suppose in some sense it does not matter because the strict Amish would never see the movie, but it does not do them any favors if they are presented as being something they are not...
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Witness (1985)
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ashish sood (ashistrong@gmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It is a film about adults, whose lives have dignity and whose choices matter to them. The story focuses on a detective (Harrison Ford) protecting a young Amish boy who becomes the target of a ruthless killer after he witnesses a brutal murder. Witness is as much about the meeting of cultures as about cops and robbers, this is one of those lucky movies which works out well on all counts and shows that there are still craftsmen lurking in Hollywood. The film is powerful, assured, full of beautiful imagery and devoid of easy moralising, which is good. Ford is Chicago Detective John Book, assigned to investigate a murder that was committed by crooked cop Danny Glover. The only witness is the son of an Amish widow, played by Kelly McGillis. When Book gets too close to the truth, the crooked cops try to kill him, forcing Book to take it on the lamb and hide out in the Amish country. There, he slowly makes a transition into their society, their way of life, and of course, he starts to fall for Kelly McGillis. (who would later star with pretty boy Cruise in "Top Gun"). Alexander Godunov, who later played the murderous Karl in "Die Hard", makes his debut here as an Amish farmer who is, Ford's romantic rival for Kelly. Also making his debut here is a much younger Viggo Mortensen as another Amish father. Mortensen's barely evident in the role out here,although had his eventual success as Aragorn in "Lord of the Rings" ........ After Star Wars & Indiana Jones,Ford succeeded in a serious role and his multi-layered performance earned him his only Oscar Nomination till date.Well directed Romantic Thriller by Peter Weir (Director of Dead poet's Society and Truman Show) that earned him his first Academy Award Nomination. Do watch this one for great Cinematography and Artwork My Rating - 8/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Wonderfully Poignant, Suspenseful Film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Helio Copter
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I only just recently watched this film for the first time by catching it on television. I had been aware of it in terms of the title and Harrison Ford, but had never actually read up on the plot. I am very glad that I watched it. This film is so much more than the crime/legal drama that I had imagined it to be. The directing, cinematography, screenplay and acting are all wonderfully executed. The contrast between the overt, aggressive world of police and murder investigations in the city with the subdued, understated world of the Amish, is exceptionally well portrayed. Harrison Ford does a fine job in his role. The single most beautiful performance, though, is Kelly McGillis. As other reviews have noted, she does not have an excess of spoken dialog, but her physical acting, in particular her eyes and face, is incredibly evocative and moving. If anyone should have gotten a nomination, it should have been her. Watching her play this role was a revelation to me. One also has to credit the great performance of the then-very-young Lukas Haas. His impressive turn may be as much a true key to this film's success as any other single element. The rest of the characters are well-cast themselves. I greatly admired the ending to this film. I think that it speaks to Peter Weir's directatorial sensibilities. In the hands of a lesser director, it could have been far more clich&eacute;d, but far less powerful. I was nearly thirty years late seeing WITNESS, but I think that it is a timelessly poignant example of excellent storytelling.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Never get tired of the 'barn-raising' scene
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Andreapworth
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Whenever I happen upon this movie (cable), I get sucked in, although I've seen it enough times. It's just a good story with it's own suspense. We all are rooting for little Lucas and the fact that John Book has to hide him and his mother away from the 'bad guys'. So many scenes are worth seeing again, especially when John Book gets hurt and must rely on the the Amish people to heal him - no doctors, of course. And of course, when Rachel's father wakes him up at the crack of dawn for milking. And when Radhel gives him some clothes that were her late husband's and explains that zippers and buttons are 'too proud'. And as mentioned, if you once see the barn raising scene, it will stay with you forever. Truly moving and a real example of community and what can be done by all people.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Maybe it had a point at the time...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Andrew Werling (awerling)
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Okay, so John Book is in dire straits, and so is a kid and probably his mother, but he seems to feel none of this urgency, and we watch irritating scenes of him falling in love, drinking lemonade, barn-raising, milking a cow...just not very well crafted in my opinion. And the soundtrack was cheesy. Great acting, cinematography, I'll give it that. I think the film took on too much. I just found it nearly impossible to believe his calmness in the face of one of the worst realities a cop can face: the corruption of his friends and mentors. And maybe I'm just jaded by better films on this topic which were made later: L.A. Confidential, 13 Blocks, even Copland. But I just felt antsy watching this in 2012, and I usually really dig Peter Weir films, even the cheesy ones.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Murder, Corruption & Doomed Love
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    seymourblack-1
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Witness" is a subtle, thoughtful and intelligently directed film which is both a crime thriller and an extraordinary love story. A police investigation into a brutal murder provides this drama with its momentum and drive and a tragic romantic tale adds the intensity, warmth and poignancy that elevates this movie to a higher level than that normally achieved by more routine thrillers. The story about two people from different backgrounds who fall in love, but know that their love can't transcend their circumstances, has a timeless and universal appeal which explains why this movie has retained its popularity so consistently since it was first released in 1985. When a recently widowed young Amish woman and her son are in a train station in Philadelphia, the 8-year-old boy witnesses the murder of an undercover cop. Detective Captain John Book (Harrison Ford) is put in charge of the investigation and questions Samuel Lapp (Lukas Haas), but even after showing him mug shots and arranging line-ups of suspects, the boy isn't able to finger the culprit. A little while later, however, Samuel is looking around the police office when he notices the killer's picture on a newspaper clipping that's pinned up inside a glass cabinet. When he brings this to Book's attention, it's quite a shock because the man in the photograph is the highly decorated Detective Lieutenant McFee (Danny Glover) of the Narcotics Division. Detective Book tells his superior officer Detective Chief Schaeffer (Josef Sommer) about this development and Schaeffer asks him to keep the information confidential. Shortly after, when he's shot at and injured by McFee, it becomes obvious to Book that McFee and Schaeffer are both corrupt and Samuel and his mother Rachel (Kelly McGillis) are in mortal danger. In order to protect them, Book drives them back to their Amish community but after his arrival there, he collapses and has to remain with the Amish where Rachel gradually nurses him back to health. During Book's period of recuperation, he and Rachel fall in love but he soon realises that neither of them could survive indefinitely in the other's world. Book adapts well to living with the Amish and earns their respect as he readily helps with milking cows and building a barn, but his presence in their community places them in danger, as becomes all too clear when the story reaches its action-packed conclusion. Non-verbal communication is used frequently in this movie and provides the action with an extremely natural feel. A couple of the stand-out sequences are those in which Samuel looks at Book in a way that immediately signifies that he's seen something important (when he sees McFee's photograph) and another is when Book and Rachel dance together in a barn to Sam Cooke's "What A Wonderful World". The power to convey their thoughts and feelings so clearly in this way is very touching at times and also testifies strongly to the quality of the acting. The differences between the worlds that Book and Rachel inhabit couldn't be greater as the Amish reside in rural surroundings and live a quiet, non-violent existence in which it's normal for everyone to help everyone else. These people embrace old fashioned values and don't use modern conveniences such as cars and refrigerators etc. By contrast, Book's existence as a city cop is far less serene and regularly brings him into contact with violence, corruption and various other forms of errant human behaviour. "Witness", with its interesting characters, its absorbing story of murder, corruption and doomed love and its marvellous acting performances, is tremendously enjoyable to watch and leaves a lasting impression.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "One Of Ford's Best!"
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gwnightscream
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/9/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Harrison Ford, Kelly McGillis, Lucas Haas, Jan Rubes, Danny Glover, Josef Sommer, Patti LuPone, and Alexander Godunov star in this 1985 thriller. This film begins in Pennsylvania in a small Amish town where a widow, Rachel Lapp (McGillis) attends her late husband's funeral with her family and friends. Soon, Rachel and her young son, Samuel (Haas) head to Baltimore to visit her sister until Samuel witnesses a cop's murder in Philadelphia. Ford plays John Book, a cop who investigates the case and tries to protect Rachel and Samuel. When he's almost killed by crooked cops, John takes Rachel and Samuel home, but hides there with them learning their Amish ways. Rubes plays Rachel's father-in-law, Eli, Glover plays cop, McFee, Sommer plays John's mentor, Schaeffer, LuPone plays John's sister, Elaine and Godunov (Die Hard) plays Daniel, an Amish friend of Rachel's family. This is one of Ford's best and he and McGillis are great together. Maurice Jarre's score is also excellent and I recommend this.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
 </reviews>
</filme>
