<filme>
 <id>
  1527
 </id>
 <imdburl>
  http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0120820
 </imdburl>
 <ano>
  1998
 </ano>
 <titulo>
  Sem Sentido
 </titulo>
 <rating>
  5.6
 </rating>
 <sinopse>
  A student gets his senses enhanced by an experimental drug. But abuse is not an option.
 </sinopse>
 <storyline>
  Darryl Witherspoon is a young black college student who wants to win annual junior analyst competition, which can land him a job in a big brokerage company. He becomes a guinea pig for the drug developed at the college which is promised to heighten all senses by ten times.
 </storyline>
 <generos>
  <genero>
   Comedy
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Romance
  </genero>
 </generos>
 <keywords>
  <keyword>
   college
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   drugs
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   medical experiment
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   business
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   sensory deprivation
  </keyword>
 </keywords>
 <diretores>
  <diretor>
   Penelope Spheeris
  </diretor>
 </diretores>
 <escritores>
  <escritor>
   Greg Erb
  </escritor>
  <escritor>
   Craig Mazin
  </escritor>
 </escritores>
 <atores>
  <ator>
   Marlon Wayans
  </ator>
  <ator>
   David Spade
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Brad Dourif
  </ator>
 </atores>
 <reviews>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Darryl needs a cookie.....
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    FlashCallahan
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Darryl Witherspoon is a college student who wants to win annual junior analyst competition, which can land him a job in a big brokerage company. But because he hardly earns any money, and that of what he does, he gives to his family, he becomes a guinea pig for a drug developed at the college which is promised to heighten all senses by ten times.... The first thing you notice about watching any movie starring Wayans from Mo' Money, right up to The Heat, is the fact that the man doesn't age, and it can really put you off track when you are trying to follow the movie. Seriously though, the man has looked about twenty two for over twenty years. And that's about the most interesting thing about this generic, not very funny high concept comedy. Wayans is okay, but whilst watching it, I kept thinking Eddie Murphy would have done this better in 1988, and Akroyd would have been great as the Spade character. Plus it could have been the old sweary Murphy too. So hilarity ensues when Darryl starts to experience heightened sense. He sees women's derri&egrave;res up close, he smells people's breath, and hears people on the toilet, you can tell where the rest of the humour goes. Spade though, is brilliant as the adversary, here ally oozes slime, and would have been better suited to this type of role, he's easily the best thing about this. The plot is predictable, and it turns out predictable. Just as things are going great for Darryl, something happens with the drug, and makes things go bad for a while, and then things get better again. Don't be fooled by the fact that its directed by the same person who did Wayne's World, That's all down to Mike Myers. This is generic toilet humour with very little going for it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    No sense
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Raul Faust
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Senseless" used to be one of my favorite movies when I was a young boy. You know, in puberty era. Yesterday I happened to watch it again, and man, this movie doesn't feel that good anymore. Main plot is completely original, making me congratulate the writers for such creativity. Directing, although being predictable sometimes, never disappoints. Even thought I laughed in most scenes that had jokes, sometimes it feels like there's been too few comedy scenes. Marlon Wayans is what makes these jokes actually work. The scene in which Darryl tries to kiss that other girl and his "member" doesn't work used to be a lot funnier in past. Now, am I becoming bad humored or this kind of joke got old. Rest of the cast is just normal and there's nothing bad to say about them. "Senseless" is pretty much it, some laughs here and there, an original story with a clich&eacute;d yet ridiculous ending that Hollywood usually makes and nothing else.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Turn off !
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ahmed elshikh (ahmed_abd_elreheem@yahoo.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/2/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I looked up the definitions of "Turn off" in my dictionary to find this : 1 - (transitive) To repulse, disgust, or discourage. Example : _The Excrement, urine, semen,well the whole rude humor really turns me off. _Tamara Taylor as Janice turns me off when she does nothing but smiling dully. _Good comedies with good ideas turn me off when they use easy dirty jokes. _I swear to god, (Senseless) turned me off for days after watching it due to its fart jokes. 2 - (transitive) To power down; to stop a device by switching it off. Example : _Turn off the TV and unplug it when (Senseless) is on. 3 - (intransitive) To leave a road; exit. Example : _Turn off at the next exit so we can avoid that dirty comedies on the cinema ahead of us. Related terms : Marlon Wayans, the Wayans brothers, Scary Movie 2.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Just terrible
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    AtomAnt101
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/5/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I registered an account on IMDb just so I could comment on how bad this movie is. The fact that so many people on here consider Senseless to be good is an idea that I regard with absolute horror. This film is the most unfunny, rotten pile of human excrement I've ever had the misfortune of sitting through, and that's saying a lot because I saw part of Charlie's Angels once. I am genuinely shocked that none of the actors who were a part of this abomination ruined their careers making it. I think it goes without saying that the writers should all go to prison, and Marlon Wayans should be burned at the stake as a warning to all the other idiots who are thinking about releasing something this terrible on the public. Senseless was physically painful for me to watch, and I feel it is my duty to prevent as many people as possible from experiencing the pain I felt, so to convince you, the reader, why you should avoid this film at all costs I have listed the following: * The plot is really stupid. * Everything is predictably stupid. * Not funny at all; jokes are all stupid. * Marlon Wayans isn't funny. * Marlon Wayans can't really act. * Marlon Wayans is stupid. * Marlon Wayans. * Stupid.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I've just watched...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jOsSse
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/9/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    and i love it! it is a great comedy movie, very entertaining, and unique. this movie is original, one of the best Wayans Bros. productions. btw Wayans bros. rocks, i've seen 'don't be a menace' and damn it rocks,i saw 'senseless' and now i wanna see 'im gonna git you sucka'. i know, old movies, but.. where does the comedy went?? the recent comedies are light, and they partly suck. go Wayans, make another big creation for us! i truly recommend it, i couldn't stop laughin! Marlon Wayans is like the black Jim Carrey (in my opinion) so rent it on DVD, and come here! this movie deserves a big 10 for its original idea and funny stuffs
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An insult to the viewers intelligence
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    placebotonic
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/8/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    When I'm running out of DVD's to watch, I'm kind of ready to watch anything, so last night, this was it. IMDb score was decent enough, but it was obvious to me I wasn't going to get awed by the movie. Senseless is a comedy where the characters KNOW they're in a comedy and would do anything to get a laugh, which means, follow every clich&eacute; in history of comedy and exploit it until there's only some dust left. The plot is utterly predictable, Marlon Wayans does not understand the concept of the funny, or the concept of acting. Sure, you have to cut some slack to a comedy, you know, laws of physics do not necessarily apply, people are overly goofy, but seriously, if someone acted like the extreme non plus ultra overboard character of Marlon Wayans in real life, it would take less than a day for him to land in an insane asylum. I don't think this movie could possibly be parodied, unless the character would grimace through 100 percent of the movie, not just 95. Also, no disrespect to the actress, but I could not understand the Darryl's shock when he first saw his 'dream girl'. I just thought, wait, what, THIS girl took his breath away? In a university campus virtually littered with pretty girls? Uh... yeah... right, also, the chemical lab is full of bubbling glow-in-the-dark colored liquids, fumes, plus the stereotypical chemyst? It's like this movie was made by two screenplay writers and two directors, one team worked on making this movie for 4 year old kids, the other team worked on making it for 16+ kids and adults, then they put it in a blender, drank it, and vomited this movie. I know, it's far easier to make a good drama, than a good comedy movie, but this piece... not just didn't make me laugh, it made me uncomfortable, irritated, nervous and angry, I felt insulted and violated. I know of no other movie that even came close to this and for achieving this, it gets a 3 instead of 1. If you have a choice to watch this movie or stare at the ceiling, I recommend the ceiling.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Its A Good Movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    piinkk_panther
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/7/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I think this movie was very well done. It had lots of laughs,an entertaining plot and good acting for the most part.It also had great actors in it (Matthew Lillard,Marlon Wayans, David Spade etc.) Wayans did an amazing job but i have to say that Lillard was the funniest, even though he didn't have a very big part. This definitely wasn't Spade's best movie though, because he came off very boring and quite annoying in most scenes. But overall, this movie was pretty good. I really liked it, and if your a Wayans or Lillard fan, I'm sure you will too. This movie is pretty much all about immature jokes, so if you are not looking for that kind of comedy, you should try a different movie.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Very funny and also touching
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    vchimpanzee
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/6/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Darryl Witherspoon is a senior economics major whose mother has been raising several children on her own in a bad section of New York City. He is very bright and has a good chance of getting out of that neighborhood. But he has bills to pay and may get kicked out of the apartment he shares with hockey player Tim. Darryl has a good chance at being the one junior analyst hired that year by the prestigious Wall Street firm Smythe-Bates. But his competition includes Scott Thorpe, whose father works for the firm. Scott belongs to the fraternity Darryl wants to join, and he thinks he is better than everyone else and that Darryl isn't good enough to be one of them. Darryl also can't make it as a hockey player. Impressing Smythe-Bates becomes less of a priority as Darryl looks for work just to keep his apartment. The university is testing an experimental drug which heightens the five senses. Despite the potential side effects, Darryl is determined to do whatever it takes to make the money he needs. One possible problem with the drug he is not told about: at too high a dosage, one of the five senses shuts down, followed by another, and another. It's not possible to predict which of the senses will go or when, but you can bet this will happen at the worst possible time. Darryl also wants to meet girls, and Janice is attractive, pleasant and intelligent. Can he win her love? Can he find a way to impress Smythe-Bates? This was very funny. I liked the concept--as in "Smallville", a shiny green liquid can give an ordinary person super powers, and it can also cause all sorts of trouble. But the movie wasn't just funny. The romantic scenes were also warm and touching. The writing was quite intelligent. Someone must have known how Wall Street operates and the economic principles that guide the financial industry. I'm surprised we haven't heard more from Marlon Wayans. Although he seemed like a silly clown at times, he really demonstrated comic abilities when Darryl struggled with the drug's problems. And he showed superior talent for both comedy and drama when the drug did what it was supposed to do. David Spade was somewhat less of a loser here than he usually is. He excels at playing jerk loser characters, but Scott had more dimension than the usual Spade type. Richard McDonagle was quite good as one of the top men at Smythe-Bates. And Tamara Taylor impressed as Janice. Esther Scott had a brief but effective performance as Darryl's determined mother. This was really worth seeing. Don't be misled by the title.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    what ever happened to humour in this world
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    stuart-1888
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/1/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I don't believe the poor rating that this film has been given. This is one of the funniest films I have seen in a long time. If people watched it with an open mind and stopped trying to serious movie critics and analyse every film they see, they would realise that it is great fun and entertaining. I have recommended this film to lots of my mates and they all thought it was side-splittingly funny. Everybody out there who gave it a crap rating should watch it again, as I pity them for their lack of humour and understanding of a good comedy. I gave this film a ten and I think it was worth every point. Anybody else agree-let me know.Vote and lets get this movie up from the paltry score of 5.4(what an insult)ENOUGH SAID. WAYANS BROTHERS ROCK.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Pathetic!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    saint405
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/6/2005
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Senseless is a tragedy film with one character being the center of attention, throw in a stupid plot about a new drug, add a subplot about trying to win a job, and why not, pluck a few good actors out of the bag and throw it into this film to make a horrible film! Marlon Waynes as Witherspoon is not funny at all. All he does is scream, cry, run around, and itch his behind! David Spade was totally useless as the evil villain Scott who was nothing but a big dork and we have the wonderful Matthew Lillard playing some junkie gay thug. Now the start of this film is okay with Marlon running around doing errands, trying to raise money for his mom and his college education by giving blood multiple times and working as a equipment manager but the film falls like a rock! No funny jokes at fall, Marlons out burst are the most idiotic things, Spade is totally uncool, and the girlfriend is just thrown in for some zest which even burns the suck fire brighter! Avoid this film at all cost, don't bother! You will get dumber by watching this movie, it's pathetic! 1 out of ten, horrible!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Darryl needs a cookie.....
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    FlashCallahan
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Darryl Witherspoon is a college student who wants to win annual junior analyst competition, which can land him a job in a big brokerage company. But because he hardly earns any money, and that of what he does, he gives to his family, he becomes a guinea pig for a drug developed at the college which is promised to heighten all senses by ten times.... The first thing you notice about watching any movie starring Wayans from Mo' Money, right up to The Heat, is the fact that the man doesn't age, and it can really put you off track when you are trying to follow the movie. Seriously though, the man has looked about twenty two for over twenty years. And that's about the most interesting thing about this generic, not very funny high concept comedy. Wayans is okay, but whilst watching it, I kept thinking Eddie Murphy would have done this better in 1988, and Akroyd would have been great as the Spade character. Plus it could have been the old sweary Murphy too. So hilarity ensues when Darryl starts to experience heightened sense. He sees women's derri&egrave;res up close, he smells people's breath, and hears people on the toilet, you can tell where the rest of the humour goes. Spade though, is brilliant as the adversary, here ally oozes slime, and would have been better suited to this type of role, he's easily the best thing about this. The plot is predictable, and it turns out predictable. Just as things are going great for Darryl, something happens with the drug, and makes things go bad for a while, and then things get better again. Don't be fooled by the fact that its directed by the same person who did Wayne's World, That's all down to Mike Myers. This is generic toilet humour with very little going for it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    No sense
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Raul Faust
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Senseless" used to be one of my favorite movies when I was a young boy. You know, in puberty era. Yesterday I happened to watch it again, and man, this movie doesn't feel that good anymore. Main plot is completely original, making me congratulate the writers for such creativity. Directing, although being predictable sometimes, never disappoints. Even thought I laughed in most scenes that had jokes, sometimes it feels like there's been too few comedy scenes. Marlon Wayans is what makes these jokes actually work. The scene in which Darryl tries to kiss that other girl and his "member" doesn't work used to be a lot funnier in past. Now, am I becoming bad humored or this kind of joke got old. Rest of the cast is just normal and there's nothing bad to say about them. "Senseless" is pretty much it, some laughs here and there, an original story with a clich&eacute;d yet ridiculous ending that Hollywood usually makes and nothing else.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Turn off !
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ahmed elshikh (ahmed_abd_elreheem@yahoo.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/2/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I looked up the definitions of "Turn off" in my dictionary to find this : 1 - (transitive) To repulse, disgust, or discourage. Example : _The Excrement, urine, semen,well the whole rude humor really turns me off. _Tamara Taylor as Janice turns me off when she does nothing but smiling dully. _Good comedies with good ideas turn me off when they use easy dirty jokes. _I swear to god, (Senseless) turned me off for days after watching it due to its fart jokes. 2 - (transitive) To power down; to stop a device by switching it off. Example : _Turn off the TV and unplug it when (Senseless) is on. 3 - (intransitive) To leave a road; exit. Example : _Turn off at the next exit so we can avoid that dirty comedies on the cinema ahead of us. Related terms : Marlon Wayans, the Wayans brothers, Scary Movie 2.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Just terrible
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    AtomAnt101
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/5/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I registered an account on IMDb just so I could comment on how bad this movie is. The fact that so many people on here consider Senseless to be good is an idea that I regard with absolute horror. This film is the most unfunny, rotten pile of human excrement I've ever had the misfortune of sitting through, and that's saying a lot because I saw part of Charlie's Angels once. I am genuinely shocked that none of the actors who were a part of this abomination ruined their careers making it. I think it goes without saying that the writers should all go to prison, and Marlon Wayans should be burned at the stake as a warning to all the other idiots who are thinking about releasing something this terrible on the public. Senseless was physically painful for me to watch, and I feel it is my duty to prevent as many people as possible from experiencing the pain I felt, so to convince you, the reader, why you should avoid this film at all costs I have listed the following: * The plot is really stupid. * Everything is predictably stupid. * Not funny at all; jokes are all stupid. * Marlon Wayans isn't funny. * Marlon Wayans can't really act. * Marlon Wayans is stupid. * Marlon Wayans. * Stupid.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I've just watched...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jOsSse
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/9/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    and i love it! it is a great comedy movie, very entertaining, and unique. this movie is original, one of the best Wayans Bros. productions. btw Wayans bros. rocks, i've seen 'don't be a menace' and damn it rocks,i saw 'senseless' and now i wanna see 'im gonna git you sucka'. i know, old movies, but.. where does the comedy went?? the recent comedies are light, and they partly suck. go Wayans, make another big creation for us! i truly recommend it, i couldn't stop laughin! Marlon Wayans is like the black Jim Carrey (in my opinion) so rent it on DVD, and come here! this movie deserves a big 10 for its original idea and funny stuffs
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An insult to the viewers intelligence
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    placebotonic
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/8/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    When I'm running out of DVD's to watch, I'm kind of ready to watch anything, so last night, this was it. IMDb score was decent enough, but it was obvious to me I wasn't going to get awed by the movie. Senseless is a comedy where the characters KNOW they're in a comedy and would do anything to get a laugh, which means, follow every clich&eacute; in history of comedy and exploit it until there's only some dust left. The plot is utterly predictable, Marlon Wayans does not understand the concept of the funny, or the concept of acting. Sure, you have to cut some slack to a comedy, you know, laws of physics do not necessarily apply, people are overly goofy, but seriously, if someone acted like the extreme non plus ultra overboard character of Marlon Wayans in real life, it would take less than a day for him to land in an insane asylum. I don't think this movie could possibly be parodied, unless the character would grimace through 100 percent of the movie, not just 95. Also, no disrespect to the actress, but I could not understand the Darryl's shock when he first saw his 'dream girl'. I just thought, wait, what, THIS girl took his breath away? In a university campus virtually littered with pretty girls? Uh... yeah... right, also, the chemical lab is full of bubbling glow-in-the-dark colored liquids, fumes, plus the stereotypical chemyst? It's like this movie was made by two screenplay writers and two directors, one team worked on making this movie for 4 year old kids, the other team worked on making it for 16+ kids and adults, then they put it in a blender, drank it, and vomited this movie. I know, it's far easier to make a good drama, than a good comedy movie, but this piece... not just didn't make me laugh, it made me uncomfortable, irritated, nervous and angry, I felt insulted and violated. I know of no other movie that even came close to this and for achieving this, it gets a 3 instead of 1. If you have a choice to watch this movie or stare at the ceiling, I recommend the ceiling.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Its A Good Movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    piinkk_panther
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/7/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I think this movie was very well done. It had lots of laughs,an entertaining plot and good acting for the most part.It also had great actors in it (Matthew Lillard,Marlon Wayans, David Spade etc.) Wayans did an amazing job but i have to say that Lillard was the funniest, even though he didn't have a very big part. This definitely wasn't Spade's best movie though, because he came off very boring and quite annoying in most scenes. But overall, this movie was pretty good. I really liked it, and if your a Wayans or Lillard fan, I'm sure you will too. This movie is pretty much all about immature jokes, so if you are not looking for that kind of comedy, you should try a different movie.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Very funny and also touching
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    vchimpanzee
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/6/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Darryl Witherspoon is a senior economics major whose mother has been raising several children on her own in a bad section of New York City. He is very bright and has a good chance of getting out of that neighborhood. But he has bills to pay and may get kicked out of the apartment he shares with hockey player Tim. Darryl has a good chance at being the one junior analyst hired that year by the prestigious Wall Street firm Smythe-Bates. But his competition includes Scott Thorpe, whose father works for the firm. Scott belongs to the fraternity Darryl wants to join, and he thinks he is better than everyone else and that Darryl isn't good enough to be one of them. Darryl also can't make it as a hockey player. Impressing Smythe-Bates becomes less of a priority as Darryl looks for work just to keep his apartment. The university is testing an experimental drug which heightens the five senses. Despite the potential side effects, Darryl is determined to do whatever it takes to make the money he needs. One possible problem with the drug he is not told about: at too high a dosage, one of the five senses shuts down, followed by another, and another. It's not possible to predict which of the senses will go or when, but you can bet this will happen at the worst possible time. Darryl also wants to meet girls, and Janice is attractive, pleasant and intelligent. Can he win her love? Can he find a way to impress Smythe-Bates? This was very funny. I liked the concept--as in "Smallville", a shiny green liquid can give an ordinary person super powers, and it can also cause all sorts of trouble. But the movie wasn't just funny. The romantic scenes were also warm and touching. The writing was quite intelligent. Someone must have known how Wall Street operates and the economic principles that guide the financial industry. I'm surprised we haven't heard more from Marlon Wayans. Although he seemed like a silly clown at times, he really demonstrated comic abilities when Darryl struggled with the drug's problems. And he showed superior talent for both comedy and drama when the drug did what it was supposed to do. David Spade was somewhat less of a loser here than he usually is. He excels at playing jerk loser characters, but Scott had more dimension than the usual Spade type. Richard McDonagle was quite good as one of the top men at Smythe-Bates. And Tamara Taylor impressed as Janice. Esther Scott had a brief but effective performance as Darryl's determined mother. This was really worth seeing. Don't be misled by the title.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    what ever happened to humour in this world
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    stuart-1888
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/1/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I don't believe the poor rating that this film has been given. This is one of the funniest films I have seen in a long time. If people watched it with an open mind and stopped trying to serious movie critics and analyse every film they see, they would realise that it is great fun and entertaining. I have recommended this film to lots of my mates and they all thought it was side-splittingly funny. Everybody out there who gave it a crap rating should watch it again, as I pity them for their lack of humour and understanding of a good comedy. I gave this film a ten and I think it was worth every point. Anybody else agree-let me know.Vote and lets get this movie up from the paltry score of 5.4(what an insult)ENOUGH SAID. WAYANS BROTHERS ROCK.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Pathetic!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    saint405
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/6/2005
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Senseless is a tragedy film with one character being the center of attention, throw in a stupid plot about a new drug, add a subplot about trying to win a job, and why not, pluck a few good actors out of the bag and throw it into this film to make a horrible film! Marlon Waynes as Witherspoon is not funny at all. All he does is scream, cry, run around, and itch his behind! David Spade was totally useless as the evil villain Scott who was nothing but a big dork and we have the wonderful Matthew Lillard playing some junkie gay thug. Now the start of this film is okay with Marlon running around doing errands, trying to raise money for his mom and his college education by giving blood multiple times and working as a equipment manager but the film falls like a rock! No funny jokes at fall, Marlons out burst are the most idiotic things, Spade is totally uncool, and the girlfriend is just thrown in for some zest which even burns the suck fire brighter! Avoid this film at all cost, don't bother! You will get dumber by watching this movie, it's pathetic! 1 out of ten, horrible!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Darryl needs a cookie.....
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    FlashCallahan
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Darryl Witherspoon is a college student who wants to win annual junior analyst competition, which can land him a job in a big brokerage company. But because he hardly earns any money, and that of what he does, he gives to his family, he becomes a guinea pig for a drug developed at the college which is promised to heighten all senses by ten times.... The first thing you notice about watching any movie starring Wayans from Mo' Money, right up to The Heat, is the fact that the man doesn't age, and it can really put you off track when you are trying to follow the movie. Seriously though, the man has looked about twenty two for over twenty years. And that's about the most interesting thing about this generic, not very funny high concept comedy. Wayans is okay, but whilst watching it, I kept thinking Eddie Murphy would have done this better in 1988, and Akroyd would have been great as the Spade character. Plus it could have been the old sweary Murphy too. So hilarity ensues when Darryl starts to experience heightened sense. He sees women's derri&egrave;res up close, he smells people's breath, and hears people on the toilet, you can tell where the rest of the humour goes. Spade though, is brilliant as the adversary, here ally oozes slime, and would have been better suited to this type of role, he's easily the best thing about this. The plot is predictable, and it turns out predictable. Just as things are going great for Darryl, something happens with the drug, and makes things go bad for a while, and then things get better again. Don't be fooled by the fact that its directed by the same person who did Wayne's World, That's all down to Mike Myers. This is generic toilet humour with very little going for it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    No sense
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Raul Faust
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Senseless" used to be one of my favorite movies when I was a young boy. You know, in puberty era. Yesterday I happened to watch it again, and man, this movie doesn't feel that good anymore. Main plot is completely original, making me congratulate the writers for such creativity. Directing, although being predictable sometimes, never disappoints. Even thought I laughed in most scenes that had jokes, sometimes it feels like there's been too few comedy scenes. Marlon Wayans is what makes these jokes actually work. The scene in which Darryl tries to kiss that other girl and his "member" doesn't work used to be a lot funnier in past. Now, am I becoming bad humored or this kind of joke got old. Rest of the cast is just normal and there's nothing bad to say about them. "Senseless" is pretty much it, some laughs here and there, an original story with a clich&eacute;d yet ridiculous ending that Hollywood usually makes and nothing else.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Turn off !
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ahmed elshikh (ahmed_abd_elreheem@yahoo.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/2/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I looked up the definitions of "Turn off" in my dictionary to find this : 1 - (transitive) To repulse, disgust, or discourage. Example : _The Excrement, urine, semen,well the whole rude humor really turns me off. _Tamara Taylor as Janice turns me off when she does nothing but smiling dully. _Good comedies with good ideas turn me off when they use easy dirty jokes. _I swear to god, (Senseless) turned me off for days after watching it due to its fart jokes. 2 - (transitive) To power down; to stop a device by switching it off. Example : _Turn off the TV and unplug it when (Senseless) is on. 3 - (intransitive) To leave a road; exit. Example : _Turn off at the next exit so we can avoid that dirty comedies on the cinema ahead of us. Related terms : Marlon Wayans, the Wayans brothers, Scary Movie 2.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Just terrible
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    AtomAnt101
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/5/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I registered an account on IMDb just so I could comment on how bad this movie is. The fact that so many people on here consider Senseless to be good is an idea that I regard with absolute horror. This film is the most unfunny, rotten pile of human excrement I've ever had the misfortune of sitting through, and that's saying a lot because I saw part of Charlie's Angels once. I am genuinely shocked that none of the actors who were a part of this abomination ruined their careers making it. I think it goes without saying that the writers should all go to prison, and Marlon Wayans should be burned at the stake as a warning to all the other idiots who are thinking about releasing something this terrible on the public. Senseless was physically painful for me to watch, and I feel it is my duty to prevent as many people as possible from experiencing the pain I felt, so to convince you, the reader, why you should avoid this film at all costs I have listed the following: * The plot is really stupid. * Everything is predictably stupid. * Not funny at all; jokes are all stupid. * Marlon Wayans isn't funny. * Marlon Wayans can't really act. * Marlon Wayans is stupid. * Marlon Wayans. * Stupid.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I've just watched...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jOsSse
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/9/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    and i love it! it is a great comedy movie, very entertaining, and unique. this movie is original, one of the best Wayans Bros. productions. btw Wayans bros. rocks, i've seen 'don't be a menace' and damn it rocks,i saw 'senseless' and now i wanna see 'im gonna git you sucka'. i know, old movies, but.. where does the comedy went?? the recent comedies are light, and they partly suck. go Wayans, make another big creation for us! i truly recommend it, i couldn't stop laughin! Marlon Wayans is like the black Jim Carrey (in my opinion) so rent it on DVD, and come here! this movie deserves a big 10 for its original idea and funny stuffs
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An insult to the viewers intelligence
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    placebotonic
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/8/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    When I'm running out of DVD's to watch, I'm kind of ready to watch anything, so last night, this was it. IMDb score was decent enough, but it was obvious to me I wasn't going to get awed by the movie. Senseless is a comedy where the characters KNOW they're in a comedy and would do anything to get a laugh, which means, follow every clich&eacute; in history of comedy and exploit it until there's only some dust left. The plot is utterly predictable, Marlon Wayans does not understand the concept of the funny, or the concept of acting. Sure, you have to cut some slack to a comedy, you know, laws of physics do not necessarily apply, people are overly goofy, but seriously, if someone acted like the extreme non plus ultra overboard character of Marlon Wayans in real life, it would take less than a day for him to land in an insane asylum. I don't think this movie could possibly be parodied, unless the character would grimace through 100 percent of the movie, not just 95. Also, no disrespect to the actress, but I could not understand the Darryl's shock when he first saw his 'dream girl'. I just thought, wait, what, THIS girl took his breath away? In a university campus virtually littered with pretty girls? Uh... yeah... right, also, the chemical lab is full of bubbling glow-in-the-dark colored liquids, fumes, plus the stereotypical chemyst? It's like this movie was made by two screenplay writers and two directors, one team worked on making this movie for 4 year old kids, the other team worked on making it for 16+ kids and adults, then they put it in a blender, drank it, and vomited this movie. I know, it's far easier to make a good drama, than a good comedy movie, but this piece... not just didn't make me laugh, it made me uncomfortable, irritated, nervous and angry, I felt insulted and violated. I know of no other movie that even came close to this and for achieving this, it gets a 3 instead of 1. If you have a choice to watch this movie or stare at the ceiling, I recommend the ceiling.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Its A Good Movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    piinkk_panther
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/7/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I think this movie was very well done. It had lots of laughs,an entertaining plot and good acting for the most part.It also had great actors in it (Matthew Lillard,Marlon Wayans, David Spade etc.) Wayans did an amazing job but i have to say that Lillard was the funniest, even though he didn't have a very big part. This definitely wasn't Spade's best movie though, because he came off very boring and quite annoying in most scenes. But overall, this movie was pretty good. I really liked it, and if your a Wayans or Lillard fan, I'm sure you will too. This movie is pretty much all about immature jokes, so if you are not looking for that kind of comedy, you should try a different movie.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Very funny and also touching
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    vchimpanzee
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/6/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Darryl Witherspoon is a senior economics major whose mother has been raising several children on her own in a bad section of New York City. He is very bright and has a good chance of getting out of that neighborhood. But he has bills to pay and may get kicked out of the apartment he shares with hockey player Tim. Darryl has a good chance at being the one junior analyst hired that year by the prestigious Wall Street firm Smythe-Bates. But his competition includes Scott Thorpe, whose father works for the firm. Scott belongs to the fraternity Darryl wants to join, and he thinks he is better than everyone else and that Darryl isn't good enough to be one of them. Darryl also can't make it as a hockey player. Impressing Smythe-Bates becomes less of a priority as Darryl looks for work just to keep his apartment. The university is testing an experimental drug which heightens the five senses. Despite the potential side effects, Darryl is determined to do whatever it takes to make the money he needs. One possible problem with the drug he is not told about: at too high a dosage, one of the five senses shuts down, followed by another, and another. It's not possible to predict which of the senses will go or when, but you can bet this will happen at the worst possible time. Darryl also wants to meet girls, and Janice is attractive, pleasant and intelligent. Can he win her love? Can he find a way to impress Smythe-Bates? This was very funny. I liked the concept--as in "Smallville", a shiny green liquid can give an ordinary person super powers, and it can also cause all sorts of trouble. But the movie wasn't just funny. The romantic scenes were also warm and touching. The writing was quite intelligent. Someone must have known how Wall Street operates and the economic principles that guide the financial industry. I'm surprised we haven't heard more from Marlon Wayans. Although he seemed like a silly clown at times, he really demonstrated comic abilities when Darryl struggled with the drug's problems. And he showed superior talent for both comedy and drama when the drug did what it was supposed to do. David Spade was somewhat less of a loser here than he usually is. He excels at playing jerk loser characters, but Scott had more dimension than the usual Spade type. Richard McDonagle was quite good as one of the top men at Smythe-Bates. And Tamara Taylor impressed as Janice. Esther Scott had a brief but effective performance as Darryl's determined mother. This was really worth seeing. Don't be misled by the title.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    what ever happened to humour in this world
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    stuart-1888
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/1/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I don't believe the poor rating that this film has been given. This is one of the funniest films I have seen in a long time. If people watched it with an open mind and stopped trying to serious movie critics and analyse every film they see, they would realise that it is great fun and entertaining. I have recommended this film to lots of my mates and they all thought it was side-splittingly funny. Everybody out there who gave it a crap rating should watch it again, as I pity them for their lack of humour and understanding of a good comedy. I gave this film a ten and I think it was worth every point. Anybody else agree-let me know.Vote and lets get this movie up from the paltry score of 5.4(what an insult)ENOUGH SAID. WAYANS BROTHERS ROCK.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Pathetic!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    saint405
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/6/2005
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Senseless is a tragedy film with one character being the center of attention, throw in a stupid plot about a new drug, add a subplot about trying to win a job, and why not, pluck a few good actors out of the bag and throw it into this film to make a horrible film! Marlon Waynes as Witherspoon is not funny at all. All he does is scream, cry, run around, and itch his behind! David Spade was totally useless as the evil villain Scott who was nothing but a big dork and we have the wonderful Matthew Lillard playing some junkie gay thug. Now the start of this film is okay with Marlon running around doing errands, trying to raise money for his mom and his college education by giving blood multiple times and working as a equipment manager but the film falls like a rock! No funny jokes at fall, Marlons out burst are the most idiotic things, Spade is totally uncool, and the girlfriend is just thrown in for some zest which even burns the suck fire brighter! Avoid this film at all cost, don't bother! You will get dumber by watching this movie, it's pathetic! 1 out of ten, horrible!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Darryl needs a cookie.....
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    FlashCallahan
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Darryl Witherspoon is a college student who wants to win annual junior analyst competition, which can land him a job in a big brokerage company. But because he hardly earns any money, and that of what he does, he gives to his family, he becomes a guinea pig for a drug developed at the college which is promised to heighten all senses by ten times.... The first thing you notice about watching any movie starring Wayans from Mo' Money, right up to The Heat, is the fact that the man doesn't age, and it can really put you off track when you are trying to follow the movie. Seriously though, the man has looked about twenty two for over twenty years. And that's about the most interesting thing about this generic, not very funny high concept comedy. Wayans is okay, but whilst watching it, I kept thinking Eddie Murphy would have done this better in 1988, and Akroyd would have been great as the Spade character. Plus it could have been the old sweary Murphy too. So hilarity ensues when Darryl starts to experience heightened sense. He sees women's derri&egrave;res up close, he smells people's breath, and hears people on the toilet, you can tell where the rest of the humour goes. Spade though, is brilliant as the adversary, here ally oozes slime, and would have been better suited to this type of role, he's easily the best thing about this. The plot is predictable, and it turns out predictable. Just as things are going great for Darryl, something happens with the drug, and makes things go bad for a while, and then things get better again. Don't be fooled by the fact that its directed by the same person who did Wayne's World, That's all down to Mike Myers. This is generic toilet humour with very little going for it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    No sense
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Raul Faust
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Senseless" used to be one of my favorite movies when I was a young boy. You know, in puberty era. Yesterday I happened to watch it again, and man, this movie doesn't feel that good anymore. Main plot is completely original, making me congratulate the writers for such creativity. Directing, although being predictable sometimes, never disappoints. Even thought I laughed in most scenes that had jokes, sometimes it feels like there's been too few comedy scenes. Marlon Wayans is what makes these jokes actually work. The scene in which Darryl tries to kiss that other girl and his "member" doesn't work used to be a lot funnier in past. Now, am I becoming bad humored or this kind of joke got old. Rest of the cast is just normal and there's nothing bad to say about them. "Senseless" is pretty much it, some laughs here and there, an original story with a clich&eacute;d yet ridiculous ending that Hollywood usually makes and nothing else.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Turn off !
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ahmed elshikh (ahmed_abd_elreheem@yahoo.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/2/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I looked up the definitions of "Turn off" in my dictionary to find this : 1 - (transitive) To repulse, disgust, or discourage. Example : _The Excrement, urine, semen,well the whole rude humor really turns me off. _Tamara Taylor as Janice turns me off when she does nothing but smiling dully. _Good comedies with good ideas turn me off when they use easy dirty jokes. _I swear to god, (Senseless) turned me off for days after watching it due to its fart jokes. 2 - (transitive) To power down; to stop a device by switching it off. Example : _Turn off the TV and unplug it when (Senseless) is on. 3 - (intransitive) To leave a road; exit. Example : _Turn off at the next exit so we can avoid that dirty comedies on the cinema ahead of us. Related terms : Marlon Wayans, the Wayans brothers, Scary Movie 2.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Just terrible
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    AtomAnt101
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/5/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I registered an account on IMDb just so I could comment on how bad this movie is. The fact that so many people on here consider Senseless to be good is an idea that I regard with absolute horror. This film is the most unfunny, rotten pile of human excrement I've ever had the misfortune of sitting through, and that's saying a lot because I saw part of Charlie's Angels once. I am genuinely shocked that none of the actors who were a part of this abomination ruined their careers making it. I think it goes without saying that the writers should all go to prison, and Marlon Wayans should be burned at the stake as a warning to all the other idiots who are thinking about releasing something this terrible on the public. Senseless was physically painful for me to watch, and I feel it is my duty to prevent as many people as possible from experiencing the pain I felt, so to convince you, the reader, why you should avoid this film at all costs I have listed the following: * The plot is really stupid. * Everything is predictably stupid. * Not funny at all; jokes are all stupid. * Marlon Wayans isn't funny. * Marlon Wayans can't really act. * Marlon Wayans is stupid. * Marlon Wayans. * Stupid.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I've just watched...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jOsSse
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/9/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    and i love it! it is a great comedy movie, very entertaining, and unique. this movie is original, one of the best Wayans Bros. productions. btw Wayans bros. rocks, i've seen 'don't be a menace' and damn it rocks,i saw 'senseless' and now i wanna see 'im gonna git you sucka'. i know, old movies, but.. where does the comedy went?? the recent comedies are light, and they partly suck. go Wayans, make another big creation for us! i truly recommend it, i couldn't stop laughin! Marlon Wayans is like the black Jim Carrey (in my opinion) so rent it on DVD, and come here! this movie deserves a big 10 for its original idea and funny stuffs
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An insult to the viewers intelligence
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    placebotonic
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/8/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    When I'm running out of DVD's to watch, I'm kind of ready to watch anything, so last night, this was it. IMDb score was decent enough, but it was obvious to me I wasn't going to get awed by the movie. Senseless is a comedy where the characters KNOW they're in a comedy and would do anything to get a laugh, which means, follow every clich&eacute; in history of comedy and exploit it until there's only some dust left. The plot is utterly predictable, Marlon Wayans does not understand the concept of the funny, or the concept of acting. Sure, you have to cut some slack to a comedy, you know, laws of physics do not necessarily apply, people are overly goofy, but seriously, if someone acted like the extreme non plus ultra overboard character of Marlon Wayans in real life, it would take less than a day for him to land in an insane asylum. I don't think this movie could possibly be parodied, unless the character would grimace through 100 percent of the movie, not just 95. Also, no disrespect to the actress, but I could not understand the Darryl's shock when he first saw his 'dream girl'. I just thought, wait, what, THIS girl took his breath away? In a university campus virtually littered with pretty girls? Uh... yeah... right, also, the chemical lab is full of bubbling glow-in-the-dark colored liquids, fumes, plus the stereotypical chemyst? It's like this movie was made by two screenplay writers and two directors, one team worked on making this movie for 4 year old kids, the other team worked on making it for 16+ kids and adults, then they put it in a blender, drank it, and vomited this movie. I know, it's far easier to make a good drama, than a good comedy movie, but this piece... not just didn't make me laugh, it made me uncomfortable, irritated, nervous and angry, I felt insulted and violated. I know of no other movie that even came close to this and for achieving this, it gets a 3 instead of 1. If you have a choice to watch this movie or stare at the ceiling, I recommend the ceiling.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Its A Good Movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    piinkk_panther
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/7/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I think this movie was very well done. It had lots of laughs,an entertaining plot and good acting for the most part.It also had great actors in it (Matthew Lillard,Marlon Wayans, David Spade etc.) Wayans did an amazing job but i have to say that Lillard was the funniest, even though he didn't have a very big part. This definitely wasn't Spade's best movie though, because he came off very boring and quite annoying in most scenes. But overall, this movie was pretty good. I really liked it, and if your a Wayans or Lillard fan, I'm sure you will too. This movie is pretty much all about immature jokes, so if you are not looking for that kind of comedy, you should try a different movie.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Very funny and also touching
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    vchimpanzee
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/6/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Darryl Witherspoon is a senior economics major whose mother has been raising several children on her own in a bad section of New York City. He is very bright and has a good chance of getting out of that neighborhood. But he has bills to pay and may get kicked out of the apartment he shares with hockey player Tim. Darryl has a good chance at being the one junior analyst hired that year by the prestigious Wall Street firm Smythe-Bates. But his competition includes Scott Thorpe, whose father works for the firm. Scott belongs to the fraternity Darryl wants to join, and he thinks he is better than everyone else and that Darryl isn't good enough to be one of them. Darryl also can't make it as a hockey player. Impressing Smythe-Bates becomes less of a priority as Darryl looks for work just to keep his apartment. The university is testing an experimental drug which heightens the five senses. Despite the potential side effects, Darryl is determined to do whatever it takes to make the money he needs. One possible problem with the drug he is not told about: at too high a dosage, one of the five senses shuts down, followed by another, and another. It's not possible to predict which of the senses will go or when, but you can bet this will happen at the worst possible time. Darryl also wants to meet girls, and Janice is attractive, pleasant and intelligent. Can he win her love? Can he find a way to impress Smythe-Bates? This was very funny. I liked the concept--as in "Smallville", a shiny green liquid can give an ordinary person super powers, and it can also cause all sorts of trouble. But the movie wasn't just funny. The romantic scenes were also warm and touching. The writing was quite intelligent. Someone must have known how Wall Street operates and the economic principles that guide the financial industry. I'm surprised we haven't heard more from Marlon Wayans. Although he seemed like a silly clown at times, he really demonstrated comic abilities when Darryl struggled with the drug's problems. And he showed superior talent for both comedy and drama when the drug did what it was supposed to do. David Spade was somewhat less of a loser here than he usually is. He excels at playing jerk loser characters, but Scott had more dimension than the usual Spade type. Richard McDonagle was quite good as one of the top men at Smythe-Bates. And Tamara Taylor impressed as Janice. Esther Scott had a brief but effective performance as Darryl's determined mother. This was really worth seeing. Don't be misled by the title.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    what ever happened to humour in this world
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    stuart-1888
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/1/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I don't believe the poor rating that this film has been given. This is one of the funniest films I have seen in a long time. If people watched it with an open mind and stopped trying to serious movie critics and analyse every film they see, they would realise that it is great fun and entertaining. I have recommended this film to lots of my mates and they all thought it was side-splittingly funny. Everybody out there who gave it a crap rating should watch it again, as I pity them for their lack of humour and understanding of a good comedy. I gave this film a ten and I think it was worth every point. Anybody else agree-let me know.Vote and lets get this movie up from the paltry score of 5.4(what an insult)ENOUGH SAID. WAYANS BROTHERS ROCK.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Pathetic!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    saint405
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/6/2005
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Senseless is a tragedy film with one character being the center of attention, throw in a stupid plot about a new drug, add a subplot about trying to win a job, and why not, pluck a few good actors out of the bag and throw it into this film to make a horrible film! Marlon Waynes as Witherspoon is not funny at all. All he does is scream, cry, run around, and itch his behind! David Spade was totally useless as the evil villain Scott who was nothing but a big dork and we have the wonderful Matthew Lillard playing some junkie gay thug. Now the start of this film is okay with Marlon running around doing errands, trying to raise money for his mom and his college education by giving blood multiple times and working as a equipment manager but the film falls like a rock! No funny jokes at fall, Marlons out burst are the most idiotic things, Spade is totally uncool, and the girlfriend is just thrown in for some zest which even burns the suck fire brighter! Avoid this film at all cost, don't bother! You will get dumber by watching this movie, it's pathetic! 1 out of ten, horrible!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
 </reviews>
</filme>
