<filme>
 <id>
  1556
 </id>
 <imdburl>
  http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0112712
 </imdburl>
 <ano>
  1995
 </ano>
 <titulo>
  Condition Red
 </titulo>
 <rating>
  4.7
 </rating>
 <sinopse>
  Prison guard falls in love with inmate. She wants him to let her escape.
 </sinopse>
 <storyline>
  Prison guard falls in love with inmate. She wants him to let her escape.
 </storyline>
 <generos>
  <genero>
   Action
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Drama
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Thriller
  </genero>
 </generos>
 <keywords>
  <keyword>
   women's prison
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   female nudity
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   independent film
  </keyword>
 </keywords>
 <diretores>
  <diretor>
   Mika Kaurism&auml;ki
  </diretor>
 </diretores>
 <escritores>
  <escritor>
   Andre Degas
  </escritor>
 </escritores>
 <atores>
  <ator>
   James Russo
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Cynda Williams
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Paul Calderon
  </ator>
 </atores>
 <reviews>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I'm who's sent when the Chinese joint can't deliver
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    sol1218
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/12/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    **SPOILERS** With problems at home and on the job Philadelphia correction officer Dan Cappelli, James Russo, just want's to get away from it all and start a new life where he can get his head back together. Being locked up with hardened criminals for as much as 12 hours a day has brutalized Dan to the point where he's on the verge of becoming one himself. It's after beating unconscious a crazed inmate who attacked his fellow correction officer and almost sawed his arm off that Dan was transfered to the womens section of the prison. It's at the womens section of the prison that Dan became involved with inmate Gidell Ryan, Cynda Williams, whom he started to have a secret relationship with. That spelled the end of Dan's career as a correction officer as well as him becoming a fugitive from the law that he was sworn to uphold. Powerful prison drama with Office Carpelli getting in a bit, to say the least, over his head with his prison girlfriend Gidell who's past, despite him checking up on her, was soon to become his future. Gidell being involved with her boyfriend nightclub owner and coke sniffing Angel Delgardo, Paul Calderon, had taken the rap for him in a money laundering scheme. This lead all the way up to Angel's boss Victor Kline,Victor Argo, a prominent Philadelphia politician with his eye on City Hall in him getting elected mayor. ***SPOILER ALERT*** Thinking that Gidell was really in love with him Dan went so far, after being suspended for attacking Angel, as sneaking her out of prison and then planing to go together with her down to Mexico. Dan was soon to find out that his not so well thought out plan was dead in the water just as his prison fugitive Gidell's love was for him. Dan's life was going down the drain as soon as we first saw him with him turning to both abusing prison inmates and drinking booze as the only outlet he had in keeping from completely cracking up. Dan's mother Ethel Mea, Anna Minot, was also draining his emotions in her being in a hospice for terminal patients knowing that she has no hope of recovering from her illness. About the only person who really loved Dan his next door neighbor Rose, Dierdre Lewis, was ignored by him and eventually dropped Dan when she found out, by accident, that he was having an affair with Gidell. It was either by accident or by fate that Dan's involvement with Gidell, as well as his mom passing away, turned out to free him from the pressures that he found himself in and were slowly driving him to over the edge. And in the end with him for the first time in the movie being free Dan can finally get his both act and life together.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    What? A prison movie with no shower scene!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    lastliberal
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/3/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I first saw Cynda Williams in One False Move and i was hooked. She is a raving beauty and can act too. Naturally, I grabbed this DVD as soon as I could. Unfortunately, like Greed, it didn't live up to the potential. The main problem was the lack of real support for Williams. James Russo (you might remember him as Mikey Tandino in Beverly Hills Cop) hasn't really gotten any better in a lead role. he just didn't display any real emotion in this movie. Yeah, he looked energetic enough when he was getting it on with Williams, but she can inspire the best in all of us. Outside of that, he was just a drunken prison guard who liked to beat on people. I am sure there are thousands of those available for casting. The back story for Williams was also weak. It was there, but it just wasn't fleshed out enough. And, the ending. Oh, the ending is a mess. Who in the world could believe that a prison guard with a drinking problem would have enough money to flee to Mexico? What was he going to live off? His looks? I'm not buying it. Watch it for Cynda Williams because there is nothing else here.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    condition: good
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    pierre nay (pnay75-1@noos.fr)
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/4/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It is a low-budget movie, but expertly directed: for instance , with few actors and means the atmosphere in the prisons is effectively rendered. The movie in fact consists of three roles only ( the late Victor Argo being seen for very few minutes), but they are all well played. Paul Calderon is quite believable as a slimy gangster. I confess that I did not know Cinda Williams before, and found her very attractive in a sultry way, but also quite convincing. The best however is James Russo, who is really outstanding, using only his gimlet eyes and clenched jaws. *** Spoilers: while you expect Russo to be broken by the death of the loved one, the unexpected but appropriate end helps greatly to make a success of Condition Red
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Bad DVD Transfer
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Tall Pall
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/11/2003
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The movie is pretty good but it looks horrible on DVD. All you see is artifacts and blocks. Its was also transfered 4:3 ratio. If you want to see this movie get the VHS instead. The DVD looks like a movie recorded off TV in EP mode
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Mediocre yet endearing.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    chthon2
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/6/2003
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Dan Capelli (James Russo) is a prison guard with a major attitude problem. After repeatedly getting too violent with inmates, he is temporarily transferred to duty in a women's prison. There, he meets Gidell (Cynda Williams), a stressed out inmate who initially just tries to make small talk with him. Dan tries to maintain detached from Gidell despite how he may really feel, but when Gidell's boyfriend Angel (James Calderon) comes into the picture, things seem to change. This is a strange movie. Independent films have this strange effect on me - even if they aren't too good, if they're character driven little plots, I get sucked in no matter what. From a technical sense, this film isn't that great. It's a character driven story with underdeveloped characters, and a movie with no plot that still manages to have plot holes. But, I couldn't help it. There was something about it's low budget-ness that I liked. Maybe it was knowing that this was such a small film that I was seeing something perhaps only a handful of other people had ever seen. James Calderon really changed for this role. I'm pretty sure he's Puerto Rican, but he looked African-American in this film. Strange what makeup can do. He and Victor Argo are too good actors who were underused in this movie. Cynda Williams is also good when she has stuff to work with, but like Kris Kristofferson, she's a performer who has had her fair share of characters that you just can't go anywhere with. But, James Russo's monologue at the end of this film makes up for all of that. Strange, how a good monologue can greatly improve a movie's quality. This one is good to watch on the movie channels if you're up after midnight and no one else is home.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Made for TV - Finnish TV
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    pkeyes
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/8/2001
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I saw this movie last night thinking it may be a good watch. I was wrong. Maybe in Finland can a prison guard practically walk out of a maximum security facility with a female prisoner "wrapped around his arms"(his girlfriend as well...) The gun fight at the airport was amusing. All that gunfire and not one shell casing could be seen from the guns or on the floor. Plot 2 - Action 4 - Acting 1. James Russo, time to get a real job.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
 </reviews>
</filme>
