<filme>
 <id>
  1558
 </id>
 <imdburl>
  http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0048956
 </imdburl>
 <ano>
  1956
 </ano>
 <titulo>
  Aparajito
 </titulo>
 <rating>
  7.9
 </rating>
 <sinopse>
  A boy leaves home to study in Calcutta, while his mother must face a life alone.
 </sinopse>
 <storyline>
  After living awhile in Benares, 10 year old Apu and his mother move in with her uncle in a small Bengali village. Apu enters a local school, where he does well. By the time he graduates, he has a scholarship to study at a college in Calcutta. So off he goes. His mother is torn by his leaving, and by his growing independence. She loves her son very much and wants him to succeed, but she does not want to be left alone.
 </storyline>
 <generos>
  <genero>
   Drama
  </genero>
 </generos>
 <keywords>
  <keyword>
   benares
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   school
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   family relationships
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   1920s
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   india
  </keyword>
 </keywords>
 <diretores>
  <diretor>
   Satyajit Ray
  </diretor>
 </diretores>
 <escritores>
  <escritor>
   Bibhutibhushan Bandyopadhyay
  </escritor>
  <escritor>
   Kanailal Basu
  </escritor>
 </escritores>
 <atores>
  <ator>
   Smaran Ghosal
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Kamala Adhikari
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Lalchand Banerjee
  </ator>
 </atores>
 <reviews>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    In a simple world, Apu lives a profound life and Satyajit Ray captures his Apu's transition wonderfully in Pather Panchali's sequel, Aparajito
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    sashank_kini-1
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The sun wakes up in the land of Benaras. An aged temple priest scatters seeds for the pigeons. Men take their morning dip in the holy river bordering a ghat (series of steps). Women wash their clothes in the same waters. A couple of pehelwans (wrestlers) exercise with gadas (heavy Indian club) close to the river banks. Priests sit close by sermonizing to their loyal devotees. Ships can be heard at a distance. It is morning. Have we never seen a morning like this? We probably have, at least most who live or have lived in India. Yet why do we watch this morning with a quaint fascination? This is because Satyajit Ray doesn't regard his morning sequence as an establishment shot as most directors would  his camera gazes with wonderment at how life begins in the land of Benaras, and that gives his morning a wholly distinctive identity. We find young Apu walking beside the ghat one morning, passing by the chanting priests and their devotees and stopping where a pehelwan is exercising. He fixedly gazes at the gada which the hefty pehelwan is swinging around his body, and then leaves. After his father's untimely demise, he reluctantly becomes a priest at the insistence of a male relative. But he seems to have little interest in this, as evident in a scene where he watches, in his priest's attire, a couple of young boys his age tumbling and gamboling happily at a distance and then follows them after ditching his dhoti. He watches as they enter a school and then at night asks his mother whether he can join the same school. Once he gets admission, he's found to be a bright student who can recite lok-geet (folk music) fluently, and we realize maybe his short stint as a priest did pay off well. Apu's world is simple, yet his life is profound. There isn't explicit symbolism anywhere yet but we know how symbolic each event in his journey is, as evident from the paragraph above. Moving to a big city like Benares from a tiny village like Nischindipur, living the city life shortly till the death of his father, moving to another village called Dewanpur, attending a school nearby and earning a scholarship, moving to Calcutta for further studies with little enthusiasm to return to the dismal village life are covered in Aparajito. Apu's thinking, values and priorities blossom as his life passes these phases; take a scene in the film where Apu, in his teens, watches a couple of street children performing but finds their act uninteresting and leaves. Had this been young Apu, he'd be very enthused by their performance and watched it till the end. Aparajito is Apu All Grown Up. His self-sacrificing mother Sarbajaya gives him all her hard-earned money so he can move to Calcutta, and she surrenders herself to a life of loneliness. Apu's priorities shift towards college studies and printing press work, and he only visits her once in every few months. Satyajit Ray uses still shots to capture her emotions and actress Karuna Banerjee's eyes speak volumes; her memorable 'Opu!' for calling Apu (Bengalis usually pronounce many of their words with an 'O' intonation) stayed with me long after the film ended. Apu's college life was probably the only sequence that impressed me less, only because I've already seen similar scenes in many other recent movies. But what matters at last is our strong attachment to Apu's world; we laugh with, weep for and find joy in watching his world. Part of the credit has to go to Ravi Shankar's enchanting score, dominated by sitar, flute and dholak, for creating the right mood for each scene. Satyajit Ray's Pather Panchali and Aparajito give the pleasure of experiencing the same world through his eyes. And we are swept over completely.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Induces Strong Emotions!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Tejas Nair
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The second part of the great Apu Trilogy is yet another masterpiece which depicts the pain of loneliness and losing loved ones. The story is a continuation to Pather Panchali and even if you haven't watched that, it doesn't matter. It touches your conscience - the characters, their attitude and the eventual situation - everything just makes you introspect! Aparajito or The Unvanquished has great photography of different locations include the river Ganges, screenplay is absolute perfection and the music is edible and vibrant. The plot moves you to such a great extent, you wonder or even might compare it with your life - past, present or future! That is the power of one of the greatest trilogy of all time! Watch this and get awakened! WATCH OUT FOR: the intricacy in which it is made! Can be watched with a typical Indian family? YES Language: No | Sex: No | Nudity: Mild | Violence: No
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Well crafted realism, lack of entertaining storytelling
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    dollilama
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I can appreciate the gritty realism that captures the harsh story of the young Indian man, that realistic portrait is captured, but is this portrait so entertaining and beautiful to watch? I don't think so, the film is simply boring, as much as I appreciate the craftsmanship, to adequately judge to the quality of a film one must acknowledge the ability to tell a story that is worth telling or enjoyed by the audience. For me that was not accomplished. The film is painfully slow, and other critiques have described a cinematography of beauty and awe, I was continuously disappointed by a series of shots that left me unimpressed, shots that simply contributed to the realistic grit of the film. Beautiful demonstration of reality, one could argue this, but aesthetically beautiful, the majority of shots were not.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Haunting and Unvanquished
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    surit87
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/7/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I truly believe that there cannot be a better film that describes life in one hour and forty minutes. Life is sorrow, despair, pain and loss. Then there are moments of celebration, these moments renew hope. 'Aparajito' blends all these emotions and create a haunting story - one that will refuse to leave your thoughts. Apu is a small boy who lives in poverty with his parents. We watch him grow into a dreamy teenager and we sympathize with him and his mother. There is hope for him, but hope draws him further and further away from his mother and then we are moved by his mother's loneliness. Simple as it may seem, there is much complexity underneath. That is the sheer genius of Satyajit Ray who directed this movie on a thin budget. In my opinion this is the best film in 'The Apu Trilogy' and Mr. Satyajit Ray's most powerful work. The actors, especially Karuna Banerjee (who plays Apu's mother) deserve applause.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An effortless masterpiece
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bbrooks94
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/5/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The second in Satyajit Ray's Apu Trilogy comes after Pather Panchali. widely regarded as one of the gemstones of Asian cinema and near impossible to top in terms of emotional power and aesthetic beauty. Yet, Aparajito comes very close. The film opens with Apu and his family (or more aptly mother and father), having moved from the countryside village, living in an apartment in the city. Very quickly, things take a turn for the worse, and tragic circumstances force Apu and his mother, one of the most tragic figures in cinema, to move back to the village. Things brighten up once more for Apu after he discovers he has a yearning for education and subsequently moves to Calcutta to study years later, but hardship and tragedy are never far from this film. It's beautifully shot, and Ray effortlessly makes the move from the tranquillity of natural scenery to the hectic alleyways of urban India. Acting is superb, especially from Karuna Banerjee towards the end of the film. The segment focusing on Apu's alienation from his mother is heart-breaking yet somehow very inevitable. It's an incredibly sad film at heart, despite the moments of comedy. It's overriding message is one of caution. We must balance our desire for discovery and success with emotional, deeper riches such as human intimacy. Perfection.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Better as a movie than the first one.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Boba_Fett1138
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/9/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Overall this movie was a better made one than the first movie out of the trilogy; "Pather Panchali". Seems like they had a bigger budget to spend this time, which really helps this movie. The story flows also better and is overall more interesting one this time as well, in my opinion. The first movie was still mostly one about growing up, while this one is more a coming-of-age story. It has less sidetracks and characters to distract from the main plot-line, which again is kept as simple as possible. It's why it works out well, though in the end some things fall kind of short, since they don't feel all that likely. It's because this movie took more of a cinematic approach to things, so the story and all of its emotions and drama are also being put on a bit thick. In that regard alone this movie is being a bit weaker and less effective than the first one. Nevertheless, the overall story still flows better and is more pleasant to follow. It definitely helps with this that the story was just more interesting to follow. Director Satyajit Ray inserted some experience he had on his own during his life in this movie as well, though the source material is still being based on the novel written by Bibhutibhushan Bandyopadhyay. This movie is actually being a combination of the last part of the first novel and the first half of the second one. The third movie out of the trilogy, "Apur Sansar", wraps up the all of the stories. Technically this is a better made movie but it's also a great looking one as well, visually. This time the movie for large part gets also set in the big town, which is a quite beautiful sight and captures what life must had been like for the average struggling citizen back then, in India. A nice done drama. 8/10 http://bobafett1138.blogspot.com/
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Aparajito
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Jackson Booth-Millard
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/7/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Aparajito, or The Unvanquished if you want, is the second part of director Satyajit Ray's acclaimed Apu Trilogy, all of which features in 1001 Movies You Must See Before You Die. Basically young Apu Ray (Pinaki Sengupta), mother Sarbojaya (BAFTA nominated Karuna Bannerjee) and father Harihar (Kanu Bannerjee) have settled into their new home in Benares. When going to work as a priest, ignoring his wife's advice to rest during his fever, Harihar collapses on the stairs and dies soon after. So earning the new responsibility to earn money, Sarbojaya starts working as a maid, a relative invites her and Apu to live in Dewanpur, and they settle in the village of Mansapota. Apu asks his mother to go to school, where he studies diligently and receives a scholarship to go to Calcutta, and her mother tearfully lets him leave. Now an adolescent, Apu (Smaran Ghosal), after finishing school, starts working for a printing press, and he visits mother Sarbajaya only a few times. Then Sarbajaya becomes seriously ill, but she does not write to Apu about it, and he only finds out about it when it is too late, and when he returns home she has already died. Apu is suggested by a relative to stay and work as a priest, but he decides to return to Calcutta, and performs the final rites of his mother there. Also starring Ramani Sengupta as Old Uncle Bhabataran, Charuprakash Ghosh as Nanda Babu and Subodh Ganguli as Headmaster. The performances are all very well done considering that the cast consists of non-professional actors, and the story combined with good Indian music, a little English language and a marvellous director make this really good drama. It was nominated the BAFTA for Best Film from any Source. Very good!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Tug of Life
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Magic Lamp
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/7/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Aparajito is a very simple story of a small boy growing up till he finishes his college graduation. Its really an extremely simple story. There are no dramatic twists in the plot. Its classic humdrum. And that's where the movie becomes magical and beautiful  capturing and showcasing those precious humdrum moments of life, because they come and go so rapidly one fails to have the opportunity to soak in them expansively to fully live and experience them. That is Ray's brilliance, to use film to underscore the subtle and the ethereal. The spark of childhood, the vigor of youth, the care of motherhood, the contemplation of old age, all flow through like the river. Every life has its ups and downs, some have more downs that the other. Life however, finds a way to tug along and then sometimes it doesn't.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    My favourite film of all time
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Jag85
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/3/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    After watching Pather Panchali, I watched the sequel Aparajito the next day. My only criticism with the first film was the slow pace, but it looks like Satyajit Ray improved on this aspect for the sequel and thus eliminated any pacing issues I may have had with the original. This time the story moved along at a fairly quick pace, as we see months and sometimes years go by in a matter of minutes. Although I often hear about Pather Panchali being regarded as the best in the Apu Trilogy, I personally liked Aparajito even better than the first. The story was gripping throughout the entire film, Karuna Bannerjee gave a truly Oscar-worthy performance as Apu's mother (even though it was only her second film) and the ending was just as powerful as the original (although Pather Panchali had a more powerful theme music). In fact, I might even go as far as saying Aparajito could possibly be my favourite film of all time. 10/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Somehow fails to strike the cord
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    nagsaptarshi
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/11/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Aporajito or The Unvanquishied is a little less important to me,an ardent fan of Satyajit Ray and his masterpiece Pather Panchali or The Song Of The Liitle Road as it somehow lacks the brilliant sparks of the first film of Ray.True,it has some moments of brilliance of the master filmmaker, like when Harihar dies or when Apu leaves home for Kolkata,yet somehow it fails to strike the cord.The difference of Apu's attitude while he goes for Kolkata the second time and he does not look back to wave his hands to his mother is also notable.But overall it is an ordinary story and quite banal.The acting skills of the protagonist Apu especially during his adolescent period is also far from being perfect.The pace is slow and unlike its first part you don't wait to see what happens next.However, the use of the sound of a train and Apu's attachment to it with the connection of his first sight of a train is brilliant.The story itself is ordinary and it is the director who salvages it a number of times.The death scenes become a routine in the end and you don't shed many tears in the most important death scene of the movie,i.e,Sarbojoya's death.Overall it is an average movie somehow over-hyped because of its creator.I would rather suggest you to watch Agantuk,one of Ray's most underrated movies yet one of his best works.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    In a simple world, Apu lives a profound life and Satyajit Ray captures his Apu's transition wonderfully in Pather Panchali's sequel, Aparajito
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    sashank_kini-1
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The sun wakes up in the land of Benaras. An aged temple priest scatters seeds for the pigeons. Men take their morning dip in the holy river bordering a ghat (series of steps). Women wash their clothes in the same waters. A couple of pehelwans (wrestlers) exercise with gadas (heavy Indian club) close to the river banks. Priests sit close by sermonizing to their loyal devotees. Ships can be heard at a distance. It is morning. Have we never seen a morning like this? We probably have, at least most who live or have lived in India. Yet why do we watch this morning with a quaint fascination? This is because Satyajit Ray doesn't regard his morning sequence as an establishment shot as most directors would  his camera gazes with wonderment at how life begins in the land of Benaras, and that gives his morning a wholly distinctive identity. We find young Apu walking beside the ghat one morning, passing by the chanting priests and their devotees and stopping where a pehelwan is exercising. He fixedly gazes at the gada which the hefty pehelwan is swinging around his body, and then leaves. After his father's untimely demise, he reluctantly becomes a priest at the insistence of a male relative. But he seems to have little interest in this, as evident in a scene where he watches, in his priest's attire, a couple of young boys his age tumbling and gamboling happily at a distance and then follows them after ditching his dhoti. He watches as they enter a school and then at night asks his mother whether he can join the same school. Once he gets admission, he's found to be a bright student who can recite lok-geet (folk music) fluently, and we realize maybe his short stint as a priest did pay off well. Apu's world is simple, yet his life is profound. There isn't explicit symbolism anywhere yet but we know how symbolic each event in his journey is, as evident from the paragraph above. Moving to a big city like Benares from a tiny village like Nischindipur, living the city life shortly till the death of his father, moving to another village called Dewanpur, attending a school nearby and earning a scholarship, moving to Calcutta for further studies with little enthusiasm to return to the dismal village life are covered in Aparajito. Apu's thinking, values and priorities blossom as his life passes these phases; take a scene in the film where Apu, in his teens, watches a couple of street children performing but finds their act uninteresting and leaves. Had this been young Apu, he'd be very enthused by their performance and watched it till the end. Aparajito is Apu All Grown Up. His self-sacrificing mother Sarbajaya gives him all her hard-earned money so he can move to Calcutta, and she surrenders herself to a life of loneliness. Apu's priorities shift towards college studies and printing press work, and he only visits her once in every few months. Satyajit Ray uses still shots to capture her emotions and actress Karuna Banerjee's eyes speak volumes; her memorable 'Opu!' for calling Apu (Bengalis usually pronounce many of their words with an 'O' intonation) stayed with me long after the film ended. Apu's college life was probably the only sequence that impressed me less, only because I've already seen similar scenes in many other recent movies. But what matters at last is our strong attachment to Apu's world; we laugh with, weep for and find joy in watching his world. Part of the credit has to go to Ravi Shankar's enchanting score, dominated by sitar, flute and dholak, for creating the right mood for each scene. Satyajit Ray's Pather Panchali and Aparajito give the pleasure of experiencing the same world through his eyes. And we are swept over completely.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Induces Strong Emotions!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Tejas Nair
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The second part of the great Apu Trilogy is yet another masterpiece which depicts the pain of loneliness and losing loved ones. The story is a continuation to Pather Panchali and even if you haven't watched that, it doesn't matter. It touches your conscience - the characters, their attitude and the eventual situation - everything just makes you introspect! Aparajito or The Unvanquished has great photography of different locations include the river Ganges, screenplay is absolute perfection and the music is edible and vibrant. The plot moves you to such a great extent, you wonder or even might compare it with your life - past, present or future! That is the power of one of the greatest trilogy of all time! Watch this and get awakened! WATCH OUT FOR: the intricacy in which it is made! Can be watched with a typical Indian family? YES Language: No | Sex: No | Nudity: Mild | Violence: No
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Well crafted realism, lack of entertaining storytelling
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    dollilama
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I can appreciate the gritty realism that captures the harsh story of the young Indian man, that realistic portrait is captured, but is this portrait so entertaining and beautiful to watch? I don't think so, the film is simply boring, as much as I appreciate the craftsmanship, to adequately judge to the quality of a film one must acknowledge the ability to tell a story that is worth telling or enjoyed by the audience. For me that was not accomplished. The film is painfully slow, and other critiques have described a cinematography of beauty and awe, I was continuously disappointed by a series of shots that left me unimpressed, shots that simply contributed to the realistic grit of the film. Beautiful demonstration of reality, one could argue this, but aesthetically beautiful, the majority of shots were not.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Haunting and Unvanquished
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    surit87
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/7/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I truly believe that there cannot be a better film that describes life in one hour and forty minutes. Life is sorrow, despair, pain and loss. Then there are moments of celebration, these moments renew hope. 'Aparajito' blends all these emotions and create a haunting story - one that will refuse to leave your thoughts. Apu is a small boy who lives in poverty with his parents. We watch him grow into a dreamy teenager and we sympathize with him and his mother. There is hope for him, but hope draws him further and further away from his mother and then we are moved by his mother's loneliness. Simple as it may seem, there is much complexity underneath. That is the sheer genius of Satyajit Ray who directed this movie on a thin budget. In my opinion this is the best film in 'The Apu Trilogy' and Mr. Satyajit Ray's most powerful work. The actors, especially Karuna Banerjee (who plays Apu's mother) deserve applause.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An effortless masterpiece
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bbrooks94
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/5/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The second in Satyajit Ray's Apu Trilogy comes after Pather Panchali. widely regarded as one of the gemstones of Asian cinema and near impossible to top in terms of emotional power and aesthetic beauty. Yet, Aparajito comes very close. The film opens with Apu and his family (or more aptly mother and father), having moved from the countryside village, living in an apartment in the city. Very quickly, things take a turn for the worse, and tragic circumstances force Apu and his mother, one of the most tragic figures in cinema, to move back to the village. Things brighten up once more for Apu after he discovers he has a yearning for education and subsequently moves to Calcutta to study years later, but hardship and tragedy are never far from this film. It's beautifully shot, and Ray effortlessly makes the move from the tranquillity of natural scenery to the hectic alleyways of urban India. Acting is superb, especially from Karuna Banerjee towards the end of the film. The segment focusing on Apu's alienation from his mother is heart-breaking yet somehow very inevitable. It's an incredibly sad film at heart, despite the moments of comedy. It's overriding message is one of caution. We must balance our desire for discovery and success with emotional, deeper riches such as human intimacy. Perfection.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Better as a movie than the first one.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Boba_Fett1138
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/9/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Overall this movie was a better made one than the first movie out of the trilogy; "Pather Panchali". Seems like they had a bigger budget to spend this time, which really helps this movie. The story flows also better and is overall more interesting one this time as well, in my opinion. The first movie was still mostly one about growing up, while this one is more a coming-of-age story. It has less sidetracks and characters to distract from the main plot-line, which again is kept as simple as possible. It's why it works out well, though in the end some things fall kind of short, since they don't feel all that likely. It's because this movie took more of a cinematic approach to things, so the story and all of its emotions and drama are also being put on a bit thick. In that regard alone this movie is being a bit weaker and less effective than the first one. Nevertheless, the overall story still flows better and is more pleasant to follow. It definitely helps with this that the story was just more interesting to follow. Director Satyajit Ray inserted some experience he had on his own during his life in this movie as well, though the source material is still being based on the novel written by Bibhutibhushan Bandyopadhyay. This movie is actually being a combination of the last part of the first novel and the first half of the second one. The third movie out of the trilogy, "Apur Sansar", wraps up the all of the stories. Technically this is a better made movie but it's also a great looking one as well, visually. This time the movie for large part gets also set in the big town, which is a quite beautiful sight and captures what life must had been like for the average struggling citizen back then, in India. A nice done drama. 8/10 http://bobafett1138.blogspot.com/
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Aparajito
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Jackson Booth-Millard
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/7/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Aparajito, or The Unvanquished if you want, is the second part of director Satyajit Ray's acclaimed Apu Trilogy, all of which features in 1001 Movies You Must See Before You Die. Basically young Apu Ray (Pinaki Sengupta), mother Sarbojaya (BAFTA nominated Karuna Bannerjee) and father Harihar (Kanu Bannerjee) have settled into their new home in Benares. When going to work as a priest, ignoring his wife's advice to rest during his fever, Harihar collapses on the stairs and dies soon after. So earning the new responsibility to earn money, Sarbojaya starts working as a maid, a relative invites her and Apu to live in Dewanpur, and they settle in the village of Mansapota. Apu asks his mother to go to school, where he studies diligently and receives a scholarship to go to Calcutta, and her mother tearfully lets him leave. Now an adolescent, Apu (Smaran Ghosal), after finishing school, starts working for a printing press, and he visits mother Sarbajaya only a few times. Then Sarbajaya becomes seriously ill, but she does not write to Apu about it, and he only finds out about it when it is too late, and when he returns home she has already died. Apu is suggested by a relative to stay and work as a priest, but he decides to return to Calcutta, and performs the final rites of his mother there. Also starring Ramani Sengupta as Old Uncle Bhabataran, Charuprakash Ghosh as Nanda Babu and Subodh Ganguli as Headmaster. The performances are all very well done considering that the cast consists of non-professional actors, and the story combined with good Indian music, a little English language and a marvellous director make this really good drama. It was nominated the BAFTA for Best Film from any Source. Very good!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Tug of Life
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Magic Lamp
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/7/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Aparajito is a very simple story of a small boy growing up till he finishes his college graduation. Its really an extremely simple story. There are no dramatic twists in the plot. Its classic humdrum. And that's where the movie becomes magical and beautiful  capturing and showcasing those precious humdrum moments of life, because they come and go so rapidly one fails to have the opportunity to soak in them expansively to fully live and experience them. That is Ray's brilliance, to use film to underscore the subtle and the ethereal. The spark of childhood, the vigor of youth, the care of motherhood, the contemplation of old age, all flow through like the river. Every life has its ups and downs, some have more downs that the other. Life however, finds a way to tug along and then sometimes it doesn't.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    My favourite film of all time
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Jag85
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/3/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    After watching Pather Panchali, I watched the sequel Aparajito the next day. My only criticism with the first film was the slow pace, but it looks like Satyajit Ray improved on this aspect for the sequel and thus eliminated any pacing issues I may have had with the original. This time the story moved along at a fairly quick pace, as we see months and sometimes years go by in a matter of minutes. Although I often hear about Pather Panchali being regarded as the best in the Apu Trilogy, I personally liked Aparajito even better than the first. The story was gripping throughout the entire film, Karuna Bannerjee gave a truly Oscar-worthy performance as Apu's mother (even though it was only her second film) and the ending was just as powerful as the original (although Pather Panchali had a more powerful theme music). In fact, I might even go as far as saying Aparajito could possibly be my favourite film of all time. 10/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Somehow fails to strike the cord
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    nagsaptarshi
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/11/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Aporajito or The Unvanquishied is a little less important to me,an ardent fan of Satyajit Ray and his masterpiece Pather Panchali or The Song Of The Liitle Road as it somehow lacks the brilliant sparks of the first film of Ray.True,it has some moments of brilliance of the master filmmaker, like when Harihar dies or when Apu leaves home for Kolkata,yet somehow it fails to strike the cord.The difference of Apu's attitude while he goes for Kolkata the second time and he does not look back to wave his hands to his mother is also notable.But overall it is an ordinary story and quite banal.The acting skills of the protagonist Apu especially during his adolescent period is also far from being perfect.The pace is slow and unlike its first part you don't wait to see what happens next.However, the use of the sound of a train and Apu's attachment to it with the connection of his first sight of a train is brilliant.The story itself is ordinary and it is the director who salvages it a number of times.The death scenes become a routine in the end and you don't shed many tears in the most important death scene of the movie,i.e,Sarbojoya's death.Overall it is an average movie somehow over-hyped because of its creator.I would rather suggest you to watch Agantuk,one of Ray's most underrated movies yet one of his best works.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    In a simple world, Apu lives a profound life and Satyajit Ray captures his Apu's transition wonderfully in Pather Panchali's sequel, Aparajito
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    sashank_kini-1
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The sun wakes up in the land of Benaras. An aged temple priest scatters seeds for the pigeons. Men take their morning dip in the holy river bordering a ghat (series of steps). Women wash their clothes in the same waters. A couple of pehelwans (wrestlers) exercise with gadas (heavy Indian club) close to the river banks. Priests sit close by sermonizing to their loyal devotees. Ships can be heard at a distance. It is morning. Have we never seen a morning like this? We probably have, at least most who live or have lived in India. Yet why do we watch this morning with a quaint fascination? This is because Satyajit Ray doesn't regard his morning sequence as an establishment shot as most directors would  his camera gazes with wonderment at how life begins in the land of Benaras, and that gives his morning a wholly distinctive identity. We find young Apu walking beside the ghat one morning, passing by the chanting priests and their devotees and stopping where a pehelwan is exercising. He fixedly gazes at the gada which the hefty pehelwan is swinging around his body, and then leaves. After his father's untimely demise, he reluctantly becomes a priest at the insistence of a male relative. But he seems to have little interest in this, as evident in a scene where he watches, in his priest's attire, a couple of young boys his age tumbling and gamboling happily at a distance and then follows them after ditching his dhoti. He watches as they enter a school and then at night asks his mother whether he can join the same school. Once he gets admission, he's found to be a bright student who can recite lok-geet (folk music) fluently, and we realize maybe his short stint as a priest did pay off well. Apu's world is simple, yet his life is profound. There isn't explicit symbolism anywhere yet but we know how symbolic each event in his journey is, as evident from the paragraph above. Moving to a big city like Benares from a tiny village like Nischindipur, living the city life shortly till the death of his father, moving to another village called Dewanpur, attending a school nearby and earning a scholarship, moving to Calcutta for further studies with little enthusiasm to return to the dismal village life are covered in Aparajito. Apu's thinking, values and priorities blossom as his life passes these phases; take a scene in the film where Apu, in his teens, watches a couple of street children performing but finds their act uninteresting and leaves. Had this been young Apu, he'd be very enthused by their performance and watched it till the end. Aparajito is Apu All Grown Up. His self-sacrificing mother Sarbajaya gives him all her hard-earned money so he can move to Calcutta, and she surrenders herself to a life of loneliness. Apu's priorities shift towards college studies and printing press work, and he only visits her once in every few months. Satyajit Ray uses still shots to capture her emotions and actress Karuna Banerjee's eyes speak volumes; her memorable 'Opu!' for calling Apu (Bengalis usually pronounce many of their words with an 'O' intonation) stayed with me long after the film ended. Apu's college life was probably the only sequence that impressed me less, only because I've already seen similar scenes in many other recent movies. But what matters at last is our strong attachment to Apu's world; we laugh with, weep for and find joy in watching his world. Part of the credit has to go to Ravi Shankar's enchanting score, dominated by sitar, flute and dholak, for creating the right mood for each scene. Satyajit Ray's Pather Panchali and Aparajito give the pleasure of experiencing the same world through his eyes. And we are swept over completely.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Induces Strong Emotions!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Tejas Nair
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The second part of the great Apu Trilogy is yet another masterpiece which depicts the pain of loneliness and losing loved ones. The story is a continuation to Pather Panchali and even if you haven't watched that, it doesn't matter. It touches your conscience - the characters, their attitude and the eventual situation - everything just makes you introspect! Aparajito or The Unvanquished has great photography of different locations include the river Ganges, screenplay is absolute perfection and the music is edible and vibrant. The plot moves you to such a great extent, you wonder or even might compare it with your life - past, present or future! That is the power of one of the greatest trilogy of all time! Watch this and get awakened! WATCH OUT FOR: the intricacy in which it is made! Can be watched with a typical Indian family? YES Language: No | Sex: No | Nudity: Mild | Violence: No
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Well crafted realism, lack of entertaining storytelling
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    dollilama
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I can appreciate the gritty realism that captures the harsh story of the young Indian man, that realistic portrait is captured, but is this portrait so entertaining and beautiful to watch? I don't think so, the film is simply boring, as much as I appreciate the craftsmanship, to adequately judge to the quality of a film one must acknowledge the ability to tell a story that is worth telling or enjoyed by the audience. For me that was not accomplished. The film is painfully slow, and other critiques have described a cinematography of beauty and awe, I was continuously disappointed by a series of shots that left me unimpressed, shots that simply contributed to the realistic grit of the film. Beautiful demonstration of reality, one could argue this, but aesthetically beautiful, the majority of shots were not.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Haunting and Unvanquished
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    surit87
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/7/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I truly believe that there cannot be a better film that describes life in one hour and forty minutes. Life is sorrow, despair, pain and loss. Then there are moments of celebration, these moments renew hope. 'Aparajito' blends all these emotions and create a haunting story - one that will refuse to leave your thoughts. Apu is a small boy who lives in poverty with his parents. We watch him grow into a dreamy teenager and we sympathize with him and his mother. There is hope for him, but hope draws him further and further away from his mother and then we are moved by his mother's loneliness. Simple as it may seem, there is much complexity underneath. That is the sheer genius of Satyajit Ray who directed this movie on a thin budget. In my opinion this is the best film in 'The Apu Trilogy' and Mr. Satyajit Ray's most powerful work. The actors, especially Karuna Banerjee (who plays Apu's mother) deserve applause.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An effortless masterpiece
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bbrooks94
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/5/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The second in Satyajit Ray's Apu Trilogy comes after Pather Panchali. widely regarded as one of the gemstones of Asian cinema and near impossible to top in terms of emotional power and aesthetic beauty. Yet, Aparajito comes very close. The film opens with Apu and his family (or more aptly mother and father), having moved from the countryside village, living in an apartment in the city. Very quickly, things take a turn for the worse, and tragic circumstances force Apu and his mother, one of the most tragic figures in cinema, to move back to the village. Things brighten up once more for Apu after he discovers he has a yearning for education and subsequently moves to Calcutta to study years later, but hardship and tragedy are never far from this film. It's beautifully shot, and Ray effortlessly makes the move from the tranquillity of natural scenery to the hectic alleyways of urban India. Acting is superb, especially from Karuna Banerjee towards the end of the film. The segment focusing on Apu's alienation from his mother is heart-breaking yet somehow very inevitable. It's an incredibly sad film at heart, despite the moments of comedy. It's overriding message is one of caution. We must balance our desire for discovery and success with emotional, deeper riches such as human intimacy. Perfection.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Better as a movie than the first one.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Boba_Fett1138
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/9/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Overall this movie was a better made one than the first movie out of the trilogy; "Pather Panchali". Seems like they had a bigger budget to spend this time, which really helps this movie. The story flows also better and is overall more interesting one this time as well, in my opinion. The first movie was still mostly one about growing up, while this one is more a coming-of-age story. It has less sidetracks and characters to distract from the main plot-line, which again is kept as simple as possible. It's why it works out well, though in the end some things fall kind of short, since they don't feel all that likely. It's because this movie took more of a cinematic approach to things, so the story and all of its emotions and drama are also being put on a bit thick. In that regard alone this movie is being a bit weaker and less effective than the first one. Nevertheless, the overall story still flows better and is more pleasant to follow. It definitely helps with this that the story was just more interesting to follow. Director Satyajit Ray inserted some experience he had on his own during his life in this movie as well, though the source material is still being based on the novel written by Bibhutibhushan Bandyopadhyay. This movie is actually being a combination of the last part of the first novel and the first half of the second one. The third movie out of the trilogy, "Apur Sansar", wraps up the all of the stories. Technically this is a better made movie but it's also a great looking one as well, visually. This time the movie for large part gets also set in the big town, which is a quite beautiful sight and captures what life must had been like for the average struggling citizen back then, in India. A nice done drama. 8/10 http://bobafett1138.blogspot.com/
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Aparajito
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Jackson Booth-Millard
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/7/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Aparajito, or The Unvanquished if you want, is the second part of director Satyajit Ray's acclaimed Apu Trilogy, all of which features in 1001 Movies You Must See Before You Die. Basically young Apu Ray (Pinaki Sengupta), mother Sarbojaya (BAFTA nominated Karuna Bannerjee) and father Harihar (Kanu Bannerjee) have settled into their new home in Benares. When going to work as a priest, ignoring his wife's advice to rest during his fever, Harihar collapses on the stairs and dies soon after. So earning the new responsibility to earn money, Sarbojaya starts working as a maid, a relative invites her and Apu to live in Dewanpur, and they settle in the village of Mansapota. Apu asks his mother to go to school, where he studies diligently and receives a scholarship to go to Calcutta, and her mother tearfully lets him leave. Now an adolescent, Apu (Smaran Ghosal), after finishing school, starts working for a printing press, and he visits mother Sarbajaya only a few times. Then Sarbajaya becomes seriously ill, but she does not write to Apu about it, and he only finds out about it when it is too late, and when he returns home she has already died. Apu is suggested by a relative to stay and work as a priest, but he decides to return to Calcutta, and performs the final rites of his mother there. Also starring Ramani Sengupta as Old Uncle Bhabataran, Charuprakash Ghosh as Nanda Babu and Subodh Ganguli as Headmaster. The performances are all very well done considering that the cast consists of non-professional actors, and the story combined with good Indian music, a little English language and a marvellous director make this really good drama. It was nominated the BAFTA for Best Film from any Source. Very good!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Tug of Life
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Magic Lamp
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/7/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Aparajito is a very simple story of a small boy growing up till he finishes his college graduation. Its really an extremely simple story. There are no dramatic twists in the plot. Its classic humdrum. And that's where the movie becomes magical and beautiful  capturing and showcasing those precious humdrum moments of life, because they come and go so rapidly one fails to have the opportunity to soak in them expansively to fully live and experience them. That is Ray's brilliance, to use film to underscore the subtle and the ethereal. The spark of childhood, the vigor of youth, the care of motherhood, the contemplation of old age, all flow through like the river. Every life has its ups and downs, some have more downs that the other. Life however, finds a way to tug along and then sometimes it doesn't.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    My favourite film of all time
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Jag85
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/3/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    After watching Pather Panchali, I watched the sequel Aparajito the next day. My only criticism with the first film was the slow pace, but it looks like Satyajit Ray improved on this aspect for the sequel and thus eliminated any pacing issues I may have had with the original. This time the story moved along at a fairly quick pace, as we see months and sometimes years go by in a matter of minutes. Although I often hear about Pather Panchali being regarded as the best in the Apu Trilogy, I personally liked Aparajito even better than the first. The story was gripping throughout the entire film, Karuna Bannerjee gave a truly Oscar-worthy performance as Apu's mother (even though it was only her second film) and the ending was just as powerful as the original (although Pather Panchali had a more powerful theme music). In fact, I might even go as far as saying Aparajito could possibly be my favourite film of all time. 10/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Somehow fails to strike the cord
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    nagsaptarshi
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/11/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Aporajito or The Unvanquishied is a little less important to me,an ardent fan of Satyajit Ray and his masterpiece Pather Panchali or The Song Of The Liitle Road as it somehow lacks the brilliant sparks of the first film of Ray.True,it has some moments of brilliance of the master filmmaker, like when Harihar dies or when Apu leaves home for Kolkata,yet somehow it fails to strike the cord.The difference of Apu's attitude while he goes for Kolkata the second time and he does not look back to wave his hands to his mother is also notable.But overall it is an ordinary story and quite banal.The acting skills of the protagonist Apu especially during his adolescent period is also far from being perfect.The pace is slow and unlike its first part you don't wait to see what happens next.However, the use of the sound of a train and Apu's attachment to it with the connection of his first sight of a train is brilliant.The story itself is ordinary and it is the director who salvages it a number of times.The death scenes become a routine in the end and you don't shed many tears in the most important death scene of the movie,i.e,Sarbojoya's death.Overall it is an average movie somehow over-hyped because of its creator.I would rather suggest you to watch Agantuk,one of Ray's most underrated movies yet one of his best works.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
 </reviews>
</filme>
