<filme>
 <id>
  1569
 </id>
 <imdburl>
  http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0094265
 </imdburl>
 <ano>
  1987
 </ano>
 <titulo>
  La vie est belle
 </titulo>
 <rating>
  5.3
 </rating>
 <sinopse>
  Kourou comes from a village to Kinshasa, Zaire's capital and the center of World Beat; music is in his heart and he has big dreams. Right away he gets a job as a domestic for Mamou, the ... &nbsp;&raquo;
 </sinopse>
 <storyline>
  Kourou comes from a village to Kinshasa, Zaire's capital and the center of World Beat; music is in his heart and he has big dreams. Right away he gets a job as a domestic for Mamou, the loud wife of a club owner, and he falls in love with Kabibi, a virginal young woman who wants to be a secretary. Meanwhile, Nvouandou, the club owner, childless after twenty years of marriage, wants a second wife and determines to marry Kabibi. Mamou pretends to approve of the match, but behind her husband's back, she pushes Kabibi into the arms of Kourou. Can Kourou win Kabibi's hand and fulfill his dreams of being a singer; can Mamou recapture the affections of Nvouandou?
 </storyline>
 <generos>
  <genero>
   Comedy
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Drama
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Musical
  </genero>
 </generos>
 <keywords>
  <keyword>
   zaire
  </keyword>
 </keywords>
 <diretores>
  <diretor>
   Beno&icirc;t Lamy
  </diretor>
  <diretor>
   Mweze Ngangura
  </diretor>
 </diretores>
 <escritores>
  <escritor>
   Beno&icirc;t Lamy
  </escritor>
  <escritor>
   Maryse Le&oacute;n Garc&iacute;a
  </escritor>
 </escritores>
 <atores>
  <ator>
   Papa Wemba
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Bibi Krubwa
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Landu Nzunzimbu Matshia
  </ator>
 </atores>
 <reviews>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Very good film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    thedirector101
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/2/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The film I found was very high lighting of the then Congo. The characters were very well played. I gave it a 9 from 10 because there were parts where the story did not match and therefore had a space in the story line. But this might be only because of the formats I have gotten used to because of watching American cinema, where most things are tied together in a useful way to tell the story. I am from Canada but have visited Africa several times and this film makes me want to go back. The film and story line gives you a very good look into Africana life as I have seen there in my travels to the western coast. The film is very good, and I recommend this film to any who want to see African film at it's best. Well done!! Thedirector101
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    while far from great, it's a good film from Zaire
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    planktonrules
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/3/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The average Western viewer will probably not get much out of this film. Given that in general we tend to have the attention-spans of gnats and like a lot of action in our films, La Vie est belle is a pretty forgettable film. BUT, it is an important film for a couple reason. First, teens could benefit from learning about African life and customs, so it can be recommended on that level. Also, for those who like international cinema, you'll probably have a higher tolerance for its lower production values and mundane nature of the plot--you don't need explosions and big-name actors to get you to watch a film. And, in either of these instances, the film will satisfy. It is a cute little movie about a man who wants to get married to wife #2 (while still married to wife #1--a custom that is not unheard of in many societies). Unfortunately, his poor ex-servant also wants this lady and does what he can to steal her from the rich man. Well, despite all this, in the end everyone seems pretty happy and the music ends. The film is lively, features a lot of modern tribally influenced music and an unusual plot.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Fun and frolics in Zaire
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    njaj1
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/11/2005
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A simple tale, and a well-rehearsed one perhaps. A young man from the country travels to the 'big city' and tries out his luck making music. It's lively, colourful, constantly moving and musically enjoyable. The characters tend to border on caricatures (clearly deliberately so), and the overwhelming cheerfulness and optimism of the movie makes for an enjoyable time. It's not the ideal choice for anyone looking for a profound and revealing account of life in Zaire, it's much too frivolous for that. On the other hand it does provide a revealing sketch of street-life in Kinshasa which viewers from outside Africa may appreciate.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Documentary-like views of Kinshasa
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    William J. Fickling (wfickling@sc.rr.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/4/2001
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This film is memorable only because you get a chance to see firsthand what the Congo (then Zaire) really looks like. Also, the music is passable. Otherwise, the story is hard to follow, the characters are easy to confuse, and the outcome is ultimately very predictable. But I'm not sorry I saw it, largely because of its documentary-like realism.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
 </reviews>
</filme>
