<filme>
 <id>
  157
 </id>
 <imdburl>
  http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0091763
 </imdburl>
 <ano>
  1986
 </ano>
 <titulo>
  Platoon
 </titulo>
 <rating>
  8.2
 </rating>
 <sinopse>
  A young recruit in Vietnam faces a moral crisis when confronted with the horrors of war and the duality of man.
 </sinopse>
 <storyline>
  Chris Taylor is a young, naive American who gives up college and volunteers for combat in Vietnam. Upon arrival, he quickly discovers that his presence is quite nonessential, and is considered insignificant to the other soldiers, as he has not fought for as long as the rest of them and felt the effects of combat. Chris has two non-commissioned officers, the ill-tempered and indestructible Staff Sergeant Robert Barnes and the more pleasant and cooperative Sergeant Elias Grodin. A line is drawn between the two NCOs and a number of men in the platoon when an illegal killing occurs during a village raid. As the war continues, Chris himself draws towards psychological meltdown. And as he struggles for survival, he soon realizes he is fighting two battles, the conflict with the enemy and the conflict between the men within his platoon.
 </storyline>
 <generos>
  <genero>
   Action
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Drama
  </genero>
  <genero>
   War
  </genero>
 </generos>
 <keywords>
  <keyword>
   vietnam
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   combat
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   soldier
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   village
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   battle
  </keyword>
 </keywords>
 <diretores>
  <diretor>
   Oliver Stone
  </diretor>
 </diretores>
 <escritores>
  <escritor>
   Oliver Stone
  </escritor>
 </escritores>
 <atores>
  <ator>
   Charlie Sheen
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Tom Berenger
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Willem Dafoe
  </ator>
 </atores>
 <reviews>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Brilliantly Done
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    davorinlonac
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Hello fellow readers, this is a review of a film I had already reviewed but decided my old review was too dull so here is my new and improved Platoon review. Platoon is one of my favorite movies of all time for numerous reasons which will be shared throughout this review. First of all, it has my favorite soundtrack ever produced in a film, and shows you the real truth of what really happened in the war. There was a grotesque village scene which was hard to watch somehow. Willem Dafoe, Tom Berenger and Charlie sheen give on of their richest performances in my favorite Oliver stone film ever! The film was brilliantly done and can very well be the closest film which I could consider my favorite. The film is a great piece of cinema and will always be...
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Possibly Oliver Stone's best
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    sme_no_densetsu
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    To be quite honest, the first time I saw Oliver Stone's "Platoon" I was disappointed. Perhaps it was the fact that the presence of Charlie Sheen in the lead role invited comparison to "Apocalypse Now", starring his dad. However, even though both are war movies set in Viet Nam, comparing them is like comparing apples & oranges. Stone's film is, first and foremost, a movie about the experiences of 'grunts' in this bloody conflict. In place of the surreal nature of "Apocalypse Now", Stone and technical adviser Dale Dye brought a sense of realism to the picture. That being said, while realism was enforced, Stone still managed to imbue his script with deeper meaning. The story revolves around young volunteer Chris Taylor (Charlie Sheen) as he arrives in Viet Nam and quickly becomes acquainted with the horrors of war. Apart from the enemy, there's conflict among the soldiers themselves, as a rift develops between the compassionate Sgt. Elias (Willem Dafoe) and the ruthless Sgt. Barnes (Tom Berenger). Despite the fact that Charlie Sheen is in the lead role, the acting is actually pretty strong. Berenger & Dafoe were both nominated for Academy Awards but they ended up losing to Michael Caine. The large ensemble cast includes several recognizable actors, often contributing memorable performances. Notable names include Keith David, Forest Whitaker, John C. McGinley, Kevin Dillon and even a young Johnny Depp. Stone's direction won him one of the film's four Academy Awards. Another Oscar deservedly rewarded the sound department for their contribution to the film. Also notable was the extensive (and effective) use of Samuel Barber's "Adagio for Strings". Both visually and sonically, the movie is impressive. Ultimately, "Platoon" isn't quite perfect but it's definitely good enough that I'm glad I gave it a second chance. The movie's realism is commendable and the storyline is thought-provoking. It may be no match for "Apocalypse Now" but that only means that it's just a very good movie and not a masterpiece.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    In war no one wins
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    silva-w-pius
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "First real casualty of war is innocents; the first real movie on the war in Vietnam is Platoon" That is a quote from the trailer that I felt encompassed what I felt about Platoon to a T. What makes Platoon so realistic is that it is part of those rare occasions where you have a story born from a director's firsthand experience, but that's what you get with Oliver stone, who served as an infantry soldier in Vietnam, allowing him to create an almost autobiographical account, and in some instances a documentary into the under belly and less glamour side of war  and by glamorous I mean not a place where you shot bad guys, then come home to a giant marching band and a handshake from the president, but instead it's actually a place where real and sometimes innocent people die. With so much realism it should be no surprise that Platoon won four Oscars in 86 in the best director, picture, sound and cinematography categories. Platoon tells the story of a student named Chris Taylor (Charlie Sheen) in the late 60's who joins up for the army believing in his heart that he is fulfilling his patriotic duty, and I feel in some part that deep down he believes that he will go to Vietnam fire a few bullets and return as a hero. But upon reaching, he joins up with a diverse platoon of men, in the outside world would probably never rub shoulders with, but here they move as one, lead by two men; Sgt. Barnes (Tom Berenger) a man with a scared appearance, that adds to his mystical aura of being a man that cannot be killed and the other Sgt. Elias (Willem Dafoe) who through the use of mind altering drugs is able to maintain an air of calm. But Chris Taylor's dreams of heroism are quickly obliterated as they delve deeper into enemy territory, witnessing acts of despicable evil towards his fellow man by the very same men he serves within the same platoon, making him quickly realises how naive his ideas of war as they are not a rite of passage he once thought but instead war is actually hell on earth where no side wins, captured perfectly in dark and sinister cinematography. Reading of the credits was like a who's who of Hollywood icons, it was probably one of the most successful bringing together of star names up until then, with the likes of; tom Berenger, Willem Dafoe (Born on the Fourth of July), Forest Whitaker (The Last King of Scotland), Keith David (The Thing), Johnny Depp (Pirates of the Caribbean) and Kevin Dillon. You are guaranteed to find a name amongst them that is one of your favourite actors. But in a sea of big names and future big names, I still felt Charlie Sheen (Hot Shots) was able to stand out and deliver a convincing portrayal of a conflicted man, caught up in the ultimate battle with himself as he has to choose between what's right and doing whatever it takes to survive, so basically choosing between safety of the body or safety of the mind. I also felt with such complex emotions he had to show at a drop of a hat, and doing them so well that it was a surprise and travesty that he wasn't nominated for a single big award. I really do feel that a man's innocents is truly lost in a war, and it is a shamed you don't get to see it played out on film, but that is what also makes Platoon so special because unlike previous films based on the war in Vietnam such as; Apocalypse Now, The Deer Hunter or Coming Home. Platoon is the very first not to look at the war from the wide perspective, and not get caught up in the big budget special effects. Instead it takes a profound and uncompromising leap into the very depths of the human condition; never shying away from exposing the sinister side to us such is in the case of Sgt. Barnes (Tom Berenger) and penetrating through the sense of false bravado to leaving a film offering a sincere exploration of self.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "Hell is the impossibility of reason"...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    aldinchova
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Rejoice O young man in thy youth" - Ecclesiastes. Written and directed by Oliver Stone, "Platoon" is considered as one of the best war movies ever made. Another masterpiece of the same director, also with Vietnam war topic is "Born on the Fourth of July" with Tom Cruise as Ron Kovic real life war veteran, based on true story. Oliver Stone took part in Vietnam war (he served there from September 1967. until November 1968. being wounded twice and receiving couple of military decorations for his participation). After he returned home he decided to put his war experiences into a script of fictionalized war story which many years later was transformed into a movie inspired by war experiences that Stone had in Vietnam. That was how "Platoon" was made. A story with authentic background. Not popular with US.Army because it is telling of highly negative side of the war (showing terrible war atrocities against civilians and horrors of fighting in the jungle) "Platoon" is a strong and emotional story about different characters of different people put together on inevitable collision course with each other. Those hidden virtues and faults of those people have always been in themselves, they are only emphasized in a war madness that surrounds them. Three main characters Sgt.Barnes (Tom Berenger) on one side, Sgt. Elias (Willem Dafoe) on the opposite one and private Chris Taylor (Charlie Sheen) between them come from different life backgrounds and often have opposite and confronting perceptions of the war and life itself. In every war, in every army, on both sides in every armed conflict there were always and there will always be people like three of them and people around them. Movie shows platoon divided between Elias and Barnes two centers of gravity and those who choose to be with one or the other. Sgt.Barnes is a battle hardened and ruthless warrior. A man who does n't care much for himself and others when it comes to having fire contact with the enemy. He lost his humanity and became like a blood thirsty animal itching for fighting because it is the only meaning of his life left. What kind of life and pain formed his personality we can only guess, but outside of war he has no place, he has no purpose. And he knows that. Deep inside he hates himself for what he is and he does n't care if he is going to live or get killed. He openly challenges others to take on him ("It's just me and six of you guys, come on, no one's gonna know") but they don't dare to do anything. Two statements define his character and beliefs, first - "Now, I got no fight with any man who does what he's told, but when he don't, the machine breaks down. And when the machine breaks down, we break down. And I ain't gonna allow that in any of you. Not one" and second - "You smoke this to escape from reality. Well, I don't need to do that, I am reality " which is kind of his life statement. Sgt. Elias is opposite of him. Battle hardened and experienced fighter too, but a man who can keep his balance, he will not cross the line, the point of no return that Sgt.Barnes crossed long time ago. Elias does n't have any illusions about the war, he had them on the beginning but they are lost meanwhile. As he says to Chris Taylor "We are going to lose this one" he considers it a wrong war to fight as he realized after disappointments that he had about its cause. If he lost his illusions he did not lose his humanity. A man who will do the right thing when it matters most and lose his life because of it. Chris Taylor is rebellious and idealistic person who escapes from life at home full of restrictions and rules trying to gain an experience of his own and what he finds is not quite as what he expected, if he had any idealistic illusions they are soon crushed by harsh realities of war and the way it transforms people pushing the best and worst in them to the limits of human tolerance. In the end he is left deeply traumatized with psychological scars that will take many years to heal and become bearable. Story about different characters of different people rejected by society but in war they have just what they need with some of them seeing it as a way to project worst parts of their personality and stay unpunished. As many other great movies, "Platoon" is a story about human character, about the best and worst in all of us. Part of us that makes us be the greatest humanists and part of us that makes us be the worst criminals. Chris Taylor puts it great when he says that he is "a child of two fathers - Elias and Barnes" because he has what both of them have. Humanity of Elias and killing instinct of Barnes because in the end he kills Barnes. Others are mere reflections like Sgt.O'Neill, an ordinary coward, psychopath Bunny, a dog of war released from his chains, or Rhah, King and Big Harold who can still find strength to joke after all. Joke is their best cure. For Chris and others there are many years left to heal from scars deep inside their souls as he says it in words that can be the point of the whole movie - "I think now looking back we did not fight the enemy, we fought ourselves and the enemy was in us... But be that as it may, those of us who did make it have an obligation to build again, to teach others what we know and to try with what's left of our lives to find a goodness and meaning to this life".
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of the most realistic war films I've ever seen
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    owenhjohnson
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Platoon" is one of the few fictional films that I find a realistic interpretation of war. It has a great story, characters to invest in, and the gritty reality of war. Oliver Stone accomplished that by basing the final battle on a battle he actually survived which probably added to the reality of the film because of Stone's survival of the Vietnam War. The film has many themes and realistic situations that you would find with non-fiction stories about the Vietnam War. Also, while I do not think it was needed, Tom Berenger made for an interesting antagonist in the film. In a lot of Vietnam films, there is always the hideout where a group of soldiers goes to get high or drunk and party. While there was that element in this film, it was done with grace and was not turned into a movie about a bunch of stoner-hippies in Vietnam. The imagery and actions by the characters that demonstrate some of the themes in the film are powerful and breathtaking. With the visuals and the actions, it feels like there were parts where that is how it actually happened during the war. Though the film sometimes went a little overboard to show the themes and to demonstrate the characters. The film has a great story and interesting characters with depth that does not take away from the action and reality of the actual fighting in the Vietnam War part.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Platoon - Review
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Daniel Metcalf
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Oliver Stone participated as an infantry soldier in the Vietnam War so what we see get in "Platoon" is a breathtaking look on the life of a soldier, shown through the eyes of a soldier named Chris who is portrayed young Charlie Sheen. Whilst the film largely showcases the negatives of war, the horrors that came with being a soldier and ultimately the mistake America made by fighting in Vietnam its primary agenda is not to be an anti-war film. In fact, the conflict between the Americans and the Vietnamese army is not the main focus of the film at all, instead it acts as a great backdrop to create a variety of situations that challenge the films characters in a number of different ways, and it is the actions and different attitudes of the characters that are important. Instead the film's conflict is between two camps that emerge as the American's divide over split attitudes. On one side we have Sgt. Barnes portrayed by Tom Berenger and on the other Sgt. Elias portrayed by Willem Dafoe. These two actors provide us with two fantastic performances and make the film what is it is. Elias can be viewed as the 'good' soldier, a kind, lesser-spoken sergeant who goes by the book and serves his country how he should. On the contrary we have Barnes, a man with a completely different set of morals, a loudmouthed soldier who will take action in to his own hands to do what he thinks is right. The divide occurs when Barnes becomes responsible for the massacre of a Vietnamese village, whilst others are willing to accept his actions and choose to protect him there are others who are not so willing to go along with a cover up including Elias. "Day by day, I struggle to maintain not only my strength but my sanity. It's all a blur. I have no energy to write. I don't know what's right and what's wrong anymore. The morale of the men is low. A civil war in the platoon. Half the men with Elias, half with Barnes. There's a lot of suspicion and hate. I can't believe we're fighting each other when we should be fighting them." That quote is from Chris, the young soldier who narrates the film for us through a series of letters sent back to his grandmother. He dropped out of college to join the army through choice and immediately struggles to fit in with the others, however throughout the film he progresses in to a more respected and adequate soldier. His progression is important to the film as he adapts to the harsh life and is influenced by others. The film's cinematography and editing is superb, most of the films scene take place in the thick forest, with extremely heavy rain painting a dark image for us that helps show the grim conditions the soldier's were really in. The film does not glorify war at all, there is no unnecessary action or over the top heroic scenes and instead everything seems real and sometimes it really is not pretty. Some scenes are really uncomfortable, especially those that involve the inhuman actions of Barnes that really do a good job of amplifying our disgust towards his character which is important as we side with Elias and Chris. Dafoe, Berenger and Sheen make this film what it is and ultimately the final scenes that involve them are the most iconic and memorable. Dafoe provides an unforgettable scene which I will not spoil. And one of the final scenes that Chris and Barnes share gives us satisfaction despite being brutal and far from a happy ending. I can not recommend this film enough; it is one of my favourite war films and a fantastic and emotional tale. Unlike other glorified films this one does not sacrifice its brutal and deeply affective centre for cheap affects and fake scenes. The heart of the film lies with its trio of star actors who are each brilliant as we see the real conflict that arises from the war and its affect within the platoon.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of the Greatest war Movies of all Time
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    josephledbury
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I am a big war movie fan and It think that this is one of the best war movies I've ever seen. It may not be as good as Apocalypse Now, but I think that this is defiantly one of the greatest war movies of all time. I first saw this and didn't notice that the main character was 21 year old Charlie Sheen, star of the TV show Two and a half Men, but I did recognize William Defoe from the movie Spiderman and I didn't recognize Tom berenger. But I think that the acting in this movie is so passionate and the reflection of their performances which is what makes this movie so realistic and tells the story of a awful war which should have never happened. The story is based on the actual experiences of Academy Award winning director Oliver Stone. What an experience that man had. Like I can't believe that the war was that bad and that in the jungle could make the soldiers lose their mind. It won four Academy Awards and well deserved for Best Sound, Best Editing, best director and coveted Best Picture of 1986. The soundtrack was defiantly what made this movie so dramatic and emotional for some. every time I hear that soundtrack, my heart just sinks. The soundtrack just hits me so fast and gets me caught up in the movie the moment the music starts. In the Top 250 with a rating of 8.2/10 and is in my top 20 favorite movies of all time. I just love this film whether it's been caught up in the dramatizations of how emotional this movie is or the fact that I love watching a movie with a lot of gun fighting. Great movie with passionate acting which expresses the very real dramatizations of a very emotional war and deserved the four Academy Awards it won.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Vietnam, the way it really was...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    robertalexanderlindsey
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Of all of the the endless movies made about the tragedies that took place in the jungles and cities of Vietnam from 1965-75, 'Platoon' is the only one that absolutely needs to be seen. Forget the far-out fantasies of 'Apocalypse Now', or the introspective ironies of 'The Deer Hunter', or the gung-ho, pro-war propaganda 'The Green Berets.' 'Platoon' puts you right in the middle of the action with an exhausted, grimy group of American troops in Vietnam, troops who've been slogging through the mud in fetid heat, bitten by leeches and menaced by North Vietnamese troops or Viet Cong who cold ambush them at any second, any time, anywhere. It also goes into other details; counting down days in-country, leeches, smoking pot in the barracks, malfunctioning claymore mines, and sudden ambushes while out on patrols... 'Platoon' shows how living under these conditions for months at a time could harden even the greenest of new recruits, or 'FNGs' (F---ing New Guys, as their more experienced colleagues liked to call them), and turn them into experienced killing machines, or something even worse. One example of this transformation is Staff Sgt. Bob Barnes, a toughened, bitter veteran who has seen combat since 1965. By 1967-68, the time in which the film begins, his entire face mirrors his experience, lacerated and deformed by his sufferings in combat. Barnes has become vicious, and is not above killing civilians or conveniently removing un-agreeable troops within his own platoon. One of these is Sgt. Elias, who has also seen combat in Vietnam since 1965. Elias is aware that America's strategy of 'winning hearts and minds' will be a failure, and that Barnes's methods are not only illegal, but destructive to the platoon... And these realizations are the reasons that Elias becomes one of Barnes's victims. And in the middle of all of this is Chris Taylor, a young college dropout who volunteered for duty in Vietnam. He is torn between the two sergeants, and when he realizes that Elias is his savior, he must act not as a human being, but as a soldier...
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Platoon is certainly one of the best films about Vietnam War and Oliver Stone's best.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    s13ky
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    If we talk about the war in Vietnam, we should talk about Platoon. It is certainly one of the best films about Vietnam War and in my opinion, it's absolutely Oliver Stone's best film since JFK and Nixon. Overall, apart from the credibility of the film director and also the authenticity in the depiction of the war, I find the screenplay, editing and film direction stand out above all, not to forget the all star casts of two famous method actors, Tom Berenger (possibly his best performance ever) and Willem Dafoe. To be honest, deep within my heart, "Platoon" ranked somewhere among "Apocalypse Now", "Full Metal Jacket" and "The Deer Hunter" (the latter isn't a war film) because of its raw visualization of the war horror that some consider a crime against humanity. I always get carried away by the spectacular music scoring, saddening, beautiful as well as frightening. The best music sequence would be "Adagio For Strings" by Samuel Barber and it's your task to find out which sequence. Oliver Stone really did well in bringing us the rich psychological portraits of soldiers who fought the popular war from a very interesting perspective, through the eyes of a rookie soldier (Charlie Sheen) who volunteered to defend his country, in a fight against communism. We witness the harsh time they faced as soon as they landed on the Saigon combat zone, in the jungle, with a simple mission of staying alive from day to day. The line between good and evil is the spot where Oliver Stone places the personal stories of the men whose horror and fear were their daily foods, real men who fought and died in the Vietnam War. This unnecessary war was taped in brutal realism. Awesome combat scenes, frank, hard and strangely beautiful. Robert Richardson as the cinematographer created a jaw-dropping atmosphere combining gray and bleak apocalyptic tones of the great wild landscapes. In conclusion, this is one of the greatest war films of cinema history, it contains some moving scenes and offers a realistic and cruel story of one of the greatest atrocities of humanity: wars.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Charlie Sheen's breakthrough performance!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jake-law123
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Not really big on Oliver Stone, but his depiction of the Vietnam war is brilliant in this heavy, dark tribute to the men who died in the war. Charlie Sheen, Tom Berenger, and Willam Dafoe all make one big triangle in this film, as it revolves around the conflict going on between them, and by them, I mean Willem Dafoe's squad, and Tom Berenger's squad in the Platoon, while Charlie Sheen is caught in the middle to deal with both, struggling to maintain his sanity as the depression of the war gets to him every day. All performances are excellent. Even though the beginning consists of Sheen being an innocent little girly man, the war progresses, and he becomes a brutal life risking grunt that ruthlessly kills everything in his path, showing how the war affects him mentally. The sound of the film sounds muddled every time somebody opens their mouth, not sure what Stone's intentions were, but it won the Oscar for sound, so whatever. The film isn't centered around combat, or the realism of war, it's centered around the duality of men, and how the war affects the minds of the soldiers, and the different types of soldiers that faced the war. The beginning scenes consist of the Platoon getting to know each other, leading up to one of the most infamous and controversial scenes in cinema history, the village. It's interesting to see different characters of different personalities conflict each other over being with a different squad leader, like are you guys in high school? Either way they find a way to make it more intense. Not too heavy on atmosphere, history, or in depth messaging like Apocalypse Now or The Deer Hunter, but it gets it around pretty easy, and the message about the war bringing out the best or the worst in men is carried out pretty easy also. Very excellent war film, isn't along the lines of Saving Private Ryan, (my favorite war film) but definitely give it a viewing.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Brilliantly Done
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    davorinlonac
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Hello fellow readers, this is a review of a film I had already reviewed but decided my old review was too dull so here is my new and improved Platoon review. Platoon is one of my favorite movies of all time for numerous reasons which will be shared throughout this review. First of all, it has my favorite soundtrack ever produced in a film, and shows you the real truth of what really happened in the war. There was a grotesque village scene which was hard to watch somehow. Willem Dafoe, Tom Berenger and Charlie sheen give on of their richest performances in my favorite Oliver stone film ever! The film was brilliantly done and can very well be the closest film which I could consider my favorite. The film is a great piece of cinema and will always be...
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Possibly Oliver Stone's best
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    sme_no_densetsu
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    To be quite honest, the first time I saw Oliver Stone's "Platoon" I was disappointed. Perhaps it was the fact that the presence of Charlie Sheen in the lead role invited comparison to "Apocalypse Now", starring his dad. However, even though both are war movies set in Viet Nam, comparing them is like comparing apples & oranges. Stone's film is, first and foremost, a movie about the experiences of 'grunts' in this bloody conflict. In place of the surreal nature of "Apocalypse Now", Stone and technical adviser Dale Dye brought a sense of realism to the picture. That being said, while realism was enforced, Stone still managed to imbue his script with deeper meaning. The story revolves around young volunteer Chris Taylor (Charlie Sheen) as he arrives in Viet Nam and quickly becomes acquainted with the horrors of war. Apart from the enemy, there's conflict among the soldiers themselves, as a rift develops between the compassionate Sgt. Elias (Willem Dafoe) and the ruthless Sgt. Barnes (Tom Berenger). Despite the fact that Charlie Sheen is in the lead role, the acting is actually pretty strong. Berenger & Dafoe were both nominated for Academy Awards but they ended up losing to Michael Caine. The large ensemble cast includes several recognizable actors, often contributing memorable performances. Notable names include Keith David, Forest Whitaker, John C. McGinley, Kevin Dillon and even a young Johnny Depp. Stone's direction won him one of the film's four Academy Awards. Another Oscar deservedly rewarded the sound department for their contribution to the film. Also notable was the extensive (and effective) use of Samuel Barber's "Adagio for Strings". Both visually and sonically, the movie is impressive. Ultimately, "Platoon" isn't quite perfect but it's definitely good enough that I'm glad I gave it a second chance. The movie's realism is commendable and the storyline is thought-provoking. It may be no match for "Apocalypse Now" but that only means that it's just a very good movie and not a masterpiece.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    In war no one wins
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    silva-w-pius
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "First real casualty of war is innocents; the first real movie on the war in Vietnam is Platoon" That is a quote from the trailer that I felt encompassed what I felt about Platoon to a T. What makes Platoon so realistic is that it is part of those rare occasions where you have a story born from a director's firsthand experience, but that's what you get with Oliver stone, who served as an infantry soldier in Vietnam, allowing him to create an almost autobiographical account, and in some instances a documentary into the under belly and less glamour side of war  and by glamorous I mean not a place where you shot bad guys, then come home to a giant marching band and a handshake from the president, but instead it's actually a place where real and sometimes innocent people die. With so much realism it should be no surprise that Platoon won four Oscars in 86 in the best director, picture, sound and cinematography categories. Platoon tells the story of a student named Chris Taylor (Charlie Sheen) in the late 60's who joins up for the army believing in his heart that he is fulfilling his patriotic duty, and I feel in some part that deep down he believes that he will go to Vietnam fire a few bullets and return as a hero. But upon reaching, he joins up with a diverse platoon of men, in the outside world would probably never rub shoulders with, but here they move as one, lead by two men; Sgt. Barnes (Tom Berenger) a man with a scared appearance, that adds to his mystical aura of being a man that cannot be killed and the other Sgt. Elias (Willem Dafoe) who through the use of mind altering drugs is able to maintain an air of calm. But Chris Taylor's dreams of heroism are quickly obliterated as they delve deeper into enemy territory, witnessing acts of despicable evil towards his fellow man by the very same men he serves within the same platoon, making him quickly realises how naive his ideas of war as they are not a rite of passage he once thought but instead war is actually hell on earth where no side wins, captured perfectly in dark and sinister cinematography. Reading of the credits was like a who's who of Hollywood icons, it was probably one of the most successful bringing together of star names up until then, with the likes of; tom Berenger, Willem Dafoe (Born on the Fourth of July), Forest Whitaker (The Last King of Scotland), Keith David (The Thing), Johnny Depp (Pirates of the Caribbean) and Kevin Dillon. You are guaranteed to find a name amongst them that is one of your favourite actors. But in a sea of big names and future big names, I still felt Charlie Sheen (Hot Shots) was able to stand out and deliver a convincing portrayal of a conflicted man, caught up in the ultimate battle with himself as he has to choose between what's right and doing whatever it takes to survive, so basically choosing between safety of the body or safety of the mind. I also felt with such complex emotions he had to show at a drop of a hat, and doing them so well that it was a surprise and travesty that he wasn't nominated for a single big award. I really do feel that a man's innocents is truly lost in a war, and it is a shamed you don't get to see it played out on film, but that is what also makes Platoon so special because unlike previous films based on the war in Vietnam such as; Apocalypse Now, The Deer Hunter or Coming Home. Platoon is the very first not to look at the war from the wide perspective, and not get caught up in the big budget special effects. Instead it takes a profound and uncompromising leap into the very depths of the human condition; never shying away from exposing the sinister side to us such is in the case of Sgt. Barnes (Tom Berenger) and penetrating through the sense of false bravado to leaving a film offering a sincere exploration of self.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "Hell is the impossibility of reason"...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    aldinchova
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Rejoice O young man in thy youth" - Ecclesiastes. Written and directed by Oliver Stone, "Platoon" is considered as one of the best war movies ever made. Another masterpiece of the same director, also with Vietnam war topic is "Born on the Fourth of July" with Tom Cruise as Ron Kovic real life war veteran, based on true story. Oliver Stone took part in Vietnam war (he served there from September 1967. until November 1968. being wounded twice and receiving couple of military decorations for his participation). After he returned home he decided to put his war experiences into a script of fictionalized war story which many years later was transformed into a movie inspired by war experiences that Stone had in Vietnam. That was how "Platoon" was made. A story with authentic background. Not popular with US.Army because it is telling of highly negative side of the war (showing terrible war atrocities against civilians and horrors of fighting in the jungle) "Platoon" is a strong and emotional story about different characters of different people put together on inevitable collision course with each other. Those hidden virtues and faults of those people have always been in themselves, they are only emphasized in a war madness that surrounds them. Three main characters Sgt.Barnes (Tom Berenger) on one side, Sgt. Elias (Willem Dafoe) on the opposite one and private Chris Taylor (Charlie Sheen) between them come from different life backgrounds and often have opposite and confronting perceptions of the war and life itself. In every war, in every army, on both sides in every armed conflict there were always and there will always be people like three of them and people around them. Movie shows platoon divided between Elias and Barnes two centers of gravity and those who choose to be with one or the other. Sgt.Barnes is a battle hardened and ruthless warrior. A man who does n't care much for himself and others when it comes to having fire contact with the enemy. He lost his humanity and became like a blood thirsty animal itching for fighting because it is the only meaning of his life left. What kind of life and pain formed his personality we can only guess, but outside of war he has no place, he has no purpose. And he knows that. Deep inside he hates himself for what he is and he does n't care if he is going to live or get killed. He openly challenges others to take on him ("It's just me and six of you guys, come on, no one's gonna know") but they don't dare to do anything. Two statements define his character and beliefs, first - "Now, I got no fight with any man who does what he's told, but when he don't, the machine breaks down. And when the machine breaks down, we break down. And I ain't gonna allow that in any of you. Not one" and second - "You smoke this to escape from reality. Well, I don't need to do that, I am reality " which is kind of his life statement. Sgt. Elias is opposite of him. Battle hardened and experienced fighter too, but a man who can keep his balance, he will not cross the line, the point of no return that Sgt.Barnes crossed long time ago. Elias does n't have any illusions about the war, he had them on the beginning but they are lost meanwhile. As he says to Chris Taylor "We are going to lose this one" he considers it a wrong war to fight as he realized after disappointments that he had about its cause. If he lost his illusions he did not lose his humanity. A man who will do the right thing when it matters most and lose his life because of it. Chris Taylor is rebellious and idealistic person who escapes from life at home full of restrictions and rules trying to gain an experience of his own and what he finds is not quite as what he expected, if he had any idealistic illusions they are soon crushed by harsh realities of war and the way it transforms people pushing the best and worst in them to the limits of human tolerance. In the end he is left deeply traumatized with psychological scars that will take many years to heal and become bearable. Story about different characters of different people rejected by society but in war they have just what they need with some of them seeing it as a way to project worst parts of their personality and stay unpunished. As many other great movies, "Platoon" is a story about human character, about the best and worst in all of us. Part of us that makes us be the greatest humanists and part of us that makes us be the worst criminals. Chris Taylor puts it great when he says that he is "a child of two fathers - Elias and Barnes" because he has what both of them have. Humanity of Elias and killing instinct of Barnes because in the end he kills Barnes. Others are mere reflections like Sgt.O'Neill, an ordinary coward, psychopath Bunny, a dog of war released from his chains, or Rhah, King and Big Harold who can still find strength to joke after all. Joke is their best cure. For Chris and others there are many years left to heal from scars deep inside their souls as he says it in words that can be the point of the whole movie - "I think now looking back we did not fight the enemy, we fought ourselves and the enemy was in us... But be that as it may, those of us who did make it have an obligation to build again, to teach others what we know and to try with what's left of our lives to find a goodness and meaning to this life".
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of the most realistic war films I've ever seen
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    owenhjohnson
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Platoon" is one of the few fictional films that I find a realistic interpretation of war. It has a great story, characters to invest in, and the gritty reality of war. Oliver Stone accomplished that by basing the final battle on a battle he actually survived which probably added to the reality of the film because of Stone's survival of the Vietnam War. The film has many themes and realistic situations that you would find with non-fiction stories about the Vietnam War. Also, while I do not think it was needed, Tom Berenger made for an interesting antagonist in the film. In a lot of Vietnam films, there is always the hideout where a group of soldiers goes to get high or drunk and party. While there was that element in this film, it was done with grace and was not turned into a movie about a bunch of stoner-hippies in Vietnam. The imagery and actions by the characters that demonstrate some of the themes in the film are powerful and breathtaking. With the visuals and the actions, it feels like there were parts where that is how it actually happened during the war. Though the film sometimes went a little overboard to show the themes and to demonstrate the characters. The film has a great story and interesting characters with depth that does not take away from the action and reality of the actual fighting in the Vietnam War part.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Platoon - Review
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Daniel Metcalf
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Oliver Stone participated as an infantry soldier in the Vietnam War so what we see get in "Platoon" is a breathtaking look on the life of a soldier, shown through the eyes of a soldier named Chris who is portrayed young Charlie Sheen. Whilst the film largely showcases the negatives of war, the horrors that came with being a soldier and ultimately the mistake America made by fighting in Vietnam its primary agenda is not to be an anti-war film. In fact, the conflict between the Americans and the Vietnamese army is not the main focus of the film at all, instead it acts as a great backdrop to create a variety of situations that challenge the films characters in a number of different ways, and it is the actions and different attitudes of the characters that are important. Instead the film's conflict is between two camps that emerge as the American's divide over split attitudes. On one side we have Sgt. Barnes portrayed by Tom Berenger and on the other Sgt. Elias portrayed by Willem Dafoe. These two actors provide us with two fantastic performances and make the film what is it is. Elias can be viewed as the 'good' soldier, a kind, lesser-spoken sergeant who goes by the book and serves his country how he should. On the contrary we have Barnes, a man with a completely different set of morals, a loudmouthed soldier who will take action in to his own hands to do what he thinks is right. The divide occurs when Barnes becomes responsible for the massacre of a Vietnamese village, whilst others are willing to accept his actions and choose to protect him there are others who are not so willing to go along with a cover up including Elias. "Day by day, I struggle to maintain not only my strength but my sanity. It's all a blur. I have no energy to write. I don't know what's right and what's wrong anymore. The morale of the men is low. A civil war in the platoon. Half the men with Elias, half with Barnes. There's a lot of suspicion and hate. I can't believe we're fighting each other when we should be fighting them." That quote is from Chris, the young soldier who narrates the film for us through a series of letters sent back to his grandmother. He dropped out of college to join the army through choice and immediately struggles to fit in with the others, however throughout the film he progresses in to a more respected and adequate soldier. His progression is important to the film as he adapts to the harsh life and is influenced by others. The film's cinematography and editing is superb, most of the films scene take place in the thick forest, with extremely heavy rain painting a dark image for us that helps show the grim conditions the soldier's were really in. The film does not glorify war at all, there is no unnecessary action or over the top heroic scenes and instead everything seems real and sometimes it really is not pretty. Some scenes are really uncomfortable, especially those that involve the inhuman actions of Barnes that really do a good job of amplifying our disgust towards his character which is important as we side with Elias and Chris. Dafoe, Berenger and Sheen make this film what it is and ultimately the final scenes that involve them are the most iconic and memorable. Dafoe provides an unforgettable scene which I will not spoil. And one of the final scenes that Chris and Barnes share gives us satisfaction despite being brutal and far from a happy ending. I can not recommend this film enough; it is one of my favourite war films and a fantastic and emotional tale. Unlike other glorified films this one does not sacrifice its brutal and deeply affective centre for cheap affects and fake scenes. The heart of the film lies with its trio of star actors who are each brilliant as we see the real conflict that arises from the war and its affect within the platoon.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of the Greatest war Movies of all Time
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    josephledbury
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I am a big war movie fan and It think that this is one of the best war movies I've ever seen. It may not be as good as Apocalypse Now, but I think that this is defiantly one of the greatest war movies of all time. I first saw this and didn't notice that the main character was 21 year old Charlie Sheen, star of the TV show Two and a half Men, but I did recognize William Defoe from the movie Spiderman and I didn't recognize Tom berenger. But I think that the acting in this movie is so passionate and the reflection of their performances which is what makes this movie so realistic and tells the story of a awful war which should have never happened. The story is based on the actual experiences of Academy Award winning director Oliver Stone. What an experience that man had. Like I can't believe that the war was that bad and that in the jungle could make the soldiers lose their mind. It won four Academy Awards and well deserved for Best Sound, Best Editing, best director and coveted Best Picture of 1986. The soundtrack was defiantly what made this movie so dramatic and emotional for some. every time I hear that soundtrack, my heart just sinks. The soundtrack just hits me so fast and gets me caught up in the movie the moment the music starts. In the Top 250 with a rating of 8.2/10 and is in my top 20 favorite movies of all time. I just love this film whether it's been caught up in the dramatizations of how emotional this movie is or the fact that I love watching a movie with a lot of gun fighting. Great movie with passionate acting which expresses the very real dramatizations of a very emotional war and deserved the four Academy Awards it won.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Vietnam, the way it really was...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    robertalexanderlindsey
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Of all of the the endless movies made about the tragedies that took place in the jungles and cities of Vietnam from 1965-75, 'Platoon' is the only one that absolutely needs to be seen. Forget the far-out fantasies of 'Apocalypse Now', or the introspective ironies of 'The Deer Hunter', or the gung-ho, pro-war propaganda 'The Green Berets.' 'Platoon' puts you right in the middle of the action with an exhausted, grimy group of American troops in Vietnam, troops who've been slogging through the mud in fetid heat, bitten by leeches and menaced by North Vietnamese troops or Viet Cong who cold ambush them at any second, any time, anywhere. It also goes into other details; counting down days in-country, leeches, smoking pot in the barracks, malfunctioning claymore mines, and sudden ambushes while out on patrols... 'Platoon' shows how living under these conditions for months at a time could harden even the greenest of new recruits, or 'FNGs' (F---ing New Guys, as their more experienced colleagues liked to call them), and turn them into experienced killing machines, or something even worse. One example of this transformation is Staff Sgt. Bob Barnes, a toughened, bitter veteran who has seen combat since 1965. By 1967-68, the time in which the film begins, his entire face mirrors his experience, lacerated and deformed by his sufferings in combat. Barnes has become vicious, and is not above killing civilians or conveniently removing un-agreeable troops within his own platoon. One of these is Sgt. Elias, who has also seen combat in Vietnam since 1965. Elias is aware that America's strategy of 'winning hearts and minds' will be a failure, and that Barnes's methods are not only illegal, but destructive to the platoon... And these realizations are the reasons that Elias becomes one of Barnes's victims. And in the middle of all of this is Chris Taylor, a young college dropout who volunteered for duty in Vietnam. He is torn between the two sergeants, and when he realizes that Elias is his savior, he must act not as a human being, but as a soldier...
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Platoon is certainly one of the best films about Vietnam War and Oliver Stone's best.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    s13ky
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    If we talk about the war in Vietnam, we should talk about Platoon. It is certainly one of the best films about Vietnam War and in my opinion, it's absolutely Oliver Stone's best film since JFK and Nixon. Overall, apart from the credibility of the film director and also the authenticity in the depiction of the war, I find the screenplay, editing and film direction stand out above all, not to forget the all star casts of two famous method actors, Tom Berenger (possibly his best performance ever) and Willem Dafoe. To be honest, deep within my heart, "Platoon" ranked somewhere among "Apocalypse Now", "Full Metal Jacket" and "The Deer Hunter" (the latter isn't a war film) because of its raw visualization of the war horror that some consider a crime against humanity. I always get carried away by the spectacular music scoring, saddening, beautiful as well as frightening. The best music sequence would be "Adagio For Strings" by Samuel Barber and it's your task to find out which sequence. Oliver Stone really did well in bringing us the rich psychological portraits of soldiers who fought the popular war from a very interesting perspective, through the eyes of a rookie soldier (Charlie Sheen) who volunteered to defend his country, in a fight against communism. We witness the harsh time they faced as soon as they landed on the Saigon combat zone, in the jungle, with a simple mission of staying alive from day to day. The line between good and evil is the spot where Oliver Stone places the personal stories of the men whose horror and fear were their daily foods, real men who fought and died in the Vietnam War. This unnecessary war was taped in brutal realism. Awesome combat scenes, frank, hard and strangely beautiful. Robert Richardson as the cinematographer created a jaw-dropping atmosphere combining gray and bleak apocalyptic tones of the great wild landscapes. In conclusion, this is one of the greatest war films of cinema history, it contains some moving scenes and offers a realistic and cruel story of one of the greatest atrocities of humanity: wars.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Charlie Sheen's breakthrough performance!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jake-law123
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Not really big on Oliver Stone, but his depiction of the Vietnam war is brilliant in this heavy, dark tribute to the men who died in the war. Charlie Sheen, Tom Berenger, and Willam Dafoe all make one big triangle in this film, as it revolves around the conflict going on between them, and by them, I mean Willem Dafoe's squad, and Tom Berenger's squad in the Platoon, while Charlie Sheen is caught in the middle to deal with both, struggling to maintain his sanity as the depression of the war gets to him every day. All performances are excellent. Even though the beginning consists of Sheen being an innocent little girly man, the war progresses, and he becomes a brutal life risking grunt that ruthlessly kills everything in his path, showing how the war affects him mentally. The sound of the film sounds muddled every time somebody opens their mouth, not sure what Stone's intentions were, but it won the Oscar for sound, so whatever. The film isn't centered around combat, or the realism of war, it's centered around the duality of men, and how the war affects the minds of the soldiers, and the different types of soldiers that faced the war. The beginning scenes consist of the Platoon getting to know each other, leading up to one of the most infamous and controversial scenes in cinema history, the village. It's interesting to see different characters of different personalities conflict each other over being with a different squad leader, like are you guys in high school? Either way they find a way to make it more intense. Not too heavy on atmosphere, history, or in depth messaging like Apocalypse Now or The Deer Hunter, but it gets it around pretty easy, and the message about the war bringing out the best or the worst in men is carried out pretty easy also. Very excellent war film, isn't along the lines of Saving Private Ryan, (my favorite war film) but definitely give it a viewing.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Brilliantly Done
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    davorinlonac
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Hello fellow readers, this is a review of a film I had already reviewed but decided my old review was too dull so here is my new and improved Platoon review. Platoon is one of my favorite movies of all time for numerous reasons which will be shared throughout this review. First of all, it has my favorite soundtrack ever produced in a film, and shows you the real truth of what really happened in the war. There was a grotesque village scene which was hard to watch somehow. Willem Dafoe, Tom Berenger and Charlie sheen give on of their richest performances in my favorite Oliver stone film ever! The film was brilliantly done and can very well be the closest film which I could consider my favorite. The film is a great piece of cinema and will always be...
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Possibly Oliver Stone's best
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    sme_no_densetsu
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    To be quite honest, the first time I saw Oliver Stone's "Platoon" I was disappointed. Perhaps it was the fact that the presence of Charlie Sheen in the lead role invited comparison to "Apocalypse Now", starring his dad. However, even though both are war movies set in Viet Nam, comparing them is like comparing apples & oranges. Stone's film is, first and foremost, a movie about the experiences of 'grunts' in this bloody conflict. In place of the surreal nature of "Apocalypse Now", Stone and technical adviser Dale Dye brought a sense of realism to the picture. That being said, while realism was enforced, Stone still managed to imbue his script with deeper meaning. The story revolves around young volunteer Chris Taylor (Charlie Sheen) as he arrives in Viet Nam and quickly becomes acquainted with the horrors of war. Apart from the enemy, there's conflict among the soldiers themselves, as a rift develops between the compassionate Sgt. Elias (Willem Dafoe) and the ruthless Sgt. Barnes (Tom Berenger). Despite the fact that Charlie Sheen is in the lead role, the acting is actually pretty strong. Berenger & Dafoe were both nominated for Academy Awards but they ended up losing to Michael Caine. The large ensemble cast includes several recognizable actors, often contributing memorable performances. Notable names include Keith David, Forest Whitaker, John C. McGinley, Kevin Dillon and even a young Johnny Depp. Stone's direction won him one of the film's four Academy Awards. Another Oscar deservedly rewarded the sound department for their contribution to the film. Also notable was the extensive (and effective) use of Samuel Barber's "Adagio for Strings". Both visually and sonically, the movie is impressive. Ultimately, "Platoon" isn't quite perfect but it's definitely good enough that I'm glad I gave it a second chance. The movie's realism is commendable and the storyline is thought-provoking. It may be no match for "Apocalypse Now" but that only means that it's just a very good movie and not a masterpiece.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    In war no one wins
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    silva-w-pius
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "First real casualty of war is innocents; the first real movie on the war in Vietnam is Platoon" That is a quote from the trailer that I felt encompassed what I felt about Platoon to a T. What makes Platoon so realistic is that it is part of those rare occasions where you have a story born from a director's firsthand experience, but that's what you get with Oliver stone, who served as an infantry soldier in Vietnam, allowing him to create an almost autobiographical account, and in some instances a documentary into the under belly and less glamour side of war  and by glamorous I mean not a place where you shot bad guys, then come home to a giant marching band and a handshake from the president, but instead it's actually a place where real and sometimes innocent people die. With so much realism it should be no surprise that Platoon won four Oscars in 86 in the best director, picture, sound and cinematography categories. Platoon tells the story of a student named Chris Taylor (Charlie Sheen) in the late 60's who joins up for the army believing in his heart that he is fulfilling his patriotic duty, and I feel in some part that deep down he believes that he will go to Vietnam fire a few bullets and return as a hero. But upon reaching, he joins up with a diverse platoon of men, in the outside world would probably never rub shoulders with, but here they move as one, lead by two men; Sgt. Barnes (Tom Berenger) a man with a scared appearance, that adds to his mystical aura of being a man that cannot be killed and the other Sgt. Elias (Willem Dafoe) who through the use of mind altering drugs is able to maintain an air of calm. But Chris Taylor's dreams of heroism are quickly obliterated as they delve deeper into enemy territory, witnessing acts of despicable evil towards his fellow man by the very same men he serves within the same platoon, making him quickly realises how naive his ideas of war as they are not a rite of passage he once thought but instead war is actually hell on earth where no side wins, captured perfectly in dark and sinister cinematography. Reading of the credits was like a who's who of Hollywood icons, it was probably one of the most successful bringing together of star names up until then, with the likes of; tom Berenger, Willem Dafoe (Born on the Fourth of July), Forest Whitaker (The Last King of Scotland), Keith David (The Thing), Johnny Depp (Pirates of the Caribbean) and Kevin Dillon. You are guaranteed to find a name amongst them that is one of your favourite actors. But in a sea of big names and future big names, I still felt Charlie Sheen (Hot Shots) was able to stand out and deliver a convincing portrayal of a conflicted man, caught up in the ultimate battle with himself as he has to choose between what's right and doing whatever it takes to survive, so basically choosing between safety of the body or safety of the mind. I also felt with such complex emotions he had to show at a drop of a hat, and doing them so well that it was a surprise and travesty that he wasn't nominated for a single big award. I really do feel that a man's innocents is truly lost in a war, and it is a shamed you don't get to see it played out on film, but that is what also makes Platoon so special because unlike previous films based on the war in Vietnam such as; Apocalypse Now, The Deer Hunter or Coming Home. Platoon is the very first not to look at the war from the wide perspective, and not get caught up in the big budget special effects. Instead it takes a profound and uncompromising leap into the very depths of the human condition; never shying away from exposing the sinister side to us such is in the case of Sgt. Barnes (Tom Berenger) and penetrating through the sense of false bravado to leaving a film offering a sincere exploration of self.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "Hell is the impossibility of reason"...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    aldinchova
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Rejoice O young man in thy youth" - Ecclesiastes. Written and directed by Oliver Stone, "Platoon" is considered as one of the best war movies ever made. Another masterpiece of the same director, also with Vietnam war topic is "Born on the Fourth of July" with Tom Cruise as Ron Kovic real life war veteran, based on true story. Oliver Stone took part in Vietnam war (he served there from September 1967. until November 1968. being wounded twice and receiving couple of military decorations for his participation). After he returned home he decided to put his war experiences into a script of fictionalized war story which many years later was transformed into a movie inspired by war experiences that Stone had in Vietnam. That was how "Platoon" was made. A story with authentic background. Not popular with US.Army because it is telling of highly negative side of the war (showing terrible war atrocities against civilians and horrors of fighting in the jungle) "Platoon" is a strong and emotional story about different characters of different people put together on inevitable collision course with each other. Those hidden virtues and faults of those people have always been in themselves, they are only emphasized in a war madness that surrounds them. Three main characters Sgt.Barnes (Tom Berenger) on one side, Sgt. Elias (Willem Dafoe) on the opposite one and private Chris Taylor (Charlie Sheen) between them come from different life backgrounds and often have opposite and confronting perceptions of the war and life itself. In every war, in every army, on both sides in every armed conflict there were always and there will always be people like three of them and people around them. Movie shows platoon divided between Elias and Barnes two centers of gravity and those who choose to be with one or the other. Sgt.Barnes is a battle hardened and ruthless warrior. A man who does n't care much for himself and others when it comes to having fire contact with the enemy. He lost his humanity and became like a blood thirsty animal itching for fighting because it is the only meaning of his life left. What kind of life and pain formed his personality we can only guess, but outside of war he has no place, he has no purpose. And he knows that. Deep inside he hates himself for what he is and he does n't care if he is going to live or get killed. He openly challenges others to take on him ("It's just me and six of you guys, come on, no one's gonna know") but they don't dare to do anything. Two statements define his character and beliefs, first - "Now, I got no fight with any man who does what he's told, but when he don't, the machine breaks down. And when the machine breaks down, we break down. And I ain't gonna allow that in any of you. Not one" and second - "You smoke this to escape from reality. Well, I don't need to do that, I am reality " which is kind of his life statement. Sgt. Elias is opposite of him. Battle hardened and experienced fighter too, but a man who can keep his balance, he will not cross the line, the point of no return that Sgt.Barnes crossed long time ago. Elias does n't have any illusions about the war, he had them on the beginning but they are lost meanwhile. As he says to Chris Taylor "We are going to lose this one" he considers it a wrong war to fight as he realized after disappointments that he had about its cause. If he lost his illusions he did not lose his humanity. A man who will do the right thing when it matters most and lose his life because of it. Chris Taylor is rebellious and idealistic person who escapes from life at home full of restrictions and rules trying to gain an experience of his own and what he finds is not quite as what he expected, if he had any idealistic illusions they are soon crushed by harsh realities of war and the way it transforms people pushing the best and worst in them to the limits of human tolerance. In the end he is left deeply traumatized with psychological scars that will take many years to heal and become bearable. Story about different characters of different people rejected by society but in war they have just what they need with some of them seeing it as a way to project worst parts of their personality and stay unpunished. As many other great movies, "Platoon" is a story about human character, about the best and worst in all of us. Part of us that makes us be the greatest humanists and part of us that makes us be the worst criminals. Chris Taylor puts it great when he says that he is "a child of two fathers - Elias and Barnes" because he has what both of them have. Humanity of Elias and killing instinct of Barnes because in the end he kills Barnes. Others are mere reflections like Sgt.O'Neill, an ordinary coward, psychopath Bunny, a dog of war released from his chains, or Rhah, King and Big Harold who can still find strength to joke after all. Joke is their best cure. For Chris and others there are many years left to heal from scars deep inside their souls as he says it in words that can be the point of the whole movie - "I think now looking back we did not fight the enemy, we fought ourselves and the enemy was in us... But be that as it may, those of us who did make it have an obligation to build again, to teach others what we know and to try with what's left of our lives to find a goodness and meaning to this life".
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of the most realistic war films I've ever seen
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    owenhjohnson
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Platoon" is one of the few fictional films that I find a realistic interpretation of war. It has a great story, characters to invest in, and the gritty reality of war. Oliver Stone accomplished that by basing the final battle on a battle he actually survived which probably added to the reality of the film because of Stone's survival of the Vietnam War. The film has many themes and realistic situations that you would find with non-fiction stories about the Vietnam War. Also, while I do not think it was needed, Tom Berenger made for an interesting antagonist in the film. In a lot of Vietnam films, there is always the hideout where a group of soldiers goes to get high or drunk and party. While there was that element in this film, it was done with grace and was not turned into a movie about a bunch of stoner-hippies in Vietnam. The imagery and actions by the characters that demonstrate some of the themes in the film are powerful and breathtaking. With the visuals and the actions, it feels like there were parts where that is how it actually happened during the war. Though the film sometimes went a little overboard to show the themes and to demonstrate the characters. The film has a great story and interesting characters with depth that does not take away from the action and reality of the actual fighting in the Vietnam War part.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Platoon - Review
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Daniel Metcalf
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Oliver Stone participated as an infantry soldier in the Vietnam War so what we see get in "Platoon" is a breathtaking look on the life of a soldier, shown through the eyes of a soldier named Chris who is portrayed young Charlie Sheen. Whilst the film largely showcases the negatives of war, the horrors that came with being a soldier and ultimately the mistake America made by fighting in Vietnam its primary agenda is not to be an anti-war film. In fact, the conflict between the Americans and the Vietnamese army is not the main focus of the film at all, instead it acts as a great backdrop to create a variety of situations that challenge the films characters in a number of different ways, and it is the actions and different attitudes of the characters that are important. Instead the film's conflict is between two camps that emerge as the American's divide over split attitudes. On one side we have Sgt. Barnes portrayed by Tom Berenger and on the other Sgt. Elias portrayed by Willem Dafoe. These two actors provide us with two fantastic performances and make the film what is it is. Elias can be viewed as the 'good' soldier, a kind, lesser-spoken sergeant who goes by the book and serves his country how he should. On the contrary we have Barnes, a man with a completely different set of morals, a loudmouthed soldier who will take action in to his own hands to do what he thinks is right. The divide occurs when Barnes becomes responsible for the massacre of a Vietnamese village, whilst others are willing to accept his actions and choose to protect him there are others who are not so willing to go along with a cover up including Elias. "Day by day, I struggle to maintain not only my strength but my sanity. It's all a blur. I have no energy to write. I don't know what's right and what's wrong anymore. The morale of the men is low. A civil war in the platoon. Half the men with Elias, half with Barnes. There's a lot of suspicion and hate. I can't believe we're fighting each other when we should be fighting them." That quote is from Chris, the young soldier who narrates the film for us through a series of letters sent back to his grandmother. He dropped out of college to join the army through choice and immediately struggles to fit in with the others, however throughout the film he progresses in to a more respected and adequate soldier. His progression is important to the film as he adapts to the harsh life and is influenced by others. The film's cinematography and editing is superb, most of the films scene take place in the thick forest, with extremely heavy rain painting a dark image for us that helps show the grim conditions the soldier's were really in. The film does not glorify war at all, there is no unnecessary action or over the top heroic scenes and instead everything seems real and sometimes it really is not pretty. Some scenes are really uncomfortable, especially those that involve the inhuman actions of Barnes that really do a good job of amplifying our disgust towards his character which is important as we side with Elias and Chris. Dafoe, Berenger and Sheen make this film what it is and ultimately the final scenes that involve them are the most iconic and memorable. Dafoe provides an unforgettable scene which I will not spoil. And one of the final scenes that Chris and Barnes share gives us satisfaction despite being brutal and far from a happy ending. I can not recommend this film enough; it is one of my favourite war films and a fantastic and emotional tale. Unlike other glorified films this one does not sacrifice its brutal and deeply affective centre for cheap affects and fake scenes. The heart of the film lies with its trio of star actors who are each brilliant as we see the real conflict that arises from the war and its affect within the platoon.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of the Greatest war Movies of all Time
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    josephledbury
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I am a big war movie fan and It think that this is one of the best war movies I've ever seen. It may not be as good as Apocalypse Now, but I think that this is defiantly one of the greatest war movies of all time. I first saw this and didn't notice that the main character was 21 year old Charlie Sheen, star of the TV show Two and a half Men, but I did recognize William Defoe from the movie Spiderman and I didn't recognize Tom berenger. But I think that the acting in this movie is so passionate and the reflection of their performances which is what makes this movie so realistic and tells the story of a awful war which should have never happened. The story is based on the actual experiences of Academy Award winning director Oliver Stone. What an experience that man had. Like I can't believe that the war was that bad and that in the jungle could make the soldiers lose their mind. It won four Academy Awards and well deserved for Best Sound, Best Editing, best director and coveted Best Picture of 1986. The soundtrack was defiantly what made this movie so dramatic and emotional for some. every time I hear that soundtrack, my heart just sinks. The soundtrack just hits me so fast and gets me caught up in the movie the moment the music starts. In the Top 250 with a rating of 8.2/10 and is in my top 20 favorite movies of all time. I just love this film whether it's been caught up in the dramatizations of how emotional this movie is or the fact that I love watching a movie with a lot of gun fighting. Great movie with passionate acting which expresses the very real dramatizations of a very emotional war and deserved the four Academy Awards it won.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Vietnam, the way it really was...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    robertalexanderlindsey
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Of all of the the endless movies made about the tragedies that took place in the jungles and cities of Vietnam from 1965-75, 'Platoon' is the only one that absolutely needs to be seen. Forget the far-out fantasies of 'Apocalypse Now', or the introspective ironies of 'The Deer Hunter', or the gung-ho, pro-war propaganda 'The Green Berets.' 'Platoon' puts you right in the middle of the action with an exhausted, grimy group of American troops in Vietnam, troops who've been slogging through the mud in fetid heat, bitten by leeches and menaced by North Vietnamese troops or Viet Cong who cold ambush them at any second, any time, anywhere. It also goes into other details; counting down days in-country, leeches, smoking pot in the barracks, malfunctioning claymore mines, and sudden ambushes while out on patrols... 'Platoon' shows how living under these conditions for months at a time could harden even the greenest of new recruits, or 'FNGs' (F---ing New Guys, as their more experienced colleagues liked to call them), and turn them into experienced killing machines, or something even worse. One example of this transformation is Staff Sgt. Bob Barnes, a toughened, bitter veteran who has seen combat since 1965. By 1967-68, the time in which the film begins, his entire face mirrors his experience, lacerated and deformed by his sufferings in combat. Barnes has become vicious, and is not above killing civilians or conveniently removing un-agreeable troops within his own platoon. One of these is Sgt. Elias, who has also seen combat in Vietnam since 1965. Elias is aware that America's strategy of 'winning hearts and minds' will be a failure, and that Barnes's methods are not only illegal, but destructive to the platoon... And these realizations are the reasons that Elias becomes one of Barnes's victims. And in the middle of all of this is Chris Taylor, a young college dropout who volunteered for duty in Vietnam. He is torn between the two sergeants, and when he realizes that Elias is his savior, he must act not as a human being, but as a soldier...
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Platoon is certainly one of the best films about Vietnam War and Oliver Stone's best.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    s13ky
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    If we talk about the war in Vietnam, we should talk about Platoon. It is certainly one of the best films about Vietnam War and in my opinion, it's absolutely Oliver Stone's best film since JFK and Nixon. Overall, apart from the credibility of the film director and also the authenticity in the depiction of the war, I find the screenplay, editing and film direction stand out above all, not to forget the all star casts of two famous method actors, Tom Berenger (possibly his best performance ever) and Willem Dafoe. To be honest, deep within my heart, "Platoon" ranked somewhere among "Apocalypse Now", "Full Metal Jacket" and "The Deer Hunter" (the latter isn't a war film) because of its raw visualization of the war horror that some consider a crime against humanity. I always get carried away by the spectacular music scoring, saddening, beautiful as well as frightening. The best music sequence would be "Adagio For Strings" by Samuel Barber and it's your task to find out which sequence. Oliver Stone really did well in bringing us the rich psychological portraits of soldiers who fought the popular war from a very interesting perspective, through the eyes of a rookie soldier (Charlie Sheen) who volunteered to defend his country, in a fight against communism. We witness the harsh time they faced as soon as they landed on the Saigon combat zone, in the jungle, with a simple mission of staying alive from day to day. The line between good and evil is the spot where Oliver Stone places the personal stories of the men whose horror and fear were their daily foods, real men who fought and died in the Vietnam War. This unnecessary war was taped in brutal realism. Awesome combat scenes, frank, hard and strangely beautiful. Robert Richardson as the cinematographer created a jaw-dropping atmosphere combining gray and bleak apocalyptic tones of the great wild landscapes. In conclusion, this is one of the greatest war films of cinema history, it contains some moving scenes and offers a realistic and cruel story of one of the greatest atrocities of humanity: wars.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Charlie Sheen's breakthrough performance!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jake-law123
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Not really big on Oliver Stone, but his depiction of the Vietnam war is brilliant in this heavy, dark tribute to the men who died in the war. Charlie Sheen, Tom Berenger, and Willam Dafoe all make one big triangle in this film, as it revolves around the conflict going on between them, and by them, I mean Willem Dafoe's squad, and Tom Berenger's squad in the Platoon, while Charlie Sheen is caught in the middle to deal with both, struggling to maintain his sanity as the depression of the war gets to him every day. All performances are excellent. Even though the beginning consists of Sheen being an innocent little girly man, the war progresses, and he becomes a brutal life risking grunt that ruthlessly kills everything in his path, showing how the war affects him mentally. The sound of the film sounds muddled every time somebody opens their mouth, not sure what Stone's intentions were, but it won the Oscar for sound, so whatever. The film isn't centered around combat, or the realism of war, it's centered around the duality of men, and how the war affects the minds of the soldiers, and the different types of soldiers that faced the war. The beginning scenes consist of the Platoon getting to know each other, leading up to one of the most infamous and controversial scenes in cinema history, the village. It's interesting to see different characters of different personalities conflict each other over being with a different squad leader, like are you guys in high school? Either way they find a way to make it more intense. Not too heavy on atmosphere, history, or in depth messaging like Apocalypse Now or The Deer Hunter, but it gets it around pretty easy, and the message about the war bringing out the best or the worst in men is carried out pretty easy also. Very excellent war film, isn't along the lines of Saving Private Ryan, (my favorite war film) but definitely give it a viewing.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Brilliantly Done
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    davorinlonac
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Hello fellow readers, this is a review of a film I had already reviewed but decided my old review was too dull so here is my new and improved Platoon review. Platoon is one of my favorite movies of all time for numerous reasons which will be shared throughout this review. First of all, it has my favorite soundtrack ever produced in a film, and shows you the real truth of what really happened in the war. There was a grotesque village scene which was hard to watch somehow. Willem Dafoe, Tom Berenger and Charlie sheen give on of their richest performances in my favorite Oliver stone film ever! The film was brilliantly done and can very well be the closest film which I could consider my favorite. The film is a great piece of cinema and will always be...
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Possibly Oliver Stone's best
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    sme_no_densetsu
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    To be quite honest, the first time I saw Oliver Stone's "Platoon" I was disappointed. Perhaps it was the fact that the presence of Charlie Sheen in the lead role invited comparison to "Apocalypse Now", starring his dad. However, even though both are war movies set in Viet Nam, comparing them is like comparing apples & oranges. Stone's film is, first and foremost, a movie about the experiences of 'grunts' in this bloody conflict. In place of the surreal nature of "Apocalypse Now", Stone and technical adviser Dale Dye brought a sense of realism to the picture. That being said, while realism was enforced, Stone still managed to imbue his script with deeper meaning. The story revolves around young volunteer Chris Taylor (Charlie Sheen) as he arrives in Viet Nam and quickly becomes acquainted with the horrors of war. Apart from the enemy, there's conflict among the soldiers themselves, as a rift develops between the compassionate Sgt. Elias (Willem Dafoe) and the ruthless Sgt. Barnes (Tom Berenger). Despite the fact that Charlie Sheen is in the lead role, the acting is actually pretty strong. Berenger & Dafoe were both nominated for Academy Awards but they ended up losing to Michael Caine. The large ensemble cast includes several recognizable actors, often contributing memorable performances. Notable names include Keith David, Forest Whitaker, John C. McGinley, Kevin Dillon and even a young Johnny Depp. Stone's direction won him one of the film's four Academy Awards. Another Oscar deservedly rewarded the sound department for their contribution to the film. Also notable was the extensive (and effective) use of Samuel Barber's "Adagio for Strings". Both visually and sonically, the movie is impressive. Ultimately, "Platoon" isn't quite perfect but it's definitely good enough that I'm glad I gave it a second chance. The movie's realism is commendable and the storyline is thought-provoking. It may be no match for "Apocalypse Now" but that only means that it's just a very good movie and not a masterpiece.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    In war no one wins
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    silva-w-pius
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "First real casualty of war is innocents; the first real movie on the war in Vietnam is Platoon" That is a quote from the trailer that I felt encompassed what I felt about Platoon to a T. What makes Platoon so realistic is that it is part of those rare occasions where you have a story born from a director's firsthand experience, but that's what you get with Oliver stone, who served as an infantry soldier in Vietnam, allowing him to create an almost autobiographical account, and in some instances a documentary into the under belly and less glamour side of war  and by glamorous I mean not a place where you shot bad guys, then come home to a giant marching band and a handshake from the president, but instead it's actually a place where real and sometimes innocent people die. With so much realism it should be no surprise that Platoon won four Oscars in 86 in the best director, picture, sound and cinematography categories. Platoon tells the story of a student named Chris Taylor (Charlie Sheen) in the late 60's who joins up for the army believing in his heart that he is fulfilling his patriotic duty, and I feel in some part that deep down he believes that he will go to Vietnam fire a few bullets and return as a hero. But upon reaching, he joins up with a diverse platoon of men, in the outside world would probably never rub shoulders with, but here they move as one, lead by two men; Sgt. Barnes (Tom Berenger) a man with a scared appearance, that adds to his mystical aura of being a man that cannot be killed and the other Sgt. Elias (Willem Dafoe) who through the use of mind altering drugs is able to maintain an air of calm. But Chris Taylor's dreams of heroism are quickly obliterated as they delve deeper into enemy territory, witnessing acts of despicable evil towards his fellow man by the very same men he serves within the same platoon, making him quickly realises how naive his ideas of war as they are not a rite of passage he once thought but instead war is actually hell on earth where no side wins, captured perfectly in dark and sinister cinematography. Reading of the credits was like a who's who of Hollywood icons, it was probably one of the most successful bringing together of star names up until then, with the likes of; tom Berenger, Willem Dafoe (Born on the Fourth of July), Forest Whitaker (The Last King of Scotland), Keith David (The Thing), Johnny Depp (Pirates of the Caribbean) and Kevin Dillon. You are guaranteed to find a name amongst them that is one of your favourite actors. But in a sea of big names and future big names, I still felt Charlie Sheen (Hot Shots) was able to stand out and deliver a convincing portrayal of a conflicted man, caught up in the ultimate battle with himself as he has to choose between what's right and doing whatever it takes to survive, so basically choosing between safety of the body or safety of the mind. I also felt with such complex emotions he had to show at a drop of a hat, and doing them so well that it was a surprise and travesty that he wasn't nominated for a single big award. I really do feel that a man's innocents is truly lost in a war, and it is a shamed you don't get to see it played out on film, but that is what also makes Platoon so special because unlike previous films based on the war in Vietnam such as; Apocalypse Now, The Deer Hunter or Coming Home. Platoon is the very first not to look at the war from the wide perspective, and not get caught up in the big budget special effects. Instead it takes a profound and uncompromising leap into the very depths of the human condition; never shying away from exposing the sinister side to us such is in the case of Sgt. Barnes (Tom Berenger) and penetrating through the sense of false bravado to leaving a film offering a sincere exploration of self.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "Hell is the impossibility of reason"...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    aldinchova
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Rejoice O young man in thy youth" - Ecclesiastes. Written and directed by Oliver Stone, "Platoon" is considered as one of the best war movies ever made. Another masterpiece of the same director, also with Vietnam war topic is "Born on the Fourth of July" with Tom Cruise as Ron Kovic real life war veteran, based on true story. Oliver Stone took part in Vietnam war (he served there from September 1967. until November 1968. being wounded twice and receiving couple of military decorations for his participation). After he returned home he decided to put his war experiences into a script of fictionalized war story which many years later was transformed into a movie inspired by war experiences that Stone had in Vietnam. That was how "Platoon" was made. A story with authentic background. Not popular with US.Army because it is telling of highly negative side of the war (showing terrible war atrocities against civilians and horrors of fighting in the jungle) "Platoon" is a strong and emotional story about different characters of different people put together on inevitable collision course with each other. Those hidden virtues and faults of those people have always been in themselves, they are only emphasized in a war madness that surrounds them. Three main characters Sgt.Barnes (Tom Berenger) on one side, Sgt. Elias (Willem Dafoe) on the opposite one and private Chris Taylor (Charlie Sheen) between them come from different life backgrounds and often have opposite and confronting perceptions of the war and life itself. In every war, in every army, on both sides in every armed conflict there were always and there will always be people like three of them and people around them. Movie shows platoon divided between Elias and Barnes two centers of gravity and those who choose to be with one or the other. Sgt.Barnes is a battle hardened and ruthless warrior. A man who does n't care much for himself and others when it comes to having fire contact with the enemy. He lost his humanity and became like a blood thirsty animal itching for fighting because it is the only meaning of his life left. What kind of life and pain formed his personality we can only guess, but outside of war he has no place, he has no purpose. And he knows that. Deep inside he hates himself for what he is and he does n't care if he is going to live or get killed. He openly challenges others to take on him ("It's just me and six of you guys, come on, no one's gonna know") but they don't dare to do anything. Two statements define his character and beliefs, first - "Now, I got no fight with any man who does what he's told, but when he don't, the machine breaks down. And when the machine breaks down, we break down. And I ain't gonna allow that in any of you. Not one" and second - "You smoke this to escape from reality. Well, I don't need to do that, I am reality " which is kind of his life statement. Sgt. Elias is opposite of him. Battle hardened and experienced fighter too, but a man who can keep his balance, he will not cross the line, the point of no return that Sgt.Barnes crossed long time ago. Elias does n't have any illusions about the war, he had them on the beginning but they are lost meanwhile. As he says to Chris Taylor "We are going to lose this one" he considers it a wrong war to fight as he realized after disappointments that he had about its cause. If he lost his illusions he did not lose his humanity. A man who will do the right thing when it matters most and lose his life because of it. Chris Taylor is rebellious and idealistic person who escapes from life at home full of restrictions and rules trying to gain an experience of his own and what he finds is not quite as what he expected, if he had any idealistic illusions they are soon crushed by harsh realities of war and the way it transforms people pushing the best and worst in them to the limits of human tolerance. In the end he is left deeply traumatized with psychological scars that will take many years to heal and become bearable. Story about different characters of different people rejected by society but in war they have just what they need with some of them seeing it as a way to project worst parts of their personality and stay unpunished. As many other great movies, "Platoon" is a story about human character, about the best and worst in all of us. Part of us that makes us be the greatest humanists and part of us that makes us be the worst criminals. Chris Taylor puts it great when he says that he is "a child of two fathers - Elias and Barnes" because he has what both of them have. Humanity of Elias and killing instinct of Barnes because in the end he kills Barnes. Others are mere reflections like Sgt.O'Neill, an ordinary coward, psychopath Bunny, a dog of war released from his chains, or Rhah, King and Big Harold who can still find strength to joke after all. Joke is their best cure. For Chris and others there are many years left to heal from scars deep inside their souls as he says it in words that can be the point of the whole movie - "I think now looking back we did not fight the enemy, we fought ourselves and the enemy was in us... But be that as it may, those of us who did make it have an obligation to build again, to teach others what we know and to try with what's left of our lives to find a goodness and meaning to this life".
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of the most realistic war films I've ever seen
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    owenhjohnson
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Platoon" is one of the few fictional films that I find a realistic interpretation of war. It has a great story, characters to invest in, and the gritty reality of war. Oliver Stone accomplished that by basing the final battle on a battle he actually survived which probably added to the reality of the film because of Stone's survival of the Vietnam War. The film has many themes and realistic situations that you would find with non-fiction stories about the Vietnam War. Also, while I do not think it was needed, Tom Berenger made for an interesting antagonist in the film. In a lot of Vietnam films, there is always the hideout where a group of soldiers goes to get high or drunk and party. While there was that element in this film, it was done with grace and was not turned into a movie about a bunch of stoner-hippies in Vietnam. The imagery and actions by the characters that demonstrate some of the themes in the film are powerful and breathtaking. With the visuals and the actions, it feels like there were parts where that is how it actually happened during the war. Though the film sometimes went a little overboard to show the themes and to demonstrate the characters. The film has a great story and interesting characters with depth that does not take away from the action and reality of the actual fighting in the Vietnam War part.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Platoon - Review
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Daniel Metcalf
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Oliver Stone participated as an infantry soldier in the Vietnam War so what we see get in "Platoon" is a breathtaking look on the life of a soldier, shown through the eyes of a soldier named Chris who is portrayed young Charlie Sheen. Whilst the film largely showcases the negatives of war, the horrors that came with being a soldier and ultimately the mistake America made by fighting in Vietnam its primary agenda is not to be an anti-war film. In fact, the conflict between the Americans and the Vietnamese army is not the main focus of the film at all, instead it acts as a great backdrop to create a variety of situations that challenge the films characters in a number of different ways, and it is the actions and different attitudes of the characters that are important. Instead the film's conflict is between two camps that emerge as the American's divide over split attitudes. On one side we have Sgt. Barnes portrayed by Tom Berenger and on the other Sgt. Elias portrayed by Willem Dafoe. These two actors provide us with two fantastic performances and make the film what is it is. Elias can be viewed as the 'good' soldier, a kind, lesser-spoken sergeant who goes by the book and serves his country how he should. On the contrary we have Barnes, a man with a completely different set of morals, a loudmouthed soldier who will take action in to his own hands to do what he thinks is right. The divide occurs when Barnes becomes responsible for the massacre of a Vietnamese village, whilst others are willing to accept his actions and choose to protect him there are others who are not so willing to go along with a cover up including Elias. "Day by day, I struggle to maintain not only my strength but my sanity. It's all a blur. I have no energy to write. I don't know what's right and what's wrong anymore. The morale of the men is low. A civil war in the platoon. Half the men with Elias, half with Barnes. There's a lot of suspicion and hate. I can't believe we're fighting each other when we should be fighting them." That quote is from Chris, the young soldier who narrates the film for us through a series of letters sent back to his grandmother. He dropped out of college to join the army through choice and immediately struggles to fit in with the others, however throughout the film he progresses in to a more respected and adequate soldier. His progression is important to the film as he adapts to the harsh life and is influenced by others. The film's cinematography and editing is superb, most of the films scene take place in the thick forest, with extremely heavy rain painting a dark image for us that helps show the grim conditions the soldier's were really in. The film does not glorify war at all, there is no unnecessary action or over the top heroic scenes and instead everything seems real and sometimes it really is not pretty. Some scenes are really uncomfortable, especially those that involve the inhuman actions of Barnes that really do a good job of amplifying our disgust towards his character which is important as we side with Elias and Chris. Dafoe, Berenger and Sheen make this film what it is and ultimately the final scenes that involve them are the most iconic and memorable. Dafoe provides an unforgettable scene which I will not spoil. And one of the final scenes that Chris and Barnes share gives us satisfaction despite being brutal and far from a happy ending. I can not recommend this film enough; it is one of my favourite war films and a fantastic and emotional tale. Unlike other glorified films this one does not sacrifice its brutal and deeply affective centre for cheap affects and fake scenes. The heart of the film lies with its trio of star actors who are each brilliant as we see the real conflict that arises from the war and its affect within the platoon.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of the Greatest war Movies of all Time
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    josephledbury
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I am a big war movie fan and It think that this is one of the best war movies I've ever seen. It may not be as good as Apocalypse Now, but I think that this is defiantly one of the greatest war movies of all time. I first saw this and didn't notice that the main character was 21 year old Charlie Sheen, star of the TV show Two and a half Men, but I did recognize William Defoe from the movie Spiderman and I didn't recognize Tom berenger. But I think that the acting in this movie is so passionate and the reflection of their performances which is what makes this movie so realistic and tells the story of a awful war which should have never happened. The story is based on the actual experiences of Academy Award winning director Oliver Stone. What an experience that man had. Like I can't believe that the war was that bad and that in the jungle could make the soldiers lose their mind. It won four Academy Awards and well deserved for Best Sound, Best Editing, best director and coveted Best Picture of 1986. The soundtrack was defiantly what made this movie so dramatic and emotional for some. every time I hear that soundtrack, my heart just sinks. The soundtrack just hits me so fast and gets me caught up in the movie the moment the music starts. In the Top 250 with a rating of 8.2/10 and is in my top 20 favorite movies of all time. I just love this film whether it's been caught up in the dramatizations of how emotional this movie is or the fact that I love watching a movie with a lot of gun fighting. Great movie with passionate acting which expresses the very real dramatizations of a very emotional war and deserved the four Academy Awards it won.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Vietnam, the way it really was...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    robertalexanderlindsey
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Of all of the the endless movies made about the tragedies that took place in the jungles and cities of Vietnam from 1965-75, 'Platoon' is the only one that absolutely needs to be seen. Forget the far-out fantasies of 'Apocalypse Now', or the introspective ironies of 'The Deer Hunter', or the gung-ho, pro-war propaganda 'The Green Berets.' 'Platoon' puts you right in the middle of the action with an exhausted, grimy group of American troops in Vietnam, troops who've been slogging through the mud in fetid heat, bitten by leeches and menaced by North Vietnamese troops or Viet Cong who cold ambush them at any second, any time, anywhere. It also goes into other details; counting down days in-country, leeches, smoking pot in the barracks, malfunctioning claymore mines, and sudden ambushes while out on patrols... 'Platoon' shows how living under these conditions for months at a time could harden even the greenest of new recruits, or 'FNGs' (F---ing New Guys, as their more experienced colleagues liked to call them), and turn them into experienced killing machines, or something even worse. One example of this transformation is Staff Sgt. Bob Barnes, a toughened, bitter veteran who has seen combat since 1965. By 1967-68, the time in which the film begins, his entire face mirrors his experience, lacerated and deformed by his sufferings in combat. Barnes has become vicious, and is not above killing civilians or conveniently removing un-agreeable troops within his own platoon. One of these is Sgt. Elias, who has also seen combat in Vietnam since 1965. Elias is aware that America's strategy of 'winning hearts and minds' will be a failure, and that Barnes's methods are not only illegal, but destructive to the platoon... And these realizations are the reasons that Elias becomes one of Barnes's victims. And in the middle of all of this is Chris Taylor, a young college dropout who volunteered for duty in Vietnam. He is torn between the two sergeants, and when he realizes that Elias is his savior, he must act not as a human being, but as a soldier...
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Platoon is certainly one of the best films about Vietnam War and Oliver Stone's best.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    s13ky
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    If we talk about the war in Vietnam, we should talk about Platoon. It is certainly one of the best films about Vietnam War and in my opinion, it's absolutely Oliver Stone's best film since JFK and Nixon. Overall, apart from the credibility of the film director and also the authenticity in the depiction of the war, I find the screenplay, editing and film direction stand out above all, not to forget the all star casts of two famous method actors, Tom Berenger (possibly his best performance ever) and Willem Dafoe. To be honest, deep within my heart, "Platoon" ranked somewhere among "Apocalypse Now", "Full Metal Jacket" and "The Deer Hunter" (the latter isn't a war film) because of its raw visualization of the war horror that some consider a crime against humanity. I always get carried away by the spectacular music scoring, saddening, beautiful as well as frightening. The best music sequence would be "Adagio For Strings" by Samuel Barber and it's your task to find out which sequence. Oliver Stone really did well in bringing us the rich psychological portraits of soldiers who fought the popular war from a very interesting perspective, through the eyes of a rookie soldier (Charlie Sheen) who volunteered to defend his country, in a fight against communism. We witness the harsh time they faced as soon as they landed on the Saigon combat zone, in the jungle, with a simple mission of staying alive from day to day. The line between good and evil is the spot where Oliver Stone places the personal stories of the men whose horror and fear were their daily foods, real men who fought and died in the Vietnam War. This unnecessary war was taped in brutal realism. Awesome combat scenes, frank, hard and strangely beautiful. Robert Richardson as the cinematographer created a jaw-dropping atmosphere combining gray and bleak apocalyptic tones of the great wild landscapes. In conclusion, this is one of the greatest war films of cinema history, it contains some moving scenes and offers a realistic and cruel story of one of the greatest atrocities of humanity: wars.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Charlie Sheen's breakthrough performance!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jake-law123
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Not really big on Oliver Stone, but his depiction of the Vietnam war is brilliant in this heavy, dark tribute to the men who died in the war. Charlie Sheen, Tom Berenger, and Willam Dafoe all make one big triangle in this film, as it revolves around the conflict going on between them, and by them, I mean Willem Dafoe's squad, and Tom Berenger's squad in the Platoon, while Charlie Sheen is caught in the middle to deal with both, struggling to maintain his sanity as the depression of the war gets to him every day. All performances are excellent. Even though the beginning consists of Sheen being an innocent little girly man, the war progresses, and he becomes a brutal life risking grunt that ruthlessly kills everything in his path, showing how the war affects him mentally. The sound of the film sounds muddled every time somebody opens their mouth, not sure what Stone's intentions were, but it won the Oscar for sound, so whatever. The film isn't centered around combat, or the realism of war, it's centered around the duality of men, and how the war affects the minds of the soldiers, and the different types of soldiers that faced the war. The beginning scenes consist of the Platoon getting to know each other, leading up to one of the most infamous and controversial scenes in cinema history, the village. It's interesting to see different characters of different personalities conflict each other over being with a different squad leader, like are you guys in high school? Either way they find a way to make it more intense. Not too heavy on atmosphere, history, or in depth messaging like Apocalypse Now or The Deer Hunter, but it gets it around pretty easy, and the message about the war bringing out the best or the worst in men is carried out pretty easy also. Very excellent war film, isn't along the lines of Saving Private Ryan, (my favorite war film) but definitely give it a viewing.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Brilliantly Done
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    davorinlonac
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Hello fellow readers, this is a review of a film I had already reviewed but decided my old review was too dull so here is my new and improved Platoon review. Platoon is one of my favorite movies of all time for numerous reasons which will be shared throughout this review. First of all, it has my favorite soundtrack ever produced in a film, and shows you the real truth of what really happened in the war. There was a grotesque village scene which was hard to watch somehow. Willem Dafoe, Tom Berenger and Charlie sheen give on of their richest performances in my favorite Oliver stone film ever! The film was brilliantly done and can very well be the closest film which I could consider my favorite. The film is a great piece of cinema and will always be...
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Possibly Oliver Stone's best
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    sme_no_densetsu
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    To be quite honest, the first time I saw Oliver Stone's "Platoon" I was disappointed. Perhaps it was the fact that the presence of Charlie Sheen in the lead role invited comparison to "Apocalypse Now", starring his dad. However, even though both are war movies set in Viet Nam, comparing them is like comparing apples & oranges. Stone's film is, first and foremost, a movie about the experiences of 'grunts' in this bloody conflict. In place of the surreal nature of "Apocalypse Now", Stone and technical adviser Dale Dye brought a sense of realism to the picture. That being said, while realism was enforced, Stone still managed to imbue his script with deeper meaning. The story revolves around young volunteer Chris Taylor (Charlie Sheen) as he arrives in Viet Nam and quickly becomes acquainted with the horrors of war. Apart from the enemy, there's conflict among the soldiers themselves, as a rift develops between the compassionate Sgt. Elias (Willem Dafoe) and the ruthless Sgt. Barnes (Tom Berenger). Despite the fact that Charlie Sheen is in the lead role, the acting is actually pretty strong. Berenger & Dafoe were both nominated for Academy Awards but they ended up losing to Michael Caine. The large ensemble cast includes several recognizable actors, often contributing memorable performances. Notable names include Keith David, Forest Whitaker, John C. McGinley, Kevin Dillon and even a young Johnny Depp. Stone's direction won him one of the film's four Academy Awards. Another Oscar deservedly rewarded the sound department for their contribution to the film. Also notable was the extensive (and effective) use of Samuel Barber's "Adagio for Strings". Both visually and sonically, the movie is impressive. Ultimately, "Platoon" isn't quite perfect but it's definitely good enough that I'm glad I gave it a second chance. The movie's realism is commendable and the storyline is thought-provoking. It may be no match for "Apocalypse Now" but that only means that it's just a very good movie and not a masterpiece.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    In war no one wins
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    silva-w-pius
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "First real casualty of war is innocents; the first real movie on the war in Vietnam is Platoon" That is a quote from the trailer that I felt encompassed what I felt about Platoon to a T. What makes Platoon so realistic is that it is part of those rare occasions where you have a story born from a director's firsthand experience, but that's what you get with Oliver stone, who served as an infantry soldier in Vietnam, allowing him to create an almost autobiographical account, and in some instances a documentary into the under belly and less glamour side of war  and by glamorous I mean not a place where you shot bad guys, then come home to a giant marching band and a handshake from the president, but instead it's actually a place where real and sometimes innocent people die. With so much realism it should be no surprise that Platoon won four Oscars in 86 in the best director, picture, sound and cinematography categories. Platoon tells the story of a student named Chris Taylor (Charlie Sheen) in the late 60's who joins up for the army believing in his heart that he is fulfilling his patriotic duty, and I feel in some part that deep down he believes that he will go to Vietnam fire a few bullets and return as a hero. But upon reaching, he joins up with a diverse platoon of men, in the outside world would probably never rub shoulders with, but here they move as one, lead by two men; Sgt. Barnes (Tom Berenger) a man with a scared appearance, that adds to his mystical aura of being a man that cannot be killed and the other Sgt. Elias (Willem Dafoe) who through the use of mind altering drugs is able to maintain an air of calm. But Chris Taylor's dreams of heroism are quickly obliterated as they delve deeper into enemy territory, witnessing acts of despicable evil towards his fellow man by the very same men he serves within the same platoon, making him quickly realises how naive his ideas of war as they are not a rite of passage he once thought but instead war is actually hell on earth where no side wins, captured perfectly in dark and sinister cinematography. Reading of the credits was like a who's who of Hollywood icons, it was probably one of the most successful bringing together of star names up until then, with the likes of; tom Berenger, Willem Dafoe (Born on the Fourth of July), Forest Whitaker (The Last King of Scotland), Keith David (The Thing), Johnny Depp (Pirates of the Caribbean) and Kevin Dillon. You are guaranteed to find a name amongst them that is one of your favourite actors. But in a sea of big names and future big names, I still felt Charlie Sheen (Hot Shots) was able to stand out and deliver a convincing portrayal of a conflicted man, caught up in the ultimate battle with himself as he has to choose between what's right and doing whatever it takes to survive, so basically choosing between safety of the body or safety of the mind. I also felt with such complex emotions he had to show at a drop of a hat, and doing them so well that it was a surprise and travesty that he wasn't nominated for a single big award. I really do feel that a man's innocents is truly lost in a war, and it is a shamed you don't get to see it played out on film, but that is what also makes Platoon so special because unlike previous films based on the war in Vietnam such as; Apocalypse Now, The Deer Hunter or Coming Home. Platoon is the very first not to look at the war from the wide perspective, and not get caught up in the big budget special effects. Instead it takes a profound and uncompromising leap into the very depths of the human condition; never shying away from exposing the sinister side to us such is in the case of Sgt. Barnes (Tom Berenger) and penetrating through the sense of false bravado to leaving a film offering a sincere exploration of self.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "Hell is the impossibility of reason"...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    aldinchova
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Rejoice O young man in thy youth" - Ecclesiastes. Written and directed by Oliver Stone, "Platoon" is considered as one of the best war movies ever made. Another masterpiece of the same director, also with Vietnam war topic is "Born on the Fourth of July" with Tom Cruise as Ron Kovic real life war veteran, based on true story. Oliver Stone took part in Vietnam war (he served there from September 1967. until November 1968. being wounded twice and receiving couple of military decorations for his participation). After he returned home he decided to put his war experiences into a script of fictionalized war story which many years later was transformed into a movie inspired by war experiences that Stone had in Vietnam. That was how "Platoon" was made. A story with authentic background. Not popular with US.Army because it is telling of highly negative side of the war (showing terrible war atrocities against civilians and horrors of fighting in the jungle) "Platoon" is a strong and emotional story about different characters of different people put together on inevitable collision course with each other. Those hidden virtues and faults of those people have always been in themselves, they are only emphasized in a war madness that surrounds them. Three main characters Sgt.Barnes (Tom Berenger) on one side, Sgt. Elias (Willem Dafoe) on the opposite one and private Chris Taylor (Charlie Sheen) between them come from different life backgrounds and often have opposite and confronting perceptions of the war and life itself. In every war, in every army, on both sides in every armed conflict there were always and there will always be people like three of them and people around them. Movie shows platoon divided between Elias and Barnes two centers of gravity and those who choose to be with one or the other. Sgt.Barnes is a battle hardened and ruthless warrior. A man who does n't care much for himself and others when it comes to having fire contact with the enemy. He lost his humanity and became like a blood thirsty animal itching for fighting because it is the only meaning of his life left. What kind of life and pain formed his personality we can only guess, but outside of war he has no place, he has no purpose. And he knows that. Deep inside he hates himself for what he is and he does n't care if he is going to live or get killed. He openly challenges others to take on him ("It's just me and six of you guys, come on, no one's gonna know") but they don't dare to do anything. Two statements define his character and beliefs, first - "Now, I got no fight with any man who does what he's told, but when he don't, the machine breaks down. And when the machine breaks down, we break down. And I ain't gonna allow that in any of you. Not one" and second - "You smoke this to escape from reality. Well, I don't need to do that, I am reality " which is kind of his life statement. Sgt. Elias is opposite of him. Battle hardened and experienced fighter too, but a man who can keep his balance, he will not cross the line, the point of no return that Sgt.Barnes crossed long time ago. Elias does n't have any illusions about the war, he had them on the beginning but they are lost meanwhile. As he says to Chris Taylor "We are going to lose this one" he considers it a wrong war to fight as he realized after disappointments that he had about its cause. If he lost his illusions he did not lose his humanity. A man who will do the right thing when it matters most and lose his life because of it. Chris Taylor is rebellious and idealistic person who escapes from life at home full of restrictions and rules trying to gain an experience of his own and what he finds is not quite as what he expected, if he had any idealistic illusions they are soon crushed by harsh realities of war and the way it transforms people pushing the best and worst in them to the limits of human tolerance. In the end he is left deeply traumatized with psychological scars that will take many years to heal and become bearable. Story about different characters of different people rejected by society but in war they have just what they need with some of them seeing it as a way to project worst parts of their personality and stay unpunished. As many other great movies, "Platoon" is a story about human character, about the best and worst in all of us. Part of us that makes us be the greatest humanists and part of us that makes us be the worst criminals. Chris Taylor puts it great when he says that he is "a child of two fathers - Elias and Barnes" because he has what both of them have. Humanity of Elias and killing instinct of Barnes because in the end he kills Barnes. Others are mere reflections like Sgt.O'Neill, an ordinary coward, psychopath Bunny, a dog of war released from his chains, or Rhah, King and Big Harold who can still find strength to joke after all. Joke is their best cure. For Chris and others there are many years left to heal from scars deep inside their souls as he says it in words that can be the point of the whole movie - "I think now looking back we did not fight the enemy, we fought ourselves and the enemy was in us... But be that as it may, those of us who did make it have an obligation to build again, to teach others what we know and to try with what's left of our lives to find a goodness and meaning to this life".
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of the most realistic war films I've ever seen
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    owenhjohnson
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Platoon" is one of the few fictional films that I find a realistic interpretation of war. It has a great story, characters to invest in, and the gritty reality of war. Oliver Stone accomplished that by basing the final battle on a battle he actually survived which probably added to the reality of the film because of Stone's survival of the Vietnam War. The film has many themes and realistic situations that you would find with non-fiction stories about the Vietnam War. Also, while I do not think it was needed, Tom Berenger made for an interesting antagonist in the film. In a lot of Vietnam films, there is always the hideout where a group of soldiers goes to get high or drunk and party. While there was that element in this film, it was done with grace and was not turned into a movie about a bunch of stoner-hippies in Vietnam. The imagery and actions by the characters that demonstrate some of the themes in the film are powerful and breathtaking. With the visuals and the actions, it feels like there were parts where that is how it actually happened during the war. Though the film sometimes went a little overboard to show the themes and to demonstrate the characters. The film has a great story and interesting characters with depth that does not take away from the action and reality of the actual fighting in the Vietnam War part.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Platoon - Review
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Daniel Metcalf
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Oliver Stone participated as an infantry soldier in the Vietnam War so what we see get in "Platoon" is a breathtaking look on the life of a soldier, shown through the eyes of a soldier named Chris who is portrayed young Charlie Sheen. Whilst the film largely showcases the negatives of war, the horrors that came with being a soldier and ultimately the mistake America made by fighting in Vietnam its primary agenda is not to be an anti-war film. In fact, the conflict between the Americans and the Vietnamese army is not the main focus of the film at all, instead it acts as a great backdrop to create a variety of situations that challenge the films characters in a number of different ways, and it is the actions and different attitudes of the characters that are important. Instead the film's conflict is between two camps that emerge as the American's divide over split attitudes. On one side we have Sgt. Barnes portrayed by Tom Berenger and on the other Sgt. Elias portrayed by Willem Dafoe. These two actors provide us with two fantastic performances and make the film what is it is. Elias can be viewed as the 'good' soldier, a kind, lesser-spoken sergeant who goes by the book and serves his country how he should. On the contrary we have Barnes, a man with a completely different set of morals, a loudmouthed soldier who will take action in to his own hands to do what he thinks is right. The divide occurs when Barnes becomes responsible for the massacre of a Vietnamese village, whilst others are willing to accept his actions and choose to protect him there are others who are not so willing to go along with a cover up including Elias. "Day by day, I struggle to maintain not only my strength but my sanity. It's all a blur. I have no energy to write. I don't know what's right and what's wrong anymore. The morale of the men is low. A civil war in the platoon. Half the men with Elias, half with Barnes. There's a lot of suspicion and hate. I can't believe we're fighting each other when we should be fighting them." That quote is from Chris, the young soldier who narrates the film for us through a series of letters sent back to his grandmother. He dropped out of college to join the army through choice and immediately struggles to fit in with the others, however throughout the film he progresses in to a more respected and adequate soldier. His progression is important to the film as he adapts to the harsh life and is influenced by others. The film's cinematography and editing is superb, most of the films scene take place in the thick forest, with extremely heavy rain painting a dark image for us that helps show the grim conditions the soldier's were really in. The film does not glorify war at all, there is no unnecessary action or over the top heroic scenes and instead everything seems real and sometimes it really is not pretty. Some scenes are really uncomfortable, especially those that involve the inhuman actions of Barnes that really do a good job of amplifying our disgust towards his character which is important as we side with Elias and Chris. Dafoe, Berenger and Sheen make this film what it is and ultimately the final scenes that involve them are the most iconic and memorable. Dafoe provides an unforgettable scene which I will not spoil. And one of the final scenes that Chris and Barnes share gives us satisfaction despite being brutal and far from a happy ending. I can not recommend this film enough; it is one of my favourite war films and a fantastic and emotional tale. Unlike other glorified films this one does not sacrifice its brutal and deeply affective centre for cheap affects and fake scenes. The heart of the film lies with its trio of star actors who are each brilliant as we see the real conflict that arises from the war and its affect within the platoon.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of the Greatest war Movies of all Time
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    josephledbury
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I am a big war movie fan and It think that this is one of the best war movies I've ever seen. It may not be as good as Apocalypse Now, but I think that this is defiantly one of the greatest war movies of all time. I first saw this and didn't notice that the main character was 21 year old Charlie Sheen, star of the TV show Two and a half Men, but I did recognize William Defoe from the movie Spiderman and I didn't recognize Tom berenger. But I think that the acting in this movie is so passionate and the reflection of their performances which is what makes this movie so realistic and tells the story of a awful war which should have never happened. The story is based on the actual experiences of Academy Award winning director Oliver Stone. What an experience that man had. Like I can't believe that the war was that bad and that in the jungle could make the soldiers lose their mind. It won four Academy Awards and well deserved for Best Sound, Best Editing, best director and coveted Best Picture of 1986. The soundtrack was defiantly what made this movie so dramatic and emotional for some. every time I hear that soundtrack, my heart just sinks. The soundtrack just hits me so fast and gets me caught up in the movie the moment the music starts. In the Top 250 with a rating of 8.2/10 and is in my top 20 favorite movies of all time. I just love this film whether it's been caught up in the dramatizations of how emotional this movie is or the fact that I love watching a movie with a lot of gun fighting. Great movie with passionate acting which expresses the very real dramatizations of a very emotional war and deserved the four Academy Awards it won.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Vietnam, the way it really was...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    robertalexanderlindsey
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Of all of the the endless movies made about the tragedies that took place in the jungles and cities of Vietnam from 1965-75, 'Platoon' is the only one that absolutely needs to be seen. Forget the far-out fantasies of 'Apocalypse Now', or the introspective ironies of 'The Deer Hunter', or the gung-ho, pro-war propaganda 'The Green Berets.' 'Platoon' puts you right in the middle of the action with an exhausted, grimy group of American troops in Vietnam, troops who've been slogging through the mud in fetid heat, bitten by leeches and menaced by North Vietnamese troops or Viet Cong who cold ambush them at any second, any time, anywhere. It also goes into other details; counting down days in-country, leeches, smoking pot in the barracks, malfunctioning claymore mines, and sudden ambushes while out on patrols... 'Platoon' shows how living under these conditions for months at a time could harden even the greenest of new recruits, or 'FNGs' (F---ing New Guys, as their more experienced colleagues liked to call them), and turn them into experienced killing machines, or something even worse. One example of this transformation is Staff Sgt. Bob Barnes, a toughened, bitter veteran who has seen combat since 1965. By 1967-68, the time in which the film begins, his entire face mirrors his experience, lacerated and deformed by his sufferings in combat. Barnes has become vicious, and is not above killing civilians or conveniently removing un-agreeable troops within his own platoon. One of these is Sgt. Elias, who has also seen combat in Vietnam since 1965. Elias is aware that America's strategy of 'winning hearts and minds' will be a failure, and that Barnes's methods are not only illegal, but destructive to the platoon... And these realizations are the reasons that Elias becomes one of Barnes's victims. And in the middle of all of this is Chris Taylor, a young college dropout who volunteered for duty in Vietnam. He is torn between the two sergeants, and when he realizes that Elias is his savior, he must act not as a human being, but as a soldier...
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Platoon is certainly one of the best films about Vietnam War and Oliver Stone's best.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    s13ky
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    If we talk about the war in Vietnam, we should talk about Platoon. It is certainly one of the best films about Vietnam War and in my opinion, it's absolutely Oliver Stone's best film since JFK and Nixon. Overall, apart from the credibility of the film director and also the authenticity in the depiction of the war, I find the screenplay, editing and film direction stand out above all, not to forget the all star casts of two famous method actors, Tom Berenger (possibly his best performance ever) and Willem Dafoe. To be honest, deep within my heart, "Platoon" ranked somewhere among "Apocalypse Now", "Full Metal Jacket" and "The Deer Hunter" (the latter isn't a war film) because of its raw visualization of the war horror that some consider a crime against humanity. I always get carried away by the spectacular music scoring, saddening, beautiful as well as frightening. The best music sequence would be "Adagio For Strings" by Samuel Barber and it's your task to find out which sequence. Oliver Stone really did well in bringing us the rich psychological portraits of soldiers who fought the popular war from a very interesting perspective, through the eyes of a rookie soldier (Charlie Sheen) who volunteered to defend his country, in a fight against communism. We witness the harsh time they faced as soon as they landed on the Saigon combat zone, in the jungle, with a simple mission of staying alive from day to day. The line between good and evil is the spot where Oliver Stone places the personal stories of the men whose horror and fear were their daily foods, real men who fought and died in the Vietnam War. This unnecessary war was taped in brutal realism. Awesome combat scenes, frank, hard and strangely beautiful. Robert Richardson as the cinematographer created a jaw-dropping atmosphere combining gray and bleak apocalyptic tones of the great wild landscapes. In conclusion, this is one of the greatest war films of cinema history, it contains some moving scenes and offers a realistic and cruel story of one of the greatest atrocities of humanity: wars.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Charlie Sheen's breakthrough performance!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jake-law123
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Not really big on Oliver Stone, but his depiction of the Vietnam war is brilliant in this heavy, dark tribute to the men who died in the war. Charlie Sheen, Tom Berenger, and Willam Dafoe all make one big triangle in this film, as it revolves around the conflict going on between them, and by them, I mean Willem Dafoe's squad, and Tom Berenger's squad in the Platoon, while Charlie Sheen is caught in the middle to deal with both, struggling to maintain his sanity as the depression of the war gets to him every day. All performances are excellent. Even though the beginning consists of Sheen being an innocent little girly man, the war progresses, and he becomes a brutal life risking grunt that ruthlessly kills everything in his path, showing how the war affects him mentally. The sound of the film sounds muddled every time somebody opens their mouth, not sure what Stone's intentions were, but it won the Oscar for sound, so whatever. The film isn't centered around combat, or the realism of war, it's centered around the duality of men, and how the war affects the minds of the soldiers, and the different types of soldiers that faced the war. The beginning scenes consist of the Platoon getting to know each other, leading up to one of the most infamous and controversial scenes in cinema history, the village. It's interesting to see different characters of different personalities conflict each other over being with a different squad leader, like are you guys in high school? Either way they find a way to make it more intense. Not too heavy on atmosphere, history, or in depth messaging like Apocalypse Now or The Deer Hunter, but it gets it around pretty easy, and the message about the war bringing out the best or the worst in men is carried out pretty easy also. Very excellent war film, isn't along the lines of Saving Private Ryan, (my favorite war film) but definitely give it a viewing.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Brilliantly Done
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    davorinlonac
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Hello fellow readers, this is a review of a film I had already reviewed but decided my old review was too dull so here is my new and improved Platoon review. Platoon is one of my favorite movies of all time for numerous reasons which will be shared throughout this review. First of all, it has my favorite soundtrack ever produced in a film, and shows you the real truth of what really happened in the war. There was a grotesque village scene which was hard to watch somehow. Willem Dafoe, Tom Berenger and Charlie sheen give on of their richest performances in my favorite Oliver stone film ever! The film was brilliantly done and can very well be the closest film which I could consider my favorite. The film is a great piece of cinema and will always be...
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Possibly Oliver Stone's best
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    sme_no_densetsu
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    To be quite honest, the first time I saw Oliver Stone's "Platoon" I was disappointed. Perhaps it was the fact that the presence of Charlie Sheen in the lead role invited comparison to "Apocalypse Now", starring his dad. However, even though both are war movies set in Viet Nam, comparing them is like comparing apples & oranges. Stone's film is, first and foremost, a movie about the experiences of 'grunts' in this bloody conflict. In place of the surreal nature of "Apocalypse Now", Stone and technical adviser Dale Dye brought a sense of realism to the picture. That being said, while realism was enforced, Stone still managed to imbue his script with deeper meaning. The story revolves around young volunteer Chris Taylor (Charlie Sheen) as he arrives in Viet Nam and quickly becomes acquainted with the horrors of war. Apart from the enemy, there's conflict among the soldiers themselves, as a rift develops between the compassionate Sgt. Elias (Willem Dafoe) and the ruthless Sgt. Barnes (Tom Berenger). Despite the fact that Charlie Sheen is in the lead role, the acting is actually pretty strong. Berenger & Dafoe were both nominated for Academy Awards but they ended up losing to Michael Caine. The large ensemble cast includes several recognizable actors, often contributing memorable performances. Notable names include Keith David, Forest Whitaker, John C. McGinley, Kevin Dillon and even a young Johnny Depp. Stone's direction won him one of the film's four Academy Awards. Another Oscar deservedly rewarded the sound department for their contribution to the film. Also notable was the extensive (and effective) use of Samuel Barber's "Adagio for Strings". Both visually and sonically, the movie is impressive. Ultimately, "Platoon" isn't quite perfect but it's definitely good enough that I'm glad I gave it a second chance. The movie's realism is commendable and the storyline is thought-provoking. It may be no match for "Apocalypse Now" but that only means that it's just a very good movie and not a masterpiece.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    In war no one wins
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    silva-w-pius
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "First real casualty of war is innocents; the first real movie on the war in Vietnam is Platoon" That is a quote from the trailer that I felt encompassed what I felt about Platoon to a T. What makes Platoon so realistic is that it is part of those rare occasions where you have a story born from a director's firsthand experience, but that's what you get with Oliver stone, who served as an infantry soldier in Vietnam, allowing him to create an almost autobiographical account, and in some instances a documentary into the under belly and less glamour side of war  and by glamorous I mean not a place where you shot bad guys, then come home to a giant marching band and a handshake from the president, but instead it's actually a place where real and sometimes innocent people die. With so much realism it should be no surprise that Platoon won four Oscars in 86 in the best director, picture, sound and cinematography categories. Platoon tells the story of a student named Chris Taylor (Charlie Sheen) in the late 60's who joins up for the army believing in his heart that he is fulfilling his patriotic duty, and I feel in some part that deep down he believes that he will go to Vietnam fire a few bullets and return as a hero. But upon reaching, he joins up with a diverse platoon of men, in the outside world would probably never rub shoulders with, but here they move as one, lead by two men; Sgt. Barnes (Tom Berenger) a man with a scared appearance, that adds to his mystical aura of being a man that cannot be killed and the other Sgt. Elias (Willem Dafoe) who through the use of mind altering drugs is able to maintain an air of calm. But Chris Taylor's dreams of heroism are quickly obliterated as they delve deeper into enemy territory, witnessing acts of despicable evil towards his fellow man by the very same men he serves within the same platoon, making him quickly realises how naive his ideas of war as they are not a rite of passage he once thought but instead war is actually hell on earth where no side wins, captured perfectly in dark and sinister cinematography. Reading of the credits was like a who's who of Hollywood icons, it was probably one of the most successful bringing together of star names up until then, with the likes of; tom Berenger, Willem Dafoe (Born on the Fourth of July), Forest Whitaker (The Last King of Scotland), Keith David (The Thing), Johnny Depp (Pirates of the Caribbean) and Kevin Dillon. You are guaranteed to find a name amongst them that is one of your favourite actors. But in a sea of big names and future big names, I still felt Charlie Sheen (Hot Shots) was able to stand out and deliver a convincing portrayal of a conflicted man, caught up in the ultimate battle with himself as he has to choose between what's right and doing whatever it takes to survive, so basically choosing between safety of the body or safety of the mind. I also felt with such complex emotions he had to show at a drop of a hat, and doing them so well that it was a surprise and travesty that he wasn't nominated for a single big award. I really do feel that a man's innocents is truly lost in a war, and it is a shamed you don't get to see it played out on film, but that is what also makes Platoon so special because unlike previous films based on the war in Vietnam such as; Apocalypse Now, The Deer Hunter or Coming Home. Platoon is the very first not to look at the war from the wide perspective, and not get caught up in the big budget special effects. Instead it takes a profound and uncompromising leap into the very depths of the human condition; never shying away from exposing the sinister side to us such is in the case of Sgt. Barnes (Tom Berenger) and penetrating through the sense of false bravado to leaving a film offering a sincere exploration of self.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "Hell is the impossibility of reason"...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    aldinchova
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Rejoice O young man in thy youth" - Ecclesiastes. Written and directed by Oliver Stone, "Platoon" is considered as one of the best war movies ever made. Another masterpiece of the same director, also with Vietnam war topic is "Born on the Fourth of July" with Tom Cruise as Ron Kovic real life war veteran, based on true story. Oliver Stone took part in Vietnam war (he served there from September 1967. until November 1968. being wounded twice and receiving couple of military decorations for his participation). After he returned home he decided to put his war experiences into a script of fictionalized war story which many years later was transformed into a movie inspired by war experiences that Stone had in Vietnam. That was how "Platoon" was made. A story with authentic background. Not popular with US.Army because it is telling of highly negative side of the war (showing terrible war atrocities against civilians and horrors of fighting in the jungle) "Platoon" is a strong and emotional story about different characters of different people put together on inevitable collision course with each other. Those hidden virtues and faults of those people have always been in themselves, they are only emphasized in a war madness that surrounds them. Three main characters Sgt.Barnes (Tom Berenger) on one side, Sgt. Elias (Willem Dafoe) on the opposite one and private Chris Taylor (Charlie Sheen) between them come from different life backgrounds and often have opposite and confronting perceptions of the war and life itself. In every war, in every army, on both sides in every armed conflict there were always and there will always be people like three of them and people around them. Movie shows platoon divided between Elias and Barnes two centers of gravity and those who choose to be with one or the other. Sgt.Barnes is a battle hardened and ruthless warrior. A man who does n't care much for himself and others when it comes to having fire contact with the enemy. He lost his humanity and became like a blood thirsty animal itching for fighting because it is the only meaning of his life left. What kind of life and pain formed his personality we can only guess, but outside of war he has no place, he has no purpose. And he knows that. Deep inside he hates himself for what he is and he does n't care if he is going to live or get killed. He openly challenges others to take on him ("It's just me and six of you guys, come on, no one's gonna know") but they don't dare to do anything. Two statements define his character and beliefs, first - "Now, I got no fight with any man who does what he's told, but when he don't, the machine breaks down. And when the machine breaks down, we break down. And I ain't gonna allow that in any of you. Not one" and second - "You smoke this to escape from reality. Well, I don't need to do that, I am reality " which is kind of his life statement. Sgt. Elias is opposite of him. Battle hardened and experienced fighter too, but a man who can keep his balance, he will not cross the line, the point of no return that Sgt.Barnes crossed long time ago. Elias does n't have any illusions about the war, he had them on the beginning but they are lost meanwhile. As he says to Chris Taylor "We are going to lose this one" he considers it a wrong war to fight as he realized after disappointments that he had about its cause. If he lost his illusions he did not lose his humanity. A man who will do the right thing when it matters most and lose his life because of it. Chris Taylor is rebellious and idealistic person who escapes from life at home full of restrictions and rules trying to gain an experience of his own and what he finds is not quite as what he expected, if he had any idealistic illusions they are soon crushed by harsh realities of war and the way it transforms people pushing the best and worst in them to the limits of human tolerance. In the end he is left deeply traumatized with psychological scars that will take many years to heal and become bearable. Story about different characters of different people rejected by society but in war they have just what they need with some of them seeing it as a way to project worst parts of their personality and stay unpunished. As many other great movies, "Platoon" is a story about human character, about the best and worst in all of us. Part of us that makes us be the greatest humanists and part of us that makes us be the worst criminals. Chris Taylor puts it great when he says that he is "a child of two fathers - Elias and Barnes" because he has what both of them have. Humanity of Elias and killing instinct of Barnes because in the end he kills Barnes. Others are mere reflections like Sgt.O'Neill, an ordinary coward, psychopath Bunny, a dog of war released from his chains, or Rhah, King and Big Harold who can still find strength to joke after all. Joke is their best cure. For Chris and others there are many years left to heal from scars deep inside their souls as he says it in words that can be the point of the whole movie - "I think now looking back we did not fight the enemy, we fought ourselves and the enemy was in us... But be that as it may, those of us who did make it have an obligation to build again, to teach others what we know and to try with what's left of our lives to find a goodness and meaning to this life".
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of the most realistic war films I've ever seen
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    owenhjohnson
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Platoon" is one of the few fictional films that I find a realistic interpretation of war. It has a great story, characters to invest in, and the gritty reality of war. Oliver Stone accomplished that by basing the final battle on a battle he actually survived which probably added to the reality of the film because of Stone's survival of the Vietnam War. The film has many themes and realistic situations that you would find with non-fiction stories about the Vietnam War. Also, while I do not think it was needed, Tom Berenger made for an interesting antagonist in the film. In a lot of Vietnam films, there is always the hideout where a group of soldiers goes to get high or drunk and party. While there was that element in this film, it was done with grace and was not turned into a movie about a bunch of stoner-hippies in Vietnam. The imagery and actions by the characters that demonstrate some of the themes in the film are powerful and breathtaking. With the visuals and the actions, it feels like there were parts where that is how it actually happened during the war. Though the film sometimes went a little overboard to show the themes and to demonstrate the characters. The film has a great story and interesting characters with depth that does not take away from the action and reality of the actual fighting in the Vietnam War part.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Platoon - Review
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Daniel Metcalf
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Oliver Stone participated as an infantry soldier in the Vietnam War so what we see get in "Platoon" is a breathtaking look on the life of a soldier, shown through the eyes of a soldier named Chris who is portrayed young Charlie Sheen. Whilst the film largely showcases the negatives of war, the horrors that came with being a soldier and ultimately the mistake America made by fighting in Vietnam its primary agenda is not to be an anti-war film. In fact, the conflict between the Americans and the Vietnamese army is not the main focus of the film at all, instead it acts as a great backdrop to create a variety of situations that challenge the films characters in a number of different ways, and it is the actions and different attitudes of the characters that are important. Instead the film's conflict is between two camps that emerge as the American's divide over split attitudes. On one side we have Sgt. Barnes portrayed by Tom Berenger and on the other Sgt. Elias portrayed by Willem Dafoe. These two actors provide us with two fantastic performances and make the film what is it is. Elias can be viewed as the 'good' soldier, a kind, lesser-spoken sergeant who goes by the book and serves his country how he should. On the contrary we have Barnes, a man with a completely different set of morals, a loudmouthed soldier who will take action in to his own hands to do what he thinks is right. The divide occurs when Barnes becomes responsible for the massacre of a Vietnamese village, whilst others are willing to accept his actions and choose to protect him there are others who are not so willing to go along with a cover up including Elias. "Day by day, I struggle to maintain not only my strength but my sanity. It's all a blur. I have no energy to write. I don't know what's right and what's wrong anymore. The morale of the men is low. A civil war in the platoon. Half the men with Elias, half with Barnes. There's a lot of suspicion and hate. I can't believe we're fighting each other when we should be fighting them." That quote is from Chris, the young soldier who narrates the film for us through a series of letters sent back to his grandmother. He dropped out of college to join the army through choice and immediately struggles to fit in with the others, however throughout the film he progresses in to a more respected and adequate soldier. His progression is important to the film as he adapts to the harsh life and is influenced by others. The film's cinematography and editing is superb, most of the films scene take place in the thick forest, with extremely heavy rain painting a dark image for us that helps show the grim conditions the soldier's were really in. The film does not glorify war at all, there is no unnecessary action or over the top heroic scenes and instead everything seems real and sometimes it really is not pretty. Some scenes are really uncomfortable, especially those that involve the inhuman actions of Barnes that really do a good job of amplifying our disgust towards his character which is important as we side with Elias and Chris. Dafoe, Berenger and Sheen make this film what it is and ultimately the final scenes that involve them are the most iconic and memorable. Dafoe provides an unforgettable scene which I will not spoil. And one of the final scenes that Chris and Barnes share gives us satisfaction despite being brutal and far from a happy ending. I can not recommend this film enough; it is one of my favourite war films and a fantastic and emotional tale. Unlike other glorified films this one does not sacrifice its brutal and deeply affective centre for cheap affects and fake scenes. The heart of the film lies with its trio of star actors who are each brilliant as we see the real conflict that arises from the war and its affect within the platoon.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of the Greatest war Movies of all Time
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    josephledbury
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I am a big war movie fan and It think that this is one of the best war movies I've ever seen. It may not be as good as Apocalypse Now, but I think that this is defiantly one of the greatest war movies of all time. I first saw this and didn't notice that the main character was 21 year old Charlie Sheen, star of the TV show Two and a half Men, but I did recognize William Defoe from the movie Spiderman and I didn't recognize Tom berenger. But I think that the acting in this movie is so passionate and the reflection of their performances which is what makes this movie so realistic and tells the story of a awful war which should have never happened. The story is based on the actual experiences of Academy Award winning director Oliver Stone. What an experience that man had. Like I can't believe that the war was that bad and that in the jungle could make the soldiers lose their mind. It won four Academy Awards and well deserved for Best Sound, Best Editing, best director and coveted Best Picture of 1986. The soundtrack was defiantly what made this movie so dramatic and emotional for some. every time I hear that soundtrack, my heart just sinks. The soundtrack just hits me so fast and gets me caught up in the movie the moment the music starts. In the Top 250 with a rating of 8.2/10 and is in my top 20 favorite movies of all time. I just love this film whether it's been caught up in the dramatizations of how emotional this movie is or the fact that I love watching a movie with a lot of gun fighting. Great movie with passionate acting which expresses the very real dramatizations of a very emotional war and deserved the four Academy Awards it won.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Vietnam, the way it really was...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    robertalexanderlindsey
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Of all of the the endless movies made about the tragedies that took place in the jungles and cities of Vietnam from 1965-75, 'Platoon' is the only one that absolutely needs to be seen. Forget the far-out fantasies of 'Apocalypse Now', or the introspective ironies of 'The Deer Hunter', or the gung-ho, pro-war propaganda 'The Green Berets.' 'Platoon' puts you right in the middle of the action with an exhausted, grimy group of American troops in Vietnam, troops who've been slogging through the mud in fetid heat, bitten by leeches and menaced by North Vietnamese troops or Viet Cong who cold ambush them at any second, any time, anywhere. It also goes into other details; counting down days in-country, leeches, smoking pot in the barracks, malfunctioning claymore mines, and sudden ambushes while out on patrols... 'Platoon' shows how living under these conditions for months at a time could harden even the greenest of new recruits, or 'FNGs' (F---ing New Guys, as their more experienced colleagues liked to call them), and turn them into experienced killing machines, or something even worse. One example of this transformation is Staff Sgt. Bob Barnes, a toughened, bitter veteran who has seen combat since 1965. By 1967-68, the time in which the film begins, his entire face mirrors his experience, lacerated and deformed by his sufferings in combat. Barnes has become vicious, and is not above killing civilians or conveniently removing un-agreeable troops within his own platoon. One of these is Sgt. Elias, who has also seen combat in Vietnam since 1965. Elias is aware that America's strategy of 'winning hearts and minds' will be a failure, and that Barnes's methods are not only illegal, but destructive to the platoon... And these realizations are the reasons that Elias becomes one of Barnes's victims. And in the middle of all of this is Chris Taylor, a young college dropout who volunteered for duty in Vietnam. He is torn between the two sergeants, and when he realizes that Elias is his savior, he must act not as a human being, but as a soldier...
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Platoon is certainly one of the best films about Vietnam War and Oliver Stone's best.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    s13ky
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    If we talk about the war in Vietnam, we should talk about Platoon. It is certainly one of the best films about Vietnam War and in my opinion, it's absolutely Oliver Stone's best film since JFK and Nixon. Overall, apart from the credibility of the film director and also the authenticity in the depiction of the war, I find the screenplay, editing and film direction stand out above all, not to forget the all star casts of two famous method actors, Tom Berenger (possibly his best performance ever) and Willem Dafoe. To be honest, deep within my heart, "Platoon" ranked somewhere among "Apocalypse Now", "Full Metal Jacket" and "The Deer Hunter" (the latter isn't a war film) because of its raw visualization of the war horror that some consider a crime against humanity. I always get carried away by the spectacular music scoring, saddening, beautiful as well as frightening. The best music sequence would be "Adagio For Strings" by Samuel Barber and it's your task to find out which sequence. Oliver Stone really did well in bringing us the rich psychological portraits of soldiers who fought the popular war from a very interesting perspective, through the eyes of a rookie soldier (Charlie Sheen) who volunteered to defend his country, in a fight against communism. We witness the harsh time they faced as soon as they landed on the Saigon combat zone, in the jungle, with a simple mission of staying alive from day to day. The line between good and evil is the spot where Oliver Stone places the personal stories of the men whose horror and fear were their daily foods, real men who fought and died in the Vietnam War. This unnecessary war was taped in brutal realism. Awesome combat scenes, frank, hard and strangely beautiful. Robert Richardson as the cinematographer created a jaw-dropping atmosphere combining gray and bleak apocalyptic tones of the great wild landscapes. In conclusion, this is one of the greatest war films of cinema history, it contains some moving scenes and offers a realistic and cruel story of one of the greatest atrocities of humanity: wars.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Charlie Sheen's breakthrough performance!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jake-law123
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Not really big on Oliver Stone, but his depiction of the Vietnam war is brilliant in this heavy, dark tribute to the men who died in the war. Charlie Sheen, Tom Berenger, and Willam Dafoe all make one big triangle in this film, as it revolves around the conflict going on between them, and by them, I mean Willem Dafoe's squad, and Tom Berenger's squad in the Platoon, while Charlie Sheen is caught in the middle to deal with both, struggling to maintain his sanity as the depression of the war gets to him every day. All performances are excellent. Even though the beginning consists of Sheen being an innocent little girly man, the war progresses, and he becomes a brutal life risking grunt that ruthlessly kills everything in his path, showing how the war affects him mentally. The sound of the film sounds muddled every time somebody opens their mouth, not sure what Stone's intentions were, but it won the Oscar for sound, so whatever. The film isn't centered around combat, or the realism of war, it's centered around the duality of men, and how the war affects the minds of the soldiers, and the different types of soldiers that faced the war. The beginning scenes consist of the Platoon getting to know each other, leading up to one of the most infamous and controversial scenes in cinema history, the village. It's interesting to see different characters of different personalities conflict each other over being with a different squad leader, like are you guys in high school? Either way they find a way to make it more intense. Not too heavy on atmosphere, history, or in depth messaging like Apocalypse Now or The Deer Hunter, but it gets it around pretty easy, and the message about the war bringing out the best or the worst in men is carried out pretty easy also. Very excellent war film, isn't along the lines of Saving Private Ryan, (my favorite war film) but definitely give it a viewing.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Brilliantly Done
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    davorinlonac
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Hello fellow readers, this is a review of a film I had already reviewed but decided my old review was too dull so here is my new and improved Platoon review. Platoon is one of my favorite movies of all time for numerous reasons which will be shared throughout this review. First of all, it has my favorite soundtrack ever produced in a film, and shows you the real truth of what really happened in the war. There was a grotesque village scene which was hard to watch somehow. Willem Dafoe, Tom Berenger and Charlie sheen give on of their richest performances in my favorite Oliver stone film ever! The film was brilliantly done and can very well be the closest film which I could consider my favorite. The film is a great piece of cinema and will always be...
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Possibly Oliver Stone's best
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    sme_no_densetsu
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    To be quite honest, the first time I saw Oliver Stone's "Platoon" I was disappointed. Perhaps it was the fact that the presence of Charlie Sheen in the lead role invited comparison to "Apocalypse Now", starring his dad. However, even though both are war movies set in Viet Nam, comparing them is like comparing apples & oranges. Stone's film is, first and foremost, a movie about the experiences of 'grunts' in this bloody conflict. In place of the surreal nature of "Apocalypse Now", Stone and technical adviser Dale Dye brought a sense of realism to the picture. That being said, while realism was enforced, Stone still managed to imbue his script with deeper meaning. The story revolves around young volunteer Chris Taylor (Charlie Sheen) as he arrives in Viet Nam and quickly becomes acquainted with the horrors of war. Apart from the enemy, there's conflict among the soldiers themselves, as a rift develops between the compassionate Sgt. Elias (Willem Dafoe) and the ruthless Sgt. Barnes (Tom Berenger). Despite the fact that Charlie Sheen is in the lead role, the acting is actually pretty strong. Berenger & Dafoe were both nominated for Academy Awards but they ended up losing to Michael Caine. The large ensemble cast includes several recognizable actors, often contributing memorable performances. Notable names include Keith David, Forest Whitaker, John C. McGinley, Kevin Dillon and even a young Johnny Depp. Stone's direction won him one of the film's four Academy Awards. Another Oscar deservedly rewarded the sound department for their contribution to the film. Also notable was the extensive (and effective) use of Samuel Barber's "Adagio for Strings". Both visually and sonically, the movie is impressive. Ultimately, "Platoon" isn't quite perfect but it's definitely good enough that I'm glad I gave it a second chance. The movie's realism is commendable and the storyline is thought-provoking. It may be no match for "Apocalypse Now" but that only means that it's just a very good movie and not a masterpiece.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    In war no one wins
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    silva-w-pius
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "First real casualty of war is innocents; the first real movie on the war in Vietnam is Platoon" That is a quote from the trailer that I felt encompassed what I felt about Platoon to a T. What makes Platoon so realistic is that it is part of those rare occasions where you have a story born from a director's firsthand experience, but that's what you get with Oliver stone, who served as an infantry soldier in Vietnam, allowing him to create an almost autobiographical account, and in some instances a documentary into the under belly and less glamour side of war  and by glamorous I mean not a place where you shot bad guys, then come home to a giant marching band and a handshake from the president, but instead it's actually a place where real and sometimes innocent people die. With so much realism it should be no surprise that Platoon won four Oscars in 86 in the best director, picture, sound and cinematography categories. Platoon tells the story of a student named Chris Taylor (Charlie Sheen) in the late 60's who joins up for the army believing in his heart that he is fulfilling his patriotic duty, and I feel in some part that deep down he believes that he will go to Vietnam fire a few bullets and return as a hero. But upon reaching, he joins up with a diverse platoon of men, in the outside world would probably never rub shoulders with, but here they move as one, lead by two men; Sgt. Barnes (Tom Berenger) a man with a scared appearance, that adds to his mystical aura of being a man that cannot be killed and the other Sgt. Elias (Willem Dafoe) who through the use of mind altering drugs is able to maintain an air of calm. But Chris Taylor's dreams of heroism are quickly obliterated as they delve deeper into enemy territory, witnessing acts of despicable evil towards his fellow man by the very same men he serves within the same platoon, making him quickly realises how naive his ideas of war as they are not a rite of passage he once thought but instead war is actually hell on earth where no side wins, captured perfectly in dark and sinister cinematography. Reading of the credits was like a who's who of Hollywood icons, it was probably one of the most successful bringing together of star names up until then, with the likes of; tom Berenger, Willem Dafoe (Born on the Fourth of July), Forest Whitaker (The Last King of Scotland), Keith David (The Thing), Johnny Depp (Pirates of the Caribbean) and Kevin Dillon. You are guaranteed to find a name amongst them that is one of your favourite actors. But in a sea of big names and future big names, I still felt Charlie Sheen (Hot Shots) was able to stand out and deliver a convincing portrayal of a conflicted man, caught up in the ultimate battle with himself as he has to choose between what's right and doing whatever it takes to survive, so basically choosing between safety of the body or safety of the mind. I also felt with such complex emotions he had to show at a drop of a hat, and doing them so well that it was a surprise and travesty that he wasn't nominated for a single big award. I really do feel that a man's innocents is truly lost in a war, and it is a shamed you don't get to see it played out on film, but that is what also makes Platoon so special because unlike previous films based on the war in Vietnam such as; Apocalypse Now, The Deer Hunter or Coming Home. Platoon is the very first not to look at the war from the wide perspective, and not get caught up in the big budget special effects. Instead it takes a profound and uncompromising leap into the very depths of the human condition; never shying away from exposing the sinister side to us such is in the case of Sgt. Barnes (Tom Berenger) and penetrating through the sense of false bravado to leaving a film offering a sincere exploration of self.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "Hell is the impossibility of reason"...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    aldinchova
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Rejoice O young man in thy youth" - Ecclesiastes. Written and directed by Oliver Stone, "Platoon" is considered as one of the best war movies ever made. Another masterpiece of the same director, also with Vietnam war topic is "Born on the Fourth of July" with Tom Cruise as Ron Kovic real life war veteran, based on true story. Oliver Stone took part in Vietnam war (he served there from September 1967. until November 1968. being wounded twice and receiving couple of military decorations for his participation). After he returned home he decided to put his war experiences into a script of fictionalized war story which many years later was transformed into a movie inspired by war experiences that Stone had in Vietnam. That was how "Platoon" was made. A story with authentic background. Not popular with US.Army because it is telling of highly negative side of the war (showing terrible war atrocities against civilians and horrors of fighting in the jungle) "Platoon" is a strong and emotional story about different characters of different people put together on inevitable collision course with each other. Those hidden virtues and faults of those people have always been in themselves, they are only emphasized in a war madness that surrounds them. Three main characters Sgt.Barnes (Tom Berenger) on one side, Sgt. Elias (Willem Dafoe) on the opposite one and private Chris Taylor (Charlie Sheen) between them come from different life backgrounds and often have opposite and confronting perceptions of the war and life itself. In every war, in every army, on both sides in every armed conflict there were always and there will always be people like three of them and people around them. Movie shows platoon divided between Elias and Barnes two centers of gravity and those who choose to be with one or the other. Sgt.Barnes is a battle hardened and ruthless warrior. A man who does n't care much for himself and others when it comes to having fire contact with the enemy. He lost his humanity and became like a blood thirsty animal itching for fighting because it is the only meaning of his life left. What kind of life and pain formed his personality we can only guess, but outside of war he has no place, he has no purpose. And he knows that. Deep inside he hates himself for what he is and he does n't care if he is going to live or get killed. He openly challenges others to take on him ("It's just me and six of you guys, come on, no one's gonna know") but they don't dare to do anything. Two statements define his character and beliefs, first - "Now, I got no fight with any man who does what he's told, but when he don't, the machine breaks down. And when the machine breaks down, we break down. And I ain't gonna allow that in any of you. Not one" and second - "You smoke this to escape from reality. Well, I don't need to do that, I am reality " which is kind of his life statement. Sgt. Elias is opposite of him. Battle hardened and experienced fighter too, but a man who can keep his balance, he will not cross the line, the point of no return that Sgt.Barnes crossed long time ago. Elias does n't have any illusions about the war, he had them on the beginning but they are lost meanwhile. As he says to Chris Taylor "We are going to lose this one" he considers it a wrong war to fight as he realized after disappointments that he had about its cause. If he lost his illusions he did not lose his humanity. A man who will do the right thing when it matters most and lose his life because of it. Chris Taylor is rebellious and idealistic person who escapes from life at home full of restrictions and rules trying to gain an experience of his own and what he finds is not quite as what he expected, if he had any idealistic illusions they are soon crushed by harsh realities of war and the way it transforms people pushing the best and worst in them to the limits of human tolerance. In the end he is left deeply traumatized with psychological scars that will take many years to heal and become bearable. Story about different characters of different people rejected by society but in war they have just what they need with some of them seeing it as a way to project worst parts of their personality and stay unpunished. As many other great movies, "Platoon" is a story about human character, about the best and worst in all of us. Part of us that makes us be the greatest humanists and part of us that makes us be the worst criminals. Chris Taylor puts it great when he says that he is "a child of two fathers - Elias and Barnes" because he has what both of them have. Humanity of Elias and killing instinct of Barnes because in the end he kills Barnes. Others are mere reflections like Sgt.O'Neill, an ordinary coward, psychopath Bunny, a dog of war released from his chains, or Rhah, King and Big Harold who can still find strength to joke after all. Joke is their best cure. For Chris and others there are many years left to heal from scars deep inside their souls as he says it in words that can be the point of the whole movie - "I think now looking back we did not fight the enemy, we fought ourselves and the enemy was in us... But be that as it may, those of us who did make it have an obligation to build again, to teach others what we know and to try with what's left of our lives to find a goodness and meaning to this life".
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of the most realistic war films I've ever seen
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    owenhjohnson
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Platoon" is one of the few fictional films that I find a realistic interpretation of war. It has a great story, characters to invest in, and the gritty reality of war. Oliver Stone accomplished that by basing the final battle on a battle he actually survived which probably added to the reality of the film because of Stone's survival of the Vietnam War. The film has many themes and realistic situations that you would find with non-fiction stories about the Vietnam War. Also, while I do not think it was needed, Tom Berenger made for an interesting antagonist in the film. In a lot of Vietnam films, there is always the hideout where a group of soldiers goes to get high or drunk and party. While there was that element in this film, it was done with grace and was not turned into a movie about a bunch of stoner-hippies in Vietnam. The imagery and actions by the characters that demonstrate some of the themes in the film are powerful and breathtaking. With the visuals and the actions, it feels like there were parts where that is how it actually happened during the war. Though the film sometimes went a little overboard to show the themes and to demonstrate the characters. The film has a great story and interesting characters with depth that does not take away from the action and reality of the actual fighting in the Vietnam War part.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Platoon - Review
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Daniel Metcalf
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Oliver Stone participated as an infantry soldier in the Vietnam War so what we see get in "Platoon" is a breathtaking look on the life of a soldier, shown through the eyes of a soldier named Chris who is portrayed young Charlie Sheen. Whilst the film largely showcases the negatives of war, the horrors that came with being a soldier and ultimately the mistake America made by fighting in Vietnam its primary agenda is not to be an anti-war film. In fact, the conflict between the Americans and the Vietnamese army is not the main focus of the film at all, instead it acts as a great backdrop to create a variety of situations that challenge the films characters in a number of different ways, and it is the actions and different attitudes of the characters that are important. Instead the film's conflict is between two camps that emerge as the American's divide over split attitudes. On one side we have Sgt. Barnes portrayed by Tom Berenger and on the other Sgt. Elias portrayed by Willem Dafoe. These two actors provide us with two fantastic performances and make the film what is it is. Elias can be viewed as the 'good' soldier, a kind, lesser-spoken sergeant who goes by the book and serves his country how he should. On the contrary we have Barnes, a man with a completely different set of morals, a loudmouthed soldier who will take action in to his own hands to do what he thinks is right. The divide occurs when Barnes becomes responsible for the massacre of a Vietnamese village, whilst others are willing to accept his actions and choose to protect him there are others who are not so willing to go along with a cover up including Elias. "Day by day, I struggle to maintain not only my strength but my sanity. It's all a blur. I have no energy to write. I don't know what's right and what's wrong anymore. The morale of the men is low. A civil war in the platoon. Half the men with Elias, half with Barnes. There's a lot of suspicion and hate. I can't believe we're fighting each other when we should be fighting them." That quote is from Chris, the young soldier who narrates the film for us through a series of letters sent back to his grandmother. He dropped out of college to join the army through choice and immediately struggles to fit in with the others, however throughout the film he progresses in to a more respected and adequate soldier. His progression is important to the film as he adapts to the harsh life and is influenced by others. The film's cinematography and editing is superb, most of the films scene take place in the thick forest, with extremely heavy rain painting a dark image for us that helps show the grim conditions the soldier's were really in. The film does not glorify war at all, there is no unnecessary action or over the top heroic scenes and instead everything seems real and sometimes it really is not pretty. Some scenes are really uncomfortable, especially those that involve the inhuman actions of Barnes that really do a good job of amplifying our disgust towards his character which is important as we side with Elias and Chris. Dafoe, Berenger and Sheen make this film what it is and ultimately the final scenes that involve them are the most iconic and memorable. Dafoe provides an unforgettable scene which I will not spoil. And one of the final scenes that Chris and Barnes share gives us satisfaction despite being brutal and far from a happy ending. I can not recommend this film enough; it is one of my favourite war films and a fantastic and emotional tale. Unlike other glorified films this one does not sacrifice its brutal and deeply affective centre for cheap affects and fake scenes. The heart of the film lies with its trio of star actors who are each brilliant as we see the real conflict that arises from the war and its affect within the platoon.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of the Greatest war Movies of all Time
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    josephledbury
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I am a big war movie fan and It think that this is one of the best war movies I've ever seen. It may not be as good as Apocalypse Now, but I think that this is defiantly one of the greatest war movies of all time. I first saw this and didn't notice that the main character was 21 year old Charlie Sheen, star of the TV show Two and a half Men, but I did recognize William Defoe from the movie Spiderman and I didn't recognize Tom berenger. But I think that the acting in this movie is so passionate and the reflection of their performances which is what makes this movie so realistic and tells the story of a awful war which should have never happened. The story is based on the actual experiences of Academy Award winning director Oliver Stone. What an experience that man had. Like I can't believe that the war was that bad and that in the jungle could make the soldiers lose their mind. It won four Academy Awards and well deserved for Best Sound, Best Editing, best director and coveted Best Picture of 1986. The soundtrack was defiantly what made this movie so dramatic and emotional for some. every time I hear that soundtrack, my heart just sinks. The soundtrack just hits me so fast and gets me caught up in the movie the moment the music starts. In the Top 250 with a rating of 8.2/10 and is in my top 20 favorite movies of all time. I just love this film whether it's been caught up in the dramatizations of how emotional this movie is or the fact that I love watching a movie with a lot of gun fighting. Great movie with passionate acting which expresses the very real dramatizations of a very emotional war and deserved the four Academy Awards it won.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Vietnam, the way it really was...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    robertalexanderlindsey
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Of all of the the endless movies made about the tragedies that took place in the jungles and cities of Vietnam from 1965-75, 'Platoon' is the only one that absolutely needs to be seen. Forget the far-out fantasies of 'Apocalypse Now', or the introspective ironies of 'The Deer Hunter', or the gung-ho, pro-war propaganda 'The Green Berets.' 'Platoon' puts you right in the middle of the action with an exhausted, grimy group of American troops in Vietnam, troops who've been slogging through the mud in fetid heat, bitten by leeches and menaced by North Vietnamese troops or Viet Cong who cold ambush them at any second, any time, anywhere. It also goes into other details; counting down days in-country, leeches, smoking pot in the barracks, malfunctioning claymore mines, and sudden ambushes while out on patrols... 'Platoon' shows how living under these conditions for months at a time could harden even the greenest of new recruits, or 'FNGs' (F---ing New Guys, as their more experienced colleagues liked to call them), and turn them into experienced killing machines, or something even worse. One example of this transformation is Staff Sgt. Bob Barnes, a toughened, bitter veteran who has seen combat since 1965. By 1967-68, the time in which the film begins, his entire face mirrors his experience, lacerated and deformed by his sufferings in combat. Barnes has become vicious, and is not above killing civilians or conveniently removing un-agreeable troops within his own platoon. One of these is Sgt. Elias, who has also seen combat in Vietnam since 1965. Elias is aware that America's strategy of 'winning hearts and minds' will be a failure, and that Barnes's methods are not only illegal, but destructive to the platoon... And these realizations are the reasons that Elias becomes one of Barnes's victims. And in the middle of all of this is Chris Taylor, a young college dropout who volunteered for duty in Vietnam. He is torn between the two sergeants, and when he realizes that Elias is his savior, he must act not as a human being, but as a soldier...
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Platoon is certainly one of the best films about Vietnam War and Oliver Stone's best.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    s13ky
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    If we talk about the war in Vietnam, we should talk about Platoon. It is certainly one of the best films about Vietnam War and in my opinion, it's absolutely Oliver Stone's best film since JFK and Nixon. Overall, apart from the credibility of the film director and also the authenticity in the depiction of the war, I find the screenplay, editing and film direction stand out above all, not to forget the all star casts of two famous method actors, Tom Berenger (possibly his best performance ever) and Willem Dafoe. To be honest, deep within my heart, "Platoon" ranked somewhere among "Apocalypse Now", "Full Metal Jacket" and "The Deer Hunter" (the latter isn't a war film) because of its raw visualization of the war horror that some consider a crime against humanity. I always get carried away by the spectacular music scoring, saddening, beautiful as well as frightening. The best music sequence would be "Adagio For Strings" by Samuel Barber and it's your task to find out which sequence. Oliver Stone really did well in bringing us the rich psychological portraits of soldiers who fought the popular war from a very interesting perspective, through the eyes of a rookie soldier (Charlie Sheen) who volunteered to defend his country, in a fight against communism. We witness the harsh time they faced as soon as they landed on the Saigon combat zone, in the jungle, with a simple mission of staying alive from day to day. The line between good and evil is the spot where Oliver Stone places the personal stories of the men whose horror and fear were their daily foods, real men who fought and died in the Vietnam War. This unnecessary war was taped in brutal realism. Awesome combat scenes, frank, hard and strangely beautiful. Robert Richardson as the cinematographer created a jaw-dropping atmosphere combining gray and bleak apocalyptic tones of the great wild landscapes. In conclusion, this is one of the greatest war films of cinema history, it contains some moving scenes and offers a realistic and cruel story of one of the greatest atrocities of humanity: wars.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Charlie Sheen's breakthrough performance!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jake-law123
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Not really big on Oliver Stone, but his depiction of the Vietnam war is brilliant in this heavy, dark tribute to the men who died in the war. Charlie Sheen, Tom Berenger, and Willam Dafoe all make one big triangle in this film, as it revolves around the conflict going on between them, and by them, I mean Willem Dafoe's squad, and Tom Berenger's squad in the Platoon, while Charlie Sheen is caught in the middle to deal with both, struggling to maintain his sanity as the depression of the war gets to him every day. All performances are excellent. Even though the beginning consists of Sheen being an innocent little girly man, the war progresses, and he becomes a brutal life risking grunt that ruthlessly kills everything in his path, showing how the war affects him mentally. The sound of the film sounds muddled every time somebody opens their mouth, not sure what Stone's intentions were, but it won the Oscar for sound, so whatever. The film isn't centered around combat, or the realism of war, it's centered around the duality of men, and how the war affects the minds of the soldiers, and the different types of soldiers that faced the war. The beginning scenes consist of the Platoon getting to know each other, leading up to one of the most infamous and controversial scenes in cinema history, the village. It's interesting to see different characters of different personalities conflict each other over being with a different squad leader, like are you guys in high school? Either way they find a way to make it more intense. Not too heavy on atmosphere, history, or in depth messaging like Apocalypse Now or The Deer Hunter, but it gets it around pretty easy, and the message about the war bringing out the best or the worst in men is carried out pretty easy also. Very excellent war film, isn't along the lines of Saving Private Ryan, (my favorite war film) but definitely give it a viewing.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Brilliantly Done
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    davorinlonac
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Hello fellow readers, this is a review of a film I had already reviewed but decided my old review was too dull so here is my new and improved Platoon review. Platoon is one of my favorite movies of all time for numerous reasons which will be shared throughout this review. First of all, it has my favorite soundtrack ever produced in a film, and shows you the real truth of what really happened in the war. There was a grotesque village scene which was hard to watch somehow. Willem Dafoe, Tom Berenger and Charlie sheen give on of their richest performances in my favorite Oliver stone film ever! The film was brilliantly done and can very well be the closest film which I could consider my favorite. The film is a great piece of cinema and will always be...
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Possibly Oliver Stone's best
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    sme_no_densetsu
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    To be quite honest, the first time I saw Oliver Stone's "Platoon" I was disappointed. Perhaps it was the fact that the presence of Charlie Sheen in the lead role invited comparison to "Apocalypse Now", starring his dad. However, even though both are war movies set in Viet Nam, comparing them is like comparing apples & oranges. Stone's film is, first and foremost, a movie about the experiences of 'grunts' in this bloody conflict. In place of the surreal nature of "Apocalypse Now", Stone and technical adviser Dale Dye brought a sense of realism to the picture. That being said, while realism was enforced, Stone still managed to imbue his script with deeper meaning. The story revolves around young volunteer Chris Taylor (Charlie Sheen) as he arrives in Viet Nam and quickly becomes acquainted with the horrors of war. Apart from the enemy, there's conflict among the soldiers themselves, as a rift develops between the compassionate Sgt. Elias (Willem Dafoe) and the ruthless Sgt. Barnes (Tom Berenger). Despite the fact that Charlie Sheen is in the lead role, the acting is actually pretty strong. Berenger & Dafoe were both nominated for Academy Awards but they ended up losing to Michael Caine. The large ensemble cast includes several recognizable actors, often contributing memorable performances. Notable names include Keith David, Forest Whitaker, John C. McGinley, Kevin Dillon and even a young Johnny Depp. Stone's direction won him one of the film's four Academy Awards. Another Oscar deservedly rewarded the sound department for their contribution to the film. Also notable was the extensive (and effective) use of Samuel Barber's "Adagio for Strings". Both visually and sonically, the movie is impressive. Ultimately, "Platoon" isn't quite perfect but it's definitely good enough that I'm glad I gave it a second chance. The movie's realism is commendable and the storyline is thought-provoking. It may be no match for "Apocalypse Now" but that only means that it's just a very good movie and not a masterpiece.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    In war no one wins
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    silva-w-pius
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "First real casualty of war is innocents; the first real movie on the war in Vietnam is Platoon" That is a quote from the trailer that I felt encompassed what I felt about Platoon to a T. What makes Platoon so realistic is that it is part of those rare occasions where you have a story born from a director's firsthand experience, but that's what you get with Oliver stone, who served as an infantry soldier in Vietnam, allowing him to create an almost autobiographical account, and in some instances a documentary into the under belly and less glamour side of war  and by glamorous I mean not a place where you shot bad guys, then come home to a giant marching band and a handshake from the president, but instead it's actually a place where real and sometimes innocent people die. With so much realism it should be no surprise that Platoon won four Oscars in 86 in the best director, picture, sound and cinematography categories. Platoon tells the story of a student named Chris Taylor (Charlie Sheen) in the late 60's who joins up for the army believing in his heart that he is fulfilling his patriotic duty, and I feel in some part that deep down he believes that he will go to Vietnam fire a few bullets and return as a hero. But upon reaching, he joins up with a diverse platoon of men, in the outside world would probably never rub shoulders with, but here they move as one, lead by two men; Sgt. Barnes (Tom Berenger) a man with a scared appearance, that adds to his mystical aura of being a man that cannot be killed and the other Sgt. Elias (Willem Dafoe) who through the use of mind altering drugs is able to maintain an air of calm. But Chris Taylor's dreams of heroism are quickly obliterated as they delve deeper into enemy territory, witnessing acts of despicable evil towards his fellow man by the very same men he serves within the same platoon, making him quickly realises how naive his ideas of war as they are not a rite of passage he once thought but instead war is actually hell on earth where no side wins, captured perfectly in dark and sinister cinematography. Reading of the credits was like a who's who of Hollywood icons, it was probably one of the most successful bringing together of star names up until then, with the likes of; tom Berenger, Willem Dafoe (Born on the Fourth of July), Forest Whitaker (The Last King of Scotland), Keith David (The Thing), Johnny Depp (Pirates of the Caribbean) and Kevin Dillon. You are guaranteed to find a name amongst them that is one of your favourite actors. But in a sea of big names and future big names, I still felt Charlie Sheen (Hot Shots) was able to stand out and deliver a convincing portrayal of a conflicted man, caught up in the ultimate battle with himself as he has to choose between what's right and doing whatever it takes to survive, so basically choosing between safety of the body or safety of the mind. I also felt with such complex emotions he had to show at a drop of a hat, and doing them so well that it was a surprise and travesty that he wasn't nominated for a single big award. I really do feel that a man's innocents is truly lost in a war, and it is a shamed you don't get to see it played out on film, but that is what also makes Platoon so special because unlike previous films based on the war in Vietnam such as; Apocalypse Now, The Deer Hunter or Coming Home. Platoon is the very first not to look at the war from the wide perspective, and not get caught up in the big budget special effects. Instead it takes a profound and uncompromising leap into the very depths of the human condition; never shying away from exposing the sinister side to us such is in the case of Sgt. Barnes (Tom Berenger) and penetrating through the sense of false bravado to leaving a film offering a sincere exploration of self.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "Hell is the impossibility of reason"...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    aldinchova
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Rejoice O young man in thy youth" - Ecclesiastes. Written and directed by Oliver Stone, "Platoon" is considered as one of the best war movies ever made. Another masterpiece of the same director, also with Vietnam war topic is "Born on the Fourth of July" with Tom Cruise as Ron Kovic real life war veteran, based on true story. Oliver Stone took part in Vietnam war (he served there from September 1967. until November 1968. being wounded twice and receiving couple of military decorations for his participation). After he returned home he decided to put his war experiences into a script of fictionalized war story which many years later was transformed into a movie inspired by war experiences that Stone had in Vietnam. That was how "Platoon" was made. A story with authentic background. Not popular with US.Army because it is telling of highly negative side of the war (showing terrible war atrocities against civilians and horrors of fighting in the jungle) "Platoon" is a strong and emotional story about different characters of different people put together on inevitable collision course with each other. Those hidden virtues and faults of those people have always been in themselves, they are only emphasized in a war madness that surrounds them. Three main characters Sgt.Barnes (Tom Berenger) on one side, Sgt. Elias (Willem Dafoe) on the opposite one and private Chris Taylor (Charlie Sheen) between them come from different life backgrounds and often have opposite and confronting perceptions of the war and life itself. In every war, in every army, on both sides in every armed conflict there were always and there will always be people like three of them and people around them. Movie shows platoon divided between Elias and Barnes two centers of gravity and those who choose to be with one or the other. Sgt.Barnes is a battle hardened and ruthless warrior. A man who does n't care much for himself and others when it comes to having fire contact with the enemy. He lost his humanity and became like a blood thirsty animal itching for fighting because it is the only meaning of his life left. What kind of life and pain formed his personality we can only guess, but outside of war he has no place, he has no purpose. And he knows that. Deep inside he hates himself for what he is and he does n't care if he is going to live or get killed. He openly challenges others to take on him ("It's just me and six of you guys, come on, no one's gonna know") but they don't dare to do anything. Two statements define his character and beliefs, first - "Now, I got no fight with any man who does what he's told, but when he don't, the machine breaks down. And when the machine breaks down, we break down. And I ain't gonna allow that in any of you. Not one" and second - "You smoke this to escape from reality. Well, I don't need to do that, I am reality " which is kind of his life statement. Sgt. Elias is opposite of him. Battle hardened and experienced fighter too, but a man who can keep his balance, he will not cross the line, the point of no return that Sgt.Barnes crossed long time ago. Elias does n't have any illusions about the war, he had them on the beginning but they are lost meanwhile. As he says to Chris Taylor "We are going to lose this one" he considers it a wrong war to fight as he realized after disappointments that he had about its cause. If he lost his illusions he did not lose his humanity. A man who will do the right thing when it matters most and lose his life because of it. Chris Taylor is rebellious and idealistic person who escapes from life at home full of restrictions and rules trying to gain an experience of his own and what he finds is not quite as what he expected, if he had any idealistic illusions they are soon crushed by harsh realities of war and the way it transforms people pushing the best and worst in them to the limits of human tolerance. In the end he is left deeply traumatized with psychological scars that will take many years to heal and become bearable. Story about different characters of different people rejected by society but in war they have just what they need with some of them seeing it as a way to project worst parts of their personality and stay unpunished. As many other great movies, "Platoon" is a story about human character, about the best and worst in all of us. Part of us that makes us be the greatest humanists and part of us that makes us be the worst criminals. Chris Taylor puts it great when he says that he is "a child of two fathers - Elias and Barnes" because he has what both of them have. Humanity of Elias and killing instinct of Barnes because in the end he kills Barnes. Others are mere reflections like Sgt.O'Neill, an ordinary coward, psychopath Bunny, a dog of war released from his chains, or Rhah, King and Big Harold who can still find strength to joke after all. Joke is their best cure. For Chris and others there are many years left to heal from scars deep inside their souls as he says it in words that can be the point of the whole movie - "I think now looking back we did not fight the enemy, we fought ourselves and the enemy was in us... But be that as it may, those of us who did make it have an obligation to build again, to teach others what we know and to try with what's left of our lives to find a goodness and meaning to this life".
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of the most realistic war films I've ever seen
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    owenhjohnson
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Platoon" is one of the few fictional films that I find a realistic interpretation of war. It has a great story, characters to invest in, and the gritty reality of war. Oliver Stone accomplished that by basing the final battle on a battle he actually survived which probably added to the reality of the film because of Stone's survival of the Vietnam War. The film has many themes and realistic situations that you would find with non-fiction stories about the Vietnam War. Also, while I do not think it was needed, Tom Berenger made for an interesting antagonist in the film. In a lot of Vietnam films, there is always the hideout where a group of soldiers goes to get high or drunk and party. While there was that element in this film, it was done with grace and was not turned into a movie about a bunch of stoner-hippies in Vietnam. The imagery and actions by the characters that demonstrate some of the themes in the film are powerful and breathtaking. With the visuals and the actions, it feels like there were parts where that is how it actually happened during the war. Though the film sometimes went a little overboard to show the themes and to demonstrate the characters. The film has a great story and interesting characters with depth that does not take away from the action and reality of the actual fighting in the Vietnam War part.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Platoon - Review
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Daniel Metcalf
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Oliver Stone participated as an infantry soldier in the Vietnam War so what we see get in "Platoon" is a breathtaking look on the life of a soldier, shown through the eyes of a soldier named Chris who is portrayed young Charlie Sheen. Whilst the film largely showcases the negatives of war, the horrors that came with being a soldier and ultimately the mistake America made by fighting in Vietnam its primary agenda is not to be an anti-war film. In fact, the conflict between the Americans and the Vietnamese army is not the main focus of the film at all, instead it acts as a great backdrop to create a variety of situations that challenge the films characters in a number of different ways, and it is the actions and different attitudes of the characters that are important. Instead the film's conflict is between two camps that emerge as the American's divide over split attitudes. On one side we have Sgt. Barnes portrayed by Tom Berenger and on the other Sgt. Elias portrayed by Willem Dafoe. These two actors provide us with two fantastic performances and make the film what is it is. Elias can be viewed as the 'good' soldier, a kind, lesser-spoken sergeant who goes by the book and serves his country how he should. On the contrary we have Barnes, a man with a completely different set of morals, a loudmouthed soldier who will take action in to his own hands to do what he thinks is right. The divide occurs when Barnes becomes responsible for the massacre of a Vietnamese village, whilst others are willing to accept his actions and choose to protect him there are others who are not so willing to go along with a cover up including Elias. "Day by day, I struggle to maintain not only my strength but my sanity. It's all a blur. I have no energy to write. I don't know what's right and what's wrong anymore. The morale of the men is low. A civil war in the platoon. Half the men with Elias, half with Barnes. There's a lot of suspicion and hate. I can't believe we're fighting each other when we should be fighting them." That quote is from Chris, the young soldier who narrates the film for us through a series of letters sent back to his grandmother. He dropped out of college to join the army through choice and immediately struggles to fit in with the others, however throughout the film he progresses in to a more respected and adequate soldier. His progression is important to the film as he adapts to the harsh life and is influenced by others. The film's cinematography and editing is superb, most of the films scene take place in the thick forest, with extremely heavy rain painting a dark image for us that helps show the grim conditions the soldier's were really in. The film does not glorify war at all, there is no unnecessary action or over the top heroic scenes and instead everything seems real and sometimes it really is not pretty. Some scenes are really uncomfortable, especially those that involve the inhuman actions of Barnes that really do a good job of amplifying our disgust towards his character which is important as we side with Elias and Chris. Dafoe, Berenger and Sheen make this film what it is and ultimately the final scenes that involve them are the most iconic and memorable. Dafoe provides an unforgettable scene which I will not spoil. And one of the final scenes that Chris and Barnes share gives us satisfaction despite being brutal and far from a happy ending. I can not recommend this film enough; it is one of my favourite war films and a fantastic and emotional tale. Unlike other glorified films this one does not sacrifice its brutal and deeply affective centre for cheap affects and fake scenes. The heart of the film lies with its trio of star actors who are each brilliant as we see the real conflict that arises from the war and its affect within the platoon.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of the Greatest war Movies of all Time
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    josephledbury
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I am a big war movie fan and It think that this is one of the best war movies I've ever seen. It may not be as good as Apocalypse Now, but I think that this is defiantly one of the greatest war movies of all time. I first saw this and didn't notice that the main character was 21 year old Charlie Sheen, star of the TV show Two and a half Men, but I did recognize William Defoe from the movie Spiderman and I didn't recognize Tom berenger. But I think that the acting in this movie is so passionate and the reflection of their performances which is what makes this movie so realistic and tells the story of a awful war which should have never happened. The story is based on the actual experiences of Academy Award winning director Oliver Stone. What an experience that man had. Like I can't believe that the war was that bad and that in the jungle could make the soldiers lose their mind. It won four Academy Awards and well deserved for Best Sound, Best Editing, best director and coveted Best Picture of 1986. The soundtrack was defiantly what made this movie so dramatic and emotional for some. every time I hear that soundtrack, my heart just sinks. The soundtrack just hits me so fast and gets me caught up in the movie the moment the music starts. In the Top 250 with a rating of 8.2/10 and is in my top 20 favorite movies of all time. I just love this film whether it's been caught up in the dramatizations of how emotional this movie is or the fact that I love watching a movie with a lot of gun fighting. Great movie with passionate acting which expresses the very real dramatizations of a very emotional war and deserved the four Academy Awards it won.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Vietnam, the way it really was...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    robertalexanderlindsey
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Of all of the the endless movies made about the tragedies that took place in the jungles and cities of Vietnam from 1965-75, 'Platoon' is the only one that absolutely needs to be seen. Forget the far-out fantasies of 'Apocalypse Now', or the introspective ironies of 'The Deer Hunter', or the gung-ho, pro-war propaganda 'The Green Berets.' 'Platoon' puts you right in the middle of the action with an exhausted, grimy group of American troops in Vietnam, troops who've been slogging through the mud in fetid heat, bitten by leeches and menaced by North Vietnamese troops or Viet Cong who cold ambush them at any second, any time, anywhere. It also goes into other details; counting down days in-country, leeches, smoking pot in the barracks, malfunctioning claymore mines, and sudden ambushes while out on patrols... 'Platoon' shows how living under these conditions for months at a time could harden even the greenest of new recruits, or 'FNGs' (F---ing New Guys, as their more experienced colleagues liked to call them), and turn them into experienced killing machines, or something even worse. One example of this transformation is Staff Sgt. Bob Barnes, a toughened, bitter veteran who has seen combat since 1965. By 1967-68, the time in which the film begins, his entire face mirrors his experience, lacerated and deformed by his sufferings in combat. Barnes has become vicious, and is not above killing civilians or conveniently removing un-agreeable troops within his own platoon. One of these is Sgt. Elias, who has also seen combat in Vietnam since 1965. Elias is aware that America's strategy of 'winning hearts and minds' will be a failure, and that Barnes's methods are not only illegal, but destructive to the platoon... And these realizations are the reasons that Elias becomes one of Barnes's victims. And in the middle of all of this is Chris Taylor, a young college dropout who volunteered for duty in Vietnam. He is torn between the two sergeants, and when he realizes that Elias is his savior, he must act not as a human being, but as a soldier...
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Platoon is certainly one of the best films about Vietnam War and Oliver Stone's best.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    s13ky
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    If we talk about the war in Vietnam, we should talk about Platoon. It is certainly one of the best films about Vietnam War and in my opinion, it's absolutely Oliver Stone's best film since JFK and Nixon. Overall, apart from the credibility of the film director and also the authenticity in the depiction of the war, I find the screenplay, editing and film direction stand out above all, not to forget the all star casts of two famous method actors, Tom Berenger (possibly his best performance ever) and Willem Dafoe. To be honest, deep within my heart, "Platoon" ranked somewhere among "Apocalypse Now", "Full Metal Jacket" and "The Deer Hunter" (the latter isn't a war film) because of its raw visualization of the war horror that some consider a crime against humanity. I always get carried away by the spectacular music scoring, saddening, beautiful as well as frightening. The best music sequence would be "Adagio For Strings" by Samuel Barber and it's your task to find out which sequence. Oliver Stone really did well in bringing us the rich psychological portraits of soldiers who fought the popular war from a very interesting perspective, through the eyes of a rookie soldier (Charlie Sheen) who volunteered to defend his country, in a fight against communism. We witness the harsh time they faced as soon as they landed on the Saigon combat zone, in the jungle, with a simple mission of staying alive from day to day. The line between good and evil is the spot where Oliver Stone places the personal stories of the men whose horror and fear were their daily foods, real men who fought and died in the Vietnam War. This unnecessary war was taped in brutal realism. Awesome combat scenes, frank, hard and strangely beautiful. Robert Richardson as the cinematographer created a jaw-dropping atmosphere combining gray and bleak apocalyptic tones of the great wild landscapes. In conclusion, this is one of the greatest war films of cinema history, it contains some moving scenes and offers a realistic and cruel story of one of the greatest atrocities of humanity: wars.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Charlie Sheen's breakthrough performance!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jake-law123
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Not really big on Oliver Stone, but his depiction of the Vietnam war is brilliant in this heavy, dark tribute to the men who died in the war. Charlie Sheen, Tom Berenger, and Willam Dafoe all make one big triangle in this film, as it revolves around the conflict going on between them, and by them, I mean Willem Dafoe's squad, and Tom Berenger's squad in the Platoon, while Charlie Sheen is caught in the middle to deal with both, struggling to maintain his sanity as the depression of the war gets to him every day. All performances are excellent. Even though the beginning consists of Sheen being an innocent little girly man, the war progresses, and he becomes a brutal life risking grunt that ruthlessly kills everything in his path, showing how the war affects him mentally. The sound of the film sounds muddled every time somebody opens their mouth, not sure what Stone's intentions were, but it won the Oscar for sound, so whatever. The film isn't centered around combat, or the realism of war, it's centered around the duality of men, and how the war affects the minds of the soldiers, and the different types of soldiers that faced the war. The beginning scenes consist of the Platoon getting to know each other, leading up to one of the most infamous and controversial scenes in cinema history, the village. It's interesting to see different characters of different personalities conflict each other over being with a different squad leader, like are you guys in high school? Either way they find a way to make it more intense. Not too heavy on atmosphere, history, or in depth messaging like Apocalypse Now or The Deer Hunter, but it gets it around pretty easy, and the message about the war bringing out the best or the worst in men is carried out pretty easy also. Very excellent war film, isn't along the lines of Saving Private Ryan, (my favorite war film) but definitely give it a viewing.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Brilliantly Done
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    davorinlonac
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Hello fellow readers, this is a review of a film I had already reviewed but decided my old review was too dull so here is my new and improved Platoon review. Platoon is one of my favorite movies of all time for numerous reasons which will be shared throughout this review. First of all, it has my favorite soundtrack ever produced in a film, and shows you the real truth of what really happened in the war. There was a grotesque village scene which was hard to watch somehow. Willem Dafoe, Tom Berenger and Charlie sheen give on of their richest performances in my favorite Oliver stone film ever! The film was brilliantly done and can very well be the closest film which I could consider my favorite. The film is a great piece of cinema and will always be...
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Possibly Oliver Stone's best
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    sme_no_densetsu
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    To be quite honest, the first time I saw Oliver Stone's "Platoon" I was disappointed. Perhaps it was the fact that the presence of Charlie Sheen in the lead role invited comparison to "Apocalypse Now", starring his dad. However, even though both are war movies set in Viet Nam, comparing them is like comparing apples & oranges. Stone's film is, first and foremost, a movie about the experiences of 'grunts' in this bloody conflict. In place of the surreal nature of "Apocalypse Now", Stone and technical adviser Dale Dye brought a sense of realism to the picture. That being said, while realism was enforced, Stone still managed to imbue his script with deeper meaning. The story revolves around young volunteer Chris Taylor (Charlie Sheen) as he arrives in Viet Nam and quickly becomes acquainted with the horrors of war. Apart from the enemy, there's conflict among the soldiers themselves, as a rift develops between the compassionate Sgt. Elias (Willem Dafoe) and the ruthless Sgt. Barnes (Tom Berenger). Despite the fact that Charlie Sheen is in the lead role, the acting is actually pretty strong. Berenger & Dafoe were both nominated for Academy Awards but they ended up losing to Michael Caine. The large ensemble cast includes several recognizable actors, often contributing memorable performances. Notable names include Keith David, Forest Whitaker, John C. McGinley, Kevin Dillon and even a young Johnny Depp. Stone's direction won him one of the film's four Academy Awards. Another Oscar deservedly rewarded the sound department for their contribution to the film. Also notable was the extensive (and effective) use of Samuel Barber's "Adagio for Strings". Both visually and sonically, the movie is impressive. Ultimately, "Platoon" isn't quite perfect but it's definitely good enough that I'm glad I gave it a second chance. The movie's realism is commendable and the storyline is thought-provoking. It may be no match for "Apocalypse Now" but that only means that it's just a very good movie and not a masterpiece.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    In war no one wins
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    silva-w-pius
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "First real casualty of war is innocents; the first real movie on the war in Vietnam is Platoon" That is a quote from the trailer that I felt encompassed what I felt about Platoon to a T. What makes Platoon so realistic is that it is part of those rare occasions where you have a story born from a director's firsthand experience, but that's what you get with Oliver stone, who served as an infantry soldier in Vietnam, allowing him to create an almost autobiographical account, and in some instances a documentary into the under belly and less glamour side of war  and by glamorous I mean not a place where you shot bad guys, then come home to a giant marching band and a handshake from the president, but instead it's actually a place where real and sometimes innocent people die. With so much realism it should be no surprise that Platoon won four Oscars in 86 in the best director, picture, sound and cinematography categories. Platoon tells the story of a student named Chris Taylor (Charlie Sheen) in the late 60's who joins up for the army believing in his heart that he is fulfilling his patriotic duty, and I feel in some part that deep down he believes that he will go to Vietnam fire a few bullets and return as a hero. But upon reaching, he joins up with a diverse platoon of men, in the outside world would probably never rub shoulders with, but here they move as one, lead by two men; Sgt. Barnes (Tom Berenger) a man with a scared appearance, that adds to his mystical aura of being a man that cannot be killed and the other Sgt. Elias (Willem Dafoe) who through the use of mind altering drugs is able to maintain an air of calm. But Chris Taylor's dreams of heroism are quickly obliterated as they delve deeper into enemy territory, witnessing acts of despicable evil towards his fellow man by the very same men he serves within the same platoon, making him quickly realises how naive his ideas of war as they are not a rite of passage he once thought but instead war is actually hell on earth where no side wins, captured perfectly in dark and sinister cinematography. Reading of the credits was like a who's who of Hollywood icons, it was probably one of the most successful bringing together of star names up until then, with the likes of; tom Berenger, Willem Dafoe (Born on the Fourth of July), Forest Whitaker (The Last King of Scotland), Keith David (The Thing), Johnny Depp (Pirates of the Caribbean) and Kevin Dillon. You are guaranteed to find a name amongst them that is one of your favourite actors. But in a sea of big names and future big names, I still felt Charlie Sheen (Hot Shots) was able to stand out and deliver a convincing portrayal of a conflicted man, caught up in the ultimate battle with himself as he has to choose between what's right and doing whatever it takes to survive, so basically choosing between safety of the body or safety of the mind. I also felt with such complex emotions he had to show at a drop of a hat, and doing them so well that it was a surprise and travesty that he wasn't nominated for a single big award. I really do feel that a man's innocents is truly lost in a war, and it is a shamed you don't get to see it played out on film, but that is what also makes Platoon so special because unlike previous films based on the war in Vietnam such as; Apocalypse Now, The Deer Hunter or Coming Home. Platoon is the very first not to look at the war from the wide perspective, and not get caught up in the big budget special effects. Instead it takes a profound and uncompromising leap into the very depths of the human condition; never shying away from exposing the sinister side to us such is in the case of Sgt. Barnes (Tom Berenger) and penetrating through the sense of false bravado to leaving a film offering a sincere exploration of self.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "Hell is the impossibility of reason"...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    aldinchova
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Rejoice O young man in thy youth" - Ecclesiastes. Written and directed by Oliver Stone, "Platoon" is considered as one of the best war movies ever made. Another masterpiece of the same director, also with Vietnam war topic is "Born on the Fourth of July" with Tom Cruise as Ron Kovic real life war veteran, based on true story. Oliver Stone took part in Vietnam war (he served there from September 1967. until November 1968. being wounded twice and receiving couple of military decorations for his participation). After he returned home he decided to put his war experiences into a script of fictionalized war story which many years later was transformed into a movie inspired by war experiences that Stone had in Vietnam. That was how "Platoon" was made. A story with authentic background. Not popular with US.Army because it is telling of highly negative side of the war (showing terrible war atrocities against civilians and horrors of fighting in the jungle) "Platoon" is a strong and emotional story about different characters of different people put together on inevitable collision course with each other. Those hidden virtues and faults of those people have always been in themselves, they are only emphasized in a war madness that surrounds them. Three main characters Sgt.Barnes (Tom Berenger) on one side, Sgt. Elias (Willem Dafoe) on the opposite one and private Chris Taylor (Charlie Sheen) between them come from different life backgrounds and often have opposite and confronting perceptions of the war and life itself. In every war, in every army, on both sides in every armed conflict there were always and there will always be people like three of them and people around them. Movie shows platoon divided between Elias and Barnes two centers of gravity and those who choose to be with one or the other. Sgt.Barnes is a battle hardened and ruthless warrior. A man who does n't care much for himself and others when it comes to having fire contact with the enemy. He lost his humanity and became like a blood thirsty animal itching for fighting because it is the only meaning of his life left. What kind of life and pain formed his personality we can only guess, but outside of war he has no place, he has no purpose. And he knows that. Deep inside he hates himself for what he is and he does n't care if he is going to live or get killed. He openly challenges others to take on him ("It's just me and six of you guys, come on, no one's gonna know") but they don't dare to do anything. Two statements define his character and beliefs, first - "Now, I got no fight with any man who does what he's told, but when he don't, the machine breaks down. And when the machine breaks down, we break down. And I ain't gonna allow that in any of you. Not one" and second - "You smoke this to escape from reality. Well, I don't need to do that, I am reality " which is kind of his life statement. Sgt. Elias is opposite of him. Battle hardened and experienced fighter too, but a man who can keep his balance, he will not cross the line, the point of no return that Sgt.Barnes crossed long time ago. Elias does n't have any illusions about the war, he had them on the beginning but they are lost meanwhile. As he says to Chris Taylor "We are going to lose this one" he considers it a wrong war to fight as he realized after disappointments that he had about its cause. If he lost his illusions he did not lose his humanity. A man who will do the right thing when it matters most and lose his life because of it. Chris Taylor is rebellious and idealistic person who escapes from life at home full of restrictions and rules trying to gain an experience of his own and what he finds is not quite as what he expected, if he had any idealistic illusions they are soon crushed by harsh realities of war and the way it transforms people pushing the best and worst in them to the limits of human tolerance. In the end he is left deeply traumatized with psychological scars that will take many years to heal and become bearable. Story about different characters of different people rejected by society but in war they have just what they need with some of them seeing it as a way to project worst parts of their personality and stay unpunished. As many other great movies, "Platoon" is a story about human character, about the best and worst in all of us. Part of us that makes us be the greatest humanists and part of us that makes us be the worst criminals. Chris Taylor puts it great when he says that he is "a child of two fathers - Elias and Barnes" because he has what both of them have. Humanity of Elias and killing instinct of Barnes because in the end he kills Barnes. Others are mere reflections like Sgt.O'Neill, an ordinary coward, psychopath Bunny, a dog of war released from his chains, or Rhah, King and Big Harold who can still find strength to joke after all. Joke is their best cure. For Chris and others there are many years left to heal from scars deep inside their souls as he says it in words that can be the point of the whole movie - "I think now looking back we did not fight the enemy, we fought ourselves and the enemy was in us... But be that as it may, those of us who did make it have an obligation to build again, to teach others what we know and to try with what's left of our lives to find a goodness and meaning to this life".
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of the most realistic war films I've ever seen
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    owenhjohnson
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Platoon" is one of the few fictional films that I find a realistic interpretation of war. It has a great story, characters to invest in, and the gritty reality of war. Oliver Stone accomplished that by basing the final battle on a battle he actually survived which probably added to the reality of the film because of Stone's survival of the Vietnam War. The film has many themes and realistic situations that you would find with non-fiction stories about the Vietnam War. Also, while I do not think it was needed, Tom Berenger made for an interesting antagonist in the film. In a lot of Vietnam films, there is always the hideout where a group of soldiers goes to get high or drunk and party. While there was that element in this film, it was done with grace and was not turned into a movie about a bunch of stoner-hippies in Vietnam. The imagery and actions by the characters that demonstrate some of the themes in the film are powerful and breathtaking. With the visuals and the actions, it feels like there were parts where that is how it actually happened during the war. Though the film sometimes went a little overboard to show the themes and to demonstrate the characters. The film has a great story and interesting characters with depth that does not take away from the action and reality of the actual fighting in the Vietnam War part.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Platoon - Review
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Daniel Metcalf
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Oliver Stone participated as an infantry soldier in the Vietnam War so what we see get in "Platoon" is a breathtaking look on the life of a soldier, shown through the eyes of a soldier named Chris who is portrayed young Charlie Sheen. Whilst the film largely showcases the negatives of war, the horrors that came with being a soldier and ultimately the mistake America made by fighting in Vietnam its primary agenda is not to be an anti-war film. In fact, the conflict between the Americans and the Vietnamese army is not the main focus of the film at all, instead it acts as a great backdrop to create a variety of situations that challenge the films characters in a number of different ways, and it is the actions and different attitudes of the characters that are important. Instead the film's conflict is between two camps that emerge as the American's divide over split attitudes. On one side we have Sgt. Barnes portrayed by Tom Berenger and on the other Sgt. Elias portrayed by Willem Dafoe. These two actors provide us with two fantastic performances and make the film what is it is. Elias can be viewed as the 'good' soldier, a kind, lesser-spoken sergeant who goes by the book and serves his country how he should. On the contrary we have Barnes, a man with a completely different set of morals, a loudmouthed soldier who will take action in to his own hands to do what he thinks is right. The divide occurs when Barnes becomes responsible for the massacre of a Vietnamese village, whilst others are willing to accept his actions and choose to protect him there are others who are not so willing to go along with a cover up including Elias. "Day by day, I struggle to maintain not only my strength but my sanity. It's all a blur. I have no energy to write. I don't know what's right and what's wrong anymore. The morale of the men is low. A civil war in the platoon. Half the men with Elias, half with Barnes. There's a lot of suspicion and hate. I can't believe we're fighting each other when we should be fighting them." That quote is from Chris, the young soldier who narrates the film for us through a series of letters sent back to his grandmother. He dropped out of college to join the army through choice and immediately struggles to fit in with the others, however throughout the film he progresses in to a more respected and adequate soldier. His progression is important to the film as he adapts to the harsh life and is influenced by others. The film's cinematography and editing is superb, most of the films scene take place in the thick forest, with extremely heavy rain painting a dark image for us that helps show the grim conditions the soldier's were really in. The film does not glorify war at all, there is no unnecessary action or over the top heroic scenes and instead everything seems real and sometimes it really is not pretty. Some scenes are really uncomfortable, especially those that involve the inhuman actions of Barnes that really do a good job of amplifying our disgust towards his character which is important as we side with Elias and Chris. Dafoe, Berenger and Sheen make this film what it is and ultimately the final scenes that involve them are the most iconic and memorable. Dafoe provides an unforgettable scene which I will not spoil. And one of the final scenes that Chris and Barnes share gives us satisfaction despite being brutal and far from a happy ending. I can not recommend this film enough; it is one of my favourite war films and a fantastic and emotional tale. Unlike other glorified films this one does not sacrifice its brutal and deeply affective centre for cheap affects and fake scenes. The heart of the film lies with its trio of star actors who are each brilliant as we see the real conflict that arises from the war and its affect within the platoon.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of the Greatest war Movies of all Time
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    josephledbury
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I am a big war movie fan and It think that this is one of the best war movies I've ever seen. It may not be as good as Apocalypse Now, but I think that this is defiantly one of the greatest war movies of all time. I first saw this and didn't notice that the main character was 21 year old Charlie Sheen, star of the TV show Two and a half Men, but I did recognize William Defoe from the movie Spiderman and I didn't recognize Tom berenger. But I think that the acting in this movie is so passionate and the reflection of their performances which is what makes this movie so realistic and tells the story of a awful war which should have never happened. The story is based on the actual experiences of Academy Award winning director Oliver Stone. What an experience that man had. Like I can't believe that the war was that bad and that in the jungle could make the soldiers lose their mind. It won four Academy Awards and well deserved for Best Sound, Best Editing, best director and coveted Best Picture of 1986. The soundtrack was defiantly what made this movie so dramatic and emotional for some. every time I hear that soundtrack, my heart just sinks. The soundtrack just hits me so fast and gets me caught up in the movie the moment the music starts. In the Top 250 with a rating of 8.2/10 and is in my top 20 favorite movies of all time. I just love this film whether it's been caught up in the dramatizations of how emotional this movie is or the fact that I love watching a movie with a lot of gun fighting. Great movie with passionate acting which expresses the very real dramatizations of a very emotional war and deserved the four Academy Awards it won.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Vietnam, the way it really was...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    robertalexanderlindsey
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Of all of the the endless movies made about the tragedies that took place in the jungles and cities of Vietnam from 1965-75, 'Platoon' is the only one that absolutely needs to be seen. Forget the far-out fantasies of 'Apocalypse Now', or the introspective ironies of 'The Deer Hunter', or the gung-ho, pro-war propaganda 'The Green Berets.' 'Platoon' puts you right in the middle of the action with an exhausted, grimy group of American troops in Vietnam, troops who've been slogging through the mud in fetid heat, bitten by leeches and menaced by North Vietnamese troops or Viet Cong who cold ambush them at any second, any time, anywhere. It also goes into other details; counting down days in-country, leeches, smoking pot in the barracks, malfunctioning claymore mines, and sudden ambushes while out on patrols... 'Platoon' shows how living under these conditions for months at a time could harden even the greenest of new recruits, or 'FNGs' (F---ing New Guys, as their more experienced colleagues liked to call them), and turn them into experienced killing machines, or something even worse. One example of this transformation is Staff Sgt. Bob Barnes, a toughened, bitter veteran who has seen combat since 1965. By 1967-68, the time in which the film begins, his entire face mirrors his experience, lacerated and deformed by his sufferings in combat. Barnes has become vicious, and is not above killing civilians or conveniently removing un-agreeable troops within his own platoon. One of these is Sgt. Elias, who has also seen combat in Vietnam since 1965. Elias is aware that America's strategy of 'winning hearts and minds' will be a failure, and that Barnes's methods are not only illegal, but destructive to the platoon... And these realizations are the reasons that Elias becomes one of Barnes's victims. And in the middle of all of this is Chris Taylor, a young college dropout who volunteered for duty in Vietnam. He is torn between the two sergeants, and when he realizes that Elias is his savior, he must act not as a human being, but as a soldier...
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Platoon is certainly one of the best films about Vietnam War and Oliver Stone's best.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    s13ky
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    If we talk about the war in Vietnam, we should talk about Platoon. It is certainly one of the best films about Vietnam War and in my opinion, it's absolutely Oliver Stone's best film since JFK and Nixon. Overall, apart from the credibility of the film director and also the authenticity in the depiction of the war, I find the screenplay, editing and film direction stand out above all, not to forget the all star casts of two famous method actors, Tom Berenger (possibly his best performance ever) and Willem Dafoe. To be honest, deep within my heart, "Platoon" ranked somewhere among "Apocalypse Now", "Full Metal Jacket" and "The Deer Hunter" (the latter isn't a war film) because of its raw visualization of the war horror that some consider a crime against humanity. I always get carried away by the spectacular music scoring, saddening, beautiful as well as frightening. The best music sequence would be "Adagio For Strings" by Samuel Barber and it's your task to find out which sequence. Oliver Stone really did well in bringing us the rich psychological portraits of soldiers who fought the popular war from a very interesting perspective, through the eyes of a rookie soldier (Charlie Sheen) who volunteered to defend his country, in a fight against communism. We witness the harsh time they faced as soon as they landed on the Saigon combat zone, in the jungle, with a simple mission of staying alive from day to day. The line between good and evil is the spot where Oliver Stone places the personal stories of the men whose horror and fear were their daily foods, real men who fought and died in the Vietnam War. This unnecessary war was taped in brutal realism. Awesome combat scenes, frank, hard and strangely beautiful. Robert Richardson as the cinematographer created a jaw-dropping atmosphere combining gray and bleak apocalyptic tones of the great wild landscapes. In conclusion, this is one of the greatest war films of cinema history, it contains some moving scenes and offers a realistic and cruel story of one of the greatest atrocities of humanity: wars.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Charlie Sheen's breakthrough performance!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jake-law123
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Not really big on Oliver Stone, but his depiction of the Vietnam war is brilliant in this heavy, dark tribute to the men who died in the war. Charlie Sheen, Tom Berenger, and Willam Dafoe all make one big triangle in this film, as it revolves around the conflict going on between them, and by them, I mean Willem Dafoe's squad, and Tom Berenger's squad in the Platoon, while Charlie Sheen is caught in the middle to deal with both, struggling to maintain his sanity as the depression of the war gets to him every day. All performances are excellent. Even though the beginning consists of Sheen being an innocent little girly man, the war progresses, and he becomes a brutal life risking grunt that ruthlessly kills everything in his path, showing how the war affects him mentally. The sound of the film sounds muddled every time somebody opens their mouth, not sure what Stone's intentions were, but it won the Oscar for sound, so whatever. The film isn't centered around combat, or the realism of war, it's centered around the duality of men, and how the war affects the minds of the soldiers, and the different types of soldiers that faced the war. The beginning scenes consist of the Platoon getting to know each other, leading up to one of the most infamous and controversial scenes in cinema history, the village. It's interesting to see different characters of different personalities conflict each other over being with a different squad leader, like are you guys in high school? Either way they find a way to make it more intense. Not too heavy on atmosphere, history, or in depth messaging like Apocalypse Now or The Deer Hunter, but it gets it around pretty easy, and the message about the war bringing out the best or the worst in men is carried out pretty easy also. Very excellent war film, isn't along the lines of Saving Private Ryan, (my favorite war film) but definitely give it a viewing.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Brilliantly Done
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    davorinlonac
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Hello fellow readers, this is a review of a film I had already reviewed but decided my old review was too dull so here is my new and improved Platoon review. Platoon is one of my favorite movies of all time for numerous reasons which will be shared throughout this review. First of all, it has my favorite soundtrack ever produced in a film, and shows you the real truth of what really happened in the war. There was a grotesque village scene which was hard to watch somehow. Willem Dafoe, Tom Berenger and Charlie sheen give on of their richest performances in my favorite Oliver stone film ever! The film was brilliantly done and can very well be the closest film which I could consider my favorite. The film is a great piece of cinema and will always be...
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Possibly Oliver Stone's best
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    sme_no_densetsu
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    To be quite honest, the first time I saw Oliver Stone's "Platoon" I was disappointed. Perhaps it was the fact that the presence of Charlie Sheen in the lead role invited comparison to "Apocalypse Now", starring his dad. However, even though both are war movies set in Viet Nam, comparing them is like comparing apples & oranges. Stone's film is, first and foremost, a movie about the experiences of 'grunts' in this bloody conflict. In place of the surreal nature of "Apocalypse Now", Stone and technical adviser Dale Dye brought a sense of realism to the picture. That being said, while realism was enforced, Stone still managed to imbue his script with deeper meaning. The story revolves around young volunteer Chris Taylor (Charlie Sheen) as he arrives in Viet Nam and quickly becomes acquainted with the horrors of war. Apart from the enemy, there's conflict among the soldiers themselves, as a rift develops between the compassionate Sgt. Elias (Willem Dafoe) and the ruthless Sgt. Barnes (Tom Berenger). Despite the fact that Charlie Sheen is in the lead role, the acting is actually pretty strong. Berenger & Dafoe were both nominated for Academy Awards but they ended up losing to Michael Caine. The large ensemble cast includes several recognizable actors, often contributing memorable performances. Notable names include Keith David, Forest Whitaker, John C. McGinley, Kevin Dillon and even a young Johnny Depp. Stone's direction won him one of the film's four Academy Awards. Another Oscar deservedly rewarded the sound department for their contribution to the film. Also notable was the extensive (and effective) use of Samuel Barber's "Adagio for Strings". Both visually and sonically, the movie is impressive. Ultimately, "Platoon" isn't quite perfect but it's definitely good enough that I'm glad I gave it a second chance. The movie's realism is commendable and the storyline is thought-provoking. It may be no match for "Apocalypse Now" but that only means that it's just a very good movie and not a masterpiece.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    In war no one wins
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    silva-w-pius
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "First real casualty of war is innocents; the first real movie on the war in Vietnam is Platoon" That is a quote from the trailer that I felt encompassed what I felt about Platoon to a T. What makes Platoon so realistic is that it is part of those rare occasions where you have a story born from a director's firsthand experience, but that's what you get with Oliver stone, who served as an infantry soldier in Vietnam, allowing him to create an almost autobiographical account, and in some instances a documentary into the under belly and less glamour side of war  and by glamorous I mean not a place where you shot bad guys, then come home to a giant marching band and a handshake from the president, but instead it's actually a place where real and sometimes innocent people die. With so much realism it should be no surprise that Platoon won four Oscars in 86 in the best director, picture, sound and cinematography categories. Platoon tells the story of a student named Chris Taylor (Charlie Sheen) in the late 60's who joins up for the army believing in his heart that he is fulfilling his patriotic duty, and I feel in some part that deep down he believes that he will go to Vietnam fire a few bullets and return as a hero. But upon reaching, he joins up with a diverse platoon of men, in the outside world would probably never rub shoulders with, but here they move as one, lead by two men; Sgt. Barnes (Tom Berenger) a man with a scared appearance, that adds to his mystical aura of being a man that cannot be killed and the other Sgt. Elias (Willem Dafoe) who through the use of mind altering drugs is able to maintain an air of calm. But Chris Taylor's dreams of heroism are quickly obliterated as they delve deeper into enemy territory, witnessing acts of despicable evil towards his fellow man by the very same men he serves within the same platoon, making him quickly realises how naive his ideas of war as they are not a rite of passage he once thought but instead war is actually hell on earth where no side wins, captured perfectly in dark and sinister cinematography. Reading of the credits was like a who's who of Hollywood icons, it was probably one of the most successful bringing together of star names up until then, with the likes of; tom Berenger, Willem Dafoe (Born on the Fourth of July), Forest Whitaker (The Last King of Scotland), Keith David (The Thing), Johnny Depp (Pirates of the Caribbean) and Kevin Dillon. You are guaranteed to find a name amongst them that is one of your favourite actors. But in a sea of big names and future big names, I still felt Charlie Sheen (Hot Shots) was able to stand out and deliver a convincing portrayal of a conflicted man, caught up in the ultimate battle with himself as he has to choose between what's right and doing whatever it takes to survive, so basically choosing between safety of the body or safety of the mind. I also felt with such complex emotions he had to show at a drop of a hat, and doing them so well that it was a surprise and travesty that he wasn't nominated for a single big award. I really do feel that a man's innocents is truly lost in a war, and it is a shamed you don't get to see it played out on film, but that is what also makes Platoon so special because unlike previous films based on the war in Vietnam such as; Apocalypse Now, The Deer Hunter or Coming Home. Platoon is the very first not to look at the war from the wide perspective, and not get caught up in the big budget special effects. Instead it takes a profound and uncompromising leap into the very depths of the human condition; never shying away from exposing the sinister side to us such is in the case of Sgt. Barnes (Tom Berenger) and penetrating through the sense of false bravado to leaving a film offering a sincere exploration of self.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "Hell is the impossibility of reason"...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    aldinchova
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Rejoice O young man in thy youth" - Ecclesiastes. Written and directed by Oliver Stone, "Platoon" is considered as one of the best war movies ever made. Another masterpiece of the same director, also with Vietnam war topic is "Born on the Fourth of July" with Tom Cruise as Ron Kovic real life war veteran, based on true story. Oliver Stone took part in Vietnam war (he served there from September 1967. until November 1968. being wounded twice and receiving couple of military decorations for his participation). After he returned home he decided to put his war experiences into a script of fictionalized war story which many years later was transformed into a movie inspired by war experiences that Stone had in Vietnam. That was how "Platoon" was made. A story with authentic background. Not popular with US.Army because it is telling of highly negative side of the war (showing terrible war atrocities against civilians and horrors of fighting in the jungle) "Platoon" is a strong and emotional story about different characters of different people put together on inevitable collision course with each other. Those hidden virtues and faults of those people have always been in themselves, they are only emphasized in a war madness that surrounds them. Three main characters Sgt.Barnes (Tom Berenger) on one side, Sgt. Elias (Willem Dafoe) on the opposite one and private Chris Taylor (Charlie Sheen) between them come from different life backgrounds and often have opposite and confronting perceptions of the war and life itself. In every war, in every army, on both sides in every armed conflict there were always and there will always be people like three of them and people around them. Movie shows platoon divided between Elias and Barnes two centers of gravity and those who choose to be with one or the other. Sgt.Barnes is a battle hardened and ruthless warrior. A man who does n't care much for himself and others when it comes to having fire contact with the enemy. He lost his humanity and became like a blood thirsty animal itching for fighting because it is the only meaning of his life left. What kind of life and pain formed his personality we can only guess, but outside of war he has no place, he has no purpose. And he knows that. Deep inside he hates himself for what he is and he does n't care if he is going to live or get killed. He openly challenges others to take on him ("It's just me and six of you guys, come on, no one's gonna know") but they don't dare to do anything. Two statements define his character and beliefs, first - "Now, I got no fight with any man who does what he's told, but when he don't, the machine breaks down. And when the machine breaks down, we break down. And I ain't gonna allow that in any of you. Not one" and second - "You smoke this to escape from reality. Well, I don't need to do that, I am reality " which is kind of his life statement. Sgt. Elias is opposite of him. Battle hardened and experienced fighter too, but a man who can keep his balance, he will not cross the line, the point of no return that Sgt.Barnes crossed long time ago. Elias does n't have any illusions about the war, he had them on the beginning but they are lost meanwhile. As he says to Chris Taylor "We are going to lose this one" he considers it a wrong war to fight as he realized after disappointments that he had about its cause. If he lost his illusions he did not lose his humanity. A man who will do the right thing when it matters most and lose his life because of it. Chris Taylor is rebellious and idealistic person who escapes from life at home full of restrictions and rules trying to gain an experience of his own and what he finds is not quite as what he expected, if he had any idealistic illusions they are soon crushed by harsh realities of war and the way it transforms people pushing the best and worst in them to the limits of human tolerance. In the end he is left deeply traumatized with psychological scars that will take many years to heal and become bearable. Story about different characters of different people rejected by society but in war they have just what they need with some of them seeing it as a way to project worst parts of their personality and stay unpunished. As many other great movies, "Platoon" is a story about human character, about the best and worst in all of us. Part of us that makes us be the greatest humanists and part of us that makes us be the worst criminals. Chris Taylor puts it great when he says that he is "a child of two fathers - Elias and Barnes" because he has what both of them have. Humanity of Elias and killing instinct of Barnes because in the end he kills Barnes. Others are mere reflections like Sgt.O'Neill, an ordinary coward, psychopath Bunny, a dog of war released from his chains, or Rhah, King and Big Harold who can still find strength to joke after all. Joke is their best cure. For Chris and others there are many years left to heal from scars deep inside their souls as he says it in words that can be the point of the whole movie - "I think now looking back we did not fight the enemy, we fought ourselves and the enemy was in us... But be that as it may, those of us who did make it have an obligation to build again, to teach others what we know and to try with what's left of our lives to find a goodness and meaning to this life".
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of the most realistic war films I've ever seen
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    owenhjohnson
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Platoon" is one of the few fictional films that I find a realistic interpretation of war. It has a great story, characters to invest in, and the gritty reality of war. Oliver Stone accomplished that by basing the final battle on a battle he actually survived which probably added to the reality of the film because of Stone's survival of the Vietnam War. The film has many themes and realistic situations that you would find with non-fiction stories about the Vietnam War. Also, while I do not think it was needed, Tom Berenger made for an interesting antagonist in the film. In a lot of Vietnam films, there is always the hideout where a group of soldiers goes to get high or drunk and party. While there was that element in this film, it was done with grace and was not turned into a movie about a bunch of stoner-hippies in Vietnam. The imagery and actions by the characters that demonstrate some of the themes in the film are powerful and breathtaking. With the visuals and the actions, it feels like there were parts where that is how it actually happened during the war. Though the film sometimes went a little overboard to show the themes and to demonstrate the characters. The film has a great story and interesting characters with depth that does not take away from the action and reality of the actual fighting in the Vietnam War part.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Platoon - Review
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Daniel Metcalf
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Oliver Stone participated as an infantry soldier in the Vietnam War so what we see get in "Platoon" is a breathtaking look on the life of a soldier, shown through the eyes of a soldier named Chris who is portrayed young Charlie Sheen. Whilst the film largely showcases the negatives of war, the horrors that came with being a soldier and ultimately the mistake America made by fighting in Vietnam its primary agenda is not to be an anti-war film. In fact, the conflict between the Americans and the Vietnamese army is not the main focus of the film at all, instead it acts as a great backdrop to create a variety of situations that challenge the films characters in a number of different ways, and it is the actions and different attitudes of the characters that are important. Instead the film's conflict is between two camps that emerge as the American's divide over split attitudes. On one side we have Sgt. Barnes portrayed by Tom Berenger and on the other Sgt. Elias portrayed by Willem Dafoe. These two actors provide us with two fantastic performances and make the film what is it is. Elias can be viewed as the 'good' soldier, a kind, lesser-spoken sergeant who goes by the book and serves his country how he should. On the contrary we have Barnes, a man with a completely different set of morals, a loudmouthed soldier who will take action in to his own hands to do what he thinks is right. The divide occurs when Barnes becomes responsible for the massacre of a Vietnamese village, whilst others are willing to accept his actions and choose to protect him there are others who are not so willing to go along with a cover up including Elias. "Day by day, I struggle to maintain not only my strength but my sanity. It's all a blur. I have no energy to write. I don't know what's right and what's wrong anymore. The morale of the men is low. A civil war in the platoon. Half the men with Elias, half with Barnes. There's a lot of suspicion and hate. I can't believe we're fighting each other when we should be fighting them." That quote is from Chris, the young soldier who narrates the film for us through a series of letters sent back to his grandmother. He dropped out of college to join the army through choice and immediately struggles to fit in with the others, however throughout the film he progresses in to a more respected and adequate soldier. His progression is important to the film as he adapts to the harsh life and is influenced by others. The film's cinematography and editing is superb, most of the films scene take place in the thick forest, with extremely heavy rain painting a dark image for us that helps show the grim conditions the soldier's were really in. The film does not glorify war at all, there is no unnecessary action or over the top heroic scenes and instead everything seems real and sometimes it really is not pretty. Some scenes are really uncomfortable, especially those that involve the inhuman actions of Barnes that really do a good job of amplifying our disgust towards his character which is important as we side with Elias and Chris. Dafoe, Berenger and Sheen make this film what it is and ultimately the final scenes that involve them are the most iconic and memorable. Dafoe provides an unforgettable scene which I will not spoil. And one of the final scenes that Chris and Barnes share gives us satisfaction despite being brutal and far from a happy ending. I can not recommend this film enough; it is one of my favourite war films and a fantastic and emotional tale. Unlike other glorified films this one does not sacrifice its brutal and deeply affective centre for cheap affects and fake scenes. The heart of the film lies with its trio of star actors who are each brilliant as we see the real conflict that arises from the war and its affect within the platoon.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of the Greatest war Movies of all Time
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    josephledbury
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I am a big war movie fan and It think that this is one of the best war movies I've ever seen. It may not be as good as Apocalypse Now, but I think that this is defiantly one of the greatest war movies of all time. I first saw this and didn't notice that the main character was 21 year old Charlie Sheen, star of the TV show Two and a half Men, but I did recognize William Defoe from the movie Spiderman and I didn't recognize Tom berenger. But I think that the acting in this movie is so passionate and the reflection of their performances which is what makes this movie so realistic and tells the story of a awful war which should have never happened. The story is based on the actual experiences of Academy Award winning director Oliver Stone. What an experience that man had. Like I can't believe that the war was that bad and that in the jungle could make the soldiers lose their mind. It won four Academy Awards and well deserved for Best Sound, Best Editing, best director and coveted Best Picture of 1986. The soundtrack was defiantly what made this movie so dramatic and emotional for some. every time I hear that soundtrack, my heart just sinks. The soundtrack just hits me so fast and gets me caught up in the movie the moment the music starts. In the Top 250 with a rating of 8.2/10 and is in my top 20 favorite movies of all time. I just love this film whether it's been caught up in the dramatizations of how emotional this movie is or the fact that I love watching a movie with a lot of gun fighting. Great movie with passionate acting which expresses the very real dramatizations of a very emotional war and deserved the four Academy Awards it won.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Vietnam, the way it really was...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    robertalexanderlindsey
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Of all of the the endless movies made about the tragedies that took place in the jungles and cities of Vietnam from 1965-75, 'Platoon' is the only one that absolutely needs to be seen. Forget the far-out fantasies of 'Apocalypse Now', or the introspective ironies of 'The Deer Hunter', or the gung-ho, pro-war propaganda 'The Green Berets.' 'Platoon' puts you right in the middle of the action with an exhausted, grimy group of American troops in Vietnam, troops who've been slogging through the mud in fetid heat, bitten by leeches and menaced by North Vietnamese troops or Viet Cong who cold ambush them at any second, any time, anywhere. It also goes into other details; counting down days in-country, leeches, smoking pot in the barracks, malfunctioning claymore mines, and sudden ambushes while out on patrols... 'Platoon' shows how living under these conditions for months at a time could harden even the greenest of new recruits, or 'FNGs' (F---ing New Guys, as their more experienced colleagues liked to call them), and turn them into experienced killing machines, or something even worse. One example of this transformation is Staff Sgt. Bob Barnes, a toughened, bitter veteran who has seen combat since 1965. By 1967-68, the time in which the film begins, his entire face mirrors his experience, lacerated and deformed by his sufferings in combat. Barnes has become vicious, and is not above killing civilians or conveniently removing un-agreeable troops within his own platoon. One of these is Sgt. Elias, who has also seen combat in Vietnam since 1965. Elias is aware that America's strategy of 'winning hearts and minds' will be a failure, and that Barnes's methods are not only illegal, but destructive to the platoon... And these realizations are the reasons that Elias becomes one of Barnes's victims. And in the middle of all of this is Chris Taylor, a young college dropout who volunteered for duty in Vietnam. He is torn between the two sergeants, and when he realizes that Elias is his savior, he must act not as a human being, but as a soldier...
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Platoon is certainly one of the best films about Vietnam War and Oliver Stone's best.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    s13ky
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    If we talk about the war in Vietnam, we should talk about Platoon. It is certainly one of the best films about Vietnam War and in my opinion, it's absolutely Oliver Stone's best film since JFK and Nixon. Overall, apart from the credibility of the film director and also the authenticity in the depiction of the war, I find the screenplay, editing and film direction stand out above all, not to forget the all star casts of two famous method actors, Tom Berenger (possibly his best performance ever) and Willem Dafoe. To be honest, deep within my heart, "Platoon" ranked somewhere among "Apocalypse Now", "Full Metal Jacket" and "The Deer Hunter" (the latter isn't a war film) because of its raw visualization of the war horror that some consider a crime against humanity. I always get carried away by the spectacular music scoring, saddening, beautiful as well as frightening. The best music sequence would be "Adagio For Strings" by Samuel Barber and it's your task to find out which sequence. Oliver Stone really did well in bringing us the rich psychological portraits of soldiers who fought the popular war from a very interesting perspective, through the eyes of a rookie soldier (Charlie Sheen) who volunteered to defend his country, in a fight against communism. We witness the harsh time they faced as soon as they landed on the Saigon combat zone, in the jungle, with a simple mission of staying alive from day to day. The line between good and evil is the spot where Oliver Stone places the personal stories of the men whose horror and fear were their daily foods, real men who fought and died in the Vietnam War. This unnecessary war was taped in brutal realism. Awesome combat scenes, frank, hard and strangely beautiful. Robert Richardson as the cinematographer created a jaw-dropping atmosphere combining gray and bleak apocalyptic tones of the great wild landscapes. In conclusion, this is one of the greatest war films of cinema history, it contains some moving scenes and offers a realistic and cruel story of one of the greatest atrocities of humanity: wars.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Charlie Sheen's breakthrough performance!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jake-law123
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Not really big on Oliver Stone, but his depiction of the Vietnam war is brilliant in this heavy, dark tribute to the men who died in the war. Charlie Sheen, Tom Berenger, and Willam Dafoe all make one big triangle in this film, as it revolves around the conflict going on between them, and by them, I mean Willem Dafoe's squad, and Tom Berenger's squad in the Platoon, while Charlie Sheen is caught in the middle to deal with both, struggling to maintain his sanity as the depression of the war gets to him every day. All performances are excellent. Even though the beginning consists of Sheen being an innocent little girly man, the war progresses, and he becomes a brutal life risking grunt that ruthlessly kills everything in his path, showing how the war affects him mentally. The sound of the film sounds muddled every time somebody opens their mouth, not sure what Stone's intentions were, but it won the Oscar for sound, so whatever. The film isn't centered around combat, or the realism of war, it's centered around the duality of men, and how the war affects the minds of the soldiers, and the different types of soldiers that faced the war. The beginning scenes consist of the Platoon getting to know each other, leading up to one of the most infamous and controversial scenes in cinema history, the village. It's interesting to see different characters of different personalities conflict each other over being with a different squad leader, like are you guys in high school? Either way they find a way to make it more intense. Not too heavy on atmosphere, history, or in depth messaging like Apocalypse Now or The Deer Hunter, but it gets it around pretty easy, and the message about the war bringing out the best or the worst in men is carried out pretty easy also. Very excellent war film, isn't along the lines of Saving Private Ryan, (my favorite war film) but definitely give it a viewing.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
 </reviews>
</filme>
