<filme>
 <id>
  1573
 </id>
 <imdburl>
  http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0063715
 </imdburl>
 <ano>
  1968
 </ano>
 <titulo>
  Hist&oacute;rias Extraordin&aacute;rias
 </titulo>
 <rating>
  6.5
 </rating>
 <sinopse>
  Three directors each adapt a Poe short story to the screen: "Toby Dammit" features a disheveled drugged and drunk English movie star who nods acceptance in the Italian press and his ... &nbsp;&raquo;
 </sinopse>
 <storyline>
  Three directors each adapt a Poe short story to the screen: "Toby Dammit" features a disheveled drugged and drunk English movie star who nods acceptance in the Italian press and his producers fawn over him. "Metzengerstein" features a Mediveal countess who has a love-hate relationship with a black stallion - who, it turns out is really her dead lover. "William Wilson" tells the story of a sadistic Austrian student with an exact double whom he later kills.
 </storyline>
 <generos>
  <genero>
   Horror
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Mystery
  </genero>
 </generos>
 <keywords>
  <keyword>
   castle
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   actor
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   army
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   catholic
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   rescue
  </keyword>
 </keywords>
 <diretores>
  <diretor>
   Federico Fellini
  </diretor>
  <diretor>
   Louis Malle
  </diretor>
 </diretores>
 <escritores>
  <escritor>
   Edgar Allan Poe
  </escritor>
  <escritor>
   Roger Vadim
  </escritor>
 </escritores>
 <atores>
  <ator>
   Jane Fonda
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Brigitte Bardot
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Alain Delon
  </ator>
 </atores>
 <reviews>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A lot of style--not a lot of substance.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    planktonrules
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The style of "Spirits of the Dead" was not very unusual for the 1960s in Europe. Several other films consisted of top directors doing short films as part of an anthology movie, such as "Boccaccio 70". In the case of "Spirits of the Dead", the films are all adaptations of Edgar Allen Poe stories--and in some cases they stray quite a bit from the original source material. "Metzengerstein" is directed by Roger Vadim and is a film about a sadistic sybaritic noblewoman (Jane Fonda--Vadim's wife at the time). She regularly indulges in all sorts of sexual excesses with her friends, torments her vassals for kicks and is a thoroughly despicable wretch. One day, she sees a distant cousin whose family and hers are rivals. She becomes obsessed by the man (which is interesting, as it's played by Jane's real life brother, Peter) and eventually she does something very evil and spiteful because he will not come to her twisted parties. What's next? See for yourself. I must warn you that this first film is very dull, slow-paced and is pretty silly and forgettable. The worst part about it for me was seeing Jane's silly costumes. While the film appears set in about the year 1500, her costumes appear to be straight from the Vadim space epic, "Barbarella" and this is utterly ridiculous. And, I noticed that most reviewers disliked this short. As for me, I didn't see a whole lot to like about it other than a rare chance to see the two Fondas working together. "William Wilson" is directed by Louis Malle, stars Alain Delon. The film begins with Wilson running into a confessional and loudly demanding that the priest listen to him--even though he acknowledges he is not a Catholic. He admits to a murder and then begins a long story of why he did this dastardly act. During this story, Wilson admits to being a complete sadist and is a man who has no remorse or feeling about others. He is a predatory creature--and why he goes to confess is just something you'll need to see for yourself. What's next? See for yourself. In addition to Delon, this film stars Brigitte Bardot sporting a black wig. She is, as usual, gorgeous. However, you should be forewarned about this film. It is pretty sadistic and nasty in places--and is definitely for adults only. The story is mildly interesting (like a "Twilight Zone" episode) and worth seeing...just don't watch it with your mom or Pastor Jenkins. "Toby Dammit" is by Federico Fellini. This segment is a treat for die-hard Fellini fans, as it has so much that they will probably love. Much of the film seems like it was inspired by "8 1/2" as well as "La Dulce Vita" as it consists of a very much adored celebrity having sycophants falling at his feet as well as a long procession of weird looking extras. It is 100% style...and not a lot of substance. Terrance Stamp plays this celebrity and he plays it as if he's a boorish jerk strung out on heroin--which you assume the character is. I have noticed that critically speaking, it's the most loved of the three films, though I thought the plot itself was very, very weak. It's more like watching a freak show (again, not unusual for many Fellini films) but without a lot of payoff in the end. My overall verdict is that despite the ultra-famous directors, the film lacks substance and, believe it or not, the very cheap Poe films directed by Roger Corman are significantly better. The bottom line is that Malle and Fellini have done so much better work than this and it's a film only for completists who want to see everything they've made. A big disappointment for me.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Somewhat fun, classy Anthology effort
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    GL84
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/9/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A collection of three different Edgar Allen Poe tales by three different directors. The Good Stor(ies): Metzengerstein-Living a life of decadence and depravity, a sadistic baroness enjoys living alone in her castle watching her distant cousin carry on his life whilst ignoring her advances and existence. When word reaches her that he has perished in a deadly fire on his land, she becomes distraught and begins a fanatical obsession with restoring a tapestry depicting a fiery, wild horse he supposedly own by him, while carrying on an equally deadly obsession with a stray horse that appears shortly afterword that bears a striking resemblance to the individual in the cloth. Easily the best of the stories, with a rather impressive mixture of Gothic atmosphere here with it's crumbling castle setting, expansive layouts and decadence littering the entire area, which creates a visually haunting location to use here. As well, the lone action scene, the fire to the adjacent estate, is equally impressive with it's large-scale impact, noteworthy fire stunt and visual dynamics as this is usually the ending to many of these Gothic horrors with the burning-the-house-down finale here placed in the middle section, which is quite innovative, and with both of these segments meshing with her sense of sadism and depravity with humiliation games, orgies and other forms of entertainment overall create a rather impressive entry. William Wilson-Rushing into a church, a distraught man begs the local priest to hear his confession. Starting with his first introduction, he relates the story of a man who is his identical in every way, even sharing the same name as each other, and whenever he tries to entertain himself through his usual sense of depraved fun, his doppelganger appears to ruin it, and by the time it finally grows to a maddening scale, he engages his mysterious twin in a final game of fate. This here is certainly watchable enough as the depravity here is increased with games as the dunking into the rats, surgery on the nude woman and whipping the woman he won in the card game, which creates a rather creepy air when they're all interrupted and dropped with clever rationalizations. There's even a bloody sword-fight to give it some nice action as well. The only real flaw to this one is that the segment tends to meander from the same set-up to the next without any variation, really keeping this one from doing anything entertaining with it's premise. It does grow tiresome to know everything is going to keep repeating, regardless of what's going on, so it looses a little there but is overall quite enjoyable. The Bad Stor(ies): Toby Dammit-Arriving in Italy, a boozing, drugged actor is constantly shuffled around from one personal requested-appearance to the next without delay, causing him to sink deeper into his sense of personal despair. Finally arriving at a gala award show for his honor, he finds the locals gathered there far too much for his sanity to overcome, and when he begins to let his inhibitions loose to their fullest extent, finds himself in a deeper Hell than before. This was overall quite boring as the entire segment plays out as though it's an acid-trip nightmare. Sure, it's overtly weird and generally quite stylish visually, but that doesn't really make it scary. The drive through the deserted streets at night is about the only thing worthwhile here, as it's a lengthy, extended sequence that really gets far more enjoyable over time, though the majority of time taken up by the strange award ceremony rather than being scary really dooms this entry. Not enough for the movie overall, but just slightly. Today's Rating/R: Violence, Nudity and Language
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Fonda's radiant
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    kols
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/9/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Which is the only reason I give this turkey one star. First saw this when it came out, just as Doris Day and Rock Hudson were giving way to Peckinpah, so it seemed like a breath of fresh air and Fonda did carry the first story, which seemed hackneyed even in 1969. The only interesting part of the second story was, well, for an adolescent male, the naked girl tied up on the dissection table. Very racy for the time. Bardot (same episode, different scene) looked awful in a black fright-wig. Would have liked to have seen her stripped and some implied sex, as in the scene with the girl. Otherwise, the plot was just boring, Delon just irritating and Bardot doing a mannish parody of Feminism. As for Fellini, Fellini's Fellini and you should never expect anything else than irrational imagery from him. Except that, like Vadim and Malle, he suffers from the same boring self-absorbance and insufferable self-indulgence that characterized much of that time's European Cine. But, in 1969, it did really impress me. Now-a-days, it makes me thank God for Hawkes and Wayne and the Hustons and the thousands of other Americans who knew how to make real movies. To be blunt, with a few genre exceptions (Ronin), many European film makers seem primarily interested in doing the same thing I was doing while watching the girl on the table. Writing this review now because just saw it again on TCM and was mightily disappointed, except for the girl on the table.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Colorful Poe.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Robert J. Maxwell (rmax304823@yahoo.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/9/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "William Wilson", directed by Louis Malle, with Alain Delon as the titular hero and his own double, is really pretty good. Delon gets to whip the proud Bridget Bardot, which is going a little too far, although heaven knows she deserves a good licking. The tone of the story is suitably elegant and ironic. The men wear carefully tailored generic uniforms with cream-colored jackets. William Wilson is a naughty boy. He deceives people, breaks hearts, cheats at cards. BUT -- he can't seem to get away with any of it because whenever he pulls one of his stunts, a masked figure calling himself William Wilson shows up and exposes him for the fraud he is. Wilson finally kills his Doppelganger and then himself. It's one of my favorite Poe stories because it's different. Most stories of doubles from this period materialize Freud's "id", the savage part of our minds that we try so desperately to suppress. Examples range from Mr. Hyde to Professor Moriarty. Pure evil. But this double represent Freud's "superego," the conscience. Nicely done. The last segment was directed by Federico Fellini with photography by Giuseppe Rotunno and score by Nino Rota. I mention this because these two craftsmen make the story unmistakably Fellini's. I don't think the director could have done it without them. It's based (very loosely) on Poe's "Never Bet The Devil Your Head." Terence Stamp is the internationally famous movie star, Toby Dammit, and arrives in Rome to accept one of those awards like the Palm D'Or or the Oscar. The Rome into which Stamp descends is an hallucinatory vision of hell, beginning with the slightly insane and thoroughly claret-colored airport. What follows is a hilarious parody of an awards ceremony. While a drunken Stamp waits his turn, one after another phony is paraded onto the stage under the blazing lights, striding through studio fog, accompanied by a joyous ruckus. There is a group called The Three Angels From Hell that collectively receive one of these awards. Asked to say a few words, each follows the other and blankly mouths the same appreciation: "I'm very moved by this. All I can say is 'Thank you'." They project the believability of some guy behind the supermarket check-out counter who says, "Have a nice day." I ought to mention, before describing more of the story, that the focus isn't entirely on the awards ceremony. Stamp has to be interviewed on a TV program first, for instance, and -- throughout -- there are all sorts of inexplicable and bizarre goings on. At the interview, a carefully groomed and very beautiful woman steps before the camera and lauds the interviewee. Then she slowly and deliberately drops to her knees, still grinning, puts her nose on the floor and crawls away. Is she deranged? Is the director irretrievably mad? No! It's just her way of taking herself off camera and crawling out of the way so that the interview can get started. Other whimsical events and shots take place, too many to mention. At any rate, Terence Stamp is so liquified at the awards ceremony he can only stagger to the stage. It's been suggested to him that he recite something from Shakespeare, "the most famous poet in the world -- second only to our Dante." But keep it short. Short Shakespeare. We don't want to bore the audience. Stamp's face is a ghastly death mask of agony as he begins some well-known lines from "MacBeth" but he quits, tells the audience and the staff what they can do to themselves, stumbles outside, gets into his Ferrari and speeds away. The story slows down considerably despite the Ferrari's speed and the reckless laughter of the drunken maniac behind its wheel. Stamp finds himself spinning around in empty shabby neighborhoods full of dead ends, with stuffed dummies representing chefs and flocks of sheep scattered about, as in a "Twilight Zone" episode. At the end, he encounters a bridge with a gap in the middle of it. On the other side of the gap is the devil in the guise of a pretty little blond girl. He senses that the devil is challenging him to speed the car across the gap. He should not have accepted the challenge. Roger Vadim's colorful "Metzengerstein" is from a story I haven't read, but the plot can be summed up easily enough. Juliet, in all her noble nubility, falls in love with Romeo but accidentally kills him half-way through, upon which he turns into a horse. Juliet senses his presence in the horse and rides him constantly, finally to their joint destiny. (What is it with women and horses anyway?) The viewer will be surprised to find out that in Medieval France the half-naked girls wore gaudy costumes not unlike those of Las Vegas showgirls. I didn't mind it. I didn't mind Jane Fonda's determined debaucheries either. Except those gang bangs were disgusting. What do those dumb page boys or whatever they are have that I don't have? What puts the ape in apricot? Fonda speaks French in this one. I was able to follow most of it because she speaks with such a marked American accent, as if she'd learned French at Vassar, the same French I learned in high school.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Vadim segment is a mess but worth the look for Fellini's
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    TheLittleSongbird
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    In all honesty, Federico Fellini, whose directing and style I greatly admire, was one of two main attractions to Histoires Extraordinaries in the first place. The other was Edgar Allan Poe. And his segment is the best of the three for me. True, it is more Fellini than Poe with the protagonist like watching 8 1/2 or La Dolce Vita and the dream sequences and the quality of the art direction like 8 1/2 and Juliet of the Spirits, but I love that he adapted a story and put his own style into it. As ever it is beautifully filmed, with a nice score, is superbly directed by Fellini with his sense of nostalgia and themes interesting and boasts a mesmerising performance from Terrence Stamp. Louis Malle's segment is perhaps the most true to Poe's writing. It is straightforward storytelling but chillingly effective at it. It is handsomely filmed also, and Alain Delon as well as good-looking is very convincing. Sadly, the segment directed by Roger Vadim is a mess. It is nice to look at and Jane Fonda is always watchable, but the pace is dull, the direction is all over the place, the story never knows whether it wants to be a drama or a Gothic tale and Peter Fonda is simply wasted. Overall though it is a good and interesting film. And who can go wrong with the great Vincent Price narrating? I cannot see where you can personally. 8/10 Bethany Cox
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Puzzle of dried flowers
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Vincentiu
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/3/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    interesting. for cast, directors, passing of time. for Poe or for remembers from old age. but not more.because this puzzle is dusty, strange and out of charm. Roger Vadim gives a mannerist version of Elisabeth Bathory and form of love with artificial notes - option for Peter Fonda is not inspired idea -, Louis Malle creates an interesting universe , tired after short time, with a blank cold statue as axis, with few cruel ingredients and meeting between Bardot and Delon as heart. Fellini, well, Fellini is Fellini and it is important. because his style, atmosphere of his universe, a Terence Stamp like mask of Mastroiani are just virtues in this case. it is enough ? maybe not. the final impression is about a puzzle of dried flowers.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Malle's Homage to Cocteau's Les Enfants Terribles
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bensonj
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It's interesting that no IMDb commenters seem to have caught Malle's significant homage in "William Wilson." Malle makes Wilson far more sadistic that Poe's character. In the opening school sequence, Poe's Wilson is, to be sure, a leader of the other students: "the ardor, the enthusiasm, and the imperiousness of my disposition, soon rendered me a marked character among my schoolmates, and by slow, but natural gradations, gave me an ascendancy over all not greatly older than myself." Any sadism is, at most, implied: "If there is on earth a supreme and unqualified despotism, it is the despotism of a master mind in boyhood over the less energetic spirits of its companions." In Poe, Wilson does not try to strangle his doppelganger, nor is he expelled from the school. He approaches the other's bed at night, apparently sees his own face on the sleeping boy and "passed silently from the chamber, and left at once, the halls of that old academy, never to enter them again." In Malle's film, Wilson is torturing another student as a snowball fight rages in the background. The doppelganger makes his first appearance by hitting Wilson with a snowball. The snow fight, the torture, the significant hit by a snowball, the expulsion from school are not in Poe's tale. But all these elements ARE in Jean Cocteau's novel LES ENFANTS TERRIBLES. The snowball fight not only is featured in Jean-Pierre Melville's film of the novel, but Cocteau filmed the scene earlier in his own BLOOD OF A POET. The torture is briefly in Melville's film, but described more fully in the novel: "By the spasmodic flaring of the gas lamp he could be seen to be a small boy with his back against the wall, hemmed in by his captives...One of these...was squatting between his legs and twisting his ears...Weeping, he sought to close his eyes, to avert his head. But every time he struggled, his torturer seized a fistful of gray snow and scrubbed his ears with it." As the snow fight continues, Cocteau's iconic character Dargelos throws a snowball that hits another student and puts in motion the events of the novel/film. Dargelos is the same sort of malignant leader of his schoolmates as Malle's young Wilson. The headmaster calls his influence on his classmates unhealthy, and after an outrageous act he is expelled from the school. Even more to the point, Dargelos has a doppelganger in the form of the character Agathe. In Melville's film Dargelos and Agathe are played by same person, and their mysterious resemblance is important to the story. All of these added Cocteau elements are so strong that one assumes that Malle intended viewers to recognize the reference.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An American icon transformed into Sixties Eurotrash
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    LCShackley
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/12/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    There's not much Poe here, except his name. Roger Corman did a better job of sticking to the original stories than this trio of "stellar" directors: Vadim, Malle, and Fellini. In the spirit of the indulgent 60s, these three auteurs twisted Poe into the shape of their own imagination, rewriting and "sexing up" the stories to appeal to the pompous art-house crowd. There are some beautiful locations and striking visuals, to be sure...plus long, long stretches of boredom (Jane Fonda playing with a horse, Terence Stamp driving drunk). The music is also dated and laughable, especially Nino Rota's pop dreck under the Fellini segment. Trivia: be on the lookout for Andreas Voutsinas as a bearded courtier in the Vadim segment. He was Jane Fonda's acting coach, but best-known to American audiences as the creepy Carmen Ghia in Mel Brooks's original "The Producers" (released the same year as this film).
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    If only Toby Dammit was feature-length...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tomgillespie2002
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/9/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Also known as Histoires Extraordinaires, this film combines three short stories by Edgar Allen Poe, and has each segment directed by a different European director. The first, entitled Metzengerstein, is directed by the man that helmed Barbarella, Roger Vadim. It tells the story of a beautiful yet debauched countess Federica (Jane Fonda) who falls in love with her family rival, Baron Wilhelm (Peter Fonda - bit weird, them being real-life brother and sister), who frees her leg from a trap in the woods. After he rejects her, she orders the burning of one of his villages, and the Baron is killed when attempting a rescue of one of his horses. The horse is taken in by Federica, who becomes obsessed with it once she notices its resemblance to the one painted on a damaged tapestry. The second story, William Wilson, is directed by French film-maker Louis Malle. It tells a familiar doppelg&auml;nger story of the wicked William Wilson (Alain Delon) who is also interrupted by his 'better half' who shares his name and his appearance, but none of his evil ways. After winning a card game against Giuseppina (Brigitte Bardot) through repeatedly cheating, his other half exposes him, and the two face a duel. The third, directed by Federico Fellini and entitled Toby Dammit, follows alcoholic Shakesperean actor Toby Dammit (Terence Stamp) who is brought to Rome to star in an adaptation of the story of Christ, re- imagined as a western. Haunted by visions of a blonde girl who has lost her ball, he goes on a drunken ride through Rome in a Ferrari. The biggest problem with this film is the variations of quality in the different episodes. Vadim's opener is a pretty poor effort, with a strange storyline focusing on a woman's obsession with a horse. It seems to be nothing more than an excuse to get Jane Fonda into some skimpy medieval outfits. That is all well and good (it was one of the key reasons why I loved Barbarella!) but it's a silly story and a waste of some beautiful cinematography. Malle's second story is a big improvement, but it is clear that his heart is not really in it. Apparently he agreed to take on the job in order to raise money for Murmur of the Heart, and compromised to make the film more accessible to mainstream audiences. But the eroticism of the card game, and the strange atmosphere that is evident throughout make it an enjoyable 40 minutes. Fellini's final segment is very much the director's own vision. It is so far gone from anything resembling Poe's original vision, it could be easily called Fellini's own. Thematically similar to most of his key works, Terence Stamp's crumbling lead character is the main focus, and his disintegrating sanity is laid out on the screen with a collection of flashing images, bizarre characters, and unconventional camera-work. It is also an attack on celebrity, as the characters that Dammit comes across don't react or flinch at his increasingly strange and unpredictable behaviour. It's a shame that Fellini is restricted to a 40 minute portion of a 2-hour film, as I would have quite happily watched Toby Dammit as a full-length feature. An enjoyable, if unspectacular overall film, with the stories getting notably better as the film goes on. www.the-wrath-of-blog.blogspot.com
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Rejected Night Gallery TV material
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    grandfunkfan
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/2/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Three Poe stories; three directors; three failures. Simply put, this movie is not entertaining. Using Poe's name, and labeling the stories as interpretations by famous directors does not cover the poor performance and overall boring conclusion. The viewer, very possibly a fan of Poe, keeps hoping for something to develop, but it never does. Jane Fonda never removes her clothes. Peter Fonda is a again outperformed by a bird. The beautiful scenery and castles are fantastic. Hells bells ring loud and clear. But the movie never turns into an entertaining event. The Night Gallery TV series had many good stories and many duds. The adaptations of Poe stories in the film Spirits of the Dead would never have been used in the most desperate space-filler needs of television. There are several good film adaptations of Poe stories, but Spirits of the Dead is not worth watching.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A lot of style--not a lot of substance.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    planktonrules
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The style of "Spirits of the Dead" was not very unusual for the 1960s in Europe. Several other films consisted of top directors doing short films as part of an anthology movie, such as "Boccaccio 70". In the case of "Spirits of the Dead", the films are all adaptations of Edgar Allen Poe stories--and in some cases they stray quite a bit from the original source material. "Metzengerstein" is directed by Roger Vadim and is a film about a sadistic sybaritic noblewoman (Jane Fonda--Vadim's wife at the time). She regularly indulges in all sorts of sexual excesses with her friends, torments her vassals for kicks and is a thoroughly despicable wretch. One day, she sees a distant cousin whose family and hers are rivals. She becomes obsessed by the man (which is interesting, as it's played by Jane's real life brother, Peter) and eventually she does something very evil and spiteful because he will not come to her twisted parties. What's next? See for yourself. I must warn you that this first film is very dull, slow-paced and is pretty silly and forgettable. The worst part about it for me was seeing Jane's silly costumes. While the film appears set in about the year 1500, her costumes appear to be straight from the Vadim space epic, "Barbarella" and this is utterly ridiculous. And, I noticed that most reviewers disliked this short. As for me, I didn't see a whole lot to like about it other than a rare chance to see the two Fondas working together. "William Wilson" is directed by Louis Malle, stars Alain Delon. The film begins with Wilson running into a confessional and loudly demanding that the priest listen to him--even though he acknowledges he is not a Catholic. He admits to a murder and then begins a long story of why he did this dastardly act. During this story, Wilson admits to being a complete sadist and is a man who has no remorse or feeling about others. He is a predatory creature--and why he goes to confess is just something you'll need to see for yourself. What's next? See for yourself. In addition to Delon, this film stars Brigitte Bardot sporting a black wig. She is, as usual, gorgeous. However, you should be forewarned about this film. It is pretty sadistic and nasty in places--and is definitely for adults only. The story is mildly interesting (like a "Twilight Zone" episode) and worth seeing...just don't watch it with your mom or Pastor Jenkins. "Toby Dammit" is by Federico Fellini. This segment is a treat for die-hard Fellini fans, as it has so much that they will probably love. Much of the film seems like it was inspired by "8 1/2" as well as "La Dulce Vita" as it consists of a very much adored celebrity having sycophants falling at his feet as well as a long procession of weird looking extras. It is 100% style...and not a lot of substance. Terrance Stamp plays this celebrity and he plays it as if he's a boorish jerk strung out on heroin--which you assume the character is. I have noticed that critically speaking, it's the most loved of the three films, though I thought the plot itself was very, very weak. It's more like watching a freak show (again, not unusual for many Fellini films) but without a lot of payoff in the end. My overall verdict is that despite the ultra-famous directors, the film lacks substance and, believe it or not, the very cheap Poe films directed by Roger Corman are significantly better. The bottom line is that Malle and Fellini have done so much better work than this and it's a film only for completists who want to see everything they've made. A big disappointment for me.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Somewhat fun, classy Anthology effort
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    GL84
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/9/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A collection of three different Edgar Allen Poe tales by three different directors. The Good Stor(ies): Metzengerstein-Living a life of decadence and depravity, a sadistic baroness enjoys living alone in her castle watching her distant cousin carry on his life whilst ignoring her advances and existence. When word reaches her that he has perished in a deadly fire on his land, she becomes distraught and begins a fanatical obsession with restoring a tapestry depicting a fiery, wild horse he supposedly own by him, while carrying on an equally deadly obsession with a stray horse that appears shortly afterword that bears a striking resemblance to the individual in the cloth. Easily the best of the stories, with a rather impressive mixture of Gothic atmosphere here with it's crumbling castle setting, expansive layouts and decadence littering the entire area, which creates a visually haunting location to use here. As well, the lone action scene, the fire to the adjacent estate, is equally impressive with it's large-scale impact, noteworthy fire stunt and visual dynamics as this is usually the ending to many of these Gothic horrors with the burning-the-house-down finale here placed in the middle section, which is quite innovative, and with both of these segments meshing with her sense of sadism and depravity with humiliation games, orgies and other forms of entertainment overall create a rather impressive entry. William Wilson-Rushing into a church, a distraught man begs the local priest to hear his confession. Starting with his first introduction, he relates the story of a man who is his identical in every way, even sharing the same name as each other, and whenever he tries to entertain himself through his usual sense of depraved fun, his doppelganger appears to ruin it, and by the time it finally grows to a maddening scale, he engages his mysterious twin in a final game of fate. This here is certainly watchable enough as the depravity here is increased with games as the dunking into the rats, surgery on the nude woman and whipping the woman he won in the card game, which creates a rather creepy air when they're all interrupted and dropped with clever rationalizations. There's even a bloody sword-fight to give it some nice action as well. The only real flaw to this one is that the segment tends to meander from the same set-up to the next without any variation, really keeping this one from doing anything entertaining with it's premise. It does grow tiresome to know everything is going to keep repeating, regardless of what's going on, so it looses a little there but is overall quite enjoyable. The Bad Stor(ies): Toby Dammit-Arriving in Italy, a boozing, drugged actor is constantly shuffled around from one personal requested-appearance to the next without delay, causing him to sink deeper into his sense of personal despair. Finally arriving at a gala award show for his honor, he finds the locals gathered there far too much for his sanity to overcome, and when he begins to let his inhibitions loose to their fullest extent, finds himself in a deeper Hell than before. This was overall quite boring as the entire segment plays out as though it's an acid-trip nightmare. Sure, it's overtly weird and generally quite stylish visually, but that doesn't really make it scary. The drive through the deserted streets at night is about the only thing worthwhile here, as it's a lengthy, extended sequence that really gets far more enjoyable over time, though the majority of time taken up by the strange award ceremony rather than being scary really dooms this entry. Not enough for the movie overall, but just slightly. Today's Rating/R: Violence, Nudity and Language
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Fonda's radiant
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    kols
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/9/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Which is the only reason I give this turkey one star. First saw this when it came out, just as Doris Day and Rock Hudson were giving way to Peckinpah, so it seemed like a breath of fresh air and Fonda did carry the first story, which seemed hackneyed even in 1969. The only interesting part of the second story was, well, for an adolescent male, the naked girl tied up on the dissection table. Very racy for the time. Bardot (same episode, different scene) looked awful in a black fright-wig. Would have liked to have seen her stripped and some implied sex, as in the scene with the girl. Otherwise, the plot was just boring, Delon just irritating and Bardot doing a mannish parody of Feminism. As for Fellini, Fellini's Fellini and you should never expect anything else than irrational imagery from him. Except that, like Vadim and Malle, he suffers from the same boring self-absorbance and insufferable self-indulgence that characterized much of that time's European Cine. But, in 1969, it did really impress me. Now-a-days, it makes me thank God for Hawkes and Wayne and the Hustons and the thousands of other Americans who knew how to make real movies. To be blunt, with a few genre exceptions (Ronin), many European film makers seem primarily interested in doing the same thing I was doing while watching the girl on the table. Writing this review now because just saw it again on TCM and was mightily disappointed, except for the girl on the table.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Colorful Poe.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Robert J. Maxwell (rmax304823@yahoo.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/9/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "William Wilson", directed by Louis Malle, with Alain Delon as the titular hero and his own double, is really pretty good. Delon gets to whip the proud Bridget Bardot, which is going a little too far, although heaven knows she deserves a good licking. The tone of the story is suitably elegant and ironic. The men wear carefully tailored generic uniforms with cream-colored jackets. William Wilson is a naughty boy. He deceives people, breaks hearts, cheats at cards. BUT -- he can't seem to get away with any of it because whenever he pulls one of his stunts, a masked figure calling himself William Wilson shows up and exposes him for the fraud he is. Wilson finally kills his Doppelganger and then himself. It's one of my favorite Poe stories because it's different. Most stories of doubles from this period materialize Freud's "id", the savage part of our minds that we try so desperately to suppress. Examples range from Mr. Hyde to Professor Moriarty. Pure evil. But this double represent Freud's "superego," the conscience. Nicely done. The last segment was directed by Federico Fellini with photography by Giuseppe Rotunno and score by Nino Rota. I mention this because these two craftsmen make the story unmistakably Fellini's. I don't think the director could have done it without them. It's based (very loosely) on Poe's "Never Bet The Devil Your Head." Terence Stamp is the internationally famous movie star, Toby Dammit, and arrives in Rome to accept one of those awards like the Palm D'Or or the Oscar. The Rome into which Stamp descends is an hallucinatory vision of hell, beginning with the slightly insane and thoroughly claret-colored airport. What follows is a hilarious parody of an awards ceremony. While a drunken Stamp waits his turn, one after another phony is paraded onto the stage under the blazing lights, striding through studio fog, accompanied by a joyous ruckus. There is a group called The Three Angels From Hell that collectively receive one of these awards. Asked to say a few words, each follows the other and blankly mouths the same appreciation: "I'm very moved by this. All I can say is 'Thank you'." They project the believability of some guy behind the supermarket check-out counter who says, "Have a nice day." I ought to mention, before describing more of the story, that the focus isn't entirely on the awards ceremony. Stamp has to be interviewed on a TV program first, for instance, and -- throughout -- there are all sorts of inexplicable and bizarre goings on. At the interview, a carefully groomed and very beautiful woman steps before the camera and lauds the interviewee. Then she slowly and deliberately drops to her knees, still grinning, puts her nose on the floor and crawls away. Is she deranged? Is the director irretrievably mad? No! It's just her way of taking herself off camera and crawling out of the way so that the interview can get started. Other whimsical events and shots take place, too many to mention. At any rate, Terence Stamp is so liquified at the awards ceremony he can only stagger to the stage. It's been suggested to him that he recite something from Shakespeare, "the most famous poet in the world -- second only to our Dante." But keep it short. Short Shakespeare. We don't want to bore the audience. Stamp's face is a ghastly death mask of agony as he begins some well-known lines from "MacBeth" but he quits, tells the audience and the staff what they can do to themselves, stumbles outside, gets into his Ferrari and speeds away. The story slows down considerably despite the Ferrari's speed and the reckless laughter of the drunken maniac behind its wheel. Stamp finds himself spinning around in empty shabby neighborhoods full of dead ends, with stuffed dummies representing chefs and flocks of sheep scattered about, as in a "Twilight Zone" episode. At the end, he encounters a bridge with a gap in the middle of it. On the other side of the gap is the devil in the guise of a pretty little blond girl. He senses that the devil is challenging him to speed the car across the gap. He should not have accepted the challenge. Roger Vadim's colorful "Metzengerstein" is from a story I haven't read, but the plot can be summed up easily enough. Juliet, in all her noble nubility, falls in love with Romeo but accidentally kills him half-way through, upon which he turns into a horse. Juliet senses his presence in the horse and rides him constantly, finally to their joint destiny. (What is it with women and horses anyway?) The viewer will be surprised to find out that in Medieval France the half-naked girls wore gaudy costumes not unlike those of Las Vegas showgirls. I didn't mind it. I didn't mind Jane Fonda's determined debaucheries either. Except those gang bangs were disgusting. What do those dumb page boys or whatever they are have that I don't have? What puts the ape in apricot? Fonda speaks French in this one. I was able to follow most of it because she speaks with such a marked American accent, as if she'd learned French at Vassar, the same French I learned in high school.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Vadim segment is a mess but worth the look for Fellini's
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    TheLittleSongbird
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    In all honesty, Federico Fellini, whose directing and style I greatly admire, was one of two main attractions to Histoires Extraordinaries in the first place. The other was Edgar Allan Poe. And his segment is the best of the three for me. True, it is more Fellini than Poe with the protagonist like watching 8 1/2 or La Dolce Vita and the dream sequences and the quality of the art direction like 8 1/2 and Juliet of the Spirits, but I love that he adapted a story and put his own style into it. As ever it is beautifully filmed, with a nice score, is superbly directed by Fellini with his sense of nostalgia and themes interesting and boasts a mesmerising performance from Terrence Stamp. Louis Malle's segment is perhaps the most true to Poe's writing. It is straightforward storytelling but chillingly effective at it. It is handsomely filmed also, and Alain Delon as well as good-looking is very convincing. Sadly, the segment directed by Roger Vadim is a mess. It is nice to look at and Jane Fonda is always watchable, but the pace is dull, the direction is all over the place, the story never knows whether it wants to be a drama or a Gothic tale and Peter Fonda is simply wasted. Overall though it is a good and interesting film. And who can go wrong with the great Vincent Price narrating? I cannot see where you can personally. 8/10 Bethany Cox
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Puzzle of dried flowers
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Vincentiu
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/3/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    interesting. for cast, directors, passing of time. for Poe or for remembers from old age. but not more.because this puzzle is dusty, strange and out of charm. Roger Vadim gives a mannerist version of Elisabeth Bathory and form of love with artificial notes - option for Peter Fonda is not inspired idea -, Louis Malle creates an interesting universe , tired after short time, with a blank cold statue as axis, with few cruel ingredients and meeting between Bardot and Delon as heart. Fellini, well, Fellini is Fellini and it is important. because his style, atmosphere of his universe, a Terence Stamp like mask of Mastroiani are just virtues in this case. it is enough ? maybe not. the final impression is about a puzzle of dried flowers.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Malle's Homage to Cocteau's Les Enfants Terribles
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bensonj
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It's interesting that no IMDb commenters seem to have caught Malle's significant homage in "William Wilson." Malle makes Wilson far more sadistic that Poe's character. In the opening school sequence, Poe's Wilson is, to be sure, a leader of the other students: "the ardor, the enthusiasm, and the imperiousness of my disposition, soon rendered me a marked character among my schoolmates, and by slow, but natural gradations, gave me an ascendancy over all not greatly older than myself." Any sadism is, at most, implied: "If there is on earth a supreme and unqualified despotism, it is the despotism of a master mind in boyhood over the less energetic spirits of its companions." In Poe, Wilson does not try to strangle his doppelganger, nor is he expelled from the school. He approaches the other's bed at night, apparently sees his own face on the sleeping boy and "passed silently from the chamber, and left at once, the halls of that old academy, never to enter them again." In Malle's film, Wilson is torturing another student as a snowball fight rages in the background. The doppelganger makes his first appearance by hitting Wilson with a snowball. The snow fight, the torture, the significant hit by a snowball, the expulsion from school are not in Poe's tale. But all these elements ARE in Jean Cocteau's novel LES ENFANTS TERRIBLES. The snowball fight not only is featured in Jean-Pierre Melville's film of the novel, but Cocteau filmed the scene earlier in his own BLOOD OF A POET. The torture is briefly in Melville's film, but described more fully in the novel: "By the spasmodic flaring of the gas lamp he could be seen to be a small boy with his back against the wall, hemmed in by his captives...One of these...was squatting between his legs and twisting his ears...Weeping, he sought to close his eyes, to avert his head. But every time he struggled, his torturer seized a fistful of gray snow and scrubbed his ears with it." As the snow fight continues, Cocteau's iconic character Dargelos throws a snowball that hits another student and puts in motion the events of the novel/film. Dargelos is the same sort of malignant leader of his schoolmates as Malle's young Wilson. The headmaster calls his influence on his classmates unhealthy, and after an outrageous act he is expelled from the school. Even more to the point, Dargelos has a doppelganger in the form of the character Agathe. In Melville's film Dargelos and Agathe are played by same person, and their mysterious resemblance is important to the story. All of these added Cocteau elements are so strong that one assumes that Malle intended viewers to recognize the reference.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An American icon transformed into Sixties Eurotrash
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    LCShackley
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/12/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    There's not much Poe here, except his name. Roger Corman did a better job of sticking to the original stories than this trio of "stellar" directors: Vadim, Malle, and Fellini. In the spirit of the indulgent 60s, these three auteurs twisted Poe into the shape of their own imagination, rewriting and "sexing up" the stories to appeal to the pompous art-house crowd. There are some beautiful locations and striking visuals, to be sure...plus long, long stretches of boredom (Jane Fonda playing with a horse, Terence Stamp driving drunk). The music is also dated and laughable, especially Nino Rota's pop dreck under the Fellini segment. Trivia: be on the lookout for Andreas Voutsinas as a bearded courtier in the Vadim segment. He was Jane Fonda's acting coach, but best-known to American audiences as the creepy Carmen Ghia in Mel Brooks's original "The Producers" (released the same year as this film).
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    If only Toby Dammit was feature-length...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tomgillespie2002
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/9/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Also known as Histoires Extraordinaires, this film combines three short stories by Edgar Allen Poe, and has each segment directed by a different European director. The first, entitled Metzengerstein, is directed by the man that helmed Barbarella, Roger Vadim. It tells the story of a beautiful yet debauched countess Federica (Jane Fonda) who falls in love with her family rival, Baron Wilhelm (Peter Fonda - bit weird, them being real-life brother and sister), who frees her leg from a trap in the woods. After he rejects her, she orders the burning of one of his villages, and the Baron is killed when attempting a rescue of one of his horses. The horse is taken in by Federica, who becomes obsessed with it once she notices its resemblance to the one painted on a damaged tapestry. The second story, William Wilson, is directed by French film-maker Louis Malle. It tells a familiar doppelg&auml;nger story of the wicked William Wilson (Alain Delon) who is also interrupted by his 'better half' who shares his name and his appearance, but none of his evil ways. After winning a card game against Giuseppina (Brigitte Bardot) through repeatedly cheating, his other half exposes him, and the two face a duel. The third, directed by Federico Fellini and entitled Toby Dammit, follows alcoholic Shakesperean actor Toby Dammit (Terence Stamp) who is brought to Rome to star in an adaptation of the story of Christ, re- imagined as a western. Haunted by visions of a blonde girl who has lost her ball, he goes on a drunken ride through Rome in a Ferrari. The biggest problem with this film is the variations of quality in the different episodes. Vadim's opener is a pretty poor effort, with a strange storyline focusing on a woman's obsession with a horse. It seems to be nothing more than an excuse to get Jane Fonda into some skimpy medieval outfits. That is all well and good (it was one of the key reasons why I loved Barbarella!) but it's a silly story and a waste of some beautiful cinematography. Malle's second story is a big improvement, but it is clear that his heart is not really in it. Apparently he agreed to take on the job in order to raise money for Murmur of the Heart, and compromised to make the film more accessible to mainstream audiences. But the eroticism of the card game, and the strange atmosphere that is evident throughout make it an enjoyable 40 minutes. Fellini's final segment is very much the director's own vision. It is so far gone from anything resembling Poe's original vision, it could be easily called Fellini's own. Thematically similar to most of his key works, Terence Stamp's crumbling lead character is the main focus, and his disintegrating sanity is laid out on the screen with a collection of flashing images, bizarre characters, and unconventional camera-work. It is also an attack on celebrity, as the characters that Dammit comes across don't react or flinch at his increasingly strange and unpredictable behaviour. It's a shame that Fellini is restricted to a 40 minute portion of a 2-hour film, as I would have quite happily watched Toby Dammit as a full-length feature. An enjoyable, if unspectacular overall film, with the stories getting notably better as the film goes on. www.the-wrath-of-blog.blogspot.com
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Rejected Night Gallery TV material
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    grandfunkfan
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/2/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Three Poe stories; three directors; three failures. Simply put, this movie is not entertaining. Using Poe's name, and labeling the stories as interpretations by famous directors does not cover the poor performance and overall boring conclusion. The viewer, very possibly a fan of Poe, keeps hoping for something to develop, but it never does. Jane Fonda never removes her clothes. Peter Fonda is a again outperformed by a bird. The beautiful scenery and castles are fantastic. Hells bells ring loud and clear. But the movie never turns into an entertaining event. The Night Gallery TV series had many good stories and many duds. The adaptations of Poe stories in the film Spirits of the Dead would never have been used in the most desperate space-filler needs of television. There are several good film adaptations of Poe stories, but Spirits of the Dead is not worth watching.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A lot of style--not a lot of substance.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    planktonrules
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The style of "Spirits of the Dead" was not very unusual for the 1960s in Europe. Several other films consisted of top directors doing short films as part of an anthology movie, such as "Boccaccio 70". In the case of "Spirits of the Dead", the films are all adaptations of Edgar Allen Poe stories--and in some cases they stray quite a bit from the original source material. "Metzengerstein" is directed by Roger Vadim and is a film about a sadistic sybaritic noblewoman (Jane Fonda--Vadim's wife at the time). She regularly indulges in all sorts of sexual excesses with her friends, torments her vassals for kicks and is a thoroughly despicable wretch. One day, she sees a distant cousin whose family and hers are rivals. She becomes obsessed by the man (which is interesting, as it's played by Jane's real life brother, Peter) and eventually she does something very evil and spiteful because he will not come to her twisted parties. What's next? See for yourself. I must warn you that this first film is very dull, slow-paced and is pretty silly and forgettable. The worst part about it for me was seeing Jane's silly costumes. While the film appears set in about the year 1500, her costumes appear to be straight from the Vadim space epic, "Barbarella" and this is utterly ridiculous. And, I noticed that most reviewers disliked this short. As for me, I didn't see a whole lot to like about it other than a rare chance to see the two Fondas working together. "William Wilson" is directed by Louis Malle, stars Alain Delon. The film begins with Wilson running into a confessional and loudly demanding that the priest listen to him--even though he acknowledges he is not a Catholic. He admits to a murder and then begins a long story of why he did this dastardly act. During this story, Wilson admits to being a complete sadist and is a man who has no remorse or feeling about others. He is a predatory creature--and why he goes to confess is just something you'll need to see for yourself. What's next? See for yourself. In addition to Delon, this film stars Brigitte Bardot sporting a black wig. She is, as usual, gorgeous. However, you should be forewarned about this film. It is pretty sadistic and nasty in places--and is definitely for adults only. The story is mildly interesting (like a "Twilight Zone" episode) and worth seeing...just don't watch it with your mom or Pastor Jenkins. "Toby Dammit" is by Federico Fellini. This segment is a treat for die-hard Fellini fans, as it has so much that they will probably love. Much of the film seems like it was inspired by "8 1/2" as well as "La Dulce Vita" as it consists of a very much adored celebrity having sycophants falling at his feet as well as a long procession of weird looking extras. It is 100% style...and not a lot of substance. Terrance Stamp plays this celebrity and he plays it as if he's a boorish jerk strung out on heroin--which you assume the character is. I have noticed that critically speaking, it's the most loved of the three films, though I thought the plot itself was very, very weak. It's more like watching a freak show (again, not unusual for many Fellini films) but without a lot of payoff in the end. My overall verdict is that despite the ultra-famous directors, the film lacks substance and, believe it or not, the very cheap Poe films directed by Roger Corman are significantly better. The bottom line is that Malle and Fellini have done so much better work than this and it's a film only for completists who want to see everything they've made. A big disappointment for me.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Somewhat fun, classy Anthology effort
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    GL84
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/9/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A collection of three different Edgar Allen Poe tales by three different directors. The Good Stor(ies): Metzengerstein-Living a life of decadence and depravity, a sadistic baroness enjoys living alone in her castle watching her distant cousin carry on his life whilst ignoring her advances and existence. When word reaches her that he has perished in a deadly fire on his land, she becomes distraught and begins a fanatical obsession with restoring a tapestry depicting a fiery, wild horse he supposedly own by him, while carrying on an equally deadly obsession with a stray horse that appears shortly afterword that bears a striking resemblance to the individual in the cloth. Easily the best of the stories, with a rather impressive mixture of Gothic atmosphere here with it's crumbling castle setting, expansive layouts and decadence littering the entire area, which creates a visually haunting location to use here. As well, the lone action scene, the fire to the adjacent estate, is equally impressive with it's large-scale impact, noteworthy fire stunt and visual dynamics as this is usually the ending to many of these Gothic horrors with the burning-the-house-down finale here placed in the middle section, which is quite innovative, and with both of these segments meshing with her sense of sadism and depravity with humiliation games, orgies and other forms of entertainment overall create a rather impressive entry. William Wilson-Rushing into a church, a distraught man begs the local priest to hear his confession. Starting with his first introduction, he relates the story of a man who is his identical in every way, even sharing the same name as each other, and whenever he tries to entertain himself through his usual sense of depraved fun, his doppelganger appears to ruin it, and by the time it finally grows to a maddening scale, he engages his mysterious twin in a final game of fate. This here is certainly watchable enough as the depravity here is increased with games as the dunking into the rats, surgery on the nude woman and whipping the woman he won in the card game, which creates a rather creepy air when they're all interrupted and dropped with clever rationalizations. There's even a bloody sword-fight to give it some nice action as well. The only real flaw to this one is that the segment tends to meander from the same set-up to the next without any variation, really keeping this one from doing anything entertaining with it's premise. It does grow tiresome to know everything is going to keep repeating, regardless of what's going on, so it looses a little there but is overall quite enjoyable. The Bad Stor(ies): Toby Dammit-Arriving in Italy, a boozing, drugged actor is constantly shuffled around from one personal requested-appearance to the next without delay, causing him to sink deeper into his sense of personal despair. Finally arriving at a gala award show for his honor, he finds the locals gathered there far too much for his sanity to overcome, and when he begins to let his inhibitions loose to their fullest extent, finds himself in a deeper Hell than before. This was overall quite boring as the entire segment plays out as though it's an acid-trip nightmare. Sure, it's overtly weird and generally quite stylish visually, but that doesn't really make it scary. The drive through the deserted streets at night is about the only thing worthwhile here, as it's a lengthy, extended sequence that really gets far more enjoyable over time, though the majority of time taken up by the strange award ceremony rather than being scary really dooms this entry. Not enough for the movie overall, but just slightly. Today's Rating/R: Violence, Nudity and Language
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Fonda's radiant
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    kols
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/9/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Which is the only reason I give this turkey one star. First saw this when it came out, just as Doris Day and Rock Hudson were giving way to Peckinpah, so it seemed like a breath of fresh air and Fonda did carry the first story, which seemed hackneyed even in 1969. The only interesting part of the second story was, well, for an adolescent male, the naked girl tied up on the dissection table. Very racy for the time. Bardot (same episode, different scene) looked awful in a black fright-wig. Would have liked to have seen her stripped and some implied sex, as in the scene with the girl. Otherwise, the plot was just boring, Delon just irritating and Bardot doing a mannish parody of Feminism. As for Fellini, Fellini's Fellini and you should never expect anything else than irrational imagery from him. Except that, like Vadim and Malle, he suffers from the same boring self-absorbance and insufferable self-indulgence that characterized much of that time's European Cine. But, in 1969, it did really impress me. Now-a-days, it makes me thank God for Hawkes and Wayne and the Hustons and the thousands of other Americans who knew how to make real movies. To be blunt, with a few genre exceptions (Ronin), many European film makers seem primarily interested in doing the same thing I was doing while watching the girl on the table. Writing this review now because just saw it again on TCM and was mightily disappointed, except for the girl on the table.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Colorful Poe.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Robert J. Maxwell (rmax304823@yahoo.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/9/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "William Wilson", directed by Louis Malle, with Alain Delon as the titular hero and his own double, is really pretty good. Delon gets to whip the proud Bridget Bardot, which is going a little too far, although heaven knows she deserves a good licking. The tone of the story is suitably elegant and ironic. The men wear carefully tailored generic uniforms with cream-colored jackets. William Wilson is a naughty boy. He deceives people, breaks hearts, cheats at cards. BUT -- he can't seem to get away with any of it because whenever he pulls one of his stunts, a masked figure calling himself William Wilson shows up and exposes him for the fraud he is. Wilson finally kills his Doppelganger and then himself. It's one of my favorite Poe stories because it's different. Most stories of doubles from this period materialize Freud's "id", the savage part of our minds that we try so desperately to suppress. Examples range from Mr. Hyde to Professor Moriarty. Pure evil. But this double represent Freud's "superego," the conscience. Nicely done. The last segment was directed by Federico Fellini with photography by Giuseppe Rotunno and score by Nino Rota. I mention this because these two craftsmen make the story unmistakably Fellini's. I don't think the director could have done it without them. It's based (very loosely) on Poe's "Never Bet The Devil Your Head." Terence Stamp is the internationally famous movie star, Toby Dammit, and arrives in Rome to accept one of those awards like the Palm D'Or or the Oscar. The Rome into which Stamp descends is an hallucinatory vision of hell, beginning with the slightly insane and thoroughly claret-colored airport. What follows is a hilarious parody of an awards ceremony. While a drunken Stamp waits his turn, one after another phony is paraded onto the stage under the blazing lights, striding through studio fog, accompanied by a joyous ruckus. There is a group called The Three Angels From Hell that collectively receive one of these awards. Asked to say a few words, each follows the other and blankly mouths the same appreciation: "I'm very moved by this. All I can say is 'Thank you'." They project the believability of some guy behind the supermarket check-out counter who says, "Have a nice day." I ought to mention, before describing more of the story, that the focus isn't entirely on the awards ceremony. Stamp has to be interviewed on a TV program first, for instance, and -- throughout -- there are all sorts of inexplicable and bizarre goings on. At the interview, a carefully groomed and very beautiful woman steps before the camera and lauds the interviewee. Then she slowly and deliberately drops to her knees, still grinning, puts her nose on the floor and crawls away. Is she deranged? Is the director irretrievably mad? No! It's just her way of taking herself off camera and crawling out of the way so that the interview can get started. Other whimsical events and shots take place, too many to mention. At any rate, Terence Stamp is so liquified at the awards ceremony he can only stagger to the stage. It's been suggested to him that he recite something from Shakespeare, "the most famous poet in the world -- second only to our Dante." But keep it short. Short Shakespeare. We don't want to bore the audience. Stamp's face is a ghastly death mask of agony as he begins some well-known lines from "MacBeth" but he quits, tells the audience and the staff what they can do to themselves, stumbles outside, gets into his Ferrari and speeds away. The story slows down considerably despite the Ferrari's speed and the reckless laughter of the drunken maniac behind its wheel. Stamp finds himself spinning around in empty shabby neighborhoods full of dead ends, with stuffed dummies representing chefs and flocks of sheep scattered about, as in a "Twilight Zone" episode. At the end, he encounters a bridge with a gap in the middle of it. On the other side of the gap is the devil in the guise of a pretty little blond girl. He senses that the devil is challenging him to speed the car across the gap. He should not have accepted the challenge. Roger Vadim's colorful "Metzengerstein" is from a story I haven't read, but the plot can be summed up easily enough. Juliet, in all her noble nubility, falls in love with Romeo but accidentally kills him half-way through, upon which he turns into a horse. Juliet senses his presence in the horse and rides him constantly, finally to their joint destiny. (What is it with women and horses anyway?) The viewer will be surprised to find out that in Medieval France the half-naked girls wore gaudy costumes not unlike those of Las Vegas showgirls. I didn't mind it. I didn't mind Jane Fonda's determined debaucheries either. Except those gang bangs were disgusting. What do those dumb page boys or whatever they are have that I don't have? What puts the ape in apricot? Fonda speaks French in this one. I was able to follow most of it because she speaks with such a marked American accent, as if she'd learned French at Vassar, the same French I learned in high school.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Vadim segment is a mess but worth the look for Fellini's
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    TheLittleSongbird
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    In all honesty, Federico Fellini, whose directing and style I greatly admire, was one of two main attractions to Histoires Extraordinaries in the first place. The other was Edgar Allan Poe. And his segment is the best of the three for me. True, it is more Fellini than Poe with the protagonist like watching 8 1/2 or La Dolce Vita and the dream sequences and the quality of the art direction like 8 1/2 and Juliet of the Spirits, but I love that he adapted a story and put his own style into it. As ever it is beautifully filmed, with a nice score, is superbly directed by Fellini with his sense of nostalgia and themes interesting and boasts a mesmerising performance from Terrence Stamp. Louis Malle's segment is perhaps the most true to Poe's writing. It is straightforward storytelling but chillingly effective at it. It is handsomely filmed also, and Alain Delon as well as good-looking is very convincing. Sadly, the segment directed by Roger Vadim is a mess. It is nice to look at and Jane Fonda is always watchable, but the pace is dull, the direction is all over the place, the story never knows whether it wants to be a drama or a Gothic tale and Peter Fonda is simply wasted. Overall though it is a good and interesting film. And who can go wrong with the great Vincent Price narrating? I cannot see where you can personally. 8/10 Bethany Cox
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Puzzle of dried flowers
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Vincentiu
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/3/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    interesting. for cast, directors, passing of time. for Poe or for remembers from old age. but not more.because this puzzle is dusty, strange and out of charm. Roger Vadim gives a mannerist version of Elisabeth Bathory and form of love with artificial notes - option for Peter Fonda is not inspired idea -, Louis Malle creates an interesting universe , tired after short time, with a blank cold statue as axis, with few cruel ingredients and meeting between Bardot and Delon as heart. Fellini, well, Fellini is Fellini and it is important. because his style, atmosphere of his universe, a Terence Stamp like mask of Mastroiani are just virtues in this case. it is enough ? maybe not. the final impression is about a puzzle of dried flowers.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Malle's Homage to Cocteau's Les Enfants Terribles
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bensonj
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It's interesting that no IMDb commenters seem to have caught Malle's significant homage in "William Wilson." Malle makes Wilson far more sadistic that Poe's character. In the opening school sequence, Poe's Wilson is, to be sure, a leader of the other students: "the ardor, the enthusiasm, and the imperiousness of my disposition, soon rendered me a marked character among my schoolmates, and by slow, but natural gradations, gave me an ascendancy over all not greatly older than myself." Any sadism is, at most, implied: "If there is on earth a supreme and unqualified despotism, it is the despotism of a master mind in boyhood over the less energetic spirits of its companions." In Poe, Wilson does not try to strangle his doppelganger, nor is he expelled from the school. He approaches the other's bed at night, apparently sees his own face on the sleeping boy and "passed silently from the chamber, and left at once, the halls of that old academy, never to enter them again." In Malle's film, Wilson is torturing another student as a snowball fight rages in the background. The doppelganger makes his first appearance by hitting Wilson with a snowball. The snow fight, the torture, the significant hit by a snowball, the expulsion from school are not in Poe's tale. But all these elements ARE in Jean Cocteau's novel LES ENFANTS TERRIBLES. The snowball fight not only is featured in Jean-Pierre Melville's film of the novel, but Cocteau filmed the scene earlier in his own BLOOD OF A POET. The torture is briefly in Melville's film, but described more fully in the novel: "By the spasmodic flaring of the gas lamp he could be seen to be a small boy with his back against the wall, hemmed in by his captives...One of these...was squatting between his legs and twisting his ears...Weeping, he sought to close his eyes, to avert his head. But every time he struggled, his torturer seized a fistful of gray snow and scrubbed his ears with it." As the snow fight continues, Cocteau's iconic character Dargelos throws a snowball that hits another student and puts in motion the events of the novel/film. Dargelos is the same sort of malignant leader of his schoolmates as Malle's young Wilson. The headmaster calls his influence on his classmates unhealthy, and after an outrageous act he is expelled from the school. Even more to the point, Dargelos has a doppelganger in the form of the character Agathe. In Melville's film Dargelos and Agathe are played by same person, and their mysterious resemblance is important to the story. All of these added Cocteau elements are so strong that one assumes that Malle intended viewers to recognize the reference.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An American icon transformed into Sixties Eurotrash
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    LCShackley
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/12/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    There's not much Poe here, except his name. Roger Corman did a better job of sticking to the original stories than this trio of "stellar" directors: Vadim, Malle, and Fellini. In the spirit of the indulgent 60s, these three auteurs twisted Poe into the shape of their own imagination, rewriting and "sexing up" the stories to appeal to the pompous art-house crowd. There are some beautiful locations and striking visuals, to be sure...plus long, long stretches of boredom (Jane Fonda playing with a horse, Terence Stamp driving drunk). The music is also dated and laughable, especially Nino Rota's pop dreck under the Fellini segment. Trivia: be on the lookout for Andreas Voutsinas as a bearded courtier in the Vadim segment. He was Jane Fonda's acting coach, but best-known to American audiences as the creepy Carmen Ghia in Mel Brooks's original "The Producers" (released the same year as this film).
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    If only Toby Dammit was feature-length...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tomgillespie2002
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/9/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Also known as Histoires Extraordinaires, this film combines three short stories by Edgar Allen Poe, and has each segment directed by a different European director. The first, entitled Metzengerstein, is directed by the man that helmed Barbarella, Roger Vadim. It tells the story of a beautiful yet debauched countess Federica (Jane Fonda) who falls in love with her family rival, Baron Wilhelm (Peter Fonda - bit weird, them being real-life brother and sister), who frees her leg from a trap in the woods. After he rejects her, she orders the burning of one of his villages, and the Baron is killed when attempting a rescue of one of his horses. The horse is taken in by Federica, who becomes obsessed with it once she notices its resemblance to the one painted on a damaged tapestry. The second story, William Wilson, is directed by French film-maker Louis Malle. It tells a familiar doppelg&auml;nger story of the wicked William Wilson (Alain Delon) who is also interrupted by his 'better half' who shares his name and his appearance, but none of his evil ways. After winning a card game against Giuseppina (Brigitte Bardot) through repeatedly cheating, his other half exposes him, and the two face a duel. The third, directed by Federico Fellini and entitled Toby Dammit, follows alcoholic Shakesperean actor Toby Dammit (Terence Stamp) who is brought to Rome to star in an adaptation of the story of Christ, re- imagined as a western. Haunted by visions of a blonde girl who has lost her ball, he goes on a drunken ride through Rome in a Ferrari. The biggest problem with this film is the variations of quality in the different episodes. Vadim's opener is a pretty poor effort, with a strange storyline focusing on a woman's obsession with a horse. It seems to be nothing more than an excuse to get Jane Fonda into some skimpy medieval outfits. That is all well and good (it was one of the key reasons why I loved Barbarella!) but it's a silly story and a waste of some beautiful cinematography. Malle's second story is a big improvement, but it is clear that his heart is not really in it. Apparently he agreed to take on the job in order to raise money for Murmur of the Heart, and compromised to make the film more accessible to mainstream audiences. But the eroticism of the card game, and the strange atmosphere that is evident throughout make it an enjoyable 40 minutes. Fellini's final segment is very much the director's own vision. It is so far gone from anything resembling Poe's original vision, it could be easily called Fellini's own. Thematically similar to most of his key works, Terence Stamp's crumbling lead character is the main focus, and his disintegrating sanity is laid out on the screen with a collection of flashing images, bizarre characters, and unconventional camera-work. It is also an attack on celebrity, as the characters that Dammit comes across don't react or flinch at his increasingly strange and unpredictable behaviour. It's a shame that Fellini is restricted to a 40 minute portion of a 2-hour film, as I would have quite happily watched Toby Dammit as a full-length feature. An enjoyable, if unspectacular overall film, with the stories getting notably better as the film goes on. www.the-wrath-of-blog.blogspot.com
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Rejected Night Gallery TV material
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    grandfunkfan
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/2/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Three Poe stories; three directors; three failures. Simply put, this movie is not entertaining. Using Poe's name, and labeling the stories as interpretations by famous directors does not cover the poor performance and overall boring conclusion. The viewer, very possibly a fan of Poe, keeps hoping for something to develop, but it never does. Jane Fonda never removes her clothes. Peter Fonda is a again outperformed by a bird. The beautiful scenery and castles are fantastic. Hells bells ring loud and clear. But the movie never turns into an entertaining event. The Night Gallery TV series had many good stories and many duds. The adaptations of Poe stories in the film Spirits of the Dead would never have been used in the most desperate space-filler needs of television. There are several good film adaptations of Poe stories, but Spirits of the Dead is not worth watching.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A lot of style--not a lot of substance.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    planktonrules
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The style of "Spirits of the Dead" was not very unusual for the 1960s in Europe. Several other films consisted of top directors doing short films as part of an anthology movie, such as "Boccaccio 70". In the case of "Spirits of the Dead", the films are all adaptations of Edgar Allen Poe stories--and in some cases they stray quite a bit from the original source material. "Metzengerstein" is directed by Roger Vadim and is a film about a sadistic sybaritic noblewoman (Jane Fonda--Vadim's wife at the time). She regularly indulges in all sorts of sexual excesses with her friends, torments her vassals for kicks and is a thoroughly despicable wretch. One day, she sees a distant cousin whose family and hers are rivals. She becomes obsessed by the man (which is interesting, as it's played by Jane's real life brother, Peter) and eventually she does something very evil and spiteful because he will not come to her twisted parties. What's next? See for yourself. I must warn you that this first film is very dull, slow-paced and is pretty silly and forgettable. The worst part about it for me was seeing Jane's silly costumes. While the film appears set in about the year 1500, her costumes appear to be straight from the Vadim space epic, "Barbarella" and this is utterly ridiculous. And, I noticed that most reviewers disliked this short. As for me, I didn't see a whole lot to like about it other than a rare chance to see the two Fondas working together. "William Wilson" is directed by Louis Malle, stars Alain Delon. The film begins with Wilson running into a confessional and loudly demanding that the priest listen to him--even though he acknowledges he is not a Catholic. He admits to a murder and then begins a long story of why he did this dastardly act. During this story, Wilson admits to being a complete sadist and is a man who has no remorse or feeling about others. He is a predatory creature--and why he goes to confess is just something you'll need to see for yourself. What's next? See for yourself. In addition to Delon, this film stars Brigitte Bardot sporting a black wig. She is, as usual, gorgeous. However, you should be forewarned about this film. It is pretty sadistic and nasty in places--and is definitely for adults only. The story is mildly interesting (like a "Twilight Zone" episode) and worth seeing...just don't watch it with your mom or Pastor Jenkins. "Toby Dammit" is by Federico Fellini. This segment is a treat for die-hard Fellini fans, as it has so much that they will probably love. Much of the film seems like it was inspired by "8 1/2" as well as "La Dulce Vita" as it consists of a very much adored celebrity having sycophants falling at his feet as well as a long procession of weird looking extras. It is 100% style...and not a lot of substance. Terrance Stamp plays this celebrity and he plays it as if he's a boorish jerk strung out on heroin--which you assume the character is. I have noticed that critically speaking, it's the most loved of the three films, though I thought the plot itself was very, very weak. It's more like watching a freak show (again, not unusual for many Fellini films) but without a lot of payoff in the end. My overall verdict is that despite the ultra-famous directors, the film lacks substance and, believe it or not, the very cheap Poe films directed by Roger Corman are significantly better. The bottom line is that Malle and Fellini have done so much better work than this and it's a film only for completists who want to see everything they've made. A big disappointment for me.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Somewhat fun, classy Anthology effort
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    GL84
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/9/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A collection of three different Edgar Allen Poe tales by three different directors. The Good Stor(ies): Metzengerstein-Living a life of decadence and depravity, a sadistic baroness enjoys living alone in her castle watching her distant cousin carry on his life whilst ignoring her advances and existence. When word reaches her that he has perished in a deadly fire on his land, she becomes distraught and begins a fanatical obsession with restoring a tapestry depicting a fiery, wild horse he supposedly own by him, while carrying on an equally deadly obsession with a stray horse that appears shortly afterword that bears a striking resemblance to the individual in the cloth. Easily the best of the stories, with a rather impressive mixture of Gothic atmosphere here with it's crumbling castle setting, expansive layouts and decadence littering the entire area, which creates a visually haunting location to use here. As well, the lone action scene, the fire to the adjacent estate, is equally impressive with it's large-scale impact, noteworthy fire stunt and visual dynamics as this is usually the ending to many of these Gothic horrors with the burning-the-house-down finale here placed in the middle section, which is quite innovative, and with both of these segments meshing with her sense of sadism and depravity with humiliation games, orgies and other forms of entertainment overall create a rather impressive entry. William Wilson-Rushing into a church, a distraught man begs the local priest to hear his confession. Starting with his first introduction, he relates the story of a man who is his identical in every way, even sharing the same name as each other, and whenever he tries to entertain himself through his usual sense of depraved fun, his doppelganger appears to ruin it, and by the time it finally grows to a maddening scale, he engages his mysterious twin in a final game of fate. This here is certainly watchable enough as the depravity here is increased with games as the dunking into the rats, surgery on the nude woman and whipping the woman he won in the card game, which creates a rather creepy air when they're all interrupted and dropped with clever rationalizations. There's even a bloody sword-fight to give it some nice action as well. The only real flaw to this one is that the segment tends to meander from the same set-up to the next without any variation, really keeping this one from doing anything entertaining with it's premise. It does grow tiresome to know everything is going to keep repeating, regardless of what's going on, so it looses a little there but is overall quite enjoyable. The Bad Stor(ies): Toby Dammit-Arriving in Italy, a boozing, drugged actor is constantly shuffled around from one personal requested-appearance to the next without delay, causing him to sink deeper into his sense of personal despair. Finally arriving at a gala award show for his honor, he finds the locals gathered there far too much for his sanity to overcome, and when he begins to let his inhibitions loose to their fullest extent, finds himself in a deeper Hell than before. This was overall quite boring as the entire segment plays out as though it's an acid-trip nightmare. Sure, it's overtly weird and generally quite stylish visually, but that doesn't really make it scary. The drive through the deserted streets at night is about the only thing worthwhile here, as it's a lengthy, extended sequence that really gets far more enjoyable over time, though the majority of time taken up by the strange award ceremony rather than being scary really dooms this entry. Not enough for the movie overall, but just slightly. Today's Rating/R: Violence, Nudity and Language
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Fonda's radiant
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    kols
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/9/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Which is the only reason I give this turkey one star. First saw this when it came out, just as Doris Day and Rock Hudson were giving way to Peckinpah, so it seemed like a breath of fresh air and Fonda did carry the first story, which seemed hackneyed even in 1969. The only interesting part of the second story was, well, for an adolescent male, the naked girl tied up on the dissection table. Very racy for the time. Bardot (same episode, different scene) looked awful in a black fright-wig. Would have liked to have seen her stripped and some implied sex, as in the scene with the girl. Otherwise, the plot was just boring, Delon just irritating and Bardot doing a mannish parody of Feminism. As for Fellini, Fellini's Fellini and you should never expect anything else than irrational imagery from him. Except that, like Vadim and Malle, he suffers from the same boring self-absorbance and insufferable self-indulgence that characterized much of that time's European Cine. But, in 1969, it did really impress me. Now-a-days, it makes me thank God for Hawkes and Wayne and the Hustons and the thousands of other Americans who knew how to make real movies. To be blunt, with a few genre exceptions (Ronin), many European film makers seem primarily interested in doing the same thing I was doing while watching the girl on the table. Writing this review now because just saw it again on TCM and was mightily disappointed, except for the girl on the table.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Colorful Poe.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Robert J. Maxwell (rmax304823@yahoo.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/9/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "William Wilson", directed by Louis Malle, with Alain Delon as the titular hero and his own double, is really pretty good. Delon gets to whip the proud Bridget Bardot, which is going a little too far, although heaven knows she deserves a good licking. The tone of the story is suitably elegant and ironic. The men wear carefully tailored generic uniforms with cream-colored jackets. William Wilson is a naughty boy. He deceives people, breaks hearts, cheats at cards. BUT -- he can't seem to get away with any of it because whenever he pulls one of his stunts, a masked figure calling himself William Wilson shows up and exposes him for the fraud he is. Wilson finally kills his Doppelganger and then himself. It's one of my favorite Poe stories because it's different. Most stories of doubles from this period materialize Freud's "id", the savage part of our minds that we try so desperately to suppress. Examples range from Mr. Hyde to Professor Moriarty. Pure evil. But this double represent Freud's "superego," the conscience. Nicely done. The last segment was directed by Federico Fellini with photography by Giuseppe Rotunno and score by Nino Rota. I mention this because these two craftsmen make the story unmistakably Fellini's. I don't think the director could have done it without them. It's based (very loosely) on Poe's "Never Bet The Devil Your Head." Terence Stamp is the internationally famous movie star, Toby Dammit, and arrives in Rome to accept one of those awards like the Palm D'Or or the Oscar. The Rome into which Stamp descends is an hallucinatory vision of hell, beginning with the slightly insane and thoroughly claret-colored airport. What follows is a hilarious parody of an awards ceremony. While a drunken Stamp waits his turn, one after another phony is paraded onto the stage under the blazing lights, striding through studio fog, accompanied by a joyous ruckus. There is a group called The Three Angels From Hell that collectively receive one of these awards. Asked to say a few words, each follows the other and blankly mouths the same appreciation: "I'm very moved by this. All I can say is 'Thank you'." They project the believability of some guy behind the supermarket check-out counter who says, "Have a nice day." I ought to mention, before describing more of the story, that the focus isn't entirely on the awards ceremony. Stamp has to be interviewed on a TV program first, for instance, and -- throughout -- there are all sorts of inexplicable and bizarre goings on. At the interview, a carefully groomed and very beautiful woman steps before the camera and lauds the interviewee. Then she slowly and deliberately drops to her knees, still grinning, puts her nose on the floor and crawls away. Is she deranged? Is the director irretrievably mad? No! It's just her way of taking herself off camera and crawling out of the way so that the interview can get started. Other whimsical events and shots take place, too many to mention. At any rate, Terence Stamp is so liquified at the awards ceremony he can only stagger to the stage. It's been suggested to him that he recite something from Shakespeare, "the most famous poet in the world -- second only to our Dante." But keep it short. Short Shakespeare. We don't want to bore the audience. Stamp's face is a ghastly death mask of agony as he begins some well-known lines from "MacBeth" but he quits, tells the audience and the staff what they can do to themselves, stumbles outside, gets into his Ferrari and speeds away. The story slows down considerably despite the Ferrari's speed and the reckless laughter of the drunken maniac behind its wheel. Stamp finds himself spinning around in empty shabby neighborhoods full of dead ends, with stuffed dummies representing chefs and flocks of sheep scattered about, as in a "Twilight Zone" episode. At the end, he encounters a bridge with a gap in the middle of it. On the other side of the gap is the devil in the guise of a pretty little blond girl. He senses that the devil is challenging him to speed the car across the gap. He should not have accepted the challenge. Roger Vadim's colorful "Metzengerstein" is from a story I haven't read, but the plot can be summed up easily enough. Juliet, in all her noble nubility, falls in love with Romeo but accidentally kills him half-way through, upon which he turns into a horse. Juliet senses his presence in the horse and rides him constantly, finally to their joint destiny. (What is it with women and horses anyway?) The viewer will be surprised to find out that in Medieval France the half-naked girls wore gaudy costumes not unlike those of Las Vegas showgirls. I didn't mind it. I didn't mind Jane Fonda's determined debaucheries either. Except those gang bangs were disgusting. What do those dumb page boys or whatever they are have that I don't have? What puts the ape in apricot? Fonda speaks French in this one. I was able to follow most of it because she speaks with such a marked American accent, as if she'd learned French at Vassar, the same French I learned in high school.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Vadim segment is a mess but worth the look for Fellini's
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    TheLittleSongbird
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    In all honesty, Federico Fellini, whose directing and style I greatly admire, was one of two main attractions to Histoires Extraordinaries in the first place. The other was Edgar Allan Poe. And his segment is the best of the three for me. True, it is more Fellini than Poe with the protagonist like watching 8 1/2 or La Dolce Vita and the dream sequences and the quality of the art direction like 8 1/2 and Juliet of the Spirits, but I love that he adapted a story and put his own style into it. As ever it is beautifully filmed, with a nice score, is superbly directed by Fellini with his sense of nostalgia and themes interesting and boasts a mesmerising performance from Terrence Stamp. Louis Malle's segment is perhaps the most true to Poe's writing. It is straightforward storytelling but chillingly effective at it. It is handsomely filmed also, and Alain Delon as well as good-looking is very convincing. Sadly, the segment directed by Roger Vadim is a mess. It is nice to look at and Jane Fonda is always watchable, but the pace is dull, the direction is all over the place, the story never knows whether it wants to be a drama or a Gothic tale and Peter Fonda is simply wasted. Overall though it is a good and interesting film. And who can go wrong with the great Vincent Price narrating? I cannot see where you can personally. 8/10 Bethany Cox
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Puzzle of dried flowers
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Vincentiu
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/3/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    interesting. for cast, directors, passing of time. for Poe or for remembers from old age. but not more.because this puzzle is dusty, strange and out of charm. Roger Vadim gives a mannerist version of Elisabeth Bathory and form of love with artificial notes - option for Peter Fonda is not inspired idea -, Louis Malle creates an interesting universe , tired after short time, with a blank cold statue as axis, with few cruel ingredients and meeting between Bardot and Delon as heart. Fellini, well, Fellini is Fellini and it is important. because his style, atmosphere of his universe, a Terence Stamp like mask of Mastroiani are just virtues in this case. it is enough ? maybe not. the final impression is about a puzzle of dried flowers.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Malle's Homage to Cocteau's Les Enfants Terribles
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bensonj
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It's interesting that no IMDb commenters seem to have caught Malle's significant homage in "William Wilson." Malle makes Wilson far more sadistic that Poe's character. In the opening school sequence, Poe's Wilson is, to be sure, a leader of the other students: "the ardor, the enthusiasm, and the imperiousness of my disposition, soon rendered me a marked character among my schoolmates, and by slow, but natural gradations, gave me an ascendancy over all not greatly older than myself." Any sadism is, at most, implied: "If there is on earth a supreme and unqualified despotism, it is the despotism of a master mind in boyhood over the less energetic spirits of its companions." In Poe, Wilson does not try to strangle his doppelganger, nor is he expelled from the school. He approaches the other's bed at night, apparently sees his own face on the sleeping boy and "passed silently from the chamber, and left at once, the halls of that old academy, never to enter them again." In Malle's film, Wilson is torturing another student as a snowball fight rages in the background. The doppelganger makes his first appearance by hitting Wilson with a snowball. The snow fight, the torture, the significant hit by a snowball, the expulsion from school are not in Poe's tale. But all these elements ARE in Jean Cocteau's novel LES ENFANTS TERRIBLES. The snowball fight not only is featured in Jean-Pierre Melville's film of the novel, but Cocteau filmed the scene earlier in his own BLOOD OF A POET. The torture is briefly in Melville's film, but described more fully in the novel: "By the spasmodic flaring of the gas lamp he could be seen to be a small boy with his back against the wall, hemmed in by his captives...One of these...was squatting between his legs and twisting his ears...Weeping, he sought to close his eyes, to avert his head. But every time he struggled, his torturer seized a fistful of gray snow and scrubbed his ears with it." As the snow fight continues, Cocteau's iconic character Dargelos throws a snowball that hits another student and puts in motion the events of the novel/film. Dargelos is the same sort of malignant leader of his schoolmates as Malle's young Wilson. The headmaster calls his influence on his classmates unhealthy, and after an outrageous act he is expelled from the school. Even more to the point, Dargelos has a doppelganger in the form of the character Agathe. In Melville's film Dargelos and Agathe are played by same person, and their mysterious resemblance is important to the story. All of these added Cocteau elements are so strong that one assumes that Malle intended viewers to recognize the reference.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An American icon transformed into Sixties Eurotrash
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    LCShackley
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/12/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    There's not much Poe here, except his name. Roger Corman did a better job of sticking to the original stories than this trio of "stellar" directors: Vadim, Malle, and Fellini. In the spirit of the indulgent 60s, these three auteurs twisted Poe into the shape of their own imagination, rewriting and "sexing up" the stories to appeal to the pompous art-house crowd. There are some beautiful locations and striking visuals, to be sure...plus long, long stretches of boredom (Jane Fonda playing with a horse, Terence Stamp driving drunk). The music is also dated and laughable, especially Nino Rota's pop dreck under the Fellini segment. Trivia: be on the lookout for Andreas Voutsinas as a bearded courtier in the Vadim segment. He was Jane Fonda's acting coach, but best-known to American audiences as the creepy Carmen Ghia in Mel Brooks's original "The Producers" (released the same year as this film).
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    If only Toby Dammit was feature-length...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tomgillespie2002
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/9/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Also known as Histoires Extraordinaires, this film combines three short stories by Edgar Allen Poe, and has each segment directed by a different European director. The first, entitled Metzengerstein, is directed by the man that helmed Barbarella, Roger Vadim. It tells the story of a beautiful yet debauched countess Federica (Jane Fonda) who falls in love with her family rival, Baron Wilhelm (Peter Fonda - bit weird, them being real-life brother and sister), who frees her leg from a trap in the woods. After he rejects her, she orders the burning of one of his villages, and the Baron is killed when attempting a rescue of one of his horses. The horse is taken in by Federica, who becomes obsessed with it once she notices its resemblance to the one painted on a damaged tapestry. The second story, William Wilson, is directed by French film-maker Louis Malle. It tells a familiar doppelg&auml;nger story of the wicked William Wilson (Alain Delon) who is also interrupted by his 'better half' who shares his name and his appearance, but none of his evil ways. After winning a card game against Giuseppina (Brigitte Bardot) through repeatedly cheating, his other half exposes him, and the two face a duel. The third, directed by Federico Fellini and entitled Toby Dammit, follows alcoholic Shakesperean actor Toby Dammit (Terence Stamp) who is brought to Rome to star in an adaptation of the story of Christ, re- imagined as a western. Haunted by visions of a blonde girl who has lost her ball, he goes on a drunken ride through Rome in a Ferrari. The biggest problem with this film is the variations of quality in the different episodes. Vadim's opener is a pretty poor effort, with a strange storyline focusing on a woman's obsession with a horse. It seems to be nothing more than an excuse to get Jane Fonda into some skimpy medieval outfits. That is all well and good (it was one of the key reasons why I loved Barbarella!) but it's a silly story and a waste of some beautiful cinematography. Malle's second story is a big improvement, but it is clear that his heart is not really in it. Apparently he agreed to take on the job in order to raise money for Murmur of the Heart, and compromised to make the film more accessible to mainstream audiences. But the eroticism of the card game, and the strange atmosphere that is evident throughout make it an enjoyable 40 minutes. Fellini's final segment is very much the director's own vision. It is so far gone from anything resembling Poe's original vision, it could be easily called Fellini's own. Thematically similar to most of his key works, Terence Stamp's crumbling lead character is the main focus, and his disintegrating sanity is laid out on the screen with a collection of flashing images, bizarre characters, and unconventional camera-work. It is also an attack on celebrity, as the characters that Dammit comes across don't react or flinch at his increasingly strange and unpredictable behaviour. It's a shame that Fellini is restricted to a 40 minute portion of a 2-hour film, as I would have quite happily watched Toby Dammit as a full-length feature. An enjoyable, if unspectacular overall film, with the stories getting notably better as the film goes on. www.the-wrath-of-blog.blogspot.com
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Rejected Night Gallery TV material
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    grandfunkfan
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/2/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Three Poe stories; three directors; three failures. Simply put, this movie is not entertaining. Using Poe's name, and labeling the stories as interpretations by famous directors does not cover the poor performance and overall boring conclusion. The viewer, very possibly a fan of Poe, keeps hoping for something to develop, but it never does. Jane Fonda never removes her clothes. Peter Fonda is a again outperformed by a bird. The beautiful scenery and castles are fantastic. Hells bells ring loud and clear. But the movie never turns into an entertaining event. The Night Gallery TV series had many good stories and many duds. The adaptations of Poe stories in the film Spirits of the Dead would never have been used in the most desperate space-filler needs of television. There are several good film adaptations of Poe stories, but Spirits of the Dead is not worth watching.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A lot of style--not a lot of substance.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    planktonrules
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The style of "Spirits of the Dead" was not very unusual for the 1960s in Europe. Several other films consisted of top directors doing short films as part of an anthology movie, such as "Boccaccio 70". In the case of "Spirits of the Dead", the films are all adaptations of Edgar Allen Poe stories--and in some cases they stray quite a bit from the original source material. "Metzengerstein" is directed by Roger Vadim and is a film about a sadistic sybaritic noblewoman (Jane Fonda--Vadim's wife at the time). She regularly indulges in all sorts of sexual excesses with her friends, torments her vassals for kicks and is a thoroughly despicable wretch. One day, she sees a distant cousin whose family and hers are rivals. She becomes obsessed by the man (which is interesting, as it's played by Jane's real life brother, Peter) and eventually she does something very evil and spiteful because he will not come to her twisted parties. What's next? See for yourself. I must warn you that this first film is very dull, slow-paced and is pretty silly and forgettable. The worst part about it for me was seeing Jane's silly costumes. While the film appears set in about the year 1500, her costumes appear to be straight from the Vadim space epic, "Barbarella" and this is utterly ridiculous. And, I noticed that most reviewers disliked this short. As for me, I didn't see a whole lot to like about it other than a rare chance to see the two Fondas working together. "William Wilson" is directed by Louis Malle, stars Alain Delon. The film begins with Wilson running into a confessional and loudly demanding that the priest listen to him--even though he acknowledges he is not a Catholic. He admits to a murder and then begins a long story of why he did this dastardly act. During this story, Wilson admits to being a complete sadist and is a man who has no remorse or feeling about others. He is a predatory creature--and why he goes to confess is just something you'll need to see for yourself. What's next? See for yourself. In addition to Delon, this film stars Brigitte Bardot sporting a black wig. She is, as usual, gorgeous. However, you should be forewarned about this film. It is pretty sadistic and nasty in places--and is definitely for adults only. The story is mildly interesting (like a "Twilight Zone" episode) and worth seeing...just don't watch it with your mom or Pastor Jenkins. "Toby Dammit" is by Federico Fellini. This segment is a treat for die-hard Fellini fans, as it has so much that they will probably love. Much of the film seems like it was inspired by "8 1/2" as well as "La Dulce Vita" as it consists of a very much adored celebrity having sycophants falling at his feet as well as a long procession of weird looking extras. It is 100% style...and not a lot of substance. Terrance Stamp plays this celebrity and he plays it as if he's a boorish jerk strung out on heroin--which you assume the character is. I have noticed that critically speaking, it's the most loved of the three films, though I thought the plot itself was very, very weak. It's more like watching a freak show (again, not unusual for many Fellini films) but without a lot of payoff in the end. My overall verdict is that despite the ultra-famous directors, the film lacks substance and, believe it or not, the very cheap Poe films directed by Roger Corman are significantly better. The bottom line is that Malle and Fellini have done so much better work than this and it's a film only for completists who want to see everything they've made. A big disappointment for me.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Somewhat fun, classy Anthology effort
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    GL84
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/9/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A collection of three different Edgar Allen Poe tales by three different directors. The Good Stor(ies): Metzengerstein-Living a life of decadence and depravity, a sadistic baroness enjoys living alone in her castle watching her distant cousin carry on his life whilst ignoring her advances and existence. When word reaches her that he has perished in a deadly fire on his land, she becomes distraught and begins a fanatical obsession with restoring a tapestry depicting a fiery, wild horse he supposedly own by him, while carrying on an equally deadly obsession with a stray horse that appears shortly afterword that bears a striking resemblance to the individual in the cloth. Easily the best of the stories, with a rather impressive mixture of Gothic atmosphere here with it's crumbling castle setting, expansive layouts and decadence littering the entire area, which creates a visually haunting location to use here. As well, the lone action scene, the fire to the adjacent estate, is equally impressive with it's large-scale impact, noteworthy fire stunt and visual dynamics as this is usually the ending to many of these Gothic horrors with the burning-the-house-down finale here placed in the middle section, which is quite innovative, and with both of these segments meshing with her sense of sadism and depravity with humiliation games, orgies and other forms of entertainment overall create a rather impressive entry. William Wilson-Rushing into a church, a distraught man begs the local priest to hear his confession. Starting with his first introduction, he relates the story of a man who is his identical in every way, even sharing the same name as each other, and whenever he tries to entertain himself through his usual sense of depraved fun, his doppelganger appears to ruin it, and by the time it finally grows to a maddening scale, he engages his mysterious twin in a final game of fate. This here is certainly watchable enough as the depravity here is increased with games as the dunking into the rats, surgery on the nude woman and whipping the woman he won in the card game, which creates a rather creepy air when they're all interrupted and dropped with clever rationalizations. There's even a bloody sword-fight to give it some nice action as well. The only real flaw to this one is that the segment tends to meander from the same set-up to the next without any variation, really keeping this one from doing anything entertaining with it's premise. It does grow tiresome to know everything is going to keep repeating, regardless of what's going on, so it looses a little there but is overall quite enjoyable. The Bad Stor(ies): Toby Dammit-Arriving in Italy, a boozing, drugged actor is constantly shuffled around from one personal requested-appearance to the next without delay, causing him to sink deeper into his sense of personal despair. Finally arriving at a gala award show for his honor, he finds the locals gathered there far too much for his sanity to overcome, and when he begins to let his inhibitions loose to their fullest extent, finds himself in a deeper Hell than before. This was overall quite boring as the entire segment plays out as though it's an acid-trip nightmare. Sure, it's overtly weird and generally quite stylish visually, but that doesn't really make it scary. The drive through the deserted streets at night is about the only thing worthwhile here, as it's a lengthy, extended sequence that really gets far more enjoyable over time, though the majority of time taken up by the strange award ceremony rather than being scary really dooms this entry. Not enough for the movie overall, but just slightly. Today's Rating/R: Violence, Nudity and Language
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Fonda's radiant
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    kols
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/9/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Which is the only reason I give this turkey one star. First saw this when it came out, just as Doris Day and Rock Hudson were giving way to Peckinpah, so it seemed like a breath of fresh air and Fonda did carry the first story, which seemed hackneyed even in 1969. The only interesting part of the second story was, well, for an adolescent male, the naked girl tied up on the dissection table. Very racy for the time. Bardot (same episode, different scene) looked awful in a black fright-wig. Would have liked to have seen her stripped and some implied sex, as in the scene with the girl. Otherwise, the plot was just boring, Delon just irritating and Bardot doing a mannish parody of Feminism. As for Fellini, Fellini's Fellini and you should never expect anything else than irrational imagery from him. Except that, like Vadim and Malle, he suffers from the same boring self-absorbance and insufferable self-indulgence that characterized much of that time's European Cine. But, in 1969, it did really impress me. Now-a-days, it makes me thank God for Hawkes and Wayne and the Hustons and the thousands of other Americans who knew how to make real movies. To be blunt, with a few genre exceptions (Ronin), many European film makers seem primarily interested in doing the same thing I was doing while watching the girl on the table. Writing this review now because just saw it again on TCM and was mightily disappointed, except for the girl on the table.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Colorful Poe.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Robert J. Maxwell (rmax304823@yahoo.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/9/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "William Wilson", directed by Louis Malle, with Alain Delon as the titular hero and his own double, is really pretty good. Delon gets to whip the proud Bridget Bardot, which is going a little too far, although heaven knows she deserves a good licking. The tone of the story is suitably elegant and ironic. The men wear carefully tailored generic uniforms with cream-colored jackets. William Wilson is a naughty boy. He deceives people, breaks hearts, cheats at cards. BUT -- he can't seem to get away with any of it because whenever he pulls one of his stunts, a masked figure calling himself William Wilson shows up and exposes him for the fraud he is. Wilson finally kills his Doppelganger and then himself. It's one of my favorite Poe stories because it's different. Most stories of doubles from this period materialize Freud's "id", the savage part of our minds that we try so desperately to suppress. Examples range from Mr. Hyde to Professor Moriarty. Pure evil. But this double represent Freud's "superego," the conscience. Nicely done. The last segment was directed by Federico Fellini with photography by Giuseppe Rotunno and score by Nino Rota. I mention this because these two craftsmen make the story unmistakably Fellini's. I don't think the director could have done it without them. It's based (very loosely) on Poe's "Never Bet The Devil Your Head." Terence Stamp is the internationally famous movie star, Toby Dammit, and arrives in Rome to accept one of those awards like the Palm D'Or or the Oscar. The Rome into which Stamp descends is an hallucinatory vision of hell, beginning with the slightly insane and thoroughly claret-colored airport. What follows is a hilarious parody of an awards ceremony. While a drunken Stamp waits his turn, one after another phony is paraded onto the stage under the blazing lights, striding through studio fog, accompanied by a joyous ruckus. There is a group called The Three Angels From Hell that collectively receive one of these awards. Asked to say a few words, each follows the other and blankly mouths the same appreciation: "I'm very moved by this. All I can say is 'Thank you'." They project the believability of some guy behind the supermarket check-out counter who says, "Have a nice day." I ought to mention, before describing more of the story, that the focus isn't entirely on the awards ceremony. Stamp has to be interviewed on a TV program first, for instance, and -- throughout -- there are all sorts of inexplicable and bizarre goings on. At the interview, a carefully groomed and very beautiful woman steps before the camera and lauds the interviewee. Then she slowly and deliberately drops to her knees, still grinning, puts her nose on the floor and crawls away. Is she deranged? Is the director irretrievably mad? No! It's just her way of taking herself off camera and crawling out of the way so that the interview can get started. Other whimsical events and shots take place, too many to mention. At any rate, Terence Stamp is so liquified at the awards ceremony he can only stagger to the stage. It's been suggested to him that he recite something from Shakespeare, "the most famous poet in the world -- second only to our Dante." But keep it short. Short Shakespeare. We don't want to bore the audience. Stamp's face is a ghastly death mask of agony as he begins some well-known lines from "MacBeth" but he quits, tells the audience and the staff what they can do to themselves, stumbles outside, gets into his Ferrari and speeds away. The story slows down considerably despite the Ferrari's speed and the reckless laughter of the drunken maniac behind its wheel. Stamp finds himself spinning around in empty shabby neighborhoods full of dead ends, with stuffed dummies representing chefs and flocks of sheep scattered about, as in a "Twilight Zone" episode. At the end, he encounters a bridge with a gap in the middle of it. On the other side of the gap is the devil in the guise of a pretty little blond girl. He senses that the devil is challenging him to speed the car across the gap. He should not have accepted the challenge. Roger Vadim's colorful "Metzengerstein" is from a story I haven't read, but the plot can be summed up easily enough. Juliet, in all her noble nubility, falls in love with Romeo but accidentally kills him half-way through, upon which he turns into a horse. Juliet senses his presence in the horse and rides him constantly, finally to their joint destiny. (What is it with women and horses anyway?) The viewer will be surprised to find out that in Medieval France the half-naked girls wore gaudy costumes not unlike those of Las Vegas showgirls. I didn't mind it. I didn't mind Jane Fonda's determined debaucheries either. Except those gang bangs were disgusting. What do those dumb page boys or whatever they are have that I don't have? What puts the ape in apricot? Fonda speaks French in this one. I was able to follow most of it because she speaks with such a marked American accent, as if she'd learned French at Vassar, the same French I learned in high school.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Vadim segment is a mess but worth the look for Fellini's
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    TheLittleSongbird
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    In all honesty, Federico Fellini, whose directing and style I greatly admire, was one of two main attractions to Histoires Extraordinaries in the first place. The other was Edgar Allan Poe. And his segment is the best of the three for me. True, it is more Fellini than Poe with the protagonist like watching 8 1/2 or La Dolce Vita and the dream sequences and the quality of the art direction like 8 1/2 and Juliet of the Spirits, but I love that he adapted a story and put his own style into it. As ever it is beautifully filmed, with a nice score, is superbly directed by Fellini with his sense of nostalgia and themes interesting and boasts a mesmerising performance from Terrence Stamp. Louis Malle's segment is perhaps the most true to Poe's writing. It is straightforward storytelling but chillingly effective at it. It is handsomely filmed also, and Alain Delon as well as good-looking is very convincing. Sadly, the segment directed by Roger Vadim is a mess. It is nice to look at and Jane Fonda is always watchable, but the pace is dull, the direction is all over the place, the story never knows whether it wants to be a drama or a Gothic tale and Peter Fonda is simply wasted. Overall though it is a good and interesting film. And who can go wrong with the great Vincent Price narrating? I cannot see where you can personally. 8/10 Bethany Cox
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Puzzle of dried flowers
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Vincentiu
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/3/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    interesting. for cast, directors, passing of time. for Poe or for remembers from old age. but not more.because this puzzle is dusty, strange and out of charm. Roger Vadim gives a mannerist version of Elisabeth Bathory and form of love with artificial notes - option for Peter Fonda is not inspired idea -, Louis Malle creates an interesting universe , tired after short time, with a blank cold statue as axis, with few cruel ingredients and meeting between Bardot and Delon as heart. Fellini, well, Fellini is Fellini and it is important. because his style, atmosphere of his universe, a Terence Stamp like mask of Mastroiani are just virtues in this case. it is enough ? maybe not. the final impression is about a puzzle of dried flowers.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Malle's Homage to Cocteau's Les Enfants Terribles
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bensonj
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It's interesting that no IMDb commenters seem to have caught Malle's significant homage in "William Wilson." Malle makes Wilson far more sadistic that Poe's character. In the opening school sequence, Poe's Wilson is, to be sure, a leader of the other students: "the ardor, the enthusiasm, and the imperiousness of my disposition, soon rendered me a marked character among my schoolmates, and by slow, but natural gradations, gave me an ascendancy over all not greatly older than myself." Any sadism is, at most, implied: "If there is on earth a supreme and unqualified despotism, it is the despotism of a master mind in boyhood over the less energetic spirits of its companions." In Poe, Wilson does not try to strangle his doppelganger, nor is he expelled from the school. He approaches the other's bed at night, apparently sees his own face on the sleeping boy and "passed silently from the chamber, and left at once, the halls of that old academy, never to enter them again." In Malle's film, Wilson is torturing another student as a snowball fight rages in the background. The doppelganger makes his first appearance by hitting Wilson with a snowball. The snow fight, the torture, the significant hit by a snowball, the expulsion from school are not in Poe's tale. But all these elements ARE in Jean Cocteau's novel LES ENFANTS TERRIBLES. The snowball fight not only is featured in Jean-Pierre Melville's film of the novel, but Cocteau filmed the scene earlier in his own BLOOD OF A POET. The torture is briefly in Melville's film, but described more fully in the novel: "By the spasmodic flaring of the gas lamp he could be seen to be a small boy with his back against the wall, hemmed in by his captives...One of these...was squatting between his legs and twisting his ears...Weeping, he sought to close his eyes, to avert his head. But every time he struggled, his torturer seized a fistful of gray snow and scrubbed his ears with it." As the snow fight continues, Cocteau's iconic character Dargelos throws a snowball that hits another student and puts in motion the events of the novel/film. Dargelos is the same sort of malignant leader of his schoolmates as Malle's young Wilson. The headmaster calls his influence on his classmates unhealthy, and after an outrageous act he is expelled from the school. Even more to the point, Dargelos has a doppelganger in the form of the character Agathe. In Melville's film Dargelos and Agathe are played by same person, and their mysterious resemblance is important to the story. All of these added Cocteau elements are so strong that one assumes that Malle intended viewers to recognize the reference.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An American icon transformed into Sixties Eurotrash
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    LCShackley
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/12/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    There's not much Poe here, except his name. Roger Corman did a better job of sticking to the original stories than this trio of "stellar" directors: Vadim, Malle, and Fellini. In the spirit of the indulgent 60s, these three auteurs twisted Poe into the shape of their own imagination, rewriting and "sexing up" the stories to appeal to the pompous art-house crowd. There are some beautiful locations and striking visuals, to be sure...plus long, long stretches of boredom (Jane Fonda playing with a horse, Terence Stamp driving drunk). The music is also dated and laughable, especially Nino Rota's pop dreck under the Fellini segment. Trivia: be on the lookout for Andreas Voutsinas as a bearded courtier in the Vadim segment. He was Jane Fonda's acting coach, but best-known to American audiences as the creepy Carmen Ghia in Mel Brooks's original "The Producers" (released the same year as this film).
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    If only Toby Dammit was feature-length...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tomgillespie2002
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/9/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Also known as Histoires Extraordinaires, this film combines three short stories by Edgar Allen Poe, and has each segment directed by a different European director. The first, entitled Metzengerstein, is directed by the man that helmed Barbarella, Roger Vadim. It tells the story of a beautiful yet debauched countess Federica (Jane Fonda) who falls in love with her family rival, Baron Wilhelm (Peter Fonda - bit weird, them being real-life brother and sister), who frees her leg from a trap in the woods. After he rejects her, she orders the burning of one of his villages, and the Baron is killed when attempting a rescue of one of his horses. The horse is taken in by Federica, who becomes obsessed with it once she notices its resemblance to the one painted on a damaged tapestry. The second story, William Wilson, is directed by French film-maker Louis Malle. It tells a familiar doppelg&auml;nger story of the wicked William Wilson (Alain Delon) who is also interrupted by his 'better half' who shares his name and his appearance, but none of his evil ways. After winning a card game against Giuseppina (Brigitte Bardot) through repeatedly cheating, his other half exposes him, and the two face a duel. The third, directed by Federico Fellini and entitled Toby Dammit, follows alcoholic Shakesperean actor Toby Dammit (Terence Stamp) who is brought to Rome to star in an adaptation of the story of Christ, re- imagined as a western. Haunted by visions of a blonde girl who has lost her ball, he goes on a drunken ride through Rome in a Ferrari. The biggest problem with this film is the variations of quality in the different episodes. Vadim's opener is a pretty poor effort, with a strange storyline focusing on a woman's obsession with a horse. It seems to be nothing more than an excuse to get Jane Fonda into some skimpy medieval outfits. That is all well and good (it was one of the key reasons why I loved Barbarella!) but it's a silly story and a waste of some beautiful cinematography. Malle's second story is a big improvement, but it is clear that his heart is not really in it. Apparently he agreed to take on the job in order to raise money for Murmur of the Heart, and compromised to make the film more accessible to mainstream audiences. But the eroticism of the card game, and the strange atmosphere that is evident throughout make it an enjoyable 40 minutes. Fellini's final segment is very much the director's own vision. It is so far gone from anything resembling Poe's original vision, it could be easily called Fellini's own. Thematically similar to most of his key works, Terence Stamp's crumbling lead character is the main focus, and his disintegrating sanity is laid out on the screen with a collection of flashing images, bizarre characters, and unconventional camera-work. It is also an attack on celebrity, as the characters that Dammit comes across don't react or flinch at his increasingly strange and unpredictable behaviour. It's a shame that Fellini is restricted to a 40 minute portion of a 2-hour film, as I would have quite happily watched Toby Dammit as a full-length feature. An enjoyable, if unspectacular overall film, with the stories getting notably better as the film goes on. www.the-wrath-of-blog.blogspot.com
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Rejected Night Gallery TV material
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    grandfunkfan
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/2/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Three Poe stories; three directors; three failures. Simply put, this movie is not entertaining. Using Poe's name, and labeling the stories as interpretations by famous directors does not cover the poor performance and overall boring conclusion. The viewer, very possibly a fan of Poe, keeps hoping for something to develop, but it never does. Jane Fonda never removes her clothes. Peter Fonda is a again outperformed by a bird. The beautiful scenery and castles are fantastic. Hells bells ring loud and clear. But the movie never turns into an entertaining event. The Night Gallery TV series had many good stories and many duds. The adaptations of Poe stories in the film Spirits of the Dead would never have been used in the most desperate space-filler needs of television. There are several good film adaptations of Poe stories, but Spirits of the Dead is not worth watching.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A lot of style--not a lot of substance.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    planktonrules
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The style of "Spirits of the Dead" was not very unusual for the 1960s in Europe. Several other films consisted of top directors doing short films as part of an anthology movie, such as "Boccaccio 70". In the case of "Spirits of the Dead", the films are all adaptations of Edgar Allen Poe stories--and in some cases they stray quite a bit from the original source material. "Metzengerstein" is directed by Roger Vadim and is a film about a sadistic sybaritic noblewoman (Jane Fonda--Vadim's wife at the time). She regularly indulges in all sorts of sexual excesses with her friends, torments her vassals for kicks and is a thoroughly despicable wretch. One day, she sees a distant cousin whose family and hers are rivals. She becomes obsessed by the man (which is interesting, as it's played by Jane's real life brother, Peter) and eventually she does something very evil and spiteful because he will not come to her twisted parties. What's next? See for yourself. I must warn you that this first film is very dull, slow-paced and is pretty silly and forgettable. The worst part about it for me was seeing Jane's silly costumes. While the film appears set in about the year 1500, her costumes appear to be straight from the Vadim space epic, "Barbarella" and this is utterly ridiculous. And, I noticed that most reviewers disliked this short. As for me, I didn't see a whole lot to like about it other than a rare chance to see the two Fondas working together. "William Wilson" is directed by Louis Malle, stars Alain Delon. The film begins with Wilson running into a confessional and loudly demanding that the priest listen to him--even though he acknowledges he is not a Catholic. He admits to a murder and then begins a long story of why he did this dastardly act. During this story, Wilson admits to being a complete sadist and is a man who has no remorse or feeling about others. He is a predatory creature--and why he goes to confess is just something you'll need to see for yourself. What's next? See for yourself. In addition to Delon, this film stars Brigitte Bardot sporting a black wig. She is, as usual, gorgeous. However, you should be forewarned about this film. It is pretty sadistic and nasty in places--and is definitely for adults only. The story is mildly interesting (like a "Twilight Zone" episode) and worth seeing...just don't watch it with your mom or Pastor Jenkins. "Toby Dammit" is by Federico Fellini. This segment is a treat for die-hard Fellini fans, as it has so much that they will probably love. Much of the film seems like it was inspired by "8 1/2" as well as "La Dulce Vita" as it consists of a very much adored celebrity having sycophants falling at his feet as well as a long procession of weird looking extras. It is 100% style...and not a lot of substance. Terrance Stamp plays this celebrity and he plays it as if he's a boorish jerk strung out on heroin--which you assume the character is. I have noticed that critically speaking, it's the most loved of the three films, though I thought the plot itself was very, very weak. It's more like watching a freak show (again, not unusual for many Fellini films) but without a lot of payoff in the end. My overall verdict is that despite the ultra-famous directors, the film lacks substance and, believe it or not, the very cheap Poe films directed by Roger Corman are significantly better. The bottom line is that Malle and Fellini have done so much better work than this and it's a film only for completists who want to see everything they've made. A big disappointment for me.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Somewhat fun, classy Anthology effort
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    GL84
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/9/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A collection of three different Edgar Allen Poe tales by three different directors. The Good Stor(ies): Metzengerstein-Living a life of decadence and depravity, a sadistic baroness enjoys living alone in her castle watching her distant cousin carry on his life whilst ignoring her advances and existence. When word reaches her that he has perished in a deadly fire on his land, she becomes distraught and begins a fanatical obsession with restoring a tapestry depicting a fiery, wild horse he supposedly own by him, while carrying on an equally deadly obsession with a stray horse that appears shortly afterword that bears a striking resemblance to the individual in the cloth. Easily the best of the stories, with a rather impressive mixture of Gothic atmosphere here with it's crumbling castle setting, expansive layouts and decadence littering the entire area, which creates a visually haunting location to use here. As well, the lone action scene, the fire to the adjacent estate, is equally impressive with it's large-scale impact, noteworthy fire stunt and visual dynamics as this is usually the ending to many of these Gothic horrors with the burning-the-house-down finale here placed in the middle section, which is quite innovative, and with both of these segments meshing with her sense of sadism and depravity with humiliation games, orgies and other forms of entertainment overall create a rather impressive entry. William Wilson-Rushing into a church, a distraught man begs the local priest to hear his confession. Starting with his first introduction, he relates the story of a man who is his identical in every way, even sharing the same name as each other, and whenever he tries to entertain himself through his usual sense of depraved fun, his doppelganger appears to ruin it, and by the time it finally grows to a maddening scale, he engages his mysterious twin in a final game of fate. This here is certainly watchable enough as the depravity here is increased with games as the dunking into the rats, surgery on the nude woman and whipping the woman he won in the card game, which creates a rather creepy air when they're all interrupted and dropped with clever rationalizations. There's even a bloody sword-fight to give it some nice action as well. The only real flaw to this one is that the segment tends to meander from the same set-up to the next without any variation, really keeping this one from doing anything entertaining with it's premise. It does grow tiresome to know everything is going to keep repeating, regardless of what's going on, so it looses a little there but is overall quite enjoyable. The Bad Stor(ies): Toby Dammit-Arriving in Italy, a boozing, drugged actor is constantly shuffled around from one personal requested-appearance to the next without delay, causing him to sink deeper into his sense of personal despair. Finally arriving at a gala award show for his honor, he finds the locals gathered there far too much for his sanity to overcome, and when he begins to let his inhibitions loose to their fullest extent, finds himself in a deeper Hell than before. This was overall quite boring as the entire segment plays out as though it's an acid-trip nightmare. Sure, it's overtly weird and generally quite stylish visually, but that doesn't really make it scary. The drive through the deserted streets at night is about the only thing worthwhile here, as it's a lengthy, extended sequence that really gets far more enjoyable over time, though the majority of time taken up by the strange award ceremony rather than being scary really dooms this entry. Not enough for the movie overall, but just slightly. Today's Rating/R: Violence, Nudity and Language
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Fonda's radiant
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    kols
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/9/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Which is the only reason I give this turkey one star. First saw this when it came out, just as Doris Day and Rock Hudson were giving way to Peckinpah, so it seemed like a breath of fresh air and Fonda did carry the first story, which seemed hackneyed even in 1969. The only interesting part of the second story was, well, for an adolescent male, the naked girl tied up on the dissection table. Very racy for the time. Bardot (same episode, different scene) looked awful in a black fright-wig. Would have liked to have seen her stripped and some implied sex, as in the scene with the girl. Otherwise, the plot was just boring, Delon just irritating and Bardot doing a mannish parody of Feminism. As for Fellini, Fellini's Fellini and you should never expect anything else than irrational imagery from him. Except that, like Vadim and Malle, he suffers from the same boring self-absorbance and insufferable self-indulgence that characterized much of that time's European Cine. But, in 1969, it did really impress me. Now-a-days, it makes me thank God for Hawkes and Wayne and the Hustons and the thousands of other Americans who knew how to make real movies. To be blunt, with a few genre exceptions (Ronin), many European film makers seem primarily interested in doing the same thing I was doing while watching the girl on the table. Writing this review now because just saw it again on TCM and was mightily disappointed, except for the girl on the table.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Colorful Poe.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Robert J. Maxwell (rmax304823@yahoo.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/9/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "William Wilson", directed by Louis Malle, with Alain Delon as the titular hero and his own double, is really pretty good. Delon gets to whip the proud Bridget Bardot, which is going a little too far, although heaven knows she deserves a good licking. The tone of the story is suitably elegant and ironic. The men wear carefully tailored generic uniforms with cream-colored jackets. William Wilson is a naughty boy. He deceives people, breaks hearts, cheats at cards. BUT -- he can't seem to get away with any of it because whenever he pulls one of his stunts, a masked figure calling himself William Wilson shows up and exposes him for the fraud he is. Wilson finally kills his Doppelganger and then himself. It's one of my favorite Poe stories because it's different. Most stories of doubles from this period materialize Freud's "id", the savage part of our minds that we try so desperately to suppress. Examples range from Mr. Hyde to Professor Moriarty. Pure evil. But this double represent Freud's "superego," the conscience. Nicely done. The last segment was directed by Federico Fellini with photography by Giuseppe Rotunno and score by Nino Rota. I mention this because these two craftsmen make the story unmistakably Fellini's. I don't think the director could have done it without them. It's based (very loosely) on Poe's "Never Bet The Devil Your Head." Terence Stamp is the internationally famous movie star, Toby Dammit, and arrives in Rome to accept one of those awards like the Palm D'Or or the Oscar. The Rome into which Stamp descends is an hallucinatory vision of hell, beginning with the slightly insane and thoroughly claret-colored airport. What follows is a hilarious parody of an awards ceremony. While a drunken Stamp waits his turn, one after another phony is paraded onto the stage under the blazing lights, striding through studio fog, accompanied by a joyous ruckus. There is a group called The Three Angels From Hell that collectively receive one of these awards. Asked to say a few words, each follows the other and blankly mouths the same appreciation: "I'm very moved by this. All I can say is 'Thank you'." They project the believability of some guy behind the supermarket check-out counter who says, "Have a nice day." I ought to mention, before describing more of the story, that the focus isn't entirely on the awards ceremony. Stamp has to be interviewed on a TV program first, for instance, and -- throughout -- there are all sorts of inexplicable and bizarre goings on. At the interview, a carefully groomed and very beautiful woman steps before the camera and lauds the interviewee. Then she slowly and deliberately drops to her knees, still grinning, puts her nose on the floor and crawls away. Is she deranged? Is the director irretrievably mad? No! It's just her way of taking herself off camera and crawling out of the way so that the interview can get started. Other whimsical events and shots take place, too many to mention. At any rate, Terence Stamp is so liquified at the awards ceremony he can only stagger to the stage. It's been suggested to him that he recite something from Shakespeare, "the most famous poet in the world -- second only to our Dante." But keep it short. Short Shakespeare. We don't want to bore the audience. Stamp's face is a ghastly death mask of agony as he begins some well-known lines from "MacBeth" but he quits, tells the audience and the staff what they can do to themselves, stumbles outside, gets into his Ferrari and speeds away. The story slows down considerably despite the Ferrari's speed and the reckless laughter of the drunken maniac behind its wheel. Stamp finds himself spinning around in empty shabby neighborhoods full of dead ends, with stuffed dummies representing chefs and flocks of sheep scattered about, as in a "Twilight Zone" episode. At the end, he encounters a bridge with a gap in the middle of it. On the other side of the gap is the devil in the guise of a pretty little blond girl. He senses that the devil is challenging him to speed the car across the gap. He should not have accepted the challenge. Roger Vadim's colorful "Metzengerstein" is from a story I haven't read, but the plot can be summed up easily enough. Juliet, in all her noble nubility, falls in love with Romeo but accidentally kills him half-way through, upon which he turns into a horse. Juliet senses his presence in the horse and rides him constantly, finally to their joint destiny. (What is it with women and horses anyway?) The viewer will be surprised to find out that in Medieval France the half-naked girls wore gaudy costumes not unlike those of Las Vegas showgirls. I didn't mind it. I didn't mind Jane Fonda's determined debaucheries either. Except those gang bangs were disgusting. What do those dumb page boys or whatever they are have that I don't have? What puts the ape in apricot? Fonda speaks French in this one. I was able to follow most of it because she speaks with such a marked American accent, as if she'd learned French at Vassar, the same French I learned in high school.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Vadim segment is a mess but worth the look for Fellini's
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    TheLittleSongbird
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    In all honesty, Federico Fellini, whose directing and style I greatly admire, was one of two main attractions to Histoires Extraordinaries in the first place. The other was Edgar Allan Poe. And his segment is the best of the three for me. True, it is more Fellini than Poe with the protagonist like watching 8 1/2 or La Dolce Vita and the dream sequences and the quality of the art direction like 8 1/2 and Juliet of the Spirits, but I love that he adapted a story and put his own style into it. As ever it is beautifully filmed, with a nice score, is superbly directed by Fellini with his sense of nostalgia and themes interesting and boasts a mesmerising performance from Terrence Stamp. Louis Malle's segment is perhaps the most true to Poe's writing. It is straightforward storytelling but chillingly effective at it. It is handsomely filmed also, and Alain Delon as well as good-looking is very convincing. Sadly, the segment directed by Roger Vadim is a mess. It is nice to look at and Jane Fonda is always watchable, but the pace is dull, the direction is all over the place, the story never knows whether it wants to be a drama or a Gothic tale and Peter Fonda is simply wasted. Overall though it is a good and interesting film. And who can go wrong with the great Vincent Price narrating? I cannot see where you can personally. 8/10 Bethany Cox
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Puzzle of dried flowers
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Vincentiu
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/3/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    interesting. for cast, directors, passing of time. for Poe or for remembers from old age. but not more.because this puzzle is dusty, strange and out of charm. Roger Vadim gives a mannerist version of Elisabeth Bathory and form of love with artificial notes - option for Peter Fonda is not inspired idea -, Louis Malle creates an interesting universe , tired after short time, with a blank cold statue as axis, with few cruel ingredients and meeting between Bardot and Delon as heart. Fellini, well, Fellini is Fellini and it is important. because his style, atmosphere of his universe, a Terence Stamp like mask of Mastroiani are just virtues in this case. it is enough ? maybe not. the final impression is about a puzzle of dried flowers.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Malle's Homage to Cocteau's Les Enfants Terribles
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bensonj
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It's interesting that no IMDb commenters seem to have caught Malle's significant homage in "William Wilson." Malle makes Wilson far more sadistic that Poe's character. In the opening school sequence, Poe's Wilson is, to be sure, a leader of the other students: "the ardor, the enthusiasm, and the imperiousness of my disposition, soon rendered me a marked character among my schoolmates, and by slow, but natural gradations, gave me an ascendancy over all not greatly older than myself." Any sadism is, at most, implied: "If there is on earth a supreme and unqualified despotism, it is the despotism of a master mind in boyhood over the less energetic spirits of its companions." In Poe, Wilson does not try to strangle his doppelganger, nor is he expelled from the school. He approaches the other's bed at night, apparently sees his own face on the sleeping boy and "passed silently from the chamber, and left at once, the halls of that old academy, never to enter them again." In Malle's film, Wilson is torturing another student as a snowball fight rages in the background. The doppelganger makes his first appearance by hitting Wilson with a snowball. The snow fight, the torture, the significant hit by a snowball, the expulsion from school are not in Poe's tale. But all these elements ARE in Jean Cocteau's novel LES ENFANTS TERRIBLES. The snowball fight not only is featured in Jean-Pierre Melville's film of the novel, but Cocteau filmed the scene earlier in his own BLOOD OF A POET. The torture is briefly in Melville's film, but described more fully in the novel: "By the spasmodic flaring of the gas lamp he could be seen to be a small boy with his back against the wall, hemmed in by his captives...One of these...was squatting between his legs and twisting his ears...Weeping, he sought to close his eyes, to avert his head. But every time he struggled, his torturer seized a fistful of gray snow and scrubbed his ears with it." As the snow fight continues, Cocteau's iconic character Dargelos throws a snowball that hits another student and puts in motion the events of the novel/film. Dargelos is the same sort of malignant leader of his schoolmates as Malle's young Wilson. The headmaster calls his influence on his classmates unhealthy, and after an outrageous act he is expelled from the school. Even more to the point, Dargelos has a doppelganger in the form of the character Agathe. In Melville's film Dargelos and Agathe are played by same person, and their mysterious resemblance is important to the story. All of these added Cocteau elements are so strong that one assumes that Malle intended viewers to recognize the reference.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An American icon transformed into Sixties Eurotrash
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    LCShackley
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/12/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    There's not much Poe here, except his name. Roger Corman did a better job of sticking to the original stories than this trio of "stellar" directors: Vadim, Malle, and Fellini. In the spirit of the indulgent 60s, these three auteurs twisted Poe into the shape of their own imagination, rewriting and "sexing up" the stories to appeal to the pompous art-house crowd. There are some beautiful locations and striking visuals, to be sure...plus long, long stretches of boredom (Jane Fonda playing with a horse, Terence Stamp driving drunk). The music is also dated and laughable, especially Nino Rota's pop dreck under the Fellini segment. Trivia: be on the lookout for Andreas Voutsinas as a bearded courtier in the Vadim segment. He was Jane Fonda's acting coach, but best-known to American audiences as the creepy Carmen Ghia in Mel Brooks's original "The Producers" (released the same year as this film).
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    If only Toby Dammit was feature-length...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tomgillespie2002
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/9/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Also known as Histoires Extraordinaires, this film combines three short stories by Edgar Allen Poe, and has each segment directed by a different European director. The first, entitled Metzengerstein, is directed by the man that helmed Barbarella, Roger Vadim. It tells the story of a beautiful yet debauched countess Federica (Jane Fonda) who falls in love with her family rival, Baron Wilhelm (Peter Fonda - bit weird, them being real-life brother and sister), who frees her leg from a trap in the woods. After he rejects her, she orders the burning of one of his villages, and the Baron is killed when attempting a rescue of one of his horses. The horse is taken in by Federica, who becomes obsessed with it once she notices its resemblance to the one painted on a damaged tapestry. The second story, William Wilson, is directed by French film-maker Louis Malle. It tells a familiar doppelg&auml;nger story of the wicked William Wilson (Alain Delon) who is also interrupted by his 'better half' who shares his name and his appearance, but none of his evil ways. After winning a card game against Giuseppina (Brigitte Bardot) through repeatedly cheating, his other half exposes him, and the two face a duel. The third, directed by Federico Fellini and entitled Toby Dammit, follows alcoholic Shakesperean actor Toby Dammit (Terence Stamp) who is brought to Rome to star in an adaptation of the story of Christ, re- imagined as a western. Haunted by visions of a blonde girl who has lost her ball, he goes on a drunken ride through Rome in a Ferrari. The biggest problem with this film is the variations of quality in the different episodes. Vadim's opener is a pretty poor effort, with a strange storyline focusing on a woman's obsession with a horse. It seems to be nothing more than an excuse to get Jane Fonda into some skimpy medieval outfits. That is all well and good (it was one of the key reasons why I loved Barbarella!) but it's a silly story and a waste of some beautiful cinematography. Malle's second story is a big improvement, but it is clear that his heart is not really in it. Apparently he agreed to take on the job in order to raise money for Murmur of the Heart, and compromised to make the film more accessible to mainstream audiences. But the eroticism of the card game, and the strange atmosphere that is evident throughout make it an enjoyable 40 minutes. Fellini's final segment is very much the director's own vision. It is so far gone from anything resembling Poe's original vision, it could be easily called Fellini's own. Thematically similar to most of his key works, Terence Stamp's crumbling lead character is the main focus, and his disintegrating sanity is laid out on the screen with a collection of flashing images, bizarre characters, and unconventional camera-work. It is also an attack on celebrity, as the characters that Dammit comes across don't react or flinch at his increasingly strange and unpredictable behaviour. It's a shame that Fellini is restricted to a 40 minute portion of a 2-hour film, as I would have quite happily watched Toby Dammit as a full-length feature. An enjoyable, if unspectacular overall film, with the stories getting notably better as the film goes on. www.the-wrath-of-blog.blogspot.com
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Rejected Night Gallery TV material
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    grandfunkfan
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/2/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Three Poe stories; three directors; three failures. Simply put, this movie is not entertaining. Using Poe's name, and labeling the stories as interpretations by famous directors does not cover the poor performance and overall boring conclusion. The viewer, very possibly a fan of Poe, keeps hoping for something to develop, but it never does. Jane Fonda never removes her clothes. Peter Fonda is a again outperformed by a bird. The beautiful scenery and castles are fantastic. Hells bells ring loud and clear. But the movie never turns into an entertaining event. The Night Gallery TV series had many good stories and many duds. The adaptations of Poe stories in the film Spirits of the Dead would never have been used in the most desperate space-filler needs of television. There are several good film adaptations of Poe stories, but Spirits of the Dead is not worth watching.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
 </reviews>
</filme>
