<filme>
 <id>
  1577
 </id>
 <imdburl>
  http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0049521
 </imdburl>
 <ano>
  1956
 </ano>
 <titulo>
  La mort en ce jardin
 </titulo>
 <rating>
  6.9
 </rating>
 <sinopse>
  Chark, an adventurer comes to small village in the near of a gold digger's camp. He is arrested by the local police, who accuse him of having comitted a bank robbery in a neighoured town. ... &nbsp;&raquo;
 </sinopse>
 <storyline>
  Chark, an adventurer comes to small village in the near of a gold digger's camp. He is arrested by the local police, who accuse him of having comitted a bank robbery in a neighoured town. The police also confiscate the gold mine for the state, due to this the gold diggers start an revolution, but it is beaten. Chark, Father Lizzardi, Castin and his daugher and Djin, a whore to whom castin is in love are fleeing into the jungle. where they start to fight for their lifes.
 </storyline>
 <generos>
  <genero>
   Adventure
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Drama
  </genero>
 </generos>
 <keywords>
  <keyword>
   jungle
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   revolution
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   shootout
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   coup d'&eacute;tat
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   diamond
  </keyword>
 </keywords>
 <diretores>
  <diretor>
   Luis Bu&ntilde;uel
  </diretor>
 </diretores>
 <escritores>
  <escritor>
   Luis Alcoriza
  </escritor>
  <escritor>
   Luis Bu&ntilde;uel
  </escritor>
 </escritores>
 <atores>
  <ator>
   Simone Signoret
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Georges Marchal
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Charles Vanel
  </ator>
 </atores>
 <reviews>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Rather ordinary.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    planktonrules
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/12/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This film is a surprise for those expecting one of the strange and surreal sort of movies that the director (Luis Bu&ntilde;uel) was known for making during the 1960s. Instead, it's a very direct sort of thing. And, while one of the main characters is a priest, no sort of anticlerical sort of subtext is apparently intended (again, unusual for one of Bu&ntilde;uel's films). The film is set in some sort of repressive South American country. The local miners are all resentful of the local military that pushes them around and there is talk of a revolution. The priest urges them not to fight, as he thinks they'll be crushed--which is exactly what happens. Then he and a group of motley folks set off into the jungle to escape the carnage. Unfortunately, things aren't much better in the jungle, as hunger, torrential rain and madness are their constant companions. Seeing how wet and dirty the actors are during the jungle scenes makes you feel a bit sorry for them. You also might feel sorry for the folks wanting a surreal film or who expect brilliance because of the film's director. Now I am NOT saying the film wasn't well made, but it could have been made by just about any director. And, while the jungle scenes were good, the beginning is pretty dull and the ending a bit anticlimactic. Not a bad film but certainly not a film for the novice to Bu&ntilde;uel's films--more for the seasoned fans who want to see all of his work.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Brutal and Unpleasant
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    (reader4)
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/10/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Rarely have I been so disappointed in a film. Bunuel *and* Simon Signoret? What could be better? I have seen many of Luis Bunuel's movies, and consider myself a fan. From his first, Un Chien Andalou (1929), to his last, That Obscure Object of Desire (1977), I have seen more than half the films he ever made. Death in the Garden is undoubtedly the worst I have seen. There are three words for this movie: Violent. Pointless. Boring. There is virtually no surrealism in the film whatsoever. And absolutely none of Bunuel's unique humor. It consists mainly of two things: people getting shot, and people walking (or running) around. The film is incredibly violent. The vast majority of the action is people being shot. It is not gory by the standards of the twenty-first century, but it sure is for the fifties, perhaps more so than any movie up to its time. There are two good things about the film. First, and to my surprise, it is shot in absolutely gorgeous Technicolor. The scenery is breathtaking, and Edward Fitzgerald's sets are also quite eye-catching. Second, Simone Signoret has never looked more beautiful. Nor more sexy. I found it interesting that somehow they managed to make her look vaguely South American, although I couldn't put my finger on exactly how. Sad to say, her outer beauty is nullified by her inner personality. She is a monster. She is motivated solely by greed, completely devoid of any human qualities such as warmth or compassion. She doesn't care about anyone else, nor anything except her own advancement and security. The only thing I really liked was the interview with Victor Fuentes on the DVD. He is extremely articulate, and his viewpoint is continually interesting. He mentioned The Wages Of Fear (1953), which I immediately thought of as soon as the movie started. However, to compare Death in the Garden with Cluzot's movie in any respect except the setting is an insult to the latter. If it had not had Simone Signoret in it, I would have turned it off after the first ten minutes. As it was, I watched it till the end, but I am not particularly glad I did so. Want to see a great Bunuel film from his Mexican period? Watch The Exterminating Angel (1962). Want to see a great Simone Signoret movie, where she's every bit as beautiful and almost as sexy as this one? Catch Les Diaboliques (1955). I can't think of any reason for even hard core fans of Bunuel or Signoret to watch this one.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    First time I have heard a priest referred to as a "bible thumper."
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    lastliberal
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/2/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It's only now that we are able to enjoy many of the films Luis Bu&ntilde;uel made during his time in Mexico. Sure, it won't rank with his classics like Le Charme discret de la bourgeoisie or Cet obscur objet du d&eacute;sir, but this South American action thriller has a charm all it's own, Make no mistake, La mort en ce jardin, also has pure Bu&ntilde;uel elements to it, especially in the third act. Shark (Georges Marchal) and Djin (Simone Signoret) are certainly the most interesting characters in the first act. Shark may be a lout (Shut up Bible thumper!), but his skills come into play later. Djin is just hot. Great action in the jungle and a beautiful setting in Mexico.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    don't listen to the guy who said this is mediocre
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    chrisdfilm
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/11/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Bunuel doing an adventure movie is fine in my book. Why do people have to be such snobs when it comes to pigeonholing directors? Some of the films Bunuel made during this period, he may have been personally disappointed because he might have rather been making pix with subject matter more of his choosing. Nevertheless the things that Bunuel brings to this movie - the subtle deadpan humor throughout, the irreverent politics, the surreal touches (especially in the last third of the film when our fugitive protagonists are in the jungle) -- make this a gem. Plus Georges Marchal, Charles Vanel and Michel Piccoli are stupendous. And Signoret is in a class by herself. Not only was she one of the most stunningly gorgeous and sexy actresses in movies anywhere in the world in the 1950s, she was also a great actress and perfect here as the unrepentant, mercenary whore who falls in love. The last jungle sequence has some of the most beautifully surreal images in any film from the decade. The new DVD is highly recommended. A really perfect balance of elements.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Now on DVD in Region 1
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    zetes
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/11/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Underseen Bunuel movie starring Simone Signoret and Michel Piccoli, among others. These two, playing a prostitute and a priest respectively, are joined by Charles Vanel, Georges Marchal and Michele Girardon as a group of people in South America trying to escape an oppressive government. Marchal and Vanel, both diamond miners, are two men taken as revolutionaries by those in charge. The first half of the movie is about their getting into trouble, and their attempt to find a way out of the country. The second, and more interesting half takes place in the jungle, where the group gets stranded during their escape attempt. Many of Bunuel's pet themes come up, and there's a lot of his signature visual trademarks. The most potent image is that of a python Marchal kills with a machete, thrown down to the ground while they try to start the fire. Piccoli looks over at it and its corpse is writhing with fire ants. It's a pretty good story, very gripping in its latter half. It may not rank alongside Bunuel's best, but it's certainly a worthy film in his canon.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    DEATH IN THE GARDEN (Luis Bunuel, 1956) ***
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    MARIO GAUCI (marrod@melita.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/7/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This rarely seen Franco-Mexican 'potboiler' is perhaps most significant today for being the first of seven collaborations between Spanish director Luis Bunuel and genial French character actor Michel Piccoli  who would practically become an adopted son to the surrealist master's. Although I am aware of at least one late-night Italian TV screening in the early 1990s, I finally got acquainted with it via the priceless Bunuel retrospective I attended eighteen months ago at London's National Film Theater; thankfully, I came across the film again recently on DivX and, in spite of the uncharacteristically slangy American subtitles  which were difficult to make out (despite being unusually large) whenever popping up against a white background  I now gladly revisited it to mark the 25th anniversary of Bunuel's death. The film deals with the escape journey (up the river on a corrupt trader's barge bound for Brazil) of a band of misfits from a South American revolution triggered by the Fascist state's retrieval of the rights of any enterprising miner (read down-and-out bums and renegade adventurers) to hunt for diamonds (one of the film's various international monikers was, in fact, THE DIAMOND HUNTERS  which is how it is listed in the 1996 Leonard Maltin guide I own); incidentally, the country-in-turmoil setting anticipates Bunuel's next French movie, LA FIEVRE MONTE A EL PAO aka REPUBLIC OF SIN (1959). After a fairly plot-heavy first half which serves to introduce the major characters and, uncharacteristically for Bunuel, gives rise to some well-staged action sequences, the film really starts to hum when the disparate party of six (four men and two women) embark on their riverside trek through the deadly Amazon jungle (the "garden" of the title). Incidentally, the movie is said to have been a hefty 145 minutes long in Mexico, while being reduced to 107 elsewhere  echoing the fate of the not-too-dissimilar THE WAGES OF FEAR (1953), with which it shares co-star Charles Vanel! The undeniable highlight comes towards the mid-point with an extraordinary succession of shots which are distinctly Bunuelian: having finally managed to kill and skin a snake, the famished travelers are unable to light a fire to cook it on so the priest (Piccoli) quietly takes out a Bible from his sack and, just as he is tearing a leaf from it, the flame is ignited; however, their elation is short-lived since their reptilian dinner has seemingly sprung back to life while being ravaged by a multitude of ants (an unforgettable image that harks back to Bunuel's life-long love of insects); in the resulting delirium from hunger, a photo of the Arch of Triumph held dearly by Charles Vanel (as it reminded him of his dream of owning a Parisian restaurant) is startlingly accompanied by the cacophony of its typical nightlife, before being summarily torn to shreds and thrown away  an act which later alerts the unfortunate bunch that they have been going around in circles! To top it all, we also have Piccoli's feverish monologue about soft-boiled eggs which, like one of the characters from Bunuel's later masterpiece THE DISCREET CHARM OF THE BOURGEOISIE (1972), he feels compelled to impart to his fellow companions. In spite of his unsubtle name, Fr. Lizardi is easily the most fascinating character in the film  piously advocating submission to the state and yet confronted by both lust and greed when left to his own devices. Ironically enough, what finally saves the group (albeit temporarily) is the fact that 50 poor souls had to die in a plane crash, a site which they stumble upon in the middle of the forbidding jungle! Georges Marchal (in the second of four films he made with Bunuel) plays an adventurer named Shark who is hilariously introduced by giving the index finger salute to the soldiers holding the miners at bay; arrested by the latter, they step inside a Church to pray but at the same time don't hesitate to beat their prisoner into a kneeling position, after which he is stroked by Vanel's lovely deaf-mute daughter whom he had previously mistreated himself (played by Michele Girardon who, despite having no previous acting background, would eventually land a key role amidst another ensemble cast in Howard Hawks' exhilarating HATARI! [1962]though, sadly, her life ended in suicide at age 36). Simone Signoret plays Djin  another alternate name for this film was the bland GINA(!)  the locale's most popular whore whom Vanel seeks to marry, Piccoli is caught 'with' her by the townsfolk and Marchal loses no opportunity to beat up (in spite of her declared love for him); perhaps this was Bunuel's way of punishing Signoret who, reportedly, proved quite temperamental on the set! In any case, it was a nicely ironic and surreal touch to have her impeccably dressed in evening gown and jewelry (pilfered from the plane crash victims, of course) right before being shot dead by a demented Vanel. Ultimately, this must surely be one of Bunuel's most accessible films and arguably his most enjoyable genre effort which, as was his custom, the director infuses with personal touches that greatly enhance both the fun factor and thematic value of what could have easily been just another throwaway jungle adventure. Judiciously, Paul Misraki's beautiful acoustic score is only utilized for the start and end credits since the jungle segment is evocatively (yet eerily) accompanied by the sounds of wildlife.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Great, Unknown Bunuel
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bensonj
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/9/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I had seen nearly all of Bunuel's films, including his early "commercial" Mexican ones, but had actually never heard of this one before seeing it. This is really an extraordinary film! The great cast is just the beginning. It starts much like an "A" Western, with lines drawn between diamond miners and corrupt Mexican officials. Leading archetypical characters are introduced in a classic manner: the arrogant lone stranger with a distinctive cowboy hat; the old prospector who just wants to build a nest-egg so he can open a restaurant in Paris; his deaf-mute daughter; the cynical gal who does well by doing the best she can; and the naive priest. This last is, of course, a very Bunuelian character; his every good deed backfires on him, and his proselytizing is financed by big companies who find Christianized natives a cheap source of labor. The events have a classic cast and are filmed with great, stylish skill and action-film panache. But classic Bunuelian touches abound. An example: the soldiers who arrest the stranger on a trumped-up charge stop off at the church to pray, and brutally kick him to a kneeling position. The deaf-mute girl, who he had previously treated cruelly, happens to be kneeling next to him and strokes his face in compassion. When a street battle goes badly, the lead characters all seek escape on a small steamer going up-river, and when a faster patrol boat catches up to them, they take off in the jungle on foot. At this point they quickly become lost. The pace perceptibly slows, and it becomes a film of another sort entirely. Finally, in a Bunuelian ironic ending, death comes to this strange garden. The kicker of the ending (which must have seemed much stronger in 1956) must have been in the original novel and is probably what attracted Bunuel to the story. The final scenes put one in mind of Herzog's later AGUIRRE; in fact, the whole second half of this film follows a path similar to AGUIRRE. I am amazed that I can find no reference or commentary on this film in print, other than in checklists of Bunuel's work. I can only assume the film is caught in the classic Catch 22 of being unavailable because it is unknown and unknown because it is unavailable. It should be considered a major film in Bunuel's oeuvre! The comments of aw-komon-2, dbdumontiel, and UndeadMaster on this site are all right on the mark. This is definitely a film that cries for rerelease and reevaluation.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Don't believe the negativity, One of Bu&ntilde;uel's best.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Undead_Master
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/10/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is an astounding movie, and it's also one of Bunuel's most accessible films... The only problem I can find with this movie is that there are no good DVD copy's as far as i know. In the copy I watched, the subs were nearly unreadable in spots and the film had faded badly. Even with those problems, it's clear that this is one of his best movies. Maybe not in his top 5, but certainly in the top 8. Death in the garden is action packed. There's almost too much social commentary to call it a simple action film, but in every other way, that's what it is. This is a movie packed with emotional violence, physical violence, lurid sexuality (for the time)... Blood sweat tears and constant tension.. I think this may be the only Bu&ntilde;uel film with a protracted massive gun battle, and it's shot expertly. That scene alone proves without a doubt that Bu&ntilde;uel could have went to Hollywood and made big budget commercial films if he had wanted too. His command of cinematic technique would have put him right up there with the best of them, no matter what kind of movie he was working on. But don't get the wrong idea, this is still a Bunuel film in every way. It's full of social commentary, it has touches of surrealism, his shooting style is just as awesome as it's always been and the script is as sharp as a knife. This film has some of Bunuel's best characters ever. Sometimes the people in his movies serve as symbols for certain classes of people... Archetypal personalities... The characters from "Death in the garden" are molded to fit into certain category's, but they are more complex and multidimensional than usual. The moral Quandaries they face are difficult and the choices they make are always interesting. He's still examining the whole human race through the lens of a few characters, but his examination is more even handed than usual, and the characters are VERY memorable. In the end though, I would say this movie has a very pessimistic view of humanity. It's a movie full of meanness, savagery, and betrayal. Even the more likable characters are portrayed as mostly useless because of their lack of initiative. The second half of this film brings to mind the disintegration into animal behavior that you see in "The Exterminating Angel"... I could probably write for hours... Just suffice to say that this is one of his better works and it should be viewed more often... Hopefully someone like criterion will release this soon. It deserves to be re-discovered.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The two jungles.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    dbdumonteil
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/2/2002
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    CONTAINS SPOILERS .CONTAINS SPOILERS;CONTAINS SPOILERS At first sight,"la Mort en Ce Jardin" looks like an adventure yarn for the whole family,but I hope the grown-ups are old enough to know better;it's for sure a very accessible work,when compared to former ones (un chien andalou,los hurdes,el)but do not believe the great Spanish director has lost his bite:even when he filmed "Robinson Crusoe" (another "family movie"?),Bunuel's obsessions surfaced. What puzzles the spectator is the big budget:scope,colors(and the cinematography in the second part is absolutely enthralling),big French stars (Simone Signoret and Charles Vanel ,fresh from Clouzot's "les diaboliques",George Marshall,and also Michel Piccoli who ,though by no means at the beginning of his career,was not very known yet),and a score by Paul Miraski,one of Edith Piaf's favorite composers. There are two jungles:the first one is Man Jungle.Its predators are the military men,its bitter fruit is religion.As the colonels humiliate,forbid,imprison,torture and kill,the priests-here represented by father Lizzardi(Piccoli)-urge the population to resign themselves to it.This priest character is very important,because he is the rough draft of what will be completely fulfilled two years later in "Nazarin"-"La Mort en Ce Jardin" will seem more relevant if you know the 1958 film-You've got to see Piccoli,bringing religious consolation to the prisoners in their dungeon:The raider Chark (Marshall ),who is practical-minded -and who's thus akin to "Viridiana"'s cousin in the 1961 masterwork- will pretend he take the priest's holy writ seriously,only in order to escape.But the best scene in which Bunuel shows his true face is the one in the church.Chark, prisoner led by the soldiers ,walks across a church where Lizzardi is celebrating mass:with his gun,one of the soldiers forces him to kneel down.Later another character will tell the priest that everywhere he and his religious mates come,begins the exploiters'reign. This first part has often be criticized,because they say it moves too slow,but it's necessary to make acquaintance with the main characters ,who will leave the first jungle for the second one:outside Lizzardi and Chark,we have an old man( Vanel),who's forced to escape because the army thinks he is an agitator,his mute daughter,and a prostitute Djinn (Signoret,at her bitchiest). The second part has been praised quite rightly so.Bunuel succeeded in creating a stifling atmosphere full of animal noises -the music is totally absent here and will come back only for the last shots-.The astounding cinematography enhances a green hell garden and these who thinks Bunuel completely jettisoned his surrealistic art should have a second look at it:because it is HERE,even if it's fleetingly.I will take four examples:the first one is the Paris postcard:for a very short while,we do believe the fugitives are back in their dear country;the second one is the snake eaten by ants (seen through the priest's eyes).There's more to the picture than meets the eye:the plane which had crashed in the jungle and which will save some of the characters acquires a surrealistic dimension."God has saved us!" the priest tells.But the raider is not fooled:"it took fifty people's lives (the plane passengers) to save us!".But the most extraordinary picture is Signoret,in the jungle,wearing an evening gown,complete with bright jewels,she's found in the plane.Here again,the priest will be completely helpless,his bible can only be used to light a fire (always Bunuel's practical mind).And Bunuel's religious disgust reaches a climax when the old man goes crazy and yells that God has cursed them . That work ,generally regarded as a minor Bunuel work,is actually extremely intriguing.Although it has not the strength of such works as the ones I mention above ,it includes almost all his recurrent features.Adapted from a Jos&eacute; Andr&eacute; Lacour novel,dialogue by Raymond Queneau,who wrote "Zazie dans le m&eacute;tro",which Louis Malle transferred to the screen in 1960.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    mediocre adventure w/o vision
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    rogierr
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/9/2001
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Acted fairly well, quite entertaining too, this movie however is a disappointment for everyone who expects Bu&ntilde;uel's uncompromising vision. His eye for detail and appropriate camera-movements cannot compensate cinematographer Jorge Stahl's goof-ups and the pointless story, unfortunately. Besides the fact that this was the last Bu&ntilde;uel-movie that I could rent from my local video store and that it was Bu&ntilde;uel's first collaboration with the great Michel Piccoli (also: Voie lact&eacute;e, Fant&ocirc;me de la libert&eacute;, etc.) were attractive things about this movie for me. 'Jungle Attack' is the title under which it is for rent in the Netherlands: in case you were wondering whether this is really a Bu&ntilde;uel-movie or not ... that's how much Bu&ntilde;uel is in here. Finally, Piccoli (la Grande bouffe, 1973) and Signoret (les Diaboliques, 1955) don't come forward with really intriguing performances, but stay in the mediocrity of the adventurous and light story. I do not regret seeing it though. Enough allright. 6/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Rather ordinary.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    planktonrules
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/12/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This film is a surprise for those expecting one of the strange and surreal sort of movies that the director (Luis Bu&ntilde;uel) was known for making during the 1960s. Instead, it's a very direct sort of thing. And, while one of the main characters is a priest, no sort of anticlerical sort of subtext is apparently intended (again, unusual for one of Bu&ntilde;uel's films). The film is set in some sort of repressive South American country. The local miners are all resentful of the local military that pushes them around and there is talk of a revolution. The priest urges them not to fight, as he thinks they'll be crushed--which is exactly what happens. Then he and a group of motley folks set off into the jungle to escape the carnage. Unfortunately, things aren't much better in the jungle, as hunger, torrential rain and madness are their constant companions. Seeing how wet and dirty the actors are during the jungle scenes makes you feel a bit sorry for them. You also might feel sorry for the folks wanting a surreal film or who expect brilliance because of the film's director. Now I am NOT saying the film wasn't well made, but it could have been made by just about any director. And, while the jungle scenes were good, the beginning is pretty dull and the ending a bit anticlimactic. Not a bad film but certainly not a film for the novice to Bu&ntilde;uel's films--more for the seasoned fans who want to see all of his work.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Brutal and Unpleasant
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    (reader4)
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/10/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Rarely have I been so disappointed in a film. Bunuel *and* Simon Signoret? What could be better? I have seen many of Luis Bunuel's movies, and consider myself a fan. From his first, Un Chien Andalou (1929), to his last, That Obscure Object of Desire (1977), I have seen more than half the films he ever made. Death in the Garden is undoubtedly the worst I have seen. There are three words for this movie: Violent. Pointless. Boring. There is virtually no surrealism in the film whatsoever. And absolutely none of Bunuel's unique humor. It consists mainly of two things: people getting shot, and people walking (or running) around. The film is incredibly violent. The vast majority of the action is people being shot. It is not gory by the standards of the twenty-first century, but it sure is for the fifties, perhaps more so than any movie up to its time. There are two good things about the film. First, and to my surprise, it is shot in absolutely gorgeous Technicolor. The scenery is breathtaking, and Edward Fitzgerald's sets are also quite eye-catching. Second, Simone Signoret has never looked more beautiful. Nor more sexy. I found it interesting that somehow they managed to make her look vaguely South American, although I couldn't put my finger on exactly how. Sad to say, her outer beauty is nullified by her inner personality. She is a monster. She is motivated solely by greed, completely devoid of any human qualities such as warmth or compassion. She doesn't care about anyone else, nor anything except her own advancement and security. The only thing I really liked was the interview with Victor Fuentes on the DVD. He is extremely articulate, and his viewpoint is continually interesting. He mentioned The Wages Of Fear (1953), which I immediately thought of as soon as the movie started. However, to compare Death in the Garden with Cluzot's movie in any respect except the setting is an insult to the latter. If it had not had Simone Signoret in it, I would have turned it off after the first ten minutes. As it was, I watched it till the end, but I am not particularly glad I did so. Want to see a great Bunuel film from his Mexican period? Watch The Exterminating Angel (1962). Want to see a great Simone Signoret movie, where she's every bit as beautiful and almost as sexy as this one? Catch Les Diaboliques (1955). I can't think of any reason for even hard core fans of Bunuel or Signoret to watch this one.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    First time I have heard a priest referred to as a "bible thumper."
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    lastliberal
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/2/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It's only now that we are able to enjoy many of the films Luis Bu&ntilde;uel made during his time in Mexico. Sure, it won't rank with his classics like Le Charme discret de la bourgeoisie or Cet obscur objet du d&eacute;sir, but this South American action thriller has a charm all it's own, Make no mistake, La mort en ce jardin, also has pure Bu&ntilde;uel elements to it, especially in the third act. Shark (Georges Marchal) and Djin (Simone Signoret) are certainly the most interesting characters in the first act. Shark may be a lout (Shut up Bible thumper!), but his skills come into play later. Djin is just hot. Great action in the jungle and a beautiful setting in Mexico.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    don't listen to the guy who said this is mediocre
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    chrisdfilm
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/11/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Bunuel doing an adventure movie is fine in my book. Why do people have to be such snobs when it comes to pigeonholing directors? Some of the films Bunuel made during this period, he may have been personally disappointed because he might have rather been making pix with subject matter more of his choosing. Nevertheless the things that Bunuel brings to this movie - the subtle deadpan humor throughout, the irreverent politics, the surreal touches (especially in the last third of the film when our fugitive protagonists are in the jungle) -- make this a gem. Plus Georges Marchal, Charles Vanel and Michel Piccoli are stupendous. And Signoret is in a class by herself. Not only was she one of the most stunningly gorgeous and sexy actresses in movies anywhere in the world in the 1950s, she was also a great actress and perfect here as the unrepentant, mercenary whore who falls in love. The last jungle sequence has some of the most beautifully surreal images in any film from the decade. The new DVD is highly recommended. A really perfect balance of elements.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Now on DVD in Region 1
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    zetes
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/11/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Underseen Bunuel movie starring Simone Signoret and Michel Piccoli, among others. These two, playing a prostitute and a priest respectively, are joined by Charles Vanel, Georges Marchal and Michele Girardon as a group of people in South America trying to escape an oppressive government. Marchal and Vanel, both diamond miners, are two men taken as revolutionaries by those in charge. The first half of the movie is about their getting into trouble, and their attempt to find a way out of the country. The second, and more interesting half takes place in the jungle, where the group gets stranded during their escape attempt. Many of Bunuel's pet themes come up, and there's a lot of his signature visual trademarks. The most potent image is that of a python Marchal kills with a machete, thrown down to the ground while they try to start the fire. Piccoli looks over at it and its corpse is writhing with fire ants. It's a pretty good story, very gripping in its latter half. It may not rank alongside Bunuel's best, but it's certainly a worthy film in his canon.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    DEATH IN THE GARDEN (Luis Bunuel, 1956) ***
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    MARIO GAUCI (marrod@melita.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/7/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This rarely seen Franco-Mexican 'potboiler' is perhaps most significant today for being the first of seven collaborations between Spanish director Luis Bunuel and genial French character actor Michel Piccoli  who would practically become an adopted son to the surrealist master's. Although I am aware of at least one late-night Italian TV screening in the early 1990s, I finally got acquainted with it via the priceless Bunuel retrospective I attended eighteen months ago at London's National Film Theater; thankfully, I came across the film again recently on DivX and, in spite of the uncharacteristically slangy American subtitles  which were difficult to make out (despite being unusually large) whenever popping up against a white background  I now gladly revisited it to mark the 25th anniversary of Bunuel's death. The film deals with the escape journey (up the river on a corrupt trader's barge bound for Brazil) of a band of misfits from a South American revolution triggered by the Fascist state's retrieval of the rights of any enterprising miner (read down-and-out bums and renegade adventurers) to hunt for diamonds (one of the film's various international monikers was, in fact, THE DIAMOND HUNTERS  which is how it is listed in the 1996 Leonard Maltin guide I own); incidentally, the country-in-turmoil setting anticipates Bunuel's next French movie, LA FIEVRE MONTE A EL PAO aka REPUBLIC OF SIN (1959). After a fairly plot-heavy first half which serves to introduce the major characters and, uncharacteristically for Bunuel, gives rise to some well-staged action sequences, the film really starts to hum when the disparate party of six (four men and two women) embark on their riverside trek through the deadly Amazon jungle (the "garden" of the title). Incidentally, the movie is said to have been a hefty 145 minutes long in Mexico, while being reduced to 107 elsewhere  echoing the fate of the not-too-dissimilar THE WAGES OF FEAR (1953), with which it shares co-star Charles Vanel! The undeniable highlight comes towards the mid-point with an extraordinary succession of shots which are distinctly Bunuelian: having finally managed to kill and skin a snake, the famished travelers are unable to light a fire to cook it on so the priest (Piccoli) quietly takes out a Bible from his sack and, just as he is tearing a leaf from it, the flame is ignited; however, their elation is short-lived since their reptilian dinner has seemingly sprung back to life while being ravaged by a multitude of ants (an unforgettable image that harks back to Bunuel's life-long love of insects); in the resulting delirium from hunger, a photo of the Arch of Triumph held dearly by Charles Vanel (as it reminded him of his dream of owning a Parisian restaurant) is startlingly accompanied by the cacophony of its typical nightlife, before being summarily torn to shreds and thrown away  an act which later alerts the unfortunate bunch that they have been going around in circles! To top it all, we also have Piccoli's feverish monologue about soft-boiled eggs which, like one of the characters from Bunuel's later masterpiece THE DISCREET CHARM OF THE BOURGEOISIE (1972), he feels compelled to impart to his fellow companions. In spite of his unsubtle name, Fr. Lizardi is easily the most fascinating character in the film  piously advocating submission to the state and yet confronted by both lust and greed when left to his own devices. Ironically enough, what finally saves the group (albeit temporarily) is the fact that 50 poor souls had to die in a plane crash, a site which they stumble upon in the middle of the forbidding jungle! Georges Marchal (in the second of four films he made with Bunuel) plays an adventurer named Shark who is hilariously introduced by giving the index finger salute to the soldiers holding the miners at bay; arrested by the latter, they step inside a Church to pray but at the same time don't hesitate to beat their prisoner into a kneeling position, after which he is stroked by Vanel's lovely deaf-mute daughter whom he had previously mistreated himself (played by Michele Girardon who, despite having no previous acting background, would eventually land a key role amidst another ensemble cast in Howard Hawks' exhilarating HATARI! [1962]though, sadly, her life ended in suicide at age 36). Simone Signoret plays Djin  another alternate name for this film was the bland GINA(!)  the locale's most popular whore whom Vanel seeks to marry, Piccoli is caught 'with' her by the townsfolk and Marchal loses no opportunity to beat up (in spite of her declared love for him); perhaps this was Bunuel's way of punishing Signoret who, reportedly, proved quite temperamental on the set! In any case, it was a nicely ironic and surreal touch to have her impeccably dressed in evening gown and jewelry (pilfered from the plane crash victims, of course) right before being shot dead by a demented Vanel. Ultimately, this must surely be one of Bunuel's most accessible films and arguably his most enjoyable genre effort which, as was his custom, the director infuses with personal touches that greatly enhance both the fun factor and thematic value of what could have easily been just another throwaway jungle adventure. Judiciously, Paul Misraki's beautiful acoustic score is only utilized for the start and end credits since the jungle segment is evocatively (yet eerily) accompanied by the sounds of wildlife.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Great, Unknown Bunuel
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bensonj
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/9/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I had seen nearly all of Bunuel's films, including his early "commercial" Mexican ones, but had actually never heard of this one before seeing it. This is really an extraordinary film! The great cast is just the beginning. It starts much like an "A" Western, with lines drawn between diamond miners and corrupt Mexican officials. Leading archetypical characters are introduced in a classic manner: the arrogant lone stranger with a distinctive cowboy hat; the old prospector who just wants to build a nest-egg so he can open a restaurant in Paris; his deaf-mute daughter; the cynical gal who does well by doing the best she can; and the naive priest. This last is, of course, a very Bunuelian character; his every good deed backfires on him, and his proselytizing is financed by big companies who find Christianized natives a cheap source of labor. The events have a classic cast and are filmed with great, stylish skill and action-film panache. But classic Bunuelian touches abound. An example: the soldiers who arrest the stranger on a trumped-up charge stop off at the church to pray, and brutally kick him to a kneeling position. The deaf-mute girl, who he had previously treated cruelly, happens to be kneeling next to him and strokes his face in compassion. When a street battle goes badly, the lead characters all seek escape on a small steamer going up-river, and when a faster patrol boat catches up to them, they take off in the jungle on foot. At this point they quickly become lost. The pace perceptibly slows, and it becomes a film of another sort entirely. Finally, in a Bunuelian ironic ending, death comes to this strange garden. The kicker of the ending (which must have seemed much stronger in 1956) must have been in the original novel and is probably what attracted Bunuel to the story. The final scenes put one in mind of Herzog's later AGUIRRE; in fact, the whole second half of this film follows a path similar to AGUIRRE. I am amazed that I can find no reference or commentary on this film in print, other than in checklists of Bunuel's work. I can only assume the film is caught in the classic Catch 22 of being unavailable because it is unknown and unknown because it is unavailable. It should be considered a major film in Bunuel's oeuvre! The comments of aw-komon-2, dbdumontiel, and UndeadMaster on this site are all right on the mark. This is definitely a film that cries for rerelease and reevaluation.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Don't believe the negativity, One of Bu&ntilde;uel's best.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Undead_Master
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/10/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is an astounding movie, and it's also one of Bunuel's most accessible films... The only problem I can find with this movie is that there are no good DVD copy's as far as i know. In the copy I watched, the subs were nearly unreadable in spots and the film had faded badly. Even with those problems, it's clear that this is one of his best movies. Maybe not in his top 5, but certainly in the top 8. Death in the garden is action packed. There's almost too much social commentary to call it a simple action film, but in every other way, that's what it is. This is a movie packed with emotional violence, physical violence, lurid sexuality (for the time)... Blood sweat tears and constant tension.. I think this may be the only Bu&ntilde;uel film with a protracted massive gun battle, and it's shot expertly. That scene alone proves without a doubt that Bu&ntilde;uel could have went to Hollywood and made big budget commercial films if he had wanted too. His command of cinematic technique would have put him right up there with the best of them, no matter what kind of movie he was working on. But don't get the wrong idea, this is still a Bunuel film in every way. It's full of social commentary, it has touches of surrealism, his shooting style is just as awesome as it's always been and the script is as sharp as a knife. This film has some of Bunuel's best characters ever. Sometimes the people in his movies serve as symbols for certain classes of people... Archetypal personalities... The characters from "Death in the garden" are molded to fit into certain category's, but they are more complex and multidimensional than usual. The moral Quandaries they face are difficult and the choices they make are always interesting. He's still examining the whole human race through the lens of a few characters, but his examination is more even handed than usual, and the characters are VERY memorable. In the end though, I would say this movie has a very pessimistic view of humanity. It's a movie full of meanness, savagery, and betrayal. Even the more likable characters are portrayed as mostly useless because of their lack of initiative. The second half of this film brings to mind the disintegration into animal behavior that you see in "The Exterminating Angel"... I could probably write for hours... Just suffice to say that this is one of his better works and it should be viewed more often... Hopefully someone like criterion will release this soon. It deserves to be re-discovered.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The two jungles.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    dbdumonteil
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/2/2002
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    CONTAINS SPOILERS .CONTAINS SPOILERS;CONTAINS SPOILERS At first sight,"la Mort en Ce Jardin" looks like an adventure yarn for the whole family,but I hope the grown-ups are old enough to know better;it's for sure a very accessible work,when compared to former ones (un chien andalou,los hurdes,el)but do not believe the great Spanish director has lost his bite:even when he filmed "Robinson Crusoe" (another "family movie"?),Bunuel's obsessions surfaced. What puzzles the spectator is the big budget:scope,colors(and the cinematography in the second part is absolutely enthralling),big French stars (Simone Signoret and Charles Vanel ,fresh from Clouzot's "les diaboliques",George Marshall,and also Michel Piccoli who ,though by no means at the beginning of his career,was not very known yet),and a score by Paul Miraski,one of Edith Piaf's favorite composers. There are two jungles:the first one is Man Jungle.Its predators are the military men,its bitter fruit is religion.As the colonels humiliate,forbid,imprison,torture and kill,the priests-here represented by father Lizzardi(Piccoli)-urge the population to resign themselves to it.This priest character is very important,because he is the rough draft of what will be completely fulfilled two years later in "Nazarin"-"La Mort en Ce Jardin" will seem more relevant if you know the 1958 film-You've got to see Piccoli,bringing religious consolation to the prisoners in their dungeon:The raider Chark (Marshall ),who is practical-minded -and who's thus akin to "Viridiana"'s cousin in the 1961 masterwork- will pretend he take the priest's holy writ seriously,only in order to escape.But the best scene in which Bunuel shows his true face is the one in the church.Chark, prisoner led by the soldiers ,walks across a church where Lizzardi is celebrating mass:with his gun,one of the soldiers forces him to kneel down.Later another character will tell the priest that everywhere he and his religious mates come,begins the exploiters'reign. This first part has often be criticized,because they say it moves too slow,but it's necessary to make acquaintance with the main characters ,who will leave the first jungle for the second one:outside Lizzardi and Chark,we have an old man( Vanel),who's forced to escape because the army thinks he is an agitator,his mute daughter,and a prostitute Djinn (Signoret,at her bitchiest). The second part has been praised quite rightly so.Bunuel succeeded in creating a stifling atmosphere full of animal noises -the music is totally absent here and will come back only for the last shots-.The astounding cinematography enhances a green hell garden and these who thinks Bunuel completely jettisoned his surrealistic art should have a second look at it:because it is HERE,even if it's fleetingly.I will take four examples:the first one is the Paris postcard:for a very short while,we do believe the fugitives are back in their dear country;the second one is the snake eaten by ants (seen through the priest's eyes).There's more to the picture than meets the eye:the plane which had crashed in the jungle and which will save some of the characters acquires a surrealistic dimension."God has saved us!" the priest tells.But the raider is not fooled:"it took fifty people's lives (the plane passengers) to save us!".But the most extraordinary picture is Signoret,in the jungle,wearing an evening gown,complete with bright jewels,she's found in the plane.Here again,the priest will be completely helpless,his bible can only be used to light a fire (always Bunuel's practical mind).And Bunuel's religious disgust reaches a climax when the old man goes crazy and yells that God has cursed them . That work ,generally regarded as a minor Bunuel work,is actually extremely intriguing.Although it has not the strength of such works as the ones I mention above ,it includes almost all his recurrent features.Adapted from a Jos&eacute; Andr&eacute; Lacour novel,dialogue by Raymond Queneau,who wrote "Zazie dans le m&eacute;tro",which Louis Malle transferred to the screen in 1960.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    mediocre adventure w/o vision
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    rogierr
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/9/2001
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Acted fairly well, quite entertaining too, this movie however is a disappointment for everyone who expects Bu&ntilde;uel's uncompromising vision. His eye for detail and appropriate camera-movements cannot compensate cinematographer Jorge Stahl's goof-ups and the pointless story, unfortunately. Besides the fact that this was the last Bu&ntilde;uel-movie that I could rent from my local video store and that it was Bu&ntilde;uel's first collaboration with the great Michel Piccoli (also: Voie lact&eacute;e, Fant&ocirc;me de la libert&eacute;, etc.) were attractive things about this movie for me. 'Jungle Attack' is the title under which it is for rent in the Netherlands: in case you were wondering whether this is really a Bu&ntilde;uel-movie or not ... that's how much Bu&ntilde;uel is in here. Finally, Piccoli (la Grande bouffe, 1973) and Signoret (les Diaboliques, 1955) don't come forward with really intriguing performances, but stay in the mediocrity of the adventurous and light story. I do not regret seeing it though. Enough allright. 6/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
 </reviews>
</filme>
