<filme>
 <id>
  1589
 </id>
 <imdburl>
  http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0117561
 </imdburl>
 <ano>
  1996
 </ano>
 <titulo>
  Schizopolis
 </titulo>
 <rating>
  6.9
 </rating>
 <sinopse>
  Fletcher Munson, the lethargic employee of a pseudo-religious self help company, and his doppelganger, the friendly but dull dentist Dr. Jeffrey Korchek.
 </sinopse>
 <storyline>
  Fletcher Munson is a lethargic, passive worker for a Scientology-like self-help corporation called Eventualism. After the death of a colleague, he is promoted to the job of writing speeches for T. Azimuth Schwitters, the founder and head of the group. He uses this as an excuse to be emotionally and romantically distant from his wife, who, he discovers, is having an affair with his doppelganger, a dentist named Dr. Jeffrey Korchek. As Munson fumbles with the speech and Korchek becomes obsessed with a new patient, a psychotic exterminator named Elmo Oxygen goes around the town seducing lonely wives and taking photographs of his genitals.
 </storyline>
 <generos>
  <genero>
   Comedy
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Fantasy
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Mystery
  </genero>
 </generos>
 <keywords>
  <keyword>
   doppelganger
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   dentist
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   eventualism
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   corporation
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   photograph
  </keyword>
 </keywords>
 <diretores>
  <diretor>
   Steven Soderbergh
  </diretor>
 </diretores>
 <escritores>
  <escritor>
   .406 Production
  </escritor>
 </escritores>
 <atores>
  <ator>
   Steven Soderbergh
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Scott Allen
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Betsy Brantley
  </ator>
 </atores>
 <reviews>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not for everyone, and that includes me
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Charles Herold (cherold)
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Schizopolis begins with this very funny speech by Soderbergh, and early on it looks a little like some sketch comedy show from the 70s like Kentucky Fried Movie. And definitely sketch comedy is an element of this. But it's sketch comedy that tries hard to not be too funny. Ideas like a couple exchanging generic greetings are clever but no more than mildly amusing, and I think that's what the movie is going for; it doesn't want comedy to override experimental weirdness. The movie is also careful to avoid feeling too much like it has a linear story. Yes, we do follow characters through a story arc, but this is done in a purposefully disjointed manner. The pieces for something genuinely entertaining are there, but the director clearly wants something that is more challenging than enjoyable. And to certain people, that will make it more enjoyable. But I'm not one of those people. For me, it was a clever but rather tedious experiment.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An interesting and fun experiment
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mike-seaman
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Explaining Schizopolis seems counterintuitive. The movie is a mixture of autobiographical self- examination and self-deprecation. At the same time the film seems to be tackling some larger cultural themes and postmodern concepts of language and communication. In the end, I think the movie is a fun assortment of ideas being exercised together in a rather harmless fashion. Schizopolis never seems to take itself seriously, the movie is made on a small-budget, with a purposefully contained cast, self-aware and referential humor, taking stabs at life, narratives, movies, culture, and humanity while never entirely aiming at any single target (except perhaps the filmmaker himself). I recommend this movie not because it is a fully realized concept (because it isn't) or because it is a hidden gem that must be discovered (because it isn't) but it is refreshing to see an experimental film created playfully, aware of its self-indulgence and entirely at ease with it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Being Steven Soderbergh
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    CinefanR
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/4/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Movies like Lost Highway, American Beauty and other high-profile, big-budget productions have been praised for their original takes, but in fact it was "Schizopolis" that explored those possibilities first. I find it refreshing and inexplicably underrated. The film is a very funny and bizarre look into the creative mind of its author, Steven Soderbergh. Press conferences on horse urination, marital dissolution, dysfunctional families, work, love, death, identity, the hilarious (and tragic) absurdity of life everything is scrutinized here under a mask of randomness which makes everything unpredictable and crazy funny. "Schizopolis" gleefully delves into the absurd and blends it with satire in a most original social commentary, mocking all conventions and confinements. This type of humor is my kind. For fans of Kafka, Eugene Ionesco and Urmuz, Samuel Beckett, Kurt Vonnegut or David Lynch, this will be a blast. On a third viewing, all this "mess" makes perfect sense, and it's beautiful. "Sneeze!"
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Very Disappointing
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Bob_Jenkem
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/8/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I wanted to like "Schizopolis" but ended up ultimately finding it to be a very slow, pretentious, and boring movie. The first forty minutes-or-so are funny, but the second half of the movie is like watching paint dry, and the movie seems to go on much longer than it actually is. While it has a germ of an idea, Soderbergh makes one grave screen writing error around the 50-minute mark (and I'm aware this film was improvised - exactly my point), when he suddenly introduces a new main character (played by the director, who plays both characters) that takes up the rest of the movie, with almost no reference to the previous main character. By the time he shows up again in the last ten minutes, he's speaking Japanese. Why? (I know it's supposed to symbolize that the character and his wife are distant, but it's INCREDIBLY heavy-handed). For that matter, why do characters constantly speak in non-sequitors? No reason is given. Any chance at character development is killed, and the whole movie comes tumbling down. I understand he wanted to be abstract and surrealistic, but the complete lack of storytelling structure as a basis for using abstract surrealism makes the movie boring. The only good parts are the interstitial news bulletins, and there are moments of creative filmmaking in it. But overall, it's a snoozefest. But what a great title. Some funny lines in it too ("What was your last co-worker's name?" "Oh, Nameless Numberhead Man?"). This was the first Steven Soderbergh film I've seen. I won't be rushing out to watch his other movies.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    one of a kind
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mglasson
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/5/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Schizopolis is perhaps best summarized with the copy line - 'All attempts at synopses of this film have resulted in hospitalization.' It's no understatement - just about every convention and niche of film is broken in this flick, and those looking for an easy ride into movie-watching oblivion won't find it here. The film mainly revolves around ad exec Fletcher Munson (played to perfection by Soderbergh) who is unhappy in his work, marriage and life, in general. He frequently masturbates at his office job and is generally distracted by his active imagination. After a co-worker suddenly has a heart attack, Munson is stuck writing a speech for T. Azimuth Schwitters - an L. Ron Hubbard type guru who sells a brand of self-help called 'Eventualism.' One day, Munson spots his doppelganger and follows him to his home. Turns out this fella is a dentist, and, without any clear reason, he is suddenly transported into Dr. Jeffery Kortchack's body and assumes the dentist's life (which includes having an affair with his own wife from his existence as Fletcher Munson). Confused yet? Then there is also the story of Elmo, the exterminator who speaks in a language of random words (I.E., 'Jigsaw. Uh, fragment chief butter. King surgery mind??') and gets laid by all of his beautiful women clients. Language is altered and skewed throughout the film - one scene has the husband and wife exchanging analytically defined sentences ('Generic greeting!' 'Generic greeting returned!') And yes, it gets much stranger, but that is one of the many wonderful things this film has going for it - you will be completely uncertain as to what is next coming. I can do no justice trying to explain the plot; the above encapsulation is an infinitesimally small fraction of the entire story and all of its interwoven subplots, thereof. So, what the hell does it all mean? I can't say that I'm entirely sure, myself, but I always have one helluva good time riding through it. There are endless side-stories and (seemingly) left-over ideas conceived through a myriad of supremely clever and bizarre film devices. It's a jarring experience at first, but with repeated viewing, the unconnected pieces of information come together in a most surprising and rewarding fashion. To me, Schizopolis is the cinematic equivalent of a Rubic's cube - you may fumble with it for a long time, but when you finally get a side complete - Ahhh, the joy and relief of a job well done. Yet, there are five other sides that remain mixed. Soderbergh took several years to make this film completely outside of the Hollywood machine ('I was in danger of becoming a hack,' he said) So he mounted this indie-indie-independent labor of love in the vein of a guerrilla production - a project he was literally shooting in his own back yard and at the houses of friends and neighbors. Still, the film never feels like its cheating the audience because of its budget limitations. Whatever it is that he's trying to do within the film's cryptic scenes, he manages to pull off with the confidence that he knows what he's doing. Steven Soderbergh also plays the leading man - a choice more practical than really desired according to him, but his performance is amazingly funny (the scene where he's making faces at himself in the mirror is a keeper for all time). He also cast his recently separated wife (Betsy Brantley) as his wife in the film, echoing his own a personal dilemma. And though this film embraces obfuscation and absurdity, have I mentioned that it's ridiculously hilarious? This is a cross-brand of comedy that I have never-before-seen. It's kinda like the Marx Brothers directed by Richard Lester on acid. But all insipid cross-comparisons aside, I feel like there's little room for improvement in this grandiose experimental film. There may be some minor performance flaws or uneven pacing, but in a film that embraces lack of coherence, that's hardly stable grounds for critique. This film was readily dissed by critics (if an established director does something completely off the wall and confusing, it must be self-indulgent), and the 12 people that actually saw it, abhorred it (any film that has people walking out after 20 minutes must have something going for it). So do yourself (and Mr. Soderbergh) a favor and seek this one out. Accept the challenge that this film proposes and try putting this puzzle together. Not that there's any doubt about this now given his expansive oeuvre, but Steven Soderbergh is one of the leading revolutionaries working in cinema today.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Duals
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tedg (tedg@FilmsFolded.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/2/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I am glad that Soderbergh is making films, even if every other one is a glossy mess. Like many filmmakers, he lives in and loves the medium. Unlike most of them, he experiments in film with things that matter  and he does it while pretending it is a joke. This will be seen by many as a bizarre hoax, a vanity project, a sandbox. But I think not; I receive it as a small, complex personal project. His marriage was falling apart. He was baffled by matters of duality: simultaneous understanding and confusion. So he made a film featuring himself and his already ex-wife. In it, time faces itself; everyone has dual lives among which they shift. You'll only get part of what is going on the first time around, but this rewards multiple viewings. Ted's Evaluation -- 3 of 3: Worth watching.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Is this such a strange movie? No, it isn't nearly strange enough
   </titulo>
   <autor>
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/11/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Wow, dudes are falling over themselves to praise this movie on IMDb (as of this writing)! Maybe for, like, a "film buff" it's a big deal that somebody made such an aggressively chaotic movie? Whatever. If you're a comedy fan before you're a film fan, then you'll recognize that randomness is not absurdity, and that Schizopolis presents too much of the former. There are whole scenes wherein characters talk in gibberish, speaking real but ostensibly silly words--("nose army", "landmine")--that have no apparent connection to what's happening. And... that's all that's going on. It's like being expected to laugh solely because Weird Al Yankovic said "Albequerque". Some of the movie's lines and ideas are much sharper than this, but too much of its humor is at the pre-teen/grandpa level. It appears that absurdity is the central point of this movie--in other regards, Schizopolis isn't beautiful enough or comprehensible enough to matter very much. But unfortunately, on the whole, this movie is not much more than mildly odd.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The end, or a new beginning; Soderbergh's forgotten think-piece
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Graham Greene
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/8/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    An experiment; an attempt by Soderbergh to strip away the extraneous baggage of narrative cinema - and, in the process, the often debilitating obsessions with style and presentation - in order to get to the pure essence of film-making, as an outlet for spontaneous, creative expression. Soderbergh would subsequently refer to the finished product as a necessary purging; a way of going beyond the obsessive technical approach and over-reliance on the look and technique that had been so important to the atmosphere of his earliest work, so as to make possible the more liberated and immediate film-making approach of subsequent films such as Out of Sight (1998) and The Limey (1999). As a result, Schizopolis (1996) can now be seen as both the end and the beginning of something really quite wonderful; offering, as it does, the full stop following perhaps the most interesting and successful stage of the director's career - in which he developed on the cool and seductive Sex Lies and Videotape (1988), the dark and expressionistic Kafka (1991) and the underrated American masterpiece King of the Hill (1993) - and the start of a whole new chapter - in which the director found his greatest success with the highly acclaimed Erin Brockovich (2000), the Oscar winning Traffic (2000) and the hugely successful remake of Ocean's Eleven (2001). In keeping with this idea of purging, we can see with Schizopolis an attempt by Soderbergh to indulge all of his various creative quirks and eccentricities before simplifying his style and vision in a way that would be beneficial to a mainstream American audience. Although he would create similar indulgences since - including films like Full Frontal (2002), Bubble (2005) and The Good German (2006) - those particular films often feel like extra-curricular exercises that don't, in any real way, relate to his more successful endeavours, such as the Ocean's Twelve (2004) and Thirteen (2007) sequels and his adaptation of the Stanislaw Lem novel, Solaris (2002). Whereas those films hid their post-modern reinvention beneath knock-about farce or widescreen spectacle, Schizopolis is home-made, experimental cinema at its most explicit and unhinged. From the narrative set-up, to the casting, to the use of editing, music and mise-en-scene, the film is literally bursting with ideas and ingenious abstractions, with Soderbergh taking influence from a number of far greater filmmakers - such as his personal heroes, Terry Gilliam and Richard Lester, to legendary masters like Jacques Rivette and Jean Luc Godard - and yet, still manages to produce a piece of work that seems true to his own unique style and individual creative preoccupations. Naturally, given the nature of the film and the outlandishness of its characters and approach, Schizopolis often seesaws wildly from the inventive, to the stupid, to the genuinely inspired. It was and still remains a bold and daring work for the director; disregarding the lush cinematography and evocative period detail of Kafka and King of the Hill and instead developing the rough and ready, hand-held, matter-of-fact approach that he would continue to use on subsequent films like Traffic and The Limey. However, the presentation works, and the style of the film does well to convey certain themes and ideas that are expressed through the tone and opinions of a central character that is perfectly performed by the director himself. It also creates that feeling of something anarchic and aesthetically quite progressive; disregarding any such notions of box-office potential, industry trailblazing or self-congratulatory deconstruction to simply make a film that presents the pure, unfettered spirit, energy and imagination that only the very best of cinema can convey. It obviously won't be to all tastes - which goes without saying - but even so, I feel that Schizopolis is a truly unsung work within the director's career; stressing personal expression, ironic self-deprecation and genuine cinematic invention. As it stands over a decade on from its initial release, Schizopolis can now be seen as a relic to the days when Soderbergh could (for me at least) be cited as perhaps the greatest living filmmaker of his generation; with the film capturing the sense of diversity, energy and complete control over all aspects of the production that can be noted throughout his work released during the 1990's. His more recent films might be more financially successful (and certainly not without merit), but for me, they simply fail to offer that same sense of inimitable defiance, unpredictability and that eccentric disregard for convention that his work was once synonymous with. It may not be wholly triumphant overall - and is certainly not on a par with the likes of Kafka, King of the Hill and the greater than you might remember it Out of Sight - it is, nonetheless, a work of pure vision; both mesmerising and maddening in almost equal measure, and punctuated by Soderbergh's static, deadpan performance and the capricious idea that anything could happen at any given time.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of the worst movies I have ever seen
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ctrogue
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/8/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is such a bad case of a want to be 60's cult classic, yes it is very poorly made as a typical 60's low budget independently made movie. That's the problem!!! Steven Soderbergh had the bucks to make something dececent but not the imagination. I spent $27 for this movie because it was Criterion Collection and turned it off after 18 minutes. The movie I was watching prior to this was called Happenstance it showed far more imagination than any American movie made in the last 10 years! While I am venting on this crap movie, how the hell does the last Batman movie get to be number one, where are the standards that movie isn't even on DVD yet. How can it be the number one movie of all times when most of the people that voted on it could not have seen it more than once!!!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Generic Greeting!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Joseph Sylvers
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/6/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    An absurdist film, with a sense of humor, that's actually as laugh out loud funny as it is conceptually amusing. A lampooning of Scientology, relationships, the difficulties of communication, the film making business, the nightly news, corporate life and just about everything it touches. Steven Soderberg has made one of the zanniest comedies, in recent memory(I cant think of the last time I used the word zany in conversation). This is the film which restored Soderberg's creative powers after a series of slumps and a collapsing marriage, after which he would go on to Oceans 11 and infamy. These two quotes might better let you know what your in for. "Dear attractive woman number 2, only once in my life have I responded to a person the way I've responded to you, but I've forgotten when it was or even if it was in fact me that responded. I may not know much, but I know that the wind sings your name endlessly, although with a slight lisp that makes it difficult to understand if I'm standing near an air conditioner. I know that your hair sits atop your head as though it could sit nowhere else. I know that your figure would make a sculptor cast aside his tools, injuring his assistant who was looking out the window instead of paying attention. I know that your lips are as full as that sexy french model's that I desperately want to f*&k. I know that if for an instant I could have you lie next to me, or on top of me, or sit on me, or stand over me and shake, then I would be the happiest man in my pants. I know all of this, and yet you do not know me. Change your life; accept my love. Or, at least let me pay you to accept it." "Fletcher Munson: (sunnily, on homecoming) Generic greeting! Mrs. Munson: (warmly) Generic greeting returned! (they kiss and chuckle at each other) Fletcher Munson: Imminent sustenance. Mrs. Munson: Overly dramatic statement regarding upcoming meal. Fletcher Munson: Oooh! False reaction indicating hunger and excitement! Fletcher Munson: (wife snuggles up amorously) Ooh! *Really* well-rehearsed speech about workload and stress. (pause) Fletcher Munson: Genuine sorrow. Um... truthful-sounding promises of future satisfaction? Enticement to agree? Mrs. Munson: (pause) Accepted. Fletcher Munson: Gratitude." "A New Mexico woman was named Final Arbiter of Taste & Justice today, ending God's lengthy search for someone to straighten this country out. Eileen Harriet Palglace will have final say on every known subject, including who should be put to death, what clothes everyone should wear, what movies suck, and whether bald men who grow ponytails should still get laid."
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not for everyone, and that includes me
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Charles Herold (cherold)
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Schizopolis begins with this very funny speech by Soderbergh, and early on it looks a little like some sketch comedy show from the 70s like Kentucky Fried Movie. And definitely sketch comedy is an element of this. But it's sketch comedy that tries hard to not be too funny. Ideas like a couple exchanging generic greetings are clever but no more than mildly amusing, and I think that's what the movie is going for; it doesn't want comedy to override experimental weirdness. The movie is also careful to avoid feeling too much like it has a linear story. Yes, we do follow characters through a story arc, but this is done in a purposefully disjointed manner. The pieces for something genuinely entertaining are there, but the director clearly wants something that is more challenging than enjoyable. And to certain people, that will make it more enjoyable. But I'm not one of those people. For me, it was a clever but rather tedious experiment.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An interesting and fun experiment
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mike-seaman
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Explaining Schizopolis seems counterintuitive. The movie is a mixture of autobiographical self- examination and self-deprecation. At the same time the film seems to be tackling some larger cultural themes and postmodern concepts of language and communication. In the end, I think the movie is a fun assortment of ideas being exercised together in a rather harmless fashion. Schizopolis never seems to take itself seriously, the movie is made on a small-budget, with a purposefully contained cast, self-aware and referential humor, taking stabs at life, narratives, movies, culture, and humanity while never entirely aiming at any single target (except perhaps the filmmaker himself). I recommend this movie not because it is a fully realized concept (because it isn't) or because it is a hidden gem that must be discovered (because it isn't) but it is refreshing to see an experimental film created playfully, aware of its self-indulgence and entirely at ease with it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Being Steven Soderbergh
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    CinefanR
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/4/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Movies like Lost Highway, American Beauty and other high-profile, big-budget productions have been praised for their original takes, but in fact it was "Schizopolis" that explored those possibilities first. I find it refreshing and inexplicably underrated. The film is a very funny and bizarre look into the creative mind of its author, Steven Soderbergh. Press conferences on horse urination, marital dissolution, dysfunctional families, work, love, death, identity, the hilarious (and tragic) absurdity of life everything is scrutinized here under a mask of randomness which makes everything unpredictable and crazy funny. "Schizopolis" gleefully delves into the absurd and blends it with satire in a most original social commentary, mocking all conventions and confinements. This type of humor is my kind. For fans of Kafka, Eugene Ionesco and Urmuz, Samuel Beckett, Kurt Vonnegut or David Lynch, this will be a blast. On a third viewing, all this "mess" makes perfect sense, and it's beautiful. "Sneeze!"
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Very Disappointing
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Bob_Jenkem
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/8/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I wanted to like "Schizopolis" but ended up ultimately finding it to be a very slow, pretentious, and boring movie. The first forty minutes-or-so are funny, but the second half of the movie is like watching paint dry, and the movie seems to go on much longer than it actually is. While it has a germ of an idea, Soderbergh makes one grave screen writing error around the 50-minute mark (and I'm aware this film was improvised - exactly my point), when he suddenly introduces a new main character (played by the director, who plays both characters) that takes up the rest of the movie, with almost no reference to the previous main character. By the time he shows up again in the last ten minutes, he's speaking Japanese. Why? (I know it's supposed to symbolize that the character and his wife are distant, but it's INCREDIBLY heavy-handed). For that matter, why do characters constantly speak in non-sequitors? No reason is given. Any chance at character development is killed, and the whole movie comes tumbling down. I understand he wanted to be abstract and surrealistic, but the complete lack of storytelling structure as a basis for using abstract surrealism makes the movie boring. The only good parts are the interstitial news bulletins, and there are moments of creative filmmaking in it. But overall, it's a snoozefest. But what a great title. Some funny lines in it too ("What was your last co-worker's name?" "Oh, Nameless Numberhead Man?"). This was the first Steven Soderbergh film I've seen. I won't be rushing out to watch his other movies.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    one of a kind
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mglasson
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/5/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Schizopolis is perhaps best summarized with the copy line - 'All attempts at synopses of this film have resulted in hospitalization.' It's no understatement - just about every convention and niche of film is broken in this flick, and those looking for an easy ride into movie-watching oblivion won't find it here. The film mainly revolves around ad exec Fletcher Munson (played to perfection by Soderbergh) who is unhappy in his work, marriage and life, in general. He frequently masturbates at his office job and is generally distracted by his active imagination. After a co-worker suddenly has a heart attack, Munson is stuck writing a speech for T. Azimuth Schwitters - an L. Ron Hubbard type guru who sells a brand of self-help called 'Eventualism.' One day, Munson spots his doppelganger and follows him to his home. Turns out this fella is a dentist, and, without any clear reason, he is suddenly transported into Dr. Jeffery Kortchack's body and assumes the dentist's life (which includes having an affair with his own wife from his existence as Fletcher Munson). Confused yet? Then there is also the story of Elmo, the exterminator who speaks in a language of random words (I.E., 'Jigsaw. Uh, fragment chief butter. King surgery mind??') and gets laid by all of his beautiful women clients. Language is altered and skewed throughout the film - one scene has the husband and wife exchanging analytically defined sentences ('Generic greeting!' 'Generic greeting returned!') And yes, it gets much stranger, but that is one of the many wonderful things this film has going for it - you will be completely uncertain as to what is next coming. I can do no justice trying to explain the plot; the above encapsulation is an infinitesimally small fraction of the entire story and all of its interwoven subplots, thereof. So, what the hell does it all mean? I can't say that I'm entirely sure, myself, but I always have one helluva good time riding through it. There are endless side-stories and (seemingly) left-over ideas conceived through a myriad of supremely clever and bizarre film devices. It's a jarring experience at first, but with repeated viewing, the unconnected pieces of information come together in a most surprising and rewarding fashion. To me, Schizopolis is the cinematic equivalent of a Rubic's cube - you may fumble with it for a long time, but when you finally get a side complete - Ahhh, the joy and relief of a job well done. Yet, there are five other sides that remain mixed. Soderbergh took several years to make this film completely outside of the Hollywood machine ('I was in danger of becoming a hack,' he said) So he mounted this indie-indie-independent labor of love in the vein of a guerrilla production - a project he was literally shooting in his own back yard and at the houses of friends and neighbors. Still, the film never feels like its cheating the audience because of its budget limitations. Whatever it is that he's trying to do within the film's cryptic scenes, he manages to pull off with the confidence that he knows what he's doing. Steven Soderbergh also plays the leading man - a choice more practical than really desired according to him, but his performance is amazingly funny (the scene where he's making faces at himself in the mirror is a keeper for all time). He also cast his recently separated wife (Betsy Brantley) as his wife in the film, echoing his own a personal dilemma. And though this film embraces obfuscation and absurdity, have I mentioned that it's ridiculously hilarious? This is a cross-brand of comedy that I have never-before-seen. It's kinda like the Marx Brothers directed by Richard Lester on acid. But all insipid cross-comparisons aside, I feel like there's little room for improvement in this grandiose experimental film. There may be some minor performance flaws or uneven pacing, but in a film that embraces lack of coherence, that's hardly stable grounds for critique. This film was readily dissed by critics (if an established director does something completely off the wall and confusing, it must be self-indulgent), and the 12 people that actually saw it, abhorred it (any film that has people walking out after 20 minutes must have something going for it). So do yourself (and Mr. Soderbergh) a favor and seek this one out. Accept the challenge that this film proposes and try putting this puzzle together. Not that there's any doubt about this now given his expansive oeuvre, but Steven Soderbergh is one of the leading revolutionaries working in cinema today.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Duals
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tedg (tedg@FilmsFolded.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/2/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I am glad that Soderbergh is making films, even if every other one is a glossy mess. Like many filmmakers, he lives in and loves the medium. Unlike most of them, he experiments in film with things that matter  and he does it while pretending it is a joke. This will be seen by many as a bizarre hoax, a vanity project, a sandbox. But I think not; I receive it as a small, complex personal project. His marriage was falling apart. He was baffled by matters of duality: simultaneous understanding and confusion. So he made a film featuring himself and his already ex-wife. In it, time faces itself; everyone has dual lives among which they shift. You'll only get part of what is going on the first time around, but this rewards multiple viewings. Ted's Evaluation -- 3 of 3: Worth watching.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Is this such a strange movie? No, it isn't nearly strange enough
   </titulo>
   <autor>
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/11/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Wow, dudes are falling over themselves to praise this movie on IMDb (as of this writing)! Maybe for, like, a "film buff" it's a big deal that somebody made such an aggressively chaotic movie? Whatever. If you're a comedy fan before you're a film fan, then you'll recognize that randomness is not absurdity, and that Schizopolis presents too much of the former. There are whole scenes wherein characters talk in gibberish, speaking real but ostensibly silly words--("nose army", "landmine")--that have no apparent connection to what's happening. And... that's all that's going on. It's like being expected to laugh solely because Weird Al Yankovic said "Albequerque". Some of the movie's lines and ideas are much sharper than this, but too much of its humor is at the pre-teen/grandpa level. It appears that absurdity is the central point of this movie--in other regards, Schizopolis isn't beautiful enough or comprehensible enough to matter very much. But unfortunately, on the whole, this movie is not much more than mildly odd.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The end, or a new beginning; Soderbergh's forgotten think-piece
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Graham Greene
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/8/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    An experiment; an attempt by Soderbergh to strip away the extraneous baggage of narrative cinema - and, in the process, the often debilitating obsessions with style and presentation - in order to get to the pure essence of film-making, as an outlet for spontaneous, creative expression. Soderbergh would subsequently refer to the finished product as a necessary purging; a way of going beyond the obsessive technical approach and over-reliance on the look and technique that had been so important to the atmosphere of his earliest work, so as to make possible the more liberated and immediate film-making approach of subsequent films such as Out of Sight (1998) and The Limey (1999). As a result, Schizopolis (1996) can now be seen as both the end and the beginning of something really quite wonderful; offering, as it does, the full stop following perhaps the most interesting and successful stage of the director's career - in which he developed on the cool and seductive Sex Lies and Videotape (1988), the dark and expressionistic Kafka (1991) and the underrated American masterpiece King of the Hill (1993) - and the start of a whole new chapter - in which the director found his greatest success with the highly acclaimed Erin Brockovich (2000), the Oscar winning Traffic (2000) and the hugely successful remake of Ocean's Eleven (2001). In keeping with this idea of purging, we can see with Schizopolis an attempt by Soderbergh to indulge all of his various creative quirks and eccentricities before simplifying his style and vision in a way that would be beneficial to a mainstream American audience. Although he would create similar indulgences since - including films like Full Frontal (2002), Bubble (2005) and The Good German (2006) - those particular films often feel like extra-curricular exercises that don't, in any real way, relate to his more successful endeavours, such as the Ocean's Twelve (2004) and Thirteen (2007) sequels and his adaptation of the Stanislaw Lem novel, Solaris (2002). Whereas those films hid their post-modern reinvention beneath knock-about farce or widescreen spectacle, Schizopolis is home-made, experimental cinema at its most explicit and unhinged. From the narrative set-up, to the casting, to the use of editing, music and mise-en-scene, the film is literally bursting with ideas and ingenious abstractions, with Soderbergh taking influence from a number of far greater filmmakers - such as his personal heroes, Terry Gilliam and Richard Lester, to legendary masters like Jacques Rivette and Jean Luc Godard - and yet, still manages to produce a piece of work that seems true to his own unique style and individual creative preoccupations. Naturally, given the nature of the film and the outlandishness of its characters and approach, Schizopolis often seesaws wildly from the inventive, to the stupid, to the genuinely inspired. It was and still remains a bold and daring work for the director; disregarding the lush cinematography and evocative period detail of Kafka and King of the Hill and instead developing the rough and ready, hand-held, matter-of-fact approach that he would continue to use on subsequent films like Traffic and The Limey. However, the presentation works, and the style of the film does well to convey certain themes and ideas that are expressed through the tone and opinions of a central character that is perfectly performed by the director himself. It also creates that feeling of something anarchic and aesthetically quite progressive; disregarding any such notions of box-office potential, industry trailblazing or self-congratulatory deconstruction to simply make a film that presents the pure, unfettered spirit, energy and imagination that only the very best of cinema can convey. It obviously won't be to all tastes - which goes without saying - but even so, I feel that Schizopolis is a truly unsung work within the director's career; stressing personal expression, ironic self-deprecation and genuine cinematic invention. As it stands over a decade on from its initial release, Schizopolis can now be seen as a relic to the days when Soderbergh could (for me at least) be cited as perhaps the greatest living filmmaker of his generation; with the film capturing the sense of diversity, energy and complete control over all aspects of the production that can be noted throughout his work released during the 1990's. His more recent films might be more financially successful (and certainly not without merit), but for me, they simply fail to offer that same sense of inimitable defiance, unpredictability and that eccentric disregard for convention that his work was once synonymous with. It may not be wholly triumphant overall - and is certainly not on a par with the likes of Kafka, King of the Hill and the greater than you might remember it Out of Sight - it is, nonetheless, a work of pure vision; both mesmerising and maddening in almost equal measure, and punctuated by Soderbergh's static, deadpan performance and the capricious idea that anything could happen at any given time.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of the worst movies I have ever seen
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ctrogue
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/8/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is such a bad case of a want to be 60's cult classic, yes it is very poorly made as a typical 60's low budget independently made movie. That's the problem!!! Steven Soderbergh had the bucks to make something dececent but not the imagination. I spent $27 for this movie because it was Criterion Collection and turned it off after 18 minutes. The movie I was watching prior to this was called Happenstance it showed far more imagination than any American movie made in the last 10 years! While I am venting on this crap movie, how the hell does the last Batman movie get to be number one, where are the standards that movie isn't even on DVD yet. How can it be the number one movie of all times when most of the people that voted on it could not have seen it more than once!!!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Generic Greeting!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Joseph Sylvers
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/6/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    An absurdist film, with a sense of humor, that's actually as laugh out loud funny as it is conceptually amusing. A lampooning of Scientology, relationships, the difficulties of communication, the film making business, the nightly news, corporate life and just about everything it touches. Steven Soderberg has made one of the zanniest comedies, in recent memory(I cant think of the last time I used the word zany in conversation). This is the film which restored Soderberg's creative powers after a series of slumps and a collapsing marriage, after which he would go on to Oceans 11 and infamy. These two quotes might better let you know what your in for. "Dear attractive woman number 2, only once in my life have I responded to a person the way I've responded to you, but I've forgotten when it was or even if it was in fact me that responded. I may not know much, but I know that the wind sings your name endlessly, although with a slight lisp that makes it difficult to understand if I'm standing near an air conditioner. I know that your hair sits atop your head as though it could sit nowhere else. I know that your figure would make a sculptor cast aside his tools, injuring his assistant who was looking out the window instead of paying attention. I know that your lips are as full as that sexy french model's that I desperately want to f*&k. I know that if for an instant I could have you lie next to me, or on top of me, or sit on me, or stand over me and shake, then I would be the happiest man in my pants. I know all of this, and yet you do not know me. Change your life; accept my love. Or, at least let me pay you to accept it." "Fletcher Munson: (sunnily, on homecoming) Generic greeting! Mrs. Munson: (warmly) Generic greeting returned! (they kiss and chuckle at each other) Fletcher Munson: Imminent sustenance. Mrs. Munson: Overly dramatic statement regarding upcoming meal. Fletcher Munson: Oooh! False reaction indicating hunger and excitement! Fletcher Munson: (wife snuggles up amorously) Ooh! *Really* well-rehearsed speech about workload and stress. (pause) Fletcher Munson: Genuine sorrow. Um... truthful-sounding promises of future satisfaction? Enticement to agree? Mrs. Munson: (pause) Accepted. Fletcher Munson: Gratitude." "A New Mexico woman was named Final Arbiter of Taste & Justice today, ending God's lengthy search for someone to straighten this country out. Eileen Harriet Palglace will have final say on every known subject, including who should be put to death, what clothes everyone should wear, what movies suck, and whether bald men who grow ponytails should still get laid."
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not for everyone, and that includes me
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Charles Herold (cherold)
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Schizopolis begins with this very funny speech by Soderbergh, and early on it looks a little like some sketch comedy show from the 70s like Kentucky Fried Movie. And definitely sketch comedy is an element of this. But it's sketch comedy that tries hard to not be too funny. Ideas like a couple exchanging generic greetings are clever but no more than mildly amusing, and I think that's what the movie is going for; it doesn't want comedy to override experimental weirdness. The movie is also careful to avoid feeling too much like it has a linear story. Yes, we do follow characters through a story arc, but this is done in a purposefully disjointed manner. The pieces for something genuinely entertaining are there, but the director clearly wants something that is more challenging than enjoyable. And to certain people, that will make it more enjoyable. But I'm not one of those people. For me, it was a clever but rather tedious experiment.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An interesting and fun experiment
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mike-seaman
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Explaining Schizopolis seems counterintuitive. The movie is a mixture of autobiographical self- examination and self-deprecation. At the same time the film seems to be tackling some larger cultural themes and postmodern concepts of language and communication. In the end, I think the movie is a fun assortment of ideas being exercised together in a rather harmless fashion. Schizopolis never seems to take itself seriously, the movie is made on a small-budget, with a purposefully contained cast, self-aware and referential humor, taking stabs at life, narratives, movies, culture, and humanity while never entirely aiming at any single target (except perhaps the filmmaker himself). I recommend this movie not because it is a fully realized concept (because it isn't) or because it is a hidden gem that must be discovered (because it isn't) but it is refreshing to see an experimental film created playfully, aware of its self-indulgence and entirely at ease with it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Being Steven Soderbergh
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    CinefanR
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/4/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Movies like Lost Highway, American Beauty and other high-profile, big-budget productions have been praised for their original takes, but in fact it was "Schizopolis" that explored those possibilities first. I find it refreshing and inexplicably underrated. The film is a very funny and bizarre look into the creative mind of its author, Steven Soderbergh. Press conferences on horse urination, marital dissolution, dysfunctional families, work, love, death, identity, the hilarious (and tragic) absurdity of life everything is scrutinized here under a mask of randomness which makes everything unpredictable and crazy funny. "Schizopolis" gleefully delves into the absurd and blends it with satire in a most original social commentary, mocking all conventions and confinements. This type of humor is my kind. For fans of Kafka, Eugene Ionesco and Urmuz, Samuel Beckett, Kurt Vonnegut or David Lynch, this will be a blast. On a third viewing, all this "mess" makes perfect sense, and it's beautiful. "Sneeze!"
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Very Disappointing
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Bob_Jenkem
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/8/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I wanted to like "Schizopolis" but ended up ultimately finding it to be a very slow, pretentious, and boring movie. The first forty minutes-or-so are funny, but the second half of the movie is like watching paint dry, and the movie seems to go on much longer than it actually is. While it has a germ of an idea, Soderbergh makes one grave screen writing error around the 50-minute mark (and I'm aware this film was improvised - exactly my point), when he suddenly introduces a new main character (played by the director, who plays both characters) that takes up the rest of the movie, with almost no reference to the previous main character. By the time he shows up again in the last ten minutes, he's speaking Japanese. Why? (I know it's supposed to symbolize that the character and his wife are distant, but it's INCREDIBLY heavy-handed). For that matter, why do characters constantly speak in non-sequitors? No reason is given. Any chance at character development is killed, and the whole movie comes tumbling down. I understand he wanted to be abstract and surrealistic, but the complete lack of storytelling structure as a basis for using abstract surrealism makes the movie boring. The only good parts are the interstitial news bulletins, and there are moments of creative filmmaking in it. But overall, it's a snoozefest. But what a great title. Some funny lines in it too ("What was your last co-worker's name?" "Oh, Nameless Numberhead Man?"). This was the first Steven Soderbergh film I've seen. I won't be rushing out to watch his other movies.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    one of a kind
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mglasson
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/5/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Schizopolis is perhaps best summarized with the copy line - 'All attempts at synopses of this film have resulted in hospitalization.' It's no understatement - just about every convention and niche of film is broken in this flick, and those looking for an easy ride into movie-watching oblivion won't find it here. The film mainly revolves around ad exec Fletcher Munson (played to perfection by Soderbergh) who is unhappy in his work, marriage and life, in general. He frequently masturbates at his office job and is generally distracted by his active imagination. After a co-worker suddenly has a heart attack, Munson is stuck writing a speech for T. Azimuth Schwitters - an L. Ron Hubbard type guru who sells a brand of self-help called 'Eventualism.' One day, Munson spots his doppelganger and follows him to his home. Turns out this fella is a dentist, and, without any clear reason, he is suddenly transported into Dr. Jeffery Kortchack's body and assumes the dentist's life (which includes having an affair with his own wife from his existence as Fletcher Munson). Confused yet? Then there is also the story of Elmo, the exterminator who speaks in a language of random words (I.E., 'Jigsaw. Uh, fragment chief butter. King surgery mind??') and gets laid by all of his beautiful women clients. Language is altered and skewed throughout the film - one scene has the husband and wife exchanging analytically defined sentences ('Generic greeting!' 'Generic greeting returned!') And yes, it gets much stranger, but that is one of the many wonderful things this film has going for it - you will be completely uncertain as to what is next coming. I can do no justice trying to explain the plot; the above encapsulation is an infinitesimally small fraction of the entire story and all of its interwoven subplots, thereof. So, what the hell does it all mean? I can't say that I'm entirely sure, myself, but I always have one helluva good time riding through it. There are endless side-stories and (seemingly) left-over ideas conceived through a myriad of supremely clever and bizarre film devices. It's a jarring experience at first, but with repeated viewing, the unconnected pieces of information come together in a most surprising and rewarding fashion. To me, Schizopolis is the cinematic equivalent of a Rubic's cube - you may fumble with it for a long time, but when you finally get a side complete - Ahhh, the joy and relief of a job well done. Yet, there are five other sides that remain mixed. Soderbergh took several years to make this film completely outside of the Hollywood machine ('I was in danger of becoming a hack,' he said) So he mounted this indie-indie-independent labor of love in the vein of a guerrilla production - a project he was literally shooting in his own back yard and at the houses of friends and neighbors. Still, the film never feels like its cheating the audience because of its budget limitations. Whatever it is that he's trying to do within the film's cryptic scenes, he manages to pull off with the confidence that he knows what he's doing. Steven Soderbergh also plays the leading man - a choice more practical than really desired according to him, but his performance is amazingly funny (the scene where he's making faces at himself in the mirror is a keeper for all time). He also cast his recently separated wife (Betsy Brantley) as his wife in the film, echoing his own a personal dilemma. And though this film embraces obfuscation and absurdity, have I mentioned that it's ridiculously hilarious? This is a cross-brand of comedy that I have never-before-seen. It's kinda like the Marx Brothers directed by Richard Lester on acid. But all insipid cross-comparisons aside, I feel like there's little room for improvement in this grandiose experimental film. There may be some minor performance flaws or uneven pacing, but in a film that embraces lack of coherence, that's hardly stable grounds for critique. This film was readily dissed by critics (if an established director does something completely off the wall and confusing, it must be self-indulgent), and the 12 people that actually saw it, abhorred it (any film that has people walking out after 20 minutes must have something going for it). So do yourself (and Mr. Soderbergh) a favor and seek this one out. Accept the challenge that this film proposes and try putting this puzzle together. Not that there's any doubt about this now given his expansive oeuvre, but Steven Soderbergh is one of the leading revolutionaries working in cinema today.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Duals
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tedg (tedg@FilmsFolded.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/2/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I am glad that Soderbergh is making films, even if every other one is a glossy mess. Like many filmmakers, he lives in and loves the medium. Unlike most of them, he experiments in film with things that matter  and he does it while pretending it is a joke. This will be seen by many as a bizarre hoax, a vanity project, a sandbox. But I think not; I receive it as a small, complex personal project. His marriage was falling apart. He was baffled by matters of duality: simultaneous understanding and confusion. So he made a film featuring himself and his already ex-wife. In it, time faces itself; everyone has dual lives among which they shift. You'll only get part of what is going on the first time around, but this rewards multiple viewings. Ted's Evaluation -- 3 of 3: Worth watching.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Is this such a strange movie? No, it isn't nearly strange enough
   </titulo>
   <autor>
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/11/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Wow, dudes are falling over themselves to praise this movie on IMDb (as of this writing)! Maybe for, like, a "film buff" it's a big deal that somebody made such an aggressively chaotic movie? Whatever. If you're a comedy fan before you're a film fan, then you'll recognize that randomness is not absurdity, and that Schizopolis presents too much of the former. There are whole scenes wherein characters talk in gibberish, speaking real but ostensibly silly words--("nose army", "landmine")--that have no apparent connection to what's happening. And... that's all that's going on. It's like being expected to laugh solely because Weird Al Yankovic said "Albequerque". Some of the movie's lines and ideas are much sharper than this, but too much of its humor is at the pre-teen/grandpa level. It appears that absurdity is the central point of this movie--in other regards, Schizopolis isn't beautiful enough or comprehensible enough to matter very much. But unfortunately, on the whole, this movie is not much more than mildly odd.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The end, or a new beginning; Soderbergh's forgotten think-piece
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Graham Greene
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/8/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    An experiment; an attempt by Soderbergh to strip away the extraneous baggage of narrative cinema - and, in the process, the often debilitating obsessions with style and presentation - in order to get to the pure essence of film-making, as an outlet for spontaneous, creative expression. Soderbergh would subsequently refer to the finished product as a necessary purging; a way of going beyond the obsessive technical approach and over-reliance on the look and technique that had been so important to the atmosphere of his earliest work, so as to make possible the more liberated and immediate film-making approach of subsequent films such as Out of Sight (1998) and The Limey (1999). As a result, Schizopolis (1996) can now be seen as both the end and the beginning of something really quite wonderful; offering, as it does, the full stop following perhaps the most interesting and successful stage of the director's career - in which he developed on the cool and seductive Sex Lies and Videotape (1988), the dark and expressionistic Kafka (1991) and the underrated American masterpiece King of the Hill (1993) - and the start of a whole new chapter - in which the director found his greatest success with the highly acclaimed Erin Brockovich (2000), the Oscar winning Traffic (2000) and the hugely successful remake of Ocean's Eleven (2001). In keeping with this idea of purging, we can see with Schizopolis an attempt by Soderbergh to indulge all of his various creative quirks and eccentricities before simplifying his style and vision in a way that would be beneficial to a mainstream American audience. Although he would create similar indulgences since - including films like Full Frontal (2002), Bubble (2005) and The Good German (2006) - those particular films often feel like extra-curricular exercises that don't, in any real way, relate to his more successful endeavours, such as the Ocean's Twelve (2004) and Thirteen (2007) sequels and his adaptation of the Stanislaw Lem novel, Solaris (2002). Whereas those films hid their post-modern reinvention beneath knock-about farce or widescreen spectacle, Schizopolis is home-made, experimental cinema at its most explicit and unhinged. From the narrative set-up, to the casting, to the use of editing, music and mise-en-scene, the film is literally bursting with ideas and ingenious abstractions, with Soderbergh taking influence from a number of far greater filmmakers - such as his personal heroes, Terry Gilliam and Richard Lester, to legendary masters like Jacques Rivette and Jean Luc Godard - and yet, still manages to produce a piece of work that seems true to his own unique style and individual creative preoccupations. Naturally, given the nature of the film and the outlandishness of its characters and approach, Schizopolis often seesaws wildly from the inventive, to the stupid, to the genuinely inspired. It was and still remains a bold and daring work for the director; disregarding the lush cinematography and evocative period detail of Kafka and King of the Hill and instead developing the rough and ready, hand-held, matter-of-fact approach that he would continue to use on subsequent films like Traffic and The Limey. However, the presentation works, and the style of the film does well to convey certain themes and ideas that are expressed through the tone and opinions of a central character that is perfectly performed by the director himself. It also creates that feeling of something anarchic and aesthetically quite progressive; disregarding any such notions of box-office potential, industry trailblazing or self-congratulatory deconstruction to simply make a film that presents the pure, unfettered spirit, energy and imagination that only the very best of cinema can convey. It obviously won't be to all tastes - which goes without saying - but even so, I feel that Schizopolis is a truly unsung work within the director's career; stressing personal expression, ironic self-deprecation and genuine cinematic invention. As it stands over a decade on from its initial release, Schizopolis can now be seen as a relic to the days when Soderbergh could (for me at least) be cited as perhaps the greatest living filmmaker of his generation; with the film capturing the sense of diversity, energy and complete control over all aspects of the production that can be noted throughout his work released during the 1990's. His more recent films might be more financially successful (and certainly not without merit), but for me, they simply fail to offer that same sense of inimitable defiance, unpredictability and that eccentric disregard for convention that his work was once synonymous with. It may not be wholly triumphant overall - and is certainly not on a par with the likes of Kafka, King of the Hill and the greater than you might remember it Out of Sight - it is, nonetheless, a work of pure vision; both mesmerising and maddening in almost equal measure, and punctuated by Soderbergh's static, deadpan performance and the capricious idea that anything could happen at any given time.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of the worst movies I have ever seen
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ctrogue
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/8/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is such a bad case of a want to be 60's cult classic, yes it is very poorly made as a typical 60's low budget independently made movie. That's the problem!!! Steven Soderbergh had the bucks to make something dececent but not the imagination. I spent $27 for this movie because it was Criterion Collection and turned it off after 18 minutes. The movie I was watching prior to this was called Happenstance it showed far more imagination than any American movie made in the last 10 years! While I am venting on this crap movie, how the hell does the last Batman movie get to be number one, where are the standards that movie isn't even on DVD yet. How can it be the number one movie of all times when most of the people that voted on it could not have seen it more than once!!!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Generic Greeting!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Joseph Sylvers
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/6/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    An absurdist film, with a sense of humor, that's actually as laugh out loud funny as it is conceptually amusing. A lampooning of Scientology, relationships, the difficulties of communication, the film making business, the nightly news, corporate life and just about everything it touches. Steven Soderberg has made one of the zanniest comedies, in recent memory(I cant think of the last time I used the word zany in conversation). This is the film which restored Soderberg's creative powers after a series of slumps and a collapsing marriage, after which he would go on to Oceans 11 and infamy. These two quotes might better let you know what your in for. "Dear attractive woman number 2, only once in my life have I responded to a person the way I've responded to you, but I've forgotten when it was or even if it was in fact me that responded. I may not know much, but I know that the wind sings your name endlessly, although with a slight lisp that makes it difficult to understand if I'm standing near an air conditioner. I know that your hair sits atop your head as though it could sit nowhere else. I know that your figure would make a sculptor cast aside his tools, injuring his assistant who was looking out the window instead of paying attention. I know that your lips are as full as that sexy french model's that I desperately want to f*&k. I know that if for an instant I could have you lie next to me, or on top of me, or sit on me, or stand over me and shake, then I would be the happiest man in my pants. I know all of this, and yet you do not know me. Change your life; accept my love. Or, at least let me pay you to accept it." "Fletcher Munson: (sunnily, on homecoming) Generic greeting! Mrs. Munson: (warmly) Generic greeting returned! (they kiss and chuckle at each other) Fletcher Munson: Imminent sustenance. Mrs. Munson: Overly dramatic statement regarding upcoming meal. Fletcher Munson: Oooh! False reaction indicating hunger and excitement! Fletcher Munson: (wife snuggles up amorously) Ooh! *Really* well-rehearsed speech about workload and stress. (pause) Fletcher Munson: Genuine sorrow. Um... truthful-sounding promises of future satisfaction? Enticement to agree? Mrs. Munson: (pause) Accepted. Fletcher Munson: Gratitude." "A New Mexico woman was named Final Arbiter of Taste & Justice today, ending God's lengthy search for someone to straighten this country out. Eileen Harriet Palglace will have final say on every known subject, including who should be put to death, what clothes everyone should wear, what movies suck, and whether bald men who grow ponytails should still get laid."
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not for everyone, and that includes me
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Charles Herold (cherold)
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Schizopolis begins with this very funny speech by Soderbergh, and early on it looks a little like some sketch comedy show from the 70s like Kentucky Fried Movie. And definitely sketch comedy is an element of this. But it's sketch comedy that tries hard to not be too funny. Ideas like a couple exchanging generic greetings are clever but no more than mildly amusing, and I think that's what the movie is going for; it doesn't want comedy to override experimental weirdness. The movie is also careful to avoid feeling too much like it has a linear story. Yes, we do follow characters through a story arc, but this is done in a purposefully disjointed manner. The pieces for something genuinely entertaining are there, but the director clearly wants something that is more challenging than enjoyable. And to certain people, that will make it more enjoyable. But I'm not one of those people. For me, it was a clever but rather tedious experiment.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An interesting and fun experiment
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mike-seaman
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Explaining Schizopolis seems counterintuitive. The movie is a mixture of autobiographical self- examination and self-deprecation. At the same time the film seems to be tackling some larger cultural themes and postmodern concepts of language and communication. In the end, I think the movie is a fun assortment of ideas being exercised together in a rather harmless fashion. Schizopolis never seems to take itself seriously, the movie is made on a small-budget, with a purposefully contained cast, self-aware and referential humor, taking stabs at life, narratives, movies, culture, and humanity while never entirely aiming at any single target (except perhaps the filmmaker himself). I recommend this movie not because it is a fully realized concept (because it isn't) or because it is a hidden gem that must be discovered (because it isn't) but it is refreshing to see an experimental film created playfully, aware of its self-indulgence and entirely at ease with it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Being Steven Soderbergh
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    CinefanR
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/4/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Movies like Lost Highway, American Beauty and other high-profile, big-budget productions have been praised for their original takes, but in fact it was "Schizopolis" that explored those possibilities first. I find it refreshing and inexplicably underrated. The film is a very funny and bizarre look into the creative mind of its author, Steven Soderbergh. Press conferences on horse urination, marital dissolution, dysfunctional families, work, love, death, identity, the hilarious (and tragic) absurdity of life everything is scrutinized here under a mask of randomness which makes everything unpredictable and crazy funny. "Schizopolis" gleefully delves into the absurd and blends it with satire in a most original social commentary, mocking all conventions and confinements. This type of humor is my kind. For fans of Kafka, Eugene Ionesco and Urmuz, Samuel Beckett, Kurt Vonnegut or David Lynch, this will be a blast. On a third viewing, all this "mess" makes perfect sense, and it's beautiful. "Sneeze!"
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Very Disappointing
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Bob_Jenkem
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/8/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I wanted to like "Schizopolis" but ended up ultimately finding it to be a very slow, pretentious, and boring movie. The first forty minutes-or-so are funny, but the second half of the movie is like watching paint dry, and the movie seems to go on much longer than it actually is. While it has a germ of an idea, Soderbergh makes one grave screen writing error around the 50-minute mark (and I'm aware this film was improvised - exactly my point), when he suddenly introduces a new main character (played by the director, who plays both characters) that takes up the rest of the movie, with almost no reference to the previous main character. By the time he shows up again in the last ten minutes, he's speaking Japanese. Why? (I know it's supposed to symbolize that the character and his wife are distant, but it's INCREDIBLY heavy-handed). For that matter, why do characters constantly speak in non-sequitors? No reason is given. Any chance at character development is killed, and the whole movie comes tumbling down. I understand he wanted to be abstract and surrealistic, but the complete lack of storytelling structure as a basis for using abstract surrealism makes the movie boring. The only good parts are the interstitial news bulletins, and there are moments of creative filmmaking in it. But overall, it's a snoozefest. But what a great title. Some funny lines in it too ("What was your last co-worker's name?" "Oh, Nameless Numberhead Man?"). This was the first Steven Soderbergh film I've seen. I won't be rushing out to watch his other movies.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    one of a kind
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mglasson
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/5/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Schizopolis is perhaps best summarized with the copy line - 'All attempts at synopses of this film have resulted in hospitalization.' It's no understatement - just about every convention and niche of film is broken in this flick, and those looking for an easy ride into movie-watching oblivion won't find it here. The film mainly revolves around ad exec Fletcher Munson (played to perfection by Soderbergh) who is unhappy in his work, marriage and life, in general. He frequently masturbates at his office job and is generally distracted by his active imagination. After a co-worker suddenly has a heart attack, Munson is stuck writing a speech for T. Azimuth Schwitters - an L. Ron Hubbard type guru who sells a brand of self-help called 'Eventualism.' One day, Munson spots his doppelganger and follows him to his home. Turns out this fella is a dentist, and, without any clear reason, he is suddenly transported into Dr. Jeffery Kortchack's body and assumes the dentist's life (which includes having an affair with his own wife from his existence as Fletcher Munson). Confused yet? Then there is also the story of Elmo, the exterminator who speaks in a language of random words (I.E., 'Jigsaw. Uh, fragment chief butter. King surgery mind??') and gets laid by all of his beautiful women clients. Language is altered and skewed throughout the film - one scene has the husband and wife exchanging analytically defined sentences ('Generic greeting!' 'Generic greeting returned!') And yes, it gets much stranger, but that is one of the many wonderful things this film has going for it - you will be completely uncertain as to what is next coming. I can do no justice trying to explain the plot; the above encapsulation is an infinitesimally small fraction of the entire story and all of its interwoven subplots, thereof. So, what the hell does it all mean? I can't say that I'm entirely sure, myself, but I always have one helluva good time riding through it. There are endless side-stories and (seemingly) left-over ideas conceived through a myriad of supremely clever and bizarre film devices. It's a jarring experience at first, but with repeated viewing, the unconnected pieces of information come together in a most surprising and rewarding fashion. To me, Schizopolis is the cinematic equivalent of a Rubic's cube - you may fumble with it for a long time, but when you finally get a side complete - Ahhh, the joy and relief of a job well done. Yet, there are five other sides that remain mixed. Soderbergh took several years to make this film completely outside of the Hollywood machine ('I was in danger of becoming a hack,' he said) So he mounted this indie-indie-independent labor of love in the vein of a guerrilla production - a project he was literally shooting in his own back yard and at the houses of friends and neighbors. Still, the film never feels like its cheating the audience because of its budget limitations. Whatever it is that he's trying to do within the film's cryptic scenes, he manages to pull off with the confidence that he knows what he's doing. Steven Soderbergh also plays the leading man - a choice more practical than really desired according to him, but his performance is amazingly funny (the scene where he's making faces at himself in the mirror is a keeper for all time). He also cast his recently separated wife (Betsy Brantley) as his wife in the film, echoing his own a personal dilemma. And though this film embraces obfuscation and absurdity, have I mentioned that it's ridiculously hilarious? This is a cross-brand of comedy that I have never-before-seen. It's kinda like the Marx Brothers directed by Richard Lester on acid. But all insipid cross-comparisons aside, I feel like there's little room for improvement in this grandiose experimental film. There may be some minor performance flaws or uneven pacing, but in a film that embraces lack of coherence, that's hardly stable grounds for critique. This film was readily dissed by critics (if an established director does something completely off the wall and confusing, it must be self-indulgent), and the 12 people that actually saw it, abhorred it (any film that has people walking out after 20 minutes must have something going for it). So do yourself (and Mr. Soderbergh) a favor and seek this one out. Accept the challenge that this film proposes and try putting this puzzle together. Not that there's any doubt about this now given his expansive oeuvre, but Steven Soderbergh is one of the leading revolutionaries working in cinema today.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Duals
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tedg (tedg@FilmsFolded.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/2/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I am glad that Soderbergh is making films, even if every other one is a glossy mess. Like many filmmakers, he lives in and loves the medium. Unlike most of them, he experiments in film with things that matter  and he does it while pretending it is a joke. This will be seen by many as a bizarre hoax, a vanity project, a sandbox. But I think not; I receive it as a small, complex personal project. His marriage was falling apart. He was baffled by matters of duality: simultaneous understanding and confusion. So he made a film featuring himself and his already ex-wife. In it, time faces itself; everyone has dual lives among which they shift. You'll only get part of what is going on the first time around, but this rewards multiple viewings. Ted's Evaluation -- 3 of 3: Worth watching.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Is this such a strange movie? No, it isn't nearly strange enough
   </titulo>
   <autor>
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/11/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Wow, dudes are falling over themselves to praise this movie on IMDb (as of this writing)! Maybe for, like, a "film buff" it's a big deal that somebody made such an aggressively chaotic movie? Whatever. If you're a comedy fan before you're a film fan, then you'll recognize that randomness is not absurdity, and that Schizopolis presents too much of the former. There are whole scenes wherein characters talk in gibberish, speaking real but ostensibly silly words--("nose army", "landmine")--that have no apparent connection to what's happening. And... that's all that's going on. It's like being expected to laugh solely because Weird Al Yankovic said "Albequerque". Some of the movie's lines and ideas are much sharper than this, but too much of its humor is at the pre-teen/grandpa level. It appears that absurdity is the central point of this movie--in other regards, Schizopolis isn't beautiful enough or comprehensible enough to matter very much. But unfortunately, on the whole, this movie is not much more than mildly odd.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The end, or a new beginning; Soderbergh's forgotten think-piece
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Graham Greene
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/8/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    An experiment; an attempt by Soderbergh to strip away the extraneous baggage of narrative cinema - and, in the process, the often debilitating obsessions with style and presentation - in order to get to the pure essence of film-making, as an outlet for spontaneous, creative expression. Soderbergh would subsequently refer to the finished product as a necessary purging; a way of going beyond the obsessive technical approach and over-reliance on the look and technique that had been so important to the atmosphere of his earliest work, so as to make possible the more liberated and immediate film-making approach of subsequent films such as Out of Sight (1998) and The Limey (1999). As a result, Schizopolis (1996) can now be seen as both the end and the beginning of something really quite wonderful; offering, as it does, the full stop following perhaps the most interesting and successful stage of the director's career - in which he developed on the cool and seductive Sex Lies and Videotape (1988), the dark and expressionistic Kafka (1991) and the underrated American masterpiece King of the Hill (1993) - and the start of a whole new chapter - in which the director found his greatest success with the highly acclaimed Erin Brockovich (2000), the Oscar winning Traffic (2000) and the hugely successful remake of Ocean's Eleven (2001). In keeping with this idea of purging, we can see with Schizopolis an attempt by Soderbergh to indulge all of his various creative quirks and eccentricities before simplifying his style and vision in a way that would be beneficial to a mainstream American audience. Although he would create similar indulgences since - including films like Full Frontal (2002), Bubble (2005) and The Good German (2006) - those particular films often feel like extra-curricular exercises that don't, in any real way, relate to his more successful endeavours, such as the Ocean's Twelve (2004) and Thirteen (2007) sequels and his adaptation of the Stanislaw Lem novel, Solaris (2002). Whereas those films hid their post-modern reinvention beneath knock-about farce or widescreen spectacle, Schizopolis is home-made, experimental cinema at its most explicit and unhinged. From the narrative set-up, to the casting, to the use of editing, music and mise-en-scene, the film is literally bursting with ideas and ingenious abstractions, with Soderbergh taking influence from a number of far greater filmmakers - such as his personal heroes, Terry Gilliam and Richard Lester, to legendary masters like Jacques Rivette and Jean Luc Godard - and yet, still manages to produce a piece of work that seems true to his own unique style and individual creative preoccupations. Naturally, given the nature of the film and the outlandishness of its characters and approach, Schizopolis often seesaws wildly from the inventive, to the stupid, to the genuinely inspired. It was and still remains a bold and daring work for the director; disregarding the lush cinematography and evocative period detail of Kafka and King of the Hill and instead developing the rough and ready, hand-held, matter-of-fact approach that he would continue to use on subsequent films like Traffic and The Limey. However, the presentation works, and the style of the film does well to convey certain themes and ideas that are expressed through the tone and opinions of a central character that is perfectly performed by the director himself. It also creates that feeling of something anarchic and aesthetically quite progressive; disregarding any such notions of box-office potential, industry trailblazing or self-congratulatory deconstruction to simply make a film that presents the pure, unfettered spirit, energy and imagination that only the very best of cinema can convey. It obviously won't be to all tastes - which goes without saying - but even so, I feel that Schizopolis is a truly unsung work within the director's career; stressing personal expression, ironic self-deprecation and genuine cinematic invention. As it stands over a decade on from its initial release, Schizopolis can now be seen as a relic to the days when Soderbergh could (for me at least) be cited as perhaps the greatest living filmmaker of his generation; with the film capturing the sense of diversity, energy and complete control over all aspects of the production that can be noted throughout his work released during the 1990's. His more recent films might be more financially successful (and certainly not without merit), but for me, they simply fail to offer that same sense of inimitable defiance, unpredictability and that eccentric disregard for convention that his work was once synonymous with. It may not be wholly triumphant overall - and is certainly not on a par with the likes of Kafka, King of the Hill and the greater than you might remember it Out of Sight - it is, nonetheless, a work of pure vision; both mesmerising and maddening in almost equal measure, and punctuated by Soderbergh's static, deadpan performance and the capricious idea that anything could happen at any given time.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of the worst movies I have ever seen
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ctrogue
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/8/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is such a bad case of a want to be 60's cult classic, yes it is very poorly made as a typical 60's low budget independently made movie. That's the problem!!! Steven Soderbergh had the bucks to make something dececent but not the imagination. I spent $27 for this movie because it was Criterion Collection and turned it off after 18 minutes. The movie I was watching prior to this was called Happenstance it showed far more imagination than any American movie made in the last 10 years! While I am venting on this crap movie, how the hell does the last Batman movie get to be number one, where are the standards that movie isn't even on DVD yet. How can it be the number one movie of all times when most of the people that voted on it could not have seen it more than once!!!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Generic Greeting!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Joseph Sylvers
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/6/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    An absurdist film, with a sense of humor, that's actually as laugh out loud funny as it is conceptually amusing. A lampooning of Scientology, relationships, the difficulties of communication, the film making business, the nightly news, corporate life and just about everything it touches. Steven Soderberg has made one of the zanniest comedies, in recent memory(I cant think of the last time I used the word zany in conversation). This is the film which restored Soderberg's creative powers after a series of slumps and a collapsing marriage, after which he would go on to Oceans 11 and infamy. These two quotes might better let you know what your in for. "Dear attractive woman number 2, only once in my life have I responded to a person the way I've responded to you, but I've forgotten when it was or even if it was in fact me that responded. I may not know much, but I know that the wind sings your name endlessly, although with a slight lisp that makes it difficult to understand if I'm standing near an air conditioner. I know that your hair sits atop your head as though it could sit nowhere else. I know that your figure would make a sculptor cast aside his tools, injuring his assistant who was looking out the window instead of paying attention. I know that your lips are as full as that sexy french model's that I desperately want to f*&k. I know that if for an instant I could have you lie next to me, or on top of me, or sit on me, or stand over me and shake, then I would be the happiest man in my pants. I know all of this, and yet you do not know me. Change your life; accept my love. Or, at least let me pay you to accept it." "Fletcher Munson: (sunnily, on homecoming) Generic greeting! Mrs. Munson: (warmly) Generic greeting returned! (they kiss and chuckle at each other) Fletcher Munson: Imminent sustenance. Mrs. Munson: Overly dramatic statement regarding upcoming meal. Fletcher Munson: Oooh! False reaction indicating hunger and excitement! Fletcher Munson: (wife snuggles up amorously) Ooh! *Really* well-rehearsed speech about workload and stress. (pause) Fletcher Munson: Genuine sorrow. Um... truthful-sounding promises of future satisfaction? Enticement to agree? Mrs. Munson: (pause) Accepted. Fletcher Munson: Gratitude." "A New Mexico woman was named Final Arbiter of Taste & Justice today, ending God's lengthy search for someone to straighten this country out. Eileen Harriet Palglace will have final say on every known subject, including who should be put to death, what clothes everyone should wear, what movies suck, and whether bald men who grow ponytails should still get laid."
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not for everyone, and that includes me
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Charles Herold (cherold)
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Schizopolis begins with this very funny speech by Soderbergh, and early on it looks a little like some sketch comedy show from the 70s like Kentucky Fried Movie. And definitely sketch comedy is an element of this. But it's sketch comedy that tries hard to not be too funny. Ideas like a couple exchanging generic greetings are clever but no more than mildly amusing, and I think that's what the movie is going for; it doesn't want comedy to override experimental weirdness. The movie is also careful to avoid feeling too much like it has a linear story. Yes, we do follow characters through a story arc, but this is done in a purposefully disjointed manner. The pieces for something genuinely entertaining are there, but the director clearly wants something that is more challenging than enjoyable. And to certain people, that will make it more enjoyable. But I'm not one of those people. For me, it was a clever but rather tedious experiment.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An interesting and fun experiment
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mike-seaman
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Explaining Schizopolis seems counterintuitive. The movie is a mixture of autobiographical self- examination and self-deprecation. At the same time the film seems to be tackling some larger cultural themes and postmodern concepts of language and communication. In the end, I think the movie is a fun assortment of ideas being exercised together in a rather harmless fashion. Schizopolis never seems to take itself seriously, the movie is made on a small-budget, with a purposefully contained cast, self-aware and referential humor, taking stabs at life, narratives, movies, culture, and humanity while never entirely aiming at any single target (except perhaps the filmmaker himself). I recommend this movie not because it is a fully realized concept (because it isn't) or because it is a hidden gem that must be discovered (because it isn't) but it is refreshing to see an experimental film created playfully, aware of its self-indulgence and entirely at ease with it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Being Steven Soderbergh
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    CinefanR
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/4/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Movies like Lost Highway, American Beauty and other high-profile, big-budget productions have been praised for their original takes, but in fact it was "Schizopolis" that explored those possibilities first. I find it refreshing and inexplicably underrated. The film is a very funny and bizarre look into the creative mind of its author, Steven Soderbergh. Press conferences on horse urination, marital dissolution, dysfunctional families, work, love, death, identity, the hilarious (and tragic) absurdity of life everything is scrutinized here under a mask of randomness which makes everything unpredictable and crazy funny. "Schizopolis" gleefully delves into the absurd and blends it with satire in a most original social commentary, mocking all conventions and confinements. This type of humor is my kind. For fans of Kafka, Eugene Ionesco and Urmuz, Samuel Beckett, Kurt Vonnegut or David Lynch, this will be a blast. On a third viewing, all this "mess" makes perfect sense, and it's beautiful. "Sneeze!"
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Very Disappointing
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Bob_Jenkem
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/8/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I wanted to like "Schizopolis" but ended up ultimately finding it to be a very slow, pretentious, and boring movie. The first forty minutes-or-so are funny, but the second half of the movie is like watching paint dry, and the movie seems to go on much longer than it actually is. While it has a germ of an idea, Soderbergh makes one grave screen writing error around the 50-minute mark (and I'm aware this film was improvised - exactly my point), when he suddenly introduces a new main character (played by the director, who plays both characters) that takes up the rest of the movie, with almost no reference to the previous main character. By the time he shows up again in the last ten minutes, he's speaking Japanese. Why? (I know it's supposed to symbolize that the character and his wife are distant, but it's INCREDIBLY heavy-handed). For that matter, why do characters constantly speak in non-sequitors? No reason is given. Any chance at character development is killed, and the whole movie comes tumbling down. I understand he wanted to be abstract and surrealistic, but the complete lack of storytelling structure as a basis for using abstract surrealism makes the movie boring. The only good parts are the interstitial news bulletins, and there are moments of creative filmmaking in it. But overall, it's a snoozefest. But what a great title. Some funny lines in it too ("What was your last co-worker's name?" "Oh, Nameless Numberhead Man?"). This was the first Steven Soderbergh film I've seen. I won't be rushing out to watch his other movies.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    one of a kind
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mglasson
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/5/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Schizopolis is perhaps best summarized with the copy line - 'All attempts at synopses of this film have resulted in hospitalization.' It's no understatement - just about every convention and niche of film is broken in this flick, and those looking for an easy ride into movie-watching oblivion won't find it here. The film mainly revolves around ad exec Fletcher Munson (played to perfection by Soderbergh) who is unhappy in his work, marriage and life, in general. He frequently masturbates at his office job and is generally distracted by his active imagination. After a co-worker suddenly has a heart attack, Munson is stuck writing a speech for T. Azimuth Schwitters - an L. Ron Hubbard type guru who sells a brand of self-help called 'Eventualism.' One day, Munson spots his doppelganger and follows him to his home. Turns out this fella is a dentist, and, without any clear reason, he is suddenly transported into Dr. Jeffery Kortchack's body and assumes the dentist's life (which includes having an affair with his own wife from his existence as Fletcher Munson). Confused yet? Then there is also the story of Elmo, the exterminator who speaks in a language of random words (I.E., 'Jigsaw. Uh, fragment chief butter. King surgery mind??') and gets laid by all of his beautiful women clients. Language is altered and skewed throughout the film - one scene has the husband and wife exchanging analytically defined sentences ('Generic greeting!' 'Generic greeting returned!') And yes, it gets much stranger, but that is one of the many wonderful things this film has going for it - you will be completely uncertain as to what is next coming. I can do no justice trying to explain the plot; the above encapsulation is an infinitesimally small fraction of the entire story and all of its interwoven subplots, thereof. So, what the hell does it all mean? I can't say that I'm entirely sure, myself, but I always have one helluva good time riding through it. There are endless side-stories and (seemingly) left-over ideas conceived through a myriad of supremely clever and bizarre film devices. It's a jarring experience at first, but with repeated viewing, the unconnected pieces of information come together in a most surprising and rewarding fashion. To me, Schizopolis is the cinematic equivalent of a Rubic's cube - you may fumble with it for a long time, but when you finally get a side complete - Ahhh, the joy and relief of a job well done. Yet, there are five other sides that remain mixed. Soderbergh took several years to make this film completely outside of the Hollywood machine ('I was in danger of becoming a hack,' he said) So he mounted this indie-indie-independent labor of love in the vein of a guerrilla production - a project he was literally shooting in his own back yard and at the houses of friends and neighbors. Still, the film never feels like its cheating the audience because of its budget limitations. Whatever it is that he's trying to do within the film's cryptic scenes, he manages to pull off with the confidence that he knows what he's doing. Steven Soderbergh also plays the leading man - a choice more practical than really desired according to him, but his performance is amazingly funny (the scene where he's making faces at himself in the mirror is a keeper for all time). He also cast his recently separated wife (Betsy Brantley) as his wife in the film, echoing his own a personal dilemma. And though this film embraces obfuscation and absurdity, have I mentioned that it's ridiculously hilarious? This is a cross-brand of comedy that I have never-before-seen. It's kinda like the Marx Brothers directed by Richard Lester on acid. But all insipid cross-comparisons aside, I feel like there's little room for improvement in this grandiose experimental film. There may be some minor performance flaws or uneven pacing, but in a film that embraces lack of coherence, that's hardly stable grounds for critique. This film was readily dissed by critics (if an established director does something completely off the wall and confusing, it must be self-indulgent), and the 12 people that actually saw it, abhorred it (any film that has people walking out after 20 minutes must have something going for it). So do yourself (and Mr. Soderbergh) a favor and seek this one out. Accept the challenge that this film proposes and try putting this puzzle together. Not that there's any doubt about this now given his expansive oeuvre, but Steven Soderbergh is one of the leading revolutionaries working in cinema today.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Duals
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tedg (tedg@FilmsFolded.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/2/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I am glad that Soderbergh is making films, even if every other one is a glossy mess. Like many filmmakers, he lives in and loves the medium. Unlike most of them, he experiments in film with things that matter  and he does it while pretending it is a joke. This will be seen by many as a bizarre hoax, a vanity project, a sandbox. But I think not; I receive it as a small, complex personal project. His marriage was falling apart. He was baffled by matters of duality: simultaneous understanding and confusion. So he made a film featuring himself and his already ex-wife. In it, time faces itself; everyone has dual lives among which they shift. You'll only get part of what is going on the first time around, but this rewards multiple viewings. Ted's Evaluation -- 3 of 3: Worth watching.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Is this such a strange movie? No, it isn't nearly strange enough
   </titulo>
   <autor>
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/11/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Wow, dudes are falling over themselves to praise this movie on IMDb (as of this writing)! Maybe for, like, a "film buff" it's a big deal that somebody made such an aggressively chaotic movie? Whatever. If you're a comedy fan before you're a film fan, then you'll recognize that randomness is not absurdity, and that Schizopolis presents too much of the former. There are whole scenes wherein characters talk in gibberish, speaking real but ostensibly silly words--("nose army", "landmine")--that have no apparent connection to what's happening. And... that's all that's going on. It's like being expected to laugh solely because Weird Al Yankovic said "Albequerque". Some of the movie's lines and ideas are much sharper than this, but too much of its humor is at the pre-teen/grandpa level. It appears that absurdity is the central point of this movie--in other regards, Schizopolis isn't beautiful enough or comprehensible enough to matter very much. But unfortunately, on the whole, this movie is not much more than mildly odd.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The end, or a new beginning; Soderbergh's forgotten think-piece
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Graham Greene
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/8/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    An experiment; an attempt by Soderbergh to strip away the extraneous baggage of narrative cinema - and, in the process, the often debilitating obsessions with style and presentation - in order to get to the pure essence of film-making, as an outlet for spontaneous, creative expression. Soderbergh would subsequently refer to the finished product as a necessary purging; a way of going beyond the obsessive technical approach and over-reliance on the look and technique that had been so important to the atmosphere of his earliest work, so as to make possible the more liberated and immediate film-making approach of subsequent films such as Out of Sight (1998) and The Limey (1999). As a result, Schizopolis (1996) can now be seen as both the end and the beginning of something really quite wonderful; offering, as it does, the full stop following perhaps the most interesting and successful stage of the director's career - in which he developed on the cool and seductive Sex Lies and Videotape (1988), the dark and expressionistic Kafka (1991) and the underrated American masterpiece King of the Hill (1993) - and the start of a whole new chapter - in which the director found his greatest success with the highly acclaimed Erin Brockovich (2000), the Oscar winning Traffic (2000) and the hugely successful remake of Ocean's Eleven (2001). In keeping with this idea of purging, we can see with Schizopolis an attempt by Soderbergh to indulge all of his various creative quirks and eccentricities before simplifying his style and vision in a way that would be beneficial to a mainstream American audience. Although he would create similar indulgences since - including films like Full Frontal (2002), Bubble (2005) and The Good German (2006) - those particular films often feel like extra-curricular exercises that don't, in any real way, relate to his more successful endeavours, such as the Ocean's Twelve (2004) and Thirteen (2007) sequels and his adaptation of the Stanislaw Lem novel, Solaris (2002). Whereas those films hid their post-modern reinvention beneath knock-about farce or widescreen spectacle, Schizopolis is home-made, experimental cinema at its most explicit and unhinged. From the narrative set-up, to the casting, to the use of editing, music and mise-en-scene, the film is literally bursting with ideas and ingenious abstractions, with Soderbergh taking influence from a number of far greater filmmakers - such as his personal heroes, Terry Gilliam and Richard Lester, to legendary masters like Jacques Rivette and Jean Luc Godard - and yet, still manages to produce a piece of work that seems true to his own unique style and individual creative preoccupations. Naturally, given the nature of the film and the outlandishness of its characters and approach, Schizopolis often seesaws wildly from the inventive, to the stupid, to the genuinely inspired. It was and still remains a bold and daring work for the director; disregarding the lush cinematography and evocative period detail of Kafka and King of the Hill and instead developing the rough and ready, hand-held, matter-of-fact approach that he would continue to use on subsequent films like Traffic and The Limey. However, the presentation works, and the style of the film does well to convey certain themes and ideas that are expressed through the tone and opinions of a central character that is perfectly performed by the director himself. It also creates that feeling of something anarchic and aesthetically quite progressive; disregarding any such notions of box-office potential, industry trailblazing or self-congratulatory deconstruction to simply make a film that presents the pure, unfettered spirit, energy and imagination that only the very best of cinema can convey. It obviously won't be to all tastes - which goes without saying - but even so, I feel that Schizopolis is a truly unsung work within the director's career; stressing personal expression, ironic self-deprecation and genuine cinematic invention. As it stands over a decade on from its initial release, Schizopolis can now be seen as a relic to the days when Soderbergh could (for me at least) be cited as perhaps the greatest living filmmaker of his generation; with the film capturing the sense of diversity, energy and complete control over all aspects of the production that can be noted throughout his work released during the 1990's. His more recent films might be more financially successful (and certainly not without merit), but for me, they simply fail to offer that same sense of inimitable defiance, unpredictability and that eccentric disregard for convention that his work was once synonymous with. It may not be wholly triumphant overall - and is certainly not on a par with the likes of Kafka, King of the Hill and the greater than you might remember it Out of Sight - it is, nonetheless, a work of pure vision; both mesmerising and maddening in almost equal measure, and punctuated by Soderbergh's static, deadpan performance and the capricious idea that anything could happen at any given time.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of the worst movies I have ever seen
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ctrogue
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/8/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is such a bad case of a want to be 60's cult classic, yes it is very poorly made as a typical 60's low budget independently made movie. That's the problem!!! Steven Soderbergh had the bucks to make something dececent but not the imagination. I spent $27 for this movie because it was Criterion Collection and turned it off after 18 minutes. The movie I was watching prior to this was called Happenstance it showed far more imagination than any American movie made in the last 10 years! While I am venting on this crap movie, how the hell does the last Batman movie get to be number one, where are the standards that movie isn't even on DVD yet. How can it be the number one movie of all times when most of the people that voted on it could not have seen it more than once!!!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Generic Greeting!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Joseph Sylvers
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/6/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    An absurdist film, with a sense of humor, that's actually as laugh out loud funny as it is conceptually amusing. A lampooning of Scientology, relationships, the difficulties of communication, the film making business, the nightly news, corporate life and just about everything it touches. Steven Soderberg has made one of the zanniest comedies, in recent memory(I cant think of the last time I used the word zany in conversation). This is the film which restored Soderberg's creative powers after a series of slumps and a collapsing marriage, after which he would go on to Oceans 11 and infamy. These two quotes might better let you know what your in for. "Dear attractive woman number 2, only once in my life have I responded to a person the way I've responded to you, but I've forgotten when it was or even if it was in fact me that responded. I may not know much, but I know that the wind sings your name endlessly, although with a slight lisp that makes it difficult to understand if I'm standing near an air conditioner. I know that your hair sits atop your head as though it could sit nowhere else. I know that your figure would make a sculptor cast aside his tools, injuring his assistant who was looking out the window instead of paying attention. I know that your lips are as full as that sexy french model's that I desperately want to f*&k. I know that if for an instant I could have you lie next to me, or on top of me, or sit on me, or stand over me and shake, then I would be the happiest man in my pants. I know all of this, and yet you do not know me. Change your life; accept my love. Or, at least let me pay you to accept it." "Fletcher Munson: (sunnily, on homecoming) Generic greeting! Mrs. Munson: (warmly) Generic greeting returned! (they kiss and chuckle at each other) Fletcher Munson: Imminent sustenance. Mrs. Munson: Overly dramatic statement regarding upcoming meal. Fletcher Munson: Oooh! False reaction indicating hunger and excitement! Fletcher Munson: (wife snuggles up amorously) Ooh! *Really* well-rehearsed speech about workload and stress. (pause) Fletcher Munson: Genuine sorrow. Um... truthful-sounding promises of future satisfaction? Enticement to agree? Mrs. Munson: (pause) Accepted. Fletcher Munson: Gratitude." "A New Mexico woman was named Final Arbiter of Taste & Justice today, ending God's lengthy search for someone to straighten this country out. Eileen Harriet Palglace will have final say on every known subject, including who should be put to death, what clothes everyone should wear, what movies suck, and whether bald men who grow ponytails should still get laid."
   </conteudo>
  </review>
 </reviews>
</filme>
