<filme>
 <id>
  159
 </id>
 <imdburl>
  http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0103772
 </imdburl>
 <ano>
  1992
 </ano>
 <titulo>
  Instinto Selvagem
 </titulo>
 <rating>
  6.9
 </rating>
 <sinopse>
  A police detective is in charge of the investigation of a brutal murder, in which a beautiful and seductive woman could be involved.
 </sinopse>
 <storyline>
  A former rock star, Johnny Boz, is brutally killed during sex, and the case is assigned to detective Nick Curran of the SFPD. During the investigation, Nick meets Catherine Tramell, a crime novelist who was Boz's girlfriend when he died. Catherine proves to be a very clever and manipulative woman, and though Nick is more or less convinced that she murdered Boz, he is unable to find any evidence. Later, when Nilsen, Nick's rival in the police, is killed, Nick suspects of Catherine's involvement in it. He then starts to play a dangerous lust-filled mind game with Catherine to nail her, but as their relationship progresses, the body count rises and contradicting evidences force Nick to start questioning his own suspicions about Catherine's guilt.
 </storyline>
 <generos>
  <genero>
   Mystery
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Thriller
  </genero>
 </generos>
 <keywords>
  <keyword>
   suspect
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   detective
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   rock star
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   police
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   murder
  </keyword>
 </keywords>
 <diretores>
  <diretor>
   Paul Verhoeven
  </diretor>
 </diretores>
 <escritores>
  <escritor>
   Joe Eszterhas
  </escritor>
 </escritores>
 <atores>
  <ator>
   Michael Douglas
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Sharon Stone
  </ator>
  <ator>
   George Dzundza
  </ator>
 </atores>
 <reviews>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Guilty Pleasure.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    AaronCapenBanner
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Michael Douglas plays San Francisco detective Nick Curran, who is investigating the brutal icepick murder of rock star Johnny Boz, which leads him to his girlfriend, novelist Catherine Tramell(Sharon Stone, unforgettable) Nick, though suspicious of Catherine, is nonetheless attracted to her brazen sensuality, and they begin a torrid affair, even though more murders pile up, and Catherine proves to be quite manipulative and intelligent...is she guilty? Controversial film directed by Paul Verhoeven is never boring, though normally having no one in the story to root for would be a problem, film is so slickly made and in-your-face that it may be the epitome of the guilty pleasure; trashy yet enjoyable. Both lead actors are excellent though, even if the mystery is never satisfactorily resolved.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    thrilling till the end
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    acpaloveshavefun
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I recently re saw this movie, and if your a thriller fan you'll absolutely love it. I was at the edge of my seat the entire time, trying to see if I can solve it. Definitely not for kids by the way. Please do not listen for the old bittys out there who are saying that This movie is porn,if I remember correctly the movie psycho had the infamous shower scene. yes its violent and yes it has sexual content, and "Adult situation" but that's what makes a really good movie. This was a perfect example of a great movie before everyone became so politically correct. If you can't handle this as an adult, go live with the Amish, is definitely not for you.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Unsatisfying
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    leonlouisricci
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    There is so much here that is unresolved that it leaves an empty, unfulfilled feeling that the viewer has been suckered. Endless nude and sex scenes intrude on the mystery plot and in the end it is all for not much. Infamous for its explicit exploitation of said sex and nudity and forever frustrating for that's pretty much all there is. The soft-porn aside it can be a somewhat sultry, trashy ride with enough intrigue to keep the interest but not enough to make it a totally engaging entertainment. The biggest problem is the ambiguity about most of what unfolds. There are dangling plot elements and shallow, confusing side shows. In all, it is a murky, muddy, and thin piece of Pulp that has modern machinations and push the envelope displays of Crime Fiction laced with so much pomp that it's rendered impotent. The Movie has enough sizzle to attract viewers but cannot justify all the indulgence and will most likely be an unsatisfactory guilty pleasure. It is quite an overrated Film whose appeal comes from the most lowbrow lexicons of entertainment. But hey, someone once said...there's one born every minute. That's a lot of ticket buyers.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    While its premise is promising, "Basic Instinct" is executed in an inconsistent manner
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Chris Mizerak
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    There are many aspects, both good and bad, that you can pick up from Paul Verhoeven's 1992 erotic thriller Basic Instinct. On one hand, the premise of the film is kind of interesting and has a certain amount of complexity to it. Also, the film works okay enough as far as erotic films go with Sharon Stone flaunting out her body. On the other hand, the film is really cheesy and over-the-top at times as well as really dull in others. So if you're guessing that I think this film has an inconsistent feel to it, you'd probably be right. Basic Instinct follows a police detective (Michael Douglas) with a troubling past who is trying to solve the recent murder of a rock and roll star. The only eligible suspect so far is a book writer (Sharon Stone), whose stories are about women murdering men, who was the last person to see him. One of her own stories seems to play out in the same way that this victim was murdered. Naturally, the police suspects that she did it. The plot thickens however when the detective falls in love with the writer and learns some new developments about the case. In case I haven't mentioned it in any of my earlier reviews, let me get this off my chest. With a few exceptions, I really do not care at all for films centered on police detectives, cops or characters involved in similar professions since I find them to be boring, forgettable, and formulaic. While there are exceptions that either have interesting cases or characters, the rest of them just don't do a thing for me especially in terms of story, characters, and dialogue. Keeping that in mind, while I find whatever takes place in the police department to be fairly formulaic, it wasn't boring and whatever dialogue was being said wasn't as much torture to listen to as I thought it was going to be. I thought it was going to be too difficult to understand what was being said like other films of this genre, but luckily it was easy to understand what was being said, so that must count for something. On top of that, the story has a reasonably intriguing complexity to it and so do the two main characters. The hero and villain in this film are not clear cut, which is fairly authentic of real life. In reality, it's not crystal clear who the heroes and villains are, one culture may consider certain "heroes" villains, and vice versa. In other words, the screenplay was wise enough to put that aspect into the story. If you go see this film solely for looking at Sharon Stone's physique, you won't be disappointed since she really looks good in this film. I wouldn't be surprised if some viewers were reminded of the blonde women Alfred Hitchcock used in his pictures especially Kim Novak. I know I detected some similarities in terms of looks and wardrobe between Stone and the typical blondes Hitchcock used in his films. From what I've said so far, it sounds like this should be a good movie given my personal tastes. But sadly, Basic Instinct is one of those films in which the premise alone is better than the actual execution. One huge issue I had with Basic Instinct is the quality of the acting. I found the acting in this picture to be really weak. While the characters of the two leads are fascinating, the performances aren't executed well enough to do justice to the written characters. I also don't find the two leads (especially Douglas) either that believable or even that subtle/natural with their delivery. Furthermore, the performance by Jeanne Tripplehorn as a psychiatrist helping out Douglas' character is especially unconvincing, considering that I never believed that her character had enough experience in studying psychology to the point were she would become a professional one at such a young age. I simply didn't buy it at all, and the only point to her character existing in this film is solely for a plot twist that is used later in the film. I think she was of no importance to the plot whatsoever. Because of the disappointing acting quality, I don't really buy whatever ludicrous events take place in the plot as a result. Therefore, I can't take anything in the plot as seriously as the film seems to want me to. While the screenplay has its fair share of intriguing elements, there are also some elements of the screenplay especially with its dialogue that feels really cheesy and doesn't even sound the slightest bit realistic. As a result, that's how the film becomes inconsistent in terms of its delivery. In a nutshell, Basic Instinct definitely seems to be a mixed bag. While it has a good idea of what it wants to be, it seldom delivers on the promises it makes mainly because the acting is so mediocre to the point where it interferes with my ability to believe what's happening on screen. I'd only recommend this film if you're solely interested in checking out Stone's body. It's not much of an endorsement, but that's the highest praise I can give to this flick.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Murder All Around Her
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bkoganbing
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Although most reviewers have concentrated on the leads, Basic Instinct has some other fine performances in it. Still Michael Douglas as the sex obsessed cop and Sharon Stone as the amoral, multi-sexual woman who seems to have murder all around her give some iconic performances. A couple of SFPD detectives who played TV detectives, Michael Douglas in Streets Of San Francisco and George Dzundza in Law And Order, get assigned to the homicide of a former rockstar icon. The man had as the story tells us the 'coital moment of the century' before he died and as Michael Douglas finds out with Sharon Stone his prime suspect. It's not like Douglas hasn't any issues himself, he's seeing the SFPD shrink Jeanne Tripplehorn. One of those issues apparently is professional detachment as gets involved with both Tripplehorn and Stone. Far worse with Stone as she is a suspect. Murders in the past and murders in the present seem to pop up whenever Stone is around. She's an heiress to a fortune, a psychology major from college and licensed and an author of lurid novels. She knows how to press the buttons of both sexes and soon enough Douglas is in her world. The only one keeping a professional detachment is Dzundza who is not thinking with his male member. Even when an Internal Affairs cop who is investigating Douglas is murdered, Dzundza sticks by his partner. See what it gets him. In fact Dzundza and Tripplehorn don't get near enough credit for their work here. I think most know Tripplehorn as I do for playing Tom Cruise's wife in The Firm. She too is a woman with a lot of issues. As for George Dzundza as the only one in the film actually who seems to be normal, the others all seem to play off him. Still Sharon Stone's career was launched with what she did in Basic Instinct. This woman will wind up President of the USA or on death row, no middle ground for her. And you can believe she's every man and woman's coital moment of a lifetime. I don't know how successful or how good Basic Instinct 2 was, but seeing this has given me an incentive to see the sequel.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Bill Hicks and my Basic instinct was right, it's an unpleasant film.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ironhorse_iv
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It's sad to say that sex sells. Basic Instinct without a doubt sells, but it's just a sexy thriller that's got plenty of libido but not nearly as much brains as it thinks it has. It's extremely misogynistic and is very predictable. I was very disappointed with the whole movie, and had figured out the murderer within about 30 minutes into it. It's titillating, even exciting at times, but ultimately collapses under the weight of its own stupidity. The movie contained a lot of graphic sexual acts throughout the movie that makes it more of a soft porn movie in disguise & less than a film noir. It could have been better, if it cut down on the exotic a bit, and focus more on the story and give us a challenge. In the film's opening, Rockstar Boz is stabbed to death by a blonde woman with an ice pick during sex. We never see the woman's face -- just her blonde hair and, of course, most of her lust-inducing body. By just looking at the body of the killer, you can pretty much know who did it. The police find the dead body, and Det. Nick Curran, (Michael Douglas) was put on the case whom slept with his police-appointed shrink Dr. Beth Garner (Jeanne Triplehorn). Rather than getting a DNA test on the number one- suspect, Boz's girlfriend, Catherine Tramell (Sharon Stone), a famous crime novelist, the cops interview her. I know DNA testing was still in its early stages in the early '90s but convicting using DNA evidence alone has been proved fact since 1988, four years when the film was set. Well, Catherine use the interview to make fools out of them. The way she manipulates psychology was superbly awesome. Without Sharon Stone as femme fatale, this movie is nothing. Still, most people would remember from this scene just the famous leg switching, and not the acting. Although, the detectives were too stupid to realize that there is something about her that doesn't add up. We sees Catherine using it to break ice during the film. She even mentions how her book is about a detective falling for the wrong woman and that she kills him. Isn't it very clear who the killer is? Sooner than later, Nick get into Catherine's sex life. The movie moves with the suspense involving Nick and Catherine. He's supposed to be following this woman as a suspect but is actually falling for her deadly charm since Nick is dumb like the other cops. Clearly this film points out the men are just horny dumb pervs who slept before duty. The film tries to do a lot of dumb red herrings such as Beth is revealed to have had a past sexual encounter with Catherine, that according to Catherine developed an obsessive fixation on her as Beth copy her. The audience is suppose to wonder whether Beth killed Boz as is described in Catherine's book to frame her. Not once in the film, does Beth show any bit of bi or lesbians feelings. Catherine does with a girl name Roxy (Leilani Sarelle). The film was strongly opposed by gay rights activists, who criticized the film's portrayal of bisexual women as a murderous sociopaths. The featurette Blond Poison reveals the uproar the film caused during the San Francisco filming. They deplored it as being "anti-gay" and a reinforcement of Hollywood homophobia due to typecasting particularly lesbians as twisted and evil, or just act lesbians to get men's horny. I think the heterosexuals can also be equally offensive, as some feminists like Camille Paglia starts breaking things down to banal symbolisms, the opening killing with the ice pick is interpreted as, "Woman steals man's penis and uses it against him." men find themselves involuntarily cringing. Freudian Pscyhoanalysts have retained the term instinct that the film refer to human motivational forces (such as sex and aggression), sometimes represented as Eros - life instinct and Thanatos- death Instinct, but the real term is motivational forces or drives to correct the original error in the translation of Freud's work. Psychologist Abraham Maslow argued that humans no longer have instincts because we have the ability to override them in certain situations. For Maslow, an instinct is something which cannot be overridden, & therefore while the term may have applied to humans in the past, it no longer does. So the film should be title 'Basic Drives". It's clear why Joe Eszterhas was paid 3-million bucks for his script with its clever plot construction. Still there are pointless sequences like where Nick and Catherine engage in a car chase for no discernible reason other than to serve as a dire attempt to jack up the energy level. The film also has unlikeable characters. The hero Nick viciously rapes Beth in one scene. They're perfectly acceptable in the art of film, but Basic Instinct did go a little overboard with that sex. The film does good with its abstract images, the way it's shot from different angles, made it a little more elliptical, a bit less direct. The eerie Jerry Goldsmith theme gives the film a creepy tone. Basic Instinct was to transfers Mr. Verhoeven's flair for action-oriented material to the realm of Hitchcockian intrigue, but the results are so-so. Following the success of the film, Ezsterhas & Verhoeven went on to collaborate on Showgirls. (Another horrible mess). Since release, the blue-ray version add more graphic violence & sex into the film.This film is an affront to taste. It's an over-baked mind control fantasy, brought to life by a horrible script, and relieved of meaning by a hair brained plot. It's all Tougue in cheek really like a perv. It's depends on your kicks.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I'd have to be pretty stupid to write a book about killing and then kill him the way I described in my book. I'd be announcing myself as the killer. I'm not stupid.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    JohnRouseMerriottChard
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Basic Instinct is directed by Paul Verhoeven and written by Joe Eszterhaz. It stars Michael Douglas, Sharon Stone, George Dzundza, Jeanne Tripplehorn, Denis Arndt and Leilani Sarelle. Music is scored by Jerry Goldsmith and cinematography by Jan de Bont. Nick Curran (Douglas) of the SFPD is strung out and under investigation by Internal Affairs, last thing he needs is to be drawn into a dangerous relationship with a sex crazed blonde who may be a murderess... Time hasn't been kind to Verhoeven's soft-core porn thriller, where once was shock and awe killings (the film opening with a brutal mini ice-pick murder), steamy love scenes and a famed and controversial crotch shot, now is ludicrous orgasms, iffy effects and Michael Douglas' unappetising ass! Hell there was even protests during the film's initial theatre run as the gay community went up in arms about the portrayal of bisexuals possibly being mad murderers? Yet for all of its taming over the years, Basic Instinct can at least now been seen as the hugely efficient mystery thriller that it is, one that is propelled by some very good performances by the principal actors. The strength in the story is not in the sex or blood, but in the character arcs of Nick Curran and Catherine Tramell (Stone). Curran is a man perched on the edge of doom who is controlled totally by the women around him. He is by definition a quintessential film noir protagonist, in so deep he ultimately will be resigned to his fate. Catharine Tramell is a ultimate femme fatale, beautiful and seductive, she's always in control, leading all male characters where she wants them to go. There's a delicious kink to the narrative, with Verhoeven gleefully pulling the strings, a smirk no doubt etched onto his face. This is very good story telling, with a plot of substantial twists and turns. True, it does carry some soft-core baggage that can steer the restless away from the character strengths within, but for the neo-noir crowd there is much to enjoy here. 7.5/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Sharon Stone's finest hour
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    moviestar26
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    'Basic Instinct' was a film that rebooted the noir genre after it became rare in the early eighties. Prior to this the Coen brother's 'Blood Simple' attempted to revive the genre, but the industry was changing with the shift in audience's movie preferences. However this is more akin to being a sex thriller which also happens to incorporate a suspense element. 'Basic Instinct' takes the viewer back in time to the golden era of cinema when the femme fatales were glamorising the screen and became every male's dream fantasy. The film has been considered a classic and has not dated with time. The theme has been beautifully been One of my cult classic favourites from the 1990s. Whenever I catch a scene randomly on television, it brings back nostalgic memories of my childhood. I can still remember waking in the middle of the night just so I could record this movie secretly on my VCR. This is the movie that catapulted stone's career to international stardom. She immediately became a sex symbol and every man began dreaming of her. She immortalised a role that was so deep in characterisation. 'Catherine Trammel' was someone that was not only devious but smart, clever and manipulative. A role model so to speak that will certainly serve as an influence to many aspiring actresses and writers in the future. The role possessed every element that a negative character would have. Joe Esterhas is the writer. Previously he wrote 'Flash dance' and 'jagged edge' Most of his themes are similar. All negative roles about killers and murderers. 'Showgirls' and 'Jade' were also adapted for the screen. Unfortunately they failed at the box office and did not work. I think the audiences had higher expectations. 'Basic Instinct' has a fantastic script. This is the reason why the film worked. And then there is Paul Verhoeven who is a well known director in his home land. He has beautifully combined sex with the suspense genre. I am not very familiar with his Dutch movies. But he always had the style of depicting the theme of 'sex' as a weapon. I enjoyed the movie immensely, and being more of a reader than a movie- goer I jumped at the chance to read the book subsequent to seeing the motion picture. However, I feel that much of which made the movie great owes gratitude to the incredible soundtrack, imagery and skill of the actors; sometimes movies can be successfully novelised, but with Basic Instinct being the stimulus-rich move that it is I feel this was a failed attempt. The characters come off as threadbare and unexplored, lacking in depth or substance of any kind, and the seductively dark tone of the movie is lost on the page; it becomes rather humdrum and glancing, as if each page were written to keep up with the flow of the movie to be read within the hour. Where I was hoping to see some of the twisted, genius logic of Catherine Tramell explored on the page instead I found her to be de-powered, humanised and lacking of a great deal of her appeal as a result. It's worth the read for big fans of the Basic Instinct movies if only to explore the idea through a different form of media, (SPOILER) A San Francisco police detective who is investigated the murder of a retired rock star. The main suspect happens to be a novelist. She is under suspicion. She is released due to lack of evidence. Meanwhile the detective has maintains his belief that she is involved. He decides to pursue her and monitor her movements. The deeper his investigation proceeds, he succumbs to her charm and falls in love in spite knowing he is risking his life. His infatuation distances him from people around him and he refuses to listen to others. People he know become murdered. Eventually he finds it difficult to accept that she is a murderer as he begins to doubt his psychiatrist's past. (END OF SPOILER) The film is made with a sexy noir thriller tone. It brings back memories of Lawrence Kasden's 'Body Heat'. This was the last time a lead actress made an impression with a memorable role. Kathleen Turner became a popular star. At many moments the film feels like a horror thriller. There are many scenes that evoke a frightening feeling. What makes 'Basic Instinct' so unique is we are watching a women manipulating us with her attractive appeal that makes us want to believe she can be a killer. Her seductive charm works on the male protagonist, which leads to confusion. At the end we are eager to want to see her apprehended because we are disgusted how someone can desire to get away with murder for no reason. The sex scenes were unique and were the closest that could be categorised as 'soft porn'. This was one of the appealing factors that mad the film a success. 'Basic Instinct' has sustained it's quality over the years. It has managed to preserve it's quality and has not paled in front of movies that released recently. Due credit goes to Sharon Stone's performance and a winning script by Esterhas. The movie does follow true to the noir conventions. Anyone who is familiar with this will be able to notice them. However some of the typical noir rules were missing. There was no themes related to adultery or blackmailing. But it's relevance or lack of it doesn't seem significant as the this was a character driven film. Jerry Goldsmith's background score is specifically suited to the film's mood and atmosphere. It is still memorable and has different shades throughout the movie. It blends well with scenes and evokes the intriguing and haunting feeling.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Classic Verhoeven outrageousness.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    BA_Harrison
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/9/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Despite being built around the most 'basic' of plots, erotic thriller Basic Instinct remains director Paul Verhoeven's biggest commercial success, being one of the highest grossing titles of 1992. Unperturbed by the protestations of gay activists and uptight censor-happy moralists, who objected to the film's provocative cocktail of graphic sex and violence and its portrayal of bisexuals as crazed killers, the general public flocked to the cinema to revel in Verhoeven's heady concoction of wanton lust and cold-blooded violence. Written by Joe Eszterhas of Flashdance fame, the script is slick Hollywood nonsense, a flashy, trashy, twisting, turning tale clearly inspired by Hitchcock and the film-noir genre. Frequently teetering on the brink of preposterousness, its is precisely the kind of far-fetched nonsense that only a true maverick like Verhoeven could do justice toand boy, does he pull out all the stops here... Never one to do things by halves, the Dutch director opens his film as he means to go on, with a brutal murder that takes place during intercourse, a physically flawless blonde viciously stabbing her lover to death with an ice-pick. Scorching sex combined with gut churning nastiness, it's a real shocker (use the freeze-frame check out the outrageous shot of the pick going through the victim's nose!!!) and a clear indicator that this is to be no run-of-the-mill Hollywood thriller. The remainder of the film follows troubled detective Nick Curran (Michae Douglas) as he investigates the murder, stupidly becoming involved with his prime suspect, scorching hot, super intelligent, highly manipulative crime novelist Catherine Tramell (Sharon Stone), who may or may not be lining him up as her latest victim. Cue plenty more raunchy, near the knuckle nookie (including some rough rumpy-pumpy with the very sexy Jeanne 'gives me the' Tripplehorn), a few more gruesome deaths, a smidgen of exciting, pulse-pounding action, and the film's infamous blink-and-you'll miss-it shot of Stone's kebab as she uncrosses her legs during a police interview, all of which adds up to a whole heap of unmissable, jaw-dropping, eye-opening, big budget fun the likes of which we might never see again (unless Verhoeven can get Hollywood to forget all about Showgirls).
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "Good Seductive Thriller!"
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gwnightscream
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/9/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Michael Douglas, Sharon Stone, Jeanne Tripplehorn, George Dzundza and Leilani Sarelle star in this 1992 thriller. This begins in San Francisco with a retired rock star having sex with a blonde woman who brutally kills him with an icepick. Detective, Nick Curran (Douglas) and his partner, Gus (Dzundza) begin investigating and soon meet the victim's lover, Catherine Tramell (Stone) who becomes the main suspect. They learn that she's a writer and the murder coincidentally occurs in her recent novel. Nick starts to get involved with Catherine and begins questioning her motives when she plans on using him as a character in her next book. Tripplehorn plays Nick's ex-girlfriend, Beth Garner who is a psychiatrist and Sarelle plays Catherine's friend and lover, Roxy. Michael and Sharon have great chemistry and Jerry Goldsmith's score is excellent as usual. I recommend this good seductive thriller featuring Stone's famous leg-crossing scene.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Guilty Pleasure.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    AaronCapenBanner
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Michael Douglas plays San Francisco detective Nick Curran, who is investigating the brutal icepick murder of rock star Johnny Boz, which leads him to his girlfriend, novelist Catherine Tramell(Sharon Stone, unforgettable) Nick, though suspicious of Catherine, is nonetheless attracted to her brazen sensuality, and they begin a torrid affair, even though more murders pile up, and Catherine proves to be quite manipulative and intelligent...is she guilty? Controversial film directed by Paul Verhoeven is never boring, though normally having no one in the story to root for would be a problem, film is so slickly made and in-your-face that it may be the epitome of the guilty pleasure; trashy yet enjoyable. Both lead actors are excellent though, even if the mystery is never satisfactorily resolved.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    thrilling till the end
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    acpaloveshavefun
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I recently re saw this movie, and if your a thriller fan you'll absolutely love it. I was at the edge of my seat the entire time, trying to see if I can solve it. Definitely not for kids by the way. Please do not listen for the old bittys out there who are saying that This movie is porn,if I remember correctly the movie psycho had the infamous shower scene. yes its violent and yes it has sexual content, and "Adult situation" but that's what makes a really good movie. This was a perfect example of a great movie before everyone became so politically correct. If you can't handle this as an adult, go live with the Amish, is definitely not for you.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Unsatisfying
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    leonlouisricci
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    There is so much here that is unresolved that it leaves an empty, unfulfilled feeling that the viewer has been suckered. Endless nude and sex scenes intrude on the mystery plot and in the end it is all for not much. Infamous for its explicit exploitation of said sex and nudity and forever frustrating for that's pretty much all there is. The soft-porn aside it can be a somewhat sultry, trashy ride with enough intrigue to keep the interest but not enough to make it a totally engaging entertainment. The biggest problem is the ambiguity about most of what unfolds. There are dangling plot elements and shallow, confusing side shows. In all, it is a murky, muddy, and thin piece of Pulp that has modern machinations and push the envelope displays of Crime Fiction laced with so much pomp that it's rendered impotent. The Movie has enough sizzle to attract viewers but cannot justify all the indulgence and will most likely be an unsatisfactory guilty pleasure. It is quite an overrated Film whose appeal comes from the most lowbrow lexicons of entertainment. But hey, someone once said...there's one born every minute. That's a lot of ticket buyers.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    While its premise is promising, "Basic Instinct" is executed in an inconsistent manner
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Chris Mizerak
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    There are many aspects, both good and bad, that you can pick up from Paul Verhoeven's 1992 erotic thriller Basic Instinct. On one hand, the premise of the film is kind of interesting and has a certain amount of complexity to it. Also, the film works okay enough as far as erotic films go with Sharon Stone flaunting out her body. On the other hand, the film is really cheesy and over-the-top at times as well as really dull in others. So if you're guessing that I think this film has an inconsistent feel to it, you'd probably be right. Basic Instinct follows a police detective (Michael Douglas) with a troubling past who is trying to solve the recent murder of a rock and roll star. The only eligible suspect so far is a book writer (Sharon Stone), whose stories are about women murdering men, who was the last person to see him. One of her own stories seems to play out in the same way that this victim was murdered. Naturally, the police suspects that she did it. The plot thickens however when the detective falls in love with the writer and learns some new developments about the case. In case I haven't mentioned it in any of my earlier reviews, let me get this off my chest. With a few exceptions, I really do not care at all for films centered on police detectives, cops or characters involved in similar professions since I find them to be boring, forgettable, and formulaic. While there are exceptions that either have interesting cases or characters, the rest of them just don't do a thing for me especially in terms of story, characters, and dialogue. Keeping that in mind, while I find whatever takes place in the police department to be fairly formulaic, it wasn't boring and whatever dialogue was being said wasn't as much torture to listen to as I thought it was going to be. I thought it was going to be too difficult to understand what was being said like other films of this genre, but luckily it was easy to understand what was being said, so that must count for something. On top of that, the story has a reasonably intriguing complexity to it and so do the two main characters. The hero and villain in this film are not clear cut, which is fairly authentic of real life. In reality, it's not crystal clear who the heroes and villains are, one culture may consider certain "heroes" villains, and vice versa. In other words, the screenplay was wise enough to put that aspect into the story. If you go see this film solely for looking at Sharon Stone's physique, you won't be disappointed since she really looks good in this film. I wouldn't be surprised if some viewers were reminded of the blonde women Alfred Hitchcock used in his pictures especially Kim Novak. I know I detected some similarities in terms of looks and wardrobe between Stone and the typical blondes Hitchcock used in his films. From what I've said so far, it sounds like this should be a good movie given my personal tastes. But sadly, Basic Instinct is one of those films in which the premise alone is better than the actual execution. One huge issue I had with Basic Instinct is the quality of the acting. I found the acting in this picture to be really weak. While the characters of the two leads are fascinating, the performances aren't executed well enough to do justice to the written characters. I also don't find the two leads (especially Douglas) either that believable or even that subtle/natural with their delivery. Furthermore, the performance by Jeanne Tripplehorn as a psychiatrist helping out Douglas' character is especially unconvincing, considering that I never believed that her character had enough experience in studying psychology to the point were she would become a professional one at such a young age. I simply didn't buy it at all, and the only point to her character existing in this film is solely for a plot twist that is used later in the film. I think she was of no importance to the plot whatsoever. Because of the disappointing acting quality, I don't really buy whatever ludicrous events take place in the plot as a result. Therefore, I can't take anything in the plot as seriously as the film seems to want me to. While the screenplay has its fair share of intriguing elements, there are also some elements of the screenplay especially with its dialogue that feels really cheesy and doesn't even sound the slightest bit realistic. As a result, that's how the film becomes inconsistent in terms of its delivery. In a nutshell, Basic Instinct definitely seems to be a mixed bag. While it has a good idea of what it wants to be, it seldom delivers on the promises it makes mainly because the acting is so mediocre to the point where it interferes with my ability to believe what's happening on screen. I'd only recommend this film if you're solely interested in checking out Stone's body. It's not much of an endorsement, but that's the highest praise I can give to this flick.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Murder All Around Her
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bkoganbing
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Although most reviewers have concentrated on the leads, Basic Instinct has some other fine performances in it. Still Michael Douglas as the sex obsessed cop and Sharon Stone as the amoral, multi-sexual woman who seems to have murder all around her give some iconic performances. A couple of SFPD detectives who played TV detectives, Michael Douglas in Streets Of San Francisco and George Dzundza in Law And Order, get assigned to the homicide of a former rockstar icon. The man had as the story tells us the 'coital moment of the century' before he died and as Michael Douglas finds out with Sharon Stone his prime suspect. It's not like Douglas hasn't any issues himself, he's seeing the SFPD shrink Jeanne Tripplehorn. One of those issues apparently is professional detachment as gets involved with both Tripplehorn and Stone. Far worse with Stone as she is a suspect. Murders in the past and murders in the present seem to pop up whenever Stone is around. She's an heiress to a fortune, a psychology major from college and licensed and an author of lurid novels. She knows how to press the buttons of both sexes and soon enough Douglas is in her world. The only one keeping a professional detachment is Dzundza who is not thinking with his male member. Even when an Internal Affairs cop who is investigating Douglas is murdered, Dzundza sticks by his partner. See what it gets him. In fact Dzundza and Tripplehorn don't get near enough credit for their work here. I think most know Tripplehorn as I do for playing Tom Cruise's wife in The Firm. She too is a woman with a lot of issues. As for George Dzundza as the only one in the film actually who seems to be normal, the others all seem to play off him. Still Sharon Stone's career was launched with what she did in Basic Instinct. This woman will wind up President of the USA or on death row, no middle ground for her. And you can believe she's every man and woman's coital moment of a lifetime. I don't know how successful or how good Basic Instinct 2 was, but seeing this has given me an incentive to see the sequel.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Bill Hicks and my Basic instinct was right, it's an unpleasant film.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ironhorse_iv
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It's sad to say that sex sells. Basic Instinct without a doubt sells, but it's just a sexy thriller that's got plenty of libido but not nearly as much brains as it thinks it has. It's extremely misogynistic and is very predictable. I was very disappointed with the whole movie, and had figured out the murderer within about 30 minutes into it. It's titillating, even exciting at times, but ultimately collapses under the weight of its own stupidity. The movie contained a lot of graphic sexual acts throughout the movie that makes it more of a soft porn movie in disguise & less than a film noir. It could have been better, if it cut down on the exotic a bit, and focus more on the story and give us a challenge. In the film's opening, Rockstar Boz is stabbed to death by a blonde woman with an ice pick during sex. We never see the woman's face -- just her blonde hair and, of course, most of her lust-inducing body. By just looking at the body of the killer, you can pretty much know who did it. The police find the dead body, and Det. Nick Curran, (Michael Douglas) was put on the case whom slept with his police-appointed shrink Dr. Beth Garner (Jeanne Triplehorn). Rather than getting a DNA test on the number one- suspect, Boz's girlfriend, Catherine Tramell (Sharon Stone), a famous crime novelist, the cops interview her. I know DNA testing was still in its early stages in the early '90s but convicting using DNA evidence alone has been proved fact since 1988, four years when the film was set. Well, Catherine use the interview to make fools out of them. The way she manipulates psychology was superbly awesome. Without Sharon Stone as femme fatale, this movie is nothing. Still, most people would remember from this scene just the famous leg switching, and not the acting. Although, the detectives were too stupid to realize that there is something about her that doesn't add up. We sees Catherine using it to break ice during the film. She even mentions how her book is about a detective falling for the wrong woman and that she kills him. Isn't it very clear who the killer is? Sooner than later, Nick get into Catherine's sex life. The movie moves with the suspense involving Nick and Catherine. He's supposed to be following this woman as a suspect but is actually falling for her deadly charm since Nick is dumb like the other cops. Clearly this film points out the men are just horny dumb pervs who slept before duty. The film tries to do a lot of dumb red herrings such as Beth is revealed to have had a past sexual encounter with Catherine, that according to Catherine developed an obsessive fixation on her as Beth copy her. The audience is suppose to wonder whether Beth killed Boz as is described in Catherine's book to frame her. Not once in the film, does Beth show any bit of bi or lesbians feelings. Catherine does with a girl name Roxy (Leilani Sarelle). The film was strongly opposed by gay rights activists, who criticized the film's portrayal of bisexual women as a murderous sociopaths. The featurette Blond Poison reveals the uproar the film caused during the San Francisco filming. They deplored it as being "anti-gay" and a reinforcement of Hollywood homophobia due to typecasting particularly lesbians as twisted and evil, or just act lesbians to get men's horny. I think the heterosexuals can also be equally offensive, as some feminists like Camille Paglia starts breaking things down to banal symbolisms, the opening killing with the ice pick is interpreted as, "Woman steals man's penis and uses it against him." men find themselves involuntarily cringing. Freudian Pscyhoanalysts have retained the term instinct that the film refer to human motivational forces (such as sex and aggression), sometimes represented as Eros - life instinct and Thanatos- death Instinct, but the real term is motivational forces or drives to correct the original error in the translation of Freud's work. Psychologist Abraham Maslow argued that humans no longer have instincts because we have the ability to override them in certain situations. For Maslow, an instinct is something which cannot be overridden, & therefore while the term may have applied to humans in the past, it no longer does. So the film should be title 'Basic Drives". It's clear why Joe Eszterhas was paid 3-million bucks for his script with its clever plot construction. Still there are pointless sequences like where Nick and Catherine engage in a car chase for no discernible reason other than to serve as a dire attempt to jack up the energy level. The film also has unlikeable characters. The hero Nick viciously rapes Beth in one scene. They're perfectly acceptable in the art of film, but Basic Instinct did go a little overboard with that sex. The film does good with its abstract images, the way it's shot from different angles, made it a little more elliptical, a bit less direct. The eerie Jerry Goldsmith theme gives the film a creepy tone. Basic Instinct was to transfers Mr. Verhoeven's flair for action-oriented material to the realm of Hitchcockian intrigue, but the results are so-so. Following the success of the film, Ezsterhas & Verhoeven went on to collaborate on Showgirls. (Another horrible mess). Since release, the blue-ray version add more graphic violence & sex into the film.This film is an affront to taste. It's an over-baked mind control fantasy, brought to life by a horrible script, and relieved of meaning by a hair brained plot. It's all Tougue in cheek really like a perv. It's depends on your kicks.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I'd have to be pretty stupid to write a book about killing and then kill him the way I described in my book. I'd be announcing myself as the killer. I'm not stupid.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    JohnRouseMerriottChard
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Basic Instinct is directed by Paul Verhoeven and written by Joe Eszterhaz. It stars Michael Douglas, Sharon Stone, George Dzundza, Jeanne Tripplehorn, Denis Arndt and Leilani Sarelle. Music is scored by Jerry Goldsmith and cinematography by Jan de Bont. Nick Curran (Douglas) of the SFPD is strung out and under investigation by Internal Affairs, last thing he needs is to be drawn into a dangerous relationship with a sex crazed blonde who may be a murderess... Time hasn't been kind to Verhoeven's soft-core porn thriller, where once was shock and awe killings (the film opening with a brutal mini ice-pick murder), steamy love scenes and a famed and controversial crotch shot, now is ludicrous orgasms, iffy effects and Michael Douglas' unappetising ass! Hell there was even protests during the film's initial theatre run as the gay community went up in arms about the portrayal of bisexuals possibly being mad murderers? Yet for all of its taming over the years, Basic Instinct can at least now been seen as the hugely efficient mystery thriller that it is, one that is propelled by some very good performances by the principal actors. The strength in the story is not in the sex or blood, but in the character arcs of Nick Curran and Catherine Tramell (Stone). Curran is a man perched on the edge of doom who is controlled totally by the women around him. He is by definition a quintessential film noir protagonist, in so deep he ultimately will be resigned to his fate. Catharine Tramell is a ultimate femme fatale, beautiful and seductive, she's always in control, leading all male characters where she wants them to go. There's a delicious kink to the narrative, with Verhoeven gleefully pulling the strings, a smirk no doubt etched onto his face. This is very good story telling, with a plot of substantial twists and turns. True, it does carry some soft-core baggage that can steer the restless away from the character strengths within, but for the neo-noir crowd there is much to enjoy here. 7.5/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Sharon Stone's finest hour
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    moviestar26
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    'Basic Instinct' was a film that rebooted the noir genre after it became rare in the early eighties. Prior to this the Coen brother's 'Blood Simple' attempted to revive the genre, but the industry was changing with the shift in audience's movie preferences. However this is more akin to being a sex thriller which also happens to incorporate a suspense element. 'Basic Instinct' takes the viewer back in time to the golden era of cinema when the femme fatales were glamorising the screen and became every male's dream fantasy. The film has been considered a classic and has not dated with time. The theme has been beautifully been One of my cult classic favourites from the 1990s. Whenever I catch a scene randomly on television, it brings back nostalgic memories of my childhood. I can still remember waking in the middle of the night just so I could record this movie secretly on my VCR. This is the movie that catapulted stone's career to international stardom. She immediately became a sex symbol and every man began dreaming of her. She immortalised a role that was so deep in characterisation. 'Catherine Trammel' was someone that was not only devious but smart, clever and manipulative. A role model so to speak that will certainly serve as an influence to many aspiring actresses and writers in the future. The role possessed every element that a negative character would have. Joe Esterhas is the writer. Previously he wrote 'Flash dance' and 'jagged edge' Most of his themes are similar. All negative roles about killers and murderers. 'Showgirls' and 'Jade' were also adapted for the screen. Unfortunately they failed at the box office and did not work. I think the audiences had higher expectations. 'Basic Instinct' has a fantastic script. This is the reason why the film worked. And then there is Paul Verhoeven who is a well known director in his home land. He has beautifully combined sex with the suspense genre. I am not very familiar with his Dutch movies. But he always had the style of depicting the theme of 'sex' as a weapon. I enjoyed the movie immensely, and being more of a reader than a movie- goer I jumped at the chance to read the book subsequent to seeing the motion picture. However, I feel that much of which made the movie great owes gratitude to the incredible soundtrack, imagery and skill of the actors; sometimes movies can be successfully novelised, but with Basic Instinct being the stimulus-rich move that it is I feel this was a failed attempt. The characters come off as threadbare and unexplored, lacking in depth or substance of any kind, and the seductively dark tone of the movie is lost on the page; it becomes rather humdrum and glancing, as if each page were written to keep up with the flow of the movie to be read within the hour. Where I was hoping to see some of the twisted, genius logic of Catherine Tramell explored on the page instead I found her to be de-powered, humanised and lacking of a great deal of her appeal as a result. It's worth the read for big fans of the Basic Instinct movies if only to explore the idea through a different form of media, (SPOILER) A San Francisco police detective who is investigated the murder of a retired rock star. The main suspect happens to be a novelist. She is under suspicion. She is released due to lack of evidence. Meanwhile the detective has maintains his belief that she is involved. He decides to pursue her and monitor her movements. The deeper his investigation proceeds, he succumbs to her charm and falls in love in spite knowing he is risking his life. His infatuation distances him from people around him and he refuses to listen to others. People he know become murdered. Eventually he finds it difficult to accept that she is a murderer as he begins to doubt his psychiatrist's past. (END OF SPOILER) The film is made with a sexy noir thriller tone. It brings back memories of Lawrence Kasden's 'Body Heat'. This was the last time a lead actress made an impression with a memorable role. Kathleen Turner became a popular star. At many moments the film feels like a horror thriller. There are many scenes that evoke a frightening feeling. What makes 'Basic Instinct' so unique is we are watching a women manipulating us with her attractive appeal that makes us want to believe she can be a killer. Her seductive charm works on the male protagonist, which leads to confusion. At the end we are eager to want to see her apprehended because we are disgusted how someone can desire to get away with murder for no reason. The sex scenes were unique and were the closest that could be categorised as 'soft porn'. This was one of the appealing factors that mad the film a success. 'Basic Instinct' has sustained it's quality over the years. It has managed to preserve it's quality and has not paled in front of movies that released recently. Due credit goes to Sharon Stone's performance and a winning script by Esterhas. The movie does follow true to the noir conventions. Anyone who is familiar with this will be able to notice them. However some of the typical noir rules were missing. There was no themes related to adultery or blackmailing. But it's relevance or lack of it doesn't seem significant as the this was a character driven film. Jerry Goldsmith's background score is specifically suited to the film's mood and atmosphere. It is still memorable and has different shades throughout the movie. It blends well with scenes and evokes the intriguing and haunting feeling.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Classic Verhoeven outrageousness.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    BA_Harrison
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/9/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Despite being built around the most 'basic' of plots, erotic thriller Basic Instinct remains director Paul Verhoeven's biggest commercial success, being one of the highest grossing titles of 1992. Unperturbed by the protestations of gay activists and uptight censor-happy moralists, who objected to the film's provocative cocktail of graphic sex and violence and its portrayal of bisexuals as crazed killers, the general public flocked to the cinema to revel in Verhoeven's heady concoction of wanton lust and cold-blooded violence. Written by Joe Eszterhas of Flashdance fame, the script is slick Hollywood nonsense, a flashy, trashy, twisting, turning tale clearly inspired by Hitchcock and the film-noir genre. Frequently teetering on the brink of preposterousness, its is precisely the kind of far-fetched nonsense that only a true maverick like Verhoeven could do justice toand boy, does he pull out all the stops here... Never one to do things by halves, the Dutch director opens his film as he means to go on, with a brutal murder that takes place during intercourse, a physically flawless blonde viciously stabbing her lover to death with an ice-pick. Scorching sex combined with gut churning nastiness, it's a real shocker (use the freeze-frame check out the outrageous shot of the pick going through the victim's nose!!!) and a clear indicator that this is to be no run-of-the-mill Hollywood thriller. The remainder of the film follows troubled detective Nick Curran (Michae Douglas) as he investigates the murder, stupidly becoming involved with his prime suspect, scorching hot, super intelligent, highly manipulative crime novelist Catherine Tramell (Sharon Stone), who may or may not be lining him up as her latest victim. Cue plenty more raunchy, near the knuckle nookie (including some rough rumpy-pumpy with the very sexy Jeanne 'gives me the' Tripplehorn), a few more gruesome deaths, a smidgen of exciting, pulse-pounding action, and the film's infamous blink-and-you'll miss-it shot of Stone's kebab as she uncrosses her legs during a police interview, all of which adds up to a whole heap of unmissable, jaw-dropping, eye-opening, big budget fun the likes of which we might never see again (unless Verhoeven can get Hollywood to forget all about Showgirls).
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "Good Seductive Thriller!"
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gwnightscream
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/9/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Michael Douglas, Sharon Stone, Jeanne Tripplehorn, George Dzundza and Leilani Sarelle star in this 1992 thriller. This begins in San Francisco with a retired rock star having sex with a blonde woman who brutally kills him with an icepick. Detective, Nick Curran (Douglas) and his partner, Gus (Dzundza) begin investigating and soon meet the victim's lover, Catherine Tramell (Stone) who becomes the main suspect. They learn that she's a writer and the murder coincidentally occurs in her recent novel. Nick starts to get involved with Catherine and begins questioning her motives when she plans on using him as a character in her next book. Tripplehorn plays Nick's ex-girlfriend, Beth Garner who is a psychiatrist and Sarelle plays Catherine's friend and lover, Roxy. Michael and Sharon have great chemistry and Jerry Goldsmith's score is excellent as usual. I recommend this good seductive thriller featuring Stone's famous leg-crossing scene.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Guilty Pleasure.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    AaronCapenBanner
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Michael Douglas plays San Francisco detective Nick Curran, who is investigating the brutal icepick murder of rock star Johnny Boz, which leads him to his girlfriend, novelist Catherine Tramell(Sharon Stone, unforgettable) Nick, though suspicious of Catherine, is nonetheless attracted to her brazen sensuality, and they begin a torrid affair, even though more murders pile up, and Catherine proves to be quite manipulative and intelligent...is she guilty? Controversial film directed by Paul Verhoeven is never boring, though normally having no one in the story to root for would be a problem, film is so slickly made and in-your-face that it may be the epitome of the guilty pleasure; trashy yet enjoyable. Both lead actors are excellent though, even if the mystery is never satisfactorily resolved.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    thrilling till the end
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    acpaloveshavefun
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I recently re saw this movie, and if your a thriller fan you'll absolutely love it. I was at the edge of my seat the entire time, trying to see if I can solve it. Definitely not for kids by the way. Please do not listen for the old bittys out there who are saying that This movie is porn,if I remember correctly the movie psycho had the infamous shower scene. yes its violent and yes it has sexual content, and "Adult situation" but that's what makes a really good movie. This was a perfect example of a great movie before everyone became so politically correct. If you can't handle this as an adult, go live with the Amish, is definitely not for you.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Unsatisfying
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    leonlouisricci
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    There is so much here that is unresolved that it leaves an empty, unfulfilled feeling that the viewer has been suckered. Endless nude and sex scenes intrude on the mystery plot and in the end it is all for not much. Infamous for its explicit exploitation of said sex and nudity and forever frustrating for that's pretty much all there is. The soft-porn aside it can be a somewhat sultry, trashy ride with enough intrigue to keep the interest but not enough to make it a totally engaging entertainment. The biggest problem is the ambiguity about most of what unfolds. There are dangling plot elements and shallow, confusing side shows. In all, it is a murky, muddy, and thin piece of Pulp that has modern machinations and push the envelope displays of Crime Fiction laced with so much pomp that it's rendered impotent. The Movie has enough sizzle to attract viewers but cannot justify all the indulgence and will most likely be an unsatisfactory guilty pleasure. It is quite an overrated Film whose appeal comes from the most lowbrow lexicons of entertainment. But hey, someone once said...there's one born every minute. That's a lot of ticket buyers.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    While its premise is promising, "Basic Instinct" is executed in an inconsistent manner
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Chris Mizerak
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    There are many aspects, both good and bad, that you can pick up from Paul Verhoeven's 1992 erotic thriller Basic Instinct. On one hand, the premise of the film is kind of interesting and has a certain amount of complexity to it. Also, the film works okay enough as far as erotic films go with Sharon Stone flaunting out her body. On the other hand, the film is really cheesy and over-the-top at times as well as really dull in others. So if you're guessing that I think this film has an inconsistent feel to it, you'd probably be right. Basic Instinct follows a police detective (Michael Douglas) with a troubling past who is trying to solve the recent murder of a rock and roll star. The only eligible suspect so far is a book writer (Sharon Stone), whose stories are about women murdering men, who was the last person to see him. One of her own stories seems to play out in the same way that this victim was murdered. Naturally, the police suspects that she did it. The plot thickens however when the detective falls in love with the writer and learns some new developments about the case. In case I haven't mentioned it in any of my earlier reviews, let me get this off my chest. With a few exceptions, I really do not care at all for films centered on police detectives, cops or characters involved in similar professions since I find them to be boring, forgettable, and formulaic. While there are exceptions that either have interesting cases or characters, the rest of them just don't do a thing for me especially in terms of story, characters, and dialogue. Keeping that in mind, while I find whatever takes place in the police department to be fairly formulaic, it wasn't boring and whatever dialogue was being said wasn't as much torture to listen to as I thought it was going to be. I thought it was going to be too difficult to understand what was being said like other films of this genre, but luckily it was easy to understand what was being said, so that must count for something. On top of that, the story has a reasonably intriguing complexity to it and so do the two main characters. The hero and villain in this film are not clear cut, which is fairly authentic of real life. In reality, it's not crystal clear who the heroes and villains are, one culture may consider certain "heroes" villains, and vice versa. In other words, the screenplay was wise enough to put that aspect into the story. If you go see this film solely for looking at Sharon Stone's physique, you won't be disappointed since she really looks good in this film. I wouldn't be surprised if some viewers were reminded of the blonde women Alfred Hitchcock used in his pictures especially Kim Novak. I know I detected some similarities in terms of looks and wardrobe between Stone and the typical blondes Hitchcock used in his films. From what I've said so far, it sounds like this should be a good movie given my personal tastes. But sadly, Basic Instinct is one of those films in which the premise alone is better than the actual execution. One huge issue I had with Basic Instinct is the quality of the acting. I found the acting in this picture to be really weak. While the characters of the two leads are fascinating, the performances aren't executed well enough to do justice to the written characters. I also don't find the two leads (especially Douglas) either that believable or even that subtle/natural with their delivery. Furthermore, the performance by Jeanne Tripplehorn as a psychiatrist helping out Douglas' character is especially unconvincing, considering that I never believed that her character had enough experience in studying psychology to the point were she would become a professional one at such a young age. I simply didn't buy it at all, and the only point to her character existing in this film is solely for a plot twist that is used later in the film. I think she was of no importance to the plot whatsoever. Because of the disappointing acting quality, I don't really buy whatever ludicrous events take place in the plot as a result. Therefore, I can't take anything in the plot as seriously as the film seems to want me to. While the screenplay has its fair share of intriguing elements, there are also some elements of the screenplay especially with its dialogue that feels really cheesy and doesn't even sound the slightest bit realistic. As a result, that's how the film becomes inconsistent in terms of its delivery. In a nutshell, Basic Instinct definitely seems to be a mixed bag. While it has a good idea of what it wants to be, it seldom delivers on the promises it makes mainly because the acting is so mediocre to the point where it interferes with my ability to believe what's happening on screen. I'd only recommend this film if you're solely interested in checking out Stone's body. It's not much of an endorsement, but that's the highest praise I can give to this flick.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Murder All Around Her
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bkoganbing
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Although most reviewers have concentrated on the leads, Basic Instinct has some other fine performances in it. Still Michael Douglas as the sex obsessed cop and Sharon Stone as the amoral, multi-sexual woman who seems to have murder all around her give some iconic performances. A couple of SFPD detectives who played TV detectives, Michael Douglas in Streets Of San Francisco and George Dzundza in Law And Order, get assigned to the homicide of a former rockstar icon. The man had as the story tells us the 'coital moment of the century' before he died and as Michael Douglas finds out with Sharon Stone his prime suspect. It's not like Douglas hasn't any issues himself, he's seeing the SFPD shrink Jeanne Tripplehorn. One of those issues apparently is professional detachment as gets involved with both Tripplehorn and Stone. Far worse with Stone as she is a suspect. Murders in the past and murders in the present seem to pop up whenever Stone is around. She's an heiress to a fortune, a psychology major from college and licensed and an author of lurid novels. She knows how to press the buttons of both sexes and soon enough Douglas is in her world. The only one keeping a professional detachment is Dzundza who is not thinking with his male member. Even when an Internal Affairs cop who is investigating Douglas is murdered, Dzundza sticks by his partner. See what it gets him. In fact Dzundza and Tripplehorn don't get near enough credit for their work here. I think most know Tripplehorn as I do for playing Tom Cruise's wife in The Firm. She too is a woman with a lot of issues. As for George Dzundza as the only one in the film actually who seems to be normal, the others all seem to play off him. Still Sharon Stone's career was launched with what she did in Basic Instinct. This woman will wind up President of the USA or on death row, no middle ground for her. And you can believe she's every man and woman's coital moment of a lifetime. I don't know how successful or how good Basic Instinct 2 was, but seeing this has given me an incentive to see the sequel.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Bill Hicks and my Basic instinct was right, it's an unpleasant film.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ironhorse_iv
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It's sad to say that sex sells. Basic Instinct without a doubt sells, but it's just a sexy thriller that's got plenty of libido but not nearly as much brains as it thinks it has. It's extremely misogynistic and is very predictable. I was very disappointed with the whole movie, and had figured out the murderer within about 30 minutes into it. It's titillating, even exciting at times, but ultimately collapses under the weight of its own stupidity. The movie contained a lot of graphic sexual acts throughout the movie that makes it more of a soft porn movie in disguise & less than a film noir. It could have been better, if it cut down on the exotic a bit, and focus more on the story and give us a challenge. In the film's opening, Rockstar Boz is stabbed to death by a blonde woman with an ice pick during sex. We never see the woman's face -- just her blonde hair and, of course, most of her lust-inducing body. By just looking at the body of the killer, you can pretty much know who did it. The police find the dead body, and Det. Nick Curran, (Michael Douglas) was put on the case whom slept with his police-appointed shrink Dr. Beth Garner (Jeanne Triplehorn). Rather than getting a DNA test on the number one- suspect, Boz's girlfriend, Catherine Tramell (Sharon Stone), a famous crime novelist, the cops interview her. I know DNA testing was still in its early stages in the early '90s but convicting using DNA evidence alone has been proved fact since 1988, four years when the film was set. Well, Catherine use the interview to make fools out of them. The way she manipulates psychology was superbly awesome. Without Sharon Stone as femme fatale, this movie is nothing. Still, most people would remember from this scene just the famous leg switching, and not the acting. Although, the detectives were too stupid to realize that there is something about her that doesn't add up. We sees Catherine using it to break ice during the film. She even mentions how her book is about a detective falling for the wrong woman and that she kills him. Isn't it very clear who the killer is? Sooner than later, Nick get into Catherine's sex life. The movie moves with the suspense involving Nick and Catherine. He's supposed to be following this woman as a suspect but is actually falling for her deadly charm since Nick is dumb like the other cops. Clearly this film points out the men are just horny dumb pervs who slept before duty. The film tries to do a lot of dumb red herrings such as Beth is revealed to have had a past sexual encounter with Catherine, that according to Catherine developed an obsessive fixation on her as Beth copy her. The audience is suppose to wonder whether Beth killed Boz as is described in Catherine's book to frame her. Not once in the film, does Beth show any bit of bi or lesbians feelings. Catherine does with a girl name Roxy (Leilani Sarelle). The film was strongly opposed by gay rights activists, who criticized the film's portrayal of bisexual women as a murderous sociopaths. The featurette Blond Poison reveals the uproar the film caused during the San Francisco filming. They deplored it as being "anti-gay" and a reinforcement of Hollywood homophobia due to typecasting particularly lesbians as twisted and evil, or just act lesbians to get men's horny. I think the heterosexuals can also be equally offensive, as some feminists like Camille Paglia starts breaking things down to banal symbolisms, the opening killing with the ice pick is interpreted as, "Woman steals man's penis and uses it against him." men find themselves involuntarily cringing. Freudian Pscyhoanalysts have retained the term instinct that the film refer to human motivational forces (such as sex and aggression), sometimes represented as Eros - life instinct and Thanatos- death Instinct, but the real term is motivational forces or drives to correct the original error in the translation of Freud's work. Psychologist Abraham Maslow argued that humans no longer have instincts because we have the ability to override them in certain situations. For Maslow, an instinct is something which cannot be overridden, & therefore while the term may have applied to humans in the past, it no longer does. So the film should be title 'Basic Drives". It's clear why Joe Eszterhas was paid 3-million bucks for his script with its clever plot construction. Still there are pointless sequences like where Nick and Catherine engage in a car chase for no discernible reason other than to serve as a dire attempt to jack up the energy level. The film also has unlikeable characters. The hero Nick viciously rapes Beth in one scene. They're perfectly acceptable in the art of film, but Basic Instinct did go a little overboard with that sex. The film does good with its abstract images, the way it's shot from different angles, made it a little more elliptical, a bit less direct. The eerie Jerry Goldsmith theme gives the film a creepy tone. Basic Instinct was to transfers Mr. Verhoeven's flair for action-oriented material to the realm of Hitchcockian intrigue, but the results are so-so. Following the success of the film, Ezsterhas & Verhoeven went on to collaborate on Showgirls. (Another horrible mess). Since release, the blue-ray version add more graphic violence & sex into the film.This film is an affront to taste. It's an over-baked mind control fantasy, brought to life by a horrible script, and relieved of meaning by a hair brained plot. It's all Tougue in cheek really like a perv. It's depends on your kicks.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I'd have to be pretty stupid to write a book about killing and then kill him the way I described in my book. I'd be announcing myself as the killer. I'm not stupid.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    JohnRouseMerriottChard
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Basic Instinct is directed by Paul Verhoeven and written by Joe Eszterhaz. It stars Michael Douglas, Sharon Stone, George Dzundza, Jeanne Tripplehorn, Denis Arndt and Leilani Sarelle. Music is scored by Jerry Goldsmith and cinematography by Jan de Bont. Nick Curran (Douglas) of the SFPD is strung out and under investigation by Internal Affairs, last thing he needs is to be drawn into a dangerous relationship with a sex crazed blonde who may be a murderess... Time hasn't been kind to Verhoeven's soft-core porn thriller, where once was shock and awe killings (the film opening with a brutal mini ice-pick murder), steamy love scenes and a famed and controversial crotch shot, now is ludicrous orgasms, iffy effects and Michael Douglas' unappetising ass! Hell there was even protests during the film's initial theatre run as the gay community went up in arms about the portrayal of bisexuals possibly being mad murderers? Yet for all of its taming over the years, Basic Instinct can at least now been seen as the hugely efficient mystery thriller that it is, one that is propelled by some very good performances by the principal actors. The strength in the story is not in the sex or blood, but in the character arcs of Nick Curran and Catherine Tramell (Stone). Curran is a man perched on the edge of doom who is controlled totally by the women around him. He is by definition a quintessential film noir protagonist, in so deep he ultimately will be resigned to his fate. Catharine Tramell is a ultimate femme fatale, beautiful and seductive, she's always in control, leading all male characters where she wants them to go. There's a delicious kink to the narrative, with Verhoeven gleefully pulling the strings, a smirk no doubt etched onto his face. This is very good story telling, with a plot of substantial twists and turns. True, it does carry some soft-core baggage that can steer the restless away from the character strengths within, but for the neo-noir crowd there is much to enjoy here. 7.5/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Sharon Stone's finest hour
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    moviestar26
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    'Basic Instinct' was a film that rebooted the noir genre after it became rare in the early eighties. Prior to this the Coen brother's 'Blood Simple' attempted to revive the genre, but the industry was changing with the shift in audience's movie preferences. However this is more akin to being a sex thriller which also happens to incorporate a suspense element. 'Basic Instinct' takes the viewer back in time to the golden era of cinema when the femme fatales were glamorising the screen and became every male's dream fantasy. The film has been considered a classic and has not dated with time. The theme has been beautifully been One of my cult classic favourites from the 1990s. Whenever I catch a scene randomly on television, it brings back nostalgic memories of my childhood. I can still remember waking in the middle of the night just so I could record this movie secretly on my VCR. This is the movie that catapulted stone's career to international stardom. She immediately became a sex symbol and every man began dreaming of her. She immortalised a role that was so deep in characterisation. 'Catherine Trammel' was someone that was not only devious but smart, clever and manipulative. A role model so to speak that will certainly serve as an influence to many aspiring actresses and writers in the future. The role possessed every element that a negative character would have. Joe Esterhas is the writer. Previously he wrote 'Flash dance' and 'jagged edge' Most of his themes are similar. All negative roles about killers and murderers. 'Showgirls' and 'Jade' were also adapted for the screen. Unfortunately they failed at the box office and did not work. I think the audiences had higher expectations. 'Basic Instinct' has a fantastic script. This is the reason why the film worked. And then there is Paul Verhoeven who is a well known director in his home land. He has beautifully combined sex with the suspense genre. I am not very familiar with his Dutch movies. But he always had the style of depicting the theme of 'sex' as a weapon. I enjoyed the movie immensely, and being more of a reader than a movie- goer I jumped at the chance to read the book subsequent to seeing the motion picture. However, I feel that much of which made the movie great owes gratitude to the incredible soundtrack, imagery and skill of the actors; sometimes movies can be successfully novelised, but with Basic Instinct being the stimulus-rich move that it is I feel this was a failed attempt. The characters come off as threadbare and unexplored, lacking in depth or substance of any kind, and the seductively dark tone of the movie is lost on the page; it becomes rather humdrum and glancing, as if each page were written to keep up with the flow of the movie to be read within the hour. Where I was hoping to see some of the twisted, genius logic of Catherine Tramell explored on the page instead I found her to be de-powered, humanised and lacking of a great deal of her appeal as a result. It's worth the read for big fans of the Basic Instinct movies if only to explore the idea through a different form of media, (SPOILER) A San Francisco police detective who is investigated the murder of a retired rock star. The main suspect happens to be a novelist. She is under suspicion. She is released due to lack of evidence. Meanwhile the detective has maintains his belief that she is involved. He decides to pursue her and monitor her movements. The deeper his investigation proceeds, he succumbs to her charm and falls in love in spite knowing he is risking his life. His infatuation distances him from people around him and he refuses to listen to others. People he know become murdered. Eventually he finds it difficult to accept that she is a murderer as he begins to doubt his psychiatrist's past. (END OF SPOILER) The film is made with a sexy noir thriller tone. It brings back memories of Lawrence Kasden's 'Body Heat'. This was the last time a lead actress made an impression with a memorable role. Kathleen Turner became a popular star. At many moments the film feels like a horror thriller. There are many scenes that evoke a frightening feeling. What makes 'Basic Instinct' so unique is we are watching a women manipulating us with her attractive appeal that makes us want to believe she can be a killer. Her seductive charm works on the male protagonist, which leads to confusion. At the end we are eager to want to see her apprehended because we are disgusted how someone can desire to get away with murder for no reason. The sex scenes were unique and were the closest that could be categorised as 'soft porn'. This was one of the appealing factors that mad the film a success. 'Basic Instinct' has sustained it's quality over the years. It has managed to preserve it's quality and has not paled in front of movies that released recently. Due credit goes to Sharon Stone's performance and a winning script by Esterhas. The movie does follow true to the noir conventions. Anyone who is familiar with this will be able to notice them. However some of the typical noir rules were missing. There was no themes related to adultery or blackmailing. But it's relevance or lack of it doesn't seem significant as the this was a character driven film. Jerry Goldsmith's background score is specifically suited to the film's mood and atmosphere. It is still memorable and has different shades throughout the movie. It blends well with scenes and evokes the intriguing and haunting feeling.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Classic Verhoeven outrageousness.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    BA_Harrison
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/9/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Despite being built around the most 'basic' of plots, erotic thriller Basic Instinct remains director Paul Verhoeven's biggest commercial success, being one of the highest grossing titles of 1992. Unperturbed by the protestations of gay activists and uptight censor-happy moralists, who objected to the film's provocative cocktail of graphic sex and violence and its portrayal of bisexuals as crazed killers, the general public flocked to the cinema to revel in Verhoeven's heady concoction of wanton lust and cold-blooded violence. Written by Joe Eszterhas of Flashdance fame, the script is slick Hollywood nonsense, a flashy, trashy, twisting, turning tale clearly inspired by Hitchcock and the film-noir genre. Frequently teetering on the brink of preposterousness, its is precisely the kind of far-fetched nonsense that only a true maverick like Verhoeven could do justice toand boy, does he pull out all the stops here... Never one to do things by halves, the Dutch director opens his film as he means to go on, with a brutal murder that takes place during intercourse, a physically flawless blonde viciously stabbing her lover to death with an ice-pick. Scorching sex combined with gut churning nastiness, it's a real shocker (use the freeze-frame check out the outrageous shot of the pick going through the victim's nose!!!) and a clear indicator that this is to be no run-of-the-mill Hollywood thriller. The remainder of the film follows troubled detective Nick Curran (Michae Douglas) as he investigates the murder, stupidly becoming involved with his prime suspect, scorching hot, super intelligent, highly manipulative crime novelist Catherine Tramell (Sharon Stone), who may or may not be lining him up as her latest victim. Cue plenty more raunchy, near the knuckle nookie (including some rough rumpy-pumpy with the very sexy Jeanne 'gives me the' Tripplehorn), a few more gruesome deaths, a smidgen of exciting, pulse-pounding action, and the film's infamous blink-and-you'll miss-it shot of Stone's kebab as she uncrosses her legs during a police interview, all of which adds up to a whole heap of unmissable, jaw-dropping, eye-opening, big budget fun the likes of which we might never see again (unless Verhoeven can get Hollywood to forget all about Showgirls).
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "Good Seductive Thriller!"
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gwnightscream
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/9/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Michael Douglas, Sharon Stone, Jeanne Tripplehorn, George Dzundza and Leilani Sarelle star in this 1992 thriller. This begins in San Francisco with a retired rock star having sex with a blonde woman who brutally kills him with an icepick. Detective, Nick Curran (Douglas) and his partner, Gus (Dzundza) begin investigating and soon meet the victim's lover, Catherine Tramell (Stone) who becomes the main suspect. They learn that she's a writer and the murder coincidentally occurs in her recent novel. Nick starts to get involved with Catherine and begins questioning her motives when she plans on using him as a character in her next book. Tripplehorn plays Nick's ex-girlfriend, Beth Garner who is a psychiatrist and Sarelle plays Catherine's friend and lover, Roxy. Michael and Sharon have great chemistry and Jerry Goldsmith's score is excellent as usual. I recommend this good seductive thriller featuring Stone's famous leg-crossing scene.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Guilty Pleasure.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    AaronCapenBanner
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Michael Douglas plays San Francisco detective Nick Curran, who is investigating the brutal icepick murder of rock star Johnny Boz, which leads him to his girlfriend, novelist Catherine Tramell(Sharon Stone, unforgettable) Nick, though suspicious of Catherine, is nonetheless attracted to her brazen sensuality, and they begin a torrid affair, even though more murders pile up, and Catherine proves to be quite manipulative and intelligent...is she guilty? Controversial film directed by Paul Verhoeven is never boring, though normally having no one in the story to root for would be a problem, film is so slickly made and in-your-face that it may be the epitome of the guilty pleasure; trashy yet enjoyable. Both lead actors are excellent though, even if the mystery is never satisfactorily resolved.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    thrilling till the end
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    acpaloveshavefun
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I recently re saw this movie, and if your a thriller fan you'll absolutely love it. I was at the edge of my seat the entire time, trying to see if I can solve it. Definitely not for kids by the way. Please do not listen for the old bittys out there who are saying that This movie is porn,if I remember correctly the movie psycho had the infamous shower scene. yes its violent and yes it has sexual content, and "Adult situation" but that's what makes a really good movie. This was a perfect example of a great movie before everyone became so politically correct. If you can't handle this as an adult, go live with the Amish, is definitely not for you.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Unsatisfying
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    leonlouisricci
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    There is so much here that is unresolved that it leaves an empty, unfulfilled feeling that the viewer has been suckered. Endless nude and sex scenes intrude on the mystery plot and in the end it is all for not much. Infamous for its explicit exploitation of said sex and nudity and forever frustrating for that's pretty much all there is. The soft-porn aside it can be a somewhat sultry, trashy ride with enough intrigue to keep the interest but not enough to make it a totally engaging entertainment. The biggest problem is the ambiguity about most of what unfolds. There are dangling plot elements and shallow, confusing side shows. In all, it is a murky, muddy, and thin piece of Pulp that has modern machinations and push the envelope displays of Crime Fiction laced with so much pomp that it's rendered impotent. The Movie has enough sizzle to attract viewers but cannot justify all the indulgence and will most likely be an unsatisfactory guilty pleasure. It is quite an overrated Film whose appeal comes from the most lowbrow lexicons of entertainment. But hey, someone once said...there's one born every minute. That's a lot of ticket buyers.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    While its premise is promising, "Basic Instinct" is executed in an inconsistent manner
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Chris Mizerak
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    There are many aspects, both good and bad, that you can pick up from Paul Verhoeven's 1992 erotic thriller Basic Instinct. On one hand, the premise of the film is kind of interesting and has a certain amount of complexity to it. Also, the film works okay enough as far as erotic films go with Sharon Stone flaunting out her body. On the other hand, the film is really cheesy and over-the-top at times as well as really dull in others. So if you're guessing that I think this film has an inconsistent feel to it, you'd probably be right. Basic Instinct follows a police detective (Michael Douglas) with a troubling past who is trying to solve the recent murder of a rock and roll star. The only eligible suspect so far is a book writer (Sharon Stone), whose stories are about women murdering men, who was the last person to see him. One of her own stories seems to play out in the same way that this victim was murdered. Naturally, the police suspects that she did it. The plot thickens however when the detective falls in love with the writer and learns some new developments about the case. In case I haven't mentioned it in any of my earlier reviews, let me get this off my chest. With a few exceptions, I really do not care at all for films centered on police detectives, cops or characters involved in similar professions since I find them to be boring, forgettable, and formulaic. While there are exceptions that either have interesting cases or characters, the rest of them just don't do a thing for me especially in terms of story, characters, and dialogue. Keeping that in mind, while I find whatever takes place in the police department to be fairly formulaic, it wasn't boring and whatever dialogue was being said wasn't as much torture to listen to as I thought it was going to be. I thought it was going to be too difficult to understand what was being said like other films of this genre, but luckily it was easy to understand what was being said, so that must count for something. On top of that, the story has a reasonably intriguing complexity to it and so do the two main characters. The hero and villain in this film are not clear cut, which is fairly authentic of real life. In reality, it's not crystal clear who the heroes and villains are, one culture may consider certain "heroes" villains, and vice versa. In other words, the screenplay was wise enough to put that aspect into the story. If you go see this film solely for looking at Sharon Stone's physique, you won't be disappointed since she really looks good in this film. I wouldn't be surprised if some viewers were reminded of the blonde women Alfred Hitchcock used in his pictures especially Kim Novak. I know I detected some similarities in terms of looks and wardrobe between Stone and the typical blondes Hitchcock used in his films. From what I've said so far, it sounds like this should be a good movie given my personal tastes. But sadly, Basic Instinct is one of those films in which the premise alone is better than the actual execution. One huge issue I had with Basic Instinct is the quality of the acting. I found the acting in this picture to be really weak. While the characters of the two leads are fascinating, the performances aren't executed well enough to do justice to the written characters. I also don't find the two leads (especially Douglas) either that believable or even that subtle/natural with their delivery. Furthermore, the performance by Jeanne Tripplehorn as a psychiatrist helping out Douglas' character is especially unconvincing, considering that I never believed that her character had enough experience in studying psychology to the point were she would become a professional one at such a young age. I simply didn't buy it at all, and the only point to her character existing in this film is solely for a plot twist that is used later in the film. I think she was of no importance to the plot whatsoever. Because of the disappointing acting quality, I don't really buy whatever ludicrous events take place in the plot as a result. Therefore, I can't take anything in the plot as seriously as the film seems to want me to. While the screenplay has its fair share of intriguing elements, there are also some elements of the screenplay especially with its dialogue that feels really cheesy and doesn't even sound the slightest bit realistic. As a result, that's how the film becomes inconsistent in terms of its delivery. In a nutshell, Basic Instinct definitely seems to be a mixed bag. While it has a good idea of what it wants to be, it seldom delivers on the promises it makes mainly because the acting is so mediocre to the point where it interferes with my ability to believe what's happening on screen. I'd only recommend this film if you're solely interested in checking out Stone's body. It's not much of an endorsement, but that's the highest praise I can give to this flick.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Murder All Around Her
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bkoganbing
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Although most reviewers have concentrated on the leads, Basic Instinct has some other fine performances in it. Still Michael Douglas as the sex obsessed cop and Sharon Stone as the amoral, multi-sexual woman who seems to have murder all around her give some iconic performances. A couple of SFPD detectives who played TV detectives, Michael Douglas in Streets Of San Francisco and George Dzundza in Law And Order, get assigned to the homicide of a former rockstar icon. The man had as the story tells us the 'coital moment of the century' before he died and as Michael Douglas finds out with Sharon Stone his prime suspect. It's not like Douglas hasn't any issues himself, he's seeing the SFPD shrink Jeanne Tripplehorn. One of those issues apparently is professional detachment as gets involved with both Tripplehorn and Stone. Far worse with Stone as she is a suspect. Murders in the past and murders in the present seem to pop up whenever Stone is around. She's an heiress to a fortune, a psychology major from college and licensed and an author of lurid novels. She knows how to press the buttons of both sexes and soon enough Douglas is in her world. The only one keeping a professional detachment is Dzundza who is not thinking with his male member. Even when an Internal Affairs cop who is investigating Douglas is murdered, Dzundza sticks by his partner. See what it gets him. In fact Dzundza and Tripplehorn don't get near enough credit for their work here. I think most know Tripplehorn as I do for playing Tom Cruise's wife in The Firm. She too is a woman with a lot of issues. As for George Dzundza as the only one in the film actually who seems to be normal, the others all seem to play off him. Still Sharon Stone's career was launched with what she did in Basic Instinct. This woman will wind up President of the USA or on death row, no middle ground for her. And you can believe she's every man and woman's coital moment of a lifetime. I don't know how successful or how good Basic Instinct 2 was, but seeing this has given me an incentive to see the sequel.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Bill Hicks and my Basic instinct was right, it's an unpleasant film.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ironhorse_iv
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It's sad to say that sex sells. Basic Instinct without a doubt sells, but it's just a sexy thriller that's got plenty of libido but not nearly as much brains as it thinks it has. It's extremely misogynistic and is very predictable. I was very disappointed with the whole movie, and had figured out the murderer within about 30 minutes into it. It's titillating, even exciting at times, but ultimately collapses under the weight of its own stupidity. The movie contained a lot of graphic sexual acts throughout the movie that makes it more of a soft porn movie in disguise & less than a film noir. It could have been better, if it cut down on the exotic a bit, and focus more on the story and give us a challenge. In the film's opening, Rockstar Boz is stabbed to death by a blonde woman with an ice pick during sex. We never see the woman's face -- just her blonde hair and, of course, most of her lust-inducing body. By just looking at the body of the killer, you can pretty much know who did it. The police find the dead body, and Det. Nick Curran, (Michael Douglas) was put on the case whom slept with his police-appointed shrink Dr. Beth Garner (Jeanne Triplehorn). Rather than getting a DNA test on the number one- suspect, Boz's girlfriend, Catherine Tramell (Sharon Stone), a famous crime novelist, the cops interview her. I know DNA testing was still in its early stages in the early '90s but convicting using DNA evidence alone has been proved fact since 1988, four years when the film was set. Well, Catherine use the interview to make fools out of them. The way she manipulates psychology was superbly awesome. Without Sharon Stone as femme fatale, this movie is nothing. Still, most people would remember from this scene just the famous leg switching, and not the acting. Although, the detectives were too stupid to realize that there is something about her that doesn't add up. We sees Catherine using it to break ice during the film. She even mentions how her book is about a detective falling for the wrong woman and that she kills him. Isn't it very clear who the killer is? Sooner than later, Nick get into Catherine's sex life. The movie moves with the suspense involving Nick and Catherine. He's supposed to be following this woman as a suspect but is actually falling for her deadly charm since Nick is dumb like the other cops. Clearly this film points out the men are just horny dumb pervs who slept before duty. The film tries to do a lot of dumb red herrings such as Beth is revealed to have had a past sexual encounter with Catherine, that according to Catherine developed an obsessive fixation on her as Beth copy her. The audience is suppose to wonder whether Beth killed Boz as is described in Catherine's book to frame her. Not once in the film, does Beth show any bit of bi or lesbians feelings. Catherine does with a girl name Roxy (Leilani Sarelle). The film was strongly opposed by gay rights activists, who criticized the film's portrayal of bisexual women as a murderous sociopaths. The featurette Blond Poison reveals the uproar the film caused during the San Francisco filming. They deplored it as being "anti-gay" and a reinforcement of Hollywood homophobia due to typecasting particularly lesbians as twisted and evil, or just act lesbians to get men's horny. I think the heterosexuals can also be equally offensive, as some feminists like Camille Paglia starts breaking things down to banal symbolisms, the opening killing with the ice pick is interpreted as, "Woman steals man's penis and uses it against him." men find themselves involuntarily cringing. Freudian Pscyhoanalysts have retained the term instinct that the film refer to human motivational forces (such as sex and aggression), sometimes represented as Eros - life instinct and Thanatos- death Instinct, but the real term is motivational forces or drives to correct the original error in the translation of Freud's work. Psychologist Abraham Maslow argued that humans no longer have instincts because we have the ability to override them in certain situations. For Maslow, an instinct is something which cannot be overridden, & therefore while the term may have applied to humans in the past, it no longer does. So the film should be title 'Basic Drives". It's clear why Joe Eszterhas was paid 3-million bucks for his script with its clever plot construction. Still there are pointless sequences like where Nick and Catherine engage in a car chase for no discernible reason other than to serve as a dire attempt to jack up the energy level. The film also has unlikeable characters. The hero Nick viciously rapes Beth in one scene. They're perfectly acceptable in the art of film, but Basic Instinct did go a little overboard with that sex. The film does good with its abstract images, the way it's shot from different angles, made it a little more elliptical, a bit less direct. The eerie Jerry Goldsmith theme gives the film a creepy tone. Basic Instinct was to transfers Mr. Verhoeven's flair for action-oriented material to the realm of Hitchcockian intrigue, but the results are so-so. Following the success of the film, Ezsterhas & Verhoeven went on to collaborate on Showgirls. (Another horrible mess). Since release, the blue-ray version add more graphic violence & sex into the film.This film is an affront to taste. It's an over-baked mind control fantasy, brought to life by a horrible script, and relieved of meaning by a hair brained plot. It's all Tougue in cheek really like a perv. It's depends on your kicks.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I'd have to be pretty stupid to write a book about killing and then kill him the way I described in my book. I'd be announcing myself as the killer. I'm not stupid.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    JohnRouseMerriottChard
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Basic Instinct is directed by Paul Verhoeven and written by Joe Eszterhaz. It stars Michael Douglas, Sharon Stone, George Dzundza, Jeanne Tripplehorn, Denis Arndt and Leilani Sarelle. Music is scored by Jerry Goldsmith and cinematography by Jan de Bont. Nick Curran (Douglas) of the SFPD is strung out and under investigation by Internal Affairs, last thing he needs is to be drawn into a dangerous relationship with a sex crazed blonde who may be a murderess... Time hasn't been kind to Verhoeven's soft-core porn thriller, where once was shock and awe killings (the film opening with a brutal mini ice-pick murder), steamy love scenes and a famed and controversial crotch shot, now is ludicrous orgasms, iffy effects and Michael Douglas' unappetising ass! Hell there was even protests during the film's initial theatre run as the gay community went up in arms about the portrayal of bisexuals possibly being mad murderers? Yet for all of its taming over the years, Basic Instinct can at least now been seen as the hugely efficient mystery thriller that it is, one that is propelled by some very good performances by the principal actors. The strength in the story is not in the sex or blood, but in the character arcs of Nick Curran and Catherine Tramell (Stone). Curran is a man perched on the edge of doom who is controlled totally by the women around him. He is by definition a quintessential film noir protagonist, in so deep he ultimately will be resigned to his fate. Catharine Tramell is a ultimate femme fatale, beautiful and seductive, she's always in control, leading all male characters where she wants them to go. There's a delicious kink to the narrative, with Verhoeven gleefully pulling the strings, a smirk no doubt etched onto his face. This is very good story telling, with a plot of substantial twists and turns. True, it does carry some soft-core baggage that can steer the restless away from the character strengths within, but for the neo-noir crowd there is much to enjoy here. 7.5/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Sharon Stone's finest hour
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    moviestar26
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    'Basic Instinct' was a film that rebooted the noir genre after it became rare in the early eighties. Prior to this the Coen brother's 'Blood Simple' attempted to revive the genre, but the industry was changing with the shift in audience's movie preferences. However this is more akin to being a sex thriller which also happens to incorporate a suspense element. 'Basic Instinct' takes the viewer back in time to the golden era of cinema when the femme fatales were glamorising the screen and became every male's dream fantasy. The film has been considered a classic and has not dated with time. The theme has been beautifully been One of my cult classic favourites from the 1990s. Whenever I catch a scene randomly on television, it brings back nostalgic memories of my childhood. I can still remember waking in the middle of the night just so I could record this movie secretly on my VCR. This is the movie that catapulted stone's career to international stardom. She immediately became a sex symbol and every man began dreaming of her. She immortalised a role that was so deep in characterisation. 'Catherine Trammel' was someone that was not only devious but smart, clever and manipulative. A role model so to speak that will certainly serve as an influence to many aspiring actresses and writers in the future. The role possessed every element that a negative character would have. Joe Esterhas is the writer. Previously he wrote 'Flash dance' and 'jagged edge' Most of his themes are similar. All negative roles about killers and murderers. 'Showgirls' and 'Jade' were also adapted for the screen. Unfortunately they failed at the box office and did not work. I think the audiences had higher expectations. 'Basic Instinct' has a fantastic script. This is the reason why the film worked. And then there is Paul Verhoeven who is a well known director in his home land. He has beautifully combined sex with the suspense genre. I am not very familiar with his Dutch movies. But he always had the style of depicting the theme of 'sex' as a weapon. I enjoyed the movie immensely, and being more of a reader than a movie- goer I jumped at the chance to read the book subsequent to seeing the motion picture. However, I feel that much of which made the movie great owes gratitude to the incredible soundtrack, imagery and skill of the actors; sometimes movies can be successfully novelised, but with Basic Instinct being the stimulus-rich move that it is I feel this was a failed attempt. The characters come off as threadbare and unexplored, lacking in depth or substance of any kind, and the seductively dark tone of the movie is lost on the page; it becomes rather humdrum and glancing, as if each page were written to keep up with the flow of the movie to be read within the hour. Where I was hoping to see some of the twisted, genius logic of Catherine Tramell explored on the page instead I found her to be de-powered, humanised and lacking of a great deal of her appeal as a result. It's worth the read for big fans of the Basic Instinct movies if only to explore the idea through a different form of media, (SPOILER) A San Francisco police detective who is investigated the murder of a retired rock star. The main suspect happens to be a novelist. She is under suspicion. She is released due to lack of evidence. Meanwhile the detective has maintains his belief that she is involved. He decides to pursue her and monitor her movements. The deeper his investigation proceeds, he succumbs to her charm and falls in love in spite knowing he is risking his life. His infatuation distances him from people around him and he refuses to listen to others. People he know become murdered. Eventually he finds it difficult to accept that she is a murderer as he begins to doubt his psychiatrist's past. (END OF SPOILER) The film is made with a sexy noir thriller tone. It brings back memories of Lawrence Kasden's 'Body Heat'. This was the last time a lead actress made an impression with a memorable role. Kathleen Turner became a popular star. At many moments the film feels like a horror thriller. There are many scenes that evoke a frightening feeling. What makes 'Basic Instinct' so unique is we are watching a women manipulating us with her attractive appeal that makes us want to believe she can be a killer. Her seductive charm works on the male protagonist, which leads to confusion. At the end we are eager to want to see her apprehended because we are disgusted how someone can desire to get away with murder for no reason. The sex scenes were unique and were the closest that could be categorised as 'soft porn'. This was one of the appealing factors that mad the film a success. 'Basic Instinct' has sustained it's quality over the years. It has managed to preserve it's quality and has not paled in front of movies that released recently. Due credit goes to Sharon Stone's performance and a winning script by Esterhas. The movie does follow true to the noir conventions. Anyone who is familiar with this will be able to notice them. However some of the typical noir rules were missing. There was no themes related to adultery or blackmailing. But it's relevance or lack of it doesn't seem significant as the this was a character driven film. Jerry Goldsmith's background score is specifically suited to the film's mood and atmosphere. It is still memorable and has different shades throughout the movie. It blends well with scenes and evokes the intriguing and haunting feeling.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Classic Verhoeven outrageousness.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    BA_Harrison
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/9/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Despite being built around the most 'basic' of plots, erotic thriller Basic Instinct remains director Paul Verhoeven's biggest commercial success, being one of the highest grossing titles of 1992. Unperturbed by the protestations of gay activists and uptight censor-happy moralists, who objected to the film's provocative cocktail of graphic sex and violence and its portrayal of bisexuals as crazed killers, the general public flocked to the cinema to revel in Verhoeven's heady concoction of wanton lust and cold-blooded violence. Written by Joe Eszterhas of Flashdance fame, the script is slick Hollywood nonsense, a flashy, trashy, twisting, turning tale clearly inspired by Hitchcock and the film-noir genre. Frequently teetering on the brink of preposterousness, its is precisely the kind of far-fetched nonsense that only a true maverick like Verhoeven could do justice toand boy, does he pull out all the stops here... Never one to do things by halves, the Dutch director opens his film as he means to go on, with a brutal murder that takes place during intercourse, a physically flawless blonde viciously stabbing her lover to death with an ice-pick. Scorching sex combined with gut churning nastiness, it's a real shocker (use the freeze-frame check out the outrageous shot of the pick going through the victim's nose!!!) and a clear indicator that this is to be no run-of-the-mill Hollywood thriller. The remainder of the film follows troubled detective Nick Curran (Michae Douglas) as he investigates the murder, stupidly becoming involved with his prime suspect, scorching hot, super intelligent, highly manipulative crime novelist Catherine Tramell (Sharon Stone), who may or may not be lining him up as her latest victim. Cue plenty more raunchy, near the knuckle nookie (including some rough rumpy-pumpy with the very sexy Jeanne 'gives me the' Tripplehorn), a few more gruesome deaths, a smidgen of exciting, pulse-pounding action, and the film's infamous blink-and-you'll miss-it shot of Stone's kebab as she uncrosses her legs during a police interview, all of which adds up to a whole heap of unmissable, jaw-dropping, eye-opening, big budget fun the likes of which we might never see again (unless Verhoeven can get Hollywood to forget all about Showgirls).
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "Good Seductive Thriller!"
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gwnightscream
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/9/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Michael Douglas, Sharon Stone, Jeanne Tripplehorn, George Dzundza and Leilani Sarelle star in this 1992 thriller. This begins in San Francisco with a retired rock star having sex with a blonde woman who brutally kills him with an icepick. Detective, Nick Curran (Douglas) and his partner, Gus (Dzundza) begin investigating and soon meet the victim's lover, Catherine Tramell (Stone) who becomes the main suspect. They learn that she's a writer and the murder coincidentally occurs in her recent novel. Nick starts to get involved with Catherine and begins questioning her motives when she plans on using him as a character in her next book. Tripplehorn plays Nick's ex-girlfriend, Beth Garner who is a psychiatrist and Sarelle plays Catherine's friend and lover, Roxy. Michael and Sharon have great chemistry and Jerry Goldsmith's score is excellent as usual. I recommend this good seductive thriller featuring Stone's famous leg-crossing scene.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Guilty Pleasure.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    AaronCapenBanner
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Michael Douglas plays San Francisco detective Nick Curran, who is investigating the brutal icepick murder of rock star Johnny Boz, which leads him to his girlfriend, novelist Catherine Tramell(Sharon Stone, unforgettable) Nick, though suspicious of Catherine, is nonetheless attracted to her brazen sensuality, and they begin a torrid affair, even though more murders pile up, and Catherine proves to be quite manipulative and intelligent...is she guilty? Controversial film directed by Paul Verhoeven is never boring, though normally having no one in the story to root for would be a problem, film is so slickly made and in-your-face that it may be the epitome of the guilty pleasure; trashy yet enjoyable. Both lead actors are excellent though, even if the mystery is never satisfactorily resolved.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    thrilling till the end
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    acpaloveshavefun
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I recently re saw this movie, and if your a thriller fan you'll absolutely love it. I was at the edge of my seat the entire time, trying to see if I can solve it. Definitely not for kids by the way. Please do not listen for the old bittys out there who are saying that This movie is porn,if I remember correctly the movie psycho had the infamous shower scene. yes its violent and yes it has sexual content, and "Adult situation" but that's what makes a really good movie. This was a perfect example of a great movie before everyone became so politically correct. If you can't handle this as an adult, go live with the Amish, is definitely not for you.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Unsatisfying
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    leonlouisricci
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    There is so much here that is unresolved that it leaves an empty, unfulfilled feeling that the viewer has been suckered. Endless nude and sex scenes intrude on the mystery plot and in the end it is all for not much. Infamous for its explicit exploitation of said sex and nudity and forever frustrating for that's pretty much all there is. The soft-porn aside it can be a somewhat sultry, trashy ride with enough intrigue to keep the interest but not enough to make it a totally engaging entertainment. The biggest problem is the ambiguity about most of what unfolds. There are dangling plot elements and shallow, confusing side shows. In all, it is a murky, muddy, and thin piece of Pulp that has modern machinations and push the envelope displays of Crime Fiction laced with so much pomp that it's rendered impotent. The Movie has enough sizzle to attract viewers but cannot justify all the indulgence and will most likely be an unsatisfactory guilty pleasure. It is quite an overrated Film whose appeal comes from the most lowbrow lexicons of entertainment. But hey, someone once said...there's one born every minute. That's a lot of ticket buyers.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    While its premise is promising, "Basic Instinct" is executed in an inconsistent manner
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Chris Mizerak
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    There are many aspects, both good and bad, that you can pick up from Paul Verhoeven's 1992 erotic thriller Basic Instinct. On one hand, the premise of the film is kind of interesting and has a certain amount of complexity to it. Also, the film works okay enough as far as erotic films go with Sharon Stone flaunting out her body. On the other hand, the film is really cheesy and over-the-top at times as well as really dull in others. So if you're guessing that I think this film has an inconsistent feel to it, you'd probably be right. Basic Instinct follows a police detective (Michael Douglas) with a troubling past who is trying to solve the recent murder of a rock and roll star. The only eligible suspect so far is a book writer (Sharon Stone), whose stories are about women murdering men, who was the last person to see him. One of her own stories seems to play out in the same way that this victim was murdered. Naturally, the police suspects that she did it. The plot thickens however when the detective falls in love with the writer and learns some new developments about the case. In case I haven't mentioned it in any of my earlier reviews, let me get this off my chest. With a few exceptions, I really do not care at all for films centered on police detectives, cops or characters involved in similar professions since I find them to be boring, forgettable, and formulaic. While there are exceptions that either have interesting cases or characters, the rest of them just don't do a thing for me especially in terms of story, characters, and dialogue. Keeping that in mind, while I find whatever takes place in the police department to be fairly formulaic, it wasn't boring and whatever dialogue was being said wasn't as much torture to listen to as I thought it was going to be. I thought it was going to be too difficult to understand what was being said like other films of this genre, but luckily it was easy to understand what was being said, so that must count for something. On top of that, the story has a reasonably intriguing complexity to it and so do the two main characters. The hero and villain in this film are not clear cut, which is fairly authentic of real life. In reality, it's not crystal clear who the heroes and villains are, one culture may consider certain "heroes" villains, and vice versa. In other words, the screenplay was wise enough to put that aspect into the story. If you go see this film solely for looking at Sharon Stone's physique, you won't be disappointed since she really looks good in this film. I wouldn't be surprised if some viewers were reminded of the blonde women Alfred Hitchcock used in his pictures especially Kim Novak. I know I detected some similarities in terms of looks and wardrobe between Stone and the typical blondes Hitchcock used in his films. From what I've said so far, it sounds like this should be a good movie given my personal tastes. But sadly, Basic Instinct is one of those films in which the premise alone is better than the actual execution. One huge issue I had with Basic Instinct is the quality of the acting. I found the acting in this picture to be really weak. While the characters of the two leads are fascinating, the performances aren't executed well enough to do justice to the written characters. I also don't find the two leads (especially Douglas) either that believable or even that subtle/natural with their delivery. Furthermore, the performance by Jeanne Tripplehorn as a psychiatrist helping out Douglas' character is especially unconvincing, considering that I never believed that her character had enough experience in studying psychology to the point were she would become a professional one at such a young age. I simply didn't buy it at all, and the only point to her character existing in this film is solely for a plot twist that is used later in the film. I think she was of no importance to the plot whatsoever. Because of the disappointing acting quality, I don't really buy whatever ludicrous events take place in the plot as a result. Therefore, I can't take anything in the plot as seriously as the film seems to want me to. While the screenplay has its fair share of intriguing elements, there are also some elements of the screenplay especially with its dialogue that feels really cheesy and doesn't even sound the slightest bit realistic. As a result, that's how the film becomes inconsistent in terms of its delivery. In a nutshell, Basic Instinct definitely seems to be a mixed bag. While it has a good idea of what it wants to be, it seldom delivers on the promises it makes mainly because the acting is so mediocre to the point where it interferes with my ability to believe what's happening on screen. I'd only recommend this film if you're solely interested in checking out Stone's body. It's not much of an endorsement, but that's the highest praise I can give to this flick.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Murder All Around Her
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bkoganbing
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Although most reviewers have concentrated on the leads, Basic Instinct has some other fine performances in it. Still Michael Douglas as the sex obsessed cop and Sharon Stone as the amoral, multi-sexual woman who seems to have murder all around her give some iconic performances. A couple of SFPD detectives who played TV detectives, Michael Douglas in Streets Of San Francisco and George Dzundza in Law And Order, get assigned to the homicide of a former rockstar icon. The man had as the story tells us the 'coital moment of the century' before he died and as Michael Douglas finds out with Sharon Stone his prime suspect. It's not like Douglas hasn't any issues himself, he's seeing the SFPD shrink Jeanne Tripplehorn. One of those issues apparently is professional detachment as gets involved with both Tripplehorn and Stone. Far worse with Stone as she is a suspect. Murders in the past and murders in the present seem to pop up whenever Stone is around. She's an heiress to a fortune, a psychology major from college and licensed and an author of lurid novels. She knows how to press the buttons of both sexes and soon enough Douglas is in her world. The only one keeping a professional detachment is Dzundza who is not thinking with his male member. Even when an Internal Affairs cop who is investigating Douglas is murdered, Dzundza sticks by his partner. See what it gets him. In fact Dzundza and Tripplehorn don't get near enough credit for their work here. I think most know Tripplehorn as I do for playing Tom Cruise's wife in The Firm. She too is a woman with a lot of issues. As for George Dzundza as the only one in the film actually who seems to be normal, the others all seem to play off him. Still Sharon Stone's career was launched with what she did in Basic Instinct. This woman will wind up President of the USA or on death row, no middle ground for her. And you can believe she's every man and woman's coital moment of a lifetime. I don't know how successful or how good Basic Instinct 2 was, but seeing this has given me an incentive to see the sequel.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Bill Hicks and my Basic instinct was right, it's an unpleasant film.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ironhorse_iv
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It's sad to say that sex sells. Basic Instinct without a doubt sells, but it's just a sexy thriller that's got plenty of libido but not nearly as much brains as it thinks it has. It's extremely misogynistic and is very predictable. I was very disappointed with the whole movie, and had figured out the murderer within about 30 minutes into it. It's titillating, even exciting at times, but ultimately collapses under the weight of its own stupidity. The movie contained a lot of graphic sexual acts throughout the movie that makes it more of a soft porn movie in disguise & less than a film noir. It could have been better, if it cut down on the exotic a bit, and focus more on the story and give us a challenge. In the film's opening, Rockstar Boz is stabbed to death by a blonde woman with an ice pick during sex. We never see the woman's face -- just her blonde hair and, of course, most of her lust-inducing body. By just looking at the body of the killer, you can pretty much know who did it. The police find the dead body, and Det. Nick Curran, (Michael Douglas) was put on the case whom slept with his police-appointed shrink Dr. Beth Garner (Jeanne Triplehorn). Rather than getting a DNA test on the number one- suspect, Boz's girlfriend, Catherine Tramell (Sharon Stone), a famous crime novelist, the cops interview her. I know DNA testing was still in its early stages in the early '90s but convicting using DNA evidence alone has been proved fact since 1988, four years when the film was set. Well, Catherine use the interview to make fools out of them. The way she manipulates psychology was superbly awesome. Without Sharon Stone as femme fatale, this movie is nothing. Still, most people would remember from this scene just the famous leg switching, and not the acting. Although, the detectives were too stupid to realize that there is something about her that doesn't add up. We sees Catherine using it to break ice during the film. She even mentions how her book is about a detective falling for the wrong woman and that she kills him. Isn't it very clear who the killer is? Sooner than later, Nick get into Catherine's sex life. The movie moves with the suspense involving Nick and Catherine. He's supposed to be following this woman as a suspect but is actually falling for her deadly charm since Nick is dumb like the other cops. Clearly this film points out the men are just horny dumb pervs who slept before duty. The film tries to do a lot of dumb red herrings such as Beth is revealed to have had a past sexual encounter with Catherine, that according to Catherine developed an obsessive fixation on her as Beth copy her. The audience is suppose to wonder whether Beth killed Boz as is described in Catherine's book to frame her. Not once in the film, does Beth show any bit of bi or lesbians feelings. Catherine does with a girl name Roxy (Leilani Sarelle). The film was strongly opposed by gay rights activists, who criticized the film's portrayal of bisexual women as a murderous sociopaths. The featurette Blond Poison reveals the uproar the film caused during the San Francisco filming. They deplored it as being "anti-gay" and a reinforcement of Hollywood homophobia due to typecasting particularly lesbians as twisted and evil, or just act lesbians to get men's horny. I think the heterosexuals can also be equally offensive, as some feminists like Camille Paglia starts breaking things down to banal symbolisms, the opening killing with the ice pick is interpreted as, "Woman steals man's penis and uses it against him." men find themselves involuntarily cringing. Freudian Pscyhoanalysts have retained the term instinct that the film refer to human motivational forces (such as sex and aggression), sometimes represented as Eros - life instinct and Thanatos- death Instinct, but the real term is motivational forces or drives to correct the original error in the translation of Freud's work. Psychologist Abraham Maslow argued that humans no longer have instincts because we have the ability to override them in certain situations. For Maslow, an instinct is something which cannot be overridden, & therefore while the term may have applied to humans in the past, it no longer does. So the film should be title 'Basic Drives". It's clear why Joe Eszterhas was paid 3-million bucks for his script with its clever plot construction. Still there are pointless sequences like where Nick and Catherine engage in a car chase for no discernible reason other than to serve as a dire attempt to jack up the energy level. The film also has unlikeable characters. The hero Nick viciously rapes Beth in one scene. They're perfectly acceptable in the art of film, but Basic Instinct did go a little overboard with that sex. The film does good with its abstract images, the way it's shot from different angles, made it a little more elliptical, a bit less direct. The eerie Jerry Goldsmith theme gives the film a creepy tone. Basic Instinct was to transfers Mr. Verhoeven's flair for action-oriented material to the realm of Hitchcockian intrigue, but the results are so-so. Following the success of the film, Ezsterhas & Verhoeven went on to collaborate on Showgirls. (Another horrible mess). Since release, the blue-ray version add more graphic violence & sex into the film.This film is an affront to taste. It's an over-baked mind control fantasy, brought to life by a horrible script, and relieved of meaning by a hair brained plot. It's all Tougue in cheek really like a perv. It's depends on your kicks.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I'd have to be pretty stupid to write a book about killing and then kill him the way I described in my book. I'd be announcing myself as the killer. I'm not stupid.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    JohnRouseMerriottChard
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Basic Instinct is directed by Paul Verhoeven and written by Joe Eszterhaz. It stars Michael Douglas, Sharon Stone, George Dzundza, Jeanne Tripplehorn, Denis Arndt and Leilani Sarelle. Music is scored by Jerry Goldsmith and cinematography by Jan de Bont. Nick Curran (Douglas) of the SFPD is strung out and under investigation by Internal Affairs, last thing he needs is to be drawn into a dangerous relationship with a sex crazed blonde who may be a murderess... Time hasn't been kind to Verhoeven's soft-core porn thriller, where once was shock and awe killings (the film opening with a brutal mini ice-pick murder), steamy love scenes and a famed and controversial crotch shot, now is ludicrous orgasms, iffy effects and Michael Douglas' unappetising ass! Hell there was even protests during the film's initial theatre run as the gay community went up in arms about the portrayal of bisexuals possibly being mad murderers? Yet for all of its taming over the years, Basic Instinct can at least now been seen as the hugely efficient mystery thriller that it is, one that is propelled by some very good performances by the principal actors. The strength in the story is not in the sex or blood, but in the character arcs of Nick Curran and Catherine Tramell (Stone). Curran is a man perched on the edge of doom who is controlled totally by the women around him. He is by definition a quintessential film noir protagonist, in so deep he ultimately will be resigned to his fate. Catharine Tramell is a ultimate femme fatale, beautiful and seductive, she's always in control, leading all male characters where she wants them to go. There's a delicious kink to the narrative, with Verhoeven gleefully pulling the strings, a smirk no doubt etched onto his face. This is very good story telling, with a plot of substantial twists and turns. True, it does carry some soft-core baggage that can steer the restless away from the character strengths within, but for the neo-noir crowd there is much to enjoy here. 7.5/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Sharon Stone's finest hour
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    moviestar26
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    'Basic Instinct' was a film that rebooted the noir genre after it became rare in the early eighties. Prior to this the Coen brother's 'Blood Simple' attempted to revive the genre, but the industry was changing with the shift in audience's movie preferences. However this is more akin to being a sex thriller which also happens to incorporate a suspense element. 'Basic Instinct' takes the viewer back in time to the golden era of cinema when the femme fatales were glamorising the screen and became every male's dream fantasy. The film has been considered a classic and has not dated with time. The theme has been beautifully been One of my cult classic favourites from the 1990s. Whenever I catch a scene randomly on television, it brings back nostalgic memories of my childhood. I can still remember waking in the middle of the night just so I could record this movie secretly on my VCR. This is the movie that catapulted stone's career to international stardom. She immediately became a sex symbol and every man began dreaming of her. She immortalised a role that was so deep in characterisation. 'Catherine Trammel' was someone that was not only devious but smart, clever and manipulative. A role model so to speak that will certainly serve as an influence to many aspiring actresses and writers in the future. The role possessed every element that a negative character would have. Joe Esterhas is the writer. Previously he wrote 'Flash dance' and 'jagged edge' Most of his themes are similar. All negative roles about killers and murderers. 'Showgirls' and 'Jade' were also adapted for the screen. Unfortunately they failed at the box office and did not work. I think the audiences had higher expectations. 'Basic Instinct' has a fantastic script. This is the reason why the film worked. And then there is Paul Verhoeven who is a well known director in his home land. He has beautifully combined sex with the suspense genre. I am not very familiar with his Dutch movies. But he always had the style of depicting the theme of 'sex' as a weapon. I enjoyed the movie immensely, and being more of a reader than a movie- goer I jumped at the chance to read the book subsequent to seeing the motion picture. However, I feel that much of which made the movie great owes gratitude to the incredible soundtrack, imagery and skill of the actors; sometimes movies can be successfully novelised, but with Basic Instinct being the stimulus-rich move that it is I feel this was a failed attempt. The characters come off as threadbare and unexplored, lacking in depth or substance of any kind, and the seductively dark tone of the movie is lost on the page; it becomes rather humdrum and glancing, as if each page were written to keep up with the flow of the movie to be read within the hour. Where I was hoping to see some of the twisted, genius logic of Catherine Tramell explored on the page instead I found her to be de-powered, humanised and lacking of a great deal of her appeal as a result. It's worth the read for big fans of the Basic Instinct movies if only to explore the idea through a different form of media, (SPOILER) A San Francisco police detective who is investigated the murder of a retired rock star. The main suspect happens to be a novelist. She is under suspicion. She is released due to lack of evidence. Meanwhile the detective has maintains his belief that she is involved. He decides to pursue her and monitor her movements. The deeper his investigation proceeds, he succumbs to her charm and falls in love in spite knowing he is risking his life. His infatuation distances him from people around him and he refuses to listen to others. People he know become murdered. Eventually he finds it difficult to accept that she is a murderer as he begins to doubt his psychiatrist's past. (END OF SPOILER) The film is made with a sexy noir thriller tone. It brings back memories of Lawrence Kasden's 'Body Heat'. This was the last time a lead actress made an impression with a memorable role. Kathleen Turner became a popular star. At many moments the film feels like a horror thriller. There are many scenes that evoke a frightening feeling. What makes 'Basic Instinct' so unique is we are watching a women manipulating us with her attractive appeal that makes us want to believe she can be a killer. Her seductive charm works on the male protagonist, which leads to confusion. At the end we are eager to want to see her apprehended because we are disgusted how someone can desire to get away with murder for no reason. The sex scenes were unique and were the closest that could be categorised as 'soft porn'. This was one of the appealing factors that mad the film a success. 'Basic Instinct' has sustained it's quality over the years. It has managed to preserve it's quality and has not paled in front of movies that released recently. Due credit goes to Sharon Stone's performance and a winning script by Esterhas. The movie does follow true to the noir conventions. Anyone who is familiar with this will be able to notice them. However some of the typical noir rules were missing. There was no themes related to adultery or blackmailing. But it's relevance or lack of it doesn't seem significant as the this was a character driven film. Jerry Goldsmith's background score is specifically suited to the film's mood and atmosphere. It is still memorable and has different shades throughout the movie. It blends well with scenes and evokes the intriguing and haunting feeling.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Classic Verhoeven outrageousness.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    BA_Harrison
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/9/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Despite being built around the most 'basic' of plots, erotic thriller Basic Instinct remains director Paul Verhoeven's biggest commercial success, being one of the highest grossing titles of 1992. Unperturbed by the protestations of gay activists and uptight censor-happy moralists, who objected to the film's provocative cocktail of graphic sex and violence and its portrayal of bisexuals as crazed killers, the general public flocked to the cinema to revel in Verhoeven's heady concoction of wanton lust and cold-blooded violence. Written by Joe Eszterhas of Flashdance fame, the script is slick Hollywood nonsense, a flashy, trashy, twisting, turning tale clearly inspired by Hitchcock and the film-noir genre. Frequently teetering on the brink of preposterousness, its is precisely the kind of far-fetched nonsense that only a true maverick like Verhoeven could do justice toand boy, does he pull out all the stops here... Never one to do things by halves, the Dutch director opens his film as he means to go on, with a brutal murder that takes place during intercourse, a physically flawless blonde viciously stabbing her lover to death with an ice-pick. Scorching sex combined with gut churning nastiness, it's a real shocker (use the freeze-frame check out the outrageous shot of the pick going through the victim's nose!!!) and a clear indicator that this is to be no run-of-the-mill Hollywood thriller. The remainder of the film follows troubled detective Nick Curran (Michae Douglas) as he investigates the murder, stupidly becoming involved with his prime suspect, scorching hot, super intelligent, highly manipulative crime novelist Catherine Tramell (Sharon Stone), who may or may not be lining him up as her latest victim. Cue plenty more raunchy, near the knuckle nookie (including some rough rumpy-pumpy with the very sexy Jeanne 'gives me the' Tripplehorn), a few more gruesome deaths, a smidgen of exciting, pulse-pounding action, and the film's infamous blink-and-you'll miss-it shot of Stone's kebab as she uncrosses her legs during a police interview, all of which adds up to a whole heap of unmissable, jaw-dropping, eye-opening, big budget fun the likes of which we might never see again (unless Verhoeven can get Hollywood to forget all about Showgirls).
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "Good Seductive Thriller!"
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gwnightscream
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/9/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Michael Douglas, Sharon Stone, Jeanne Tripplehorn, George Dzundza and Leilani Sarelle star in this 1992 thriller. This begins in San Francisco with a retired rock star having sex with a blonde woman who brutally kills him with an icepick. Detective, Nick Curran (Douglas) and his partner, Gus (Dzundza) begin investigating and soon meet the victim's lover, Catherine Tramell (Stone) who becomes the main suspect. They learn that she's a writer and the murder coincidentally occurs in her recent novel. Nick starts to get involved with Catherine and begins questioning her motives when she plans on using him as a character in her next book. Tripplehorn plays Nick's ex-girlfriend, Beth Garner who is a psychiatrist and Sarelle plays Catherine's friend and lover, Roxy. Michael and Sharon have great chemistry and Jerry Goldsmith's score is excellent as usual. I recommend this good seductive thriller featuring Stone's famous leg-crossing scene.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Guilty Pleasure.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    AaronCapenBanner
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Michael Douglas plays San Francisco detective Nick Curran, who is investigating the brutal icepick murder of rock star Johnny Boz, which leads him to his girlfriend, novelist Catherine Tramell(Sharon Stone, unforgettable) Nick, though suspicious of Catherine, is nonetheless attracted to her brazen sensuality, and they begin a torrid affair, even though more murders pile up, and Catherine proves to be quite manipulative and intelligent...is she guilty? Controversial film directed by Paul Verhoeven is never boring, though normally having no one in the story to root for would be a problem, film is so slickly made and in-your-face that it may be the epitome of the guilty pleasure; trashy yet enjoyable. Both lead actors are excellent though, even if the mystery is never satisfactorily resolved.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    thrilling till the end
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    acpaloveshavefun
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I recently re saw this movie, and if your a thriller fan you'll absolutely love it. I was at the edge of my seat the entire time, trying to see if I can solve it. Definitely not for kids by the way. Please do not listen for the old bittys out there who are saying that This movie is porn,if I remember correctly the movie psycho had the infamous shower scene. yes its violent and yes it has sexual content, and "Adult situation" but that's what makes a really good movie. This was a perfect example of a great movie before everyone became so politically correct. If you can't handle this as an adult, go live with the Amish, is definitely not for you.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Unsatisfying
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    leonlouisricci
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    There is so much here that is unresolved that it leaves an empty, unfulfilled feeling that the viewer has been suckered. Endless nude and sex scenes intrude on the mystery plot and in the end it is all for not much. Infamous for its explicit exploitation of said sex and nudity and forever frustrating for that's pretty much all there is. The soft-porn aside it can be a somewhat sultry, trashy ride with enough intrigue to keep the interest but not enough to make it a totally engaging entertainment. The biggest problem is the ambiguity about most of what unfolds. There are dangling plot elements and shallow, confusing side shows. In all, it is a murky, muddy, and thin piece of Pulp that has modern machinations and push the envelope displays of Crime Fiction laced with so much pomp that it's rendered impotent. The Movie has enough sizzle to attract viewers but cannot justify all the indulgence and will most likely be an unsatisfactory guilty pleasure. It is quite an overrated Film whose appeal comes from the most lowbrow lexicons of entertainment. But hey, someone once said...there's one born every minute. That's a lot of ticket buyers.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    While its premise is promising, "Basic Instinct" is executed in an inconsistent manner
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Chris Mizerak
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    There are many aspects, both good and bad, that you can pick up from Paul Verhoeven's 1992 erotic thriller Basic Instinct. On one hand, the premise of the film is kind of interesting and has a certain amount of complexity to it. Also, the film works okay enough as far as erotic films go with Sharon Stone flaunting out her body. On the other hand, the film is really cheesy and over-the-top at times as well as really dull in others. So if you're guessing that I think this film has an inconsistent feel to it, you'd probably be right. Basic Instinct follows a police detective (Michael Douglas) with a troubling past who is trying to solve the recent murder of a rock and roll star. The only eligible suspect so far is a book writer (Sharon Stone), whose stories are about women murdering men, who was the last person to see him. One of her own stories seems to play out in the same way that this victim was murdered. Naturally, the police suspects that she did it. The plot thickens however when the detective falls in love with the writer and learns some new developments about the case. In case I haven't mentioned it in any of my earlier reviews, let me get this off my chest. With a few exceptions, I really do not care at all for films centered on police detectives, cops or characters involved in similar professions since I find them to be boring, forgettable, and formulaic. While there are exceptions that either have interesting cases or characters, the rest of them just don't do a thing for me especially in terms of story, characters, and dialogue. Keeping that in mind, while I find whatever takes place in the police department to be fairly formulaic, it wasn't boring and whatever dialogue was being said wasn't as much torture to listen to as I thought it was going to be. I thought it was going to be too difficult to understand what was being said like other films of this genre, but luckily it was easy to understand what was being said, so that must count for something. On top of that, the story has a reasonably intriguing complexity to it and so do the two main characters. The hero and villain in this film are not clear cut, which is fairly authentic of real life. In reality, it's not crystal clear who the heroes and villains are, one culture may consider certain "heroes" villains, and vice versa. In other words, the screenplay was wise enough to put that aspect into the story. If you go see this film solely for looking at Sharon Stone's physique, you won't be disappointed since she really looks good in this film. I wouldn't be surprised if some viewers were reminded of the blonde women Alfred Hitchcock used in his pictures especially Kim Novak. I know I detected some similarities in terms of looks and wardrobe between Stone and the typical blondes Hitchcock used in his films. From what I've said so far, it sounds like this should be a good movie given my personal tastes. But sadly, Basic Instinct is one of those films in which the premise alone is better than the actual execution. One huge issue I had with Basic Instinct is the quality of the acting. I found the acting in this picture to be really weak. While the characters of the two leads are fascinating, the performances aren't executed well enough to do justice to the written characters. I also don't find the two leads (especially Douglas) either that believable or even that subtle/natural with their delivery. Furthermore, the performance by Jeanne Tripplehorn as a psychiatrist helping out Douglas' character is especially unconvincing, considering that I never believed that her character had enough experience in studying psychology to the point were she would become a professional one at such a young age. I simply didn't buy it at all, and the only point to her character existing in this film is solely for a plot twist that is used later in the film. I think she was of no importance to the plot whatsoever. Because of the disappointing acting quality, I don't really buy whatever ludicrous events take place in the plot as a result. Therefore, I can't take anything in the plot as seriously as the film seems to want me to. While the screenplay has its fair share of intriguing elements, there are also some elements of the screenplay especially with its dialogue that feels really cheesy and doesn't even sound the slightest bit realistic. As a result, that's how the film becomes inconsistent in terms of its delivery. In a nutshell, Basic Instinct definitely seems to be a mixed bag. While it has a good idea of what it wants to be, it seldom delivers on the promises it makes mainly because the acting is so mediocre to the point where it interferes with my ability to believe what's happening on screen. I'd only recommend this film if you're solely interested in checking out Stone's body. It's not much of an endorsement, but that's the highest praise I can give to this flick.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Murder All Around Her
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bkoganbing
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Although most reviewers have concentrated on the leads, Basic Instinct has some other fine performances in it. Still Michael Douglas as the sex obsessed cop and Sharon Stone as the amoral, multi-sexual woman who seems to have murder all around her give some iconic performances. A couple of SFPD detectives who played TV detectives, Michael Douglas in Streets Of San Francisco and George Dzundza in Law And Order, get assigned to the homicide of a former rockstar icon. The man had as the story tells us the 'coital moment of the century' before he died and as Michael Douglas finds out with Sharon Stone his prime suspect. It's not like Douglas hasn't any issues himself, he's seeing the SFPD shrink Jeanne Tripplehorn. One of those issues apparently is professional detachment as gets involved with both Tripplehorn and Stone. Far worse with Stone as she is a suspect. Murders in the past and murders in the present seem to pop up whenever Stone is around. She's an heiress to a fortune, a psychology major from college and licensed and an author of lurid novels. She knows how to press the buttons of both sexes and soon enough Douglas is in her world. The only one keeping a professional detachment is Dzundza who is not thinking with his male member. Even when an Internal Affairs cop who is investigating Douglas is murdered, Dzundza sticks by his partner. See what it gets him. In fact Dzundza and Tripplehorn don't get near enough credit for their work here. I think most know Tripplehorn as I do for playing Tom Cruise's wife in The Firm. She too is a woman with a lot of issues. As for George Dzundza as the only one in the film actually who seems to be normal, the others all seem to play off him. Still Sharon Stone's career was launched with what she did in Basic Instinct. This woman will wind up President of the USA or on death row, no middle ground for her. And you can believe she's every man and woman's coital moment of a lifetime. I don't know how successful or how good Basic Instinct 2 was, but seeing this has given me an incentive to see the sequel.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Bill Hicks and my Basic instinct was right, it's an unpleasant film.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ironhorse_iv
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It's sad to say that sex sells. Basic Instinct without a doubt sells, but it's just a sexy thriller that's got plenty of libido but not nearly as much brains as it thinks it has. It's extremely misogynistic and is very predictable. I was very disappointed with the whole movie, and had figured out the murderer within about 30 minutes into it. It's titillating, even exciting at times, but ultimately collapses under the weight of its own stupidity. The movie contained a lot of graphic sexual acts throughout the movie that makes it more of a soft porn movie in disguise & less than a film noir. It could have been better, if it cut down on the exotic a bit, and focus more on the story and give us a challenge. In the film's opening, Rockstar Boz is stabbed to death by a blonde woman with an ice pick during sex. We never see the woman's face -- just her blonde hair and, of course, most of her lust-inducing body. By just looking at the body of the killer, you can pretty much know who did it. The police find the dead body, and Det. Nick Curran, (Michael Douglas) was put on the case whom slept with his police-appointed shrink Dr. Beth Garner (Jeanne Triplehorn). Rather than getting a DNA test on the number one- suspect, Boz's girlfriend, Catherine Tramell (Sharon Stone), a famous crime novelist, the cops interview her. I know DNA testing was still in its early stages in the early '90s but convicting using DNA evidence alone has been proved fact since 1988, four years when the film was set. Well, Catherine use the interview to make fools out of them. The way she manipulates psychology was superbly awesome. Without Sharon Stone as femme fatale, this movie is nothing. Still, most people would remember from this scene just the famous leg switching, and not the acting. Although, the detectives were too stupid to realize that there is something about her that doesn't add up. We sees Catherine using it to break ice during the film. She even mentions how her book is about a detective falling for the wrong woman and that she kills him. Isn't it very clear who the killer is? Sooner than later, Nick get into Catherine's sex life. The movie moves with the suspense involving Nick and Catherine. He's supposed to be following this woman as a suspect but is actually falling for her deadly charm since Nick is dumb like the other cops. Clearly this film points out the men are just horny dumb pervs who slept before duty. The film tries to do a lot of dumb red herrings such as Beth is revealed to have had a past sexual encounter with Catherine, that according to Catherine developed an obsessive fixation on her as Beth copy her. The audience is suppose to wonder whether Beth killed Boz as is described in Catherine's book to frame her. Not once in the film, does Beth show any bit of bi or lesbians feelings. Catherine does with a girl name Roxy (Leilani Sarelle). The film was strongly opposed by gay rights activists, who criticized the film's portrayal of bisexual women as a murderous sociopaths. The featurette Blond Poison reveals the uproar the film caused during the San Francisco filming. They deplored it as being "anti-gay" and a reinforcement of Hollywood homophobia due to typecasting particularly lesbians as twisted and evil, or just act lesbians to get men's horny. I think the heterosexuals can also be equally offensive, as some feminists like Camille Paglia starts breaking things down to banal symbolisms, the opening killing with the ice pick is interpreted as, "Woman steals man's penis and uses it against him." men find themselves involuntarily cringing. Freudian Pscyhoanalysts have retained the term instinct that the film refer to human motivational forces (such as sex and aggression), sometimes represented as Eros - life instinct and Thanatos- death Instinct, but the real term is motivational forces or drives to correct the original error in the translation of Freud's work. Psychologist Abraham Maslow argued that humans no longer have instincts because we have the ability to override them in certain situations. For Maslow, an instinct is something which cannot be overridden, & therefore while the term may have applied to humans in the past, it no longer does. So the film should be title 'Basic Drives". It's clear why Joe Eszterhas was paid 3-million bucks for his script with its clever plot construction. Still there are pointless sequences like where Nick and Catherine engage in a car chase for no discernible reason other than to serve as a dire attempt to jack up the energy level. The film also has unlikeable characters. The hero Nick viciously rapes Beth in one scene. They're perfectly acceptable in the art of film, but Basic Instinct did go a little overboard with that sex. The film does good with its abstract images, the way it's shot from different angles, made it a little more elliptical, a bit less direct. The eerie Jerry Goldsmith theme gives the film a creepy tone. Basic Instinct was to transfers Mr. Verhoeven's flair for action-oriented material to the realm of Hitchcockian intrigue, but the results are so-so. Following the success of the film, Ezsterhas & Verhoeven went on to collaborate on Showgirls. (Another horrible mess). Since release, the blue-ray version add more graphic violence & sex into the film.This film is an affront to taste. It's an over-baked mind control fantasy, brought to life by a horrible script, and relieved of meaning by a hair brained plot. It's all Tougue in cheek really like a perv. It's depends on your kicks.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I'd have to be pretty stupid to write a book about killing and then kill him the way I described in my book. I'd be announcing myself as the killer. I'm not stupid.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    JohnRouseMerriottChard
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Basic Instinct is directed by Paul Verhoeven and written by Joe Eszterhaz. It stars Michael Douglas, Sharon Stone, George Dzundza, Jeanne Tripplehorn, Denis Arndt and Leilani Sarelle. Music is scored by Jerry Goldsmith and cinematography by Jan de Bont. Nick Curran (Douglas) of the SFPD is strung out and under investigation by Internal Affairs, last thing he needs is to be drawn into a dangerous relationship with a sex crazed blonde who may be a murderess... Time hasn't been kind to Verhoeven's soft-core porn thriller, where once was shock and awe killings (the film opening with a brutal mini ice-pick murder), steamy love scenes and a famed and controversial crotch shot, now is ludicrous orgasms, iffy effects and Michael Douglas' unappetising ass! Hell there was even protests during the film's initial theatre run as the gay community went up in arms about the portrayal of bisexuals possibly being mad murderers? Yet for all of its taming over the years, Basic Instinct can at least now been seen as the hugely efficient mystery thriller that it is, one that is propelled by some very good performances by the principal actors. The strength in the story is not in the sex or blood, but in the character arcs of Nick Curran and Catherine Tramell (Stone). Curran is a man perched on the edge of doom who is controlled totally by the women around him. He is by definition a quintessential film noir protagonist, in so deep he ultimately will be resigned to his fate. Catharine Tramell is a ultimate femme fatale, beautiful and seductive, she's always in control, leading all male characters where she wants them to go. There's a delicious kink to the narrative, with Verhoeven gleefully pulling the strings, a smirk no doubt etched onto his face. This is very good story telling, with a plot of substantial twists and turns. True, it does carry some soft-core baggage that can steer the restless away from the character strengths within, but for the neo-noir crowd there is much to enjoy here. 7.5/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Sharon Stone's finest hour
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    moviestar26
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    'Basic Instinct' was a film that rebooted the noir genre after it became rare in the early eighties. Prior to this the Coen brother's 'Blood Simple' attempted to revive the genre, but the industry was changing with the shift in audience's movie preferences. However this is more akin to being a sex thriller which also happens to incorporate a suspense element. 'Basic Instinct' takes the viewer back in time to the golden era of cinema when the femme fatales were glamorising the screen and became every male's dream fantasy. The film has been considered a classic and has not dated with time. The theme has been beautifully been One of my cult classic favourites from the 1990s. Whenever I catch a scene randomly on television, it brings back nostalgic memories of my childhood. I can still remember waking in the middle of the night just so I could record this movie secretly on my VCR. This is the movie that catapulted stone's career to international stardom. She immediately became a sex symbol and every man began dreaming of her. She immortalised a role that was so deep in characterisation. 'Catherine Trammel' was someone that was not only devious but smart, clever and manipulative. A role model so to speak that will certainly serve as an influence to many aspiring actresses and writers in the future. The role possessed every element that a negative character would have. Joe Esterhas is the writer. Previously he wrote 'Flash dance' and 'jagged edge' Most of his themes are similar. All negative roles about killers and murderers. 'Showgirls' and 'Jade' were also adapted for the screen. Unfortunately they failed at the box office and did not work. I think the audiences had higher expectations. 'Basic Instinct' has a fantastic script. This is the reason why the film worked. And then there is Paul Verhoeven who is a well known director in his home land. He has beautifully combined sex with the suspense genre. I am not very familiar with his Dutch movies. But he always had the style of depicting the theme of 'sex' as a weapon. I enjoyed the movie immensely, and being more of a reader than a movie- goer I jumped at the chance to read the book subsequent to seeing the motion picture. However, I feel that much of which made the movie great owes gratitude to the incredible soundtrack, imagery and skill of the actors; sometimes movies can be successfully novelised, but with Basic Instinct being the stimulus-rich move that it is I feel this was a failed attempt. The characters come off as threadbare and unexplored, lacking in depth or substance of any kind, and the seductively dark tone of the movie is lost on the page; it becomes rather humdrum and glancing, as if each page were written to keep up with the flow of the movie to be read within the hour. Where I was hoping to see some of the twisted, genius logic of Catherine Tramell explored on the page instead I found her to be de-powered, humanised and lacking of a great deal of her appeal as a result. It's worth the read for big fans of the Basic Instinct movies if only to explore the idea through a different form of media, (SPOILER) A San Francisco police detective who is investigated the murder of a retired rock star. The main suspect happens to be a novelist. She is under suspicion. She is released due to lack of evidence. Meanwhile the detective has maintains his belief that she is involved. He decides to pursue her and monitor her movements. The deeper his investigation proceeds, he succumbs to her charm and falls in love in spite knowing he is risking his life. His infatuation distances him from people around him and he refuses to listen to others. People he know become murdered. Eventually he finds it difficult to accept that she is a murderer as he begins to doubt his psychiatrist's past. (END OF SPOILER) The film is made with a sexy noir thriller tone. It brings back memories of Lawrence Kasden's 'Body Heat'. This was the last time a lead actress made an impression with a memorable role. Kathleen Turner became a popular star. At many moments the film feels like a horror thriller. There are many scenes that evoke a frightening feeling. What makes 'Basic Instinct' so unique is we are watching a women manipulating us with her attractive appeal that makes us want to believe she can be a killer. Her seductive charm works on the male protagonist, which leads to confusion. At the end we are eager to want to see her apprehended because we are disgusted how someone can desire to get away with murder for no reason. The sex scenes were unique and were the closest that could be categorised as 'soft porn'. This was one of the appealing factors that mad the film a success. 'Basic Instinct' has sustained it's quality over the years. It has managed to preserve it's quality and has not paled in front of movies that released recently. Due credit goes to Sharon Stone's performance and a winning script by Esterhas. The movie does follow true to the noir conventions. Anyone who is familiar with this will be able to notice them. However some of the typical noir rules were missing. There was no themes related to adultery or blackmailing. But it's relevance or lack of it doesn't seem significant as the this was a character driven film. Jerry Goldsmith's background score is specifically suited to the film's mood and atmosphere. It is still memorable and has different shades throughout the movie. It blends well with scenes and evokes the intriguing and haunting feeling.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Classic Verhoeven outrageousness.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    BA_Harrison
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/9/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Despite being built around the most 'basic' of plots, erotic thriller Basic Instinct remains director Paul Verhoeven's biggest commercial success, being one of the highest grossing titles of 1992. Unperturbed by the protestations of gay activists and uptight censor-happy moralists, who objected to the film's provocative cocktail of graphic sex and violence and its portrayal of bisexuals as crazed killers, the general public flocked to the cinema to revel in Verhoeven's heady concoction of wanton lust and cold-blooded violence. Written by Joe Eszterhas of Flashdance fame, the script is slick Hollywood nonsense, a flashy, trashy, twisting, turning tale clearly inspired by Hitchcock and the film-noir genre. Frequently teetering on the brink of preposterousness, its is precisely the kind of far-fetched nonsense that only a true maverick like Verhoeven could do justice toand boy, does he pull out all the stops here... Never one to do things by halves, the Dutch director opens his film as he means to go on, with a brutal murder that takes place during intercourse, a physically flawless blonde viciously stabbing her lover to death with an ice-pick. Scorching sex combined with gut churning nastiness, it's a real shocker (use the freeze-frame check out the outrageous shot of the pick going through the victim's nose!!!) and a clear indicator that this is to be no run-of-the-mill Hollywood thriller. The remainder of the film follows troubled detective Nick Curran (Michae Douglas) as he investigates the murder, stupidly becoming involved with his prime suspect, scorching hot, super intelligent, highly manipulative crime novelist Catherine Tramell (Sharon Stone), who may or may not be lining him up as her latest victim. Cue plenty more raunchy, near the knuckle nookie (including some rough rumpy-pumpy with the very sexy Jeanne 'gives me the' Tripplehorn), a few more gruesome deaths, a smidgen of exciting, pulse-pounding action, and the film's infamous blink-and-you'll miss-it shot of Stone's kebab as she uncrosses her legs during a police interview, all of which adds up to a whole heap of unmissable, jaw-dropping, eye-opening, big budget fun the likes of which we might never see again (unless Verhoeven can get Hollywood to forget all about Showgirls).
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "Good Seductive Thriller!"
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gwnightscream
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/9/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Michael Douglas, Sharon Stone, Jeanne Tripplehorn, George Dzundza and Leilani Sarelle star in this 1992 thriller. This begins in San Francisco with a retired rock star having sex with a blonde woman who brutally kills him with an icepick. Detective, Nick Curran (Douglas) and his partner, Gus (Dzundza) begin investigating and soon meet the victim's lover, Catherine Tramell (Stone) who becomes the main suspect. They learn that she's a writer and the murder coincidentally occurs in her recent novel. Nick starts to get involved with Catherine and begins questioning her motives when she plans on using him as a character in her next book. Tripplehorn plays Nick's ex-girlfriend, Beth Garner who is a psychiatrist and Sarelle plays Catherine's friend and lover, Roxy. Michael and Sharon have great chemistry and Jerry Goldsmith's score is excellent as usual. I recommend this good seductive thriller featuring Stone's famous leg-crossing scene.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Guilty Pleasure.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    AaronCapenBanner
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Michael Douglas plays San Francisco detective Nick Curran, who is investigating the brutal icepick murder of rock star Johnny Boz, which leads him to his girlfriend, novelist Catherine Tramell(Sharon Stone, unforgettable) Nick, though suspicious of Catherine, is nonetheless attracted to her brazen sensuality, and they begin a torrid affair, even though more murders pile up, and Catherine proves to be quite manipulative and intelligent...is she guilty? Controversial film directed by Paul Verhoeven is never boring, though normally having no one in the story to root for would be a problem, film is so slickly made and in-your-face that it may be the epitome of the guilty pleasure; trashy yet enjoyable. Both lead actors are excellent though, even if the mystery is never satisfactorily resolved.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    thrilling till the end
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    acpaloveshavefun
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I recently re saw this movie, and if your a thriller fan you'll absolutely love it. I was at the edge of my seat the entire time, trying to see if I can solve it. Definitely not for kids by the way. Please do not listen for the old bittys out there who are saying that This movie is porn,if I remember correctly the movie psycho had the infamous shower scene. yes its violent and yes it has sexual content, and "Adult situation" but that's what makes a really good movie. This was a perfect example of a great movie before everyone became so politically correct. If you can't handle this as an adult, go live with the Amish, is definitely not for you.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Unsatisfying
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    leonlouisricci
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    There is so much here that is unresolved that it leaves an empty, unfulfilled feeling that the viewer has been suckered. Endless nude and sex scenes intrude on the mystery plot and in the end it is all for not much. Infamous for its explicit exploitation of said sex and nudity and forever frustrating for that's pretty much all there is. The soft-porn aside it can be a somewhat sultry, trashy ride with enough intrigue to keep the interest but not enough to make it a totally engaging entertainment. The biggest problem is the ambiguity about most of what unfolds. There are dangling plot elements and shallow, confusing side shows. In all, it is a murky, muddy, and thin piece of Pulp that has modern machinations and push the envelope displays of Crime Fiction laced with so much pomp that it's rendered impotent. The Movie has enough sizzle to attract viewers but cannot justify all the indulgence and will most likely be an unsatisfactory guilty pleasure. It is quite an overrated Film whose appeal comes from the most lowbrow lexicons of entertainment. But hey, someone once said...there's one born every minute. That's a lot of ticket buyers.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    While its premise is promising, "Basic Instinct" is executed in an inconsistent manner
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Chris Mizerak
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    There are many aspects, both good and bad, that you can pick up from Paul Verhoeven's 1992 erotic thriller Basic Instinct. On one hand, the premise of the film is kind of interesting and has a certain amount of complexity to it. Also, the film works okay enough as far as erotic films go with Sharon Stone flaunting out her body. On the other hand, the film is really cheesy and over-the-top at times as well as really dull in others. So if you're guessing that I think this film has an inconsistent feel to it, you'd probably be right. Basic Instinct follows a police detective (Michael Douglas) with a troubling past who is trying to solve the recent murder of a rock and roll star. The only eligible suspect so far is a book writer (Sharon Stone), whose stories are about women murdering men, who was the last person to see him. One of her own stories seems to play out in the same way that this victim was murdered. Naturally, the police suspects that she did it. The plot thickens however when the detective falls in love with the writer and learns some new developments about the case. In case I haven't mentioned it in any of my earlier reviews, let me get this off my chest. With a few exceptions, I really do not care at all for films centered on police detectives, cops or characters involved in similar professions since I find them to be boring, forgettable, and formulaic. While there are exceptions that either have interesting cases or characters, the rest of them just don't do a thing for me especially in terms of story, characters, and dialogue. Keeping that in mind, while I find whatever takes place in the police department to be fairly formulaic, it wasn't boring and whatever dialogue was being said wasn't as much torture to listen to as I thought it was going to be. I thought it was going to be too difficult to understand what was being said like other films of this genre, but luckily it was easy to understand what was being said, so that must count for something. On top of that, the story has a reasonably intriguing complexity to it and so do the two main characters. The hero and villain in this film are not clear cut, which is fairly authentic of real life. In reality, it's not crystal clear who the heroes and villains are, one culture may consider certain "heroes" villains, and vice versa. In other words, the screenplay was wise enough to put that aspect into the story. If you go see this film solely for looking at Sharon Stone's physique, you won't be disappointed since she really looks good in this film. I wouldn't be surprised if some viewers were reminded of the blonde women Alfred Hitchcock used in his pictures especially Kim Novak. I know I detected some similarities in terms of looks and wardrobe between Stone and the typical blondes Hitchcock used in his films. From what I've said so far, it sounds like this should be a good movie given my personal tastes. But sadly, Basic Instinct is one of those films in which the premise alone is better than the actual execution. One huge issue I had with Basic Instinct is the quality of the acting. I found the acting in this picture to be really weak. While the characters of the two leads are fascinating, the performances aren't executed well enough to do justice to the written characters. I also don't find the two leads (especially Douglas) either that believable or even that subtle/natural with their delivery. Furthermore, the performance by Jeanne Tripplehorn as a psychiatrist helping out Douglas' character is especially unconvincing, considering that I never believed that her character had enough experience in studying psychology to the point were she would become a professional one at such a young age. I simply didn't buy it at all, and the only point to her character existing in this film is solely for a plot twist that is used later in the film. I think she was of no importance to the plot whatsoever. Because of the disappointing acting quality, I don't really buy whatever ludicrous events take place in the plot as a result. Therefore, I can't take anything in the plot as seriously as the film seems to want me to. While the screenplay has its fair share of intriguing elements, there are also some elements of the screenplay especially with its dialogue that feels really cheesy and doesn't even sound the slightest bit realistic. As a result, that's how the film becomes inconsistent in terms of its delivery. In a nutshell, Basic Instinct definitely seems to be a mixed bag. While it has a good idea of what it wants to be, it seldom delivers on the promises it makes mainly because the acting is so mediocre to the point where it interferes with my ability to believe what's happening on screen. I'd only recommend this film if you're solely interested in checking out Stone's body. It's not much of an endorsement, but that's the highest praise I can give to this flick.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Murder All Around Her
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bkoganbing
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Although most reviewers have concentrated on the leads, Basic Instinct has some other fine performances in it. Still Michael Douglas as the sex obsessed cop and Sharon Stone as the amoral, multi-sexual woman who seems to have murder all around her give some iconic performances. A couple of SFPD detectives who played TV detectives, Michael Douglas in Streets Of San Francisco and George Dzundza in Law And Order, get assigned to the homicide of a former rockstar icon. The man had as the story tells us the 'coital moment of the century' before he died and as Michael Douglas finds out with Sharon Stone his prime suspect. It's not like Douglas hasn't any issues himself, he's seeing the SFPD shrink Jeanne Tripplehorn. One of those issues apparently is professional detachment as gets involved with both Tripplehorn and Stone. Far worse with Stone as she is a suspect. Murders in the past and murders in the present seem to pop up whenever Stone is around. She's an heiress to a fortune, a psychology major from college and licensed and an author of lurid novels. She knows how to press the buttons of both sexes and soon enough Douglas is in her world. The only one keeping a professional detachment is Dzundza who is not thinking with his male member. Even when an Internal Affairs cop who is investigating Douglas is murdered, Dzundza sticks by his partner. See what it gets him. In fact Dzundza and Tripplehorn don't get near enough credit for their work here. I think most know Tripplehorn as I do for playing Tom Cruise's wife in The Firm. She too is a woman with a lot of issues. As for George Dzundza as the only one in the film actually who seems to be normal, the others all seem to play off him. Still Sharon Stone's career was launched with what she did in Basic Instinct. This woman will wind up President of the USA or on death row, no middle ground for her. And you can believe she's every man and woman's coital moment of a lifetime. I don't know how successful or how good Basic Instinct 2 was, but seeing this has given me an incentive to see the sequel.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Bill Hicks and my Basic instinct was right, it's an unpleasant film.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ironhorse_iv
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It's sad to say that sex sells. Basic Instinct without a doubt sells, but it's just a sexy thriller that's got plenty of libido but not nearly as much brains as it thinks it has. It's extremely misogynistic and is very predictable. I was very disappointed with the whole movie, and had figured out the murderer within about 30 minutes into it. It's titillating, even exciting at times, but ultimately collapses under the weight of its own stupidity. The movie contained a lot of graphic sexual acts throughout the movie that makes it more of a soft porn movie in disguise & less than a film noir. It could have been better, if it cut down on the exotic a bit, and focus more on the story and give us a challenge. In the film's opening, Rockstar Boz is stabbed to death by a blonde woman with an ice pick during sex. We never see the woman's face -- just her blonde hair and, of course, most of her lust-inducing body. By just looking at the body of the killer, you can pretty much know who did it. The police find the dead body, and Det. Nick Curran, (Michael Douglas) was put on the case whom slept with his police-appointed shrink Dr. Beth Garner (Jeanne Triplehorn). Rather than getting a DNA test on the number one- suspect, Boz's girlfriend, Catherine Tramell (Sharon Stone), a famous crime novelist, the cops interview her. I know DNA testing was still in its early stages in the early '90s but convicting using DNA evidence alone has been proved fact since 1988, four years when the film was set. Well, Catherine use the interview to make fools out of them. The way she manipulates psychology was superbly awesome. Without Sharon Stone as femme fatale, this movie is nothing. Still, most people would remember from this scene just the famous leg switching, and not the acting. Although, the detectives were too stupid to realize that there is something about her that doesn't add up. We sees Catherine using it to break ice during the film. She even mentions how her book is about a detective falling for the wrong woman and that she kills him. Isn't it very clear who the killer is? Sooner than later, Nick get into Catherine's sex life. The movie moves with the suspense involving Nick and Catherine. He's supposed to be following this woman as a suspect but is actually falling for her deadly charm since Nick is dumb like the other cops. Clearly this film points out the men are just horny dumb pervs who slept before duty. The film tries to do a lot of dumb red herrings such as Beth is revealed to have had a past sexual encounter with Catherine, that according to Catherine developed an obsessive fixation on her as Beth copy her. The audience is suppose to wonder whether Beth killed Boz as is described in Catherine's book to frame her. Not once in the film, does Beth show any bit of bi or lesbians feelings. Catherine does with a girl name Roxy (Leilani Sarelle). The film was strongly opposed by gay rights activists, who criticized the film's portrayal of bisexual women as a murderous sociopaths. The featurette Blond Poison reveals the uproar the film caused during the San Francisco filming. They deplored it as being "anti-gay" and a reinforcement of Hollywood homophobia due to typecasting particularly lesbians as twisted and evil, or just act lesbians to get men's horny. I think the heterosexuals can also be equally offensive, as some feminists like Camille Paglia starts breaking things down to banal symbolisms, the opening killing with the ice pick is interpreted as, "Woman steals man's penis and uses it against him." men find themselves involuntarily cringing. Freudian Pscyhoanalysts have retained the term instinct that the film refer to human motivational forces (such as sex and aggression), sometimes represented as Eros - life instinct and Thanatos- death Instinct, but the real term is motivational forces or drives to correct the original error in the translation of Freud's work. Psychologist Abraham Maslow argued that humans no longer have instincts because we have the ability to override them in certain situations. For Maslow, an instinct is something which cannot be overridden, & therefore while the term may have applied to humans in the past, it no longer does. So the film should be title 'Basic Drives". It's clear why Joe Eszterhas was paid 3-million bucks for his script with its clever plot construction. Still there are pointless sequences like where Nick and Catherine engage in a car chase for no discernible reason other than to serve as a dire attempt to jack up the energy level. The film also has unlikeable characters. The hero Nick viciously rapes Beth in one scene. They're perfectly acceptable in the art of film, but Basic Instinct did go a little overboard with that sex. The film does good with its abstract images, the way it's shot from different angles, made it a little more elliptical, a bit less direct. The eerie Jerry Goldsmith theme gives the film a creepy tone. Basic Instinct was to transfers Mr. Verhoeven's flair for action-oriented material to the realm of Hitchcockian intrigue, but the results are so-so. Following the success of the film, Ezsterhas & Verhoeven went on to collaborate on Showgirls. (Another horrible mess). Since release, the blue-ray version add more graphic violence & sex into the film.This film is an affront to taste. It's an over-baked mind control fantasy, brought to life by a horrible script, and relieved of meaning by a hair brained plot. It's all Tougue in cheek really like a perv. It's depends on your kicks.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I'd have to be pretty stupid to write a book about killing and then kill him the way I described in my book. I'd be announcing myself as the killer. I'm not stupid.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    JohnRouseMerriottChard
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Basic Instinct is directed by Paul Verhoeven and written by Joe Eszterhaz. It stars Michael Douglas, Sharon Stone, George Dzundza, Jeanne Tripplehorn, Denis Arndt and Leilani Sarelle. Music is scored by Jerry Goldsmith and cinematography by Jan de Bont. Nick Curran (Douglas) of the SFPD is strung out and under investigation by Internal Affairs, last thing he needs is to be drawn into a dangerous relationship with a sex crazed blonde who may be a murderess... Time hasn't been kind to Verhoeven's soft-core porn thriller, where once was shock and awe killings (the film opening with a brutal mini ice-pick murder), steamy love scenes and a famed and controversial crotch shot, now is ludicrous orgasms, iffy effects and Michael Douglas' unappetising ass! Hell there was even protests during the film's initial theatre run as the gay community went up in arms about the portrayal of bisexuals possibly being mad murderers? Yet for all of its taming over the years, Basic Instinct can at least now been seen as the hugely efficient mystery thriller that it is, one that is propelled by some very good performances by the principal actors. The strength in the story is not in the sex or blood, but in the character arcs of Nick Curran and Catherine Tramell (Stone). Curran is a man perched on the edge of doom who is controlled totally by the women around him. He is by definition a quintessential film noir protagonist, in so deep he ultimately will be resigned to his fate. Catharine Tramell is a ultimate femme fatale, beautiful and seductive, she's always in control, leading all male characters where she wants them to go. There's a delicious kink to the narrative, with Verhoeven gleefully pulling the strings, a smirk no doubt etched onto his face. This is very good story telling, with a plot of substantial twists and turns. True, it does carry some soft-core baggage that can steer the restless away from the character strengths within, but for the neo-noir crowd there is much to enjoy here. 7.5/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Sharon Stone's finest hour
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    moviestar26
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    'Basic Instinct' was a film that rebooted the noir genre after it became rare in the early eighties. Prior to this the Coen brother's 'Blood Simple' attempted to revive the genre, but the industry was changing with the shift in audience's movie preferences. However this is more akin to being a sex thriller which also happens to incorporate a suspense element. 'Basic Instinct' takes the viewer back in time to the golden era of cinema when the femme fatales were glamorising the screen and became every male's dream fantasy. The film has been considered a classic and has not dated with time. The theme has been beautifully been One of my cult classic favourites from the 1990s. Whenever I catch a scene randomly on television, it brings back nostalgic memories of my childhood. I can still remember waking in the middle of the night just so I could record this movie secretly on my VCR. This is the movie that catapulted stone's career to international stardom. She immediately became a sex symbol and every man began dreaming of her. She immortalised a role that was so deep in characterisation. 'Catherine Trammel' was someone that was not only devious but smart, clever and manipulative. A role model so to speak that will certainly serve as an influence to many aspiring actresses and writers in the future. The role possessed every element that a negative character would have. Joe Esterhas is the writer. Previously he wrote 'Flash dance' and 'jagged edge' Most of his themes are similar. All negative roles about killers and murderers. 'Showgirls' and 'Jade' were also adapted for the screen. Unfortunately they failed at the box office and did not work. I think the audiences had higher expectations. 'Basic Instinct' has a fantastic script. This is the reason why the film worked. And then there is Paul Verhoeven who is a well known director in his home land. He has beautifully combined sex with the suspense genre. I am not very familiar with his Dutch movies. But he always had the style of depicting the theme of 'sex' as a weapon. I enjoyed the movie immensely, and being more of a reader than a movie- goer I jumped at the chance to read the book subsequent to seeing the motion picture. However, I feel that much of which made the movie great owes gratitude to the incredible soundtrack, imagery and skill of the actors; sometimes movies can be successfully novelised, but with Basic Instinct being the stimulus-rich move that it is I feel this was a failed attempt. The characters come off as threadbare and unexplored, lacking in depth or substance of any kind, and the seductively dark tone of the movie is lost on the page; it becomes rather humdrum and glancing, as if each page were written to keep up with the flow of the movie to be read within the hour. Where I was hoping to see some of the twisted, genius logic of Catherine Tramell explored on the page instead I found her to be de-powered, humanised and lacking of a great deal of her appeal as a result. It's worth the read for big fans of the Basic Instinct movies if only to explore the idea through a different form of media, (SPOILER) A San Francisco police detective who is investigated the murder of a retired rock star. The main suspect happens to be a novelist. She is under suspicion. She is released due to lack of evidence. Meanwhile the detective has maintains his belief that she is involved. He decides to pursue her and monitor her movements. The deeper his investigation proceeds, he succumbs to her charm and falls in love in spite knowing he is risking his life. His infatuation distances him from people around him and he refuses to listen to others. People he know become murdered. Eventually he finds it difficult to accept that she is a murderer as he begins to doubt his psychiatrist's past. (END OF SPOILER) The film is made with a sexy noir thriller tone. It brings back memories of Lawrence Kasden's 'Body Heat'. This was the last time a lead actress made an impression with a memorable role. Kathleen Turner became a popular star. At many moments the film feels like a horror thriller. There are many scenes that evoke a frightening feeling. What makes 'Basic Instinct' so unique is we are watching a women manipulating us with her attractive appeal that makes us want to believe she can be a killer. Her seductive charm works on the male protagonist, which leads to confusion. At the end we are eager to want to see her apprehended because we are disgusted how someone can desire to get away with murder for no reason. The sex scenes were unique and were the closest that could be categorised as 'soft porn'. This was one of the appealing factors that mad the film a success. 'Basic Instinct' has sustained it's quality over the years. It has managed to preserve it's quality and has not paled in front of movies that released recently. Due credit goes to Sharon Stone's performance and a winning script by Esterhas. The movie does follow true to the noir conventions. Anyone who is familiar with this will be able to notice them. However some of the typical noir rules were missing. There was no themes related to adultery or blackmailing. But it's relevance or lack of it doesn't seem significant as the this was a character driven film. Jerry Goldsmith's background score is specifically suited to the film's mood and atmosphere. It is still memorable and has different shades throughout the movie. It blends well with scenes and evokes the intriguing and haunting feeling.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Classic Verhoeven outrageousness.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    BA_Harrison
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/9/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Despite being built around the most 'basic' of plots, erotic thriller Basic Instinct remains director Paul Verhoeven's biggest commercial success, being one of the highest grossing titles of 1992. Unperturbed by the protestations of gay activists and uptight censor-happy moralists, who objected to the film's provocative cocktail of graphic sex and violence and its portrayal of bisexuals as crazed killers, the general public flocked to the cinema to revel in Verhoeven's heady concoction of wanton lust and cold-blooded violence. Written by Joe Eszterhas of Flashdance fame, the script is slick Hollywood nonsense, a flashy, trashy, twisting, turning tale clearly inspired by Hitchcock and the film-noir genre. Frequently teetering on the brink of preposterousness, its is precisely the kind of far-fetched nonsense that only a true maverick like Verhoeven could do justice toand boy, does he pull out all the stops here... Never one to do things by halves, the Dutch director opens his film as he means to go on, with a brutal murder that takes place during intercourse, a physically flawless blonde viciously stabbing her lover to death with an ice-pick. Scorching sex combined with gut churning nastiness, it's a real shocker (use the freeze-frame check out the outrageous shot of the pick going through the victim's nose!!!) and a clear indicator that this is to be no run-of-the-mill Hollywood thriller. The remainder of the film follows troubled detective Nick Curran (Michae Douglas) as he investigates the murder, stupidly becoming involved with his prime suspect, scorching hot, super intelligent, highly manipulative crime novelist Catherine Tramell (Sharon Stone), who may or may not be lining him up as her latest victim. Cue plenty more raunchy, near the knuckle nookie (including some rough rumpy-pumpy with the very sexy Jeanne 'gives me the' Tripplehorn), a few more gruesome deaths, a smidgen of exciting, pulse-pounding action, and the film's infamous blink-and-you'll miss-it shot of Stone's kebab as she uncrosses her legs during a police interview, all of which adds up to a whole heap of unmissable, jaw-dropping, eye-opening, big budget fun the likes of which we might never see again (unless Verhoeven can get Hollywood to forget all about Showgirls).
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "Good Seductive Thriller!"
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gwnightscream
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/9/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Michael Douglas, Sharon Stone, Jeanne Tripplehorn, George Dzundza and Leilani Sarelle star in this 1992 thriller. This begins in San Francisco with a retired rock star having sex with a blonde woman who brutally kills him with an icepick. Detective, Nick Curran (Douglas) and his partner, Gus (Dzundza) begin investigating and soon meet the victim's lover, Catherine Tramell (Stone) who becomes the main suspect. They learn that she's a writer and the murder coincidentally occurs in her recent novel. Nick starts to get involved with Catherine and begins questioning her motives when she plans on using him as a character in her next book. Tripplehorn plays Nick's ex-girlfriend, Beth Garner who is a psychiatrist and Sarelle plays Catherine's friend and lover, Roxy. Michael and Sharon have great chemistry and Jerry Goldsmith's score is excellent as usual. I recommend this good seductive thriller featuring Stone's famous leg-crossing scene.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Guilty Pleasure.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    AaronCapenBanner
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Michael Douglas plays San Francisco detective Nick Curran, who is investigating the brutal icepick murder of rock star Johnny Boz, which leads him to his girlfriend, novelist Catherine Tramell(Sharon Stone, unforgettable) Nick, though suspicious of Catherine, is nonetheless attracted to her brazen sensuality, and they begin a torrid affair, even though more murders pile up, and Catherine proves to be quite manipulative and intelligent...is she guilty? Controversial film directed by Paul Verhoeven is never boring, though normally having no one in the story to root for would be a problem, film is so slickly made and in-your-face that it may be the epitome of the guilty pleasure; trashy yet enjoyable. Both lead actors are excellent though, even if the mystery is never satisfactorily resolved.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    thrilling till the end
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    acpaloveshavefun
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I recently re saw this movie, and if your a thriller fan you'll absolutely love it. I was at the edge of my seat the entire time, trying to see if I can solve it. Definitely not for kids by the way. Please do not listen for the old bittys out there who are saying that This movie is porn,if I remember correctly the movie psycho had the infamous shower scene. yes its violent and yes it has sexual content, and "Adult situation" but that's what makes a really good movie. This was a perfect example of a great movie before everyone became so politically correct. If you can't handle this as an adult, go live with the Amish, is definitely not for you.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Unsatisfying
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    leonlouisricci
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    There is so much here that is unresolved that it leaves an empty, unfulfilled feeling that the viewer has been suckered. Endless nude and sex scenes intrude on the mystery plot and in the end it is all for not much. Infamous for its explicit exploitation of said sex and nudity and forever frustrating for that's pretty much all there is. The soft-porn aside it can be a somewhat sultry, trashy ride with enough intrigue to keep the interest but not enough to make it a totally engaging entertainment. The biggest problem is the ambiguity about most of what unfolds. There are dangling plot elements and shallow, confusing side shows. In all, it is a murky, muddy, and thin piece of Pulp that has modern machinations and push the envelope displays of Crime Fiction laced with so much pomp that it's rendered impotent. The Movie has enough sizzle to attract viewers but cannot justify all the indulgence and will most likely be an unsatisfactory guilty pleasure. It is quite an overrated Film whose appeal comes from the most lowbrow lexicons of entertainment. But hey, someone once said...there's one born every minute. That's a lot of ticket buyers.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    While its premise is promising, "Basic Instinct" is executed in an inconsistent manner
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Chris Mizerak
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    There are many aspects, both good and bad, that you can pick up from Paul Verhoeven's 1992 erotic thriller Basic Instinct. On one hand, the premise of the film is kind of interesting and has a certain amount of complexity to it. Also, the film works okay enough as far as erotic films go with Sharon Stone flaunting out her body. On the other hand, the film is really cheesy and over-the-top at times as well as really dull in others. So if you're guessing that I think this film has an inconsistent feel to it, you'd probably be right. Basic Instinct follows a police detective (Michael Douglas) with a troubling past who is trying to solve the recent murder of a rock and roll star. The only eligible suspect so far is a book writer (Sharon Stone), whose stories are about women murdering men, who was the last person to see him. One of her own stories seems to play out in the same way that this victim was murdered. Naturally, the police suspects that she did it. The plot thickens however when the detective falls in love with the writer and learns some new developments about the case. In case I haven't mentioned it in any of my earlier reviews, let me get this off my chest. With a few exceptions, I really do not care at all for films centered on police detectives, cops or characters involved in similar professions since I find them to be boring, forgettable, and formulaic. While there are exceptions that either have interesting cases or characters, the rest of them just don't do a thing for me especially in terms of story, characters, and dialogue. Keeping that in mind, while I find whatever takes place in the police department to be fairly formulaic, it wasn't boring and whatever dialogue was being said wasn't as much torture to listen to as I thought it was going to be. I thought it was going to be too difficult to understand what was being said like other films of this genre, but luckily it was easy to understand what was being said, so that must count for something. On top of that, the story has a reasonably intriguing complexity to it and so do the two main characters. The hero and villain in this film are not clear cut, which is fairly authentic of real life. In reality, it's not crystal clear who the heroes and villains are, one culture may consider certain "heroes" villains, and vice versa. In other words, the screenplay was wise enough to put that aspect into the story. If you go see this film solely for looking at Sharon Stone's physique, you won't be disappointed since she really looks good in this film. I wouldn't be surprised if some viewers were reminded of the blonde women Alfred Hitchcock used in his pictures especially Kim Novak. I know I detected some similarities in terms of looks and wardrobe between Stone and the typical blondes Hitchcock used in his films. From what I've said so far, it sounds like this should be a good movie given my personal tastes. But sadly, Basic Instinct is one of those films in which the premise alone is better than the actual execution. One huge issue I had with Basic Instinct is the quality of the acting. I found the acting in this picture to be really weak. While the characters of the two leads are fascinating, the performances aren't executed well enough to do justice to the written characters. I also don't find the two leads (especially Douglas) either that believable or even that subtle/natural with their delivery. Furthermore, the performance by Jeanne Tripplehorn as a psychiatrist helping out Douglas' character is especially unconvincing, considering that I never believed that her character had enough experience in studying psychology to the point were she would become a professional one at such a young age. I simply didn't buy it at all, and the only point to her character existing in this film is solely for a plot twist that is used later in the film. I think she was of no importance to the plot whatsoever. Because of the disappointing acting quality, I don't really buy whatever ludicrous events take place in the plot as a result. Therefore, I can't take anything in the plot as seriously as the film seems to want me to. While the screenplay has its fair share of intriguing elements, there are also some elements of the screenplay especially with its dialogue that feels really cheesy and doesn't even sound the slightest bit realistic. As a result, that's how the film becomes inconsistent in terms of its delivery. In a nutshell, Basic Instinct definitely seems to be a mixed bag. While it has a good idea of what it wants to be, it seldom delivers on the promises it makes mainly because the acting is so mediocre to the point where it interferes with my ability to believe what's happening on screen. I'd only recommend this film if you're solely interested in checking out Stone's body. It's not much of an endorsement, but that's the highest praise I can give to this flick.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Murder All Around Her
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bkoganbing
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Although most reviewers have concentrated on the leads, Basic Instinct has some other fine performances in it. Still Michael Douglas as the sex obsessed cop and Sharon Stone as the amoral, multi-sexual woman who seems to have murder all around her give some iconic performances. A couple of SFPD detectives who played TV detectives, Michael Douglas in Streets Of San Francisco and George Dzundza in Law And Order, get assigned to the homicide of a former rockstar icon. The man had as the story tells us the 'coital moment of the century' before he died and as Michael Douglas finds out with Sharon Stone his prime suspect. It's not like Douglas hasn't any issues himself, he's seeing the SFPD shrink Jeanne Tripplehorn. One of those issues apparently is professional detachment as gets involved with both Tripplehorn and Stone. Far worse with Stone as she is a suspect. Murders in the past and murders in the present seem to pop up whenever Stone is around. She's an heiress to a fortune, a psychology major from college and licensed and an author of lurid novels. She knows how to press the buttons of both sexes and soon enough Douglas is in her world. The only one keeping a professional detachment is Dzundza who is not thinking with his male member. Even when an Internal Affairs cop who is investigating Douglas is murdered, Dzundza sticks by his partner. See what it gets him. In fact Dzundza and Tripplehorn don't get near enough credit for their work here. I think most know Tripplehorn as I do for playing Tom Cruise's wife in The Firm. She too is a woman with a lot of issues. As for George Dzundza as the only one in the film actually who seems to be normal, the others all seem to play off him. Still Sharon Stone's career was launched with what she did in Basic Instinct. This woman will wind up President of the USA or on death row, no middle ground for her. And you can believe she's every man and woman's coital moment of a lifetime. I don't know how successful or how good Basic Instinct 2 was, but seeing this has given me an incentive to see the sequel.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Bill Hicks and my Basic instinct was right, it's an unpleasant film.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ironhorse_iv
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It's sad to say that sex sells. Basic Instinct without a doubt sells, but it's just a sexy thriller that's got plenty of libido but not nearly as much brains as it thinks it has. It's extremely misogynistic and is very predictable. I was very disappointed with the whole movie, and had figured out the murderer within about 30 minutes into it. It's titillating, even exciting at times, but ultimately collapses under the weight of its own stupidity. The movie contained a lot of graphic sexual acts throughout the movie that makes it more of a soft porn movie in disguise & less than a film noir. It could have been better, if it cut down on the exotic a bit, and focus more on the story and give us a challenge. In the film's opening, Rockstar Boz is stabbed to death by a blonde woman with an ice pick during sex. We never see the woman's face -- just her blonde hair and, of course, most of her lust-inducing body. By just looking at the body of the killer, you can pretty much know who did it. The police find the dead body, and Det. Nick Curran, (Michael Douglas) was put on the case whom slept with his police-appointed shrink Dr. Beth Garner (Jeanne Triplehorn). Rather than getting a DNA test on the number one- suspect, Boz's girlfriend, Catherine Tramell (Sharon Stone), a famous crime novelist, the cops interview her. I know DNA testing was still in its early stages in the early '90s but convicting using DNA evidence alone has been proved fact since 1988, four years when the film was set. Well, Catherine use the interview to make fools out of them. The way she manipulates psychology was superbly awesome. Without Sharon Stone as femme fatale, this movie is nothing. Still, most people would remember from this scene just the famous leg switching, and not the acting. Although, the detectives were too stupid to realize that there is something about her that doesn't add up. We sees Catherine using it to break ice during the film. She even mentions how her book is about a detective falling for the wrong woman and that she kills him. Isn't it very clear who the killer is? Sooner than later, Nick get into Catherine's sex life. The movie moves with the suspense involving Nick and Catherine. He's supposed to be following this woman as a suspect but is actually falling for her deadly charm since Nick is dumb like the other cops. Clearly this film points out the men are just horny dumb pervs who slept before duty. The film tries to do a lot of dumb red herrings such as Beth is revealed to have had a past sexual encounter with Catherine, that according to Catherine developed an obsessive fixation on her as Beth copy her. The audience is suppose to wonder whether Beth killed Boz as is described in Catherine's book to frame her. Not once in the film, does Beth show any bit of bi or lesbians feelings. Catherine does with a girl name Roxy (Leilani Sarelle). The film was strongly opposed by gay rights activists, who criticized the film's portrayal of bisexual women as a murderous sociopaths. The featurette Blond Poison reveals the uproar the film caused during the San Francisco filming. They deplored it as being "anti-gay" and a reinforcement of Hollywood homophobia due to typecasting particularly lesbians as twisted and evil, or just act lesbians to get men's horny. I think the heterosexuals can also be equally offensive, as some feminists like Camille Paglia starts breaking things down to banal symbolisms, the opening killing with the ice pick is interpreted as, "Woman steals man's penis and uses it against him." men find themselves involuntarily cringing. Freudian Pscyhoanalysts have retained the term instinct that the film refer to human motivational forces (such as sex and aggression), sometimes represented as Eros - life instinct and Thanatos- death Instinct, but the real term is motivational forces or drives to correct the original error in the translation of Freud's work. Psychologist Abraham Maslow argued that humans no longer have instincts because we have the ability to override them in certain situations. For Maslow, an instinct is something which cannot be overridden, & therefore while the term may have applied to humans in the past, it no longer does. So the film should be title 'Basic Drives". It's clear why Joe Eszterhas was paid 3-million bucks for his script with its clever plot construction. Still there are pointless sequences like where Nick and Catherine engage in a car chase for no discernible reason other than to serve as a dire attempt to jack up the energy level. The film also has unlikeable characters. The hero Nick viciously rapes Beth in one scene. They're perfectly acceptable in the art of film, but Basic Instinct did go a little overboard with that sex. The film does good with its abstract images, the way it's shot from different angles, made it a little more elliptical, a bit less direct. The eerie Jerry Goldsmith theme gives the film a creepy tone. Basic Instinct was to transfers Mr. Verhoeven's flair for action-oriented material to the realm of Hitchcockian intrigue, but the results are so-so. Following the success of the film, Ezsterhas & Verhoeven went on to collaborate on Showgirls. (Another horrible mess). Since release, the blue-ray version add more graphic violence & sex into the film.This film is an affront to taste. It's an over-baked mind control fantasy, brought to life by a horrible script, and relieved of meaning by a hair brained plot. It's all Tougue in cheek really like a perv. It's depends on your kicks.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I'd have to be pretty stupid to write a book about killing and then kill him the way I described in my book. I'd be announcing myself as the killer. I'm not stupid.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    JohnRouseMerriottChard
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Basic Instinct is directed by Paul Verhoeven and written by Joe Eszterhaz. It stars Michael Douglas, Sharon Stone, George Dzundza, Jeanne Tripplehorn, Denis Arndt and Leilani Sarelle. Music is scored by Jerry Goldsmith and cinematography by Jan de Bont. Nick Curran (Douglas) of the SFPD is strung out and under investigation by Internal Affairs, last thing he needs is to be drawn into a dangerous relationship with a sex crazed blonde who may be a murderess... Time hasn't been kind to Verhoeven's soft-core porn thriller, where once was shock and awe killings (the film opening with a brutal mini ice-pick murder), steamy love scenes and a famed and controversial crotch shot, now is ludicrous orgasms, iffy effects and Michael Douglas' unappetising ass! Hell there was even protests during the film's initial theatre run as the gay community went up in arms about the portrayal of bisexuals possibly being mad murderers? Yet for all of its taming over the years, Basic Instinct can at least now been seen as the hugely efficient mystery thriller that it is, one that is propelled by some very good performances by the principal actors. The strength in the story is not in the sex or blood, but in the character arcs of Nick Curran and Catherine Tramell (Stone). Curran is a man perched on the edge of doom who is controlled totally by the women around him. He is by definition a quintessential film noir protagonist, in so deep he ultimately will be resigned to his fate. Catharine Tramell is a ultimate femme fatale, beautiful and seductive, she's always in control, leading all male characters where she wants them to go. There's a delicious kink to the narrative, with Verhoeven gleefully pulling the strings, a smirk no doubt etched onto his face. This is very good story telling, with a plot of substantial twists and turns. True, it does carry some soft-core baggage that can steer the restless away from the character strengths within, but for the neo-noir crowd there is much to enjoy here. 7.5/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Sharon Stone's finest hour
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    moviestar26
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    'Basic Instinct' was a film that rebooted the noir genre after it became rare in the early eighties. Prior to this the Coen brother's 'Blood Simple' attempted to revive the genre, but the industry was changing with the shift in audience's movie preferences. However this is more akin to being a sex thriller which also happens to incorporate a suspense element. 'Basic Instinct' takes the viewer back in time to the golden era of cinema when the femme fatales were glamorising the screen and became every male's dream fantasy. The film has been considered a classic and has not dated with time. The theme has been beautifully been One of my cult classic favourites from the 1990s. Whenever I catch a scene randomly on television, it brings back nostalgic memories of my childhood. I can still remember waking in the middle of the night just so I could record this movie secretly on my VCR. This is the movie that catapulted stone's career to international stardom. She immediately became a sex symbol and every man began dreaming of her. She immortalised a role that was so deep in characterisation. 'Catherine Trammel' was someone that was not only devious but smart, clever and manipulative. A role model so to speak that will certainly serve as an influence to many aspiring actresses and writers in the future. The role possessed every element that a negative character would have. Joe Esterhas is the writer. Previously he wrote 'Flash dance' and 'jagged edge' Most of his themes are similar. All negative roles about killers and murderers. 'Showgirls' and 'Jade' were also adapted for the screen. Unfortunately they failed at the box office and did not work. I think the audiences had higher expectations. 'Basic Instinct' has a fantastic script. This is the reason why the film worked. And then there is Paul Verhoeven who is a well known director in his home land. He has beautifully combined sex with the suspense genre. I am not very familiar with his Dutch movies. But he always had the style of depicting the theme of 'sex' as a weapon. I enjoyed the movie immensely, and being more of a reader than a movie- goer I jumped at the chance to read the book subsequent to seeing the motion picture. However, I feel that much of which made the movie great owes gratitude to the incredible soundtrack, imagery and skill of the actors; sometimes movies can be successfully novelised, but with Basic Instinct being the stimulus-rich move that it is I feel this was a failed attempt. The characters come off as threadbare and unexplored, lacking in depth or substance of any kind, and the seductively dark tone of the movie is lost on the page; it becomes rather humdrum and glancing, as if each page were written to keep up with the flow of the movie to be read within the hour. Where I was hoping to see some of the twisted, genius logic of Catherine Tramell explored on the page instead I found her to be de-powered, humanised and lacking of a great deal of her appeal as a result. It's worth the read for big fans of the Basic Instinct movies if only to explore the idea through a different form of media, (SPOILER) A San Francisco police detective who is investigated the murder of a retired rock star. The main suspect happens to be a novelist. She is under suspicion. She is released due to lack of evidence. Meanwhile the detective has maintains his belief that she is involved. He decides to pursue her and monitor her movements. The deeper his investigation proceeds, he succumbs to her charm and falls in love in spite knowing he is risking his life. His infatuation distances him from people around him and he refuses to listen to others. People he know become murdered. Eventually he finds it difficult to accept that she is a murderer as he begins to doubt his psychiatrist's past. (END OF SPOILER) The film is made with a sexy noir thriller tone. It brings back memories of Lawrence Kasden's 'Body Heat'. This was the last time a lead actress made an impression with a memorable role. Kathleen Turner became a popular star. At many moments the film feels like a horror thriller. There are many scenes that evoke a frightening feeling. What makes 'Basic Instinct' so unique is we are watching a women manipulating us with her attractive appeal that makes us want to believe she can be a killer. Her seductive charm works on the male protagonist, which leads to confusion. At the end we are eager to want to see her apprehended because we are disgusted how someone can desire to get away with murder for no reason. The sex scenes were unique and were the closest that could be categorised as 'soft porn'. This was one of the appealing factors that mad the film a success. 'Basic Instinct' has sustained it's quality over the years. It has managed to preserve it's quality and has not paled in front of movies that released recently. Due credit goes to Sharon Stone's performance and a winning script by Esterhas. The movie does follow true to the noir conventions. Anyone who is familiar with this will be able to notice them. However some of the typical noir rules were missing. There was no themes related to adultery or blackmailing. But it's relevance or lack of it doesn't seem significant as the this was a character driven film. Jerry Goldsmith's background score is specifically suited to the film's mood and atmosphere. It is still memorable and has different shades throughout the movie. It blends well with scenes and evokes the intriguing and haunting feeling.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Classic Verhoeven outrageousness.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    BA_Harrison
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/9/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Despite being built around the most 'basic' of plots, erotic thriller Basic Instinct remains director Paul Verhoeven's biggest commercial success, being one of the highest grossing titles of 1992. Unperturbed by the protestations of gay activists and uptight censor-happy moralists, who objected to the film's provocative cocktail of graphic sex and violence and its portrayal of bisexuals as crazed killers, the general public flocked to the cinema to revel in Verhoeven's heady concoction of wanton lust and cold-blooded violence. Written by Joe Eszterhas of Flashdance fame, the script is slick Hollywood nonsense, a flashy, trashy, twisting, turning tale clearly inspired by Hitchcock and the film-noir genre. Frequently teetering on the brink of preposterousness, its is precisely the kind of far-fetched nonsense that only a true maverick like Verhoeven could do justice toand boy, does he pull out all the stops here... Never one to do things by halves, the Dutch director opens his film as he means to go on, with a brutal murder that takes place during intercourse, a physically flawless blonde viciously stabbing her lover to death with an ice-pick. Scorching sex combined with gut churning nastiness, it's a real shocker (use the freeze-frame check out the outrageous shot of the pick going through the victim's nose!!!) and a clear indicator that this is to be no run-of-the-mill Hollywood thriller. The remainder of the film follows troubled detective Nick Curran (Michae Douglas) as he investigates the murder, stupidly becoming involved with his prime suspect, scorching hot, super intelligent, highly manipulative crime novelist Catherine Tramell (Sharon Stone), who may or may not be lining him up as her latest victim. Cue plenty more raunchy, near the knuckle nookie (including some rough rumpy-pumpy with the very sexy Jeanne 'gives me the' Tripplehorn), a few more gruesome deaths, a smidgen of exciting, pulse-pounding action, and the film's infamous blink-and-you'll miss-it shot of Stone's kebab as she uncrosses her legs during a police interview, all of which adds up to a whole heap of unmissable, jaw-dropping, eye-opening, big budget fun the likes of which we might never see again (unless Verhoeven can get Hollywood to forget all about Showgirls).
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "Good Seductive Thriller!"
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gwnightscream
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/9/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Michael Douglas, Sharon Stone, Jeanne Tripplehorn, George Dzundza and Leilani Sarelle star in this 1992 thriller. This begins in San Francisco with a retired rock star having sex with a blonde woman who brutally kills him with an icepick. Detective, Nick Curran (Douglas) and his partner, Gus (Dzundza) begin investigating and soon meet the victim's lover, Catherine Tramell (Stone) who becomes the main suspect. They learn that she's a writer and the murder coincidentally occurs in her recent novel. Nick starts to get involved with Catherine and begins questioning her motives when she plans on using him as a character in her next book. Tripplehorn plays Nick's ex-girlfriend, Beth Garner who is a psychiatrist and Sarelle plays Catherine's friend and lover, Roxy. Michael and Sharon have great chemistry and Jerry Goldsmith's score is excellent as usual. I recommend this good seductive thriller featuring Stone's famous leg-crossing scene.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Guilty Pleasure.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    AaronCapenBanner
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Michael Douglas plays San Francisco detective Nick Curran, who is investigating the brutal icepick murder of rock star Johnny Boz, which leads him to his girlfriend, novelist Catherine Tramell(Sharon Stone, unforgettable) Nick, though suspicious of Catherine, is nonetheless attracted to her brazen sensuality, and they begin a torrid affair, even though more murders pile up, and Catherine proves to be quite manipulative and intelligent...is she guilty? Controversial film directed by Paul Verhoeven is never boring, though normally having no one in the story to root for would be a problem, film is so slickly made and in-your-face that it may be the epitome of the guilty pleasure; trashy yet enjoyable. Both lead actors are excellent though, even if the mystery is never satisfactorily resolved.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    thrilling till the end
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    acpaloveshavefun
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I recently re saw this movie, and if your a thriller fan you'll absolutely love it. I was at the edge of my seat the entire time, trying to see if I can solve it. Definitely not for kids by the way. Please do not listen for the old bittys out there who are saying that This movie is porn,if I remember correctly the movie psycho had the infamous shower scene. yes its violent and yes it has sexual content, and "Adult situation" but that's what makes a really good movie. This was a perfect example of a great movie before everyone became so politically correct. If you can't handle this as an adult, go live with the Amish, is definitely not for you.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Unsatisfying
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    leonlouisricci
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    There is so much here that is unresolved that it leaves an empty, unfulfilled feeling that the viewer has been suckered. Endless nude and sex scenes intrude on the mystery plot and in the end it is all for not much. Infamous for its explicit exploitation of said sex and nudity and forever frustrating for that's pretty much all there is. The soft-porn aside it can be a somewhat sultry, trashy ride with enough intrigue to keep the interest but not enough to make it a totally engaging entertainment. The biggest problem is the ambiguity about most of what unfolds. There are dangling plot elements and shallow, confusing side shows. In all, it is a murky, muddy, and thin piece of Pulp that has modern machinations and push the envelope displays of Crime Fiction laced with so much pomp that it's rendered impotent. The Movie has enough sizzle to attract viewers but cannot justify all the indulgence and will most likely be an unsatisfactory guilty pleasure. It is quite an overrated Film whose appeal comes from the most lowbrow lexicons of entertainment. But hey, someone once said...there's one born every minute. That's a lot of ticket buyers.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    While its premise is promising, "Basic Instinct" is executed in an inconsistent manner
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Chris Mizerak
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    There are many aspects, both good and bad, that you can pick up from Paul Verhoeven's 1992 erotic thriller Basic Instinct. On one hand, the premise of the film is kind of interesting and has a certain amount of complexity to it. Also, the film works okay enough as far as erotic films go with Sharon Stone flaunting out her body. On the other hand, the film is really cheesy and over-the-top at times as well as really dull in others. So if you're guessing that I think this film has an inconsistent feel to it, you'd probably be right. Basic Instinct follows a police detective (Michael Douglas) with a troubling past who is trying to solve the recent murder of a rock and roll star. The only eligible suspect so far is a book writer (Sharon Stone), whose stories are about women murdering men, who was the last person to see him. One of her own stories seems to play out in the same way that this victim was murdered. Naturally, the police suspects that she did it. The plot thickens however when the detective falls in love with the writer and learns some new developments about the case. In case I haven't mentioned it in any of my earlier reviews, let me get this off my chest. With a few exceptions, I really do not care at all for films centered on police detectives, cops or characters involved in similar professions since I find them to be boring, forgettable, and formulaic. While there are exceptions that either have interesting cases or characters, the rest of them just don't do a thing for me especially in terms of story, characters, and dialogue. Keeping that in mind, while I find whatever takes place in the police department to be fairly formulaic, it wasn't boring and whatever dialogue was being said wasn't as much torture to listen to as I thought it was going to be. I thought it was going to be too difficult to understand what was being said like other films of this genre, but luckily it was easy to understand what was being said, so that must count for something. On top of that, the story has a reasonably intriguing complexity to it and so do the two main characters. The hero and villain in this film are not clear cut, which is fairly authentic of real life. In reality, it's not crystal clear who the heroes and villains are, one culture may consider certain "heroes" villains, and vice versa. In other words, the screenplay was wise enough to put that aspect into the story. If you go see this film solely for looking at Sharon Stone's physique, you won't be disappointed since she really looks good in this film. I wouldn't be surprised if some viewers were reminded of the blonde women Alfred Hitchcock used in his pictures especially Kim Novak. I know I detected some similarities in terms of looks and wardrobe between Stone and the typical blondes Hitchcock used in his films. From what I've said so far, it sounds like this should be a good movie given my personal tastes. But sadly, Basic Instinct is one of those films in which the premise alone is better than the actual execution. One huge issue I had with Basic Instinct is the quality of the acting. I found the acting in this picture to be really weak. While the characters of the two leads are fascinating, the performances aren't executed well enough to do justice to the written characters. I also don't find the two leads (especially Douglas) either that believable or even that subtle/natural with their delivery. Furthermore, the performance by Jeanne Tripplehorn as a psychiatrist helping out Douglas' character is especially unconvincing, considering that I never believed that her character had enough experience in studying psychology to the point were she would become a professional one at such a young age. I simply didn't buy it at all, and the only point to her character existing in this film is solely for a plot twist that is used later in the film. I think she was of no importance to the plot whatsoever. Because of the disappointing acting quality, I don't really buy whatever ludicrous events take place in the plot as a result. Therefore, I can't take anything in the plot as seriously as the film seems to want me to. While the screenplay has its fair share of intriguing elements, there are also some elements of the screenplay especially with its dialogue that feels really cheesy and doesn't even sound the slightest bit realistic. As a result, that's how the film becomes inconsistent in terms of its delivery. In a nutshell, Basic Instinct definitely seems to be a mixed bag. While it has a good idea of what it wants to be, it seldom delivers on the promises it makes mainly because the acting is so mediocre to the point where it interferes with my ability to believe what's happening on screen. I'd only recommend this film if you're solely interested in checking out Stone's body. It's not much of an endorsement, but that's the highest praise I can give to this flick.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Murder All Around Her
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bkoganbing
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Although most reviewers have concentrated on the leads, Basic Instinct has some other fine performances in it. Still Michael Douglas as the sex obsessed cop and Sharon Stone as the amoral, multi-sexual woman who seems to have murder all around her give some iconic performances. A couple of SFPD detectives who played TV detectives, Michael Douglas in Streets Of San Francisco and George Dzundza in Law And Order, get assigned to the homicide of a former rockstar icon. The man had as the story tells us the 'coital moment of the century' before he died and as Michael Douglas finds out with Sharon Stone his prime suspect. It's not like Douglas hasn't any issues himself, he's seeing the SFPD shrink Jeanne Tripplehorn. One of those issues apparently is professional detachment as gets involved with both Tripplehorn and Stone. Far worse with Stone as she is a suspect. Murders in the past and murders in the present seem to pop up whenever Stone is around. She's an heiress to a fortune, a psychology major from college and licensed and an author of lurid novels. She knows how to press the buttons of both sexes and soon enough Douglas is in her world. The only one keeping a professional detachment is Dzundza who is not thinking with his male member. Even when an Internal Affairs cop who is investigating Douglas is murdered, Dzundza sticks by his partner. See what it gets him. In fact Dzundza and Tripplehorn don't get near enough credit for their work here. I think most know Tripplehorn as I do for playing Tom Cruise's wife in The Firm. She too is a woman with a lot of issues. As for George Dzundza as the only one in the film actually who seems to be normal, the others all seem to play off him. Still Sharon Stone's career was launched with what she did in Basic Instinct. This woman will wind up President of the USA or on death row, no middle ground for her. And you can believe she's every man and woman's coital moment of a lifetime. I don't know how successful or how good Basic Instinct 2 was, but seeing this has given me an incentive to see the sequel.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Bill Hicks and my Basic instinct was right, it's an unpleasant film.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ironhorse_iv
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It's sad to say that sex sells. Basic Instinct without a doubt sells, but it's just a sexy thriller that's got plenty of libido but not nearly as much brains as it thinks it has. It's extremely misogynistic and is very predictable. I was very disappointed with the whole movie, and had figured out the murderer within about 30 minutes into it. It's titillating, even exciting at times, but ultimately collapses under the weight of its own stupidity. The movie contained a lot of graphic sexual acts throughout the movie that makes it more of a soft porn movie in disguise & less than a film noir. It could have been better, if it cut down on the exotic a bit, and focus more on the story and give us a challenge. In the film's opening, Rockstar Boz is stabbed to death by a blonde woman with an ice pick during sex. We never see the woman's face -- just her blonde hair and, of course, most of her lust-inducing body. By just looking at the body of the killer, you can pretty much know who did it. The police find the dead body, and Det. Nick Curran, (Michael Douglas) was put on the case whom slept with his police-appointed shrink Dr. Beth Garner (Jeanne Triplehorn). Rather than getting a DNA test on the number one- suspect, Boz's girlfriend, Catherine Tramell (Sharon Stone), a famous crime novelist, the cops interview her. I know DNA testing was still in its early stages in the early '90s but convicting using DNA evidence alone has been proved fact since 1988, four years when the film was set. Well, Catherine use the interview to make fools out of them. The way she manipulates psychology was superbly awesome. Without Sharon Stone as femme fatale, this movie is nothing. Still, most people would remember from this scene just the famous leg switching, and not the acting. Although, the detectives were too stupid to realize that there is something about her that doesn't add up. We sees Catherine using it to break ice during the film. She even mentions how her book is about a detective falling for the wrong woman and that she kills him. Isn't it very clear who the killer is? Sooner than later, Nick get into Catherine's sex life. The movie moves with the suspense involving Nick and Catherine. He's supposed to be following this woman as a suspect but is actually falling for her deadly charm since Nick is dumb like the other cops. Clearly this film points out the men are just horny dumb pervs who slept before duty. The film tries to do a lot of dumb red herrings such as Beth is revealed to have had a past sexual encounter with Catherine, that according to Catherine developed an obsessive fixation on her as Beth copy her. The audience is suppose to wonder whether Beth killed Boz as is described in Catherine's book to frame her. Not once in the film, does Beth show any bit of bi or lesbians feelings. Catherine does with a girl name Roxy (Leilani Sarelle). The film was strongly opposed by gay rights activists, who criticized the film's portrayal of bisexual women as a murderous sociopaths. The featurette Blond Poison reveals the uproar the film caused during the San Francisco filming. They deplored it as being "anti-gay" and a reinforcement of Hollywood homophobia due to typecasting particularly lesbians as twisted and evil, or just act lesbians to get men's horny. I think the heterosexuals can also be equally offensive, as some feminists like Camille Paglia starts breaking things down to banal symbolisms, the opening killing with the ice pick is interpreted as, "Woman steals man's penis and uses it against him." men find themselves involuntarily cringing. Freudian Pscyhoanalysts have retained the term instinct that the film refer to human motivational forces (such as sex and aggression), sometimes represented as Eros - life instinct and Thanatos- death Instinct, but the real term is motivational forces or drives to correct the original error in the translation of Freud's work. Psychologist Abraham Maslow argued that humans no longer have instincts because we have the ability to override them in certain situations. For Maslow, an instinct is something which cannot be overridden, & therefore while the term may have applied to humans in the past, it no longer does. So the film should be title 'Basic Drives". It's clear why Joe Eszterhas was paid 3-million bucks for his script with its clever plot construction. Still there are pointless sequences like where Nick and Catherine engage in a car chase for no discernible reason other than to serve as a dire attempt to jack up the energy level. The film also has unlikeable characters. The hero Nick viciously rapes Beth in one scene. They're perfectly acceptable in the art of film, but Basic Instinct did go a little overboard with that sex. The film does good with its abstract images, the way it's shot from different angles, made it a little more elliptical, a bit less direct. The eerie Jerry Goldsmith theme gives the film a creepy tone. Basic Instinct was to transfers Mr. Verhoeven's flair for action-oriented material to the realm of Hitchcockian intrigue, but the results are so-so. Following the success of the film, Ezsterhas & Verhoeven went on to collaborate on Showgirls. (Another horrible mess). Since release, the blue-ray version add more graphic violence & sex into the film.This film is an affront to taste. It's an over-baked mind control fantasy, brought to life by a horrible script, and relieved of meaning by a hair brained plot. It's all Tougue in cheek really like a perv. It's depends on your kicks.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I'd have to be pretty stupid to write a book about killing and then kill him the way I described in my book. I'd be announcing myself as the killer. I'm not stupid.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    JohnRouseMerriottChard
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Basic Instinct is directed by Paul Verhoeven and written by Joe Eszterhaz. It stars Michael Douglas, Sharon Stone, George Dzundza, Jeanne Tripplehorn, Denis Arndt and Leilani Sarelle. Music is scored by Jerry Goldsmith and cinematography by Jan de Bont. Nick Curran (Douglas) of the SFPD is strung out and under investigation by Internal Affairs, last thing he needs is to be drawn into a dangerous relationship with a sex crazed blonde who may be a murderess... Time hasn't been kind to Verhoeven's soft-core porn thriller, where once was shock and awe killings (the film opening with a brutal mini ice-pick murder), steamy love scenes and a famed and controversial crotch shot, now is ludicrous orgasms, iffy effects and Michael Douglas' unappetising ass! Hell there was even protests during the film's initial theatre run as the gay community went up in arms about the portrayal of bisexuals possibly being mad murderers? Yet for all of its taming over the years, Basic Instinct can at least now been seen as the hugely efficient mystery thriller that it is, one that is propelled by some very good performances by the principal actors. The strength in the story is not in the sex or blood, but in the character arcs of Nick Curran and Catherine Tramell (Stone). Curran is a man perched on the edge of doom who is controlled totally by the women around him. He is by definition a quintessential film noir protagonist, in so deep he ultimately will be resigned to his fate. Catharine Tramell is a ultimate femme fatale, beautiful and seductive, she's always in control, leading all male characters where she wants them to go. There's a delicious kink to the narrative, with Verhoeven gleefully pulling the strings, a smirk no doubt etched onto his face. This is very good story telling, with a plot of substantial twists and turns. True, it does carry some soft-core baggage that can steer the restless away from the character strengths within, but for the neo-noir crowd there is much to enjoy here. 7.5/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Sharon Stone's finest hour
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    moviestar26
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    'Basic Instinct' was a film that rebooted the noir genre after it became rare in the early eighties. Prior to this the Coen brother's 'Blood Simple' attempted to revive the genre, but the industry was changing with the shift in audience's movie preferences. However this is more akin to being a sex thriller which also happens to incorporate a suspense element. 'Basic Instinct' takes the viewer back in time to the golden era of cinema when the femme fatales were glamorising the screen and became every male's dream fantasy. The film has been considered a classic and has not dated with time. The theme has been beautifully been One of my cult classic favourites from the 1990s. Whenever I catch a scene randomly on television, it brings back nostalgic memories of my childhood. I can still remember waking in the middle of the night just so I could record this movie secretly on my VCR. This is the movie that catapulted stone's career to international stardom. She immediately became a sex symbol and every man began dreaming of her. She immortalised a role that was so deep in characterisation. 'Catherine Trammel' was someone that was not only devious but smart, clever and manipulative. A role model so to speak that will certainly serve as an influence to many aspiring actresses and writers in the future. The role possessed every element that a negative character would have. Joe Esterhas is the writer. Previously he wrote 'Flash dance' and 'jagged edge' Most of his themes are similar. All negative roles about killers and murderers. 'Showgirls' and 'Jade' were also adapted for the screen. Unfortunately they failed at the box office and did not work. I think the audiences had higher expectations. 'Basic Instinct' has a fantastic script. This is the reason why the film worked. And then there is Paul Verhoeven who is a well known director in his home land. He has beautifully combined sex with the suspense genre. I am not very familiar with his Dutch movies. But he always had the style of depicting the theme of 'sex' as a weapon. I enjoyed the movie immensely, and being more of a reader than a movie- goer I jumped at the chance to read the book subsequent to seeing the motion picture. However, I feel that much of which made the movie great owes gratitude to the incredible soundtrack, imagery and skill of the actors; sometimes movies can be successfully novelised, but with Basic Instinct being the stimulus-rich move that it is I feel this was a failed attempt. The characters come off as threadbare and unexplored, lacking in depth or substance of any kind, and the seductively dark tone of the movie is lost on the page; it becomes rather humdrum and glancing, as if each page were written to keep up with the flow of the movie to be read within the hour. Where I was hoping to see some of the twisted, genius logic of Catherine Tramell explored on the page instead I found her to be de-powered, humanised and lacking of a great deal of her appeal as a result. It's worth the read for big fans of the Basic Instinct movies if only to explore the idea through a different form of media, (SPOILER) A San Francisco police detective who is investigated the murder of a retired rock star. The main suspect happens to be a novelist. She is under suspicion. She is released due to lack of evidence. Meanwhile the detective has maintains his belief that she is involved. He decides to pursue her and monitor her movements. The deeper his investigation proceeds, he succumbs to her charm and falls in love in spite knowing he is risking his life. His infatuation distances him from people around him and he refuses to listen to others. People he know become murdered. Eventually he finds it difficult to accept that she is a murderer as he begins to doubt his psychiatrist's past. (END OF SPOILER) The film is made with a sexy noir thriller tone. It brings back memories of Lawrence Kasden's 'Body Heat'. This was the last time a lead actress made an impression with a memorable role. Kathleen Turner became a popular star. At many moments the film feels like a horror thriller. There are many scenes that evoke a frightening feeling. What makes 'Basic Instinct' so unique is we are watching a women manipulating us with her attractive appeal that makes us want to believe she can be a killer. Her seductive charm works on the male protagonist, which leads to confusion. At the end we are eager to want to see her apprehended because we are disgusted how someone can desire to get away with murder for no reason. The sex scenes were unique and were the closest that could be categorised as 'soft porn'. This was one of the appealing factors that mad the film a success. 'Basic Instinct' has sustained it's quality over the years. It has managed to preserve it's quality and has not paled in front of movies that released recently. Due credit goes to Sharon Stone's performance and a winning script by Esterhas. The movie does follow true to the noir conventions. Anyone who is familiar with this will be able to notice them. However some of the typical noir rules were missing. There was no themes related to adultery or blackmailing. But it's relevance or lack of it doesn't seem significant as the this was a character driven film. Jerry Goldsmith's background score is specifically suited to the film's mood and atmosphere. It is still memorable and has different shades throughout the movie. It blends well with scenes and evokes the intriguing and haunting feeling.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Classic Verhoeven outrageousness.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    BA_Harrison
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/9/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Despite being built around the most 'basic' of plots, erotic thriller Basic Instinct remains director Paul Verhoeven's biggest commercial success, being one of the highest grossing titles of 1992. Unperturbed by the protestations of gay activists and uptight censor-happy moralists, who objected to the film's provocative cocktail of graphic sex and violence and its portrayal of bisexuals as crazed killers, the general public flocked to the cinema to revel in Verhoeven's heady concoction of wanton lust and cold-blooded violence. Written by Joe Eszterhas of Flashdance fame, the script is slick Hollywood nonsense, a flashy, trashy, twisting, turning tale clearly inspired by Hitchcock and the film-noir genre. Frequently teetering on the brink of preposterousness, its is precisely the kind of far-fetched nonsense that only a true maverick like Verhoeven could do justice toand boy, does he pull out all the stops here... Never one to do things by halves, the Dutch director opens his film as he means to go on, with a brutal murder that takes place during intercourse, a physically flawless blonde viciously stabbing her lover to death with an ice-pick. Scorching sex combined with gut churning nastiness, it's a real shocker (use the freeze-frame check out the outrageous shot of the pick going through the victim's nose!!!) and a clear indicator that this is to be no run-of-the-mill Hollywood thriller. The remainder of the film follows troubled detective Nick Curran (Michae Douglas) as he investigates the murder, stupidly becoming involved with his prime suspect, scorching hot, super intelligent, highly manipulative crime novelist Catherine Tramell (Sharon Stone), who may or may not be lining him up as her latest victim. Cue plenty more raunchy, near the knuckle nookie (including some rough rumpy-pumpy with the very sexy Jeanne 'gives me the' Tripplehorn), a few more gruesome deaths, a smidgen of exciting, pulse-pounding action, and the film's infamous blink-and-you'll miss-it shot of Stone's kebab as she uncrosses her legs during a police interview, all of which adds up to a whole heap of unmissable, jaw-dropping, eye-opening, big budget fun the likes of which we might never see again (unless Verhoeven can get Hollywood to forget all about Showgirls).
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "Good Seductive Thriller!"
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gwnightscream
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/9/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Michael Douglas, Sharon Stone, Jeanne Tripplehorn, George Dzundza and Leilani Sarelle star in this 1992 thriller. This begins in San Francisco with a retired rock star having sex with a blonde woman who brutally kills him with an icepick. Detective, Nick Curran (Douglas) and his partner, Gus (Dzundza) begin investigating and soon meet the victim's lover, Catherine Tramell (Stone) who becomes the main suspect. They learn that she's a writer and the murder coincidentally occurs in her recent novel. Nick starts to get involved with Catherine and begins questioning her motives when she plans on using him as a character in her next book. Tripplehorn plays Nick's ex-girlfriend, Beth Garner who is a psychiatrist and Sarelle plays Catherine's friend and lover, Roxy. Michael and Sharon have great chemistry and Jerry Goldsmith's score is excellent as usual. I recommend this good seductive thriller featuring Stone's famous leg-crossing scene.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Guilty Pleasure.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    AaronCapenBanner
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Michael Douglas plays San Francisco detective Nick Curran, who is investigating the brutal icepick murder of rock star Johnny Boz, which leads him to his girlfriend, novelist Catherine Tramell(Sharon Stone, unforgettable) Nick, though suspicious of Catherine, is nonetheless attracted to her brazen sensuality, and they begin a torrid affair, even though more murders pile up, and Catherine proves to be quite manipulative and intelligent...is she guilty? Controversial film directed by Paul Verhoeven is never boring, though normally having no one in the story to root for would be a problem, film is so slickly made and in-your-face that it may be the epitome of the guilty pleasure; trashy yet enjoyable. Both lead actors are excellent though, even if the mystery is never satisfactorily resolved.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    thrilling till the end
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    acpaloveshavefun
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I recently re saw this movie, and if your a thriller fan you'll absolutely love it. I was at the edge of my seat the entire time, trying to see if I can solve it. Definitely not for kids by the way. Please do not listen for the old bittys out there who are saying that This movie is porn,if I remember correctly the movie psycho had the infamous shower scene. yes its violent and yes it has sexual content, and "Adult situation" but that's what makes a really good movie. This was a perfect example of a great movie before everyone became so politically correct. If you can't handle this as an adult, go live with the Amish, is definitely not for you.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Unsatisfying
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    leonlouisricci
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    There is so much here that is unresolved that it leaves an empty, unfulfilled feeling that the viewer has been suckered. Endless nude and sex scenes intrude on the mystery plot and in the end it is all for not much. Infamous for its explicit exploitation of said sex and nudity and forever frustrating for that's pretty much all there is. The soft-porn aside it can be a somewhat sultry, trashy ride with enough intrigue to keep the interest but not enough to make it a totally engaging entertainment. The biggest problem is the ambiguity about most of what unfolds. There are dangling plot elements and shallow, confusing side shows. In all, it is a murky, muddy, and thin piece of Pulp that has modern machinations and push the envelope displays of Crime Fiction laced with so much pomp that it's rendered impotent. The Movie has enough sizzle to attract viewers but cannot justify all the indulgence and will most likely be an unsatisfactory guilty pleasure. It is quite an overrated Film whose appeal comes from the most lowbrow lexicons of entertainment. But hey, someone once said...there's one born every minute. That's a lot of ticket buyers.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    While its premise is promising, "Basic Instinct" is executed in an inconsistent manner
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Chris Mizerak
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    There are many aspects, both good and bad, that you can pick up from Paul Verhoeven's 1992 erotic thriller Basic Instinct. On one hand, the premise of the film is kind of interesting and has a certain amount of complexity to it. Also, the film works okay enough as far as erotic films go with Sharon Stone flaunting out her body. On the other hand, the film is really cheesy and over-the-top at times as well as really dull in others. So if you're guessing that I think this film has an inconsistent feel to it, you'd probably be right. Basic Instinct follows a police detective (Michael Douglas) with a troubling past who is trying to solve the recent murder of a rock and roll star. The only eligible suspect so far is a book writer (Sharon Stone), whose stories are about women murdering men, who was the last person to see him. One of her own stories seems to play out in the same way that this victim was murdered. Naturally, the police suspects that she did it. The plot thickens however when the detective falls in love with the writer and learns some new developments about the case. In case I haven't mentioned it in any of my earlier reviews, let me get this off my chest. With a few exceptions, I really do not care at all for films centered on police detectives, cops or characters involved in similar professions since I find them to be boring, forgettable, and formulaic. While there are exceptions that either have interesting cases or characters, the rest of them just don't do a thing for me especially in terms of story, characters, and dialogue. Keeping that in mind, while I find whatever takes place in the police department to be fairly formulaic, it wasn't boring and whatever dialogue was being said wasn't as much torture to listen to as I thought it was going to be. I thought it was going to be too difficult to understand what was being said like other films of this genre, but luckily it was easy to understand what was being said, so that must count for something. On top of that, the story has a reasonably intriguing complexity to it and so do the two main characters. The hero and villain in this film are not clear cut, which is fairly authentic of real life. In reality, it's not crystal clear who the heroes and villains are, one culture may consider certain "heroes" villains, and vice versa. In other words, the screenplay was wise enough to put that aspect into the story. If you go see this film solely for looking at Sharon Stone's physique, you won't be disappointed since she really looks good in this film. I wouldn't be surprised if some viewers were reminded of the blonde women Alfred Hitchcock used in his pictures especially Kim Novak. I know I detected some similarities in terms of looks and wardrobe between Stone and the typical blondes Hitchcock used in his films. From what I've said so far, it sounds like this should be a good movie given my personal tastes. But sadly, Basic Instinct is one of those films in which the premise alone is better than the actual execution. One huge issue I had with Basic Instinct is the quality of the acting. I found the acting in this picture to be really weak. While the characters of the two leads are fascinating, the performances aren't executed well enough to do justice to the written characters. I also don't find the two leads (especially Douglas) either that believable or even that subtle/natural with their delivery. Furthermore, the performance by Jeanne Tripplehorn as a psychiatrist helping out Douglas' character is especially unconvincing, considering that I never believed that her character had enough experience in studying psychology to the point were she would become a professional one at such a young age. I simply didn't buy it at all, and the only point to her character existing in this film is solely for a plot twist that is used later in the film. I think she was of no importance to the plot whatsoever. Because of the disappointing acting quality, I don't really buy whatever ludicrous events take place in the plot as a result. Therefore, I can't take anything in the plot as seriously as the film seems to want me to. While the screenplay has its fair share of intriguing elements, there are also some elements of the screenplay especially with its dialogue that feels really cheesy and doesn't even sound the slightest bit realistic. As a result, that's how the film becomes inconsistent in terms of its delivery. In a nutshell, Basic Instinct definitely seems to be a mixed bag. While it has a good idea of what it wants to be, it seldom delivers on the promises it makes mainly because the acting is so mediocre to the point where it interferes with my ability to believe what's happening on screen. I'd only recommend this film if you're solely interested in checking out Stone's body. It's not much of an endorsement, but that's the highest praise I can give to this flick.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Murder All Around Her
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bkoganbing
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Although most reviewers have concentrated on the leads, Basic Instinct has some other fine performances in it. Still Michael Douglas as the sex obsessed cop and Sharon Stone as the amoral, multi-sexual woman who seems to have murder all around her give some iconic performances. A couple of SFPD detectives who played TV detectives, Michael Douglas in Streets Of San Francisco and George Dzundza in Law And Order, get assigned to the homicide of a former rockstar icon. The man had as the story tells us the 'coital moment of the century' before he died and as Michael Douglas finds out with Sharon Stone his prime suspect. It's not like Douglas hasn't any issues himself, he's seeing the SFPD shrink Jeanne Tripplehorn. One of those issues apparently is professional detachment as gets involved with both Tripplehorn and Stone. Far worse with Stone as she is a suspect. Murders in the past and murders in the present seem to pop up whenever Stone is around. She's an heiress to a fortune, a psychology major from college and licensed and an author of lurid novels. She knows how to press the buttons of both sexes and soon enough Douglas is in her world. The only one keeping a professional detachment is Dzundza who is not thinking with his male member. Even when an Internal Affairs cop who is investigating Douglas is murdered, Dzundza sticks by his partner. See what it gets him. In fact Dzundza and Tripplehorn don't get near enough credit for their work here. I think most know Tripplehorn as I do for playing Tom Cruise's wife in The Firm. She too is a woman with a lot of issues. As for George Dzundza as the only one in the film actually who seems to be normal, the others all seem to play off him. Still Sharon Stone's career was launched with what she did in Basic Instinct. This woman will wind up President of the USA or on death row, no middle ground for her. And you can believe she's every man and woman's coital moment of a lifetime. I don't know how successful or how good Basic Instinct 2 was, but seeing this has given me an incentive to see the sequel.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Bill Hicks and my Basic instinct was right, it's an unpleasant film.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ironhorse_iv
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It's sad to say that sex sells. Basic Instinct without a doubt sells, but it's just a sexy thriller that's got plenty of libido but not nearly as much brains as it thinks it has. It's extremely misogynistic and is very predictable. I was very disappointed with the whole movie, and had figured out the murderer within about 30 minutes into it. It's titillating, even exciting at times, but ultimately collapses under the weight of its own stupidity. The movie contained a lot of graphic sexual acts throughout the movie that makes it more of a soft porn movie in disguise & less than a film noir. It could have been better, if it cut down on the exotic a bit, and focus more on the story and give us a challenge. In the film's opening, Rockstar Boz is stabbed to death by a blonde woman with an ice pick during sex. We never see the woman's face -- just her blonde hair and, of course, most of her lust-inducing body. By just looking at the body of the killer, you can pretty much know who did it. The police find the dead body, and Det. Nick Curran, (Michael Douglas) was put on the case whom slept with his police-appointed shrink Dr. Beth Garner (Jeanne Triplehorn). Rather than getting a DNA test on the number one- suspect, Boz's girlfriend, Catherine Tramell (Sharon Stone), a famous crime novelist, the cops interview her. I know DNA testing was still in its early stages in the early '90s but convicting using DNA evidence alone has been proved fact since 1988, four years when the film was set. Well, Catherine use the interview to make fools out of them. The way she manipulates psychology was superbly awesome. Without Sharon Stone as femme fatale, this movie is nothing. Still, most people would remember from this scene just the famous leg switching, and not the acting. Although, the detectives were too stupid to realize that there is something about her that doesn't add up. We sees Catherine using it to break ice during the film. She even mentions how her book is about a detective falling for the wrong woman and that she kills him. Isn't it very clear who the killer is? Sooner than later, Nick get into Catherine's sex life. The movie moves with the suspense involving Nick and Catherine. He's supposed to be following this woman as a suspect but is actually falling for her deadly charm since Nick is dumb like the other cops. Clearly this film points out the men are just horny dumb pervs who slept before duty. The film tries to do a lot of dumb red herrings such as Beth is revealed to have had a past sexual encounter with Catherine, that according to Catherine developed an obsessive fixation on her as Beth copy her. The audience is suppose to wonder whether Beth killed Boz as is described in Catherine's book to frame her. Not once in the film, does Beth show any bit of bi or lesbians feelings. Catherine does with a girl name Roxy (Leilani Sarelle). The film was strongly opposed by gay rights activists, who criticized the film's portrayal of bisexual women as a murderous sociopaths. The featurette Blond Poison reveals the uproar the film caused during the San Francisco filming. They deplored it as being "anti-gay" and a reinforcement of Hollywood homophobia due to typecasting particularly lesbians as twisted and evil, or just act lesbians to get men's horny. I think the heterosexuals can also be equally offensive, as some feminists like Camille Paglia starts breaking things down to banal symbolisms, the opening killing with the ice pick is interpreted as, "Woman steals man's penis and uses it against him." men find themselves involuntarily cringing. Freudian Pscyhoanalysts have retained the term instinct that the film refer to human motivational forces (such as sex and aggression), sometimes represented as Eros - life instinct and Thanatos- death Instinct, but the real term is motivational forces or drives to correct the original error in the translation of Freud's work. Psychologist Abraham Maslow argued that humans no longer have instincts because we have the ability to override them in certain situations. For Maslow, an instinct is something which cannot be overridden, & therefore while the term may have applied to humans in the past, it no longer does. So the film should be title 'Basic Drives". It's clear why Joe Eszterhas was paid 3-million bucks for his script with its clever plot construction. Still there are pointless sequences like where Nick and Catherine engage in a car chase for no discernible reason other than to serve as a dire attempt to jack up the energy level. The film also has unlikeable characters. The hero Nick viciously rapes Beth in one scene. They're perfectly acceptable in the art of film, but Basic Instinct did go a little overboard with that sex. The film does good with its abstract images, the way it's shot from different angles, made it a little more elliptical, a bit less direct. The eerie Jerry Goldsmith theme gives the film a creepy tone. Basic Instinct was to transfers Mr. Verhoeven's flair for action-oriented material to the realm of Hitchcockian intrigue, but the results are so-so. Following the success of the film, Ezsterhas & Verhoeven went on to collaborate on Showgirls. (Another horrible mess). Since release, the blue-ray version add more graphic violence & sex into the film.This film is an affront to taste. It's an over-baked mind control fantasy, brought to life by a horrible script, and relieved of meaning by a hair brained plot. It's all Tougue in cheek really like a perv. It's depends on your kicks.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I'd have to be pretty stupid to write a book about killing and then kill him the way I described in my book. I'd be announcing myself as the killer. I'm not stupid.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    JohnRouseMerriottChard
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Basic Instinct is directed by Paul Verhoeven and written by Joe Eszterhaz. It stars Michael Douglas, Sharon Stone, George Dzundza, Jeanne Tripplehorn, Denis Arndt and Leilani Sarelle. Music is scored by Jerry Goldsmith and cinematography by Jan de Bont. Nick Curran (Douglas) of the SFPD is strung out and under investigation by Internal Affairs, last thing he needs is to be drawn into a dangerous relationship with a sex crazed blonde who may be a murderess... Time hasn't been kind to Verhoeven's soft-core porn thriller, where once was shock and awe killings (the film opening with a brutal mini ice-pick murder), steamy love scenes and a famed and controversial crotch shot, now is ludicrous orgasms, iffy effects and Michael Douglas' unappetising ass! Hell there was even protests during the film's initial theatre run as the gay community went up in arms about the portrayal of bisexuals possibly being mad murderers? Yet for all of its taming over the years, Basic Instinct can at least now been seen as the hugely efficient mystery thriller that it is, one that is propelled by some very good performances by the principal actors. The strength in the story is not in the sex or blood, but in the character arcs of Nick Curran and Catherine Tramell (Stone). Curran is a man perched on the edge of doom who is controlled totally by the women around him. He is by definition a quintessential film noir protagonist, in so deep he ultimately will be resigned to his fate. Catharine Tramell is a ultimate femme fatale, beautiful and seductive, she's always in control, leading all male characters where she wants them to go. There's a delicious kink to the narrative, with Verhoeven gleefully pulling the strings, a smirk no doubt etched onto his face. This is very good story telling, with a plot of substantial twists and turns. True, it does carry some soft-core baggage that can steer the restless away from the character strengths within, but for the neo-noir crowd there is much to enjoy here. 7.5/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Sharon Stone's finest hour
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    moviestar26
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    'Basic Instinct' was a film that rebooted the noir genre after it became rare in the early eighties. Prior to this the Coen brother's 'Blood Simple' attempted to revive the genre, but the industry was changing with the shift in audience's movie preferences. However this is more akin to being a sex thriller which also happens to incorporate a suspense element. 'Basic Instinct' takes the viewer back in time to the golden era of cinema when the femme fatales were glamorising the screen and became every male's dream fantasy. The film has been considered a classic and has not dated with time. The theme has been beautifully been One of my cult classic favourites from the 1990s. Whenever I catch a scene randomly on television, it brings back nostalgic memories of my childhood. I can still remember waking in the middle of the night just so I could record this movie secretly on my VCR. This is the movie that catapulted stone's career to international stardom. She immediately became a sex symbol and every man began dreaming of her. She immortalised a role that was so deep in characterisation. 'Catherine Trammel' was someone that was not only devious but smart, clever and manipulative. A role model so to speak that will certainly serve as an influence to many aspiring actresses and writers in the future. The role possessed every element that a negative character would have. Joe Esterhas is the writer. Previously he wrote 'Flash dance' and 'jagged edge' Most of his themes are similar. All negative roles about killers and murderers. 'Showgirls' and 'Jade' were also adapted for the screen. Unfortunately they failed at the box office and did not work. I think the audiences had higher expectations. 'Basic Instinct' has a fantastic script. This is the reason why the film worked. And then there is Paul Verhoeven who is a well known director in his home land. He has beautifully combined sex with the suspense genre. I am not very familiar with his Dutch movies. But he always had the style of depicting the theme of 'sex' as a weapon. I enjoyed the movie immensely, and being more of a reader than a movie- goer I jumped at the chance to read the book subsequent to seeing the motion picture. However, I feel that much of which made the movie great owes gratitude to the incredible soundtrack, imagery and skill of the actors; sometimes movies can be successfully novelised, but with Basic Instinct being the stimulus-rich move that it is I feel this was a failed attempt. The characters come off as threadbare and unexplored, lacking in depth or substance of any kind, and the seductively dark tone of the movie is lost on the page; it becomes rather humdrum and glancing, as if each page were written to keep up with the flow of the movie to be read within the hour. Where I was hoping to see some of the twisted, genius logic of Catherine Tramell explored on the page instead I found her to be de-powered, humanised and lacking of a great deal of her appeal as a result. It's worth the read for big fans of the Basic Instinct movies if only to explore the idea through a different form of media, (SPOILER) A San Francisco police detective who is investigated the murder of a retired rock star. The main suspect happens to be a novelist. She is under suspicion. She is released due to lack of evidence. Meanwhile the detective has maintains his belief that she is involved. He decides to pursue her and monitor her movements. The deeper his investigation proceeds, he succumbs to her charm and falls in love in spite knowing he is risking his life. His infatuation distances him from people around him and he refuses to listen to others. People he know become murdered. Eventually he finds it difficult to accept that she is a murderer as he begins to doubt his psychiatrist's past. (END OF SPOILER) The film is made with a sexy noir thriller tone. It brings back memories of Lawrence Kasden's 'Body Heat'. This was the last time a lead actress made an impression with a memorable role. Kathleen Turner became a popular star. At many moments the film feels like a horror thriller. There are many scenes that evoke a frightening feeling. What makes 'Basic Instinct' so unique is we are watching a women manipulating us with her attractive appeal that makes us want to believe she can be a killer. Her seductive charm works on the male protagonist, which leads to confusion. At the end we are eager to want to see her apprehended because we are disgusted how someone can desire to get away with murder for no reason. The sex scenes were unique and were the closest that could be categorised as 'soft porn'. This was one of the appealing factors that mad the film a success. 'Basic Instinct' has sustained it's quality over the years. It has managed to preserve it's quality and has not paled in front of movies that released recently. Due credit goes to Sharon Stone's performance and a winning script by Esterhas. The movie does follow true to the noir conventions. Anyone who is familiar with this will be able to notice them. However some of the typical noir rules were missing. There was no themes related to adultery or blackmailing. But it's relevance or lack of it doesn't seem significant as the this was a character driven film. Jerry Goldsmith's background score is specifically suited to the film's mood and atmosphere. It is still memorable and has different shades throughout the movie. It blends well with scenes and evokes the intriguing and haunting feeling.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Classic Verhoeven outrageousness.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    BA_Harrison
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/9/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Despite being built around the most 'basic' of plots, erotic thriller Basic Instinct remains director Paul Verhoeven's biggest commercial success, being one of the highest grossing titles of 1992. Unperturbed by the protestations of gay activists and uptight censor-happy moralists, who objected to the film's provocative cocktail of graphic sex and violence and its portrayal of bisexuals as crazed killers, the general public flocked to the cinema to revel in Verhoeven's heady concoction of wanton lust and cold-blooded violence. Written by Joe Eszterhas of Flashdance fame, the script is slick Hollywood nonsense, a flashy, trashy, twisting, turning tale clearly inspired by Hitchcock and the film-noir genre. Frequently teetering on the brink of preposterousness, its is precisely the kind of far-fetched nonsense that only a true maverick like Verhoeven could do justice toand boy, does he pull out all the stops here... Never one to do things by halves, the Dutch director opens his film as he means to go on, with a brutal murder that takes place during intercourse, a physically flawless blonde viciously stabbing her lover to death with an ice-pick. Scorching sex combined with gut churning nastiness, it's a real shocker (use the freeze-frame check out the outrageous shot of the pick going through the victim's nose!!!) and a clear indicator that this is to be no run-of-the-mill Hollywood thriller. The remainder of the film follows troubled detective Nick Curran (Michae Douglas) as he investigates the murder, stupidly becoming involved with his prime suspect, scorching hot, super intelligent, highly manipulative crime novelist Catherine Tramell (Sharon Stone), who may or may not be lining him up as her latest victim. Cue plenty more raunchy, near the knuckle nookie (including some rough rumpy-pumpy with the very sexy Jeanne 'gives me the' Tripplehorn), a few more gruesome deaths, a smidgen of exciting, pulse-pounding action, and the film's infamous blink-and-you'll miss-it shot of Stone's kebab as she uncrosses her legs during a police interview, all of which adds up to a whole heap of unmissable, jaw-dropping, eye-opening, big budget fun the likes of which we might never see again (unless Verhoeven can get Hollywood to forget all about Showgirls).
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "Good Seductive Thriller!"
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gwnightscream
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/9/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Michael Douglas, Sharon Stone, Jeanne Tripplehorn, George Dzundza and Leilani Sarelle star in this 1992 thriller. This begins in San Francisco with a retired rock star having sex with a blonde woman who brutally kills him with an icepick. Detective, Nick Curran (Douglas) and his partner, Gus (Dzundza) begin investigating and soon meet the victim's lover, Catherine Tramell (Stone) who becomes the main suspect. They learn that she's a writer and the murder coincidentally occurs in her recent novel. Nick starts to get involved with Catherine and begins questioning her motives when she plans on using him as a character in her next book. Tripplehorn plays Nick's ex-girlfriend, Beth Garner who is a psychiatrist and Sarelle plays Catherine's friend and lover, Roxy. Michael and Sharon have great chemistry and Jerry Goldsmith's score is excellent as usual. I recommend this good seductive thriller featuring Stone's famous leg-crossing scene.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
 </reviews>
</filme>
