<filme>
 <id>
  1598
 </id>
 <imdburl>
  http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0118859
 </imdburl>
 <ano>
  1997
 </ano>
 <titulo>
  City of Industry
 </titulo>
 <rating>
  6.0
 </rating>
 <sinopse>
  A retired thief swears revenge on the lunatic who murdered his brother and partner, while going on the run with the loot they stole.
 </sinopse>
 <storyline>
  Lee Egan lures his older brother Roy out of "retirement" with a sweet jewel heist, only to get killed by a backstabbing partner; then it's up to Roy to get revenge.
 </storyline>
 <generos>
  <genero>
   Crime
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Drama
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Thriller
  </genero>
 </generos>
 <keywords>
  <keyword>
   revenge
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   jewel heist
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   heist
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   stripper
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   jewel theft
  </keyword>
 </keywords>
 <diretores>
  <diretor>
   John Irvin
  </diretor>
 </diretores>
 <escritores>
  <escritor>
   Ken Solarz
  </escritor>
 </escritores>
 <atores>
  <ator>
   Harvey Keitel
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Stephen Dorff
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Timothy Hutton
  </ator>
 </atores>
 <reviews>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not Again!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jmillerdp
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Oh boy! Another "Heist Gone Wrong" movie! And, wouldn't you think that Harvey Keitel would be getting tired of these? After "Reservoir Dogs," you'd think he'd want a break! But, not here. The heist is planned, carried out, and, guess what?!, there is instant double crossing, shooting and everything else. Heavens! The second that happened, I pretty much checked out, and just waited the rest of the movie out. And, of course, it's a "final heist" for Keitel's character. So, that naturally means that everything's going to go wrong, guaranteed! The film is entirely on the shoulders of Harvey Keitel's performance. His fearless brand of acting is what make the film worth watching. But, it's standard plot makes it not worth it otherwise. ****** (6 Out of 10 Stars)
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not your average run of the mill PULP FICTION wannabe
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    JasparLamarCrabb
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    SPOILER ALERT! Easy to dismiss as another in a series of PULP FICTION wannabes, this is much better than expected. Directed with a lot of finesse by John Irvin and starring Harvey Keitel, CITY OF INDUSTRY is a fine crime thriller. Keitel is part of a gang of thieves (which also includes his brother), ripped off by loony cohort Stephen Dorff. A tense game of cat and mouse takes place as Keitel tries to track Dorff down. Keitel, who could easily sleepwalk through this type of film, gives a very good performance (he takes a real beating...several times) and has a lot of chemistry with Famke Janssen (as the widow of one of his cronies). The film is not flawless. The night photography is at times too dark, there is surely one too many name-less characters chasing Keitel, and Dorff is not really threatening enough to be convincing. Nevertheless, it's a well put together revenge film. Stephen Endelman's staccato music is a big plus.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Violent and exciting movie about seedy delinquents who pull off a fateful heist in L.A.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ma-cortes
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is a studio character with tones of suspense about some two-fisted criminals in L.A city . An old thief named Roy Egan (Harvey Keitel) , is drawn into the final jewel heist to Russian Mafia when his youngest brother named Lee (Timothy Hutton) asks him for a last score before they get out of the game . Lee forms a motley group (Keitel , Wade Dominguez and Stephen Dorff) to carry out the violent robbing . Unfortunately for him , Lee's picked one wrong partner and the events get worse . One of them decides he doesn't want to share the goods and betrays the group and happens murders and wreak havoc .The retired thief swears revenge on the lunatic who murdered his partners, while going on the run with the loot they stole. This modern adaptation of noir cinema contains thrills , intrigue, explosive scenes of action and over-riding feeling of heat . Interesting premise in which takes places a moving cat-and-mouse hunt through the seedier sides of L.A . Exciting and stirring finale full of shootouts , violence and fights into a factory . Good performances from all-star cast as Harvey Keitel as an old pro robber who has vowed to avenge his brother , Stephen Dorff as a volatile , violent wheelman and Famke Janssen as a suffering wife . Nice musical score including an emotive song at the beginning . Colorful cinematography by Thomas Burstyn who permeates the whole movie even in the hours of night and darkness . The motion picture is professionally directed by John Irvin with a well-achieved realization and elaborate scenes , though doesn't always live up to its promise . He worked extensively in TV before making his film debut with &uml;The dogs of war&uml; a cool rendition of a best-seller by Frederick Forsyth dealing with mercenaries in Africa. He went on directing &uml;Ghost story&uml; starred by old Hollywood-all-star and &uml;Champions&uml; about a courageous recovery from cancer stricken a steeple-chase jockey . After that , he realized a fine Vietnam movie as &uml;The Hamburger Hill&uml;, &uml;Turtle diary&uml;, an Arnold Szwenegger vehicle as &uml;Raw Deal&uml; and a good and realistic TV &uml;Robin Hood&uml;. Finally , he made underrated films that not had the same inspiration since them as &uml;Next of kin&uml; , &uml;Eminent domain&uml; , &uml;Freefall&uml; and a sparkling comedy ,&uml;Widows peak&uml; and is also of note a wartime genre as &uml;When trumpets fade&uml;(1998). And of course , &uml;City of Industry&uml; , being one of the jewels in Irvin's crown , it results to be one of this most interesting works and an efficient contemporary Noir which had moderated success .
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Another well made violent crime movie, except for !
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ahmed elshikh (ahmed_abd_elreheem@yahoo.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/3/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    No doubt it's catchy, incisive and coming to the point as no-nonsense movie. I loved the cast. (Famke Janssen)'s performance and beauty (her hair was exceptional !), (Harvey Keitel)'s silent mountainous anger, and (Stephen Dorff)'s attitude; they did the job finely. And I loved some scenes as well; like (Keitel) exploding with pain in a closed room, or getting out with the laptop debonairly, (Dorff) screaming devilishly (Rooooyyyy).. but as a whole it wasn't all flawless. Firstly, there are no depths, if you would think that that was a shortcoming. I mean the relationship between the lead and the woman was poor. Surely it doesn't need to develop into a romance, but with another treatment it could have been more memorable or touchy. However according to the movie's character as "another violent crime movie" it's the small shortcoming. Now medium shortcoming : the title. (City of Industry) fits a documentary more than a crime movie; especially this crime movie. The time that we have watched got nothing to do with a title of that kind. It's just a way to describe the background of the events with no serious shadows. I hate when they allege a meaning or a singularity by only a strange, outwardly profound, title ! Then the X Large shortcoming : the theft. This is unquestionably the stupidest heist in the history of mankind. How they went to steal a bank in the high noon with no masks, no gloves, and no disguise or whatsoever ??!! If there were no cameras recording them, what about the people themselves ??! Shame on this movie makers and cast as well. This is, sorrowfully, pure nonsense ! It's half heist, half revenge movie. Great ? No. Average ? Yes. Watchable and satisfying ? Of course.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A fairly gripping crime thriller that falls a bit flat
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Electrified_Voltage
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/9/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    About 3 &frac12; years ago, I came across a copy of this movie in the video store. I had never heard of it, and knew nothing about its general reception. I read the blurb on the back of the case, and thought it looked interesting, so I decided to rent it. By the time I watched it, I think I knew it wasn't the most popular crime thriller ever made, and like probably many other viewers, I was disappointed, finding it to be a rather weak film of its genre. Earlier this week, I rented it again. I couldn't remember it that well from my first viewing, and decided to give it a second chance. This time, I had lower expectations than before, but was expecting to be more impressed than I was the first time, which I was. That doesn't mean I didn't notice any severe flaws this time, though. Roy Egan is a retired thief who is lured out of retirement by his younger brother, Lee, for a major jewel heist. Lee has chosen two other partners for this robbery, Jorge Montana and Skip Kovich. The heist is a success, but afterwards, Skip gets greedy and suddenly kills Lee and Jorge! He tries to kill Roy as well, but the veteran thief manages to get away! After this, Roy swears to have his vengeance for the killing of his brother, and sets out on a mission to find the whereabouts of Skip! During this mission, his foe realizes he is searching for him, and is obviously not going to make it any easier for him. Roy isn't the only one who has suffered a loss in the family as a result of Skip's greed and insanity. The lunatic's other victim, Jorge, has left behind his wife and kids. His widow, Rachel, is eventually involved in Roy's mission after she learns what has happened to her husband. Harvey Keitel plays the starring role of Roy Egan, and does a decent job, but this may not be the case with the entire cast. I didn't care much for Stephen Dorff as Skip Kovich, but I'm not entirely sure if that was because of the actor's performance or because of the character. The characters in this film are generally pretty shallow. There isn't much emotional depth or detail to them. However, at least there are some characters I could sympathize with, most notably Rachel Montana, and I guess Roy Egan to a certain extent. There are fairly weak moments, such as some unnecessary sex scenes (at least one involving Skip and his girlfriend), the film drags at times, and the dialogue may not be perfect. Despite these flaws, there's still at least some suspense, as well as poignant moments, and enough to keep me interested until the end, during my second viewing, that is. Now that I've seen "City of Industry" twice, I don't exactly think it's bad, as I definitely found more redeeming qualities the second time than I did the first (I'm not sure if I really found any the first time), and a major reason for this is that it just MIGHT be a better film to watch alone. On the other hand, it's still a flawed thriller, flawed enough for me to see why it's so polarizing and has been widely overlooked since its release in the late 90's. I wouldn't have really been missing out on THAT much if I had never noticed this film in the video store several years ago (meaning I still wouldn't be aware of its existence now), and I certainly wouldn't consider it a must-see for anyone, but if you like this genre, maybe this movie will do. Just don't expect anything too brilliant or original.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    doesn't completely butcher the genre (6.5/10)
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    disdressed12
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/5/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    this was a fairly entertaining crime drama.it moved at a quick pace and it wasn't boring.i liked the fact that it didn't feel as depressing as many movies of the genre.it's still dark and gritty,just not oppressive.it pretty much follows the standard formula.betrayal,leading to revenge ending in bloodshed,usually death.it's all pretty predictable,and there a few illogical moments.still,it is entertaining for what it is.what elevates this material though, is Harvey Keitel,who makes just about any film he's in better than it otherwise might have been.Stephen Dorff,Timothy Hutton,Famke Janssen,Michael Jai White,and Wade Dominguez co star.and Lucy Liu also has a small role.recommended as long as you know what you're in for.it doesn't break any new ground,but it doesn't completely butcher the genre either.for me,City of Industry is a 6.5/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I'm my own police.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    lastliberal
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/11/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Sure, you can find some plots holes in this film big enough to drive a semi through, but that just keeps it from gathering awards, not from being worth a view. If you like revenge flicks, and noir, and lots of action, as well as a look at Lucy's Little Lius as she does a pole dance, then you might find this film interesting. What makes it most interesting, however, is the presence of Harvey Keitel. Having him hunting you down is a real bummer. He manages to get shot and almost beat to a pulp by the Chinese, and still keeps on ticking like a Timex. Maybe he just dreamed of being on the beach in Port Arthur with Famke Janssen (of X-Men fame). It could have happened! Check it out to see who wins and loses and enjoy the ride because it is worth it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The most surprising thing about the film is how it takes such a familiar premise and gets it wrong.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    johnnyboyz (j_l_h_m@yahoo.co.uk)
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/4/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The biggest gripe I have with City of Industry is not because of its familiarity but for its execution. I love the genre of noir, pulpy crime and a couple of heist films but City of Industry is just a bank job too far; a wise talking gangster too far and a story of pulp fiction too far. City of Industry takes place in a world in which car alarms do not exist; in which if someone kicks open your apartment door and you're asleep, you do not wake up; a world in which people can survive multiple gun shot wounds without professional medical help and a world in which jewellery robbers don't wear masks. Throw in some badly done gunfights and a weak romance sub-plot and you have a sort of fun at times gritty crime film but something forgettable in the long run. The biggest problem I had with City of Industry is its point of view approach. It sounds like a funny thing to be pulling up a film for but just who exactly is the protagonist here? Who are we supposed to be following? Who's telling this story? It seems the film wants us to focus on several different characters at once but only one of them is in the film long enough for us to care for them while the others fill in the blanks when Roy Egan (Keitel) isn't on screen. At the beginning, Rachel (Janssen) and Jorge (Dominguez) talk on the phone  he is due to go to prison for a few years and Rachel, his wife, is upset about this as you'd expect only twenty minutes later the film's initial incident has happened and Jorge is out of the picture. Before you say something, this is not a spoiler because the film's premise is: a guy hunts for a betrayer after they kill his two heist partners. That gives away enough right there so why does the film have its initial character build up revolve around someone it'll kill off ten minutes later? Secondly, it seems that Egan is the character from whose point of view we're seeing this. The scene that suggests this is when he's standing at the trailer door when Skip (well played by Stephen Dorff) arrives because the camera cuts to his point of view; the point of view angle is very important as it puts the audience in the character's head, so the film has changed its mind again. The closing monologue all about how it was 'our' struggle and no one will ever know 'our' story is told to us by a character who has just spent all of about nine minutes on screen. Sorry, but it's not 'your' story because you didn't even do anything bar stay at home and look after the kids  at this point the protagonist (or who we think is the protagonist) has disappeared. So the film is muddled in who is delivering the film, whose story is it anyway? Think of any other film that uses voice over work and chances are when they show other characters doing things a million miles away from them, the film will never 'shift' to their point of view. And so the film's initial incident kicks Egan into action as he punches and shoots his way through the city looking for Skip, an amateur amongst professionals with his mistreating of women and his hip, fancy music. There is some fun to be had out of this little journey because the film is feeding its narrative drive (that is, revenge) with the obligatory yet entertaining scenes you expect. Egan floors a jerk of a bartender, he spends some time with the widow that is Rachel and he gets around stealing cars and interrogating people  good fun, you think. But then the film steers itself off the thin track it was already on. Revenge is still in the back of the film's mind but it is not the drive anymore. There is a sub-plot that opens up involving money, owed money, stolen money; I'm not sure. All I know is that Skip gets into trouble with some African-American gangsters and hell threatens to break loose; I say 'threaten' because nothing much actually happens. If we take 1999's Payback, we can see that Porter goes after Val for the money he owes him: Porter narrates and we do not get distracted by anything else until the d&eacute;nouement between Val and Porter; also, whenever Val is on screen it is a constant build up of how angry Porter is and how vulnerable Val is; in City of Industry, Skip continues to act deranged and immaturely, alienating us from the film's crime world and the revenge narrative-drive is sort of substituted for a little more violence and some characters running around for some missing money. It's at this point, around about the forty-five minute mark that the film looses us; it has abandoned its approach and has opted for explosions, impossible feats and mere petty violence. Nice opening, nice little hunt for Egan until a certain point and then 'bam', we aren't having fun anymore. Then the film gives us a satisfying d&eacute;nouement before cheating us again and having Egan disappear. Rachel is left to tell us how hard it was for her to get everything sorted out, but that's just silly since she didn't do anything. Maybe a better film have been eliminating Regan in the trailer park and then having Rachel go on the revenge mission  what fun that might've been.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Harvey dominates the screen
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    dev-aryap
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/4/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is pretty much a noir revenge story, with stone loner Roy Egan(the great Harvey Keitel) navigating the high and low of seedy LA, wending his way through dive bars, upscale LA law firms, and enduring beat downs from Asian and black gangs while pursuing THE BIG PAYBACK, son. As JB, the godfather of soul might say, "His patience thin, he want revenge." Harvey reluctantly joins a heist crew led by little brother Hutton that will knock off high-end jewelry store connected to the Russian mob. The brutally executed caper is successful, but then Skip Kovic (Dorff) goes turncoat, cancels some of the crew, including little brother, and now Harvey is out for blood. The big man looks good, obviously still hitting the weights, with some Risky Business shades and tieless Man in the Arrow shirt look. Okay, so he is in his late 50's, with a bit of a gut, and he walks with a little swayback. But, you know what, this is the man who pulled off "Fingers" son, and he would dominate the screen even if he walked around LA reading from the Congressional registry. Best scene: In his small hotel room after the post-robbery bloodbath, Harvey cuts through any Hamlet-style vacillation by pounding a card table with escalating fury, overturning it, sending out an unholy moan, and then setting out to kick some serious A. Only Harvey could turn a wordless moan and the act of overturning a card table into a statement of existential despair. Second best: when the big man gives a slimy bartender a beat down. About this second scene: post-robbery, Harvey goes to a hoodlum hangout, and tries to bribe the bartender for the whereabouts of Skip Kovic (Dorff). The bartender, who we know is in the know, tells Harvey to f- off, and Harvey steps back, squints, and waits, cigarette dangling. That goof with his silly goatee starts scrambling forward from the bar. Harvey administers a serious beat-down, KEEPING HIS CIGARETTE IN HIS MOUTH THE WHOLE TIME. Oh, and he picks up a gun for good measure. Now that is MOVIE MAKING, son. Irvin could have 86'd Eliot Gould and Michael Jai White, and the other Hollywood B-types trying to give the movie some bogus street cred. I buy Eliot Gould as a mobster as easily as I can buy a slurpee using a $3bill earned from my paper route on Mars. More of the stupendously sexy Famke Jannsen. And a nice cameo with Lucy Liu as a stripper with a SM motif. If Irvin was trying to channel the spirit of Michael Mann, he might have added more dialogue and made the Dorff character more complex. Still, I'll be here when City of 2 (Electric Boogaloo) comes out.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Caper, Double Cross, Revenge.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Robert J. Maxwell (rmax304823@yahoo.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/3/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Thief Harvey Keitel comes to Southern California to join his younger brother, Timothy Hutton, and a nice Latino (Wade Dominguez) and a driver (Stephen Dorff), to pull off a diamond heist at one of those high-end stores that line the main drag in Palm Springs. They are successful. As they are about to divvy up the loot, Dorff kills Hutton and Dominguez. He tries to kill Keitel too, but botches it, which is what you might call a bad mistake. Dorff takes off with all the loot and the rest of the movie has Keitel tracking him down, at the cost of a lot of money and an infinity of pain. At the end, having dispatched Dorff, the wounded and bleeding Keitel sees to it that Dominguez' widow (Famke Janssen) gets most of the money from the job. Keitel disappears, perhaps dying, and Janssen retires with her two kids to Port Arthur, Texas. End of story. A lot of this is familiar territory by now and has been done better elsewhere -- "Heat", for instance, or "Straight Time." But it's not badly done, despite the rather weak script. It's always interesting to see the underside of L.A. The Chinese sweat shops, the bars where the black guys hang out, everybody in shades, dilapidated single-family homes with their front yards littered with trash and children's toys, Lucy Liu doing a pole dance, San Pedro's cracking plants, dusty and mostly empty motels with propane gas tanks ready to explode at the hint of a stray bullet, careering cars knocking down utility poles and emitting showers of fake sparks, sleazy flowered shirts that scream out "Dollar Store", hotels with dark apartments where you wouldn't want to live unless you like junkies for neighbors. The director handles his background people with effortless aplomb. After he shoots two of his accomplices, Dorff chases Keitel through a louche trailer park, firing wildly. When he loses his quarry, Dorff looks angrily around. When the bullets started flying, the rednecks and their dogs scramble over fences to get out of the way, only to appear at their doorways seconds later. One fat guy in a cowboy hat cocks his shotgun, and another has a pistol at his side. It's amusing. You feel that these guys have been around such situations before. But the director has kept them in long shot and doesn't make a big to-do out of the point. Nice touch. In another scene, Keitel is beating the crap out of the bartender in an empty saloon. Two Latinos walk through the door, take a quick look at what's going on, and back out again. If there's not much new in the revenge plot, the details of life in this particular social world are pretty nicely captured. Well, I must say that the villain of the piece, Dorff, is thoroughly stereotyped. There's nothing "good" about him. He's a young, cocky, ruthless showoff. He plays raunchy music loud in his convertible. He shoots through his own girlfriend's chest in order to plug the guy holding her from behind, and shows not a wit of remorse. The director allows Dorff to commit a fundamental error. As in "Platoon," every time the F word is used, it is shouted emphatically. "And bring the EFFING money!" That's not how the F word is used. If anything is stressed in an utterance, it's the noun, not the adjective. Bonus point: Harvey Keitel has an opportunity to howl with anger and smash some furniture. Not a memorable movie, but one worth watching for diversion.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not Again!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jmillerdp
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Oh boy! Another "Heist Gone Wrong" movie! And, wouldn't you think that Harvey Keitel would be getting tired of these? After "Reservoir Dogs," you'd think he'd want a break! But, not here. The heist is planned, carried out, and, guess what?!, there is instant double crossing, shooting and everything else. Heavens! The second that happened, I pretty much checked out, and just waited the rest of the movie out. And, of course, it's a "final heist" for Keitel's character. So, that naturally means that everything's going to go wrong, guaranteed! The film is entirely on the shoulders of Harvey Keitel's performance. His fearless brand of acting is what make the film worth watching. But, it's standard plot makes it not worth it otherwise. ****** (6 Out of 10 Stars)
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not your average run of the mill PULP FICTION wannabe
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    JasparLamarCrabb
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    SPOILER ALERT! Easy to dismiss as another in a series of PULP FICTION wannabes, this is much better than expected. Directed with a lot of finesse by John Irvin and starring Harvey Keitel, CITY OF INDUSTRY is a fine crime thriller. Keitel is part of a gang of thieves (which also includes his brother), ripped off by loony cohort Stephen Dorff. A tense game of cat and mouse takes place as Keitel tries to track Dorff down. Keitel, who could easily sleepwalk through this type of film, gives a very good performance (he takes a real beating...several times) and has a lot of chemistry with Famke Janssen (as the widow of one of his cronies). The film is not flawless. The night photography is at times too dark, there is surely one too many name-less characters chasing Keitel, and Dorff is not really threatening enough to be convincing. Nevertheless, it's a well put together revenge film. Stephen Endelman's staccato music is a big plus.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Violent and exciting movie about seedy delinquents who pull off a fateful heist in L.A.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ma-cortes
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is a studio character with tones of suspense about some two-fisted criminals in L.A city . An old thief named Roy Egan (Harvey Keitel) , is drawn into the final jewel heist to Russian Mafia when his youngest brother named Lee (Timothy Hutton) asks him for a last score before they get out of the game . Lee forms a motley group (Keitel , Wade Dominguez and Stephen Dorff) to carry out the violent robbing . Unfortunately for him , Lee's picked one wrong partner and the events get worse . One of them decides he doesn't want to share the goods and betrays the group and happens murders and wreak havoc .The retired thief swears revenge on the lunatic who murdered his partners, while going on the run with the loot they stole. This modern adaptation of noir cinema contains thrills , intrigue, explosive scenes of action and over-riding feeling of heat . Interesting premise in which takes places a moving cat-and-mouse hunt through the seedier sides of L.A . Exciting and stirring finale full of shootouts , violence and fights into a factory . Good performances from all-star cast as Harvey Keitel as an old pro robber who has vowed to avenge his brother , Stephen Dorff as a volatile , violent wheelman and Famke Janssen as a suffering wife . Nice musical score including an emotive song at the beginning . Colorful cinematography by Thomas Burstyn who permeates the whole movie even in the hours of night and darkness . The motion picture is professionally directed by John Irvin with a well-achieved realization and elaborate scenes , though doesn't always live up to its promise . He worked extensively in TV before making his film debut with &uml;The dogs of war&uml; a cool rendition of a best-seller by Frederick Forsyth dealing with mercenaries in Africa. He went on directing &uml;Ghost story&uml; starred by old Hollywood-all-star and &uml;Champions&uml; about a courageous recovery from cancer stricken a steeple-chase jockey . After that , he realized a fine Vietnam movie as &uml;The Hamburger Hill&uml;, &uml;Turtle diary&uml;, an Arnold Szwenegger vehicle as &uml;Raw Deal&uml; and a good and realistic TV &uml;Robin Hood&uml;. Finally , he made underrated films that not had the same inspiration since them as &uml;Next of kin&uml; , &uml;Eminent domain&uml; , &uml;Freefall&uml; and a sparkling comedy ,&uml;Widows peak&uml; and is also of note a wartime genre as &uml;When trumpets fade&uml;(1998). And of course , &uml;City of Industry&uml; , being one of the jewels in Irvin's crown , it results to be one of this most interesting works and an efficient contemporary Noir which had moderated success .
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Another well made violent crime movie, except for !
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ahmed elshikh (ahmed_abd_elreheem@yahoo.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/3/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    No doubt it's catchy, incisive and coming to the point as no-nonsense movie. I loved the cast. (Famke Janssen)'s performance and beauty (her hair was exceptional !), (Harvey Keitel)'s silent mountainous anger, and (Stephen Dorff)'s attitude; they did the job finely. And I loved some scenes as well; like (Keitel) exploding with pain in a closed room, or getting out with the laptop debonairly, (Dorff) screaming devilishly (Rooooyyyy).. but as a whole it wasn't all flawless. Firstly, there are no depths, if you would think that that was a shortcoming. I mean the relationship between the lead and the woman was poor. Surely it doesn't need to develop into a romance, but with another treatment it could have been more memorable or touchy. However according to the movie's character as "another violent crime movie" it's the small shortcoming. Now medium shortcoming : the title. (City of Industry) fits a documentary more than a crime movie; especially this crime movie. The time that we have watched got nothing to do with a title of that kind. It's just a way to describe the background of the events with no serious shadows. I hate when they allege a meaning or a singularity by only a strange, outwardly profound, title ! Then the X Large shortcoming : the theft. This is unquestionably the stupidest heist in the history of mankind. How they went to steal a bank in the high noon with no masks, no gloves, and no disguise or whatsoever ??!! If there were no cameras recording them, what about the people themselves ??! Shame on this movie makers and cast as well. This is, sorrowfully, pure nonsense ! It's half heist, half revenge movie. Great ? No. Average ? Yes. Watchable and satisfying ? Of course.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A fairly gripping crime thriller that falls a bit flat
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Electrified_Voltage
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/9/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    About 3 &frac12; years ago, I came across a copy of this movie in the video store. I had never heard of it, and knew nothing about its general reception. I read the blurb on the back of the case, and thought it looked interesting, so I decided to rent it. By the time I watched it, I think I knew it wasn't the most popular crime thriller ever made, and like probably many other viewers, I was disappointed, finding it to be a rather weak film of its genre. Earlier this week, I rented it again. I couldn't remember it that well from my first viewing, and decided to give it a second chance. This time, I had lower expectations than before, but was expecting to be more impressed than I was the first time, which I was. That doesn't mean I didn't notice any severe flaws this time, though. Roy Egan is a retired thief who is lured out of retirement by his younger brother, Lee, for a major jewel heist. Lee has chosen two other partners for this robbery, Jorge Montana and Skip Kovich. The heist is a success, but afterwards, Skip gets greedy and suddenly kills Lee and Jorge! He tries to kill Roy as well, but the veteran thief manages to get away! After this, Roy swears to have his vengeance for the killing of his brother, and sets out on a mission to find the whereabouts of Skip! During this mission, his foe realizes he is searching for him, and is obviously not going to make it any easier for him. Roy isn't the only one who has suffered a loss in the family as a result of Skip's greed and insanity. The lunatic's other victim, Jorge, has left behind his wife and kids. His widow, Rachel, is eventually involved in Roy's mission after she learns what has happened to her husband. Harvey Keitel plays the starring role of Roy Egan, and does a decent job, but this may not be the case with the entire cast. I didn't care much for Stephen Dorff as Skip Kovich, but I'm not entirely sure if that was because of the actor's performance or because of the character. The characters in this film are generally pretty shallow. There isn't much emotional depth or detail to them. However, at least there are some characters I could sympathize with, most notably Rachel Montana, and I guess Roy Egan to a certain extent. There are fairly weak moments, such as some unnecessary sex scenes (at least one involving Skip and his girlfriend), the film drags at times, and the dialogue may not be perfect. Despite these flaws, there's still at least some suspense, as well as poignant moments, and enough to keep me interested until the end, during my second viewing, that is. Now that I've seen "City of Industry" twice, I don't exactly think it's bad, as I definitely found more redeeming qualities the second time than I did the first (I'm not sure if I really found any the first time), and a major reason for this is that it just MIGHT be a better film to watch alone. On the other hand, it's still a flawed thriller, flawed enough for me to see why it's so polarizing and has been widely overlooked since its release in the late 90's. I wouldn't have really been missing out on THAT much if I had never noticed this film in the video store several years ago (meaning I still wouldn't be aware of its existence now), and I certainly wouldn't consider it a must-see for anyone, but if you like this genre, maybe this movie will do. Just don't expect anything too brilliant or original.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    doesn't completely butcher the genre (6.5/10)
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    disdressed12
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/5/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    this was a fairly entertaining crime drama.it moved at a quick pace and it wasn't boring.i liked the fact that it didn't feel as depressing as many movies of the genre.it's still dark and gritty,just not oppressive.it pretty much follows the standard formula.betrayal,leading to revenge ending in bloodshed,usually death.it's all pretty predictable,and there a few illogical moments.still,it is entertaining for what it is.what elevates this material though, is Harvey Keitel,who makes just about any film he's in better than it otherwise might have been.Stephen Dorff,Timothy Hutton,Famke Janssen,Michael Jai White,and Wade Dominguez co star.and Lucy Liu also has a small role.recommended as long as you know what you're in for.it doesn't break any new ground,but it doesn't completely butcher the genre either.for me,City of Industry is a 6.5/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I'm my own police.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    lastliberal
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/11/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Sure, you can find some plots holes in this film big enough to drive a semi through, but that just keeps it from gathering awards, not from being worth a view. If you like revenge flicks, and noir, and lots of action, as well as a look at Lucy's Little Lius as she does a pole dance, then you might find this film interesting. What makes it most interesting, however, is the presence of Harvey Keitel. Having him hunting you down is a real bummer. He manages to get shot and almost beat to a pulp by the Chinese, and still keeps on ticking like a Timex. Maybe he just dreamed of being on the beach in Port Arthur with Famke Janssen (of X-Men fame). It could have happened! Check it out to see who wins and loses and enjoy the ride because it is worth it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The most surprising thing about the film is how it takes such a familiar premise and gets it wrong.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    johnnyboyz (j_l_h_m@yahoo.co.uk)
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/4/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The biggest gripe I have with City of Industry is not because of its familiarity but for its execution. I love the genre of noir, pulpy crime and a couple of heist films but City of Industry is just a bank job too far; a wise talking gangster too far and a story of pulp fiction too far. City of Industry takes place in a world in which car alarms do not exist; in which if someone kicks open your apartment door and you're asleep, you do not wake up; a world in which people can survive multiple gun shot wounds without professional medical help and a world in which jewellery robbers don't wear masks. Throw in some badly done gunfights and a weak romance sub-plot and you have a sort of fun at times gritty crime film but something forgettable in the long run. The biggest problem I had with City of Industry is its point of view approach. It sounds like a funny thing to be pulling up a film for but just who exactly is the protagonist here? Who are we supposed to be following? Who's telling this story? It seems the film wants us to focus on several different characters at once but only one of them is in the film long enough for us to care for them while the others fill in the blanks when Roy Egan (Keitel) isn't on screen. At the beginning, Rachel (Janssen) and Jorge (Dominguez) talk on the phone  he is due to go to prison for a few years and Rachel, his wife, is upset about this as you'd expect only twenty minutes later the film's initial incident has happened and Jorge is out of the picture. Before you say something, this is not a spoiler because the film's premise is: a guy hunts for a betrayer after they kill his two heist partners. That gives away enough right there so why does the film have its initial character build up revolve around someone it'll kill off ten minutes later? Secondly, it seems that Egan is the character from whose point of view we're seeing this. The scene that suggests this is when he's standing at the trailer door when Skip (well played by Stephen Dorff) arrives because the camera cuts to his point of view; the point of view angle is very important as it puts the audience in the character's head, so the film has changed its mind again. The closing monologue all about how it was 'our' struggle and no one will ever know 'our' story is told to us by a character who has just spent all of about nine minutes on screen. Sorry, but it's not 'your' story because you didn't even do anything bar stay at home and look after the kids  at this point the protagonist (or who we think is the protagonist) has disappeared. So the film is muddled in who is delivering the film, whose story is it anyway? Think of any other film that uses voice over work and chances are when they show other characters doing things a million miles away from them, the film will never 'shift' to their point of view. And so the film's initial incident kicks Egan into action as he punches and shoots his way through the city looking for Skip, an amateur amongst professionals with his mistreating of women and his hip, fancy music. There is some fun to be had out of this little journey because the film is feeding its narrative drive (that is, revenge) with the obligatory yet entertaining scenes you expect. Egan floors a jerk of a bartender, he spends some time with the widow that is Rachel and he gets around stealing cars and interrogating people  good fun, you think. But then the film steers itself off the thin track it was already on. Revenge is still in the back of the film's mind but it is not the drive anymore. There is a sub-plot that opens up involving money, owed money, stolen money; I'm not sure. All I know is that Skip gets into trouble with some African-American gangsters and hell threatens to break loose; I say 'threaten' because nothing much actually happens. If we take 1999's Payback, we can see that Porter goes after Val for the money he owes him: Porter narrates and we do not get distracted by anything else until the d&eacute;nouement between Val and Porter; also, whenever Val is on screen it is a constant build up of how angry Porter is and how vulnerable Val is; in City of Industry, Skip continues to act deranged and immaturely, alienating us from the film's crime world and the revenge narrative-drive is sort of substituted for a little more violence and some characters running around for some missing money. It's at this point, around about the forty-five minute mark that the film looses us; it has abandoned its approach and has opted for explosions, impossible feats and mere petty violence. Nice opening, nice little hunt for Egan until a certain point and then 'bam', we aren't having fun anymore. Then the film gives us a satisfying d&eacute;nouement before cheating us again and having Egan disappear. Rachel is left to tell us how hard it was for her to get everything sorted out, but that's just silly since she didn't do anything. Maybe a better film have been eliminating Regan in the trailer park and then having Rachel go on the revenge mission  what fun that might've been.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Harvey dominates the screen
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    dev-aryap
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/4/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is pretty much a noir revenge story, with stone loner Roy Egan(the great Harvey Keitel) navigating the high and low of seedy LA, wending his way through dive bars, upscale LA law firms, and enduring beat downs from Asian and black gangs while pursuing THE BIG PAYBACK, son. As JB, the godfather of soul might say, "His patience thin, he want revenge." Harvey reluctantly joins a heist crew led by little brother Hutton that will knock off high-end jewelry store connected to the Russian mob. The brutally executed caper is successful, but then Skip Kovic (Dorff) goes turncoat, cancels some of the crew, including little brother, and now Harvey is out for blood. The big man looks good, obviously still hitting the weights, with some Risky Business shades and tieless Man in the Arrow shirt look. Okay, so he is in his late 50's, with a bit of a gut, and he walks with a little swayback. But, you know what, this is the man who pulled off "Fingers" son, and he would dominate the screen even if he walked around LA reading from the Congressional registry. Best scene: In his small hotel room after the post-robbery bloodbath, Harvey cuts through any Hamlet-style vacillation by pounding a card table with escalating fury, overturning it, sending out an unholy moan, and then setting out to kick some serious A. Only Harvey could turn a wordless moan and the act of overturning a card table into a statement of existential despair. Second best: when the big man gives a slimy bartender a beat down. About this second scene: post-robbery, Harvey goes to a hoodlum hangout, and tries to bribe the bartender for the whereabouts of Skip Kovic (Dorff). The bartender, who we know is in the know, tells Harvey to f- off, and Harvey steps back, squints, and waits, cigarette dangling. That goof with his silly goatee starts scrambling forward from the bar. Harvey administers a serious beat-down, KEEPING HIS CIGARETTE IN HIS MOUTH THE WHOLE TIME. Oh, and he picks up a gun for good measure. Now that is MOVIE MAKING, son. Irvin could have 86'd Eliot Gould and Michael Jai White, and the other Hollywood B-types trying to give the movie some bogus street cred. I buy Eliot Gould as a mobster as easily as I can buy a slurpee using a $3bill earned from my paper route on Mars. More of the stupendously sexy Famke Jannsen. And a nice cameo with Lucy Liu as a stripper with a SM motif. If Irvin was trying to channel the spirit of Michael Mann, he might have added more dialogue and made the Dorff character more complex. Still, I'll be here when City of 2 (Electric Boogaloo) comes out.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Caper, Double Cross, Revenge.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Robert J. Maxwell (rmax304823@yahoo.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/3/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Thief Harvey Keitel comes to Southern California to join his younger brother, Timothy Hutton, and a nice Latino (Wade Dominguez) and a driver (Stephen Dorff), to pull off a diamond heist at one of those high-end stores that line the main drag in Palm Springs. They are successful. As they are about to divvy up the loot, Dorff kills Hutton and Dominguez. He tries to kill Keitel too, but botches it, which is what you might call a bad mistake. Dorff takes off with all the loot and the rest of the movie has Keitel tracking him down, at the cost of a lot of money and an infinity of pain. At the end, having dispatched Dorff, the wounded and bleeding Keitel sees to it that Dominguez' widow (Famke Janssen) gets most of the money from the job. Keitel disappears, perhaps dying, and Janssen retires with her two kids to Port Arthur, Texas. End of story. A lot of this is familiar territory by now and has been done better elsewhere -- "Heat", for instance, or "Straight Time." But it's not badly done, despite the rather weak script. It's always interesting to see the underside of L.A. The Chinese sweat shops, the bars where the black guys hang out, everybody in shades, dilapidated single-family homes with their front yards littered with trash and children's toys, Lucy Liu doing a pole dance, San Pedro's cracking plants, dusty and mostly empty motels with propane gas tanks ready to explode at the hint of a stray bullet, careering cars knocking down utility poles and emitting showers of fake sparks, sleazy flowered shirts that scream out "Dollar Store", hotels with dark apartments where you wouldn't want to live unless you like junkies for neighbors. The director handles his background people with effortless aplomb. After he shoots two of his accomplices, Dorff chases Keitel through a louche trailer park, firing wildly. When he loses his quarry, Dorff looks angrily around. When the bullets started flying, the rednecks and their dogs scramble over fences to get out of the way, only to appear at their doorways seconds later. One fat guy in a cowboy hat cocks his shotgun, and another has a pistol at his side. It's amusing. You feel that these guys have been around such situations before. But the director has kept them in long shot and doesn't make a big to-do out of the point. Nice touch. In another scene, Keitel is beating the crap out of the bartender in an empty saloon. Two Latinos walk through the door, take a quick look at what's going on, and back out again. If there's not much new in the revenge plot, the details of life in this particular social world are pretty nicely captured. Well, I must say that the villain of the piece, Dorff, is thoroughly stereotyped. There's nothing "good" about him. He's a young, cocky, ruthless showoff. He plays raunchy music loud in his convertible. He shoots through his own girlfriend's chest in order to plug the guy holding her from behind, and shows not a wit of remorse. The director allows Dorff to commit a fundamental error. As in "Platoon," every time the F word is used, it is shouted emphatically. "And bring the EFFING money!" That's not how the F word is used. If anything is stressed in an utterance, it's the noun, not the adjective. Bonus point: Harvey Keitel has an opportunity to howl with anger and smash some furniture. Not a memorable movie, but one worth watching for diversion.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not Again!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jmillerdp
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Oh boy! Another "Heist Gone Wrong" movie! And, wouldn't you think that Harvey Keitel would be getting tired of these? After "Reservoir Dogs," you'd think he'd want a break! But, not here. The heist is planned, carried out, and, guess what?!, there is instant double crossing, shooting and everything else. Heavens! The second that happened, I pretty much checked out, and just waited the rest of the movie out. And, of course, it's a "final heist" for Keitel's character. So, that naturally means that everything's going to go wrong, guaranteed! The film is entirely on the shoulders of Harvey Keitel's performance. His fearless brand of acting is what make the film worth watching. But, it's standard plot makes it not worth it otherwise. ****** (6 Out of 10 Stars)
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not your average run of the mill PULP FICTION wannabe
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    JasparLamarCrabb
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    SPOILER ALERT! Easy to dismiss as another in a series of PULP FICTION wannabes, this is much better than expected. Directed with a lot of finesse by John Irvin and starring Harvey Keitel, CITY OF INDUSTRY is a fine crime thriller. Keitel is part of a gang of thieves (which also includes his brother), ripped off by loony cohort Stephen Dorff. A tense game of cat and mouse takes place as Keitel tries to track Dorff down. Keitel, who could easily sleepwalk through this type of film, gives a very good performance (he takes a real beating...several times) and has a lot of chemistry with Famke Janssen (as the widow of one of his cronies). The film is not flawless. The night photography is at times too dark, there is surely one too many name-less characters chasing Keitel, and Dorff is not really threatening enough to be convincing. Nevertheless, it's a well put together revenge film. Stephen Endelman's staccato music is a big plus.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Violent and exciting movie about seedy delinquents who pull off a fateful heist in L.A.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ma-cortes
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is a studio character with tones of suspense about some two-fisted criminals in L.A city . An old thief named Roy Egan (Harvey Keitel) , is drawn into the final jewel heist to Russian Mafia when his youngest brother named Lee (Timothy Hutton) asks him for a last score before they get out of the game . Lee forms a motley group (Keitel , Wade Dominguez and Stephen Dorff) to carry out the violent robbing . Unfortunately for him , Lee's picked one wrong partner and the events get worse . One of them decides he doesn't want to share the goods and betrays the group and happens murders and wreak havoc .The retired thief swears revenge on the lunatic who murdered his partners, while going on the run with the loot they stole. This modern adaptation of noir cinema contains thrills , intrigue, explosive scenes of action and over-riding feeling of heat . Interesting premise in which takes places a moving cat-and-mouse hunt through the seedier sides of L.A . Exciting and stirring finale full of shootouts , violence and fights into a factory . Good performances from all-star cast as Harvey Keitel as an old pro robber who has vowed to avenge his brother , Stephen Dorff as a volatile , violent wheelman and Famke Janssen as a suffering wife . Nice musical score including an emotive song at the beginning . Colorful cinematography by Thomas Burstyn who permeates the whole movie even in the hours of night and darkness . The motion picture is professionally directed by John Irvin with a well-achieved realization and elaborate scenes , though doesn't always live up to its promise . He worked extensively in TV before making his film debut with &uml;The dogs of war&uml; a cool rendition of a best-seller by Frederick Forsyth dealing with mercenaries in Africa. He went on directing &uml;Ghost story&uml; starred by old Hollywood-all-star and &uml;Champions&uml; about a courageous recovery from cancer stricken a steeple-chase jockey . After that , he realized a fine Vietnam movie as &uml;The Hamburger Hill&uml;, &uml;Turtle diary&uml;, an Arnold Szwenegger vehicle as &uml;Raw Deal&uml; and a good and realistic TV &uml;Robin Hood&uml;. Finally , he made underrated films that not had the same inspiration since them as &uml;Next of kin&uml; , &uml;Eminent domain&uml; , &uml;Freefall&uml; and a sparkling comedy ,&uml;Widows peak&uml; and is also of note a wartime genre as &uml;When trumpets fade&uml;(1998). And of course , &uml;City of Industry&uml; , being one of the jewels in Irvin's crown , it results to be one of this most interesting works and an efficient contemporary Noir which had moderated success .
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Another well made violent crime movie, except for !
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ahmed elshikh (ahmed_abd_elreheem@yahoo.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/3/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    No doubt it's catchy, incisive and coming to the point as no-nonsense movie. I loved the cast. (Famke Janssen)'s performance and beauty (her hair was exceptional !), (Harvey Keitel)'s silent mountainous anger, and (Stephen Dorff)'s attitude; they did the job finely. And I loved some scenes as well; like (Keitel) exploding with pain in a closed room, or getting out with the laptop debonairly, (Dorff) screaming devilishly (Rooooyyyy).. but as a whole it wasn't all flawless. Firstly, there are no depths, if you would think that that was a shortcoming. I mean the relationship between the lead and the woman was poor. Surely it doesn't need to develop into a romance, but with another treatment it could have been more memorable or touchy. However according to the movie's character as "another violent crime movie" it's the small shortcoming. Now medium shortcoming : the title. (City of Industry) fits a documentary more than a crime movie; especially this crime movie. The time that we have watched got nothing to do with a title of that kind. It's just a way to describe the background of the events with no serious shadows. I hate when they allege a meaning or a singularity by only a strange, outwardly profound, title ! Then the X Large shortcoming : the theft. This is unquestionably the stupidest heist in the history of mankind. How they went to steal a bank in the high noon with no masks, no gloves, and no disguise or whatsoever ??!! If there were no cameras recording them, what about the people themselves ??! Shame on this movie makers and cast as well. This is, sorrowfully, pure nonsense ! It's half heist, half revenge movie. Great ? No. Average ? Yes. Watchable and satisfying ? Of course.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A fairly gripping crime thriller that falls a bit flat
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Electrified_Voltage
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/9/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    About 3 &frac12; years ago, I came across a copy of this movie in the video store. I had never heard of it, and knew nothing about its general reception. I read the blurb on the back of the case, and thought it looked interesting, so I decided to rent it. By the time I watched it, I think I knew it wasn't the most popular crime thriller ever made, and like probably many other viewers, I was disappointed, finding it to be a rather weak film of its genre. Earlier this week, I rented it again. I couldn't remember it that well from my first viewing, and decided to give it a second chance. This time, I had lower expectations than before, but was expecting to be more impressed than I was the first time, which I was. That doesn't mean I didn't notice any severe flaws this time, though. Roy Egan is a retired thief who is lured out of retirement by his younger brother, Lee, for a major jewel heist. Lee has chosen two other partners for this robbery, Jorge Montana and Skip Kovich. The heist is a success, but afterwards, Skip gets greedy and suddenly kills Lee and Jorge! He tries to kill Roy as well, but the veteran thief manages to get away! After this, Roy swears to have his vengeance for the killing of his brother, and sets out on a mission to find the whereabouts of Skip! During this mission, his foe realizes he is searching for him, and is obviously not going to make it any easier for him. Roy isn't the only one who has suffered a loss in the family as a result of Skip's greed and insanity. The lunatic's other victim, Jorge, has left behind his wife and kids. His widow, Rachel, is eventually involved in Roy's mission after she learns what has happened to her husband. Harvey Keitel plays the starring role of Roy Egan, and does a decent job, but this may not be the case with the entire cast. I didn't care much for Stephen Dorff as Skip Kovich, but I'm not entirely sure if that was because of the actor's performance or because of the character. The characters in this film are generally pretty shallow. There isn't much emotional depth or detail to them. However, at least there are some characters I could sympathize with, most notably Rachel Montana, and I guess Roy Egan to a certain extent. There are fairly weak moments, such as some unnecessary sex scenes (at least one involving Skip and his girlfriend), the film drags at times, and the dialogue may not be perfect. Despite these flaws, there's still at least some suspense, as well as poignant moments, and enough to keep me interested until the end, during my second viewing, that is. Now that I've seen "City of Industry" twice, I don't exactly think it's bad, as I definitely found more redeeming qualities the second time than I did the first (I'm not sure if I really found any the first time), and a major reason for this is that it just MIGHT be a better film to watch alone. On the other hand, it's still a flawed thriller, flawed enough for me to see why it's so polarizing and has been widely overlooked since its release in the late 90's. I wouldn't have really been missing out on THAT much if I had never noticed this film in the video store several years ago (meaning I still wouldn't be aware of its existence now), and I certainly wouldn't consider it a must-see for anyone, but if you like this genre, maybe this movie will do. Just don't expect anything too brilliant or original.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    doesn't completely butcher the genre (6.5/10)
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    disdressed12
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/5/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    this was a fairly entertaining crime drama.it moved at a quick pace and it wasn't boring.i liked the fact that it didn't feel as depressing as many movies of the genre.it's still dark and gritty,just not oppressive.it pretty much follows the standard formula.betrayal,leading to revenge ending in bloodshed,usually death.it's all pretty predictable,and there a few illogical moments.still,it is entertaining for what it is.what elevates this material though, is Harvey Keitel,who makes just about any film he's in better than it otherwise might have been.Stephen Dorff,Timothy Hutton,Famke Janssen,Michael Jai White,and Wade Dominguez co star.and Lucy Liu also has a small role.recommended as long as you know what you're in for.it doesn't break any new ground,but it doesn't completely butcher the genre either.for me,City of Industry is a 6.5/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I'm my own police.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    lastliberal
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/11/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Sure, you can find some plots holes in this film big enough to drive a semi through, but that just keeps it from gathering awards, not from being worth a view. If you like revenge flicks, and noir, and lots of action, as well as a look at Lucy's Little Lius as she does a pole dance, then you might find this film interesting. What makes it most interesting, however, is the presence of Harvey Keitel. Having him hunting you down is a real bummer. He manages to get shot and almost beat to a pulp by the Chinese, and still keeps on ticking like a Timex. Maybe he just dreamed of being on the beach in Port Arthur with Famke Janssen (of X-Men fame). It could have happened! Check it out to see who wins and loses and enjoy the ride because it is worth it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The most surprising thing about the film is how it takes such a familiar premise and gets it wrong.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    johnnyboyz (j_l_h_m@yahoo.co.uk)
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/4/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The biggest gripe I have with City of Industry is not because of its familiarity but for its execution. I love the genre of noir, pulpy crime and a couple of heist films but City of Industry is just a bank job too far; a wise talking gangster too far and a story of pulp fiction too far. City of Industry takes place in a world in which car alarms do not exist; in which if someone kicks open your apartment door and you're asleep, you do not wake up; a world in which people can survive multiple gun shot wounds without professional medical help and a world in which jewellery robbers don't wear masks. Throw in some badly done gunfights and a weak romance sub-plot and you have a sort of fun at times gritty crime film but something forgettable in the long run. The biggest problem I had with City of Industry is its point of view approach. It sounds like a funny thing to be pulling up a film for but just who exactly is the protagonist here? Who are we supposed to be following? Who's telling this story? It seems the film wants us to focus on several different characters at once but only one of them is in the film long enough for us to care for them while the others fill in the blanks when Roy Egan (Keitel) isn't on screen. At the beginning, Rachel (Janssen) and Jorge (Dominguez) talk on the phone  he is due to go to prison for a few years and Rachel, his wife, is upset about this as you'd expect only twenty minutes later the film's initial incident has happened and Jorge is out of the picture. Before you say something, this is not a spoiler because the film's premise is: a guy hunts for a betrayer after they kill his two heist partners. That gives away enough right there so why does the film have its initial character build up revolve around someone it'll kill off ten minutes later? Secondly, it seems that Egan is the character from whose point of view we're seeing this. The scene that suggests this is when he's standing at the trailer door when Skip (well played by Stephen Dorff) arrives because the camera cuts to his point of view; the point of view angle is very important as it puts the audience in the character's head, so the film has changed its mind again. The closing monologue all about how it was 'our' struggle and no one will ever know 'our' story is told to us by a character who has just spent all of about nine minutes on screen. Sorry, but it's not 'your' story because you didn't even do anything bar stay at home and look after the kids  at this point the protagonist (or who we think is the protagonist) has disappeared. So the film is muddled in who is delivering the film, whose story is it anyway? Think of any other film that uses voice over work and chances are when they show other characters doing things a million miles away from them, the film will never 'shift' to their point of view. And so the film's initial incident kicks Egan into action as he punches and shoots his way through the city looking for Skip, an amateur amongst professionals with his mistreating of women and his hip, fancy music. There is some fun to be had out of this little journey because the film is feeding its narrative drive (that is, revenge) with the obligatory yet entertaining scenes you expect. Egan floors a jerk of a bartender, he spends some time with the widow that is Rachel and he gets around stealing cars and interrogating people  good fun, you think. But then the film steers itself off the thin track it was already on. Revenge is still in the back of the film's mind but it is not the drive anymore. There is a sub-plot that opens up involving money, owed money, stolen money; I'm not sure. All I know is that Skip gets into trouble with some African-American gangsters and hell threatens to break loose; I say 'threaten' because nothing much actually happens. If we take 1999's Payback, we can see that Porter goes after Val for the money he owes him: Porter narrates and we do not get distracted by anything else until the d&eacute;nouement between Val and Porter; also, whenever Val is on screen it is a constant build up of how angry Porter is and how vulnerable Val is; in City of Industry, Skip continues to act deranged and immaturely, alienating us from the film's crime world and the revenge narrative-drive is sort of substituted for a little more violence and some characters running around for some missing money. It's at this point, around about the forty-five minute mark that the film looses us; it has abandoned its approach and has opted for explosions, impossible feats and mere petty violence. Nice opening, nice little hunt for Egan until a certain point and then 'bam', we aren't having fun anymore. Then the film gives us a satisfying d&eacute;nouement before cheating us again and having Egan disappear. Rachel is left to tell us how hard it was for her to get everything sorted out, but that's just silly since she didn't do anything. Maybe a better film have been eliminating Regan in the trailer park and then having Rachel go on the revenge mission  what fun that might've been.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Harvey dominates the screen
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    dev-aryap
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/4/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is pretty much a noir revenge story, with stone loner Roy Egan(the great Harvey Keitel) navigating the high and low of seedy LA, wending his way through dive bars, upscale LA law firms, and enduring beat downs from Asian and black gangs while pursuing THE BIG PAYBACK, son. As JB, the godfather of soul might say, "His patience thin, he want revenge." Harvey reluctantly joins a heist crew led by little brother Hutton that will knock off high-end jewelry store connected to the Russian mob. The brutally executed caper is successful, but then Skip Kovic (Dorff) goes turncoat, cancels some of the crew, including little brother, and now Harvey is out for blood. The big man looks good, obviously still hitting the weights, with some Risky Business shades and tieless Man in the Arrow shirt look. Okay, so he is in his late 50's, with a bit of a gut, and he walks with a little swayback. But, you know what, this is the man who pulled off "Fingers" son, and he would dominate the screen even if he walked around LA reading from the Congressional registry. Best scene: In his small hotel room after the post-robbery bloodbath, Harvey cuts through any Hamlet-style vacillation by pounding a card table with escalating fury, overturning it, sending out an unholy moan, and then setting out to kick some serious A. Only Harvey could turn a wordless moan and the act of overturning a card table into a statement of existential despair. Second best: when the big man gives a slimy bartender a beat down. About this second scene: post-robbery, Harvey goes to a hoodlum hangout, and tries to bribe the bartender for the whereabouts of Skip Kovic (Dorff). The bartender, who we know is in the know, tells Harvey to f- off, and Harvey steps back, squints, and waits, cigarette dangling. That goof with his silly goatee starts scrambling forward from the bar. Harvey administers a serious beat-down, KEEPING HIS CIGARETTE IN HIS MOUTH THE WHOLE TIME. Oh, and he picks up a gun for good measure. Now that is MOVIE MAKING, son. Irvin could have 86'd Eliot Gould and Michael Jai White, and the other Hollywood B-types trying to give the movie some bogus street cred. I buy Eliot Gould as a mobster as easily as I can buy a slurpee using a $3bill earned from my paper route on Mars. More of the stupendously sexy Famke Jannsen. And a nice cameo with Lucy Liu as a stripper with a SM motif. If Irvin was trying to channel the spirit of Michael Mann, he might have added more dialogue and made the Dorff character more complex. Still, I'll be here when City of 2 (Electric Boogaloo) comes out.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Caper, Double Cross, Revenge.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Robert J. Maxwell (rmax304823@yahoo.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/3/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Thief Harvey Keitel comes to Southern California to join his younger brother, Timothy Hutton, and a nice Latino (Wade Dominguez) and a driver (Stephen Dorff), to pull off a diamond heist at one of those high-end stores that line the main drag in Palm Springs. They are successful. As they are about to divvy up the loot, Dorff kills Hutton and Dominguez. He tries to kill Keitel too, but botches it, which is what you might call a bad mistake. Dorff takes off with all the loot and the rest of the movie has Keitel tracking him down, at the cost of a lot of money and an infinity of pain. At the end, having dispatched Dorff, the wounded and bleeding Keitel sees to it that Dominguez' widow (Famke Janssen) gets most of the money from the job. Keitel disappears, perhaps dying, and Janssen retires with her two kids to Port Arthur, Texas. End of story. A lot of this is familiar territory by now and has been done better elsewhere -- "Heat", for instance, or "Straight Time." But it's not badly done, despite the rather weak script. It's always interesting to see the underside of L.A. The Chinese sweat shops, the bars where the black guys hang out, everybody in shades, dilapidated single-family homes with their front yards littered with trash and children's toys, Lucy Liu doing a pole dance, San Pedro's cracking plants, dusty and mostly empty motels with propane gas tanks ready to explode at the hint of a stray bullet, careering cars knocking down utility poles and emitting showers of fake sparks, sleazy flowered shirts that scream out "Dollar Store", hotels with dark apartments where you wouldn't want to live unless you like junkies for neighbors. The director handles his background people with effortless aplomb. After he shoots two of his accomplices, Dorff chases Keitel through a louche trailer park, firing wildly. When he loses his quarry, Dorff looks angrily around. When the bullets started flying, the rednecks and their dogs scramble over fences to get out of the way, only to appear at their doorways seconds later. One fat guy in a cowboy hat cocks his shotgun, and another has a pistol at his side. It's amusing. You feel that these guys have been around such situations before. But the director has kept them in long shot and doesn't make a big to-do out of the point. Nice touch. In another scene, Keitel is beating the crap out of the bartender in an empty saloon. Two Latinos walk through the door, take a quick look at what's going on, and back out again. If there's not much new in the revenge plot, the details of life in this particular social world are pretty nicely captured. Well, I must say that the villain of the piece, Dorff, is thoroughly stereotyped. There's nothing "good" about him. He's a young, cocky, ruthless showoff. He plays raunchy music loud in his convertible. He shoots through his own girlfriend's chest in order to plug the guy holding her from behind, and shows not a wit of remorse. The director allows Dorff to commit a fundamental error. As in "Platoon," every time the F word is used, it is shouted emphatically. "And bring the EFFING money!" That's not how the F word is used. If anything is stressed in an utterance, it's the noun, not the adjective. Bonus point: Harvey Keitel has an opportunity to howl with anger and smash some furniture. Not a memorable movie, but one worth watching for diversion.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not Again!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jmillerdp
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Oh boy! Another "Heist Gone Wrong" movie! And, wouldn't you think that Harvey Keitel would be getting tired of these? After "Reservoir Dogs," you'd think he'd want a break! But, not here. The heist is planned, carried out, and, guess what?!, there is instant double crossing, shooting and everything else. Heavens! The second that happened, I pretty much checked out, and just waited the rest of the movie out. And, of course, it's a "final heist" for Keitel's character. So, that naturally means that everything's going to go wrong, guaranteed! The film is entirely on the shoulders of Harvey Keitel's performance. His fearless brand of acting is what make the film worth watching. But, it's standard plot makes it not worth it otherwise. ****** (6 Out of 10 Stars)
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not your average run of the mill PULP FICTION wannabe
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    JasparLamarCrabb
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    SPOILER ALERT! Easy to dismiss as another in a series of PULP FICTION wannabes, this is much better than expected. Directed with a lot of finesse by John Irvin and starring Harvey Keitel, CITY OF INDUSTRY is a fine crime thriller. Keitel is part of a gang of thieves (which also includes his brother), ripped off by loony cohort Stephen Dorff. A tense game of cat and mouse takes place as Keitel tries to track Dorff down. Keitel, who could easily sleepwalk through this type of film, gives a very good performance (he takes a real beating...several times) and has a lot of chemistry with Famke Janssen (as the widow of one of his cronies). The film is not flawless. The night photography is at times too dark, there is surely one too many name-less characters chasing Keitel, and Dorff is not really threatening enough to be convincing. Nevertheless, it's a well put together revenge film. Stephen Endelman's staccato music is a big plus.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Violent and exciting movie about seedy delinquents who pull off a fateful heist in L.A.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ma-cortes
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is a studio character with tones of suspense about some two-fisted criminals in L.A city . An old thief named Roy Egan (Harvey Keitel) , is drawn into the final jewel heist to Russian Mafia when his youngest brother named Lee (Timothy Hutton) asks him for a last score before they get out of the game . Lee forms a motley group (Keitel , Wade Dominguez and Stephen Dorff) to carry out the violent robbing . Unfortunately for him , Lee's picked one wrong partner and the events get worse . One of them decides he doesn't want to share the goods and betrays the group and happens murders and wreak havoc .The retired thief swears revenge on the lunatic who murdered his partners, while going on the run with the loot they stole. This modern adaptation of noir cinema contains thrills , intrigue, explosive scenes of action and over-riding feeling of heat . Interesting premise in which takes places a moving cat-and-mouse hunt through the seedier sides of L.A . Exciting and stirring finale full of shootouts , violence and fights into a factory . Good performances from all-star cast as Harvey Keitel as an old pro robber who has vowed to avenge his brother , Stephen Dorff as a volatile , violent wheelman and Famke Janssen as a suffering wife . Nice musical score including an emotive song at the beginning . Colorful cinematography by Thomas Burstyn who permeates the whole movie even in the hours of night and darkness . The motion picture is professionally directed by John Irvin with a well-achieved realization and elaborate scenes , though doesn't always live up to its promise . He worked extensively in TV before making his film debut with &uml;The dogs of war&uml; a cool rendition of a best-seller by Frederick Forsyth dealing with mercenaries in Africa. He went on directing &uml;Ghost story&uml; starred by old Hollywood-all-star and &uml;Champions&uml; about a courageous recovery from cancer stricken a steeple-chase jockey . After that , he realized a fine Vietnam movie as &uml;The Hamburger Hill&uml;, &uml;Turtle diary&uml;, an Arnold Szwenegger vehicle as &uml;Raw Deal&uml; and a good and realistic TV &uml;Robin Hood&uml;. Finally , he made underrated films that not had the same inspiration since them as &uml;Next of kin&uml; , &uml;Eminent domain&uml; , &uml;Freefall&uml; and a sparkling comedy ,&uml;Widows peak&uml; and is also of note a wartime genre as &uml;When trumpets fade&uml;(1998). And of course , &uml;City of Industry&uml; , being one of the jewels in Irvin's crown , it results to be one of this most interesting works and an efficient contemporary Noir which had moderated success .
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Another well made violent crime movie, except for !
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ahmed elshikh (ahmed_abd_elreheem@yahoo.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/3/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    No doubt it's catchy, incisive and coming to the point as no-nonsense movie. I loved the cast. (Famke Janssen)'s performance and beauty (her hair was exceptional !), (Harvey Keitel)'s silent mountainous anger, and (Stephen Dorff)'s attitude; they did the job finely. And I loved some scenes as well; like (Keitel) exploding with pain in a closed room, or getting out with the laptop debonairly, (Dorff) screaming devilishly (Rooooyyyy).. but as a whole it wasn't all flawless. Firstly, there are no depths, if you would think that that was a shortcoming. I mean the relationship between the lead and the woman was poor. Surely it doesn't need to develop into a romance, but with another treatment it could have been more memorable or touchy. However according to the movie's character as "another violent crime movie" it's the small shortcoming. Now medium shortcoming : the title. (City of Industry) fits a documentary more than a crime movie; especially this crime movie. The time that we have watched got nothing to do with a title of that kind. It's just a way to describe the background of the events with no serious shadows. I hate when they allege a meaning or a singularity by only a strange, outwardly profound, title ! Then the X Large shortcoming : the theft. This is unquestionably the stupidest heist in the history of mankind. How they went to steal a bank in the high noon with no masks, no gloves, and no disguise or whatsoever ??!! If there were no cameras recording them, what about the people themselves ??! Shame on this movie makers and cast as well. This is, sorrowfully, pure nonsense ! It's half heist, half revenge movie. Great ? No. Average ? Yes. Watchable and satisfying ? Of course.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A fairly gripping crime thriller that falls a bit flat
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Electrified_Voltage
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/9/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    About 3 &frac12; years ago, I came across a copy of this movie in the video store. I had never heard of it, and knew nothing about its general reception. I read the blurb on the back of the case, and thought it looked interesting, so I decided to rent it. By the time I watched it, I think I knew it wasn't the most popular crime thriller ever made, and like probably many other viewers, I was disappointed, finding it to be a rather weak film of its genre. Earlier this week, I rented it again. I couldn't remember it that well from my first viewing, and decided to give it a second chance. This time, I had lower expectations than before, but was expecting to be more impressed than I was the first time, which I was. That doesn't mean I didn't notice any severe flaws this time, though. Roy Egan is a retired thief who is lured out of retirement by his younger brother, Lee, for a major jewel heist. Lee has chosen two other partners for this robbery, Jorge Montana and Skip Kovich. The heist is a success, but afterwards, Skip gets greedy and suddenly kills Lee and Jorge! He tries to kill Roy as well, but the veteran thief manages to get away! After this, Roy swears to have his vengeance for the killing of his brother, and sets out on a mission to find the whereabouts of Skip! During this mission, his foe realizes he is searching for him, and is obviously not going to make it any easier for him. Roy isn't the only one who has suffered a loss in the family as a result of Skip's greed and insanity. The lunatic's other victim, Jorge, has left behind his wife and kids. His widow, Rachel, is eventually involved in Roy's mission after she learns what has happened to her husband. Harvey Keitel plays the starring role of Roy Egan, and does a decent job, but this may not be the case with the entire cast. I didn't care much for Stephen Dorff as Skip Kovich, but I'm not entirely sure if that was because of the actor's performance or because of the character. The characters in this film are generally pretty shallow. There isn't much emotional depth or detail to them. However, at least there are some characters I could sympathize with, most notably Rachel Montana, and I guess Roy Egan to a certain extent. There are fairly weak moments, such as some unnecessary sex scenes (at least one involving Skip and his girlfriend), the film drags at times, and the dialogue may not be perfect. Despite these flaws, there's still at least some suspense, as well as poignant moments, and enough to keep me interested until the end, during my second viewing, that is. Now that I've seen "City of Industry" twice, I don't exactly think it's bad, as I definitely found more redeeming qualities the second time than I did the first (I'm not sure if I really found any the first time), and a major reason for this is that it just MIGHT be a better film to watch alone. On the other hand, it's still a flawed thriller, flawed enough for me to see why it's so polarizing and has been widely overlooked since its release in the late 90's. I wouldn't have really been missing out on THAT much if I had never noticed this film in the video store several years ago (meaning I still wouldn't be aware of its existence now), and I certainly wouldn't consider it a must-see for anyone, but if you like this genre, maybe this movie will do. Just don't expect anything too brilliant or original.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    doesn't completely butcher the genre (6.5/10)
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    disdressed12
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/5/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    this was a fairly entertaining crime drama.it moved at a quick pace and it wasn't boring.i liked the fact that it didn't feel as depressing as many movies of the genre.it's still dark and gritty,just not oppressive.it pretty much follows the standard formula.betrayal,leading to revenge ending in bloodshed,usually death.it's all pretty predictable,and there a few illogical moments.still,it is entertaining for what it is.what elevates this material though, is Harvey Keitel,who makes just about any film he's in better than it otherwise might have been.Stephen Dorff,Timothy Hutton,Famke Janssen,Michael Jai White,and Wade Dominguez co star.and Lucy Liu also has a small role.recommended as long as you know what you're in for.it doesn't break any new ground,but it doesn't completely butcher the genre either.for me,City of Industry is a 6.5/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I'm my own police.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    lastliberal
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/11/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Sure, you can find some plots holes in this film big enough to drive a semi through, but that just keeps it from gathering awards, not from being worth a view. If you like revenge flicks, and noir, and lots of action, as well as a look at Lucy's Little Lius as she does a pole dance, then you might find this film interesting. What makes it most interesting, however, is the presence of Harvey Keitel. Having him hunting you down is a real bummer. He manages to get shot and almost beat to a pulp by the Chinese, and still keeps on ticking like a Timex. Maybe he just dreamed of being on the beach in Port Arthur with Famke Janssen (of X-Men fame). It could have happened! Check it out to see who wins and loses and enjoy the ride because it is worth it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The most surprising thing about the film is how it takes such a familiar premise and gets it wrong.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    johnnyboyz (j_l_h_m@yahoo.co.uk)
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/4/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The biggest gripe I have with City of Industry is not because of its familiarity but for its execution. I love the genre of noir, pulpy crime and a couple of heist films but City of Industry is just a bank job too far; a wise talking gangster too far and a story of pulp fiction too far. City of Industry takes place in a world in which car alarms do not exist; in which if someone kicks open your apartment door and you're asleep, you do not wake up; a world in which people can survive multiple gun shot wounds without professional medical help and a world in which jewellery robbers don't wear masks. Throw in some badly done gunfights and a weak romance sub-plot and you have a sort of fun at times gritty crime film but something forgettable in the long run. The biggest problem I had with City of Industry is its point of view approach. It sounds like a funny thing to be pulling up a film for but just who exactly is the protagonist here? Who are we supposed to be following? Who's telling this story? It seems the film wants us to focus on several different characters at once but only one of them is in the film long enough for us to care for them while the others fill in the blanks when Roy Egan (Keitel) isn't on screen. At the beginning, Rachel (Janssen) and Jorge (Dominguez) talk on the phone  he is due to go to prison for a few years and Rachel, his wife, is upset about this as you'd expect only twenty minutes later the film's initial incident has happened and Jorge is out of the picture. Before you say something, this is not a spoiler because the film's premise is: a guy hunts for a betrayer after they kill his two heist partners. That gives away enough right there so why does the film have its initial character build up revolve around someone it'll kill off ten minutes later? Secondly, it seems that Egan is the character from whose point of view we're seeing this. The scene that suggests this is when he's standing at the trailer door when Skip (well played by Stephen Dorff) arrives because the camera cuts to his point of view; the point of view angle is very important as it puts the audience in the character's head, so the film has changed its mind again. The closing monologue all about how it was 'our' struggle and no one will ever know 'our' story is told to us by a character who has just spent all of about nine minutes on screen. Sorry, but it's not 'your' story because you didn't even do anything bar stay at home and look after the kids  at this point the protagonist (or who we think is the protagonist) has disappeared. So the film is muddled in who is delivering the film, whose story is it anyway? Think of any other film that uses voice over work and chances are when they show other characters doing things a million miles away from them, the film will never 'shift' to their point of view. And so the film's initial incident kicks Egan into action as he punches and shoots his way through the city looking for Skip, an amateur amongst professionals with his mistreating of women and his hip, fancy music. There is some fun to be had out of this little journey because the film is feeding its narrative drive (that is, revenge) with the obligatory yet entertaining scenes you expect. Egan floors a jerk of a bartender, he spends some time with the widow that is Rachel and he gets around stealing cars and interrogating people  good fun, you think. But then the film steers itself off the thin track it was already on. Revenge is still in the back of the film's mind but it is not the drive anymore. There is a sub-plot that opens up involving money, owed money, stolen money; I'm not sure. All I know is that Skip gets into trouble with some African-American gangsters and hell threatens to break loose; I say 'threaten' because nothing much actually happens. If we take 1999's Payback, we can see that Porter goes after Val for the money he owes him: Porter narrates and we do not get distracted by anything else until the d&eacute;nouement between Val and Porter; also, whenever Val is on screen it is a constant build up of how angry Porter is and how vulnerable Val is; in City of Industry, Skip continues to act deranged and immaturely, alienating us from the film's crime world and the revenge narrative-drive is sort of substituted for a little more violence and some characters running around for some missing money. It's at this point, around about the forty-five minute mark that the film looses us; it has abandoned its approach and has opted for explosions, impossible feats and mere petty violence. Nice opening, nice little hunt for Egan until a certain point and then 'bam', we aren't having fun anymore. Then the film gives us a satisfying d&eacute;nouement before cheating us again and having Egan disappear. Rachel is left to tell us how hard it was for her to get everything sorted out, but that's just silly since she didn't do anything. Maybe a better film have been eliminating Regan in the trailer park and then having Rachel go on the revenge mission  what fun that might've been.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Harvey dominates the screen
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    dev-aryap
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/4/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is pretty much a noir revenge story, with stone loner Roy Egan(the great Harvey Keitel) navigating the high and low of seedy LA, wending his way through dive bars, upscale LA law firms, and enduring beat downs from Asian and black gangs while pursuing THE BIG PAYBACK, son. As JB, the godfather of soul might say, "His patience thin, he want revenge." Harvey reluctantly joins a heist crew led by little brother Hutton that will knock off high-end jewelry store connected to the Russian mob. The brutally executed caper is successful, but then Skip Kovic (Dorff) goes turncoat, cancels some of the crew, including little brother, and now Harvey is out for blood. The big man looks good, obviously still hitting the weights, with some Risky Business shades and tieless Man in the Arrow shirt look. Okay, so he is in his late 50's, with a bit of a gut, and he walks with a little swayback. But, you know what, this is the man who pulled off "Fingers" son, and he would dominate the screen even if he walked around LA reading from the Congressional registry. Best scene: In his small hotel room after the post-robbery bloodbath, Harvey cuts through any Hamlet-style vacillation by pounding a card table with escalating fury, overturning it, sending out an unholy moan, and then setting out to kick some serious A. Only Harvey could turn a wordless moan and the act of overturning a card table into a statement of existential despair. Second best: when the big man gives a slimy bartender a beat down. About this second scene: post-robbery, Harvey goes to a hoodlum hangout, and tries to bribe the bartender for the whereabouts of Skip Kovic (Dorff). The bartender, who we know is in the know, tells Harvey to f- off, and Harvey steps back, squints, and waits, cigarette dangling. That goof with his silly goatee starts scrambling forward from the bar. Harvey administers a serious beat-down, KEEPING HIS CIGARETTE IN HIS MOUTH THE WHOLE TIME. Oh, and he picks up a gun for good measure. Now that is MOVIE MAKING, son. Irvin could have 86'd Eliot Gould and Michael Jai White, and the other Hollywood B-types trying to give the movie some bogus street cred. I buy Eliot Gould as a mobster as easily as I can buy a slurpee using a $3bill earned from my paper route on Mars. More of the stupendously sexy Famke Jannsen. And a nice cameo with Lucy Liu as a stripper with a SM motif. If Irvin was trying to channel the spirit of Michael Mann, he might have added more dialogue and made the Dorff character more complex. Still, I'll be here when City of 2 (Electric Boogaloo) comes out.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Caper, Double Cross, Revenge.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Robert J. Maxwell (rmax304823@yahoo.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/3/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Thief Harvey Keitel comes to Southern California to join his younger brother, Timothy Hutton, and a nice Latino (Wade Dominguez) and a driver (Stephen Dorff), to pull off a diamond heist at one of those high-end stores that line the main drag in Palm Springs. They are successful. As they are about to divvy up the loot, Dorff kills Hutton and Dominguez. He tries to kill Keitel too, but botches it, which is what you might call a bad mistake. Dorff takes off with all the loot and the rest of the movie has Keitel tracking him down, at the cost of a lot of money and an infinity of pain. At the end, having dispatched Dorff, the wounded and bleeding Keitel sees to it that Dominguez' widow (Famke Janssen) gets most of the money from the job. Keitel disappears, perhaps dying, and Janssen retires with her two kids to Port Arthur, Texas. End of story. A lot of this is familiar territory by now and has been done better elsewhere -- "Heat", for instance, or "Straight Time." But it's not badly done, despite the rather weak script. It's always interesting to see the underside of L.A. The Chinese sweat shops, the bars where the black guys hang out, everybody in shades, dilapidated single-family homes with their front yards littered with trash and children's toys, Lucy Liu doing a pole dance, San Pedro's cracking plants, dusty and mostly empty motels with propane gas tanks ready to explode at the hint of a stray bullet, careering cars knocking down utility poles and emitting showers of fake sparks, sleazy flowered shirts that scream out "Dollar Store", hotels with dark apartments where you wouldn't want to live unless you like junkies for neighbors. The director handles his background people with effortless aplomb. After he shoots two of his accomplices, Dorff chases Keitel through a louche trailer park, firing wildly. When he loses his quarry, Dorff looks angrily around. When the bullets started flying, the rednecks and their dogs scramble over fences to get out of the way, only to appear at their doorways seconds later. One fat guy in a cowboy hat cocks his shotgun, and another has a pistol at his side. It's amusing. You feel that these guys have been around such situations before. But the director has kept them in long shot and doesn't make a big to-do out of the point. Nice touch. In another scene, Keitel is beating the crap out of the bartender in an empty saloon. Two Latinos walk through the door, take a quick look at what's going on, and back out again. If there's not much new in the revenge plot, the details of life in this particular social world are pretty nicely captured. Well, I must say that the villain of the piece, Dorff, is thoroughly stereotyped. There's nothing "good" about him. He's a young, cocky, ruthless showoff. He plays raunchy music loud in his convertible. He shoots through his own girlfriend's chest in order to plug the guy holding her from behind, and shows not a wit of remorse. The director allows Dorff to commit a fundamental error. As in "Platoon," every time the F word is used, it is shouted emphatically. "And bring the EFFING money!" That's not how the F word is used. If anything is stressed in an utterance, it's the noun, not the adjective. Bonus point: Harvey Keitel has an opportunity to howl with anger and smash some furniture. Not a memorable movie, but one worth watching for diversion.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not Again!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jmillerdp
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Oh boy! Another "Heist Gone Wrong" movie! And, wouldn't you think that Harvey Keitel would be getting tired of these? After "Reservoir Dogs," you'd think he'd want a break! But, not here. The heist is planned, carried out, and, guess what?!, there is instant double crossing, shooting and everything else. Heavens! The second that happened, I pretty much checked out, and just waited the rest of the movie out. And, of course, it's a "final heist" for Keitel's character. So, that naturally means that everything's going to go wrong, guaranteed! The film is entirely on the shoulders of Harvey Keitel's performance. His fearless brand of acting is what make the film worth watching. But, it's standard plot makes it not worth it otherwise. ****** (6 Out of 10 Stars)
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not your average run of the mill PULP FICTION wannabe
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    JasparLamarCrabb
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    SPOILER ALERT! Easy to dismiss as another in a series of PULP FICTION wannabes, this is much better than expected. Directed with a lot of finesse by John Irvin and starring Harvey Keitel, CITY OF INDUSTRY is a fine crime thriller. Keitel is part of a gang of thieves (which also includes his brother), ripped off by loony cohort Stephen Dorff. A tense game of cat and mouse takes place as Keitel tries to track Dorff down. Keitel, who could easily sleepwalk through this type of film, gives a very good performance (he takes a real beating...several times) and has a lot of chemistry with Famke Janssen (as the widow of one of his cronies). The film is not flawless. The night photography is at times too dark, there is surely one too many name-less characters chasing Keitel, and Dorff is not really threatening enough to be convincing. Nevertheless, it's a well put together revenge film. Stephen Endelman's staccato music is a big plus.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Violent and exciting movie about seedy delinquents who pull off a fateful heist in L.A.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ma-cortes
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is a studio character with tones of suspense about some two-fisted criminals in L.A city . An old thief named Roy Egan (Harvey Keitel) , is drawn into the final jewel heist to Russian Mafia when his youngest brother named Lee (Timothy Hutton) asks him for a last score before they get out of the game . Lee forms a motley group (Keitel , Wade Dominguez and Stephen Dorff) to carry out the violent robbing . Unfortunately for him , Lee's picked one wrong partner and the events get worse . One of them decides he doesn't want to share the goods and betrays the group and happens murders and wreak havoc .The retired thief swears revenge on the lunatic who murdered his partners, while going on the run with the loot they stole. This modern adaptation of noir cinema contains thrills , intrigue, explosive scenes of action and over-riding feeling of heat . Interesting premise in which takes places a moving cat-and-mouse hunt through the seedier sides of L.A . Exciting and stirring finale full of shootouts , violence and fights into a factory . Good performances from all-star cast as Harvey Keitel as an old pro robber who has vowed to avenge his brother , Stephen Dorff as a volatile , violent wheelman and Famke Janssen as a suffering wife . Nice musical score including an emotive song at the beginning . Colorful cinematography by Thomas Burstyn who permeates the whole movie even in the hours of night and darkness . The motion picture is professionally directed by John Irvin with a well-achieved realization and elaborate scenes , though doesn't always live up to its promise . He worked extensively in TV before making his film debut with &uml;The dogs of war&uml; a cool rendition of a best-seller by Frederick Forsyth dealing with mercenaries in Africa. He went on directing &uml;Ghost story&uml; starred by old Hollywood-all-star and &uml;Champions&uml; about a courageous recovery from cancer stricken a steeple-chase jockey . After that , he realized a fine Vietnam movie as &uml;The Hamburger Hill&uml;, &uml;Turtle diary&uml;, an Arnold Szwenegger vehicle as &uml;Raw Deal&uml; and a good and realistic TV &uml;Robin Hood&uml;. Finally , he made underrated films that not had the same inspiration since them as &uml;Next of kin&uml; , &uml;Eminent domain&uml; , &uml;Freefall&uml; and a sparkling comedy ,&uml;Widows peak&uml; and is also of note a wartime genre as &uml;When trumpets fade&uml;(1998). And of course , &uml;City of Industry&uml; , being one of the jewels in Irvin's crown , it results to be one of this most interesting works and an efficient contemporary Noir which had moderated success .
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Another well made violent crime movie, except for !
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ahmed elshikh (ahmed_abd_elreheem@yahoo.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/3/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    No doubt it's catchy, incisive and coming to the point as no-nonsense movie. I loved the cast. (Famke Janssen)'s performance and beauty (her hair was exceptional !), (Harvey Keitel)'s silent mountainous anger, and (Stephen Dorff)'s attitude; they did the job finely. And I loved some scenes as well; like (Keitel) exploding with pain in a closed room, or getting out with the laptop debonairly, (Dorff) screaming devilishly (Rooooyyyy).. but as a whole it wasn't all flawless. Firstly, there are no depths, if you would think that that was a shortcoming. I mean the relationship between the lead and the woman was poor. Surely it doesn't need to develop into a romance, but with another treatment it could have been more memorable or touchy. However according to the movie's character as "another violent crime movie" it's the small shortcoming. Now medium shortcoming : the title. (City of Industry) fits a documentary more than a crime movie; especially this crime movie. The time that we have watched got nothing to do with a title of that kind. It's just a way to describe the background of the events with no serious shadows. I hate when they allege a meaning or a singularity by only a strange, outwardly profound, title ! Then the X Large shortcoming : the theft. This is unquestionably the stupidest heist in the history of mankind. How they went to steal a bank in the high noon with no masks, no gloves, and no disguise or whatsoever ??!! If there were no cameras recording them, what about the people themselves ??! Shame on this movie makers and cast as well. This is, sorrowfully, pure nonsense ! It's half heist, half revenge movie. Great ? No. Average ? Yes. Watchable and satisfying ? Of course.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A fairly gripping crime thriller that falls a bit flat
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Electrified_Voltage
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/9/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    About 3 &frac12; years ago, I came across a copy of this movie in the video store. I had never heard of it, and knew nothing about its general reception. I read the blurb on the back of the case, and thought it looked interesting, so I decided to rent it. By the time I watched it, I think I knew it wasn't the most popular crime thriller ever made, and like probably many other viewers, I was disappointed, finding it to be a rather weak film of its genre. Earlier this week, I rented it again. I couldn't remember it that well from my first viewing, and decided to give it a second chance. This time, I had lower expectations than before, but was expecting to be more impressed than I was the first time, which I was. That doesn't mean I didn't notice any severe flaws this time, though. Roy Egan is a retired thief who is lured out of retirement by his younger brother, Lee, for a major jewel heist. Lee has chosen two other partners for this robbery, Jorge Montana and Skip Kovich. The heist is a success, but afterwards, Skip gets greedy and suddenly kills Lee and Jorge! He tries to kill Roy as well, but the veteran thief manages to get away! After this, Roy swears to have his vengeance for the killing of his brother, and sets out on a mission to find the whereabouts of Skip! During this mission, his foe realizes he is searching for him, and is obviously not going to make it any easier for him. Roy isn't the only one who has suffered a loss in the family as a result of Skip's greed and insanity. The lunatic's other victim, Jorge, has left behind his wife and kids. His widow, Rachel, is eventually involved in Roy's mission after she learns what has happened to her husband. Harvey Keitel plays the starring role of Roy Egan, and does a decent job, but this may not be the case with the entire cast. I didn't care much for Stephen Dorff as Skip Kovich, but I'm not entirely sure if that was because of the actor's performance or because of the character. The characters in this film are generally pretty shallow. There isn't much emotional depth or detail to them. However, at least there are some characters I could sympathize with, most notably Rachel Montana, and I guess Roy Egan to a certain extent. There are fairly weak moments, such as some unnecessary sex scenes (at least one involving Skip and his girlfriend), the film drags at times, and the dialogue may not be perfect. Despite these flaws, there's still at least some suspense, as well as poignant moments, and enough to keep me interested until the end, during my second viewing, that is. Now that I've seen "City of Industry" twice, I don't exactly think it's bad, as I definitely found more redeeming qualities the second time than I did the first (I'm not sure if I really found any the first time), and a major reason for this is that it just MIGHT be a better film to watch alone. On the other hand, it's still a flawed thriller, flawed enough for me to see why it's so polarizing and has been widely overlooked since its release in the late 90's. I wouldn't have really been missing out on THAT much if I had never noticed this film in the video store several years ago (meaning I still wouldn't be aware of its existence now), and I certainly wouldn't consider it a must-see for anyone, but if you like this genre, maybe this movie will do. Just don't expect anything too brilliant or original.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    doesn't completely butcher the genre (6.5/10)
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    disdressed12
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/5/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    this was a fairly entertaining crime drama.it moved at a quick pace and it wasn't boring.i liked the fact that it didn't feel as depressing as many movies of the genre.it's still dark and gritty,just not oppressive.it pretty much follows the standard formula.betrayal,leading to revenge ending in bloodshed,usually death.it's all pretty predictable,and there a few illogical moments.still,it is entertaining for what it is.what elevates this material though, is Harvey Keitel,who makes just about any film he's in better than it otherwise might have been.Stephen Dorff,Timothy Hutton,Famke Janssen,Michael Jai White,and Wade Dominguez co star.and Lucy Liu also has a small role.recommended as long as you know what you're in for.it doesn't break any new ground,but it doesn't completely butcher the genre either.for me,City of Industry is a 6.5/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I'm my own police.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    lastliberal
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/11/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Sure, you can find some plots holes in this film big enough to drive a semi through, but that just keeps it from gathering awards, not from being worth a view. If you like revenge flicks, and noir, and lots of action, as well as a look at Lucy's Little Lius as she does a pole dance, then you might find this film interesting. What makes it most interesting, however, is the presence of Harvey Keitel. Having him hunting you down is a real bummer. He manages to get shot and almost beat to a pulp by the Chinese, and still keeps on ticking like a Timex. Maybe he just dreamed of being on the beach in Port Arthur with Famke Janssen (of X-Men fame). It could have happened! Check it out to see who wins and loses and enjoy the ride because it is worth it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The most surprising thing about the film is how it takes such a familiar premise and gets it wrong.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    johnnyboyz (j_l_h_m@yahoo.co.uk)
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/4/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The biggest gripe I have with City of Industry is not because of its familiarity but for its execution. I love the genre of noir, pulpy crime and a couple of heist films but City of Industry is just a bank job too far; a wise talking gangster too far and a story of pulp fiction too far. City of Industry takes place in a world in which car alarms do not exist; in which if someone kicks open your apartment door and you're asleep, you do not wake up; a world in which people can survive multiple gun shot wounds without professional medical help and a world in which jewellery robbers don't wear masks. Throw in some badly done gunfights and a weak romance sub-plot and you have a sort of fun at times gritty crime film but something forgettable in the long run. The biggest problem I had with City of Industry is its point of view approach. It sounds like a funny thing to be pulling up a film for but just who exactly is the protagonist here? Who are we supposed to be following? Who's telling this story? It seems the film wants us to focus on several different characters at once but only one of them is in the film long enough for us to care for them while the others fill in the blanks when Roy Egan (Keitel) isn't on screen. At the beginning, Rachel (Janssen) and Jorge (Dominguez) talk on the phone  he is due to go to prison for a few years and Rachel, his wife, is upset about this as you'd expect only twenty minutes later the film's initial incident has happened and Jorge is out of the picture. Before you say something, this is not a spoiler because the film's premise is: a guy hunts for a betrayer after they kill his two heist partners. That gives away enough right there so why does the film have its initial character build up revolve around someone it'll kill off ten minutes later? Secondly, it seems that Egan is the character from whose point of view we're seeing this. The scene that suggests this is when he's standing at the trailer door when Skip (well played by Stephen Dorff) arrives because the camera cuts to his point of view; the point of view angle is very important as it puts the audience in the character's head, so the film has changed its mind again. The closing monologue all about how it was 'our' struggle and no one will ever know 'our' story is told to us by a character who has just spent all of about nine minutes on screen. Sorry, but it's not 'your' story because you didn't even do anything bar stay at home and look after the kids  at this point the protagonist (or who we think is the protagonist) has disappeared. So the film is muddled in who is delivering the film, whose story is it anyway? Think of any other film that uses voice over work and chances are when they show other characters doing things a million miles away from them, the film will never 'shift' to their point of view. And so the film's initial incident kicks Egan into action as he punches and shoots his way through the city looking for Skip, an amateur amongst professionals with his mistreating of women and his hip, fancy music. There is some fun to be had out of this little journey because the film is feeding its narrative drive (that is, revenge) with the obligatory yet entertaining scenes you expect. Egan floors a jerk of a bartender, he spends some time with the widow that is Rachel and he gets around stealing cars and interrogating people  good fun, you think. But then the film steers itself off the thin track it was already on. Revenge is still in the back of the film's mind but it is not the drive anymore. There is a sub-plot that opens up involving money, owed money, stolen money; I'm not sure. All I know is that Skip gets into trouble with some African-American gangsters and hell threatens to break loose; I say 'threaten' because nothing much actually happens. If we take 1999's Payback, we can see that Porter goes after Val for the money he owes him: Porter narrates and we do not get distracted by anything else until the d&eacute;nouement between Val and Porter; also, whenever Val is on screen it is a constant build up of how angry Porter is and how vulnerable Val is; in City of Industry, Skip continues to act deranged and immaturely, alienating us from the film's crime world and the revenge narrative-drive is sort of substituted for a little more violence and some characters running around for some missing money. It's at this point, around about the forty-five minute mark that the film looses us; it has abandoned its approach and has opted for explosions, impossible feats and mere petty violence. Nice opening, nice little hunt for Egan until a certain point and then 'bam', we aren't having fun anymore. Then the film gives us a satisfying d&eacute;nouement before cheating us again and having Egan disappear. Rachel is left to tell us how hard it was for her to get everything sorted out, but that's just silly since she didn't do anything. Maybe a better film have been eliminating Regan in the trailer park and then having Rachel go on the revenge mission  what fun that might've been.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Harvey dominates the screen
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    dev-aryap
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/4/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is pretty much a noir revenge story, with stone loner Roy Egan(the great Harvey Keitel) navigating the high and low of seedy LA, wending his way through dive bars, upscale LA law firms, and enduring beat downs from Asian and black gangs while pursuing THE BIG PAYBACK, son. As JB, the godfather of soul might say, "His patience thin, he want revenge." Harvey reluctantly joins a heist crew led by little brother Hutton that will knock off high-end jewelry store connected to the Russian mob. The brutally executed caper is successful, but then Skip Kovic (Dorff) goes turncoat, cancels some of the crew, including little brother, and now Harvey is out for blood. The big man looks good, obviously still hitting the weights, with some Risky Business shades and tieless Man in the Arrow shirt look. Okay, so he is in his late 50's, with a bit of a gut, and he walks with a little swayback. But, you know what, this is the man who pulled off "Fingers" son, and he would dominate the screen even if he walked around LA reading from the Congressional registry. Best scene: In his small hotel room after the post-robbery bloodbath, Harvey cuts through any Hamlet-style vacillation by pounding a card table with escalating fury, overturning it, sending out an unholy moan, and then setting out to kick some serious A. Only Harvey could turn a wordless moan and the act of overturning a card table into a statement of existential despair. Second best: when the big man gives a slimy bartender a beat down. About this second scene: post-robbery, Harvey goes to a hoodlum hangout, and tries to bribe the bartender for the whereabouts of Skip Kovic (Dorff). The bartender, who we know is in the know, tells Harvey to f- off, and Harvey steps back, squints, and waits, cigarette dangling. That goof with his silly goatee starts scrambling forward from the bar. Harvey administers a serious beat-down, KEEPING HIS CIGARETTE IN HIS MOUTH THE WHOLE TIME. Oh, and he picks up a gun for good measure. Now that is MOVIE MAKING, son. Irvin could have 86'd Eliot Gould and Michael Jai White, and the other Hollywood B-types trying to give the movie some bogus street cred. I buy Eliot Gould as a mobster as easily as I can buy a slurpee using a $3bill earned from my paper route on Mars. More of the stupendously sexy Famke Jannsen. And a nice cameo with Lucy Liu as a stripper with a SM motif. If Irvin was trying to channel the spirit of Michael Mann, he might have added more dialogue and made the Dorff character more complex. Still, I'll be here when City of 2 (Electric Boogaloo) comes out.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Caper, Double Cross, Revenge.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Robert J. Maxwell (rmax304823@yahoo.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/3/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Thief Harvey Keitel comes to Southern California to join his younger brother, Timothy Hutton, and a nice Latino (Wade Dominguez) and a driver (Stephen Dorff), to pull off a diamond heist at one of those high-end stores that line the main drag in Palm Springs. They are successful. As they are about to divvy up the loot, Dorff kills Hutton and Dominguez. He tries to kill Keitel too, but botches it, which is what you might call a bad mistake. Dorff takes off with all the loot and the rest of the movie has Keitel tracking him down, at the cost of a lot of money and an infinity of pain. At the end, having dispatched Dorff, the wounded and bleeding Keitel sees to it that Dominguez' widow (Famke Janssen) gets most of the money from the job. Keitel disappears, perhaps dying, and Janssen retires with her two kids to Port Arthur, Texas. End of story. A lot of this is familiar territory by now and has been done better elsewhere -- "Heat", for instance, or "Straight Time." But it's not badly done, despite the rather weak script. It's always interesting to see the underside of L.A. The Chinese sweat shops, the bars where the black guys hang out, everybody in shades, dilapidated single-family homes with their front yards littered with trash and children's toys, Lucy Liu doing a pole dance, San Pedro's cracking plants, dusty and mostly empty motels with propane gas tanks ready to explode at the hint of a stray bullet, careering cars knocking down utility poles and emitting showers of fake sparks, sleazy flowered shirts that scream out "Dollar Store", hotels with dark apartments where you wouldn't want to live unless you like junkies for neighbors. The director handles his background people with effortless aplomb. After he shoots two of his accomplices, Dorff chases Keitel through a louche trailer park, firing wildly. When he loses his quarry, Dorff looks angrily around. When the bullets started flying, the rednecks and their dogs scramble over fences to get out of the way, only to appear at their doorways seconds later. One fat guy in a cowboy hat cocks his shotgun, and another has a pistol at his side. It's amusing. You feel that these guys have been around such situations before. But the director has kept them in long shot and doesn't make a big to-do out of the point. Nice touch. In another scene, Keitel is beating the crap out of the bartender in an empty saloon. Two Latinos walk through the door, take a quick look at what's going on, and back out again. If there's not much new in the revenge plot, the details of life in this particular social world are pretty nicely captured. Well, I must say that the villain of the piece, Dorff, is thoroughly stereotyped. There's nothing "good" about him. He's a young, cocky, ruthless showoff. He plays raunchy music loud in his convertible. He shoots through his own girlfriend's chest in order to plug the guy holding her from behind, and shows not a wit of remorse. The director allows Dorff to commit a fundamental error. As in "Platoon," every time the F word is used, it is shouted emphatically. "And bring the EFFING money!" That's not how the F word is used. If anything is stressed in an utterance, it's the noun, not the adjective. Bonus point: Harvey Keitel has an opportunity to howl with anger and smash some furniture. Not a memorable movie, but one worth watching for diversion.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
 </reviews>
</filme>
