<filme>
 <id>
  1613
 </id>
 <imdburl>
  http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0114690
 </imdburl>
 <ano>
  1995
 </ano>
 <titulo>
  Tokyo Fist
 </titulo>
 <rating>
  7.0
 </rating>
 <sinopse>
  A businessman, Tsuda, runs into a childhood friend, Tajuki, on the subway. Tajuki is working as a semiprofessional boxer. Tsuda soon begins to suspect that Tajuki might be having an affair ... &nbsp;&raquo;
 </sinopse>
 <storyline>
  A businessman, Tsuda, runs into a childhood friend, Tajuki, on the subway. Tajuki is working as a semiprofessional boxer. Tsuda soon begins to suspect that Tajuki might be having an affair with his fiance Hizuru. After an altercation, Tsuda begins training rigorously himself, leading to an extremely bloody, violent confrontation.
 </storyline>
 <generos>
  <genero>
   Action
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Drama
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Thriller
  </genero>
 </generos>
 <keywords>
  <keyword>
   suicide
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   revenge
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   violence
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   maggot
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   surrealism
  </keyword>
 </keywords>
 <diretores>
  <diretor>
   Shin'ya Tsukamoto
  </diretor>
 </diretores>
 <escritores>
  <escritor>
   Hisashi Saito
  </escritor>
  <escritor>
   Shin'ya Tsukamoto
  </escritor>
 </escritores>
 <atores>
  <ator>
   Kaori Fujii
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Shin'ya Tsukamoto
  </ator>
  <ator>
   K&ocirc;ji Tsukamoto
  </ator>
 </atores>
 <reviews>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A must-see, though not wuss-oriented
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Gene John
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I feel it's sort of a shame for such a movie to have less than at least 100 reviews on its page. So here I go, helping it out with this 22nd review, if I recall it correctly... First time I read a review on Tokyo Fist on another site, I didn't quite know what to expect from this movie. I was deep down in Cronenberg horror, but this title's plot and atmosphere (as described by a rather insipid reviewer, I guess) simply eluded my intuition. Luckily, I decided to give this a try, and it was one good decision. Tokyo Fist stands at a fine border between black comedy (and also really dry), surrealism, action and plain existential malaise. Tsukamoto's cam angles and effects act perfectly coherently with his intent, from emphasizing the ridiculous monotony and isolation in Tsuda's life to highlighting the irrational ferocity of his old "friend" that almost seems to turn night into day and day into night. Now, diving a bit into the predictable Fight Club comparison, Tokyo Fist is the severe, restrained, Eastern cousin of Palahniuk's novel's adaptation. There is no noticeable trace of emotion (maybe except anger), pathetism, or nihilist verbosity in the discourse of Tokyo Fist's characters. It's as if their existence and the duty of assuming various roles (and subsequent failures) squeezed their sentimental tendencies out of them and sent them into an abyss. There is no "love trio" in this movie, no matter how tempting it would be to call it that way. Its three main characters remain as insulated as can be, until the very end - a brilliantly open and non-conclusive end to a small, powerful drama of people not able to manage their remorse or lack of meaning without showering themselves in suffering. Beyond the plot, there are some really nice hyperkinetic boxing scenes in this movie, and the generous to parodic flows of blood and bruises might seem chuckle and nausea-inducing at the same time. I am afraid, though, that what I have said doesn't give this film the aura that it deserves. If you are not necessarily an adrenaline freak yet not an instant puker either, and want to see something done artistically indeed, you ought to give this at least one punch with the eye.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The rage of apathy
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    chaos-rampant
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/3/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is not a movie you experience with the brain, rather it's an assault on the senses. Some of my favourite cinema does that, and I'm always on the lookout for movies that call us to live through a certain experience, to vicariously sense the world as another person might. The ultimate joy is for me to be able to take out something that matters, an otherwise impossible view of the world in my livingroom that makes sense. The problem of Tokyo Fist is that it's packed with so much rage and annihilation yet aims it nowhere. The boxer characters are punching, but they're not punching outwards, at society, nor inwards at the soul, they're simply pummeling and being pummeled senseless. Senseless is an apt word here, for in Tokyo Fist the mind doesn't matter, and the human body is something to be destroyed, the senses torn from it and thrown in a bloody heap on a grimy floor. Tsukamoto can be seen beating his head in a bloody pulp against a wall, but that wall signifies nothing. The spurts of blood gushing from broken noses and deformed bonecheeks, the film celebrates with the comic verve of Sam Raimi. With time Tsukamoto would grow out of the techno angst of this period, but enabling the maturity of films like Vital, a certain youthful vitality had to be sacrificed in the process. I lament this because few directors dare make films like his, even Tsukamoto himself doesn't seem able to make them anymore. Fits of jealousy, miserable love triangles, personality changes, all these are trifle story points. What I take from Tokyo Fist is the aimlessness of violence, taken to the extreme because there's nothing to absorb it. Likely Tsukamoto grew up in a Japanese society of the 80's and 90's, like the rest of the world, stifled in the mire of apathy and complacency. People had the money to buy and the selection to buy from, but not the struggle with grand ideals. The resulting New Wave of his cinema is a New Wave of disillusionment turned against itself, a shell without a solid core to make it dream a better society. In this light, it makes sense to see Tsukamoto playing a young employee, fresh out of high school and already into a suit and a tie running errands for a faceless corporation, turning into a crazed animal for whom even love is a petulant obsession, another passing need to be consummated.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Complete gut punch soaked in blood and grit
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    TimothyFarrell
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/1/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Tokyo Fist" has garnered lots of comparisons to "Fight Club". While some of them are accurate, comparing them to one another doesn't to justice to either film, both of which are stunning achievements. They both involve salesmen getting in touch with their inner brutality, they both have similar cinematography, and the open ending to "Tokyo Fist" could be interpreted as a similar resolution to "Fight Club". Thats about it. Whereas "Fight Club" was a more accessible, operatic, and unsubtle dark comedy, "Tokyo Fist" is a complete gut punch soaked in blood and grit. Shinya Tsukamoto is a true original that deserves more recognition that he has received. The film's editing style is the same as Tsukamoto's earlier "Tetsuo", but in my mind "Tokyo Fist" works better because it adds a relatively linear storyline and interesting characters. Its fascinating to see that by the end every character has transformed to what the other one was at the beginning. The meaning of the film is subtle and holds up to repeat viewings. Its not as much of a mind bender as "Tetsuo" was, but its a much more well made film overall. It shows that Tsukamoto has progressed as a filmmaker without losing his edge. (8/10)
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Stomach-churning, but ultimately rewarding
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    desh79
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/12/2004
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Watching a movie by Shinya Tsukamoto is a bit like staring into the deepest pits of hell, or the darkest recesses of the male psyche, whichever way you want to put it. But then the two seem fairly synonymous, at least if the sheer visceral anger in Tokyo Fist is anything to go by. Those aware of Tsukamoto's feature-length debut Tetsuo (1988) will be familiar with the basic premise in Tokyo Fist; flawed relationship between man and woman is brutally disrupted by an outside element which challenges the protagonist to a potentially lethal, and eventually soul-destroying, duel. Similarly to other pioneers of horror (eg. Cronenberg, Miike), Tsukamoto chooses to use all kinds of repulsive visuals. Just to give you an idea, if a face almost literally falling off after a boxing match is too much for you, it's probably best to stay away from this film. However, the brutal imagery is not completely pointless. Tokyo Fist portrays male anger with such honesty that it is sometimes painful to watch, but that's really the point since violence is not something to be cooed at or to be admired (which is what many Hollywood movies seemingly aim to achieve, witness the way audiences are prompted to cheer for the good guy as he murders the baddie). The violence in Tokyo Fist is allegorical in nature, ie. it stands for something else than just simply fists flying: the inability between men and women (and, indeed, men and men) to understand each other ultimately leads to the kind of extreme violence we see on screen. This, ironically, makes Tokyo Fist a part of the great humanist tradition in Japanese cinema, alongside Rashomon and other such movies, because, even though it uses extreme imagery to make a point, it makes the same point all the same: if we relish in jealousy, revenge and anger we will only end up destroying each other, and ultimately ourselves. Does Hollywood ever deal with violence this eloquently? Also, as with Tetsuo, the characters in Tokyo Fist seem to live entirely in a world of their own. Many shots frame them either alone, or surrounded by an anonymous mass which fails to notice them or appreciate their presence (even as Tsuda stands in the middle of a shopping mall, his face beaten to a pulp). I can't think of another film-maker who sums up urban alienation as brilliantly as Tsukamoto does; the sheer contradiction of city life, in which a great mass of people are all huddled together at close range, and yet find themselves completely lonely and alienated from one another. For all intents and purposes, Tokyo Fist is a movie which requires a strong stomach and an open mind. But it's a great achievement all the same.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Anger, violence, pain and revenge drive the action
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    macdermotfergus
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/11/2004
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Tsukamoto in this film strips away excess to reveal a animal emotions which are then stretched to excess. In this film anger, violence, pain and revenge drive the action. Tsuda and Kojima witness the murder of a girl they like and while both vow to find and punish the killers only Kojima holds on to the twisted dream to become a second rate boxer. Tsuda becomes a salaryman in a sexless relationship in which they spend the evenings watching old films (I spotted Metropolis and another which I can't place). A chance meeting between the two after many years awakens the anger that Kojima feels towards Tsuda, and the former begins making a play for Hizuru, Tsuda's girlfriend. This in turn leads Tsuda to become angry and he turns to boxing to get revenge on his former friend. Meanwhile Hikuru becomes a masochist, autonomous of both the males. The fairly graphic violence is mostly make up and is so over the top it is clearly to make the point mentioned in one of the other comments: violence is often the first recourse in a situation. However, as opposed to a film like Rocky where the violence leads to personal redemption, or an emotional force like Raging Bull, the violence is non-cathartic and meaningless. It is almost as if the characters are driven to behave in a certain way as a reflex reaction. Fast editing, powerful sound effects and blue colours mark the film out as Tsukamoto's style, and the transformation theme is another element that he returns to. Lots of fun for me, but the person I was with didn't have a clue what was going on. Make your own decision, but there is no relationship to Fight Club whatsoever: this is about human emotion, not social issues.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    This film will come through your screen, so beware it like every other film this master of cinema has made
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Bogey Man
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/1/2003
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Japanese film maker genius and multi-talent Shinya Tsukamoto's Tokyo Fist (Tokyo-ken, 1995) is as stunning and incredible experience as can be expected after seeing his two Tetsuo films in which a human body and metal (machine) became one with a horrific results. Tsukamoto's cinema is filled with hyper fast editing, shaking camera, fast forwards and every imaginable things to shock the viewer senses and make the weakest faint. Tokyo Fist is not any exception. Director himself plays Tsuda, a nerdish Japanese insurance salesman who has a beautiful girlfriend Hizuru (Kahori Fujii) whom with he lives seemingly peacefully and in love. But still it looks like Tsuda has some problems in his life and seems to be on the edge of his sanity. Soon his high school time friend Kojima arrives (played by the director's brother, K&ocirc;ji Tsukamoto) and he is a professional boxer and very fierce one. When he starts to be interested in Tsuda's girl, all physical and mental hell breaks loose as Tsuda gets an obsession to start to box himself, too, and Hizuru starts to have some very severe habits of body piercing and self mutilation. The infernal ride has begun and the viewer is not recommended to take it granted that he'll/she'll stomach the ride till the end because this is Tsukamoto. That means incredible power and impact straight to your face. The film is perhaps even wilder at some points than the first Tetsuo (1988) as the message and imagery is really heavy this time and the film is in color, too. The fists, the punches and the mayhem is always aimed straight to the camera, the viewer and audience, so the viewer will be on the edge of the seat for the whole time, and it all is of course at its most powerful when seen on the big screen. Tsukamoto has the talent to hammer and force his things to the skull and spinal cord of the viewer and he does it all with the magic of editing and cinematography, and definitely not least of Chu Ishikawa's pounding and merciless soundtrack which is here as effective and wonderful as in Tetsuo. The visuals are impressive and every twisted camera angle has its purpose and meaning as well as every bit of mist and darkness that is shed during the ride. The effect when he shakes his camera is something truly unique and definitely much more powerful way to depict the feelings and mental states of the characters than any dialogue ever could. Fast edits and unconventional usage of camera can be very irritating and needless when used without any real reason or to make the film look "stylish", but they can also be heart stoppingly effective when they have a cinematic meaning and the director could just simply write on the paper what the edit or camera angle means inside the film. Tetsuo is another great example of this and its black and white scenery is no less powerful than the colors in Tokyo Fist. Tokyo Fist is extremely menacing as there hardly are any peaceful moments and there's all the time some element there to make it clear that it is not peaceful even though it may look like it. The film's theme is about human nature and its jealous and weak sides as the characters can't live without taking or producing physical pain. The smashed faces and the scenes of surreal gore spurting at nightmarish anger are really something to make us ask why do the characters do it. Why cannot human nature solve things in other way than physical force and violence and how many of us dares to admit the brute sides of ourselves and accept them? And then of course keep them away and on the background. The final image is kind of "optimistic" but definitely no character gets out without the result and payment of their deeds. The film is also a good example for those who think that in Japanese cinema females are often on the background and weaker than men as the lead female in Tokyo Fist practically (and quite passively!) makes, at first so powerful and dominating, Kojima as her submissive slave. The film begins as in our familiar world in modern day Japan but it is not so long before Tsukamoto gives us the first glimpses of his surreal visions that are taken at their extremes in the incredible blood soaked nightmare finale "in the ring", a finale that is so fierce, kinetic and merciless piece of film making it just makes me appreciate and love Japanese cinema even more with its many sides never or very rarely paralleled in other world cinema. The gore and violence is sudden and almost unbearably shocking at times but the blood geysirs are not realistic nor they're meant to be; they are from the film's own world and as symbolic and surreal as in the Japanese samurai classic The Baby Cart aka Lone Wolf & Cub series in the early seventies, the first two parts of that series edited also into one feature film as Shogun Assassin (1980). Still none of these films manages to give the kind of impact in their violence or any other element than Tokyo Fist, but the surreal depiction of physical violence is pretty similar with Tsukamoto and The Baby Cart pieces. Perhaps only negative point I can find in Tokyo Fist is that some of the characters seem to develop a little too fast and they should have been little more motivated and restrained. For example, Tsuda seems to be completely mad already and is capable to rape his girlfriend any time so these kind of things should be explained little more carefully in order to make the piece perfect and the characters more real. Still the characters are very good and the message and theme gets delivered very effectively through their acts and there's absolutely no question that the visual magic and impact of Tsukamoto's deserves nothing less than praising and moments of pure amazement. Shinya Tsukamoto is the kind of Master of Cinema that he really deserves his name in the thanks section of the end credits of every young film maker's film who has got inspiration from his work. His films have the ability to make people faint, shock, turn the head off the screen and stun in their power and it all is done practically by himself as he works as an editor, cinematographer, art director etc. in his own films and thus expresses his visions. His films would be totally unforgettable when seen at least once in the big screen but fortunately the effect is still very strong on television, too. Tokyo Fist is among the most fierce, angry and honest rides of cinema I've ever experienced and everytime I see something from its maker, I cannot help but feel confused and amazed in front of Japan and its invaluable gifts during the centuries to the world of cinema. 9/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Japanese boxing film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    zombikev
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/10/2002
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    SPOILERS ARE LOCATED BELOW Many people will disagree with my opinion on this film. First off, many comments on this board mislead me into getting hold of it. The film is quite terrible. Sure, it has some good fighting scenes in it, and some pretty entertaining training scenes. But, the film just gets to be too chaotic. The plot is simple; the two friends become enemies over a woman. When they were youths, a girl that they had loved, was killed by street punks. They vowed to take up pro- boxing and to eventually avenge their friend. One friend takes the pro-boxing path and one takes a different stride. The film does address many good issues, but it is just bathed in distracting features. The music for one thing, was a joke. Many of the camera angles were poor, and many of the effects were just moronic. How many times can you watch a guy walk down the street through a rumble cam? And many things were repeated constantly; like the meat on the camera. I found the film interesting, but not compelling. This film related in now way to Fight Club.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Confusing boxing movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Andrew (vidgamer992@aol.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/7/2002
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I can't believe what other people are writing about this. DON'T BELIVE THEM. I rented this movie, almost bought it, and wanted a refund. I guess I had false expectations. Fight Club was amazing to me and I wanted some more. Too bad the most exciting aspect to Tokyo Fist was the box art. The movie's interesting plot was a whole love triangle between a boxer, his friend, and the friend's wife. The friend/geek becomes a boxer to win his girl back. The wife turns from housewife to Freaky, S&M psycho. Sounds great but nothing came together right for me. The movie is slow with the use of long shots throughout the film that just put me asleep. In terms of violence, it was pretty tame with cheesy effects. I like cheesy over-the-top violence but this was pretty sorry and sparse. I have seen better action scenes then this even on 80's American Action movies. If you are expecting action or a deep thought provoking experience, look for something else. People call it a masterpiece, but I am wondering if I rented the same movie that I did. The only way you can truly judge this film is watching it yourself. Be prepared for a serious letdown. I don't usually do this, but I felt the need to warn people about this much often overhyped movie.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The release of pent-up passions...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    poe426
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/2/2002
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    If there's a more dramatic context for human passion than fistfighting, I don't know what it is. From, say, GENTLEMAN JIM, THE HARDER THEY FALL, REQUIEM FOR A HEAVYWEIGHT (both versions), THE GREAT WHITE HOPE and FAT CITY to, say, HARD TIMES, ROCKY, THE GREATEST, RAGING BULL, and ALI, The Sweet Science has been used to examine The Human Condition, up close and personal; subtext is thrust to the forefront, and boxing as drama is as clear and as pure as it comes. TOKYO FIST follows in that tradition, but in a hyperkinetic way that is so over-the-top that it would make Sam Raimi blush. That's not a bad thing: pushing the cinematic envelope is sometimes necessary (audiences become jaded, and need that wake-up call). Director Tsukamoto isn't practicing his ten-second nap by any stretch of the imagination. And stretching the imagination is exactly what he does. We see a man get struck by a blow that opens his brow- and blood comes spraying forth in a way it never could in real life. It's an image so extreme that one can't help but laugh... but, in the context of the emotional cauldron that is TOKYO FIST, it's very apropos. It's the spewing forth of pent-up emotions that perhaps only a Japanese filmmaker could have conceived (which seems a sound assumption, as no other filmmaker has ever- to my knowledge- come so close to exposing raw nerve endings in a motion picture). TOKYO FIST is an amazing achievement.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Bone breaking, but more "human" than most movies.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Mike Foster
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/1/2002
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The comments of others comparing this movie to Raging Bull, Rocky and Fight Club could be misguided. This movie could have been about almost anything and the boxing is just a plot device . . . but a great one!!! . This movie is about people - most other movies are only about characters. The violence helps show just how angry a boring insurance guy (?) can get when something simple blows his world to pieces. It taunts the white-collar viewer by showing a white-collar man's wife getting easily tempted away by a physically muscular man. And the way she decends into perversity is a delightful rebuttal to the anodyne hold her husband had on her. Seeing a meaty, violent boxer intrude into a sterile, hideous modern existence/relationship forces us viewers to consider where our own humanist allegiances lie. The film says things about humanity that other films don't have the guts to say and rings totally true. If you can stomach the jagged aggressiveness of a movie but want the genuine article, see this film. I haven't had such a rough - but rewarding - ride since I last watched "In the Company of Men".
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A must-see, though not wuss-oriented
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Gene John
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I feel it's sort of a shame for such a movie to have less than at least 100 reviews on its page. So here I go, helping it out with this 22nd review, if I recall it correctly... First time I read a review on Tokyo Fist on another site, I didn't quite know what to expect from this movie. I was deep down in Cronenberg horror, but this title's plot and atmosphere (as described by a rather insipid reviewer, I guess) simply eluded my intuition. Luckily, I decided to give this a try, and it was one good decision. Tokyo Fist stands at a fine border between black comedy (and also really dry), surrealism, action and plain existential malaise. Tsukamoto's cam angles and effects act perfectly coherently with his intent, from emphasizing the ridiculous monotony and isolation in Tsuda's life to highlighting the irrational ferocity of his old "friend" that almost seems to turn night into day and day into night. Now, diving a bit into the predictable Fight Club comparison, Tokyo Fist is the severe, restrained, Eastern cousin of Palahniuk's novel's adaptation. There is no noticeable trace of emotion (maybe except anger), pathetism, or nihilist verbosity in the discourse of Tokyo Fist's characters. It's as if their existence and the duty of assuming various roles (and subsequent failures) squeezed their sentimental tendencies out of them and sent them into an abyss. There is no "love trio" in this movie, no matter how tempting it would be to call it that way. Its three main characters remain as insulated as can be, until the very end - a brilliantly open and non-conclusive end to a small, powerful drama of people not able to manage their remorse or lack of meaning without showering themselves in suffering. Beyond the plot, there are some really nice hyperkinetic boxing scenes in this movie, and the generous to parodic flows of blood and bruises might seem chuckle and nausea-inducing at the same time. I am afraid, though, that what I have said doesn't give this film the aura that it deserves. If you are not necessarily an adrenaline freak yet not an instant puker either, and want to see something done artistically indeed, you ought to give this at least one punch with the eye.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The rage of apathy
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    chaos-rampant
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/3/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is not a movie you experience with the brain, rather it's an assault on the senses. Some of my favourite cinema does that, and I'm always on the lookout for movies that call us to live through a certain experience, to vicariously sense the world as another person might. The ultimate joy is for me to be able to take out something that matters, an otherwise impossible view of the world in my livingroom that makes sense. The problem of Tokyo Fist is that it's packed with so much rage and annihilation yet aims it nowhere. The boxer characters are punching, but they're not punching outwards, at society, nor inwards at the soul, they're simply pummeling and being pummeled senseless. Senseless is an apt word here, for in Tokyo Fist the mind doesn't matter, and the human body is something to be destroyed, the senses torn from it and thrown in a bloody heap on a grimy floor. Tsukamoto can be seen beating his head in a bloody pulp against a wall, but that wall signifies nothing. The spurts of blood gushing from broken noses and deformed bonecheeks, the film celebrates with the comic verve of Sam Raimi. With time Tsukamoto would grow out of the techno angst of this period, but enabling the maturity of films like Vital, a certain youthful vitality had to be sacrificed in the process. I lament this because few directors dare make films like his, even Tsukamoto himself doesn't seem able to make them anymore. Fits of jealousy, miserable love triangles, personality changes, all these are trifle story points. What I take from Tokyo Fist is the aimlessness of violence, taken to the extreme because there's nothing to absorb it. Likely Tsukamoto grew up in a Japanese society of the 80's and 90's, like the rest of the world, stifled in the mire of apathy and complacency. People had the money to buy and the selection to buy from, but not the struggle with grand ideals. The resulting New Wave of his cinema is a New Wave of disillusionment turned against itself, a shell without a solid core to make it dream a better society. In this light, it makes sense to see Tsukamoto playing a young employee, fresh out of high school and already into a suit and a tie running errands for a faceless corporation, turning into a crazed animal for whom even love is a petulant obsession, another passing need to be consummated.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Complete gut punch soaked in blood and grit
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    TimothyFarrell
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/1/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Tokyo Fist" has garnered lots of comparisons to "Fight Club". While some of them are accurate, comparing them to one another doesn't to justice to either film, both of which are stunning achievements. They both involve salesmen getting in touch with their inner brutality, they both have similar cinematography, and the open ending to "Tokyo Fist" could be interpreted as a similar resolution to "Fight Club". Thats about it. Whereas "Fight Club" was a more accessible, operatic, and unsubtle dark comedy, "Tokyo Fist" is a complete gut punch soaked in blood and grit. Shinya Tsukamoto is a true original that deserves more recognition that he has received. The film's editing style is the same as Tsukamoto's earlier "Tetsuo", but in my mind "Tokyo Fist" works better because it adds a relatively linear storyline and interesting characters. Its fascinating to see that by the end every character has transformed to what the other one was at the beginning. The meaning of the film is subtle and holds up to repeat viewings. Its not as much of a mind bender as "Tetsuo" was, but its a much more well made film overall. It shows that Tsukamoto has progressed as a filmmaker without losing his edge. (8/10)
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Stomach-churning, but ultimately rewarding
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    desh79
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/12/2004
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Watching a movie by Shinya Tsukamoto is a bit like staring into the deepest pits of hell, or the darkest recesses of the male psyche, whichever way you want to put it. But then the two seem fairly synonymous, at least if the sheer visceral anger in Tokyo Fist is anything to go by. Those aware of Tsukamoto's feature-length debut Tetsuo (1988) will be familiar with the basic premise in Tokyo Fist; flawed relationship between man and woman is brutally disrupted by an outside element which challenges the protagonist to a potentially lethal, and eventually soul-destroying, duel. Similarly to other pioneers of horror (eg. Cronenberg, Miike), Tsukamoto chooses to use all kinds of repulsive visuals. Just to give you an idea, if a face almost literally falling off after a boxing match is too much for you, it's probably best to stay away from this film. However, the brutal imagery is not completely pointless. Tokyo Fist portrays male anger with such honesty that it is sometimes painful to watch, but that's really the point since violence is not something to be cooed at or to be admired (which is what many Hollywood movies seemingly aim to achieve, witness the way audiences are prompted to cheer for the good guy as he murders the baddie). The violence in Tokyo Fist is allegorical in nature, ie. it stands for something else than just simply fists flying: the inability between men and women (and, indeed, men and men) to understand each other ultimately leads to the kind of extreme violence we see on screen. This, ironically, makes Tokyo Fist a part of the great humanist tradition in Japanese cinema, alongside Rashomon and other such movies, because, even though it uses extreme imagery to make a point, it makes the same point all the same: if we relish in jealousy, revenge and anger we will only end up destroying each other, and ultimately ourselves. Does Hollywood ever deal with violence this eloquently? Also, as with Tetsuo, the characters in Tokyo Fist seem to live entirely in a world of their own. Many shots frame them either alone, or surrounded by an anonymous mass which fails to notice them or appreciate their presence (even as Tsuda stands in the middle of a shopping mall, his face beaten to a pulp). I can't think of another film-maker who sums up urban alienation as brilliantly as Tsukamoto does; the sheer contradiction of city life, in which a great mass of people are all huddled together at close range, and yet find themselves completely lonely and alienated from one another. For all intents and purposes, Tokyo Fist is a movie which requires a strong stomach and an open mind. But it's a great achievement all the same.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Anger, violence, pain and revenge drive the action
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    macdermotfergus
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/11/2004
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Tsukamoto in this film strips away excess to reveal a animal emotions which are then stretched to excess. In this film anger, violence, pain and revenge drive the action. Tsuda and Kojima witness the murder of a girl they like and while both vow to find and punish the killers only Kojima holds on to the twisted dream to become a second rate boxer. Tsuda becomes a salaryman in a sexless relationship in which they spend the evenings watching old films (I spotted Metropolis and another which I can't place). A chance meeting between the two after many years awakens the anger that Kojima feels towards Tsuda, and the former begins making a play for Hizuru, Tsuda's girlfriend. This in turn leads Tsuda to become angry and he turns to boxing to get revenge on his former friend. Meanwhile Hikuru becomes a masochist, autonomous of both the males. The fairly graphic violence is mostly make up and is so over the top it is clearly to make the point mentioned in one of the other comments: violence is often the first recourse in a situation. However, as opposed to a film like Rocky where the violence leads to personal redemption, or an emotional force like Raging Bull, the violence is non-cathartic and meaningless. It is almost as if the characters are driven to behave in a certain way as a reflex reaction. Fast editing, powerful sound effects and blue colours mark the film out as Tsukamoto's style, and the transformation theme is another element that he returns to. Lots of fun for me, but the person I was with didn't have a clue what was going on. Make your own decision, but there is no relationship to Fight Club whatsoever: this is about human emotion, not social issues.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    This film will come through your screen, so beware it like every other film this master of cinema has made
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Bogey Man
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/1/2003
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Japanese film maker genius and multi-talent Shinya Tsukamoto's Tokyo Fist (Tokyo-ken, 1995) is as stunning and incredible experience as can be expected after seeing his two Tetsuo films in which a human body and metal (machine) became one with a horrific results. Tsukamoto's cinema is filled with hyper fast editing, shaking camera, fast forwards and every imaginable things to shock the viewer senses and make the weakest faint. Tokyo Fist is not any exception. Director himself plays Tsuda, a nerdish Japanese insurance salesman who has a beautiful girlfriend Hizuru (Kahori Fujii) whom with he lives seemingly peacefully and in love. But still it looks like Tsuda has some problems in his life and seems to be on the edge of his sanity. Soon his high school time friend Kojima arrives (played by the director's brother, K&ocirc;ji Tsukamoto) and he is a professional boxer and very fierce one. When he starts to be interested in Tsuda's girl, all physical and mental hell breaks loose as Tsuda gets an obsession to start to box himself, too, and Hizuru starts to have some very severe habits of body piercing and self mutilation. The infernal ride has begun and the viewer is not recommended to take it granted that he'll/she'll stomach the ride till the end because this is Tsukamoto. That means incredible power and impact straight to your face. The film is perhaps even wilder at some points than the first Tetsuo (1988) as the message and imagery is really heavy this time and the film is in color, too. The fists, the punches and the mayhem is always aimed straight to the camera, the viewer and audience, so the viewer will be on the edge of the seat for the whole time, and it all is of course at its most powerful when seen on the big screen. Tsukamoto has the talent to hammer and force his things to the skull and spinal cord of the viewer and he does it all with the magic of editing and cinematography, and definitely not least of Chu Ishikawa's pounding and merciless soundtrack which is here as effective and wonderful as in Tetsuo. The visuals are impressive and every twisted camera angle has its purpose and meaning as well as every bit of mist and darkness that is shed during the ride. The effect when he shakes his camera is something truly unique and definitely much more powerful way to depict the feelings and mental states of the characters than any dialogue ever could. Fast edits and unconventional usage of camera can be very irritating and needless when used without any real reason or to make the film look "stylish", but they can also be heart stoppingly effective when they have a cinematic meaning and the director could just simply write on the paper what the edit or camera angle means inside the film. Tetsuo is another great example of this and its black and white scenery is no less powerful than the colors in Tokyo Fist. Tokyo Fist is extremely menacing as there hardly are any peaceful moments and there's all the time some element there to make it clear that it is not peaceful even though it may look like it. The film's theme is about human nature and its jealous and weak sides as the characters can't live without taking or producing physical pain. The smashed faces and the scenes of surreal gore spurting at nightmarish anger are really something to make us ask why do the characters do it. Why cannot human nature solve things in other way than physical force and violence and how many of us dares to admit the brute sides of ourselves and accept them? And then of course keep them away and on the background. The final image is kind of "optimistic" but definitely no character gets out without the result and payment of their deeds. The film is also a good example for those who think that in Japanese cinema females are often on the background and weaker than men as the lead female in Tokyo Fist practically (and quite passively!) makes, at first so powerful and dominating, Kojima as her submissive slave. The film begins as in our familiar world in modern day Japan but it is not so long before Tsukamoto gives us the first glimpses of his surreal visions that are taken at their extremes in the incredible blood soaked nightmare finale "in the ring", a finale that is so fierce, kinetic and merciless piece of film making it just makes me appreciate and love Japanese cinema even more with its many sides never or very rarely paralleled in other world cinema. The gore and violence is sudden and almost unbearably shocking at times but the blood geysirs are not realistic nor they're meant to be; they are from the film's own world and as symbolic and surreal as in the Japanese samurai classic The Baby Cart aka Lone Wolf & Cub series in the early seventies, the first two parts of that series edited also into one feature film as Shogun Assassin (1980). Still none of these films manages to give the kind of impact in their violence or any other element than Tokyo Fist, but the surreal depiction of physical violence is pretty similar with Tsukamoto and The Baby Cart pieces. Perhaps only negative point I can find in Tokyo Fist is that some of the characters seem to develop a little too fast and they should have been little more motivated and restrained. For example, Tsuda seems to be completely mad already and is capable to rape his girlfriend any time so these kind of things should be explained little more carefully in order to make the piece perfect and the characters more real. Still the characters are very good and the message and theme gets delivered very effectively through their acts and there's absolutely no question that the visual magic and impact of Tsukamoto's deserves nothing less than praising and moments of pure amazement. Shinya Tsukamoto is the kind of Master of Cinema that he really deserves his name in the thanks section of the end credits of every young film maker's film who has got inspiration from his work. His films have the ability to make people faint, shock, turn the head off the screen and stun in their power and it all is done practically by himself as he works as an editor, cinematographer, art director etc. in his own films and thus expresses his visions. His films would be totally unforgettable when seen at least once in the big screen but fortunately the effect is still very strong on television, too. Tokyo Fist is among the most fierce, angry and honest rides of cinema I've ever experienced and everytime I see something from its maker, I cannot help but feel confused and amazed in front of Japan and its invaluable gifts during the centuries to the world of cinema. 9/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Japanese boxing film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    zombikev
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/10/2002
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    SPOILERS ARE LOCATED BELOW Many people will disagree with my opinion on this film. First off, many comments on this board mislead me into getting hold of it. The film is quite terrible. Sure, it has some good fighting scenes in it, and some pretty entertaining training scenes. But, the film just gets to be too chaotic. The plot is simple; the two friends become enemies over a woman. When they were youths, a girl that they had loved, was killed by street punks. They vowed to take up pro- boxing and to eventually avenge their friend. One friend takes the pro-boxing path and one takes a different stride. The film does address many good issues, but it is just bathed in distracting features. The music for one thing, was a joke. Many of the camera angles were poor, and many of the effects were just moronic. How many times can you watch a guy walk down the street through a rumble cam? And many things were repeated constantly; like the meat on the camera. I found the film interesting, but not compelling. This film related in now way to Fight Club.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Confusing boxing movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Andrew (vidgamer992@aol.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/7/2002
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I can't believe what other people are writing about this. DON'T BELIVE THEM. I rented this movie, almost bought it, and wanted a refund. I guess I had false expectations. Fight Club was amazing to me and I wanted some more. Too bad the most exciting aspect to Tokyo Fist was the box art. The movie's interesting plot was a whole love triangle between a boxer, his friend, and the friend's wife. The friend/geek becomes a boxer to win his girl back. The wife turns from housewife to Freaky, S&M psycho. Sounds great but nothing came together right for me. The movie is slow with the use of long shots throughout the film that just put me asleep. In terms of violence, it was pretty tame with cheesy effects. I like cheesy over-the-top violence but this was pretty sorry and sparse. I have seen better action scenes then this even on 80's American Action movies. If you are expecting action or a deep thought provoking experience, look for something else. People call it a masterpiece, but I am wondering if I rented the same movie that I did. The only way you can truly judge this film is watching it yourself. Be prepared for a serious letdown. I don't usually do this, but I felt the need to warn people about this much often overhyped movie.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The release of pent-up passions...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    poe426
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/2/2002
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    If there's a more dramatic context for human passion than fistfighting, I don't know what it is. From, say, GENTLEMAN JIM, THE HARDER THEY FALL, REQUIEM FOR A HEAVYWEIGHT (both versions), THE GREAT WHITE HOPE and FAT CITY to, say, HARD TIMES, ROCKY, THE GREATEST, RAGING BULL, and ALI, The Sweet Science has been used to examine The Human Condition, up close and personal; subtext is thrust to the forefront, and boxing as drama is as clear and as pure as it comes. TOKYO FIST follows in that tradition, but in a hyperkinetic way that is so over-the-top that it would make Sam Raimi blush. That's not a bad thing: pushing the cinematic envelope is sometimes necessary (audiences become jaded, and need that wake-up call). Director Tsukamoto isn't practicing his ten-second nap by any stretch of the imagination. And stretching the imagination is exactly what he does. We see a man get struck by a blow that opens his brow- and blood comes spraying forth in a way it never could in real life. It's an image so extreme that one can't help but laugh... but, in the context of the emotional cauldron that is TOKYO FIST, it's very apropos. It's the spewing forth of pent-up emotions that perhaps only a Japanese filmmaker could have conceived (which seems a sound assumption, as no other filmmaker has ever- to my knowledge- come so close to exposing raw nerve endings in a motion picture). TOKYO FIST is an amazing achievement.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Bone breaking, but more "human" than most movies.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Mike Foster
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/1/2002
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The comments of others comparing this movie to Raging Bull, Rocky and Fight Club could be misguided. This movie could have been about almost anything and the boxing is just a plot device . . . but a great one!!! . This movie is about people - most other movies are only about characters. The violence helps show just how angry a boring insurance guy (?) can get when something simple blows his world to pieces. It taunts the white-collar viewer by showing a white-collar man's wife getting easily tempted away by a physically muscular man. And the way she decends into perversity is a delightful rebuttal to the anodyne hold her husband had on her. Seeing a meaty, violent boxer intrude into a sterile, hideous modern existence/relationship forces us viewers to consider where our own humanist allegiances lie. The film says things about humanity that other films don't have the guts to say and rings totally true. If you can stomach the jagged aggressiveness of a movie but want the genuine article, see this film. I haven't had such a rough - but rewarding - ride since I last watched "In the Company of Men".
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A must-see, though not wuss-oriented
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Gene John
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I feel it's sort of a shame for such a movie to have less than at least 100 reviews on its page. So here I go, helping it out with this 22nd review, if I recall it correctly... First time I read a review on Tokyo Fist on another site, I didn't quite know what to expect from this movie. I was deep down in Cronenberg horror, but this title's plot and atmosphere (as described by a rather insipid reviewer, I guess) simply eluded my intuition. Luckily, I decided to give this a try, and it was one good decision. Tokyo Fist stands at a fine border between black comedy (and also really dry), surrealism, action and plain existential malaise. Tsukamoto's cam angles and effects act perfectly coherently with his intent, from emphasizing the ridiculous monotony and isolation in Tsuda's life to highlighting the irrational ferocity of his old "friend" that almost seems to turn night into day and day into night. Now, diving a bit into the predictable Fight Club comparison, Tokyo Fist is the severe, restrained, Eastern cousin of Palahniuk's novel's adaptation. There is no noticeable trace of emotion (maybe except anger), pathetism, or nihilist verbosity in the discourse of Tokyo Fist's characters. It's as if their existence and the duty of assuming various roles (and subsequent failures) squeezed their sentimental tendencies out of them and sent them into an abyss. There is no "love trio" in this movie, no matter how tempting it would be to call it that way. Its three main characters remain as insulated as can be, until the very end - a brilliantly open and non-conclusive end to a small, powerful drama of people not able to manage their remorse or lack of meaning without showering themselves in suffering. Beyond the plot, there are some really nice hyperkinetic boxing scenes in this movie, and the generous to parodic flows of blood and bruises might seem chuckle and nausea-inducing at the same time. I am afraid, though, that what I have said doesn't give this film the aura that it deserves. If you are not necessarily an adrenaline freak yet not an instant puker either, and want to see something done artistically indeed, you ought to give this at least one punch with the eye.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The rage of apathy
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    chaos-rampant
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/3/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is not a movie you experience with the brain, rather it's an assault on the senses. Some of my favourite cinema does that, and I'm always on the lookout for movies that call us to live through a certain experience, to vicariously sense the world as another person might. The ultimate joy is for me to be able to take out something that matters, an otherwise impossible view of the world in my livingroom that makes sense. The problem of Tokyo Fist is that it's packed with so much rage and annihilation yet aims it nowhere. The boxer characters are punching, but they're not punching outwards, at society, nor inwards at the soul, they're simply pummeling and being pummeled senseless. Senseless is an apt word here, for in Tokyo Fist the mind doesn't matter, and the human body is something to be destroyed, the senses torn from it and thrown in a bloody heap on a grimy floor. Tsukamoto can be seen beating his head in a bloody pulp against a wall, but that wall signifies nothing. The spurts of blood gushing from broken noses and deformed bonecheeks, the film celebrates with the comic verve of Sam Raimi. With time Tsukamoto would grow out of the techno angst of this period, but enabling the maturity of films like Vital, a certain youthful vitality had to be sacrificed in the process. I lament this because few directors dare make films like his, even Tsukamoto himself doesn't seem able to make them anymore. Fits of jealousy, miserable love triangles, personality changes, all these are trifle story points. What I take from Tokyo Fist is the aimlessness of violence, taken to the extreme because there's nothing to absorb it. Likely Tsukamoto grew up in a Japanese society of the 80's and 90's, like the rest of the world, stifled in the mire of apathy and complacency. People had the money to buy and the selection to buy from, but not the struggle with grand ideals. The resulting New Wave of his cinema is a New Wave of disillusionment turned against itself, a shell without a solid core to make it dream a better society. In this light, it makes sense to see Tsukamoto playing a young employee, fresh out of high school and already into a suit and a tie running errands for a faceless corporation, turning into a crazed animal for whom even love is a petulant obsession, another passing need to be consummated.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Complete gut punch soaked in blood and grit
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    TimothyFarrell
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/1/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Tokyo Fist" has garnered lots of comparisons to "Fight Club". While some of them are accurate, comparing them to one another doesn't to justice to either film, both of which are stunning achievements. They both involve salesmen getting in touch with their inner brutality, they both have similar cinematography, and the open ending to "Tokyo Fist" could be interpreted as a similar resolution to "Fight Club". Thats about it. Whereas "Fight Club" was a more accessible, operatic, and unsubtle dark comedy, "Tokyo Fist" is a complete gut punch soaked in blood and grit. Shinya Tsukamoto is a true original that deserves more recognition that he has received. The film's editing style is the same as Tsukamoto's earlier "Tetsuo", but in my mind "Tokyo Fist" works better because it adds a relatively linear storyline and interesting characters. Its fascinating to see that by the end every character has transformed to what the other one was at the beginning. The meaning of the film is subtle and holds up to repeat viewings. Its not as much of a mind bender as "Tetsuo" was, but its a much more well made film overall. It shows that Tsukamoto has progressed as a filmmaker without losing his edge. (8/10)
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Stomach-churning, but ultimately rewarding
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    desh79
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/12/2004
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Watching a movie by Shinya Tsukamoto is a bit like staring into the deepest pits of hell, or the darkest recesses of the male psyche, whichever way you want to put it. But then the two seem fairly synonymous, at least if the sheer visceral anger in Tokyo Fist is anything to go by. Those aware of Tsukamoto's feature-length debut Tetsuo (1988) will be familiar with the basic premise in Tokyo Fist; flawed relationship between man and woman is brutally disrupted by an outside element which challenges the protagonist to a potentially lethal, and eventually soul-destroying, duel. Similarly to other pioneers of horror (eg. Cronenberg, Miike), Tsukamoto chooses to use all kinds of repulsive visuals. Just to give you an idea, if a face almost literally falling off after a boxing match is too much for you, it's probably best to stay away from this film. However, the brutal imagery is not completely pointless. Tokyo Fist portrays male anger with such honesty that it is sometimes painful to watch, but that's really the point since violence is not something to be cooed at or to be admired (which is what many Hollywood movies seemingly aim to achieve, witness the way audiences are prompted to cheer for the good guy as he murders the baddie). The violence in Tokyo Fist is allegorical in nature, ie. it stands for something else than just simply fists flying: the inability between men and women (and, indeed, men and men) to understand each other ultimately leads to the kind of extreme violence we see on screen. This, ironically, makes Tokyo Fist a part of the great humanist tradition in Japanese cinema, alongside Rashomon and other such movies, because, even though it uses extreme imagery to make a point, it makes the same point all the same: if we relish in jealousy, revenge and anger we will only end up destroying each other, and ultimately ourselves. Does Hollywood ever deal with violence this eloquently? Also, as with Tetsuo, the characters in Tokyo Fist seem to live entirely in a world of their own. Many shots frame them either alone, or surrounded by an anonymous mass which fails to notice them or appreciate their presence (even as Tsuda stands in the middle of a shopping mall, his face beaten to a pulp). I can't think of another film-maker who sums up urban alienation as brilliantly as Tsukamoto does; the sheer contradiction of city life, in which a great mass of people are all huddled together at close range, and yet find themselves completely lonely and alienated from one another. For all intents and purposes, Tokyo Fist is a movie which requires a strong stomach and an open mind. But it's a great achievement all the same.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Anger, violence, pain and revenge drive the action
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    macdermotfergus
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/11/2004
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Tsukamoto in this film strips away excess to reveal a animal emotions which are then stretched to excess. In this film anger, violence, pain and revenge drive the action. Tsuda and Kojima witness the murder of a girl they like and while both vow to find and punish the killers only Kojima holds on to the twisted dream to become a second rate boxer. Tsuda becomes a salaryman in a sexless relationship in which they spend the evenings watching old films (I spotted Metropolis and another which I can't place). A chance meeting between the two after many years awakens the anger that Kojima feels towards Tsuda, and the former begins making a play for Hizuru, Tsuda's girlfriend. This in turn leads Tsuda to become angry and he turns to boxing to get revenge on his former friend. Meanwhile Hikuru becomes a masochist, autonomous of both the males. The fairly graphic violence is mostly make up and is so over the top it is clearly to make the point mentioned in one of the other comments: violence is often the first recourse in a situation. However, as opposed to a film like Rocky where the violence leads to personal redemption, or an emotional force like Raging Bull, the violence is non-cathartic and meaningless. It is almost as if the characters are driven to behave in a certain way as a reflex reaction. Fast editing, powerful sound effects and blue colours mark the film out as Tsukamoto's style, and the transformation theme is another element that he returns to. Lots of fun for me, but the person I was with didn't have a clue what was going on. Make your own decision, but there is no relationship to Fight Club whatsoever: this is about human emotion, not social issues.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    This film will come through your screen, so beware it like every other film this master of cinema has made
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Bogey Man
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/1/2003
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Japanese film maker genius and multi-talent Shinya Tsukamoto's Tokyo Fist (Tokyo-ken, 1995) is as stunning and incredible experience as can be expected after seeing his two Tetsuo films in which a human body and metal (machine) became one with a horrific results. Tsukamoto's cinema is filled with hyper fast editing, shaking camera, fast forwards and every imaginable things to shock the viewer senses and make the weakest faint. Tokyo Fist is not any exception. Director himself plays Tsuda, a nerdish Japanese insurance salesman who has a beautiful girlfriend Hizuru (Kahori Fujii) whom with he lives seemingly peacefully and in love. But still it looks like Tsuda has some problems in his life and seems to be on the edge of his sanity. Soon his high school time friend Kojima arrives (played by the director's brother, K&ocirc;ji Tsukamoto) and he is a professional boxer and very fierce one. When he starts to be interested in Tsuda's girl, all physical and mental hell breaks loose as Tsuda gets an obsession to start to box himself, too, and Hizuru starts to have some very severe habits of body piercing and self mutilation. The infernal ride has begun and the viewer is not recommended to take it granted that he'll/she'll stomach the ride till the end because this is Tsukamoto. That means incredible power and impact straight to your face. The film is perhaps even wilder at some points than the first Tetsuo (1988) as the message and imagery is really heavy this time and the film is in color, too. The fists, the punches and the mayhem is always aimed straight to the camera, the viewer and audience, so the viewer will be on the edge of the seat for the whole time, and it all is of course at its most powerful when seen on the big screen. Tsukamoto has the talent to hammer and force his things to the skull and spinal cord of the viewer and he does it all with the magic of editing and cinematography, and definitely not least of Chu Ishikawa's pounding and merciless soundtrack which is here as effective and wonderful as in Tetsuo. The visuals are impressive and every twisted camera angle has its purpose and meaning as well as every bit of mist and darkness that is shed during the ride. The effect when he shakes his camera is something truly unique and definitely much more powerful way to depict the feelings and mental states of the characters than any dialogue ever could. Fast edits and unconventional usage of camera can be very irritating and needless when used without any real reason or to make the film look "stylish", but they can also be heart stoppingly effective when they have a cinematic meaning and the director could just simply write on the paper what the edit or camera angle means inside the film. Tetsuo is another great example of this and its black and white scenery is no less powerful than the colors in Tokyo Fist. Tokyo Fist is extremely menacing as there hardly are any peaceful moments and there's all the time some element there to make it clear that it is not peaceful even though it may look like it. The film's theme is about human nature and its jealous and weak sides as the characters can't live without taking or producing physical pain. The smashed faces and the scenes of surreal gore spurting at nightmarish anger are really something to make us ask why do the characters do it. Why cannot human nature solve things in other way than physical force and violence and how many of us dares to admit the brute sides of ourselves and accept them? And then of course keep them away and on the background. The final image is kind of "optimistic" but definitely no character gets out without the result and payment of their deeds. The film is also a good example for those who think that in Japanese cinema females are often on the background and weaker than men as the lead female in Tokyo Fist practically (and quite passively!) makes, at first so powerful and dominating, Kojima as her submissive slave. The film begins as in our familiar world in modern day Japan but it is not so long before Tsukamoto gives us the first glimpses of his surreal visions that are taken at their extremes in the incredible blood soaked nightmare finale "in the ring", a finale that is so fierce, kinetic and merciless piece of film making it just makes me appreciate and love Japanese cinema even more with its many sides never or very rarely paralleled in other world cinema. The gore and violence is sudden and almost unbearably shocking at times but the blood geysirs are not realistic nor they're meant to be; they are from the film's own world and as symbolic and surreal as in the Japanese samurai classic The Baby Cart aka Lone Wolf & Cub series in the early seventies, the first two parts of that series edited also into one feature film as Shogun Assassin (1980). Still none of these films manages to give the kind of impact in their violence or any other element than Tokyo Fist, but the surreal depiction of physical violence is pretty similar with Tsukamoto and The Baby Cart pieces. Perhaps only negative point I can find in Tokyo Fist is that some of the characters seem to develop a little too fast and they should have been little more motivated and restrained. For example, Tsuda seems to be completely mad already and is capable to rape his girlfriend any time so these kind of things should be explained little more carefully in order to make the piece perfect and the characters more real. Still the characters are very good and the message and theme gets delivered very effectively through their acts and there's absolutely no question that the visual magic and impact of Tsukamoto's deserves nothing less than praising and moments of pure amazement. Shinya Tsukamoto is the kind of Master of Cinema that he really deserves his name in the thanks section of the end credits of every young film maker's film who has got inspiration from his work. His films have the ability to make people faint, shock, turn the head off the screen and stun in their power and it all is done practically by himself as he works as an editor, cinematographer, art director etc. in his own films and thus expresses his visions. His films would be totally unforgettable when seen at least once in the big screen but fortunately the effect is still very strong on television, too. Tokyo Fist is among the most fierce, angry and honest rides of cinema I've ever experienced and everytime I see something from its maker, I cannot help but feel confused and amazed in front of Japan and its invaluable gifts during the centuries to the world of cinema. 9/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Japanese boxing film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    zombikev
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/10/2002
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    SPOILERS ARE LOCATED BELOW Many people will disagree with my opinion on this film. First off, many comments on this board mislead me into getting hold of it. The film is quite terrible. Sure, it has some good fighting scenes in it, and some pretty entertaining training scenes. But, the film just gets to be too chaotic. The plot is simple; the two friends become enemies over a woman. When they were youths, a girl that they had loved, was killed by street punks. They vowed to take up pro- boxing and to eventually avenge their friend. One friend takes the pro-boxing path and one takes a different stride. The film does address many good issues, but it is just bathed in distracting features. The music for one thing, was a joke. Many of the camera angles were poor, and many of the effects were just moronic. How many times can you watch a guy walk down the street through a rumble cam? And many things were repeated constantly; like the meat on the camera. I found the film interesting, but not compelling. This film related in now way to Fight Club.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Confusing boxing movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Andrew (vidgamer992@aol.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/7/2002
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I can't believe what other people are writing about this. DON'T BELIVE THEM. I rented this movie, almost bought it, and wanted a refund. I guess I had false expectations. Fight Club was amazing to me and I wanted some more. Too bad the most exciting aspect to Tokyo Fist was the box art. The movie's interesting plot was a whole love triangle between a boxer, his friend, and the friend's wife. The friend/geek becomes a boxer to win his girl back. The wife turns from housewife to Freaky, S&M psycho. Sounds great but nothing came together right for me. The movie is slow with the use of long shots throughout the film that just put me asleep. In terms of violence, it was pretty tame with cheesy effects. I like cheesy over-the-top violence but this was pretty sorry and sparse. I have seen better action scenes then this even on 80's American Action movies. If you are expecting action or a deep thought provoking experience, look for something else. People call it a masterpiece, but I am wondering if I rented the same movie that I did. The only way you can truly judge this film is watching it yourself. Be prepared for a serious letdown. I don't usually do this, but I felt the need to warn people about this much often overhyped movie.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The release of pent-up passions...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    poe426
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/2/2002
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    If there's a more dramatic context for human passion than fistfighting, I don't know what it is. From, say, GENTLEMAN JIM, THE HARDER THEY FALL, REQUIEM FOR A HEAVYWEIGHT (both versions), THE GREAT WHITE HOPE and FAT CITY to, say, HARD TIMES, ROCKY, THE GREATEST, RAGING BULL, and ALI, The Sweet Science has been used to examine The Human Condition, up close and personal; subtext is thrust to the forefront, and boxing as drama is as clear and as pure as it comes. TOKYO FIST follows in that tradition, but in a hyperkinetic way that is so over-the-top that it would make Sam Raimi blush. That's not a bad thing: pushing the cinematic envelope is sometimes necessary (audiences become jaded, and need that wake-up call). Director Tsukamoto isn't practicing his ten-second nap by any stretch of the imagination. And stretching the imagination is exactly what he does. We see a man get struck by a blow that opens his brow- and blood comes spraying forth in a way it never could in real life. It's an image so extreme that one can't help but laugh... but, in the context of the emotional cauldron that is TOKYO FIST, it's very apropos. It's the spewing forth of pent-up emotions that perhaps only a Japanese filmmaker could have conceived (which seems a sound assumption, as no other filmmaker has ever- to my knowledge- come so close to exposing raw nerve endings in a motion picture). TOKYO FIST is an amazing achievement.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Bone breaking, but more "human" than most movies.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Mike Foster
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/1/2002
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The comments of others comparing this movie to Raging Bull, Rocky and Fight Club could be misguided. This movie could have been about almost anything and the boxing is just a plot device . . . but a great one!!! . This movie is about people - most other movies are only about characters. The violence helps show just how angry a boring insurance guy (?) can get when something simple blows his world to pieces. It taunts the white-collar viewer by showing a white-collar man's wife getting easily tempted away by a physically muscular man. And the way she decends into perversity is a delightful rebuttal to the anodyne hold her husband had on her. Seeing a meaty, violent boxer intrude into a sterile, hideous modern existence/relationship forces us viewers to consider where our own humanist allegiances lie. The film says things about humanity that other films don't have the guts to say and rings totally true. If you can stomach the jagged aggressiveness of a movie but want the genuine article, see this film. I haven't had such a rough - but rewarding - ride since I last watched "In the Company of Men".
   </conteudo>
  </review>
 </reviews>
</filme>
