<filme>
 <id>
  1624
 </id>
 <imdburl>
  http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0118744
 </imdburl>
 <ano>
  1998
 </ano>
 <titulo>
  Segredo de Sangue
 </titulo>
 <rating>
  5.0
 </rating>
 <sinopse>
  Helen is the young girlfriend of good-looking Jackson Baring. When Helen gets pregnant and marries Jackson, they decide to move to his hometown, Kilronan, and have a baby there. But his ... &nbsp;&raquo;
 </sinopse>
 <storyline>
  Helen is the young girlfriend of good-looking Jackson Baring. When Helen gets pregnant and marries Jackson, they decide to move to his hometown, Kilronan, and have a baby there. But his mother Martha, who lives there, starts to do weird things, and obviously she's not too friendly to Helen.
 </storyline>
 <generos>
  <genero>
   Drama
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Thriller
  </genero>
 </generos>
 <keywords>
  <keyword>
   family relationships
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   grandmother grandson relationship
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   jealousy
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   attempted murder
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   in laws
  </keyword>
 </keywords>
 <diretores>
  <diretor>
   Jonathan Darby
  </diretor>
 </diretores>
 <escritores>
  <escritor>
   Jonathan Darby
  </escritor>
  <escritor>
   Jane Rusconi
  </escritor>
 </escritores>
 <atores>
  <ator>
   Jessica Lange
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Gwyneth Paltrow
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Johnathon Schaech
  </ator>
 </atores>
 <reviews>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Great suspense thriller/drama!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    DeeDeex10
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I thought this was a great suspense thriller. Both Gweneth Paltrow and Jessica Lange were fantastic. As a horse owner, I tend to nit-pick inaccurate "goofs" pertaining to the use of horses, as their usually is, but in this one, I didn't notice any. I loved the interaction with the Grandmother and one had to wonder throughout the film how the grandmother was going to portray a role in the outcome. As a woman, a Mother, a wife and who had a domineering Mother-in-law, I kept rooting for Paltrow's character to smack Lang's character and do what needed to be done, not to mention what I would have wanted to do while feeling I had to suck up to my own M.I.L. to keep a marriage intact.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Good film despite the obvious clich&eacute;s. Acting manages to save it from the total obscurity
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Rodrigo Amaro (rodrigo882008@hotmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/9/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Hush" is the kind of film that's so easy that it should work right on the first view but it's not the case. I remember watching it a few years ago and finding one of the most boring things I've ever seen except for the outstanding acting of Jessica Lange. Fate pulls its strings sometimes and one of those nights when you're desperate for something to show up on TV and there you go, there was this and I got a little gripped into seeing it again, this time paying more attention to details. Well, it turned out to be quite a good film, undeserving the low rating that is getting now. An twisted and thrilling tale about acceptance and skeletons in the closet? You can say that. Gwyneth Paltrow plays the lovable Helen, a successful and beautiful woman, loved by the a man who's also both of the fore-mentioned qualities, the great Jackson (Johnathon Schaech) of the powerful Baring family. But he has a mother, the surprising Martha (Jessica Lange) of whom Helen always tries to please to the best since Jackson and his mom has some strong bonds between them and she wants to be part of this quite perfect family. Habitual to flicks of the same caliber, there's secrets, tension between both women and a certain disdain the old lady feels for the younger and it's up to Helen to discover what's the problem with the Baring family. Her only great ally is Jackson's grandmother (Nina Foch, excellent), father of Martha's late husband, and keeper of some family secrets that can storm a big mess in everyone's lives. There isn't much to be said about "Hush" except that the cast is great, even though they're not at their greatest moment. Except Lange and Foch who are brilliant, and the memorable special appearance of Hal Holbrook as the doctor. But it's Lange who steals the show playing an pitiful villain, sometimes adorable, other times really cruel but most of the time always in control of the situation. The plot should include more characters to make this more tense and less concentrated in those three main characters. The relationship between Jackson and Martha could've go to more controversial ways, cause everything seems to indicate that (the scene where he's covered in mud and she cleans him, they're like pretending it's just a silly joke. There's something going on there). I know Jonathan Darby has directed better films (like the criminally underrated and almost forgotten "The Enemy Within" with Forest Whitaker) but what he makes his here is quite good, never cheap and at the most entertaining to watch for its cast and the beautiful cinematography. 8/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Jessica Lange Makes It Worth Watching, But She Can't Make It Good
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    sddavis63 (revsdd@gmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/6/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Even way back in 1998, the question would have been a valid one: does the world really need yet another of the "mother in law hates the new daughter in law for taking her son away from her so she sets out to destroy her" movies? Really - hasn't this been done to death? Well, in 1998 somebody decided that, indeed, another one was needed - and the end result was this rather unoriginal story that doesn't do anything that other movies of this type haven't already done. Frankly, the only thing that saved this was the performance of Jessica Lange as Martha Baring, the obsessively jealous and controlling mother in law. Lange, I thought, did a good job with her character. At first, Martha seems almost normal and welcoming of her new daughter in law Helen (Gwyneth Paltrow). But she gradually becomes more and more menacing and by the end borders on the insane, and that was all brilliantly pulled off by Lange, who made an otherwise bland movie worth watching. Unfortunately, one superb performance can't save an otherwise weak movie. (4/10)
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    From a premise like this, I expected more and better
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    raisleygordon
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/1/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    In theory, "Hush" sounds like an ideal movie, but I'm afraid the results leave a lot to be desired. How in the world did these actors, especially Gwyneth Paltrow, get duped into participating in this project? Everyone is phoning in their performances here. This is a movie you might as well be listening to on the radio. The "story", not that there is much of one, is this: A New York couple, Jackson and Helen, are visiting his mother, Martha, for the holidays. She smokes, drinks, and tries to tear this couple apart (from what I can recall, anyway). The closest any of these characters get to being menacing, is when Helen (Jessica Lange's character) changes the temperature in the hot tub her mother is bathing in at the spa (or wherever the tub is). I didn't buy the story, I wasn't engaged, and I didn't care about the characters (or what would eventually happen to them). The things that happen, happen simply because the screenplay requires it to. ** out of ****
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Oedipal Mayhem
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    JasparLamarCrabb
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/11/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Unbelievably bad. Writer/director Jonathan Darby concocts a ridiculous southern fried horror tale. Jessica Lange, channeling both Blanche Dubois AND Baby Jane Hudson, runs a horse farm and is visited by son Johnathon Schaech and new bride Gwyneth Paltrow. Oedipal mayhem ensues. Lange, unable to let Schaech go, terrorizes Paltrow. By the time Paltrow winds up in bed giving birth the film reaches a frenzied level of camp. It's always a curiosity how good actors end up in such dreck. It's a wonder if Lange, Schaech and Paltrow read the script, a half-baked amalgamation of Tennessee Williams and Tobe Hooper. While the supporting cast is populated with the dependable Hal Holbrook, Nina Foch, and Debi Mazer, they bring very little to the film. Foch is used merely to explain the motives of the deranged Lange. Lange's performance takes it's place next to Faye Dunaway's Joan Crawford in the pantheon of American Kabuki.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Plot holes a bus could drive through
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    (tottenhamtillidie@gmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/10/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This could have been so much better and is one of those movies where a lack of direction comes to the fore. Its not very suspenseful when the director is unable to build suspense, case-in- point the end where Jackson does an about turn from being the doting son to never wanting to see his mother again quicker than you could say "cut". I'm also still trying to figure out how Jackson drove from a packed Churchill Downs racecourse in Kentucky to the farm in virginia in minutes (it would take me that long to find the car in the car park)! Some good points were the ageless Jessica Lange who was fairly convincing as the evil, scheming mother and Paltrow fans will be happy to know they can use the pause button to see her in her birthday suit. No doubt, this movie is in the $5 bins at walmart by now, leave it in there, this really isn't worth your time or money.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Classic Hitchcockian Style Thriller
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    shawn_m_roeder
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/11/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I thoroughly enjoyed this movie the first time I saw it ten years ago. The film reminded me of some of my favorite Hitchcock flicks, namely Shadow of a Doubt and Notorious. The story builds slowly and generates just enough paranoia of impending danger to keep the audience interested. By the time everything comes together, the audience has an emotional investment in the main character and experiences genuine anxiety at her ordeal. This is so refreshingly different from the movies that slice and dice cardboard characters in an attempt to generate suspense. After seeing how poorly people have reacted to this film, I revisited it to see if my memory served me correctly. My assessment remains the same. Jessica Lange gives a stellar performance as the homicidal control freak. Gwyneth Paltrow is easy to empathize with as the paranoid daughter-in-law. Nina Foch is hysterical as the cheerful old lady who knows all the family secrets. I have met each of these characters in the real world. The only reason I would hesitate to call this a masterpiece is because there is no Hitchcock cameo. Still, this is a worthy imitation of the master's work.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Rarely do I...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Lee Eisenberg (eisenberg.lee@gmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/4/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    ...call a movie gross, but I feel that I have to call "Hush" just that. I couldn't see that the movie had any purpose except to show the nastiest things possible. Jessica Lange and Gwyneth Paltrow must have been in dire financial straits if they chose to star in this. Now, I should say that I don't consider this a bad movie. Truth be told, Jessica Lange made a really creepy character. But seriously folks, if you've seen any other movies starring either woman, then it should be more than obvious that they've both starred in far superior movies. Could the people behind this movie have done anything to improve it? I don't know. I personally wish that they would stop making these sorts of movies. Look, just avoid this one. There's no reason to watch it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not even bad enough to be good
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mrlocco
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/3/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    An absolutely awful movie I watched only because of Gwyneth Paltrow who I had previously admired greatly. Not so much now. Shame on her for being party to this load of rubbish. It started off quite promisingly, well actually the wheels didn't start coming off until burglary/attack on Paltrow when it was blatantly and painfully obvious that the mother had arranged this. No explanation of the reason for this. Things went rapidly downhill from there, yes the scenery was attractive if you like that sort of thing but credit for that is due to mother nature not the cinematographer. I think the second worst aspect, after the terrible story line, was Lange's acting. Incidentally, Oxytocin is rendered useless in the digestive system and is only effective if absorbed through the mucous membranes or given intravenously, and even then has a half life of 3 minutes I believe, so it would be totally useless taken in food. Also if my mother-in-law had treated me like that when I was in labour and then tried to kill me with a lethal injection I would not have stayed in the house even for a dramatic denouement the next morning. Then the son, after being led around by the nose by the evil mother does a complete about face in the space of a few minutes on the strength of his wifes unsubstantiated accusations. A rubbish movie best avoided.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Good work in a poor framework
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    dsvoss
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/12/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Gwyneth Paltrow's character gets pregnant and marries into a messed-up family. When the weirdness starts to look dangerous, the audience has lots of suspects. Mom might be neurotic and even a little bit deranged, but it's not clear she's psychotic enough to be responsible; the truly nasty stuff is always done off screen. Her son behaves oddly at times, and there's so much talk about horse breeding that one can imagine a plausible conspiracy involving any combination of the peripheral characters as well. The only thing certain is that Paltrow and her baby had better watch out. It's not a bad thriller, contrary to many of the reviews I've read. Jessica Lange nicely takes us through Mom's rapid mood swings, keeping the audience uncomfortable and unsettled. The other significant characters are ambiguous enough that, while putting forward pleasant faces, they all seem to be hiding a dark side. And the visual images are superb; definitely NOT B-movie quality stuff. The main problem is the fragmented nature of the plot. Some points are developed at length, but other developments needing explanation fly by -- and if you watch the trailer, which contained lots of scenes that never appeared in the movie, the reason for the haste must be that tons of material landed on the cutting-room floor. Seems as though the director let this horse get away from him. But if you can focus on the uncertainty surrounding who is really manipulating Paltrow and why they are doing it, you can enjoy this one.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Great suspense thriller/drama!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    DeeDeex10
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I thought this was a great suspense thriller. Both Gweneth Paltrow and Jessica Lange were fantastic. As a horse owner, I tend to nit-pick inaccurate "goofs" pertaining to the use of horses, as their usually is, but in this one, I didn't notice any. I loved the interaction with the Grandmother and one had to wonder throughout the film how the grandmother was going to portray a role in the outcome. As a woman, a Mother, a wife and who had a domineering Mother-in-law, I kept rooting for Paltrow's character to smack Lang's character and do what needed to be done, not to mention what I would have wanted to do while feeling I had to suck up to my own M.I.L. to keep a marriage intact.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Good film despite the obvious clich&eacute;s. Acting manages to save it from the total obscurity
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Rodrigo Amaro (rodrigo882008@hotmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/9/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Hush" is the kind of film that's so easy that it should work right on the first view but it's not the case. I remember watching it a few years ago and finding one of the most boring things I've ever seen except for the outstanding acting of Jessica Lange. Fate pulls its strings sometimes and one of those nights when you're desperate for something to show up on TV and there you go, there was this and I got a little gripped into seeing it again, this time paying more attention to details. Well, it turned out to be quite a good film, undeserving the low rating that is getting now. An twisted and thrilling tale about acceptance and skeletons in the closet? You can say that. Gwyneth Paltrow plays the lovable Helen, a successful and beautiful woman, loved by the a man who's also both of the fore-mentioned qualities, the great Jackson (Johnathon Schaech) of the powerful Baring family. But he has a mother, the surprising Martha (Jessica Lange) of whom Helen always tries to please to the best since Jackson and his mom has some strong bonds between them and she wants to be part of this quite perfect family. Habitual to flicks of the same caliber, there's secrets, tension between both women and a certain disdain the old lady feels for the younger and it's up to Helen to discover what's the problem with the Baring family. Her only great ally is Jackson's grandmother (Nina Foch, excellent), father of Martha's late husband, and keeper of some family secrets that can storm a big mess in everyone's lives. There isn't much to be said about "Hush" except that the cast is great, even though they're not at their greatest moment. Except Lange and Foch who are brilliant, and the memorable special appearance of Hal Holbrook as the doctor. But it's Lange who steals the show playing an pitiful villain, sometimes adorable, other times really cruel but most of the time always in control of the situation. The plot should include more characters to make this more tense and less concentrated in those three main characters. The relationship between Jackson and Martha could've go to more controversial ways, cause everything seems to indicate that (the scene where he's covered in mud and she cleans him, they're like pretending it's just a silly joke. There's something going on there). I know Jonathan Darby has directed better films (like the criminally underrated and almost forgotten "The Enemy Within" with Forest Whitaker) but what he makes his here is quite good, never cheap and at the most entertaining to watch for its cast and the beautiful cinematography. 8/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Jessica Lange Makes It Worth Watching, But She Can't Make It Good
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    sddavis63 (revsdd@gmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/6/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Even way back in 1998, the question would have been a valid one: does the world really need yet another of the "mother in law hates the new daughter in law for taking her son away from her so she sets out to destroy her" movies? Really - hasn't this been done to death? Well, in 1998 somebody decided that, indeed, another one was needed - and the end result was this rather unoriginal story that doesn't do anything that other movies of this type haven't already done. Frankly, the only thing that saved this was the performance of Jessica Lange as Martha Baring, the obsessively jealous and controlling mother in law. Lange, I thought, did a good job with her character. At first, Martha seems almost normal and welcoming of her new daughter in law Helen (Gwyneth Paltrow). But she gradually becomes more and more menacing and by the end borders on the insane, and that was all brilliantly pulled off by Lange, who made an otherwise bland movie worth watching. Unfortunately, one superb performance can't save an otherwise weak movie. (4/10)
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    From a premise like this, I expected more and better
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    raisleygordon
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/1/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    In theory, "Hush" sounds like an ideal movie, but I'm afraid the results leave a lot to be desired. How in the world did these actors, especially Gwyneth Paltrow, get duped into participating in this project? Everyone is phoning in their performances here. This is a movie you might as well be listening to on the radio. The "story", not that there is much of one, is this: A New York couple, Jackson and Helen, are visiting his mother, Martha, for the holidays. She smokes, drinks, and tries to tear this couple apart (from what I can recall, anyway). The closest any of these characters get to being menacing, is when Helen (Jessica Lange's character) changes the temperature in the hot tub her mother is bathing in at the spa (or wherever the tub is). I didn't buy the story, I wasn't engaged, and I didn't care about the characters (or what would eventually happen to them). The things that happen, happen simply because the screenplay requires it to. ** out of ****
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Oedipal Mayhem
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    JasparLamarCrabb
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/11/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Unbelievably bad. Writer/director Jonathan Darby concocts a ridiculous southern fried horror tale. Jessica Lange, channeling both Blanche Dubois AND Baby Jane Hudson, runs a horse farm and is visited by son Johnathon Schaech and new bride Gwyneth Paltrow. Oedipal mayhem ensues. Lange, unable to let Schaech go, terrorizes Paltrow. By the time Paltrow winds up in bed giving birth the film reaches a frenzied level of camp. It's always a curiosity how good actors end up in such dreck. It's a wonder if Lange, Schaech and Paltrow read the script, a half-baked amalgamation of Tennessee Williams and Tobe Hooper. While the supporting cast is populated with the dependable Hal Holbrook, Nina Foch, and Debi Mazer, they bring very little to the film. Foch is used merely to explain the motives of the deranged Lange. Lange's performance takes it's place next to Faye Dunaway's Joan Crawford in the pantheon of American Kabuki.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Plot holes a bus could drive through
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    (tottenhamtillidie@gmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/10/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This could have been so much better and is one of those movies where a lack of direction comes to the fore. Its not very suspenseful when the director is unable to build suspense, case-in- point the end where Jackson does an about turn from being the doting son to never wanting to see his mother again quicker than you could say "cut". I'm also still trying to figure out how Jackson drove from a packed Churchill Downs racecourse in Kentucky to the farm in virginia in minutes (it would take me that long to find the car in the car park)! Some good points were the ageless Jessica Lange who was fairly convincing as the evil, scheming mother and Paltrow fans will be happy to know they can use the pause button to see her in her birthday suit. No doubt, this movie is in the $5 bins at walmart by now, leave it in there, this really isn't worth your time or money.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Classic Hitchcockian Style Thriller
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    shawn_m_roeder
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/11/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I thoroughly enjoyed this movie the first time I saw it ten years ago. The film reminded me of some of my favorite Hitchcock flicks, namely Shadow of a Doubt and Notorious. The story builds slowly and generates just enough paranoia of impending danger to keep the audience interested. By the time everything comes together, the audience has an emotional investment in the main character and experiences genuine anxiety at her ordeal. This is so refreshingly different from the movies that slice and dice cardboard characters in an attempt to generate suspense. After seeing how poorly people have reacted to this film, I revisited it to see if my memory served me correctly. My assessment remains the same. Jessica Lange gives a stellar performance as the homicidal control freak. Gwyneth Paltrow is easy to empathize with as the paranoid daughter-in-law. Nina Foch is hysterical as the cheerful old lady who knows all the family secrets. I have met each of these characters in the real world. The only reason I would hesitate to call this a masterpiece is because there is no Hitchcock cameo. Still, this is a worthy imitation of the master's work.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Rarely do I...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Lee Eisenberg (eisenberg.lee@gmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/4/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    ...call a movie gross, but I feel that I have to call "Hush" just that. I couldn't see that the movie had any purpose except to show the nastiest things possible. Jessica Lange and Gwyneth Paltrow must have been in dire financial straits if they chose to star in this. Now, I should say that I don't consider this a bad movie. Truth be told, Jessica Lange made a really creepy character. But seriously folks, if you've seen any other movies starring either woman, then it should be more than obvious that they've both starred in far superior movies. Could the people behind this movie have done anything to improve it? I don't know. I personally wish that they would stop making these sorts of movies. Look, just avoid this one. There's no reason to watch it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not even bad enough to be good
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mrlocco
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/3/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    An absolutely awful movie I watched only because of Gwyneth Paltrow who I had previously admired greatly. Not so much now. Shame on her for being party to this load of rubbish. It started off quite promisingly, well actually the wheels didn't start coming off until burglary/attack on Paltrow when it was blatantly and painfully obvious that the mother had arranged this. No explanation of the reason for this. Things went rapidly downhill from there, yes the scenery was attractive if you like that sort of thing but credit for that is due to mother nature not the cinematographer. I think the second worst aspect, after the terrible story line, was Lange's acting. Incidentally, Oxytocin is rendered useless in the digestive system and is only effective if absorbed through the mucous membranes or given intravenously, and even then has a half life of 3 minutes I believe, so it would be totally useless taken in food. Also if my mother-in-law had treated me like that when I was in labour and then tried to kill me with a lethal injection I would not have stayed in the house even for a dramatic denouement the next morning. Then the son, after being led around by the nose by the evil mother does a complete about face in the space of a few minutes on the strength of his wifes unsubstantiated accusations. A rubbish movie best avoided.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Good work in a poor framework
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    dsvoss
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/12/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Gwyneth Paltrow's character gets pregnant and marries into a messed-up family. When the weirdness starts to look dangerous, the audience has lots of suspects. Mom might be neurotic and even a little bit deranged, but it's not clear she's psychotic enough to be responsible; the truly nasty stuff is always done off screen. Her son behaves oddly at times, and there's so much talk about horse breeding that one can imagine a plausible conspiracy involving any combination of the peripheral characters as well. The only thing certain is that Paltrow and her baby had better watch out. It's not a bad thriller, contrary to many of the reviews I've read. Jessica Lange nicely takes us through Mom's rapid mood swings, keeping the audience uncomfortable and unsettled. The other significant characters are ambiguous enough that, while putting forward pleasant faces, they all seem to be hiding a dark side. And the visual images are superb; definitely NOT B-movie quality stuff. The main problem is the fragmented nature of the plot. Some points are developed at length, but other developments needing explanation fly by -- and if you watch the trailer, which contained lots of scenes that never appeared in the movie, the reason for the haste must be that tons of material landed on the cutting-room floor. Seems as though the director let this horse get away from him. But if you can focus on the uncertainty surrounding who is really manipulating Paltrow and why they are doing it, you can enjoy this one.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Great suspense thriller/drama!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    DeeDeex10
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I thought this was a great suspense thriller. Both Gweneth Paltrow and Jessica Lange were fantastic. As a horse owner, I tend to nit-pick inaccurate "goofs" pertaining to the use of horses, as their usually is, but in this one, I didn't notice any. I loved the interaction with the Grandmother and one had to wonder throughout the film how the grandmother was going to portray a role in the outcome. As a woman, a Mother, a wife and who had a domineering Mother-in-law, I kept rooting for Paltrow's character to smack Lang's character and do what needed to be done, not to mention what I would have wanted to do while feeling I had to suck up to my own M.I.L. to keep a marriage intact.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Good film despite the obvious clich&eacute;s. Acting manages to save it from the total obscurity
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Rodrigo Amaro (rodrigo882008@hotmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/9/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Hush" is the kind of film that's so easy that it should work right on the first view but it's not the case. I remember watching it a few years ago and finding one of the most boring things I've ever seen except for the outstanding acting of Jessica Lange. Fate pulls its strings sometimes and one of those nights when you're desperate for something to show up on TV and there you go, there was this and I got a little gripped into seeing it again, this time paying more attention to details. Well, it turned out to be quite a good film, undeserving the low rating that is getting now. An twisted and thrilling tale about acceptance and skeletons in the closet? You can say that. Gwyneth Paltrow plays the lovable Helen, a successful and beautiful woman, loved by the a man who's also both of the fore-mentioned qualities, the great Jackson (Johnathon Schaech) of the powerful Baring family. But he has a mother, the surprising Martha (Jessica Lange) of whom Helen always tries to please to the best since Jackson and his mom has some strong bonds between them and she wants to be part of this quite perfect family. Habitual to flicks of the same caliber, there's secrets, tension between both women and a certain disdain the old lady feels for the younger and it's up to Helen to discover what's the problem with the Baring family. Her only great ally is Jackson's grandmother (Nina Foch, excellent), father of Martha's late husband, and keeper of some family secrets that can storm a big mess in everyone's lives. There isn't much to be said about "Hush" except that the cast is great, even though they're not at their greatest moment. Except Lange and Foch who are brilliant, and the memorable special appearance of Hal Holbrook as the doctor. But it's Lange who steals the show playing an pitiful villain, sometimes adorable, other times really cruel but most of the time always in control of the situation. The plot should include more characters to make this more tense and less concentrated in those three main characters. The relationship between Jackson and Martha could've go to more controversial ways, cause everything seems to indicate that (the scene where he's covered in mud and she cleans him, they're like pretending it's just a silly joke. There's something going on there). I know Jonathan Darby has directed better films (like the criminally underrated and almost forgotten "The Enemy Within" with Forest Whitaker) but what he makes his here is quite good, never cheap and at the most entertaining to watch for its cast and the beautiful cinematography. 8/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Jessica Lange Makes It Worth Watching, But She Can't Make It Good
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    sddavis63 (revsdd@gmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/6/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Even way back in 1998, the question would have been a valid one: does the world really need yet another of the "mother in law hates the new daughter in law for taking her son away from her so she sets out to destroy her" movies? Really - hasn't this been done to death? Well, in 1998 somebody decided that, indeed, another one was needed - and the end result was this rather unoriginal story that doesn't do anything that other movies of this type haven't already done. Frankly, the only thing that saved this was the performance of Jessica Lange as Martha Baring, the obsessively jealous and controlling mother in law. Lange, I thought, did a good job with her character. At first, Martha seems almost normal and welcoming of her new daughter in law Helen (Gwyneth Paltrow). But she gradually becomes more and more menacing and by the end borders on the insane, and that was all brilliantly pulled off by Lange, who made an otherwise bland movie worth watching. Unfortunately, one superb performance can't save an otherwise weak movie. (4/10)
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    From a premise like this, I expected more and better
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    raisleygordon
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/1/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    In theory, "Hush" sounds like an ideal movie, but I'm afraid the results leave a lot to be desired. How in the world did these actors, especially Gwyneth Paltrow, get duped into participating in this project? Everyone is phoning in their performances here. This is a movie you might as well be listening to on the radio. The "story", not that there is much of one, is this: A New York couple, Jackson and Helen, are visiting his mother, Martha, for the holidays. She smokes, drinks, and tries to tear this couple apart (from what I can recall, anyway). The closest any of these characters get to being menacing, is when Helen (Jessica Lange's character) changes the temperature in the hot tub her mother is bathing in at the spa (or wherever the tub is). I didn't buy the story, I wasn't engaged, and I didn't care about the characters (or what would eventually happen to them). The things that happen, happen simply because the screenplay requires it to. ** out of ****
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Oedipal Mayhem
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    JasparLamarCrabb
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/11/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Unbelievably bad. Writer/director Jonathan Darby concocts a ridiculous southern fried horror tale. Jessica Lange, channeling both Blanche Dubois AND Baby Jane Hudson, runs a horse farm and is visited by son Johnathon Schaech and new bride Gwyneth Paltrow. Oedipal mayhem ensues. Lange, unable to let Schaech go, terrorizes Paltrow. By the time Paltrow winds up in bed giving birth the film reaches a frenzied level of camp. It's always a curiosity how good actors end up in such dreck. It's a wonder if Lange, Schaech and Paltrow read the script, a half-baked amalgamation of Tennessee Williams and Tobe Hooper. While the supporting cast is populated with the dependable Hal Holbrook, Nina Foch, and Debi Mazer, they bring very little to the film. Foch is used merely to explain the motives of the deranged Lange. Lange's performance takes it's place next to Faye Dunaway's Joan Crawford in the pantheon of American Kabuki.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Plot holes a bus could drive through
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    (tottenhamtillidie@gmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/10/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This could have been so much better and is one of those movies where a lack of direction comes to the fore. Its not very suspenseful when the director is unable to build suspense, case-in- point the end where Jackson does an about turn from being the doting son to never wanting to see his mother again quicker than you could say "cut". I'm also still trying to figure out how Jackson drove from a packed Churchill Downs racecourse in Kentucky to the farm in virginia in minutes (it would take me that long to find the car in the car park)! Some good points were the ageless Jessica Lange who was fairly convincing as the evil, scheming mother and Paltrow fans will be happy to know they can use the pause button to see her in her birthday suit. No doubt, this movie is in the $5 bins at walmart by now, leave it in there, this really isn't worth your time or money.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Classic Hitchcockian Style Thriller
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    shawn_m_roeder
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/11/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I thoroughly enjoyed this movie the first time I saw it ten years ago. The film reminded me of some of my favorite Hitchcock flicks, namely Shadow of a Doubt and Notorious. The story builds slowly and generates just enough paranoia of impending danger to keep the audience interested. By the time everything comes together, the audience has an emotional investment in the main character and experiences genuine anxiety at her ordeal. This is so refreshingly different from the movies that slice and dice cardboard characters in an attempt to generate suspense. After seeing how poorly people have reacted to this film, I revisited it to see if my memory served me correctly. My assessment remains the same. Jessica Lange gives a stellar performance as the homicidal control freak. Gwyneth Paltrow is easy to empathize with as the paranoid daughter-in-law. Nina Foch is hysterical as the cheerful old lady who knows all the family secrets. I have met each of these characters in the real world. The only reason I would hesitate to call this a masterpiece is because there is no Hitchcock cameo. Still, this is a worthy imitation of the master's work.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Rarely do I...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Lee Eisenberg (eisenberg.lee@gmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/4/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    ...call a movie gross, but I feel that I have to call "Hush" just that. I couldn't see that the movie had any purpose except to show the nastiest things possible. Jessica Lange and Gwyneth Paltrow must have been in dire financial straits if they chose to star in this. Now, I should say that I don't consider this a bad movie. Truth be told, Jessica Lange made a really creepy character. But seriously folks, if you've seen any other movies starring either woman, then it should be more than obvious that they've both starred in far superior movies. Could the people behind this movie have done anything to improve it? I don't know. I personally wish that they would stop making these sorts of movies. Look, just avoid this one. There's no reason to watch it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not even bad enough to be good
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mrlocco
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/3/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    An absolutely awful movie I watched only because of Gwyneth Paltrow who I had previously admired greatly. Not so much now. Shame on her for being party to this load of rubbish. It started off quite promisingly, well actually the wheels didn't start coming off until burglary/attack on Paltrow when it was blatantly and painfully obvious that the mother had arranged this. No explanation of the reason for this. Things went rapidly downhill from there, yes the scenery was attractive if you like that sort of thing but credit for that is due to mother nature not the cinematographer. I think the second worst aspect, after the terrible story line, was Lange's acting. Incidentally, Oxytocin is rendered useless in the digestive system and is only effective if absorbed through the mucous membranes or given intravenously, and even then has a half life of 3 minutes I believe, so it would be totally useless taken in food. Also if my mother-in-law had treated me like that when I was in labour and then tried to kill me with a lethal injection I would not have stayed in the house even for a dramatic denouement the next morning. Then the son, after being led around by the nose by the evil mother does a complete about face in the space of a few minutes on the strength of his wifes unsubstantiated accusations. A rubbish movie best avoided.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Good work in a poor framework
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    dsvoss
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/12/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Gwyneth Paltrow's character gets pregnant and marries into a messed-up family. When the weirdness starts to look dangerous, the audience has lots of suspects. Mom might be neurotic and even a little bit deranged, but it's not clear she's psychotic enough to be responsible; the truly nasty stuff is always done off screen. Her son behaves oddly at times, and there's so much talk about horse breeding that one can imagine a plausible conspiracy involving any combination of the peripheral characters as well. The only thing certain is that Paltrow and her baby had better watch out. It's not a bad thriller, contrary to many of the reviews I've read. Jessica Lange nicely takes us through Mom's rapid mood swings, keeping the audience uncomfortable and unsettled. The other significant characters are ambiguous enough that, while putting forward pleasant faces, they all seem to be hiding a dark side. And the visual images are superb; definitely NOT B-movie quality stuff. The main problem is the fragmented nature of the plot. Some points are developed at length, but other developments needing explanation fly by -- and if you watch the trailer, which contained lots of scenes that never appeared in the movie, the reason for the haste must be that tons of material landed on the cutting-room floor. Seems as though the director let this horse get away from him. But if you can focus on the uncertainty surrounding who is really manipulating Paltrow and why they are doing it, you can enjoy this one.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Great suspense thriller/drama!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    DeeDeex10
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I thought this was a great suspense thriller. Both Gweneth Paltrow and Jessica Lange were fantastic. As a horse owner, I tend to nit-pick inaccurate "goofs" pertaining to the use of horses, as their usually is, but in this one, I didn't notice any. I loved the interaction with the Grandmother and one had to wonder throughout the film how the grandmother was going to portray a role in the outcome. As a woman, a Mother, a wife and who had a domineering Mother-in-law, I kept rooting for Paltrow's character to smack Lang's character and do what needed to be done, not to mention what I would have wanted to do while feeling I had to suck up to my own M.I.L. to keep a marriage intact.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Good film despite the obvious clich&eacute;s. Acting manages to save it from the total obscurity
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Rodrigo Amaro (rodrigo882008@hotmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/9/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Hush" is the kind of film that's so easy that it should work right on the first view but it's not the case. I remember watching it a few years ago and finding one of the most boring things I've ever seen except for the outstanding acting of Jessica Lange. Fate pulls its strings sometimes and one of those nights when you're desperate for something to show up on TV and there you go, there was this and I got a little gripped into seeing it again, this time paying more attention to details. Well, it turned out to be quite a good film, undeserving the low rating that is getting now. An twisted and thrilling tale about acceptance and skeletons in the closet? You can say that. Gwyneth Paltrow plays the lovable Helen, a successful and beautiful woman, loved by the a man who's also both of the fore-mentioned qualities, the great Jackson (Johnathon Schaech) of the powerful Baring family. But he has a mother, the surprising Martha (Jessica Lange) of whom Helen always tries to please to the best since Jackson and his mom has some strong bonds between them and she wants to be part of this quite perfect family. Habitual to flicks of the same caliber, there's secrets, tension between both women and a certain disdain the old lady feels for the younger and it's up to Helen to discover what's the problem with the Baring family. Her only great ally is Jackson's grandmother (Nina Foch, excellent), father of Martha's late husband, and keeper of some family secrets that can storm a big mess in everyone's lives. There isn't much to be said about "Hush" except that the cast is great, even though they're not at their greatest moment. Except Lange and Foch who are brilliant, and the memorable special appearance of Hal Holbrook as the doctor. But it's Lange who steals the show playing an pitiful villain, sometimes adorable, other times really cruel but most of the time always in control of the situation. The plot should include more characters to make this more tense and less concentrated in those three main characters. The relationship between Jackson and Martha could've go to more controversial ways, cause everything seems to indicate that (the scene where he's covered in mud and she cleans him, they're like pretending it's just a silly joke. There's something going on there). I know Jonathan Darby has directed better films (like the criminally underrated and almost forgotten "The Enemy Within" with Forest Whitaker) but what he makes his here is quite good, never cheap and at the most entertaining to watch for its cast and the beautiful cinematography. 8/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Jessica Lange Makes It Worth Watching, But She Can't Make It Good
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    sddavis63 (revsdd@gmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/6/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Even way back in 1998, the question would have been a valid one: does the world really need yet another of the "mother in law hates the new daughter in law for taking her son away from her so she sets out to destroy her" movies? Really - hasn't this been done to death? Well, in 1998 somebody decided that, indeed, another one was needed - and the end result was this rather unoriginal story that doesn't do anything that other movies of this type haven't already done. Frankly, the only thing that saved this was the performance of Jessica Lange as Martha Baring, the obsessively jealous and controlling mother in law. Lange, I thought, did a good job with her character. At first, Martha seems almost normal and welcoming of her new daughter in law Helen (Gwyneth Paltrow). But she gradually becomes more and more menacing and by the end borders on the insane, and that was all brilliantly pulled off by Lange, who made an otherwise bland movie worth watching. Unfortunately, one superb performance can't save an otherwise weak movie. (4/10)
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    From a premise like this, I expected more and better
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    raisleygordon
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/1/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    In theory, "Hush" sounds like an ideal movie, but I'm afraid the results leave a lot to be desired. How in the world did these actors, especially Gwyneth Paltrow, get duped into participating in this project? Everyone is phoning in their performances here. This is a movie you might as well be listening to on the radio. The "story", not that there is much of one, is this: A New York couple, Jackson and Helen, are visiting his mother, Martha, for the holidays. She smokes, drinks, and tries to tear this couple apart (from what I can recall, anyway). The closest any of these characters get to being menacing, is when Helen (Jessica Lange's character) changes the temperature in the hot tub her mother is bathing in at the spa (or wherever the tub is). I didn't buy the story, I wasn't engaged, and I didn't care about the characters (or what would eventually happen to them). The things that happen, happen simply because the screenplay requires it to. ** out of ****
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Oedipal Mayhem
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    JasparLamarCrabb
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/11/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Unbelievably bad. Writer/director Jonathan Darby concocts a ridiculous southern fried horror tale. Jessica Lange, channeling both Blanche Dubois AND Baby Jane Hudson, runs a horse farm and is visited by son Johnathon Schaech and new bride Gwyneth Paltrow. Oedipal mayhem ensues. Lange, unable to let Schaech go, terrorizes Paltrow. By the time Paltrow winds up in bed giving birth the film reaches a frenzied level of camp. It's always a curiosity how good actors end up in such dreck. It's a wonder if Lange, Schaech and Paltrow read the script, a half-baked amalgamation of Tennessee Williams and Tobe Hooper. While the supporting cast is populated with the dependable Hal Holbrook, Nina Foch, and Debi Mazer, they bring very little to the film. Foch is used merely to explain the motives of the deranged Lange. Lange's performance takes it's place next to Faye Dunaway's Joan Crawford in the pantheon of American Kabuki.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Plot holes a bus could drive through
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    (tottenhamtillidie@gmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/10/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This could have been so much better and is one of those movies where a lack of direction comes to the fore. Its not very suspenseful when the director is unable to build suspense, case-in- point the end where Jackson does an about turn from being the doting son to never wanting to see his mother again quicker than you could say "cut". I'm also still trying to figure out how Jackson drove from a packed Churchill Downs racecourse in Kentucky to the farm in virginia in minutes (it would take me that long to find the car in the car park)! Some good points were the ageless Jessica Lange who was fairly convincing as the evil, scheming mother and Paltrow fans will be happy to know they can use the pause button to see her in her birthday suit. No doubt, this movie is in the $5 bins at walmart by now, leave it in there, this really isn't worth your time or money.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Classic Hitchcockian Style Thriller
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    shawn_m_roeder
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/11/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I thoroughly enjoyed this movie the first time I saw it ten years ago. The film reminded me of some of my favorite Hitchcock flicks, namely Shadow of a Doubt and Notorious. The story builds slowly and generates just enough paranoia of impending danger to keep the audience interested. By the time everything comes together, the audience has an emotional investment in the main character and experiences genuine anxiety at her ordeal. This is so refreshingly different from the movies that slice and dice cardboard characters in an attempt to generate suspense. After seeing how poorly people have reacted to this film, I revisited it to see if my memory served me correctly. My assessment remains the same. Jessica Lange gives a stellar performance as the homicidal control freak. Gwyneth Paltrow is easy to empathize with as the paranoid daughter-in-law. Nina Foch is hysterical as the cheerful old lady who knows all the family secrets. I have met each of these characters in the real world. The only reason I would hesitate to call this a masterpiece is because there is no Hitchcock cameo. Still, this is a worthy imitation of the master's work.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Rarely do I...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Lee Eisenberg (eisenberg.lee@gmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/4/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    ...call a movie gross, but I feel that I have to call "Hush" just that. I couldn't see that the movie had any purpose except to show the nastiest things possible. Jessica Lange and Gwyneth Paltrow must have been in dire financial straits if they chose to star in this. Now, I should say that I don't consider this a bad movie. Truth be told, Jessica Lange made a really creepy character. But seriously folks, if you've seen any other movies starring either woman, then it should be more than obvious that they've both starred in far superior movies. Could the people behind this movie have done anything to improve it? I don't know. I personally wish that they would stop making these sorts of movies. Look, just avoid this one. There's no reason to watch it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not even bad enough to be good
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mrlocco
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/3/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    An absolutely awful movie I watched only because of Gwyneth Paltrow who I had previously admired greatly. Not so much now. Shame on her for being party to this load of rubbish. It started off quite promisingly, well actually the wheels didn't start coming off until burglary/attack on Paltrow when it was blatantly and painfully obvious that the mother had arranged this. No explanation of the reason for this. Things went rapidly downhill from there, yes the scenery was attractive if you like that sort of thing but credit for that is due to mother nature not the cinematographer. I think the second worst aspect, after the terrible story line, was Lange's acting. Incidentally, Oxytocin is rendered useless in the digestive system and is only effective if absorbed through the mucous membranes or given intravenously, and even then has a half life of 3 minutes I believe, so it would be totally useless taken in food. Also if my mother-in-law had treated me like that when I was in labour and then tried to kill me with a lethal injection I would not have stayed in the house even for a dramatic denouement the next morning. Then the son, after being led around by the nose by the evil mother does a complete about face in the space of a few minutes on the strength of his wifes unsubstantiated accusations. A rubbish movie best avoided.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Good work in a poor framework
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    dsvoss
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/12/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Gwyneth Paltrow's character gets pregnant and marries into a messed-up family. When the weirdness starts to look dangerous, the audience has lots of suspects. Mom might be neurotic and even a little bit deranged, but it's not clear she's psychotic enough to be responsible; the truly nasty stuff is always done off screen. Her son behaves oddly at times, and there's so much talk about horse breeding that one can imagine a plausible conspiracy involving any combination of the peripheral characters as well. The only thing certain is that Paltrow and her baby had better watch out. It's not a bad thriller, contrary to many of the reviews I've read. Jessica Lange nicely takes us through Mom's rapid mood swings, keeping the audience uncomfortable and unsettled. The other significant characters are ambiguous enough that, while putting forward pleasant faces, they all seem to be hiding a dark side. And the visual images are superb; definitely NOT B-movie quality stuff. The main problem is the fragmented nature of the plot. Some points are developed at length, but other developments needing explanation fly by -- and if you watch the trailer, which contained lots of scenes that never appeared in the movie, the reason for the haste must be that tons of material landed on the cutting-room floor. Seems as though the director let this horse get away from him. But if you can focus on the uncertainty surrounding who is really manipulating Paltrow and why they are doing it, you can enjoy this one.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Great suspense thriller/drama!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    DeeDeex10
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I thought this was a great suspense thriller. Both Gweneth Paltrow and Jessica Lange were fantastic. As a horse owner, I tend to nit-pick inaccurate "goofs" pertaining to the use of horses, as their usually is, but in this one, I didn't notice any. I loved the interaction with the Grandmother and one had to wonder throughout the film how the grandmother was going to portray a role in the outcome. As a woman, a Mother, a wife and who had a domineering Mother-in-law, I kept rooting for Paltrow's character to smack Lang's character and do what needed to be done, not to mention what I would have wanted to do while feeling I had to suck up to my own M.I.L. to keep a marriage intact.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Good film despite the obvious clich&eacute;s. Acting manages to save it from the total obscurity
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Rodrigo Amaro (rodrigo882008@hotmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/9/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Hush" is the kind of film that's so easy that it should work right on the first view but it's not the case. I remember watching it a few years ago and finding one of the most boring things I've ever seen except for the outstanding acting of Jessica Lange. Fate pulls its strings sometimes and one of those nights when you're desperate for something to show up on TV and there you go, there was this and I got a little gripped into seeing it again, this time paying more attention to details. Well, it turned out to be quite a good film, undeserving the low rating that is getting now. An twisted and thrilling tale about acceptance and skeletons in the closet? You can say that. Gwyneth Paltrow plays the lovable Helen, a successful and beautiful woman, loved by the a man who's also both of the fore-mentioned qualities, the great Jackson (Johnathon Schaech) of the powerful Baring family. But he has a mother, the surprising Martha (Jessica Lange) of whom Helen always tries to please to the best since Jackson and his mom has some strong bonds between them and she wants to be part of this quite perfect family. Habitual to flicks of the same caliber, there's secrets, tension between both women and a certain disdain the old lady feels for the younger and it's up to Helen to discover what's the problem with the Baring family. Her only great ally is Jackson's grandmother (Nina Foch, excellent), father of Martha's late husband, and keeper of some family secrets that can storm a big mess in everyone's lives. There isn't much to be said about "Hush" except that the cast is great, even though they're not at their greatest moment. Except Lange and Foch who are brilliant, and the memorable special appearance of Hal Holbrook as the doctor. But it's Lange who steals the show playing an pitiful villain, sometimes adorable, other times really cruel but most of the time always in control of the situation. The plot should include more characters to make this more tense and less concentrated in those three main characters. The relationship between Jackson and Martha could've go to more controversial ways, cause everything seems to indicate that (the scene where he's covered in mud and she cleans him, they're like pretending it's just a silly joke. There's something going on there). I know Jonathan Darby has directed better films (like the criminally underrated and almost forgotten "The Enemy Within" with Forest Whitaker) but what he makes his here is quite good, never cheap and at the most entertaining to watch for its cast and the beautiful cinematography. 8/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Jessica Lange Makes It Worth Watching, But She Can't Make It Good
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    sddavis63 (revsdd@gmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/6/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Even way back in 1998, the question would have been a valid one: does the world really need yet another of the "mother in law hates the new daughter in law for taking her son away from her so she sets out to destroy her" movies? Really - hasn't this been done to death? Well, in 1998 somebody decided that, indeed, another one was needed - and the end result was this rather unoriginal story that doesn't do anything that other movies of this type haven't already done. Frankly, the only thing that saved this was the performance of Jessica Lange as Martha Baring, the obsessively jealous and controlling mother in law. Lange, I thought, did a good job with her character. At first, Martha seems almost normal and welcoming of her new daughter in law Helen (Gwyneth Paltrow). But she gradually becomes more and more menacing and by the end borders on the insane, and that was all brilliantly pulled off by Lange, who made an otherwise bland movie worth watching. Unfortunately, one superb performance can't save an otherwise weak movie. (4/10)
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    From a premise like this, I expected more and better
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    raisleygordon
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/1/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    In theory, "Hush" sounds like an ideal movie, but I'm afraid the results leave a lot to be desired. How in the world did these actors, especially Gwyneth Paltrow, get duped into participating in this project? Everyone is phoning in their performances here. This is a movie you might as well be listening to on the radio. The "story", not that there is much of one, is this: A New York couple, Jackson and Helen, are visiting his mother, Martha, for the holidays. She smokes, drinks, and tries to tear this couple apart (from what I can recall, anyway). The closest any of these characters get to being menacing, is when Helen (Jessica Lange's character) changes the temperature in the hot tub her mother is bathing in at the spa (or wherever the tub is). I didn't buy the story, I wasn't engaged, and I didn't care about the characters (or what would eventually happen to them). The things that happen, happen simply because the screenplay requires it to. ** out of ****
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Oedipal Mayhem
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    JasparLamarCrabb
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/11/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Unbelievably bad. Writer/director Jonathan Darby concocts a ridiculous southern fried horror tale. Jessica Lange, channeling both Blanche Dubois AND Baby Jane Hudson, runs a horse farm and is visited by son Johnathon Schaech and new bride Gwyneth Paltrow. Oedipal mayhem ensues. Lange, unable to let Schaech go, terrorizes Paltrow. By the time Paltrow winds up in bed giving birth the film reaches a frenzied level of camp. It's always a curiosity how good actors end up in such dreck. It's a wonder if Lange, Schaech and Paltrow read the script, a half-baked amalgamation of Tennessee Williams and Tobe Hooper. While the supporting cast is populated with the dependable Hal Holbrook, Nina Foch, and Debi Mazer, they bring very little to the film. Foch is used merely to explain the motives of the deranged Lange. Lange's performance takes it's place next to Faye Dunaway's Joan Crawford in the pantheon of American Kabuki.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Plot holes a bus could drive through
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    (tottenhamtillidie@gmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/10/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This could have been so much better and is one of those movies where a lack of direction comes to the fore. Its not very suspenseful when the director is unable to build suspense, case-in- point the end where Jackson does an about turn from being the doting son to never wanting to see his mother again quicker than you could say "cut". I'm also still trying to figure out how Jackson drove from a packed Churchill Downs racecourse in Kentucky to the farm in virginia in minutes (it would take me that long to find the car in the car park)! Some good points were the ageless Jessica Lange who was fairly convincing as the evil, scheming mother and Paltrow fans will be happy to know they can use the pause button to see her in her birthday suit. No doubt, this movie is in the $5 bins at walmart by now, leave it in there, this really isn't worth your time or money.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Classic Hitchcockian Style Thriller
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    shawn_m_roeder
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/11/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I thoroughly enjoyed this movie the first time I saw it ten years ago. The film reminded me of some of my favorite Hitchcock flicks, namely Shadow of a Doubt and Notorious. The story builds slowly and generates just enough paranoia of impending danger to keep the audience interested. By the time everything comes together, the audience has an emotional investment in the main character and experiences genuine anxiety at her ordeal. This is so refreshingly different from the movies that slice and dice cardboard characters in an attempt to generate suspense. After seeing how poorly people have reacted to this film, I revisited it to see if my memory served me correctly. My assessment remains the same. Jessica Lange gives a stellar performance as the homicidal control freak. Gwyneth Paltrow is easy to empathize with as the paranoid daughter-in-law. Nina Foch is hysterical as the cheerful old lady who knows all the family secrets. I have met each of these characters in the real world. The only reason I would hesitate to call this a masterpiece is because there is no Hitchcock cameo. Still, this is a worthy imitation of the master's work.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Rarely do I...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Lee Eisenberg (eisenberg.lee@gmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/4/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    ...call a movie gross, but I feel that I have to call "Hush" just that. I couldn't see that the movie had any purpose except to show the nastiest things possible. Jessica Lange and Gwyneth Paltrow must have been in dire financial straits if they chose to star in this. Now, I should say that I don't consider this a bad movie. Truth be told, Jessica Lange made a really creepy character. But seriously folks, if you've seen any other movies starring either woman, then it should be more than obvious that they've both starred in far superior movies. Could the people behind this movie have done anything to improve it? I don't know. I personally wish that they would stop making these sorts of movies. Look, just avoid this one. There's no reason to watch it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not even bad enough to be good
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mrlocco
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/3/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    An absolutely awful movie I watched only because of Gwyneth Paltrow who I had previously admired greatly. Not so much now. Shame on her for being party to this load of rubbish. It started off quite promisingly, well actually the wheels didn't start coming off until burglary/attack on Paltrow when it was blatantly and painfully obvious that the mother had arranged this. No explanation of the reason for this. Things went rapidly downhill from there, yes the scenery was attractive if you like that sort of thing but credit for that is due to mother nature not the cinematographer. I think the second worst aspect, after the terrible story line, was Lange's acting. Incidentally, Oxytocin is rendered useless in the digestive system and is only effective if absorbed through the mucous membranes or given intravenously, and even then has a half life of 3 minutes I believe, so it would be totally useless taken in food. Also if my mother-in-law had treated me like that when I was in labour and then tried to kill me with a lethal injection I would not have stayed in the house even for a dramatic denouement the next morning. Then the son, after being led around by the nose by the evil mother does a complete about face in the space of a few minutes on the strength of his wifes unsubstantiated accusations. A rubbish movie best avoided.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Good work in a poor framework
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    dsvoss
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/12/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Gwyneth Paltrow's character gets pregnant and marries into a messed-up family. When the weirdness starts to look dangerous, the audience has lots of suspects. Mom might be neurotic and even a little bit deranged, but it's not clear she's psychotic enough to be responsible; the truly nasty stuff is always done off screen. Her son behaves oddly at times, and there's so much talk about horse breeding that one can imagine a plausible conspiracy involving any combination of the peripheral characters as well. The only thing certain is that Paltrow and her baby had better watch out. It's not a bad thriller, contrary to many of the reviews I've read. Jessica Lange nicely takes us through Mom's rapid mood swings, keeping the audience uncomfortable and unsettled. The other significant characters are ambiguous enough that, while putting forward pleasant faces, they all seem to be hiding a dark side. And the visual images are superb; definitely NOT B-movie quality stuff. The main problem is the fragmented nature of the plot. Some points are developed at length, but other developments needing explanation fly by -- and if you watch the trailer, which contained lots of scenes that never appeared in the movie, the reason for the haste must be that tons of material landed on the cutting-room floor. Seems as though the director let this horse get away from him. But if you can focus on the uncertainty surrounding who is really manipulating Paltrow and why they are doing it, you can enjoy this one.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Great suspense thriller/drama!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    DeeDeex10
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I thought this was a great suspense thriller. Both Gweneth Paltrow and Jessica Lange were fantastic. As a horse owner, I tend to nit-pick inaccurate "goofs" pertaining to the use of horses, as their usually is, but in this one, I didn't notice any. I loved the interaction with the Grandmother and one had to wonder throughout the film how the grandmother was going to portray a role in the outcome. As a woman, a Mother, a wife and who had a domineering Mother-in-law, I kept rooting for Paltrow's character to smack Lang's character and do what needed to be done, not to mention what I would have wanted to do while feeling I had to suck up to my own M.I.L. to keep a marriage intact.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Good film despite the obvious clich&eacute;s. Acting manages to save it from the total obscurity
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Rodrigo Amaro (rodrigo882008@hotmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/9/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Hush" is the kind of film that's so easy that it should work right on the first view but it's not the case. I remember watching it a few years ago and finding one of the most boring things I've ever seen except for the outstanding acting of Jessica Lange. Fate pulls its strings sometimes and one of those nights when you're desperate for something to show up on TV and there you go, there was this and I got a little gripped into seeing it again, this time paying more attention to details. Well, it turned out to be quite a good film, undeserving the low rating that is getting now. An twisted and thrilling tale about acceptance and skeletons in the closet? You can say that. Gwyneth Paltrow plays the lovable Helen, a successful and beautiful woman, loved by the a man who's also both of the fore-mentioned qualities, the great Jackson (Johnathon Schaech) of the powerful Baring family. But he has a mother, the surprising Martha (Jessica Lange) of whom Helen always tries to please to the best since Jackson and his mom has some strong bonds between them and she wants to be part of this quite perfect family. Habitual to flicks of the same caliber, there's secrets, tension between both women and a certain disdain the old lady feels for the younger and it's up to Helen to discover what's the problem with the Baring family. Her only great ally is Jackson's grandmother (Nina Foch, excellent), father of Martha's late husband, and keeper of some family secrets that can storm a big mess in everyone's lives. There isn't much to be said about "Hush" except that the cast is great, even though they're not at their greatest moment. Except Lange and Foch who are brilliant, and the memorable special appearance of Hal Holbrook as the doctor. But it's Lange who steals the show playing an pitiful villain, sometimes adorable, other times really cruel but most of the time always in control of the situation. The plot should include more characters to make this more tense and less concentrated in those three main characters. The relationship between Jackson and Martha could've go to more controversial ways, cause everything seems to indicate that (the scene where he's covered in mud and she cleans him, they're like pretending it's just a silly joke. There's something going on there). I know Jonathan Darby has directed better films (like the criminally underrated and almost forgotten "The Enemy Within" with Forest Whitaker) but what he makes his here is quite good, never cheap and at the most entertaining to watch for its cast and the beautiful cinematography. 8/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Jessica Lange Makes It Worth Watching, But She Can't Make It Good
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    sddavis63 (revsdd@gmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/6/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Even way back in 1998, the question would have been a valid one: does the world really need yet another of the "mother in law hates the new daughter in law for taking her son away from her so she sets out to destroy her" movies? Really - hasn't this been done to death? Well, in 1998 somebody decided that, indeed, another one was needed - and the end result was this rather unoriginal story that doesn't do anything that other movies of this type haven't already done. Frankly, the only thing that saved this was the performance of Jessica Lange as Martha Baring, the obsessively jealous and controlling mother in law. Lange, I thought, did a good job with her character. At first, Martha seems almost normal and welcoming of her new daughter in law Helen (Gwyneth Paltrow). But she gradually becomes more and more menacing and by the end borders on the insane, and that was all brilliantly pulled off by Lange, who made an otherwise bland movie worth watching. Unfortunately, one superb performance can't save an otherwise weak movie. (4/10)
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    From a premise like this, I expected more and better
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    raisleygordon
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/1/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    In theory, "Hush" sounds like an ideal movie, but I'm afraid the results leave a lot to be desired. How in the world did these actors, especially Gwyneth Paltrow, get duped into participating in this project? Everyone is phoning in their performances here. This is a movie you might as well be listening to on the radio. The "story", not that there is much of one, is this: A New York couple, Jackson and Helen, are visiting his mother, Martha, for the holidays. She smokes, drinks, and tries to tear this couple apart (from what I can recall, anyway). The closest any of these characters get to being menacing, is when Helen (Jessica Lange's character) changes the temperature in the hot tub her mother is bathing in at the spa (or wherever the tub is). I didn't buy the story, I wasn't engaged, and I didn't care about the characters (or what would eventually happen to them). The things that happen, happen simply because the screenplay requires it to. ** out of ****
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Oedipal Mayhem
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    JasparLamarCrabb
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/11/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Unbelievably bad. Writer/director Jonathan Darby concocts a ridiculous southern fried horror tale. Jessica Lange, channeling both Blanche Dubois AND Baby Jane Hudson, runs a horse farm and is visited by son Johnathon Schaech and new bride Gwyneth Paltrow. Oedipal mayhem ensues. Lange, unable to let Schaech go, terrorizes Paltrow. By the time Paltrow winds up in bed giving birth the film reaches a frenzied level of camp. It's always a curiosity how good actors end up in such dreck. It's a wonder if Lange, Schaech and Paltrow read the script, a half-baked amalgamation of Tennessee Williams and Tobe Hooper. While the supporting cast is populated with the dependable Hal Holbrook, Nina Foch, and Debi Mazer, they bring very little to the film. Foch is used merely to explain the motives of the deranged Lange. Lange's performance takes it's place next to Faye Dunaway's Joan Crawford in the pantheon of American Kabuki.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Plot holes a bus could drive through
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    (tottenhamtillidie@gmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/10/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This could have been so much better and is one of those movies where a lack of direction comes to the fore. Its not very suspenseful when the director is unable to build suspense, case-in- point the end where Jackson does an about turn from being the doting son to never wanting to see his mother again quicker than you could say "cut". I'm also still trying to figure out how Jackson drove from a packed Churchill Downs racecourse in Kentucky to the farm in virginia in minutes (it would take me that long to find the car in the car park)! Some good points were the ageless Jessica Lange who was fairly convincing as the evil, scheming mother and Paltrow fans will be happy to know they can use the pause button to see her in her birthday suit. No doubt, this movie is in the $5 bins at walmart by now, leave it in there, this really isn't worth your time or money.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Classic Hitchcockian Style Thriller
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    shawn_m_roeder
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/11/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I thoroughly enjoyed this movie the first time I saw it ten years ago. The film reminded me of some of my favorite Hitchcock flicks, namely Shadow of a Doubt and Notorious. The story builds slowly and generates just enough paranoia of impending danger to keep the audience interested. By the time everything comes together, the audience has an emotional investment in the main character and experiences genuine anxiety at her ordeal. This is so refreshingly different from the movies that slice and dice cardboard characters in an attempt to generate suspense. After seeing how poorly people have reacted to this film, I revisited it to see if my memory served me correctly. My assessment remains the same. Jessica Lange gives a stellar performance as the homicidal control freak. Gwyneth Paltrow is easy to empathize with as the paranoid daughter-in-law. Nina Foch is hysterical as the cheerful old lady who knows all the family secrets. I have met each of these characters in the real world. The only reason I would hesitate to call this a masterpiece is because there is no Hitchcock cameo. Still, this is a worthy imitation of the master's work.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Rarely do I...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Lee Eisenberg (eisenberg.lee@gmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/4/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    ...call a movie gross, but I feel that I have to call "Hush" just that. I couldn't see that the movie had any purpose except to show the nastiest things possible. Jessica Lange and Gwyneth Paltrow must have been in dire financial straits if they chose to star in this. Now, I should say that I don't consider this a bad movie. Truth be told, Jessica Lange made a really creepy character. But seriously folks, if you've seen any other movies starring either woman, then it should be more than obvious that they've both starred in far superior movies. Could the people behind this movie have done anything to improve it? I don't know. I personally wish that they would stop making these sorts of movies. Look, just avoid this one. There's no reason to watch it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not even bad enough to be good
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mrlocco
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/3/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    An absolutely awful movie I watched only because of Gwyneth Paltrow who I had previously admired greatly. Not so much now. Shame on her for being party to this load of rubbish. It started off quite promisingly, well actually the wheels didn't start coming off until burglary/attack on Paltrow when it was blatantly and painfully obvious that the mother had arranged this. No explanation of the reason for this. Things went rapidly downhill from there, yes the scenery was attractive if you like that sort of thing but credit for that is due to mother nature not the cinematographer. I think the second worst aspect, after the terrible story line, was Lange's acting. Incidentally, Oxytocin is rendered useless in the digestive system and is only effective if absorbed through the mucous membranes or given intravenously, and even then has a half life of 3 minutes I believe, so it would be totally useless taken in food. Also if my mother-in-law had treated me like that when I was in labour and then tried to kill me with a lethal injection I would not have stayed in the house even for a dramatic denouement the next morning. Then the son, after being led around by the nose by the evil mother does a complete about face in the space of a few minutes on the strength of his wifes unsubstantiated accusations. A rubbish movie best avoided.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Good work in a poor framework
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    dsvoss
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/12/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Gwyneth Paltrow's character gets pregnant and marries into a messed-up family. When the weirdness starts to look dangerous, the audience has lots of suspects. Mom might be neurotic and even a little bit deranged, but it's not clear she's psychotic enough to be responsible; the truly nasty stuff is always done off screen. Her son behaves oddly at times, and there's so much talk about horse breeding that one can imagine a plausible conspiracy involving any combination of the peripheral characters as well. The only thing certain is that Paltrow and her baby had better watch out. It's not a bad thriller, contrary to many of the reviews I've read. Jessica Lange nicely takes us through Mom's rapid mood swings, keeping the audience uncomfortable and unsettled. The other significant characters are ambiguous enough that, while putting forward pleasant faces, they all seem to be hiding a dark side. And the visual images are superb; definitely NOT B-movie quality stuff. The main problem is the fragmented nature of the plot. Some points are developed at length, but other developments needing explanation fly by -- and if you watch the trailer, which contained lots of scenes that never appeared in the movie, the reason for the haste must be that tons of material landed on the cutting-room floor. Seems as though the director let this horse get away from him. But if you can focus on the uncertainty surrounding who is really manipulating Paltrow and why they are doing it, you can enjoy this one.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Great suspense thriller/drama!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    DeeDeex10
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I thought this was a great suspense thriller. Both Gweneth Paltrow and Jessica Lange were fantastic. As a horse owner, I tend to nit-pick inaccurate "goofs" pertaining to the use of horses, as their usually is, but in this one, I didn't notice any. I loved the interaction with the Grandmother and one had to wonder throughout the film how the grandmother was going to portray a role in the outcome. As a woman, a Mother, a wife and who had a domineering Mother-in-law, I kept rooting for Paltrow's character to smack Lang's character and do what needed to be done, not to mention what I would have wanted to do while feeling I had to suck up to my own M.I.L. to keep a marriage intact.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Good film despite the obvious clich&eacute;s. Acting manages to save it from the total obscurity
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Rodrigo Amaro (rodrigo882008@hotmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/9/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Hush" is the kind of film that's so easy that it should work right on the first view but it's not the case. I remember watching it a few years ago and finding one of the most boring things I've ever seen except for the outstanding acting of Jessica Lange. Fate pulls its strings sometimes and one of those nights when you're desperate for something to show up on TV and there you go, there was this and I got a little gripped into seeing it again, this time paying more attention to details. Well, it turned out to be quite a good film, undeserving the low rating that is getting now. An twisted and thrilling tale about acceptance and skeletons in the closet? You can say that. Gwyneth Paltrow plays the lovable Helen, a successful and beautiful woman, loved by the a man who's also both of the fore-mentioned qualities, the great Jackson (Johnathon Schaech) of the powerful Baring family. But he has a mother, the surprising Martha (Jessica Lange) of whom Helen always tries to please to the best since Jackson and his mom has some strong bonds between them and she wants to be part of this quite perfect family. Habitual to flicks of the same caliber, there's secrets, tension between both women and a certain disdain the old lady feels for the younger and it's up to Helen to discover what's the problem with the Baring family. Her only great ally is Jackson's grandmother (Nina Foch, excellent), father of Martha's late husband, and keeper of some family secrets that can storm a big mess in everyone's lives. There isn't much to be said about "Hush" except that the cast is great, even though they're not at their greatest moment. Except Lange and Foch who are brilliant, and the memorable special appearance of Hal Holbrook as the doctor. But it's Lange who steals the show playing an pitiful villain, sometimes adorable, other times really cruel but most of the time always in control of the situation. The plot should include more characters to make this more tense and less concentrated in those three main characters. The relationship between Jackson and Martha could've go to more controversial ways, cause everything seems to indicate that (the scene where he's covered in mud and she cleans him, they're like pretending it's just a silly joke. There's something going on there). I know Jonathan Darby has directed better films (like the criminally underrated and almost forgotten "The Enemy Within" with Forest Whitaker) but what he makes his here is quite good, never cheap and at the most entertaining to watch for its cast and the beautiful cinematography. 8/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Jessica Lange Makes It Worth Watching, But She Can't Make It Good
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    sddavis63 (revsdd@gmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/6/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Even way back in 1998, the question would have been a valid one: does the world really need yet another of the "mother in law hates the new daughter in law for taking her son away from her so she sets out to destroy her" movies? Really - hasn't this been done to death? Well, in 1998 somebody decided that, indeed, another one was needed - and the end result was this rather unoriginal story that doesn't do anything that other movies of this type haven't already done. Frankly, the only thing that saved this was the performance of Jessica Lange as Martha Baring, the obsessively jealous and controlling mother in law. Lange, I thought, did a good job with her character. At first, Martha seems almost normal and welcoming of her new daughter in law Helen (Gwyneth Paltrow). But she gradually becomes more and more menacing and by the end borders on the insane, and that was all brilliantly pulled off by Lange, who made an otherwise bland movie worth watching. Unfortunately, one superb performance can't save an otherwise weak movie. (4/10)
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    From a premise like this, I expected more and better
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    raisleygordon
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/1/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    In theory, "Hush" sounds like an ideal movie, but I'm afraid the results leave a lot to be desired. How in the world did these actors, especially Gwyneth Paltrow, get duped into participating in this project? Everyone is phoning in their performances here. This is a movie you might as well be listening to on the radio. The "story", not that there is much of one, is this: A New York couple, Jackson and Helen, are visiting his mother, Martha, for the holidays. She smokes, drinks, and tries to tear this couple apart (from what I can recall, anyway). The closest any of these characters get to being menacing, is when Helen (Jessica Lange's character) changes the temperature in the hot tub her mother is bathing in at the spa (or wherever the tub is). I didn't buy the story, I wasn't engaged, and I didn't care about the characters (or what would eventually happen to them). The things that happen, happen simply because the screenplay requires it to. ** out of ****
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Oedipal Mayhem
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    JasparLamarCrabb
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/11/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Unbelievably bad. Writer/director Jonathan Darby concocts a ridiculous southern fried horror tale. Jessica Lange, channeling both Blanche Dubois AND Baby Jane Hudson, runs a horse farm and is visited by son Johnathon Schaech and new bride Gwyneth Paltrow. Oedipal mayhem ensues. Lange, unable to let Schaech go, terrorizes Paltrow. By the time Paltrow winds up in bed giving birth the film reaches a frenzied level of camp. It's always a curiosity how good actors end up in such dreck. It's a wonder if Lange, Schaech and Paltrow read the script, a half-baked amalgamation of Tennessee Williams and Tobe Hooper. While the supporting cast is populated with the dependable Hal Holbrook, Nina Foch, and Debi Mazer, they bring very little to the film. Foch is used merely to explain the motives of the deranged Lange. Lange's performance takes it's place next to Faye Dunaway's Joan Crawford in the pantheon of American Kabuki.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Plot holes a bus could drive through
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    (tottenhamtillidie@gmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/10/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This could have been so much better and is one of those movies where a lack of direction comes to the fore. Its not very suspenseful when the director is unable to build suspense, case-in- point the end where Jackson does an about turn from being the doting son to never wanting to see his mother again quicker than you could say "cut". I'm also still trying to figure out how Jackson drove from a packed Churchill Downs racecourse in Kentucky to the farm in virginia in minutes (it would take me that long to find the car in the car park)! Some good points were the ageless Jessica Lange who was fairly convincing as the evil, scheming mother and Paltrow fans will be happy to know they can use the pause button to see her in her birthday suit. No doubt, this movie is in the $5 bins at walmart by now, leave it in there, this really isn't worth your time or money.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Classic Hitchcockian Style Thriller
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    shawn_m_roeder
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/11/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I thoroughly enjoyed this movie the first time I saw it ten years ago. The film reminded me of some of my favorite Hitchcock flicks, namely Shadow of a Doubt and Notorious. The story builds slowly and generates just enough paranoia of impending danger to keep the audience interested. By the time everything comes together, the audience has an emotional investment in the main character and experiences genuine anxiety at her ordeal. This is so refreshingly different from the movies that slice and dice cardboard characters in an attempt to generate suspense. After seeing how poorly people have reacted to this film, I revisited it to see if my memory served me correctly. My assessment remains the same. Jessica Lange gives a stellar performance as the homicidal control freak. Gwyneth Paltrow is easy to empathize with as the paranoid daughter-in-law. Nina Foch is hysterical as the cheerful old lady who knows all the family secrets. I have met each of these characters in the real world. The only reason I would hesitate to call this a masterpiece is because there is no Hitchcock cameo. Still, this is a worthy imitation of the master's work.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Rarely do I...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Lee Eisenberg (eisenberg.lee@gmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/4/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    ...call a movie gross, but I feel that I have to call "Hush" just that. I couldn't see that the movie had any purpose except to show the nastiest things possible. Jessica Lange and Gwyneth Paltrow must have been in dire financial straits if they chose to star in this. Now, I should say that I don't consider this a bad movie. Truth be told, Jessica Lange made a really creepy character. But seriously folks, if you've seen any other movies starring either woman, then it should be more than obvious that they've both starred in far superior movies. Could the people behind this movie have done anything to improve it? I don't know. I personally wish that they would stop making these sorts of movies. Look, just avoid this one. There's no reason to watch it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not even bad enough to be good
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mrlocco
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/3/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    An absolutely awful movie I watched only because of Gwyneth Paltrow who I had previously admired greatly. Not so much now. Shame on her for being party to this load of rubbish. It started off quite promisingly, well actually the wheels didn't start coming off until burglary/attack on Paltrow when it was blatantly and painfully obvious that the mother had arranged this. No explanation of the reason for this. Things went rapidly downhill from there, yes the scenery was attractive if you like that sort of thing but credit for that is due to mother nature not the cinematographer. I think the second worst aspect, after the terrible story line, was Lange's acting. Incidentally, Oxytocin is rendered useless in the digestive system and is only effective if absorbed through the mucous membranes or given intravenously, and even then has a half life of 3 minutes I believe, so it would be totally useless taken in food. Also if my mother-in-law had treated me like that when I was in labour and then tried to kill me with a lethal injection I would not have stayed in the house even for a dramatic denouement the next morning. Then the son, after being led around by the nose by the evil mother does a complete about face in the space of a few minutes on the strength of his wifes unsubstantiated accusations. A rubbish movie best avoided.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Good work in a poor framework
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    dsvoss
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/12/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Gwyneth Paltrow's character gets pregnant and marries into a messed-up family. When the weirdness starts to look dangerous, the audience has lots of suspects. Mom might be neurotic and even a little bit deranged, but it's not clear she's psychotic enough to be responsible; the truly nasty stuff is always done off screen. Her son behaves oddly at times, and there's so much talk about horse breeding that one can imagine a plausible conspiracy involving any combination of the peripheral characters as well. The only thing certain is that Paltrow and her baby had better watch out. It's not a bad thriller, contrary to many of the reviews I've read. Jessica Lange nicely takes us through Mom's rapid mood swings, keeping the audience uncomfortable and unsettled. The other significant characters are ambiguous enough that, while putting forward pleasant faces, they all seem to be hiding a dark side. And the visual images are superb; definitely NOT B-movie quality stuff. The main problem is the fragmented nature of the plot. Some points are developed at length, but other developments needing explanation fly by -- and if you watch the trailer, which contained lots of scenes that never appeared in the movie, the reason for the haste must be that tons of material landed on the cutting-room floor. Seems as though the director let this horse get away from him. But if you can focus on the uncertainty surrounding who is really manipulating Paltrow and why they are doing it, you can enjoy this one.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
 </reviews>
</filme>
