<filme>
 <id>
  1633
 </id>
 <imdburl>
  http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0109028
 </imdburl>
 <ano>
  1995
 </ano>
 <titulo>
  &Aacute; k&ouml;ldum klaka
 </titulo>
 <rating>
  6.9
 </rating>
 <sinopse>
  A Japanese businessman travels to Iceland and has a series of misadventures while venturing to a remote area to perform a traditional burial ritual where his parents died several years back.
 </sinopse>
 <storyline>
  Hirata finds himself canceling his vacation plans to Hawaii when his grandfather reminds him of his duty to his parents. Seven years earlier, Hirata's parents had been killed in an accident in Iceland and Japanese tradition holds that their souls will not be at ease until the proper ceremonies have been performed. Thus, Hirata sets out on a journey, a quest to the river where his parents perished. Along the way, in this Icelandic-Japanese road movie, he encounters many difficulties, tough situations, and odd people in the land of fire and ice. Fridrik Thor Fridriksson's vision infuses Iceland's stark and beautiful landscape with a haunting spirituality.
 </storyline>
 <generos>
  <genero>
   Comedy
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Drama
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Mystery
  </genero>
 </generos>
 <keywords>
  <keyword>
   iceland
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   japanese
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   tradition
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   ice
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   spirituality
  </keyword>
 </keywords>
 <diretores>
  <diretor>
   Fri&eth;rik &THORN;&oacute;r Fri&eth;riksson
  </diretor>
 </diretores>
 <escritores>
  <escritor>
   Fri&eth;rik &THORN;&oacute;r Fri&eth;riksson
  </escritor>
  <escritor>
   Jim Stark
  </escritor>
 </escritores>
 <atores>
  <ator>
   Masatoshi Nagase
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Lili Taylor
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Fisher Stevens
  </ator>
 </atores>
 <reviews>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Odd and intriguing
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    zetes
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/7/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Masatoshi Nagase (best known for his role in Jarmusch's Mystery Train, and also the Japanese films Suicide Club, The Hidden Blade and Electric Dragon 80.000V) stars as a Japanese man whose grandfather (cult director Seijun Suzuki, who appears for a couple of minutes) insists he spend his vacation performing traditional burial rites of his parents, who died while living in Iceland. Nagase flies to Reykjavik and proceeds to drive across the country in the middle of the winter to the remote spot where they passed. Though they don't go into any details on his parents' death, Iceland seems like a very likely place to die, since it's full of dangerous, unpopulated terrain. This is basically a road movie, where Nagase meets various odd people along his way. It's maybe a bit weirder than most - I'd say it's kind of one of those weird-for-the-sake-of-weird type movies. But Fridriksson does a great job of making his home country look like a world of wonder. "Iceland is very strange country" Nagase always says when someone asks him what he thinks of it, in English of course, since it's the common language between him and most Icelanders (I'd say about 80% of the dialogue is in English). The film doesn't really go anywhere plot-wise, and some of the episodes are more successful than others. The most notable flop is the long sequence where Nagase picks up a couple of stranded American tourists, Fisher Stevens and Lili Taylor. Those two are painfully annoying, especially when they talk to each other via their sock puppets. That's really some needless quirk. Overall, though, I was intrigued.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Wonderful
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Maurizio
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/10/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is really a wonderful film! I might be a little influenced by the fact that I've been to Iceland twice and I loved it (and still do, and pretty surely there's going to be a third time), but I really did feel this movie. The storyline is quite simple and has been well described by other reviewers, so straight to what this movie contains. Well, anybody who's been to Iceland will realize immediately the high grade of realism, both in the landscapes and in the people the main man meets on his way, their attitudes, mentality, way of talking and all the rest. Icelanders really ARE the way you see them in this movie! Also the atmosphere of the country in the winter is perfect, deeply charming in its desolation. But whats gets the most in this film is the humanity of the various characters. The main man is a likable guy, a little stiff in his behaving with the rest of the world, but that might be part of the Japanese culture as far as I know. Completely unlikable the two Americans, who are indeed negative characters, while I loved the old man who befriends the protagonist in the last part of the movie. The deepest humanity is to be found in him. This is a movie that will get stuck into your mind for a very long time, don't miss it!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Points to the intertextuality of Icelandic and Japanese film elements
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    scf-8
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/3/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I saw Cold Fever when it was first released in the U.S. and have been (unsuccessfully so far) looking for it for about 5 years to see it again. Some of the other comments have pointed to the way the Japanese and Icelandic elements--of folklore and spirituality, principally--weave together. I have always thought it was a beautiful homage to Kurosawa and perhaps other Japanese filmmakers, not just in the plot (which others have correctly seen as a "road movie") but in the whole pacing and look of the film--the colors, the composition of scenes, the attention to the characters. It's really too bad more people haven't seen it. Hirata's enlightenment through his contacts with other characters who may be real, delusional (he is, in fact, fevered), or actual ghosts or spirits is compelling and thought-provoking for the viewer, who must also question what is "real," as well as what it means.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    What a movie!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    wmchase65
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/9/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    In Cold Fever Fredrick Thor Fredrickson gives the viewer a peak into the Incelandic culture. Simply a beautiful film...15 years ago I was an exchange student and lived in Keflavik for a semester. It was the time of my life. While in Iceland a met some amazing people. One person in particular (an icelandic national) I consider one of my best friend today. I've been back to Iceland 5 times since, and he (and his family) have also visited me here in the states numerous times too...Needlesstosay, Iceland has a very spcecial place in my heart... People often ask me "so what's Iceland like?" Of course I tell them all I know, but if they really want to get a glimpse into Iceland, I have them watch "cold fever".....truly a great piece of art!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Film stuck in my head for last 5 years
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Graham Stanford
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/2/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Something about this film has kept me thinking about it since I saw it in 2001. I had the fortunate opportunity to see it because, at that time, Des Moines (Iowa) had one of the best indie-movie rental places (Oddities), ever. Oddities just stocked walls of foreign films and rows of independent films. Cold fever had the intriguing elements of a young Japenese businessman reluctantly, and by family obligation, traveling around Iceland. That was enough for us to want to check it out. The story is tremendous. I love the style and the performances give by the actors. Fri&eth;rik &THORN;&oacute;r Fri&eth;riksson really captures the feeling of the main character on film. It is almost haunting how Hirata operates... how he meanders through the vastness of the landscape. Great film, great ending. I wish they would get it on DVD along with other works by the director
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Teny Years On - The Film Still Works
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    robert-642
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/5/2005
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Ten years later this very compact film still works its magic. Much has been said by many of the other contributors with one exception. It is not a film to be rushed. Rather you need to view at the speed the film dictates - not unlike "Paris, Texas. Like the swirling mists and snow it slowly envelops you. No frame is wasted. Even a casual remark in the aeroplane en-route to Iceland gives a link for the future. Many different cultures have their cultural layers peeled back; American, Japanese, Icelandic and Norse mythology. It's up to the viewer to see what he or she sees. I think the most telling scene in the film is the Icelander who befriends Hirata. Although he does not want to accompany Hirata to the ritual grave scene because of a 'spirit dream', he nonetheless is there to show him the way home. In so doing, he witnesses a universal value with Hirate - the passing of life. There's much to be said for good small budget films. The story and direction have to be tightly constrained.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Much more than a tourist advertisement
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    lowkeylysmythe
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/11/2004
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This film is indeed a beautiful film showing Iceland's many attractions as the previous reviewer mentioned, but it also draws very interesting parallels between the native beliefs of Icelanders, which in fact are quite similar to what prevailed across Europe before Christianity came(Iceland was settled by Vikings and was among the last places Europeans held to their pagan religion), and the Shinto practices in Japan. One accompanies the main character, a shallow, immature corporate executive from his comfortable Tokyo life to Iceland: where layer by layer he is stripped of comfort, certainty, even rationality, until he is brought to a place where he realizes a simple and profound humanity. This film is funny, the cinematography is amazing, and it is spiritually enriching. How many films can you say all that about?
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Magnificent Film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Tathata (Tathata@comcast.net)
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/9/2004
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A wonderful spiritual comedy. The cinematography is unchallengeable. A beautiful landscape that oft times provides the illusion the filming was done in black and white. For those who love films about the majestic and mysterious journey of life, this one is not to be missed. On my top 10 list and waiting for release on DVD. In order to meet the 10 line minimum comment, I am forced into verbosity. Favorite scenes include the singing men in the truck, the cowboy bar, the conversation with the sheep's head, and of course the journey's revelation. For you Northerner's, ingnor the fact our hero would have frozen to death in the first 15 minutes and hear the message. Truly, this one could tempt you to vacation in Iceland.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Trip for the soul...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Martin
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/2/2004
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is one of my top 10 movies. The trip Masatoshi Nagase has to make in the movie is priceless. Despite the annoying people, criminals, freezing temperatures and using various mode of transportation, he never one complains. I think in some ways he discovers something about himself and his parents that he didn't know before this trip. Also of how strong he really had become with determination. First time I saw this movie a few years back, I realize that I too have to take a trip home (Caribbean) pay tribute to my Dad. Just hope it won't take me as long to get to my destination. So in part I can relate to this movie.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Interesting movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Martijn F
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/1/2003
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I like this one quite a bit! It is a bit extraordinary, with a good storie, good acting of the head actor, and especially beautiful music (Icelandic, a bit like Sigur Ros/ Bjork with classical influences). I believe the music is composed by the person who also composed the music for the Icelandic movie "Angels of the universe", or "Englar alheimsins" (brilliant music!), from which I have the soundtrack (composed by Hilmarsson AND Sigur Ros!!!). This here is also good, charming, and with superb and beautiful settings and pictures of a beautiful country: Iceland! So try it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Odd and intriguing
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    zetes
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/7/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Masatoshi Nagase (best known for his role in Jarmusch's Mystery Train, and also the Japanese films Suicide Club, The Hidden Blade and Electric Dragon 80.000V) stars as a Japanese man whose grandfather (cult director Seijun Suzuki, who appears for a couple of minutes) insists he spend his vacation performing traditional burial rites of his parents, who died while living in Iceland. Nagase flies to Reykjavik and proceeds to drive across the country in the middle of the winter to the remote spot where they passed. Though they don't go into any details on his parents' death, Iceland seems like a very likely place to die, since it's full of dangerous, unpopulated terrain. This is basically a road movie, where Nagase meets various odd people along his way. It's maybe a bit weirder than most - I'd say it's kind of one of those weird-for-the-sake-of-weird type movies. But Fridriksson does a great job of making his home country look like a world of wonder. "Iceland is very strange country" Nagase always says when someone asks him what he thinks of it, in English of course, since it's the common language between him and most Icelanders (I'd say about 80% of the dialogue is in English). The film doesn't really go anywhere plot-wise, and some of the episodes are more successful than others. The most notable flop is the long sequence where Nagase picks up a couple of stranded American tourists, Fisher Stevens and Lili Taylor. Those two are painfully annoying, especially when they talk to each other via their sock puppets. That's really some needless quirk. Overall, though, I was intrigued.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Wonderful
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Maurizio
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/10/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is really a wonderful film! I might be a little influenced by the fact that I've been to Iceland twice and I loved it (and still do, and pretty surely there's going to be a third time), but I really did feel this movie. The storyline is quite simple and has been well described by other reviewers, so straight to what this movie contains. Well, anybody who's been to Iceland will realize immediately the high grade of realism, both in the landscapes and in the people the main man meets on his way, their attitudes, mentality, way of talking and all the rest. Icelanders really ARE the way you see them in this movie! Also the atmosphere of the country in the winter is perfect, deeply charming in its desolation. But whats gets the most in this film is the humanity of the various characters. The main man is a likable guy, a little stiff in his behaving with the rest of the world, but that might be part of the Japanese culture as far as I know. Completely unlikable the two Americans, who are indeed negative characters, while I loved the old man who befriends the protagonist in the last part of the movie. The deepest humanity is to be found in him. This is a movie that will get stuck into your mind for a very long time, don't miss it!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Points to the intertextuality of Icelandic and Japanese film elements
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    scf-8
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/3/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I saw Cold Fever when it was first released in the U.S. and have been (unsuccessfully so far) looking for it for about 5 years to see it again. Some of the other comments have pointed to the way the Japanese and Icelandic elements--of folklore and spirituality, principally--weave together. I have always thought it was a beautiful homage to Kurosawa and perhaps other Japanese filmmakers, not just in the plot (which others have correctly seen as a "road movie") but in the whole pacing and look of the film--the colors, the composition of scenes, the attention to the characters. It's really too bad more people haven't seen it. Hirata's enlightenment through his contacts with other characters who may be real, delusional (he is, in fact, fevered), or actual ghosts or spirits is compelling and thought-provoking for the viewer, who must also question what is "real," as well as what it means.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    What a movie!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    wmchase65
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/9/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    In Cold Fever Fredrick Thor Fredrickson gives the viewer a peak into the Incelandic culture. Simply a beautiful film...15 years ago I was an exchange student and lived in Keflavik for a semester. It was the time of my life. While in Iceland a met some amazing people. One person in particular (an icelandic national) I consider one of my best friend today. I've been back to Iceland 5 times since, and he (and his family) have also visited me here in the states numerous times too...Needlesstosay, Iceland has a very spcecial place in my heart... People often ask me "so what's Iceland like?" Of course I tell them all I know, but if they really want to get a glimpse into Iceland, I have them watch "cold fever".....truly a great piece of art!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Film stuck in my head for last 5 years
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Graham Stanford
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/2/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Something about this film has kept me thinking about it since I saw it in 2001. I had the fortunate opportunity to see it because, at that time, Des Moines (Iowa) had one of the best indie-movie rental places (Oddities), ever. Oddities just stocked walls of foreign films and rows of independent films. Cold fever had the intriguing elements of a young Japenese businessman reluctantly, and by family obligation, traveling around Iceland. That was enough for us to want to check it out. The story is tremendous. I love the style and the performances give by the actors. Fri&eth;rik &THORN;&oacute;r Fri&eth;riksson really captures the feeling of the main character on film. It is almost haunting how Hirata operates... how he meanders through the vastness of the landscape. Great film, great ending. I wish they would get it on DVD along with other works by the director
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Teny Years On - The Film Still Works
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    robert-642
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/5/2005
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Ten years later this very compact film still works its magic. Much has been said by many of the other contributors with one exception. It is not a film to be rushed. Rather you need to view at the speed the film dictates - not unlike "Paris, Texas. Like the swirling mists and snow it slowly envelops you. No frame is wasted. Even a casual remark in the aeroplane en-route to Iceland gives a link for the future. Many different cultures have their cultural layers peeled back; American, Japanese, Icelandic and Norse mythology. It's up to the viewer to see what he or she sees. I think the most telling scene in the film is the Icelander who befriends Hirata. Although he does not want to accompany Hirata to the ritual grave scene because of a 'spirit dream', he nonetheless is there to show him the way home. In so doing, he witnesses a universal value with Hirate - the passing of life. There's much to be said for good small budget films. The story and direction have to be tightly constrained.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Much more than a tourist advertisement
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    lowkeylysmythe
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/11/2004
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This film is indeed a beautiful film showing Iceland's many attractions as the previous reviewer mentioned, but it also draws very interesting parallels between the native beliefs of Icelanders, which in fact are quite similar to what prevailed across Europe before Christianity came(Iceland was settled by Vikings and was among the last places Europeans held to their pagan religion), and the Shinto practices in Japan. One accompanies the main character, a shallow, immature corporate executive from his comfortable Tokyo life to Iceland: where layer by layer he is stripped of comfort, certainty, even rationality, until he is brought to a place where he realizes a simple and profound humanity. This film is funny, the cinematography is amazing, and it is spiritually enriching. How many films can you say all that about?
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Magnificent Film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Tathata (Tathata@comcast.net)
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/9/2004
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A wonderful spiritual comedy. The cinematography is unchallengeable. A beautiful landscape that oft times provides the illusion the filming was done in black and white. For those who love films about the majestic and mysterious journey of life, this one is not to be missed. On my top 10 list and waiting for release on DVD. In order to meet the 10 line minimum comment, I am forced into verbosity. Favorite scenes include the singing men in the truck, the cowboy bar, the conversation with the sheep's head, and of course the journey's revelation. For you Northerner's, ingnor the fact our hero would have frozen to death in the first 15 minutes and hear the message. Truly, this one could tempt you to vacation in Iceland.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Trip for the soul...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Martin
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/2/2004
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is one of my top 10 movies. The trip Masatoshi Nagase has to make in the movie is priceless. Despite the annoying people, criminals, freezing temperatures and using various mode of transportation, he never one complains. I think in some ways he discovers something about himself and his parents that he didn't know before this trip. Also of how strong he really had become with determination. First time I saw this movie a few years back, I realize that I too have to take a trip home (Caribbean) pay tribute to my Dad. Just hope it won't take me as long to get to my destination. So in part I can relate to this movie.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Interesting movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Martijn F
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/1/2003
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I like this one quite a bit! It is a bit extraordinary, with a good storie, good acting of the head actor, and especially beautiful music (Icelandic, a bit like Sigur Ros/ Bjork with classical influences). I believe the music is composed by the person who also composed the music for the Icelandic movie "Angels of the universe", or "Englar alheimsins" (brilliant music!), from which I have the soundtrack (composed by Hilmarsson AND Sigur Ros!!!). This here is also good, charming, and with superb and beautiful settings and pictures of a beautiful country: Iceland! So try it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Odd and intriguing
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    zetes
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/7/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Masatoshi Nagase (best known for his role in Jarmusch's Mystery Train, and also the Japanese films Suicide Club, The Hidden Blade and Electric Dragon 80.000V) stars as a Japanese man whose grandfather (cult director Seijun Suzuki, who appears for a couple of minutes) insists he spend his vacation performing traditional burial rites of his parents, who died while living in Iceland. Nagase flies to Reykjavik and proceeds to drive across the country in the middle of the winter to the remote spot where they passed. Though they don't go into any details on his parents' death, Iceland seems like a very likely place to die, since it's full of dangerous, unpopulated terrain. This is basically a road movie, where Nagase meets various odd people along his way. It's maybe a bit weirder than most - I'd say it's kind of one of those weird-for-the-sake-of-weird type movies. But Fridriksson does a great job of making his home country look like a world of wonder. "Iceland is very strange country" Nagase always says when someone asks him what he thinks of it, in English of course, since it's the common language between him and most Icelanders (I'd say about 80% of the dialogue is in English). The film doesn't really go anywhere plot-wise, and some of the episodes are more successful than others. The most notable flop is the long sequence where Nagase picks up a couple of stranded American tourists, Fisher Stevens and Lili Taylor. Those two are painfully annoying, especially when they talk to each other via their sock puppets. That's really some needless quirk. Overall, though, I was intrigued.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Wonderful
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Maurizio
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/10/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is really a wonderful film! I might be a little influenced by the fact that I've been to Iceland twice and I loved it (and still do, and pretty surely there's going to be a third time), but I really did feel this movie. The storyline is quite simple and has been well described by other reviewers, so straight to what this movie contains. Well, anybody who's been to Iceland will realize immediately the high grade of realism, both in the landscapes and in the people the main man meets on his way, their attitudes, mentality, way of talking and all the rest. Icelanders really ARE the way you see them in this movie! Also the atmosphere of the country in the winter is perfect, deeply charming in its desolation. But whats gets the most in this film is the humanity of the various characters. The main man is a likable guy, a little stiff in his behaving with the rest of the world, but that might be part of the Japanese culture as far as I know. Completely unlikable the two Americans, who are indeed negative characters, while I loved the old man who befriends the protagonist in the last part of the movie. The deepest humanity is to be found in him. This is a movie that will get stuck into your mind for a very long time, don't miss it!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Points to the intertextuality of Icelandic and Japanese film elements
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    scf-8
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/3/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I saw Cold Fever when it was first released in the U.S. and have been (unsuccessfully so far) looking for it for about 5 years to see it again. Some of the other comments have pointed to the way the Japanese and Icelandic elements--of folklore and spirituality, principally--weave together. I have always thought it was a beautiful homage to Kurosawa and perhaps other Japanese filmmakers, not just in the plot (which others have correctly seen as a "road movie") but in the whole pacing and look of the film--the colors, the composition of scenes, the attention to the characters. It's really too bad more people haven't seen it. Hirata's enlightenment through his contacts with other characters who may be real, delusional (he is, in fact, fevered), or actual ghosts or spirits is compelling and thought-provoking for the viewer, who must also question what is "real," as well as what it means.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    What a movie!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    wmchase65
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/9/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    In Cold Fever Fredrick Thor Fredrickson gives the viewer a peak into the Incelandic culture. Simply a beautiful film...15 years ago I was an exchange student and lived in Keflavik for a semester. It was the time of my life. While in Iceland a met some amazing people. One person in particular (an icelandic national) I consider one of my best friend today. I've been back to Iceland 5 times since, and he (and his family) have also visited me here in the states numerous times too...Needlesstosay, Iceland has a very spcecial place in my heart... People often ask me "so what's Iceland like?" Of course I tell them all I know, but if they really want to get a glimpse into Iceland, I have them watch "cold fever".....truly a great piece of art!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Film stuck in my head for last 5 years
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Graham Stanford
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/2/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Something about this film has kept me thinking about it since I saw it in 2001. I had the fortunate opportunity to see it because, at that time, Des Moines (Iowa) had one of the best indie-movie rental places (Oddities), ever. Oddities just stocked walls of foreign films and rows of independent films. Cold fever had the intriguing elements of a young Japenese businessman reluctantly, and by family obligation, traveling around Iceland. That was enough for us to want to check it out. The story is tremendous. I love the style and the performances give by the actors. Fri&eth;rik &THORN;&oacute;r Fri&eth;riksson really captures the feeling of the main character on film. It is almost haunting how Hirata operates... how he meanders through the vastness of the landscape. Great film, great ending. I wish they would get it on DVD along with other works by the director
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Teny Years On - The Film Still Works
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    robert-642
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/5/2005
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Ten years later this very compact film still works its magic. Much has been said by many of the other contributors with one exception. It is not a film to be rushed. Rather you need to view at the speed the film dictates - not unlike "Paris, Texas. Like the swirling mists and snow it slowly envelops you. No frame is wasted. Even a casual remark in the aeroplane en-route to Iceland gives a link for the future. Many different cultures have their cultural layers peeled back; American, Japanese, Icelandic and Norse mythology. It's up to the viewer to see what he or she sees. I think the most telling scene in the film is the Icelander who befriends Hirata. Although he does not want to accompany Hirata to the ritual grave scene because of a 'spirit dream', he nonetheless is there to show him the way home. In so doing, he witnesses a universal value with Hirate - the passing of life. There's much to be said for good small budget films. The story and direction have to be tightly constrained.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Much more than a tourist advertisement
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    lowkeylysmythe
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/11/2004
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This film is indeed a beautiful film showing Iceland's many attractions as the previous reviewer mentioned, but it also draws very interesting parallels between the native beliefs of Icelanders, which in fact are quite similar to what prevailed across Europe before Christianity came(Iceland was settled by Vikings and was among the last places Europeans held to their pagan religion), and the Shinto practices in Japan. One accompanies the main character, a shallow, immature corporate executive from his comfortable Tokyo life to Iceland: where layer by layer he is stripped of comfort, certainty, even rationality, until he is brought to a place where he realizes a simple and profound humanity. This film is funny, the cinematography is amazing, and it is spiritually enriching. How many films can you say all that about?
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Magnificent Film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Tathata (Tathata@comcast.net)
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/9/2004
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A wonderful spiritual comedy. The cinematography is unchallengeable. A beautiful landscape that oft times provides the illusion the filming was done in black and white. For those who love films about the majestic and mysterious journey of life, this one is not to be missed. On my top 10 list and waiting for release on DVD. In order to meet the 10 line minimum comment, I am forced into verbosity. Favorite scenes include the singing men in the truck, the cowboy bar, the conversation with the sheep's head, and of course the journey's revelation. For you Northerner's, ingnor the fact our hero would have frozen to death in the first 15 minutes and hear the message. Truly, this one could tempt you to vacation in Iceland.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Trip for the soul...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Martin
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/2/2004
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is one of my top 10 movies. The trip Masatoshi Nagase has to make in the movie is priceless. Despite the annoying people, criminals, freezing temperatures and using various mode of transportation, he never one complains. I think in some ways he discovers something about himself and his parents that he didn't know before this trip. Also of how strong he really had become with determination. First time I saw this movie a few years back, I realize that I too have to take a trip home (Caribbean) pay tribute to my Dad. Just hope it won't take me as long to get to my destination. So in part I can relate to this movie.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Interesting movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Martijn F
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/1/2003
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I like this one quite a bit! It is a bit extraordinary, with a good storie, good acting of the head actor, and especially beautiful music (Icelandic, a bit like Sigur Ros/ Bjork with classical influences). I believe the music is composed by the person who also composed the music for the Icelandic movie "Angels of the universe", or "Englar alheimsins" (brilliant music!), from which I have the soundtrack (composed by Hilmarsson AND Sigur Ros!!!). This here is also good, charming, and with superb and beautiful settings and pictures of a beautiful country: Iceland! So try it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
 </reviews>
</filme>
