<filme>
 <id>
  1637
 </id>
 <imdburl>
  http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0116418
 </imdburl>
 <ano>
  1996
 </ano>
 <titulo>
  Girls Town
 </titulo>
 <rating>
  5.7
 </rating>
 <sinopse>
  A look at a group of girl friends coming-of-age during their senior year of high school in urban America. Nikki and Emma have a heart to heart talk one evening about how much they'll miss ... &nbsp;&raquo;
 </sinopse>
 <storyline>
  A look at a group of girl friends coming-of-age during their senior year of high school in urban America. Nikki and Emma have a heart to heart talk one evening about how much they'll miss each other at college next year, but the next day, Nikki doesn't show up at school: she's committed suicide. The friends steal Nikki's journal and discover that she'd been raped. The rest of the movie shows our heroines growing closer in the wake of Nikki's death and the relevation of her secret (Emma reveals that she's also been raped), taking revenge on the men who oppress them, and trying to grow up and move on with their lives. Emma has to deal with a shallow boyfriend, Angela with an overbearing mother, and Patti is trying to finish high school while trying to raise a child and avoid the child's loser father.
 </storyline>
 <generos>
  <genero>
   Comedy
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Drama
  </genero>
 </generos>
 <keywords>
  <keyword>
   high school
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   suicide
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   cigarette smoking
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   teenage mother
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   rape victim
  </keyword>
 </keywords>
 <diretores>
  <diretor>
   Jim McKay
  </diretor>
 </diretores>
 <escritores>
  <escritor>
   Jim McKay
  </escritor>
  <escritor>
   Denise Casano
  </escritor>
 </escritores>
 <atores>
  <ator>
   Lili Taylor
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Bruklin Harris
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Anna Grace
  </ator>
 </atores>
 <reviews>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Subvert the patriarchy!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    maggielassie
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/12/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Awesome film. A coming-of-age film that contains a very realistic depiction of urban life and growing up in a big city. In it, 3 straight teenage girls (Patti, Angela and Emma) lose their friend Nikki, who mysteriously kills herself. Eager to find out why she did that, they manage to retrieve a journal from her home, and they soon find out that their friend committed suicide because she had been raped while she was doing an internship at a magazine company. Then the 3 girls start talking to each other about the things that have recently been going on in their lives. They soon find out that they too have been/are being forced into sex by the men they've been with (or are being with). They start writing some "Subvert the patriarchy!" graffiti on their school's bathroom doors, and start making plans to take revenge on all the men that have treated/are treating them like s***. A wonderful scene is when they all wreck the car of the guy who'd raped Emma. She'd been raped at the back of his car so this was all so powerfully symbolic to take revenge that way. I couldn't stop laughing when the three girls trash the car. :D Patti's boyfriend is very violent towards her, and they also had some awesome plans to deal with him too, which ultimately will lead to them making plans against the rapist who was at least partly responsible for Nikki's death. Great film. There aren't many films like this in which poor working-class women unite together (across race divisions) and try hard to deal with a misogynistic, racist patriarchal society. The way they start feeling the harsh symptoms of it is telling. I loved the Audre Lorde quote ("The fact that we are here and that I speak these words is an attempt to break that silence and bridge some of those differences between us, for it is not difference which immobilizes us, but silence. And there are so many silences to be broken.") near the end, suggesting that the three teenage girls have been researching into feminism, quoting from a black lesbian feminist of the Second Wave. The 1990's female rap music enhances the film. I think there might have been more female rap artists in the 90's, before all the sexist hip hop took over. The only downside is that the film was a tad bit slow at one point, and some scenes could have been replaced with others, better ones.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A little on the feminist side, but okay drama.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    fedor8
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/9/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The only real problem I have with this film is that it implies that men are the cause of most - if not practically all - of women's problems. In its quest to prove this point the film gives an unrepresentative portrayal of men, and treads into feminist waters. It isn't representative because two of the four girls were (date-)raped. That's 50%. And of the other two one is constantly beaten by her child's father. That's 75% abused, altogether. After Taylor hears that two of her friends (including the suicide girl) were date-raped she says that this is completely common and so normal it isn't even worth talking about. This is nonsense; I find it hard to believe that male urban youth of America mostly consists of violent thugs and rapists. Later on Taylor complains that she would never get hired as a mechanic because she is a woman. (Who had the brilliant idea of casting Taylor as a hobby mechanic?!) And what's this PC nonsense about date-rape anyway? Americans have too few ("real") problems so they have to invent them. The girl with the long nails is supposed to play basketball; and how exactly does she manage to do that, with those gross, gigantic nails? She couldn't play golf with those things! And how come the white girl didn't get into trouble with the guy whose car she demolished (since the whole school knew who did it)? As far as the girl who committed suicide is concerned, at the beginning of the film she expresses her wish to study "African-American history". (She gets accepted into Princeton but she decides to waste it on something useless as that. Who's gonna hire her with a degree like that?) Otherwise, this film about the increasingly dumbed-down (American) youth is interesting to watch. The revenge scenes are fun, and the dialog is generally good. Taylor is quite good. The (c)rap soundtrack is hideous, though (but fitting in a way, I suppose).
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Great slice of high school
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Chris Newfield
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/6/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I accidentally ran into this movie on the Sundance channel and couldn't stop watching it. Menace and danger plus banality and boredom - high school from top to bottom, and nothing that anyone does or says in this really well-acted film is anything other than exactly what a 17-year-old would do or say. Good moments include the teen mom telling off a guy for dogging her one day and accepting his charm offensive the next; the only visible mom having no ability to say any unangry, unjudgemental thing to her tough, suffering daughter; and the ineffective and heartbreaking confrontation with the guy the three friends think drove their fourth friend to suicide. The girls are p_ssed, resentful, revengeful, smart, excited, violent, and together all in on the right scale - an excellent girls' Dazed and Confused that gets a perfect 10 for realness.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Who would want to hang out with these girls?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ChelseaGirl98
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/1/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I liked this movie's realism; it was shot in documentary style so it seemed almost as if the dialog were being improvised. The acting was excellent too. However, several of the characters were not very likable, which is a major problem in a film. Oddly, while the dialog was very real, many of the situations were not. Lily Taylor's character is foul-mouthed and obnoxious, and dresses like a boy even though she is past her teens. It is inconceivable that anyone would want to sleep with her, yet she seems to have no trouble finding sex partners. Emma is nasty to her boyfriend, who tries to be decent to her, and he's cute too. What on earth would he see in her? It sure can't be her looks. It simply doesn't add up.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Underdeveloped and Overrated
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    emosrhott
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/1/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    When I first starting watching this film, I assumed it would be a great film that follows in the style of KIDS. However, after watching twenty minutes of it, I became sorely disappointed. The "urban" girls in the film, which are seen outside a convenience store talking vulgarly and are seemingly all troubled, are really not as troubled as they seem. The only person in this whole movie that warrants sympathy is Patti, who apparently is a single mother that got pregnant young, although she seems way older than the rest and is teased for being held back in high school for years. She's supposed to be commended for being a good mother, however you rarely see her child and you see her drinking and smoking all the time. The girls all give speeches, and they all seem to be well-adjusted. Nikki, the girl that kills herself, has been accepted to Princeton, and before she kills herself, nothing seems to be wrong at all. After she kills herself, however, her friends are upset for a bit, and on the same day of her death, they visit her mother and have the audacity to ask her if Nikki wrote a note. The mother then gets upset and kicks them out(an incident that makes the girls call her a bitch), but one of them, Emma (who is a white girl that is about to leave for Columbia), manages to steal her journal, where it is discovered that she was raped. The movie then turns into a weird Thelma and Louise type story of women who are out to get rapists. The movie dwells too much on an incident where these girls trash a "rapist"'s car, and then go on to brag about it. However, they try to act like they didn't do it when anyone says anything about it. Also, the journal included the name of Nikki's rapist, and instead of handing it over to the authorities or leaving it in Nikki's room to be discovered by her parents, they kick the guys in the balls and harass him a bit, and that's how the movie ends. In conclusion, this movie is very, very trite, should have been way more developed and edited, and includes about an hour and a half of stuff that isn't necessary. You're supposed to feel sympathy for these girls, but their attitudes, ignorance, and carelessness, warrants nothing of the sort.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    This film is why the indie are the only films that matter
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    leparrain5
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/1/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Lili Taylor is excellent in this film (as per usual). After watching this film I only wish that we could see more of the other two female actors (Bruklin Harris and Anna Grace) in this film do more work. A dark film that hits home because of the solid in the moment acting. A special film. The film credits these three fine women actors with writing credits a long with the director and Denise Casano. When watching the film you feel as if you are there due to the fine acting and excellent editing. I wish we could see more from the other two actors because they were really good in this film... it seems that this film is a lost gem.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    This Ain't 90210!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    malaga21
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/11/2005
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    What makes this movie amazing is the simplicity. The realness of the actors (thanks to an amazing sense of improv by the three leads) is what makes this my all-time favorite movie. It is the only film I can watch consecutively and never get tired of it. Jim McKay is an amazing director, as he has come out with some other good films, but, to me, none have topped this one. Lili Taylor is phenomenal as a "street-wise" single mother still in high school. Bruklyn Harris' AngelA! is a character I would personally love to be friends with and Anna Grace's style is perfect for a teenage girl. For anyone who grew up in Queens, Brooklyn, or the Bronx, this movie brings much familiarity. For those who've never been, this film will take you there.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Provocations!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    voltaire80usa
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/5/2005
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Despite previous reviews, I felt this movie was really well thought out, I saw this movie when it first came out and it definitely reached me. The subject touches but not meant to be a description of urban life at all. If you see the movie, you will understand what the real issue is. I am going to have to disagree with the dude who posted previously, this movie is geared towards anyone who believes in the issues that plague our youth and our young girls of color. It makes you want to break down the ideals that perpetuate class-ism, the gender binary and other issues that separate people. I hope others see it for what it is. Its reflective of the type of role our society and communities play in a developing child's mind. I think it should be shown to a mixed audience of boys and girls so that they can see the perspective of the other sex. I think it speaks a lot about violence in our schools.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Film loses focus
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    rosscinema (rosscinema@comcast.net)
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/2/2003
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is a film that starts out being about one thing and then ignores that and becomes about nothing! Film starts out with a group of high school friends and suddenly one of them commits suicide. After a few weak attempts at trying to figure out why their friend would do such a thing the film goes into another direction of abusive boyfriends and bickering among themselves. These girls have so much attitude that it becomes impossible to feel any sympathy for them. Then at the end of the film they put in some unbelievable plot device to answer the question for the friends suicide. Totally contrived. The only thing worth watching is Lili Taylor as she shows us once again she can play just about any type of character. Here she plays a dumb white girl that grew up in a black neighborhood and inherited all the urban problems. But the script needed a rewrite badly and director Jim McKay and Taylor who help write this film need more of a focus point to the story. This film just stumbles about aimlessly!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    What a great movie!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Jonathan
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/10/2002
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie is one of the best i've seen. Dramatic and heart-breakingly funny. 'Girls Town' is the tale of three teenagers girls from the wrong side of town, there's Nikki, who has the cahnce to attend at Princeton, Patti a single teen mother, Angela who has to deal with an overbearing mother and Emma who has the problem of dealing with over shallow boyfriends. But one day, out of the blue, Nikki doesn't turn up to school, she's killed her self. After the other girls steal her diary they find out that Nikki has been raped, thus the girls set out on a journey of self-discovery to make the men in their lifes that have hurt them, pay big time!. I feel for all the girls, being a teen my self, it made me think of how life is growing up, especially girls. A master piece of a movie for which Lili Taylor who plays Patti deserved an Oscar. Brilliant!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Subvert the patriarchy!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    maggielassie
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/12/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Awesome film. A coming-of-age film that contains a very realistic depiction of urban life and growing up in a big city. In it, 3 straight teenage girls (Patti, Angela and Emma) lose their friend Nikki, who mysteriously kills herself. Eager to find out why she did that, they manage to retrieve a journal from her home, and they soon find out that their friend committed suicide because she had been raped while she was doing an internship at a magazine company. Then the 3 girls start talking to each other about the things that have recently been going on in their lives. They soon find out that they too have been/are being forced into sex by the men they've been with (or are being with). They start writing some "Subvert the patriarchy!" graffiti on their school's bathroom doors, and start making plans to take revenge on all the men that have treated/are treating them like s***. A wonderful scene is when they all wreck the car of the guy who'd raped Emma. She'd been raped at the back of his car so this was all so powerfully symbolic to take revenge that way. I couldn't stop laughing when the three girls trash the car. :D Patti's boyfriend is very violent towards her, and they also had some awesome plans to deal with him too, which ultimately will lead to them making plans against the rapist who was at least partly responsible for Nikki's death. Great film. There aren't many films like this in which poor working-class women unite together (across race divisions) and try hard to deal with a misogynistic, racist patriarchal society. The way they start feeling the harsh symptoms of it is telling. I loved the Audre Lorde quote ("The fact that we are here and that I speak these words is an attempt to break that silence and bridge some of those differences between us, for it is not difference which immobilizes us, but silence. And there are so many silences to be broken.") near the end, suggesting that the three teenage girls have been researching into feminism, quoting from a black lesbian feminist of the Second Wave. The 1990's female rap music enhances the film. I think there might have been more female rap artists in the 90's, before all the sexist hip hop took over. The only downside is that the film was a tad bit slow at one point, and some scenes could have been replaced with others, better ones.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A little on the feminist side, but okay drama.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    fedor8
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/9/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The only real problem I have with this film is that it implies that men are the cause of most - if not practically all - of women's problems. In its quest to prove this point the film gives an unrepresentative portrayal of men, and treads into feminist waters. It isn't representative because two of the four girls were (date-)raped. That's 50%. And of the other two one is constantly beaten by her child's father. That's 75% abused, altogether. After Taylor hears that two of her friends (including the suicide girl) were date-raped she says that this is completely common and so normal it isn't even worth talking about. This is nonsense; I find it hard to believe that male urban youth of America mostly consists of violent thugs and rapists. Later on Taylor complains that she would never get hired as a mechanic because she is a woman. (Who had the brilliant idea of casting Taylor as a hobby mechanic?!) And what's this PC nonsense about date-rape anyway? Americans have too few ("real") problems so they have to invent them. The girl with the long nails is supposed to play basketball; and how exactly does she manage to do that, with those gross, gigantic nails? She couldn't play golf with those things! And how come the white girl didn't get into trouble with the guy whose car she demolished (since the whole school knew who did it)? As far as the girl who committed suicide is concerned, at the beginning of the film she expresses her wish to study "African-American history". (She gets accepted into Princeton but she decides to waste it on something useless as that. Who's gonna hire her with a degree like that?) Otherwise, this film about the increasingly dumbed-down (American) youth is interesting to watch. The revenge scenes are fun, and the dialog is generally good. Taylor is quite good. The (c)rap soundtrack is hideous, though (but fitting in a way, I suppose).
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Great slice of high school
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Chris Newfield
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/6/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I accidentally ran into this movie on the Sundance channel and couldn't stop watching it. Menace and danger plus banality and boredom - high school from top to bottom, and nothing that anyone does or says in this really well-acted film is anything other than exactly what a 17-year-old would do or say. Good moments include the teen mom telling off a guy for dogging her one day and accepting his charm offensive the next; the only visible mom having no ability to say any unangry, unjudgemental thing to her tough, suffering daughter; and the ineffective and heartbreaking confrontation with the guy the three friends think drove their fourth friend to suicide. The girls are p_ssed, resentful, revengeful, smart, excited, violent, and together all in on the right scale - an excellent girls' Dazed and Confused that gets a perfect 10 for realness.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Who would want to hang out with these girls?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ChelseaGirl98
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/1/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I liked this movie's realism; it was shot in documentary style so it seemed almost as if the dialog were being improvised. The acting was excellent too. However, several of the characters were not very likable, which is a major problem in a film. Oddly, while the dialog was very real, many of the situations were not. Lily Taylor's character is foul-mouthed and obnoxious, and dresses like a boy even though she is past her teens. It is inconceivable that anyone would want to sleep with her, yet she seems to have no trouble finding sex partners. Emma is nasty to her boyfriend, who tries to be decent to her, and he's cute too. What on earth would he see in her? It sure can't be her looks. It simply doesn't add up.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Underdeveloped and Overrated
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    emosrhott
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/1/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    When I first starting watching this film, I assumed it would be a great film that follows in the style of KIDS. However, after watching twenty minutes of it, I became sorely disappointed. The "urban" girls in the film, which are seen outside a convenience store talking vulgarly and are seemingly all troubled, are really not as troubled as they seem. The only person in this whole movie that warrants sympathy is Patti, who apparently is a single mother that got pregnant young, although she seems way older than the rest and is teased for being held back in high school for years. She's supposed to be commended for being a good mother, however you rarely see her child and you see her drinking and smoking all the time. The girls all give speeches, and they all seem to be well-adjusted. Nikki, the girl that kills herself, has been accepted to Princeton, and before she kills herself, nothing seems to be wrong at all. After she kills herself, however, her friends are upset for a bit, and on the same day of her death, they visit her mother and have the audacity to ask her if Nikki wrote a note. The mother then gets upset and kicks them out(an incident that makes the girls call her a bitch), but one of them, Emma (who is a white girl that is about to leave for Columbia), manages to steal her journal, where it is discovered that she was raped. The movie then turns into a weird Thelma and Louise type story of women who are out to get rapists. The movie dwells too much on an incident where these girls trash a "rapist"'s car, and then go on to brag about it. However, they try to act like they didn't do it when anyone says anything about it. Also, the journal included the name of Nikki's rapist, and instead of handing it over to the authorities or leaving it in Nikki's room to be discovered by her parents, they kick the guys in the balls and harass him a bit, and that's how the movie ends. In conclusion, this movie is very, very trite, should have been way more developed and edited, and includes about an hour and a half of stuff that isn't necessary. You're supposed to feel sympathy for these girls, but their attitudes, ignorance, and carelessness, warrants nothing of the sort.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    This film is why the indie are the only films that matter
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    leparrain5
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/1/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Lili Taylor is excellent in this film (as per usual). After watching this film I only wish that we could see more of the other two female actors (Bruklin Harris and Anna Grace) in this film do more work. A dark film that hits home because of the solid in the moment acting. A special film. The film credits these three fine women actors with writing credits a long with the director and Denise Casano. When watching the film you feel as if you are there due to the fine acting and excellent editing. I wish we could see more from the other two actors because they were really good in this film... it seems that this film is a lost gem.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    This Ain't 90210!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    malaga21
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/11/2005
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    What makes this movie amazing is the simplicity. The realness of the actors (thanks to an amazing sense of improv by the three leads) is what makes this my all-time favorite movie. It is the only film I can watch consecutively and never get tired of it. Jim McKay is an amazing director, as he has come out with some other good films, but, to me, none have topped this one. Lili Taylor is phenomenal as a "street-wise" single mother still in high school. Bruklyn Harris' AngelA! is a character I would personally love to be friends with and Anna Grace's style is perfect for a teenage girl. For anyone who grew up in Queens, Brooklyn, or the Bronx, this movie brings much familiarity. For those who've never been, this film will take you there.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Provocations!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    voltaire80usa
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/5/2005
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Despite previous reviews, I felt this movie was really well thought out, I saw this movie when it first came out and it definitely reached me. The subject touches but not meant to be a description of urban life at all. If you see the movie, you will understand what the real issue is. I am going to have to disagree with the dude who posted previously, this movie is geared towards anyone who believes in the issues that plague our youth and our young girls of color. It makes you want to break down the ideals that perpetuate class-ism, the gender binary and other issues that separate people. I hope others see it for what it is. Its reflective of the type of role our society and communities play in a developing child's mind. I think it should be shown to a mixed audience of boys and girls so that they can see the perspective of the other sex. I think it speaks a lot about violence in our schools.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Film loses focus
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    rosscinema (rosscinema@comcast.net)
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/2/2003
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is a film that starts out being about one thing and then ignores that and becomes about nothing! Film starts out with a group of high school friends and suddenly one of them commits suicide. After a few weak attempts at trying to figure out why their friend would do such a thing the film goes into another direction of abusive boyfriends and bickering among themselves. These girls have so much attitude that it becomes impossible to feel any sympathy for them. Then at the end of the film they put in some unbelievable plot device to answer the question for the friends suicide. Totally contrived. The only thing worth watching is Lili Taylor as she shows us once again she can play just about any type of character. Here she plays a dumb white girl that grew up in a black neighborhood and inherited all the urban problems. But the script needed a rewrite badly and director Jim McKay and Taylor who help write this film need more of a focus point to the story. This film just stumbles about aimlessly!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    What a great movie!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Jonathan
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/10/2002
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie is one of the best i've seen. Dramatic and heart-breakingly funny. 'Girls Town' is the tale of three teenagers girls from the wrong side of town, there's Nikki, who has the cahnce to attend at Princeton, Patti a single teen mother, Angela who has to deal with an overbearing mother and Emma who has the problem of dealing with over shallow boyfriends. But one day, out of the blue, Nikki doesn't turn up to school, she's killed her self. After the other girls steal her diary they find out that Nikki has been raped, thus the girls set out on a journey of self-discovery to make the men in their lifes that have hurt them, pay big time!. I feel for all the girls, being a teen my self, it made me think of how life is growing up, especially girls. A master piece of a movie for which Lili Taylor who plays Patti deserved an Oscar. Brilliant!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
 </reviews>
</filme>
