<filme>
 <id>
  1639
 </id>
 <imdburl>
  http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0115600
 </imdburl>
 <ano>
  1996
 </ano>
 <titulo>
  Az&uacute;car amarga
 </titulo>
 <rating>
  6.8
 </rating>
 <sinopse>
  Gustavo is a young Havana Communist who believes in the revolution; he hopes for a scholarship to study aeronautical engineering in Prague. But his faith in the new Cuba is tested: his ... &nbsp;&raquo;
 </sinopse>
 <storyline>
  Gustavo is a young Havana Communist who believes in the revolution; he hopes for a scholarship to study aeronautical engineering in Prague. But his faith in the new Cuba is tested: his father, a psychiatrist, can make four times as much playing piano at a hotel for foreigners; his sweetheart, Yolanda, wants a career as a dancer and longs for the riches of Miami; his younger brother Bobby simply wants to play rock music, and as a result is in constant trouble with the authorities. When Bobby takes a shocking step of revolt and Gustavo is refused service at a foreigners-only bar, the contradictions in his resolve to become a "new man" push him to the breaking point.
 </storyline>
 <generos>
  <genero>
   Drama
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Romance
  </genero>
 </generos>
 <keywords>
  <keyword>
   communist
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   aeronautical engineering
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   scholarship
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   hotel
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   psychiatrist
  </keyword>
 </keywords>
 <diretores>
  <diretor>
   Leon Ichaso
  </diretor>
 </diretores>
 <escritores>
  <escritor>
   Pelayo Garc&iacute;a
  </escritor>
  <escritor>
   Leon Ichaso
  </escritor>
 </escritores>
 <atores>
  <ator>
   Ren&eacute; Lavan
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Mayte Vil&aacute;n
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Miguel Guti&eacute;rrez
  </ator>
 </atores>
 <reviews>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Bitter Sugar
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Spuzzlightyear
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/3/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Just OK drama here exploring the hardships of living in Cuba. Gustavo tries to eak out a living in Havana while waiting to go abroad with a scholarship, his dad gets a job at a swanky tourist resort because his psychiatrist job doesn't pay enough and his brother seems to do nothing but protest all day long. Meanwhile, Gustavo has his eye on a cute little brunette, but even, yes, she has some secrets. While it's intentions are certainly genuine, I think this was a wee bit too much politics to cram into one movie. Gustavo's problems are interesting, but his brother's are just a bit unnecessary, distracting and, quite frankly, over the top to be in this movie. The cinematography is excellent and whatnot but the story could have used a little simmering down.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Unique perspective on Cuba
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    DAW-8
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/9/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Bitter Sugar addresses MORE problems associated with politics and economic systems than almost any film from any country in a single film (There should be some award for such achievements...). One of the greatest things it accomplishes is illustrating the problems with BOTH ideal-socialist Cuba (which is gradually disappearing) and the alternative, open-market Cuba that is gradually developing in the 1990s. The bad side of a socialist state/society is clearly shown with the Gustavo's naive belief in the party and promises from the party that never pay off, as well as the imprisonment of cultural/political subversives such as his brother. On the capitalist side, there is the creeping inequality associated with capitalism, which metes out privilege and opportunity to the highest bidder, thus turning the nationalist dream on its head, turning national against national, as seen in the tourist hotels and bars where locals can't afford goods and services or are turned away. This capitalism colonizes even emotions such as love, or at least sex plus the semblance of emotional presence and attachment (which some say IS love), which can be exchanged for opportunity: Gustavo's girlfriend has all the talent but no opportunity to achieve her 'ideal' career as socialism promises. This film shows how there is no perfect way out, no utopia, no perfect system. The relationships between the characters, though clich&eacute; (a couple, two brothers, father-son) and simple, work very well. Neither Gustavo nor his girlfriend are ideologues, they each come to realize that their choice is neither simple, nor certain in terms of where it will lead them. Few films have effectively shown how complicated personal politics really are in socialist/communist states. Most either just show the ruthlessness of the state, or the humanity of an individual or group of individuals against the state, without contradictions. This film is neither pro- nor anti- Castro. Or it is both/and. This is Cuban national cinema; made for the Cuban nation as opposed to the Cuban state. It is a critical reflection on the new Cuba, and thus indirectly states that socialist Cuba may be no worse, at the same time as it is a critical reflection on socialist Cuba. It addresses almost the major problems contemporary Cubans face, and the contradictions between them and in the solutions to them. If we want to engage in a debate about the bias of the film, maybe considering the director/writer is a good place to start. Leon Ichaso is Cuban-born. He directed a few episodes of Miami Vice (politically left or right? anyone?), made a few films about salsa musicians and their personal struggles or struggles to be true to their culture, a documentary about Muhammad Ali, and most recently, the TV series about terrorists in LA 'Sleeper Cell'. Only this last one, in my opinion, definitively puts him in a political camp (right wing, obviously).
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    things can get bitter in many respects
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Lee Eisenberg (eisenberg.lee@gmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/7/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    When I rented Leon Ichaso's "Azucar amarga" (or "Bitter Sugar"), I didn't realize that it was an American movie critical of Cuba's government; I assumed that it was a Cuban-made film. It portrays young ardent Communist Gustavo in Havana who has to start questioning his ideals due to events surrounding him: his love interest Yolanda wants to flee to Miami, his father can make more money performing for tourists, and his brother injects himself with AIDS-infected blood as a protest. A pretty bleak look at a society that Michael Moore practically glorified in "Sicko". Personally, I think that if anyone's going to criticize Castro's government, they should still remind people of Fulgencio Batista's brutality, which this movie doesn't. But it's still worth seeing, just as a look inside the present-day Cuba, and what people sometimes have to do to get by.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Outstanding Film!! A Must See!!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Ritzy McCarthy
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/8/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I couldn't stop thinking about this film after watching it. It is remarkable how life has deteriorated in Cuba since I left in 1980 at the tender age of fifteen. This was the same year Lavan left the island on the Mariel boat lift. My family moved to Chicago, not Miami, so I quickly blended into American society and 'forgot'about Cuba. Family members who left post Mariel often described the conditions there, but I could never bring myself to fathom so much of it was real. I'm extremely grateful to be an American citizen living the American dream. However, my heart 'cries' for the many young people who are trapped in an obsolete communist society where they can't even afford to have dreams. This movie forced me to consider how the lives of my young nieces and nephews might have turned out. My father fought for Cuba's Revolution; he was a young idealist revolutionary just like Gustavo. Dad left the island in 1986 after years of disillusionment. People who haven't lived 'it' can't comprehend it. I'm always fascinated by those individuals who are quick to criticize anti-Castro voices, even though they've never actually experienced life in an oppressive regime. How could they possibly understand that living there is like living in an insane asylum? The AIDS facility were Gustavo's brother was forcibly interned is nothing more than a microcosm of the entire island of Cuba where people hopelessly and aimlessly exist. Not live, but exist. I give this movie the highest rating. It deserves it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Despair in paradise
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jotix100
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/1/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Leon Ichaso's "Azucar Amarga" came and went without much fanfare. This was a film made with little money and without any big distributor to give it more exposure in the American market. The film is critical of the way Cuba, as a society, started the current trend after the loss of patronage of the old Soviet Union in the late eighties. In order to get the badly needed hard currency, Cuba opened its doors to a massive invasion of international tourism, mainly from Europe and South America. With that, the US dollar was legalized. The results can be seen in this film that examines that society. First of all, for those that have expressed their skepticism about the young people injecting themselves with AIDS infected blood, obviously, they haven't read the accounts by different world newspapers, and the New York Times, locally. This is a phenomenon that desperate people will resort to in order to escape the fact they are looked down in their own society for daring to be different. The other aspect one sees in the film is the prostitution being practiced among young women with college education as a way to make ends meet. This kind of sex tourism is being practiced in the island. European men flock to Cuba in search of beautiful women they couldn't otherwise afford in their own countries. Yolanda, the beautiful woman in the film, turns to the Italian Claudio as a way to have things she couldn't have otherwise. Another issue in the film involves the equality the revolution promised. When Gustavo and Yolanda go to the beach bar to get a cold drink, they are turned away. Since everything must be paid in dollars, it's clear the two young lovers don't belong. The hotels are basically for tourists that can pay and not the poor locals. Gustavo's father is another typical example of how some professionals, trying to get access to dollars, go into tourist oriented jobs like playing piano in hotel lounges. Thomas, is a psychiatrist whose job in the local currency equals about a few dollars a month! Leon Ichaso and his collaborators clearly know what they are talking about. The result is a film that is an eye opener about what the reality is in that unfortunate land. The revolution might have started with good intentions, but after more than forty years the only way to make it out of there is either to marry a foreigner, or take to the open seas and hope they make it to either Miami, or Central America, if the sharks don't get to them first. Claudio Chea's black and white cinematography works well in the film. The music score is pleasant. Rene Lavan, Mayte Villain, Miguel Gutierrez and the rest of the cast respond well to the direction Mr. Ichaso gave them. This is a film that tries to make sense of what's going on in that country.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Excellent. the real truth about Cuban present regimen
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    betrayed
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/7/2005
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I have seen this film on numerous occasions. It brings back memories of the suffering of Cuba under communism, while the world remains silence. The performance of every single actor in my opinion is superior. Many people, probably does not know that Rene Lavan came to USA during the Mariel boat lift, as a child and grew up in Miami. Mr. Ichaso theme is accurate and to the point. I never understood, why it did not stay longer in the movies. The musical score is fabulous. If this was a foreign film, why it was not considered as such. This film should have competed with foreign productions. It was done by foreigners in the land of the freedom
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One-sided trash
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tom-1203
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/5/2005
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This film sets out to be nothing more than a crass criticism of Cuba's Communist state, with the plot strung along by a tepid and saccharine romance. There's really no artistic vision here - most of the direction is trying to be "classic", but then you get "heady" bursts of realism with some wobbly camera-work during a protest march. The soundtrack's not bad, some of the acting's pretty good, but everything in the film is designed to be easy to watch, and keep you just engaged enough so you can learn about how terrible Castro is. And this criticism isn't to deny that the regime has its problems. I can't claim any direct knowledge of Cuba, but I am aware of the oppression, and the poverty. But this film doesn't want to explore any of these issues. Why is Cuba prostituting itself (literally) to foreign capital? Well the American embargo would have had its crushing effects on Cuba's economy long before if it hadn't been for the Soviet subsidy. It *is* far more damaging, if you're going to have a tourist industry, to have an apartheid system in an attempt to stop the tourist economy "polluting" your political system, but what drove Cuba to its reliance on tourism in the first place? And what really gets me about this film is they're clearly looking to America for liberation. Did everyone forget that America propped up Batista, under which the Cubans were not only unfree but starving? Oh yeah, the USA's got a great track record of bringing freedom to Latin America - Pinochet in Chile, the contras in Nicaragua. And even its liberation of Panama came after propping up the vicious dictatorship of Torrijos then Noriega for 30-odd years. And what does it say about America that impoverished Cuba has higher literacy rates and comparable life expectancy? Cubans enjoy health care which the 40 million impoverished Americans who can't afford health insurance can only dream of. The film addressed none of these issues, and it's not that I mind a film taking a position, how can it not? But give your viewer some credit, don't just expect them to swallow it whole. Just showing particularly extreme manifestations of protest doesn't automatically win your case. This is a Miami-Cuban's caricature of modern Cuba, scribbled in 5 minutes. You think for the effort they've put in it could be something more substantial.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Excellent
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    yamian
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/5/2004
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I have read most of the commentaries here, before writing my own, and I could make a pattern: whenever somebody makes a very negative commentary about the film, at the same time shows that is not Cuban or has lack of knowledge about Cuba's reality. First of all, let's say it: it is true that the film is not 100% accurate, but we are not talking about a documentary. Secondly, for all those people worried about the AIDS shot, I'm very sorry to tell you that this was a true story. Thirdly, most of the Cubans that I have known, including myself, have somehow had a Gustavo inside, and/or have lived pieces of this story by themselves. The story is a mixture of reality and fantasy (after all is always like this in any art), that anyone that has passed in Cuba part of his/her life during the same years that the film shows will feel it very close. Some people could be lucky and never have seen anything like the ones that are depicted, but as I'm telling you, this was just luck. Many, many Cubans have suffered or still suffer on their own flesh these atrocities.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    an insult to intelligence
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Luciano Sanchez (lucciano7@yahoo.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/3/2004
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is definitely the worst movie I've seen in many years; apart from the absolute lack of cinematographic value, this exercise of fascist stupidity can only make you laugh as the "movie" advances. The stereotypes portrayed in Azucar Amarga are so difficult to believe that one wonders if the director (or whoever provided the money) has some kind of problem. Well, i guess there are a lot of people in this country who are now enlightened with their knowledge of world cinema an Latin American politics. Good for you. I'm only sorry for having spent my time watching this instead of doing something else.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Fascinating political film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    philip1970 (pasc@rcn.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/1/2004
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A heartwrenching drama, and touching film for a political disaster at the doorstep of the U.S...this film is a must for anyone interested in using the cinema to know today's Cuba through an extremely tragic but realistic story
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Bitter Sugar
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Spuzzlightyear
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/3/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Just OK drama here exploring the hardships of living in Cuba. Gustavo tries to eak out a living in Havana while waiting to go abroad with a scholarship, his dad gets a job at a swanky tourist resort because his psychiatrist job doesn't pay enough and his brother seems to do nothing but protest all day long. Meanwhile, Gustavo has his eye on a cute little brunette, but even, yes, she has some secrets. While it's intentions are certainly genuine, I think this was a wee bit too much politics to cram into one movie. Gustavo's problems are interesting, but his brother's are just a bit unnecessary, distracting and, quite frankly, over the top to be in this movie. The cinematography is excellent and whatnot but the story could have used a little simmering down.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Unique perspective on Cuba
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    DAW-8
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/9/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Bitter Sugar addresses MORE problems associated with politics and economic systems than almost any film from any country in a single film (There should be some award for such achievements...). One of the greatest things it accomplishes is illustrating the problems with BOTH ideal-socialist Cuba (which is gradually disappearing) and the alternative, open-market Cuba that is gradually developing in the 1990s. The bad side of a socialist state/society is clearly shown with the Gustavo's naive belief in the party and promises from the party that never pay off, as well as the imprisonment of cultural/political subversives such as his brother. On the capitalist side, there is the creeping inequality associated with capitalism, which metes out privilege and opportunity to the highest bidder, thus turning the nationalist dream on its head, turning national against national, as seen in the tourist hotels and bars where locals can't afford goods and services or are turned away. This capitalism colonizes even emotions such as love, or at least sex plus the semblance of emotional presence and attachment (which some say IS love), which can be exchanged for opportunity: Gustavo's girlfriend has all the talent but no opportunity to achieve her 'ideal' career as socialism promises. This film shows how there is no perfect way out, no utopia, no perfect system. The relationships between the characters, though clich&eacute; (a couple, two brothers, father-son) and simple, work very well. Neither Gustavo nor his girlfriend are ideologues, they each come to realize that their choice is neither simple, nor certain in terms of where it will lead them. Few films have effectively shown how complicated personal politics really are in socialist/communist states. Most either just show the ruthlessness of the state, or the humanity of an individual or group of individuals against the state, without contradictions. This film is neither pro- nor anti- Castro. Or it is both/and. This is Cuban national cinema; made for the Cuban nation as opposed to the Cuban state. It is a critical reflection on the new Cuba, and thus indirectly states that socialist Cuba may be no worse, at the same time as it is a critical reflection on socialist Cuba. It addresses almost the major problems contemporary Cubans face, and the contradictions between them and in the solutions to them. If we want to engage in a debate about the bias of the film, maybe considering the director/writer is a good place to start. Leon Ichaso is Cuban-born. He directed a few episodes of Miami Vice (politically left or right? anyone?), made a few films about salsa musicians and their personal struggles or struggles to be true to their culture, a documentary about Muhammad Ali, and most recently, the TV series about terrorists in LA 'Sleeper Cell'. Only this last one, in my opinion, definitively puts him in a political camp (right wing, obviously).
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    things can get bitter in many respects
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Lee Eisenberg (eisenberg.lee@gmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/7/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    When I rented Leon Ichaso's "Azucar amarga" (or "Bitter Sugar"), I didn't realize that it was an American movie critical of Cuba's government; I assumed that it was a Cuban-made film. It portrays young ardent Communist Gustavo in Havana who has to start questioning his ideals due to events surrounding him: his love interest Yolanda wants to flee to Miami, his father can make more money performing for tourists, and his brother injects himself with AIDS-infected blood as a protest. A pretty bleak look at a society that Michael Moore practically glorified in "Sicko". Personally, I think that if anyone's going to criticize Castro's government, they should still remind people of Fulgencio Batista's brutality, which this movie doesn't. But it's still worth seeing, just as a look inside the present-day Cuba, and what people sometimes have to do to get by.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Outstanding Film!! A Must See!!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Ritzy McCarthy
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/8/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I couldn't stop thinking about this film after watching it. It is remarkable how life has deteriorated in Cuba since I left in 1980 at the tender age of fifteen. This was the same year Lavan left the island on the Mariel boat lift. My family moved to Chicago, not Miami, so I quickly blended into American society and 'forgot'about Cuba. Family members who left post Mariel often described the conditions there, but I could never bring myself to fathom so much of it was real. I'm extremely grateful to be an American citizen living the American dream. However, my heart 'cries' for the many young people who are trapped in an obsolete communist society where they can't even afford to have dreams. This movie forced me to consider how the lives of my young nieces and nephews might have turned out. My father fought for Cuba's Revolution; he was a young idealist revolutionary just like Gustavo. Dad left the island in 1986 after years of disillusionment. People who haven't lived 'it' can't comprehend it. I'm always fascinated by those individuals who are quick to criticize anti-Castro voices, even though they've never actually experienced life in an oppressive regime. How could they possibly understand that living there is like living in an insane asylum? The AIDS facility were Gustavo's brother was forcibly interned is nothing more than a microcosm of the entire island of Cuba where people hopelessly and aimlessly exist. Not live, but exist. I give this movie the highest rating. It deserves it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Despair in paradise
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jotix100
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/1/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Leon Ichaso's "Azucar Amarga" came and went without much fanfare. This was a film made with little money and without any big distributor to give it more exposure in the American market. The film is critical of the way Cuba, as a society, started the current trend after the loss of patronage of the old Soviet Union in the late eighties. In order to get the badly needed hard currency, Cuba opened its doors to a massive invasion of international tourism, mainly from Europe and South America. With that, the US dollar was legalized. The results can be seen in this film that examines that society. First of all, for those that have expressed their skepticism about the young people injecting themselves with AIDS infected blood, obviously, they haven't read the accounts by different world newspapers, and the New York Times, locally. This is a phenomenon that desperate people will resort to in order to escape the fact they are looked down in their own society for daring to be different. The other aspect one sees in the film is the prostitution being practiced among young women with college education as a way to make ends meet. This kind of sex tourism is being practiced in the island. European men flock to Cuba in search of beautiful women they couldn't otherwise afford in their own countries. Yolanda, the beautiful woman in the film, turns to the Italian Claudio as a way to have things she couldn't have otherwise. Another issue in the film involves the equality the revolution promised. When Gustavo and Yolanda go to the beach bar to get a cold drink, they are turned away. Since everything must be paid in dollars, it's clear the two young lovers don't belong. The hotels are basically for tourists that can pay and not the poor locals. Gustavo's father is another typical example of how some professionals, trying to get access to dollars, go into tourist oriented jobs like playing piano in hotel lounges. Thomas, is a psychiatrist whose job in the local currency equals about a few dollars a month! Leon Ichaso and his collaborators clearly know what they are talking about. The result is a film that is an eye opener about what the reality is in that unfortunate land. The revolution might have started with good intentions, but after more than forty years the only way to make it out of there is either to marry a foreigner, or take to the open seas and hope they make it to either Miami, or Central America, if the sharks don't get to them first. Claudio Chea's black and white cinematography works well in the film. The music score is pleasant. Rene Lavan, Mayte Villain, Miguel Gutierrez and the rest of the cast respond well to the direction Mr. Ichaso gave them. This is a film that tries to make sense of what's going on in that country.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Excellent. the real truth about Cuban present regimen
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    betrayed
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/7/2005
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I have seen this film on numerous occasions. It brings back memories of the suffering of Cuba under communism, while the world remains silence. The performance of every single actor in my opinion is superior. Many people, probably does not know that Rene Lavan came to USA during the Mariel boat lift, as a child and grew up in Miami. Mr. Ichaso theme is accurate and to the point. I never understood, why it did not stay longer in the movies. The musical score is fabulous. If this was a foreign film, why it was not considered as such. This film should have competed with foreign productions. It was done by foreigners in the land of the freedom
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One-sided trash
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tom-1203
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/5/2005
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This film sets out to be nothing more than a crass criticism of Cuba's Communist state, with the plot strung along by a tepid and saccharine romance. There's really no artistic vision here - most of the direction is trying to be "classic", but then you get "heady" bursts of realism with some wobbly camera-work during a protest march. The soundtrack's not bad, some of the acting's pretty good, but everything in the film is designed to be easy to watch, and keep you just engaged enough so you can learn about how terrible Castro is. And this criticism isn't to deny that the regime has its problems. I can't claim any direct knowledge of Cuba, but I am aware of the oppression, and the poverty. But this film doesn't want to explore any of these issues. Why is Cuba prostituting itself (literally) to foreign capital? Well the American embargo would have had its crushing effects on Cuba's economy long before if it hadn't been for the Soviet subsidy. It *is* far more damaging, if you're going to have a tourist industry, to have an apartheid system in an attempt to stop the tourist economy "polluting" your political system, but what drove Cuba to its reliance on tourism in the first place? And what really gets me about this film is they're clearly looking to America for liberation. Did everyone forget that America propped up Batista, under which the Cubans were not only unfree but starving? Oh yeah, the USA's got a great track record of bringing freedom to Latin America - Pinochet in Chile, the contras in Nicaragua. And even its liberation of Panama came after propping up the vicious dictatorship of Torrijos then Noriega for 30-odd years. And what does it say about America that impoverished Cuba has higher literacy rates and comparable life expectancy? Cubans enjoy health care which the 40 million impoverished Americans who can't afford health insurance can only dream of. The film addressed none of these issues, and it's not that I mind a film taking a position, how can it not? But give your viewer some credit, don't just expect them to swallow it whole. Just showing particularly extreme manifestations of protest doesn't automatically win your case. This is a Miami-Cuban's caricature of modern Cuba, scribbled in 5 minutes. You think for the effort they've put in it could be something more substantial.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Excellent
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    yamian
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/5/2004
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I have read most of the commentaries here, before writing my own, and I could make a pattern: whenever somebody makes a very negative commentary about the film, at the same time shows that is not Cuban or has lack of knowledge about Cuba's reality. First of all, let's say it: it is true that the film is not 100% accurate, but we are not talking about a documentary. Secondly, for all those people worried about the AIDS shot, I'm very sorry to tell you that this was a true story. Thirdly, most of the Cubans that I have known, including myself, have somehow had a Gustavo inside, and/or have lived pieces of this story by themselves. The story is a mixture of reality and fantasy (after all is always like this in any art), that anyone that has passed in Cuba part of his/her life during the same years that the film shows will feel it very close. Some people could be lucky and never have seen anything like the ones that are depicted, but as I'm telling you, this was just luck. Many, many Cubans have suffered or still suffer on their own flesh these atrocities.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    an insult to intelligence
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Luciano Sanchez (lucciano7@yahoo.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/3/2004
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is definitely the worst movie I've seen in many years; apart from the absolute lack of cinematographic value, this exercise of fascist stupidity can only make you laugh as the "movie" advances. The stereotypes portrayed in Azucar Amarga are so difficult to believe that one wonders if the director (or whoever provided the money) has some kind of problem. Well, i guess there are a lot of people in this country who are now enlightened with their knowledge of world cinema an Latin American politics. Good for you. I'm only sorry for having spent my time watching this instead of doing something else.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Fascinating political film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    philip1970 (pasc@rcn.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/1/2004
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A heartwrenching drama, and touching film for a political disaster at the doorstep of the U.S...this film is a must for anyone interested in using the cinema to know today's Cuba through an extremely tragic but realistic story
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Bitter Sugar
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Spuzzlightyear
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/3/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Just OK drama here exploring the hardships of living in Cuba. Gustavo tries to eak out a living in Havana while waiting to go abroad with a scholarship, his dad gets a job at a swanky tourist resort because his psychiatrist job doesn't pay enough and his brother seems to do nothing but protest all day long. Meanwhile, Gustavo has his eye on a cute little brunette, but even, yes, she has some secrets. While it's intentions are certainly genuine, I think this was a wee bit too much politics to cram into one movie. Gustavo's problems are interesting, but his brother's are just a bit unnecessary, distracting and, quite frankly, over the top to be in this movie. The cinematography is excellent and whatnot but the story could have used a little simmering down.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Unique perspective on Cuba
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    DAW-8
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/9/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Bitter Sugar addresses MORE problems associated with politics and economic systems than almost any film from any country in a single film (There should be some award for such achievements...). One of the greatest things it accomplishes is illustrating the problems with BOTH ideal-socialist Cuba (which is gradually disappearing) and the alternative, open-market Cuba that is gradually developing in the 1990s. The bad side of a socialist state/society is clearly shown with the Gustavo's naive belief in the party and promises from the party that never pay off, as well as the imprisonment of cultural/political subversives such as his brother. On the capitalist side, there is the creeping inequality associated with capitalism, which metes out privilege and opportunity to the highest bidder, thus turning the nationalist dream on its head, turning national against national, as seen in the tourist hotels and bars where locals can't afford goods and services or are turned away. This capitalism colonizes even emotions such as love, or at least sex plus the semblance of emotional presence and attachment (which some say IS love), which can be exchanged for opportunity: Gustavo's girlfriend has all the talent but no opportunity to achieve her 'ideal' career as socialism promises. This film shows how there is no perfect way out, no utopia, no perfect system. The relationships between the characters, though clich&eacute; (a couple, two brothers, father-son) and simple, work very well. Neither Gustavo nor his girlfriend are ideologues, they each come to realize that their choice is neither simple, nor certain in terms of where it will lead them. Few films have effectively shown how complicated personal politics really are in socialist/communist states. Most either just show the ruthlessness of the state, or the humanity of an individual or group of individuals against the state, without contradictions. This film is neither pro- nor anti- Castro. Or it is both/and. This is Cuban national cinema; made for the Cuban nation as opposed to the Cuban state. It is a critical reflection on the new Cuba, and thus indirectly states that socialist Cuba may be no worse, at the same time as it is a critical reflection on socialist Cuba. It addresses almost the major problems contemporary Cubans face, and the contradictions between them and in the solutions to them. If we want to engage in a debate about the bias of the film, maybe considering the director/writer is a good place to start. Leon Ichaso is Cuban-born. He directed a few episodes of Miami Vice (politically left or right? anyone?), made a few films about salsa musicians and their personal struggles or struggles to be true to their culture, a documentary about Muhammad Ali, and most recently, the TV series about terrorists in LA 'Sleeper Cell'. Only this last one, in my opinion, definitively puts him in a political camp (right wing, obviously).
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    things can get bitter in many respects
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Lee Eisenberg (eisenberg.lee@gmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/7/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    When I rented Leon Ichaso's "Azucar amarga" (or "Bitter Sugar"), I didn't realize that it was an American movie critical of Cuba's government; I assumed that it was a Cuban-made film. It portrays young ardent Communist Gustavo in Havana who has to start questioning his ideals due to events surrounding him: his love interest Yolanda wants to flee to Miami, his father can make more money performing for tourists, and his brother injects himself with AIDS-infected blood as a protest. A pretty bleak look at a society that Michael Moore practically glorified in "Sicko". Personally, I think that if anyone's going to criticize Castro's government, they should still remind people of Fulgencio Batista's brutality, which this movie doesn't. But it's still worth seeing, just as a look inside the present-day Cuba, and what people sometimes have to do to get by.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Outstanding Film!! A Must See!!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Ritzy McCarthy
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/8/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I couldn't stop thinking about this film after watching it. It is remarkable how life has deteriorated in Cuba since I left in 1980 at the tender age of fifteen. This was the same year Lavan left the island on the Mariel boat lift. My family moved to Chicago, not Miami, so I quickly blended into American society and 'forgot'about Cuba. Family members who left post Mariel often described the conditions there, but I could never bring myself to fathom so much of it was real. I'm extremely grateful to be an American citizen living the American dream. However, my heart 'cries' for the many young people who are trapped in an obsolete communist society where they can't even afford to have dreams. This movie forced me to consider how the lives of my young nieces and nephews might have turned out. My father fought for Cuba's Revolution; he was a young idealist revolutionary just like Gustavo. Dad left the island in 1986 after years of disillusionment. People who haven't lived 'it' can't comprehend it. I'm always fascinated by those individuals who are quick to criticize anti-Castro voices, even though they've never actually experienced life in an oppressive regime. How could they possibly understand that living there is like living in an insane asylum? The AIDS facility were Gustavo's brother was forcibly interned is nothing more than a microcosm of the entire island of Cuba where people hopelessly and aimlessly exist. Not live, but exist. I give this movie the highest rating. It deserves it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Despair in paradise
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jotix100
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/1/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Leon Ichaso's "Azucar Amarga" came and went without much fanfare. This was a film made with little money and without any big distributor to give it more exposure in the American market. The film is critical of the way Cuba, as a society, started the current trend after the loss of patronage of the old Soviet Union in the late eighties. In order to get the badly needed hard currency, Cuba opened its doors to a massive invasion of international tourism, mainly from Europe and South America. With that, the US dollar was legalized. The results can be seen in this film that examines that society. First of all, for those that have expressed their skepticism about the young people injecting themselves with AIDS infected blood, obviously, they haven't read the accounts by different world newspapers, and the New York Times, locally. This is a phenomenon that desperate people will resort to in order to escape the fact they are looked down in their own society for daring to be different. The other aspect one sees in the film is the prostitution being practiced among young women with college education as a way to make ends meet. This kind of sex tourism is being practiced in the island. European men flock to Cuba in search of beautiful women they couldn't otherwise afford in their own countries. Yolanda, the beautiful woman in the film, turns to the Italian Claudio as a way to have things she couldn't have otherwise. Another issue in the film involves the equality the revolution promised. When Gustavo and Yolanda go to the beach bar to get a cold drink, they are turned away. Since everything must be paid in dollars, it's clear the two young lovers don't belong. The hotels are basically for tourists that can pay and not the poor locals. Gustavo's father is another typical example of how some professionals, trying to get access to dollars, go into tourist oriented jobs like playing piano in hotel lounges. Thomas, is a psychiatrist whose job in the local currency equals about a few dollars a month! Leon Ichaso and his collaborators clearly know what they are talking about. The result is a film that is an eye opener about what the reality is in that unfortunate land. The revolution might have started with good intentions, but after more than forty years the only way to make it out of there is either to marry a foreigner, or take to the open seas and hope they make it to either Miami, or Central America, if the sharks don't get to them first. Claudio Chea's black and white cinematography works well in the film. The music score is pleasant. Rene Lavan, Mayte Villain, Miguel Gutierrez and the rest of the cast respond well to the direction Mr. Ichaso gave them. This is a film that tries to make sense of what's going on in that country.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Excellent. the real truth about Cuban present regimen
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    betrayed
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/7/2005
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I have seen this film on numerous occasions. It brings back memories of the suffering of Cuba under communism, while the world remains silence. The performance of every single actor in my opinion is superior. Many people, probably does not know that Rene Lavan came to USA during the Mariel boat lift, as a child and grew up in Miami. Mr. Ichaso theme is accurate and to the point. I never understood, why it did not stay longer in the movies. The musical score is fabulous. If this was a foreign film, why it was not considered as such. This film should have competed with foreign productions. It was done by foreigners in the land of the freedom
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One-sided trash
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tom-1203
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/5/2005
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This film sets out to be nothing more than a crass criticism of Cuba's Communist state, with the plot strung along by a tepid and saccharine romance. There's really no artistic vision here - most of the direction is trying to be "classic", but then you get "heady" bursts of realism with some wobbly camera-work during a protest march. The soundtrack's not bad, some of the acting's pretty good, but everything in the film is designed to be easy to watch, and keep you just engaged enough so you can learn about how terrible Castro is. And this criticism isn't to deny that the regime has its problems. I can't claim any direct knowledge of Cuba, but I am aware of the oppression, and the poverty. But this film doesn't want to explore any of these issues. Why is Cuba prostituting itself (literally) to foreign capital? Well the American embargo would have had its crushing effects on Cuba's economy long before if it hadn't been for the Soviet subsidy. It *is* far more damaging, if you're going to have a tourist industry, to have an apartheid system in an attempt to stop the tourist economy "polluting" your political system, but what drove Cuba to its reliance on tourism in the first place? And what really gets me about this film is they're clearly looking to America for liberation. Did everyone forget that America propped up Batista, under which the Cubans were not only unfree but starving? Oh yeah, the USA's got a great track record of bringing freedom to Latin America - Pinochet in Chile, the contras in Nicaragua. And even its liberation of Panama came after propping up the vicious dictatorship of Torrijos then Noriega for 30-odd years. And what does it say about America that impoverished Cuba has higher literacy rates and comparable life expectancy? Cubans enjoy health care which the 40 million impoverished Americans who can't afford health insurance can only dream of. The film addressed none of these issues, and it's not that I mind a film taking a position, how can it not? But give your viewer some credit, don't just expect them to swallow it whole. Just showing particularly extreme manifestations of protest doesn't automatically win your case. This is a Miami-Cuban's caricature of modern Cuba, scribbled in 5 minutes. You think for the effort they've put in it could be something more substantial.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Excellent
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    yamian
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/5/2004
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I have read most of the commentaries here, before writing my own, and I could make a pattern: whenever somebody makes a very negative commentary about the film, at the same time shows that is not Cuban or has lack of knowledge about Cuba's reality. First of all, let's say it: it is true that the film is not 100% accurate, but we are not talking about a documentary. Secondly, for all those people worried about the AIDS shot, I'm very sorry to tell you that this was a true story. Thirdly, most of the Cubans that I have known, including myself, have somehow had a Gustavo inside, and/or have lived pieces of this story by themselves. The story is a mixture of reality and fantasy (after all is always like this in any art), that anyone that has passed in Cuba part of his/her life during the same years that the film shows will feel it very close. Some people could be lucky and never have seen anything like the ones that are depicted, but as I'm telling you, this was just luck. Many, many Cubans have suffered or still suffer on their own flesh these atrocities.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    an insult to intelligence
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Luciano Sanchez (lucciano7@yahoo.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/3/2004
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is definitely the worst movie I've seen in many years; apart from the absolute lack of cinematographic value, this exercise of fascist stupidity can only make you laugh as the "movie" advances. The stereotypes portrayed in Azucar Amarga are so difficult to believe that one wonders if the director (or whoever provided the money) has some kind of problem. Well, i guess there are a lot of people in this country who are now enlightened with their knowledge of world cinema an Latin American politics. Good for you. I'm only sorry for having spent my time watching this instead of doing something else.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Fascinating political film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    philip1970 (pasc@rcn.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/1/2004
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A heartwrenching drama, and touching film for a political disaster at the doorstep of the U.S...this film is a must for anyone interested in using the cinema to know today's Cuba through an extremely tragic but realistic story
   </conteudo>
  </review>
 </reviews>
</filme>
