<filme>
 <id>
  1640
 </id>
 <imdburl>
  http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0116581
 </imdburl>
 <ano>
  1996
 </ano>
 <titulo>
  Le huiti&egrave;me jour
 </titulo>
 <rating>
  7.3
 </rating>
 <sinopse>
  Georges has Down's syndrome, living at a mental-institution. Harry is a busy businessman, giving lectures for young aspiring salesmen. He is successful in his business life, but his social ... &nbsp;&raquo;
 </sinopse>
 <storyline>
  Georges has Down's syndrome, living at a mental-institution. Harry is a busy businessman, giving lectures for young aspiring salesmen. He is successful in his business life, but his social life is a disaster since his wife left him and took their two children with her. This weekend his children came by train to meet him, but Harry, working as always, forgot to pick them up. Neither his wife nor his children want to see him again and he is driving around on the country roads, anguished and angry. He almost runs over Georges, on the run from the institution since everybody else went home with their parents except him, whose mother is dead. Harry tries to get rid of Georges but he won't leave his new friend. Eventually a special friendship forms between the two of them, a friendship which makes Harry a different person.
 </storyline>
 <generos>
  <genero>
   Comedy
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Drama
  </genero>
 </generos>
 <keywords>
  <keyword>
   children
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   friendship
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   businessman
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   friend
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   mental institution
  </keyword>
 </keywords>
 <diretores>
  <diretor>
   Jaco Van Dormael
  </diretor>
 </diretores>
 <escritores>
  <escritor>
   Jaco Van Dormael
  </escritor>
 </escritores>
 <atores>
  <ator>
   Daniel Auteuil
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Pascal Duquenne
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Miou-Miou
  </ator>
 </atores>
 <reviews>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Mystery of the 8th Day
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Chrysanthepop
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    With 'Le Huiti&egrave;me Jour' director Jaco van Dormael tells us a moving tale of two complete strangers (who couldn't be more different from each other), whose paths cross as they travel opposite directions. After this odd encounter, together, both take turns heading towards each other's destinations but with heartbreaking results. However, this journey allows them to find something they didn't know they were looking for. Let's get the flaws out of the way: Certain scenes may feel a little dramatic but it still remains within the tone of the film, never looking out of place. Even though Harry and Georges are the primary focus of the film, some of the important supporting characters are poorly developed, especially Georges's hating sister and Miou Miou's Julie. But those minuses aside, is 'Le Huiti&egrave;me Jour' a road movie (the landscapes are dazzling)? Is it a study of two characters? Is it a 'buddy' movie (certainly not the typical Hollywood kind)? Is it a dramedy? It's poetry. The film, in a way, moves from one genre to another but it flows beautifully. The balance in humour, and intensity is first rate. The jokes work well and the timing is just right. I did find the ending to be a tad too dramatic. What Georges shows the viewer is that, while people desire similarities, it is our differences that make us unique. Yet, that is the very reason why Georges is rejected by the 'real world'. What Harry further shows is that none of these supposed similarities that people look for in each other matters because acceptance, respect, being open to possibilities and being true to oneself are what will bring the greater joy. 'Le Huiti&egrave;me Jour' is stunningly filmed and wonderfully acted. Pascal Duquenne and Daniel Auteuil are superb. Duquenne delivers a very natural performance and Auteuil is terrifically restrained. They are well supported by Isabelle Sadoyan, Michele Maes and the two actors who play Harry's daughter. 'Le Huiti&egrave;me Jour' engages you right from the start. It's funny, intense, enlightening and reaches straight for the heart.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Beautiful.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Santonix Lee
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I have not watched many French-language films in my lifetime, but The Eighth Day and Amelie are way up there on my list of favourite movies. Perhaps it's just overexposure to the monolithic crap Hollywood mass produces today, but these films have an atmosphere that are like a breath of fresh air. Even with (or perhaps because of) little to no special effects to bedazzle you, you are immersed before you know it. The spontaneity and sheer oddness of some of the scenes add to the charm of the film, as does the tumultuous and unlikely friendship between a workaholic and a man with Down's syndrome. The Eighth Day gives you something to reflect on, a pause from the fast paced lifestyles we are caught up in today.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    How a movie becomes a Film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    kwsndsm
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/4/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    **May contain spoilers** I finally own "Le huiti&egrave;me jour". First time I saw it was as a rental, while living in the US. This movie is a true Film, it is a fairytale, where reality and fantasy is interwoven in a true use of style, acting, vision and direction. Watched it yesterday, having found that it was now available on DVD, and buying it in the US of all places. Harry and George start out as the odd couple, but as the Film progress they become two sides of humans and humanity, George is prefacing the end through his words and actions through the Film, and only at the end all of them becomes apparent. This story is one which I think all should on occasion try to see, it is movie making at it's best. The dream sequences would not translate into words as strongly as the visual impact, the fact that no words are spoken through some of them, and the 'force' with which our emotions and thoughts react to them. It is not supposed to be 'believable' it is supposed to tell a story, and it does that to the best possible extent imaginable. And indeed on the Eight day "all is good". This is one of my favorite movies all time.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Straight into my heart.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    per_jaderbrink
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/8/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The number of times I've had tears in my eyes when watching a movie are few. And there is only one time when I have really cried and that was when I saw this movie. This movie has some kliches but I really don't care. I cry even as I write this and it was quite some time since I saw it. It is perfectly acted and all the production values are good, but what really matters is the simple and wonderful message. We all know it in our hearts, but it is not always easy to remember that the only thing that really matters in life is LOVE in all it's forms. It's only when we love that we're truly alive. I know how sentimental I sound and I promise I'm not usually like that. I'm quite a cynic. This movie has brought out stronger feelings of both sorrow and happiness in me than any other movies and it will probably always be the first movie I recommend others to see.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    good..
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    didiermustntdie
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/7/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    a great film, one of the funniest films ever. the only thing that disturbed me is the music sounds like flashdance...what a feeling.. also it would be more believable if the character Daniel Auteuil plays were a loser businessman,that would be less effective but more believable. but anything else is valid, credible and even realist.. the scene with Georges's sister is touching , the scene with the maid is moving and bitter,the shoe shop scene ,the opening sequence and some others are hilarious. but the car shop one is gone too far.. oh well, another issue on the subplot,he is neither unfaithful nor abusive. I don't know what's the problem between harry and his wife. I think I would stand by harry's side like I did in "war of roses". it's my first film about Down syndrome people, those forgotten souls(people now only care about and spend too much time and energy on blacks who are actually the real oppressors today)...
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The beauty of the small things.... again.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Doktor Hackenbush
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/5/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    An executive, very successful in his professional life but very unable in his familiar life, meets a boy with down syndrome, escaped from a residence . Both characters feel very alone, and the apparently less intelligent one will show to the executive the beauty of the small things in life... With this argument, the somehow Amelie-like atmosphere and the sentimental music, I didn't expect but a moralistic disgusting movie. Anyway, as there were some interesting scenes (the boy is sometimes quite a violent guy), and the interpretation of both actors, Daniel Auteil and Pasqal Duquenne, was very good, I decided to go on watching the movie. The French cinema, in general, has the ability of showing something that seems quite much to life, opposed to the more stereotyped American cinema. But, because of that, it is much more disappointing to see after the absurd ending, with the impossible death of the boy, the charming tone, the happiness of the executive's family, the cheap moral, the unbearable laughter of the daughters, the guy waving from heaven as Michael Landon... Really nasty, in my humble opinion.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A touching film for good natured souls
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Gordon-11
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/8/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This film is about the unlikely friendship between a businessman and a man with Down Syndrome. The character development in this film is excellent. We get to believe that Harry is a businessman who neglects his family, and Georges is an innocent man who craves loving and care from the "normal" society. Acting is excellent, and the Cannes best actor award is well deserved. The fantasy scenes in the film highlights the fact that Georges misery towards his abandonment by his family, and his desire to be treated like a normal person. The song that gets played repeatedly also reinforces this message. The film shows that people who are mentally handicapped are good natured. We have been treating them with discrimination and neglect, a fact that is highlighted by the scene where Georges gives a present to the waitress in the kitchen). If we get to understand and share these people's world, both we and the mentally handicapped can become very happy. I was so drawn into the film and the characters' emotional experiences. It is a touching film for good natured souls.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of My Favorite Movies!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    (sylviastel@aol.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/2/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I saw this film first on my way home from Paris to Newark aboard Air France in August 1996. The film itself I believe is quite a masterpiece. It's the kind of film that people should be making. I still think Daniel Auteuil is one of the sexiest actors around. In this French film, he plays a divorced father and businessman who has lost his zest for life until he across a Down Syndrome man who lives in an institution with other Down Syndrome patients. The actors including the actor who actually has Down Syndrome create a believable friendship and relationship between these two unlikely men. Daniel's life and ours changes forever with the Down Syndrome man. He realizes that life is not just work and not play but for the living and loving and that's what life should be all about. The ending is kind of silly though but I still think it's one of my favorite movies. It's enough to bring a tear to your eye.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Good acting but not much else.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    The_Triad
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/1/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Eighth Day is supposed to be a charming experience, but I found it to be largely irritating and dull. The film focuses around Harry, played by Daniel Auteuil, a salesman who's life is falling apart. Stuck in his daily routine, estranged from his wife and failing to be a father to his children. This, cut-and-paste character then meets Georges, a guy with Down's Syndrome who proceeds as we all know by now to help him turn his life around and get back to being a father to his kids. The problem is that we are given no insight as to why Harry puts up with Georges after the initial meeting. Harry's life is in a bad enough state as it is, it's completely implausible that he'd risk losing his job by taking time off to try and get Georges to his mother's house. The humour completely misses the mark, instead of showing us why Harry is putting up with this guy, we are treated to a series of irritating, unfunny skits in which Harry bears the brunt of Georges mishaps. The film reaches its peak when Georges remembers it's Harry's daughters birthday and along with other people from his home steal a bus, take Harry out of a conference, set off some fireworks, et viola! Harry is a good father again and now he can see the kids. For a film that is supposed to be grounded in realism (despite its poor attempt at a fantasy/reality message) this is completely implausible and unbelievable. Add to this the demise of Georges character, which I cannot fathom as to how people have been in tears at, as he is surely one of the most irritating characters ever created. The best thing about the film is it does have two great performances from its two leads, but these are not good enough for me to recommend that anyone sit through it. A lot of comments for this film has suggested its similarity and superiority to Rain Man, this is not so in my eyes, this is a watered down sub-standard effort with none of Rain Man's humour or warmth.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not Heartwarming, NOT a joy to watch.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tvgeek91
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/4/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I found myself watching this movie in my French class, and, quite simply, I did not like it. I don't believe that either of the characters, Georges and Harry, were sympathetic by the end of the film. It is made clear that Georges cares about nobody but himself and we are supposed to care for him purely because he has down syndrome. Harry is so caught up in business that he didn't remember to pick up the two daughters that he supposedly cares about so much. He attacks his estranged wife and shows no sign of guilt for this over his sadness that she didn't agree to let him see his kids. I wouldn't let him see my kids if thats the way he behaved. Everything is all better at the end of the movie just because he set off some fireworks. That just doesn't make sense to me. In a movie that takes place in reality, the fantasy scenes were awkward and seemed to be squeezed in to anyplace that they could find and didn't convey a necessary message. Georges's sudden death at the end of the film was totally random and had very reason why it should occur. I don't regret seeing any movie, but if you're going to see a Daniel Auteuil movie I would recommend seeing Cache.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Mystery of the 8th Day
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Chrysanthepop
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    With 'Le Huiti&egrave;me Jour' director Jaco van Dormael tells us a moving tale of two complete strangers (who couldn't be more different from each other), whose paths cross as they travel opposite directions. After this odd encounter, together, both take turns heading towards each other's destinations but with heartbreaking results. However, this journey allows them to find something they didn't know they were looking for. Let's get the flaws out of the way: Certain scenes may feel a little dramatic but it still remains within the tone of the film, never looking out of place. Even though Harry and Georges are the primary focus of the film, some of the important supporting characters are poorly developed, especially Georges's hating sister and Miou Miou's Julie. But those minuses aside, is 'Le Huiti&egrave;me Jour' a road movie (the landscapes are dazzling)? Is it a study of two characters? Is it a 'buddy' movie (certainly not the typical Hollywood kind)? Is it a dramedy? It's poetry. The film, in a way, moves from one genre to another but it flows beautifully. The balance in humour, and intensity is first rate. The jokes work well and the timing is just right. I did find the ending to be a tad too dramatic. What Georges shows the viewer is that, while people desire similarities, it is our differences that make us unique. Yet, that is the very reason why Georges is rejected by the 'real world'. What Harry further shows is that none of these supposed similarities that people look for in each other matters because acceptance, respect, being open to possibilities and being true to oneself are what will bring the greater joy. 'Le Huiti&egrave;me Jour' is stunningly filmed and wonderfully acted. Pascal Duquenne and Daniel Auteuil are superb. Duquenne delivers a very natural performance and Auteuil is terrifically restrained. They are well supported by Isabelle Sadoyan, Michele Maes and the two actors who play Harry's daughter. 'Le Huiti&egrave;me Jour' engages you right from the start. It's funny, intense, enlightening and reaches straight for the heart.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Beautiful.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Santonix Lee
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I have not watched many French-language films in my lifetime, but The Eighth Day and Amelie are way up there on my list of favourite movies. Perhaps it's just overexposure to the monolithic crap Hollywood mass produces today, but these films have an atmosphere that are like a breath of fresh air. Even with (or perhaps because of) little to no special effects to bedazzle you, you are immersed before you know it. The spontaneity and sheer oddness of some of the scenes add to the charm of the film, as does the tumultuous and unlikely friendship between a workaholic and a man with Down's syndrome. The Eighth Day gives you something to reflect on, a pause from the fast paced lifestyles we are caught up in today.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    How a movie becomes a Film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    kwsndsm
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/4/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    **May contain spoilers** I finally own "Le huiti&egrave;me jour". First time I saw it was as a rental, while living in the US. This movie is a true Film, it is a fairytale, where reality and fantasy is interwoven in a true use of style, acting, vision and direction. Watched it yesterday, having found that it was now available on DVD, and buying it in the US of all places. Harry and George start out as the odd couple, but as the Film progress they become two sides of humans and humanity, George is prefacing the end through his words and actions through the Film, and only at the end all of them becomes apparent. This story is one which I think all should on occasion try to see, it is movie making at it's best. The dream sequences would not translate into words as strongly as the visual impact, the fact that no words are spoken through some of them, and the 'force' with which our emotions and thoughts react to them. It is not supposed to be 'believable' it is supposed to tell a story, and it does that to the best possible extent imaginable. And indeed on the Eight day "all is good". This is one of my favorite movies all time.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Straight into my heart.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    per_jaderbrink
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/8/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The number of times I've had tears in my eyes when watching a movie are few. And there is only one time when I have really cried and that was when I saw this movie. This movie has some kliches but I really don't care. I cry even as I write this and it was quite some time since I saw it. It is perfectly acted and all the production values are good, but what really matters is the simple and wonderful message. We all know it in our hearts, but it is not always easy to remember that the only thing that really matters in life is LOVE in all it's forms. It's only when we love that we're truly alive. I know how sentimental I sound and I promise I'm not usually like that. I'm quite a cynic. This movie has brought out stronger feelings of both sorrow and happiness in me than any other movies and it will probably always be the first movie I recommend others to see.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    good..
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    didiermustntdie
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/7/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    a great film, one of the funniest films ever. the only thing that disturbed me is the music sounds like flashdance...what a feeling.. also it would be more believable if the character Daniel Auteuil plays were a loser businessman,that would be less effective but more believable. but anything else is valid, credible and even realist.. the scene with Georges's sister is touching , the scene with the maid is moving and bitter,the shoe shop scene ,the opening sequence and some others are hilarious. but the car shop one is gone too far.. oh well, another issue on the subplot,he is neither unfaithful nor abusive. I don't know what's the problem between harry and his wife. I think I would stand by harry's side like I did in "war of roses". it's my first film about Down syndrome people, those forgotten souls(people now only care about and spend too much time and energy on blacks who are actually the real oppressors today)...
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The beauty of the small things.... again.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Doktor Hackenbush
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/5/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    An executive, very successful in his professional life but very unable in his familiar life, meets a boy with down syndrome, escaped from a residence . Both characters feel very alone, and the apparently less intelligent one will show to the executive the beauty of the small things in life... With this argument, the somehow Amelie-like atmosphere and the sentimental music, I didn't expect but a moralistic disgusting movie. Anyway, as there were some interesting scenes (the boy is sometimes quite a violent guy), and the interpretation of both actors, Daniel Auteil and Pasqal Duquenne, was very good, I decided to go on watching the movie. The French cinema, in general, has the ability of showing something that seems quite much to life, opposed to the more stereotyped American cinema. But, because of that, it is much more disappointing to see after the absurd ending, with the impossible death of the boy, the charming tone, the happiness of the executive's family, the cheap moral, the unbearable laughter of the daughters, the guy waving from heaven as Michael Landon... Really nasty, in my humble opinion.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A touching film for good natured souls
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Gordon-11
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/8/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This film is about the unlikely friendship between a businessman and a man with Down Syndrome. The character development in this film is excellent. We get to believe that Harry is a businessman who neglects his family, and Georges is an innocent man who craves loving and care from the "normal" society. Acting is excellent, and the Cannes best actor award is well deserved. The fantasy scenes in the film highlights the fact that Georges misery towards his abandonment by his family, and his desire to be treated like a normal person. The song that gets played repeatedly also reinforces this message. The film shows that people who are mentally handicapped are good natured. We have been treating them with discrimination and neglect, a fact that is highlighted by the scene where Georges gives a present to the waitress in the kitchen). If we get to understand and share these people's world, both we and the mentally handicapped can become very happy. I was so drawn into the film and the characters' emotional experiences. It is a touching film for good natured souls.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of My Favorite Movies!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    (sylviastel@aol.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/2/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I saw this film first on my way home from Paris to Newark aboard Air France in August 1996. The film itself I believe is quite a masterpiece. It's the kind of film that people should be making. I still think Daniel Auteuil is one of the sexiest actors around. In this French film, he plays a divorced father and businessman who has lost his zest for life until he across a Down Syndrome man who lives in an institution with other Down Syndrome patients. The actors including the actor who actually has Down Syndrome create a believable friendship and relationship between these two unlikely men. Daniel's life and ours changes forever with the Down Syndrome man. He realizes that life is not just work and not play but for the living and loving and that's what life should be all about. The ending is kind of silly though but I still think it's one of my favorite movies. It's enough to bring a tear to your eye.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Good acting but not much else.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    The_Triad
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/1/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Eighth Day is supposed to be a charming experience, but I found it to be largely irritating and dull. The film focuses around Harry, played by Daniel Auteuil, a salesman who's life is falling apart. Stuck in his daily routine, estranged from his wife and failing to be a father to his children. This, cut-and-paste character then meets Georges, a guy with Down's Syndrome who proceeds as we all know by now to help him turn his life around and get back to being a father to his kids. The problem is that we are given no insight as to why Harry puts up with Georges after the initial meeting. Harry's life is in a bad enough state as it is, it's completely implausible that he'd risk losing his job by taking time off to try and get Georges to his mother's house. The humour completely misses the mark, instead of showing us why Harry is putting up with this guy, we are treated to a series of irritating, unfunny skits in which Harry bears the brunt of Georges mishaps. The film reaches its peak when Georges remembers it's Harry's daughters birthday and along with other people from his home steal a bus, take Harry out of a conference, set off some fireworks, et viola! Harry is a good father again and now he can see the kids. For a film that is supposed to be grounded in realism (despite its poor attempt at a fantasy/reality message) this is completely implausible and unbelievable. Add to this the demise of Georges character, which I cannot fathom as to how people have been in tears at, as he is surely one of the most irritating characters ever created. The best thing about the film is it does have two great performances from its two leads, but these are not good enough for me to recommend that anyone sit through it. A lot of comments for this film has suggested its similarity and superiority to Rain Man, this is not so in my eyes, this is a watered down sub-standard effort with none of Rain Man's humour or warmth.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not Heartwarming, NOT a joy to watch.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tvgeek91
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/4/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I found myself watching this movie in my French class, and, quite simply, I did not like it. I don't believe that either of the characters, Georges and Harry, were sympathetic by the end of the film. It is made clear that Georges cares about nobody but himself and we are supposed to care for him purely because he has down syndrome. Harry is so caught up in business that he didn't remember to pick up the two daughters that he supposedly cares about so much. He attacks his estranged wife and shows no sign of guilt for this over his sadness that she didn't agree to let him see his kids. I wouldn't let him see my kids if thats the way he behaved. Everything is all better at the end of the movie just because he set off some fireworks. That just doesn't make sense to me. In a movie that takes place in reality, the fantasy scenes were awkward and seemed to be squeezed in to anyplace that they could find and didn't convey a necessary message. Georges's sudden death at the end of the film was totally random and had very reason why it should occur. I don't regret seeing any movie, but if you're going to see a Daniel Auteuil movie I would recommend seeing Cache.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Mystery of the 8th Day
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Chrysanthepop
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    With 'Le Huiti&egrave;me Jour' director Jaco van Dormael tells us a moving tale of two complete strangers (who couldn't be more different from each other), whose paths cross as they travel opposite directions. After this odd encounter, together, both take turns heading towards each other's destinations but with heartbreaking results. However, this journey allows them to find something they didn't know they were looking for. Let's get the flaws out of the way: Certain scenes may feel a little dramatic but it still remains within the tone of the film, never looking out of place. Even though Harry and Georges are the primary focus of the film, some of the important supporting characters are poorly developed, especially Georges's hating sister and Miou Miou's Julie. But those minuses aside, is 'Le Huiti&egrave;me Jour' a road movie (the landscapes are dazzling)? Is it a study of two characters? Is it a 'buddy' movie (certainly not the typical Hollywood kind)? Is it a dramedy? It's poetry. The film, in a way, moves from one genre to another but it flows beautifully. The balance in humour, and intensity is first rate. The jokes work well and the timing is just right. I did find the ending to be a tad too dramatic. What Georges shows the viewer is that, while people desire similarities, it is our differences that make us unique. Yet, that is the very reason why Georges is rejected by the 'real world'. What Harry further shows is that none of these supposed similarities that people look for in each other matters because acceptance, respect, being open to possibilities and being true to oneself are what will bring the greater joy. 'Le Huiti&egrave;me Jour' is stunningly filmed and wonderfully acted. Pascal Duquenne and Daniel Auteuil are superb. Duquenne delivers a very natural performance and Auteuil is terrifically restrained. They are well supported by Isabelle Sadoyan, Michele Maes and the two actors who play Harry's daughter. 'Le Huiti&egrave;me Jour' engages you right from the start. It's funny, intense, enlightening and reaches straight for the heart.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Beautiful.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Santonix Lee
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I have not watched many French-language films in my lifetime, but The Eighth Day and Amelie are way up there on my list of favourite movies. Perhaps it's just overexposure to the monolithic crap Hollywood mass produces today, but these films have an atmosphere that are like a breath of fresh air. Even with (or perhaps because of) little to no special effects to bedazzle you, you are immersed before you know it. The spontaneity and sheer oddness of some of the scenes add to the charm of the film, as does the tumultuous and unlikely friendship between a workaholic and a man with Down's syndrome. The Eighth Day gives you something to reflect on, a pause from the fast paced lifestyles we are caught up in today.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    How a movie becomes a Film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    kwsndsm
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/4/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    **May contain spoilers** I finally own "Le huiti&egrave;me jour". First time I saw it was as a rental, while living in the US. This movie is a true Film, it is a fairytale, where reality and fantasy is interwoven in a true use of style, acting, vision and direction. Watched it yesterday, having found that it was now available on DVD, and buying it in the US of all places. Harry and George start out as the odd couple, but as the Film progress they become two sides of humans and humanity, George is prefacing the end through his words and actions through the Film, and only at the end all of them becomes apparent. This story is one which I think all should on occasion try to see, it is movie making at it's best. The dream sequences would not translate into words as strongly as the visual impact, the fact that no words are spoken through some of them, and the 'force' with which our emotions and thoughts react to them. It is not supposed to be 'believable' it is supposed to tell a story, and it does that to the best possible extent imaginable. And indeed on the Eight day "all is good". This is one of my favorite movies all time.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Straight into my heart.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    per_jaderbrink
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/8/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The number of times I've had tears in my eyes when watching a movie are few. And there is only one time when I have really cried and that was when I saw this movie. This movie has some kliches but I really don't care. I cry even as I write this and it was quite some time since I saw it. It is perfectly acted and all the production values are good, but what really matters is the simple and wonderful message. We all know it in our hearts, but it is not always easy to remember that the only thing that really matters in life is LOVE in all it's forms. It's only when we love that we're truly alive. I know how sentimental I sound and I promise I'm not usually like that. I'm quite a cynic. This movie has brought out stronger feelings of both sorrow and happiness in me than any other movies and it will probably always be the first movie I recommend others to see.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    good..
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    didiermustntdie
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/7/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    a great film, one of the funniest films ever. the only thing that disturbed me is the music sounds like flashdance...what a feeling.. also it would be more believable if the character Daniel Auteuil plays were a loser businessman,that would be less effective but more believable. but anything else is valid, credible and even realist.. the scene with Georges's sister is touching , the scene with the maid is moving and bitter,the shoe shop scene ,the opening sequence and some others are hilarious. but the car shop one is gone too far.. oh well, another issue on the subplot,he is neither unfaithful nor abusive. I don't know what's the problem between harry and his wife. I think I would stand by harry's side like I did in "war of roses". it's my first film about Down syndrome people, those forgotten souls(people now only care about and spend too much time and energy on blacks who are actually the real oppressors today)...
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The beauty of the small things.... again.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Doktor Hackenbush
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/5/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    An executive, very successful in his professional life but very unable in his familiar life, meets a boy with down syndrome, escaped from a residence . Both characters feel very alone, and the apparently less intelligent one will show to the executive the beauty of the small things in life... With this argument, the somehow Amelie-like atmosphere and the sentimental music, I didn't expect but a moralistic disgusting movie. Anyway, as there were some interesting scenes (the boy is sometimes quite a violent guy), and the interpretation of both actors, Daniel Auteil and Pasqal Duquenne, was very good, I decided to go on watching the movie. The French cinema, in general, has the ability of showing something that seems quite much to life, opposed to the more stereotyped American cinema. But, because of that, it is much more disappointing to see after the absurd ending, with the impossible death of the boy, the charming tone, the happiness of the executive's family, the cheap moral, the unbearable laughter of the daughters, the guy waving from heaven as Michael Landon... Really nasty, in my humble opinion.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A touching film for good natured souls
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Gordon-11
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/8/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This film is about the unlikely friendship between a businessman and a man with Down Syndrome. The character development in this film is excellent. We get to believe that Harry is a businessman who neglects his family, and Georges is an innocent man who craves loving and care from the "normal" society. Acting is excellent, and the Cannes best actor award is well deserved. The fantasy scenes in the film highlights the fact that Georges misery towards his abandonment by his family, and his desire to be treated like a normal person. The song that gets played repeatedly also reinforces this message. The film shows that people who are mentally handicapped are good natured. We have been treating them with discrimination and neglect, a fact that is highlighted by the scene where Georges gives a present to the waitress in the kitchen). If we get to understand and share these people's world, both we and the mentally handicapped can become very happy. I was so drawn into the film and the characters' emotional experiences. It is a touching film for good natured souls.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of My Favorite Movies!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    (sylviastel@aol.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/2/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I saw this film first on my way home from Paris to Newark aboard Air France in August 1996. The film itself I believe is quite a masterpiece. It's the kind of film that people should be making. I still think Daniel Auteuil is one of the sexiest actors around. In this French film, he plays a divorced father and businessman who has lost his zest for life until he across a Down Syndrome man who lives in an institution with other Down Syndrome patients. The actors including the actor who actually has Down Syndrome create a believable friendship and relationship between these two unlikely men. Daniel's life and ours changes forever with the Down Syndrome man. He realizes that life is not just work and not play but for the living and loving and that's what life should be all about. The ending is kind of silly though but I still think it's one of my favorite movies. It's enough to bring a tear to your eye.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Good acting but not much else.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    The_Triad
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/1/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Eighth Day is supposed to be a charming experience, but I found it to be largely irritating and dull. The film focuses around Harry, played by Daniel Auteuil, a salesman who's life is falling apart. Stuck in his daily routine, estranged from his wife and failing to be a father to his children. This, cut-and-paste character then meets Georges, a guy with Down's Syndrome who proceeds as we all know by now to help him turn his life around and get back to being a father to his kids. The problem is that we are given no insight as to why Harry puts up with Georges after the initial meeting. Harry's life is in a bad enough state as it is, it's completely implausible that he'd risk losing his job by taking time off to try and get Georges to his mother's house. The humour completely misses the mark, instead of showing us why Harry is putting up with this guy, we are treated to a series of irritating, unfunny skits in which Harry bears the brunt of Georges mishaps. The film reaches its peak when Georges remembers it's Harry's daughters birthday and along with other people from his home steal a bus, take Harry out of a conference, set off some fireworks, et viola! Harry is a good father again and now he can see the kids. For a film that is supposed to be grounded in realism (despite its poor attempt at a fantasy/reality message) this is completely implausible and unbelievable. Add to this the demise of Georges character, which I cannot fathom as to how people have been in tears at, as he is surely one of the most irritating characters ever created. The best thing about the film is it does have two great performances from its two leads, but these are not good enough for me to recommend that anyone sit through it. A lot of comments for this film has suggested its similarity and superiority to Rain Man, this is not so in my eyes, this is a watered down sub-standard effort with none of Rain Man's humour or warmth.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not Heartwarming, NOT a joy to watch.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tvgeek91
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/4/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I found myself watching this movie in my French class, and, quite simply, I did not like it. I don't believe that either of the characters, Georges and Harry, were sympathetic by the end of the film. It is made clear that Georges cares about nobody but himself and we are supposed to care for him purely because he has down syndrome. Harry is so caught up in business that he didn't remember to pick up the two daughters that he supposedly cares about so much. He attacks his estranged wife and shows no sign of guilt for this over his sadness that she didn't agree to let him see his kids. I wouldn't let him see my kids if thats the way he behaved. Everything is all better at the end of the movie just because he set off some fireworks. That just doesn't make sense to me. In a movie that takes place in reality, the fantasy scenes were awkward and seemed to be squeezed in to anyplace that they could find and didn't convey a necessary message. Georges's sudden death at the end of the film was totally random and had very reason why it should occur. I don't regret seeing any movie, but if you're going to see a Daniel Auteuil movie I would recommend seeing Cache.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Mystery of the 8th Day
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Chrysanthepop
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    With 'Le Huiti&egrave;me Jour' director Jaco van Dormael tells us a moving tale of two complete strangers (who couldn't be more different from each other), whose paths cross as they travel opposite directions. After this odd encounter, together, both take turns heading towards each other's destinations but with heartbreaking results. However, this journey allows them to find something they didn't know they were looking for. Let's get the flaws out of the way: Certain scenes may feel a little dramatic but it still remains within the tone of the film, never looking out of place. Even though Harry and Georges are the primary focus of the film, some of the important supporting characters are poorly developed, especially Georges's hating sister and Miou Miou's Julie. But those minuses aside, is 'Le Huiti&egrave;me Jour' a road movie (the landscapes are dazzling)? Is it a study of two characters? Is it a 'buddy' movie (certainly not the typical Hollywood kind)? Is it a dramedy? It's poetry. The film, in a way, moves from one genre to another but it flows beautifully. The balance in humour, and intensity is first rate. The jokes work well and the timing is just right. I did find the ending to be a tad too dramatic. What Georges shows the viewer is that, while people desire similarities, it is our differences that make us unique. Yet, that is the very reason why Georges is rejected by the 'real world'. What Harry further shows is that none of these supposed similarities that people look for in each other matters because acceptance, respect, being open to possibilities and being true to oneself are what will bring the greater joy. 'Le Huiti&egrave;me Jour' is stunningly filmed and wonderfully acted. Pascal Duquenne and Daniel Auteuil are superb. Duquenne delivers a very natural performance and Auteuil is terrifically restrained. They are well supported by Isabelle Sadoyan, Michele Maes and the two actors who play Harry's daughter. 'Le Huiti&egrave;me Jour' engages you right from the start. It's funny, intense, enlightening and reaches straight for the heart.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Beautiful.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Santonix Lee
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I have not watched many French-language films in my lifetime, but The Eighth Day and Amelie are way up there on my list of favourite movies. Perhaps it's just overexposure to the monolithic crap Hollywood mass produces today, but these films have an atmosphere that are like a breath of fresh air. Even with (or perhaps because of) little to no special effects to bedazzle you, you are immersed before you know it. The spontaneity and sheer oddness of some of the scenes add to the charm of the film, as does the tumultuous and unlikely friendship between a workaholic and a man with Down's syndrome. The Eighth Day gives you something to reflect on, a pause from the fast paced lifestyles we are caught up in today.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    How a movie becomes a Film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    kwsndsm
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/4/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    **May contain spoilers** I finally own "Le huiti&egrave;me jour". First time I saw it was as a rental, while living in the US. This movie is a true Film, it is a fairytale, where reality and fantasy is interwoven in a true use of style, acting, vision and direction. Watched it yesterday, having found that it was now available on DVD, and buying it in the US of all places. Harry and George start out as the odd couple, but as the Film progress they become two sides of humans and humanity, George is prefacing the end through his words and actions through the Film, and only at the end all of them becomes apparent. This story is one which I think all should on occasion try to see, it is movie making at it's best. The dream sequences would not translate into words as strongly as the visual impact, the fact that no words are spoken through some of them, and the 'force' with which our emotions and thoughts react to them. It is not supposed to be 'believable' it is supposed to tell a story, and it does that to the best possible extent imaginable. And indeed on the Eight day "all is good". This is one of my favorite movies all time.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Straight into my heart.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    per_jaderbrink
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/8/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The number of times I've had tears in my eyes when watching a movie are few. And there is only one time when I have really cried and that was when I saw this movie. This movie has some kliches but I really don't care. I cry even as I write this and it was quite some time since I saw it. It is perfectly acted and all the production values are good, but what really matters is the simple and wonderful message. We all know it in our hearts, but it is not always easy to remember that the only thing that really matters in life is LOVE in all it's forms. It's only when we love that we're truly alive. I know how sentimental I sound and I promise I'm not usually like that. I'm quite a cynic. This movie has brought out stronger feelings of both sorrow and happiness in me than any other movies and it will probably always be the first movie I recommend others to see.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    good..
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    didiermustntdie
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/7/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    a great film, one of the funniest films ever. the only thing that disturbed me is the music sounds like flashdance...what a feeling.. also it would be more believable if the character Daniel Auteuil plays were a loser businessman,that would be less effective but more believable. but anything else is valid, credible and even realist.. the scene with Georges's sister is touching , the scene with the maid is moving and bitter,the shoe shop scene ,the opening sequence and some others are hilarious. but the car shop one is gone too far.. oh well, another issue on the subplot,he is neither unfaithful nor abusive. I don't know what's the problem between harry and his wife. I think I would stand by harry's side like I did in "war of roses". it's my first film about Down syndrome people, those forgotten souls(people now only care about and spend too much time and energy on blacks who are actually the real oppressors today)...
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The beauty of the small things.... again.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Doktor Hackenbush
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/5/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    An executive, very successful in his professional life but very unable in his familiar life, meets a boy with down syndrome, escaped from a residence . Both characters feel very alone, and the apparently less intelligent one will show to the executive the beauty of the small things in life... With this argument, the somehow Amelie-like atmosphere and the sentimental music, I didn't expect but a moralistic disgusting movie. Anyway, as there were some interesting scenes (the boy is sometimes quite a violent guy), and the interpretation of both actors, Daniel Auteil and Pasqal Duquenne, was very good, I decided to go on watching the movie. The French cinema, in general, has the ability of showing something that seems quite much to life, opposed to the more stereotyped American cinema. But, because of that, it is much more disappointing to see after the absurd ending, with the impossible death of the boy, the charming tone, the happiness of the executive's family, the cheap moral, the unbearable laughter of the daughters, the guy waving from heaven as Michael Landon... Really nasty, in my humble opinion.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A touching film for good natured souls
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Gordon-11
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/8/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This film is about the unlikely friendship between a businessman and a man with Down Syndrome. The character development in this film is excellent. We get to believe that Harry is a businessman who neglects his family, and Georges is an innocent man who craves loving and care from the "normal" society. Acting is excellent, and the Cannes best actor award is well deserved. The fantasy scenes in the film highlights the fact that Georges misery towards his abandonment by his family, and his desire to be treated like a normal person. The song that gets played repeatedly also reinforces this message. The film shows that people who are mentally handicapped are good natured. We have been treating them with discrimination and neglect, a fact that is highlighted by the scene where Georges gives a present to the waitress in the kitchen). If we get to understand and share these people's world, both we and the mentally handicapped can become very happy. I was so drawn into the film and the characters' emotional experiences. It is a touching film for good natured souls.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of My Favorite Movies!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    (sylviastel@aol.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/2/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I saw this film first on my way home from Paris to Newark aboard Air France in August 1996. The film itself I believe is quite a masterpiece. It's the kind of film that people should be making. I still think Daniel Auteuil is one of the sexiest actors around. In this French film, he plays a divorced father and businessman who has lost his zest for life until he across a Down Syndrome man who lives in an institution with other Down Syndrome patients. The actors including the actor who actually has Down Syndrome create a believable friendship and relationship between these two unlikely men. Daniel's life and ours changes forever with the Down Syndrome man. He realizes that life is not just work and not play but for the living and loving and that's what life should be all about. The ending is kind of silly though but I still think it's one of my favorite movies. It's enough to bring a tear to your eye.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Good acting but not much else.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    The_Triad
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/1/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Eighth Day is supposed to be a charming experience, but I found it to be largely irritating and dull. The film focuses around Harry, played by Daniel Auteuil, a salesman who's life is falling apart. Stuck in his daily routine, estranged from his wife and failing to be a father to his children. This, cut-and-paste character then meets Georges, a guy with Down's Syndrome who proceeds as we all know by now to help him turn his life around and get back to being a father to his kids. The problem is that we are given no insight as to why Harry puts up with Georges after the initial meeting. Harry's life is in a bad enough state as it is, it's completely implausible that he'd risk losing his job by taking time off to try and get Georges to his mother's house. The humour completely misses the mark, instead of showing us why Harry is putting up with this guy, we are treated to a series of irritating, unfunny skits in which Harry bears the brunt of Georges mishaps. The film reaches its peak when Georges remembers it's Harry's daughters birthday and along with other people from his home steal a bus, take Harry out of a conference, set off some fireworks, et viola! Harry is a good father again and now he can see the kids. For a film that is supposed to be grounded in realism (despite its poor attempt at a fantasy/reality message) this is completely implausible and unbelievable. Add to this the demise of Georges character, which I cannot fathom as to how people have been in tears at, as he is surely one of the most irritating characters ever created. The best thing about the film is it does have two great performances from its two leads, but these are not good enough for me to recommend that anyone sit through it. A lot of comments for this film has suggested its similarity and superiority to Rain Man, this is not so in my eyes, this is a watered down sub-standard effort with none of Rain Man's humour or warmth.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not Heartwarming, NOT a joy to watch.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tvgeek91
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/4/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I found myself watching this movie in my French class, and, quite simply, I did not like it. I don't believe that either of the characters, Georges and Harry, were sympathetic by the end of the film. It is made clear that Georges cares about nobody but himself and we are supposed to care for him purely because he has down syndrome. Harry is so caught up in business that he didn't remember to pick up the two daughters that he supposedly cares about so much. He attacks his estranged wife and shows no sign of guilt for this over his sadness that she didn't agree to let him see his kids. I wouldn't let him see my kids if thats the way he behaved. Everything is all better at the end of the movie just because he set off some fireworks. That just doesn't make sense to me. In a movie that takes place in reality, the fantasy scenes were awkward and seemed to be squeezed in to anyplace that they could find and didn't convey a necessary message. Georges's sudden death at the end of the film was totally random and had very reason why it should occur. I don't regret seeing any movie, but if you're going to see a Daniel Auteuil movie I would recommend seeing Cache.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
 </reviews>
</filme>
