<filme>
 <id>
  1647
 </id>
 <imdburl>
  http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0119250
 </imdburl>
 <ano>
  1997
 </ano>
 <titulo>
  Fogos de Artif&iacute;cio
 </titulo>
 <rating>
  7.8
 </rating>
 <sinopse>
  A police officer leaves the force in the face of harrowing personal and professional difficulties. Spiraling into a depression he makes questionable decisions.
 </sinopse>
 <storyline>
  Nishi is a cop whose wife is slowly dying of Leukemia. One of his partners gets shot on the job and is confined to a wheel chair for the rest of his life and becomes suicidal. Nishi, feeling guilt over his partners accident, tries to help him in any way he can. At the same time, Nishi leaves the police force to spend more time with his dying wife. However, in order to do the right things for those he loves, Nishi must do wrong things. Spiraling deeper into desperation and slowly building up to tragedy.
 </storyline>
 <generos>
  <genero>
   Crime
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Drama
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Romance
  </genero>
 </generos>
 <keywords>
  <keyword>
   police
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   guilt
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   leukemia
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   police investigation
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   blood
  </keyword>
 </keywords>
 <diretores>
  <diretor>
   Takeshi Kitano
  </diretor>
 </diretores>
 <escritores>
  <escritor>
   Takeshi Kitano
  </escritor>
 </escritores>
 <atores>
  <ator>
   Takeshi Kitano
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Kayoko Kishimoto
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Ren Ohsugi
  </ator>
 </atores>
 <reviews>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Love, painting and poetry...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ivanbmm
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I don't gave 10 because there is some dose of violence in this movie to my taste. However, fading away this violence there is one of the most beautiful stories of love, painting and poetry that I've ever seen. I keep scanning movie forums, looking for these kind of movies. In my view, they are felt with more down-to-earth love stories, which I am finding rare to find now-a-days. The closer I can get from Hana-bi is Poetry by Chang-dong Lee. The reason I love both is the same. They are full of beautiful metaphors to give colour to such trivial stories, realistic characters like Nishi (Takeshi Kitano) and off course, poetic visuals. Hana-bi is worth watching for poetry lovers.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Explosions in the sky
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    lionelduffy
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/12/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is a perfectly judged movie. The peerless Takeshi Kitano moves almost wordlessly through this film conveying moments of genuine tenderness alongside vengeful violence. The mastery with which he alternates between the tender and the brutal without ever losing the pathos of his character Nishi's situation is stunning. As ever Kitano reaches for the simplistic as opposed to the bombastic - admirable for a movie peopled with comic book violent yakuza and characters shattered by the unfairness of life's mandatory dealing of the cards. Telling the story in violent flashback, Kitano balances his tale with a beautiful understated romanticism laced with comic tenderness. This is the film the deft editor, visionary director, multifaceted actor and comic genius was born to make.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Too slow and "deep" at times but mostly emotionally engaging and impacting
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bob the moo
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/7/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Nishi is a cop who is very good at his job but whose personal life is impacted with loss  a dead child and now a dying wife. When his partner is put in a wheelchair by a criminal and another officer is shot dead, Nishi finds himself plagued by guilt over his part in it all. Blaming himself Nishi tries to do the right thing by his partner Horibe and the widow of cop, while also trying to salvage some happiness in what remains of his time with his wife. I came back to Takeshi Kitano about the same time as I left the Movies You Should See podcast. I left it because I don't think it is as good as it could be and at times offers no real insight into a film other than describing "bits" however I give them a mention because they reminded me that I had only ever seen one or two of Kitano's films and that it had been some time since I had even seen those. So it was that after watching Brother, my rental site threw me Hana-Bi and I was looking forward to it due to the praise on this site and indeed the podcast itself. The expectation was not unjustified as Hana-Bi is a film of pain and beauty that is well worth seeing even if it is not the image of perfection that some would have you believe. That statement is bound to attract a low vote on IMDb but what can I tell you? That it was slow and quiet is not a problem for me but it is a feeling you get watching the film and it is not helped by some scenes feeling irrelevant within the context of the story. This is not a real killer but I felt that the slow pace needed support and seeing two minor characters argue about a fender bender (for example) saw my interest dip and the slow pace start to be felt. Otherwise though, the silence and pace suits the material and the style of the film. The violence is quite subdued (in regards what you actually see) because it occurs in the edit of the action  so the actual impact is mostly unseen. It doesn't matter though because the main thrust of the film is less the outward violence but the internal suffering of all the characters. The film does wear this aspect a little heavily at times and some will feel that some sequences are right on the edge of being pretentious and there is no point in denying that it does walk this line here and there. However for the majority it is a really well observed and emotionally engaging story built on the silent but emotive presence of Kitano as writer, director and star. As writer he has, it could be argued, left a lot to the actual making process itself since the script must have been a few pages. As director he sets the pace and I like the way his static style works within this story but it is his work as actor that always mystifies and impresses me. How he can convey so much while also appearing to be doing nothing at all I'm not sure but it somehow works and fits his style in other disciplines. He is well supported by Kishimoto, with whom he has genuine chemistry without betraying his character's nature. Osugi is not that great and it is with his character that I found the film close to being pretentious, not the actor's fault of course but I never felt for him as I did for Nishi. Hana-Bi is very slow and quiet and I can totally understand why some viewers will throw it in very early on. However sticking with it reveals a film that manages to be violent, introspective and emotionally engaging at the same time, all wrapped in the style of Kitano, who is creative across the board.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An overlooked masterpiece from the 90s
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    TimothyFarrell
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/12/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Hana-bi" may appear to be a standard cop action thriller from a simple plot description, but nothing could be further from the truth. Takashi Kitano's masterpiece is a slow moving meditation on human nature. Its violent at moments to be sure, but the "action" consists of short bursts of gun play that are stripped of any romanticism. They're all the more effective because of how sparingly they're employed. If anything, Kitano has much more in common with Yasujiro Ozu than John Woo. Kitano has fashioned a fascinating character study, one whose actual meaning is very abstract and difficult to decipher. The film's subtlety requires multiple viewings to fully appreciate. The film has a transcendental nature whose beauty is difficult to describe in words. Kitano is both a masterclass director and actor. He's best known as a stand-up comedian in Japan, which is odd because of the amount of seriousness he invests in both his positions. His lead performance is tough but has an amount of unexpected depth. Hes truly one of cinema's most charismatic performers, and he has this amazing presence despite the minimal dialog. His direction is slowly paced, but perfect. Not a single moment is wasted in this film. "Hana-bi" is one of the 90's most overlooked masterpieces, a decade known for its lack of depth or subtlety. (9/10)
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A man by the sea with or without his wife
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Christian
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/11/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Takeshi Kitano not only writes, acts in, directs and edits this meaningful fable, he also paints the artworks that are a strong element of the film. Kitano is supposedly known for his violence, but this movie has more to do about the repercussion of violence--and about life and death in general--than showing actual violent scenes. The violence is there, bursts of explosive violence, but it is short and strategically edited. Nishi, the protagonist, sees his partners die or get injured in the line of duty. One of them, Horibe, becomes wheel-chair-bound. His wife leaves him and he contemplates life and death staring at the horizon beyond the sea. He starts to paint to express himself and save himself from boredom and sorrow. Nishi, sick of his work leaves the police force to spend some time with his dying wife. The doctor just released her from the hospital and she does not have much time left... Kitano chooses to focus on the underlying emotions rather than dialogue as most of the scenes with his wife are silent. At first, this is unnerving, but slowly, as the movie progress, we understand that there is nothing left to stay. The score of the movie is its strongest point. Accomplished composer, Joe Hisaishi (who worked with Kitano on other projects as well as with Miyazaki's animated films) outdoes himself with poignant classical music that, unlike Nishi, speaks volume. He would win the Award of the Japanese Academy for this. Some good cinematography can also be observed at times. Kitano's paintings are interesting and vibrant. They add yet another level of complexity to this intriguing piece of film. All in all, a very well made film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    touching and incredible profound movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bruno-ferreira382
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/11/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Hana-bi is visual poetry, it says so much without using words.it is brilliantly directed because the movie delivers such an intense mood,the music by joe hisaishi also plays an important role in this moody film.But what it really makes the movie so profound and moving it's minimalist style, all the characters in the movie show very little emotion and yet takeshi kitano makes the film so touching by only showing the sea, the sky,the flowers, the paintings,along with joe hisaishi music.the true power of the film is that it doesn't say very much in terms of speaking,but it says a lot with its stunning images and music.I recommend this to all who want see an introspective,profound and thought provoking film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Great film though not for everybody
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    nexxit
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/10/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I only once happened to get my fingers on Kitanos movie "Brother", which got me into checking out his other movies. So i got Hana Bi since it had a lot of good reviews. I can actually understand people, that mostly watch action flicks, getting bored by this film, but for those more into poetic films, this is just the thing for you. While short on dialog, the movie is stronger on the body language of all the characters... sometimes there isn't any dialog for more than 6 minutes or so, where you just have to watch in order to understand what he is trying to tell us... For me it the movie was a bit depressing and sometimes hard to follow, but i still enjoyed it a lot. But as i said, this movie is not for everyone.... The movie is about a cop in Japan who leaves the police to spend more time with his wife who is dying of cancer, and if that was not enough to bare with, he also lost a kid and his partner gets shot and paralyzed on the job. Now he has to deal with all these tragedies at the same time... So if you want a comparison, if you liked movies like "21 grams" for example, you will love this movie!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A collision of beauty and destruction
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ackstasis
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/8/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Takeshi Kitano's 'Hana-Bi' is something of an oddity. True to his previous efforts as director, the film contains its fair share of shockingly-graphic violence, and yet at its heart lies a touching tale of love, loyalty and devotion. For the entire running time, Kitano (who, aside from directing, also wrote and starred in the film) treads a perilously fine line between the two thematic extremes; it is an intricate balancing act that, if attempted by a less-talented filmmaker, might very possibly have turned into a complete cinematic disaster. Nevertheless, the director manages to pinpoint this perfect centre of balance, and the clash of beauty and violence combines to create a jarring amalgamation of conflicting emotional responses. We, as the audience, as simultaneously repulsed and entranced; as a whole, 'Hana-bi' is one of the most beautiful film experiences of the last decade or so. The title of the film itself acknowledges these opposing visual styles. Whilst the Japanese word 'Hanabi' translates to 'Fireworks' (the title under which it was released in the United States), the addition of the hyphen to the title ('Hana-bi') emphasises two individual components of the word, which translate respectively into "Fire" and "Flower," the collision of destruction and beauty/renewal. Much of the film concerns a cop named Yoshitaka Nishi (Kitano), who is forced to retire after a shooting on the job leaves his partner, Horibe (Ren Osugi), paralysed, alone and confined to a wheelchair. All the while, Nishi is still coming to terms with the impending loss of his wife, Miyuki (Kayoko Kishimoto), who is slowly dying from leukemia. As any grieving husband might do in such a situation, Nishi decides to quietly rob a bank, and he then uses most of the proceeds to fund a final loving family holiday for his ailing partner. The scenes between Nishi and his wife are among the most touching I've ever witnessed. Miyuki has only two lines in the entire film, and so the couple spend most of their time in complete silence and quiet reflection, and yet you can truly sense the affection that they both have for each other. Their love is completely unspoken, and this makes it all the more touching when Miyuki does finally speak. Another touching character is Horibe, the loyal police force partner whose crippling injury leaves him alone and depressed. After attempting suicide, Horibe receives painting materials in the mail, and he commits his emotions to canvas, finally uncovering a reason for his continued existence (importantly, the artwork we see in the film was actually created by Kitano in 1994, after a near-fatal motorcycle accident). The film's phenomenally moving soundtrack was composed by renowned Japanese composer Joe Hisaishi, in his fourth collaboration with the director. There are very few negative criticisms that can be said of 'Hana-bi.' One possible item is that the film's unusual flashback structure made some plot-points difficult to follow, and I'm still unsure of which cop's lonesome widow Nishi was in the habit of visiting. However, that's the only critique that springs straight to mind. All in all, 'Hana-bi' is a gloriously assorted blend of violence, love and gentle humour, and a first viewing is not likely to be forgotten in a hurry.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    an existential ode to violence
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    badtothebono
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/8/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    So, it has come to this. In the top-rated comment on this flick, somebody says "Nishi is an honorable man". Really? This is a guy who mainly kills and maims people in the movie. He takes a short break to rob a bank. Honorable? How would you like your kids to go to school with the kids of someone who calls that honorable? Wait, there's more! The person also says "we can tell he's constantly thinking." How can we do that? Well, do you know that joke "How can you tell when a CEO/politician/lawyer is lying?" ... "His/her lips move." Well, Nishi's lips never move, so I guess that means he is thinking. Of course, this is existentialism to warm the hearts of the cult of victimization. Existentalism supposedly stresses that an individual take responsibility for the consequences of one's acts. Not Nishi. Borrow money from the yakuza. What, they want it back? Kill them. The cops find out. Kill yourself and your wife. Really honorable.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Just one name:Takeshi Kitano
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    johnny-08
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/6/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is fourth movie that I watched from Takeshi Kitano and I have to say that I'm a little disappointed with this one.I know that this is probably his most awarding movie but I don't think this is his best.Far from there.I find "Dolls" his greatest achievement.Don't get me wrong "Hana-bi" is very good movie but I expected something better.It's because Kitano put so high standards and sometimes it is hard to achieve them. The plot is about Yoshitaka Nishi who is cop and his wife is dying of Leukemia.His partner gets shot in the job and he ends up in a wheel chair.Nishi is trying to help him because he feels that somehow he's guilty for what happened.Soon Nishi leaves police so he can spend more time with his wife.All his life he did wright things and know he has to do all wrong things so he can survive.He soon sinks deeper and deeper in his problems that are leading to tragedy. I liked the plot but this isn't nothing new.What is new is Kitano's way in filming this one.His camera is excellent and that part is very good but something about this movie as whole didn't fit perfectly to me.I don't know what that is but "Dolls" are better to me.I'm repeating myself so I'll quit know.Just one more thing;fans of Kitano won't be disappointed with this movie and also this movie is a great way to become a fan of this great film-maker.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Love, painting and poetry...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ivanbmm
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I don't gave 10 because there is some dose of violence in this movie to my taste. However, fading away this violence there is one of the most beautiful stories of love, painting and poetry that I've ever seen. I keep scanning movie forums, looking for these kind of movies. In my view, they are felt with more down-to-earth love stories, which I am finding rare to find now-a-days. The closer I can get from Hana-bi is Poetry by Chang-dong Lee. The reason I love both is the same. They are full of beautiful metaphors to give colour to such trivial stories, realistic characters like Nishi (Takeshi Kitano) and off course, poetic visuals. Hana-bi is worth watching for poetry lovers.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Explosions in the sky
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    lionelduffy
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/12/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is a perfectly judged movie. The peerless Takeshi Kitano moves almost wordlessly through this film conveying moments of genuine tenderness alongside vengeful violence. The mastery with which he alternates between the tender and the brutal without ever losing the pathos of his character Nishi's situation is stunning. As ever Kitano reaches for the simplistic as opposed to the bombastic - admirable for a movie peopled with comic book violent yakuza and characters shattered by the unfairness of life's mandatory dealing of the cards. Telling the story in violent flashback, Kitano balances his tale with a beautiful understated romanticism laced with comic tenderness. This is the film the deft editor, visionary director, multifaceted actor and comic genius was born to make.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Too slow and "deep" at times but mostly emotionally engaging and impacting
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bob the moo
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/7/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Nishi is a cop who is very good at his job but whose personal life is impacted with loss  a dead child and now a dying wife. When his partner is put in a wheelchair by a criminal and another officer is shot dead, Nishi finds himself plagued by guilt over his part in it all. Blaming himself Nishi tries to do the right thing by his partner Horibe and the widow of cop, while also trying to salvage some happiness in what remains of his time with his wife. I came back to Takeshi Kitano about the same time as I left the Movies You Should See podcast. I left it because I don't think it is as good as it could be and at times offers no real insight into a film other than describing "bits" however I give them a mention because they reminded me that I had only ever seen one or two of Kitano's films and that it had been some time since I had even seen those. So it was that after watching Brother, my rental site threw me Hana-Bi and I was looking forward to it due to the praise on this site and indeed the podcast itself. The expectation was not unjustified as Hana-Bi is a film of pain and beauty that is well worth seeing even if it is not the image of perfection that some would have you believe. That statement is bound to attract a low vote on IMDb but what can I tell you? That it was slow and quiet is not a problem for me but it is a feeling you get watching the film and it is not helped by some scenes feeling irrelevant within the context of the story. This is not a real killer but I felt that the slow pace needed support and seeing two minor characters argue about a fender bender (for example) saw my interest dip and the slow pace start to be felt. Otherwise though, the silence and pace suits the material and the style of the film. The violence is quite subdued (in regards what you actually see) because it occurs in the edit of the action  so the actual impact is mostly unseen. It doesn't matter though because the main thrust of the film is less the outward violence but the internal suffering of all the characters. The film does wear this aspect a little heavily at times and some will feel that some sequences are right on the edge of being pretentious and there is no point in denying that it does walk this line here and there. However for the majority it is a really well observed and emotionally engaging story built on the silent but emotive presence of Kitano as writer, director and star. As writer he has, it could be argued, left a lot to the actual making process itself since the script must have been a few pages. As director he sets the pace and I like the way his static style works within this story but it is his work as actor that always mystifies and impresses me. How he can convey so much while also appearing to be doing nothing at all I'm not sure but it somehow works and fits his style in other disciplines. He is well supported by Kishimoto, with whom he has genuine chemistry without betraying his character's nature. Osugi is not that great and it is with his character that I found the film close to being pretentious, not the actor's fault of course but I never felt for him as I did for Nishi. Hana-Bi is very slow and quiet and I can totally understand why some viewers will throw it in very early on. However sticking with it reveals a film that manages to be violent, introspective and emotionally engaging at the same time, all wrapped in the style of Kitano, who is creative across the board.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An overlooked masterpiece from the 90s
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    TimothyFarrell
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/12/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Hana-bi" may appear to be a standard cop action thriller from a simple plot description, but nothing could be further from the truth. Takashi Kitano's masterpiece is a slow moving meditation on human nature. Its violent at moments to be sure, but the "action" consists of short bursts of gun play that are stripped of any romanticism. They're all the more effective because of how sparingly they're employed. If anything, Kitano has much more in common with Yasujiro Ozu than John Woo. Kitano has fashioned a fascinating character study, one whose actual meaning is very abstract and difficult to decipher. The film's subtlety requires multiple viewings to fully appreciate. The film has a transcendental nature whose beauty is difficult to describe in words. Kitano is both a masterclass director and actor. He's best known as a stand-up comedian in Japan, which is odd because of the amount of seriousness he invests in both his positions. His lead performance is tough but has an amount of unexpected depth. Hes truly one of cinema's most charismatic performers, and he has this amazing presence despite the minimal dialog. His direction is slowly paced, but perfect. Not a single moment is wasted in this film. "Hana-bi" is one of the 90's most overlooked masterpieces, a decade known for its lack of depth or subtlety. (9/10)
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A man by the sea with or without his wife
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Christian
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/11/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Takeshi Kitano not only writes, acts in, directs and edits this meaningful fable, he also paints the artworks that are a strong element of the film. Kitano is supposedly known for his violence, but this movie has more to do about the repercussion of violence--and about life and death in general--than showing actual violent scenes. The violence is there, bursts of explosive violence, but it is short and strategically edited. Nishi, the protagonist, sees his partners die or get injured in the line of duty. One of them, Horibe, becomes wheel-chair-bound. His wife leaves him and he contemplates life and death staring at the horizon beyond the sea. He starts to paint to express himself and save himself from boredom and sorrow. Nishi, sick of his work leaves the police force to spend some time with his dying wife. The doctor just released her from the hospital and she does not have much time left... Kitano chooses to focus on the underlying emotions rather than dialogue as most of the scenes with his wife are silent. At first, this is unnerving, but slowly, as the movie progress, we understand that there is nothing left to stay. The score of the movie is its strongest point. Accomplished composer, Joe Hisaishi (who worked with Kitano on other projects as well as with Miyazaki's animated films) outdoes himself with poignant classical music that, unlike Nishi, speaks volume. He would win the Award of the Japanese Academy for this. Some good cinematography can also be observed at times. Kitano's paintings are interesting and vibrant. They add yet another level of complexity to this intriguing piece of film. All in all, a very well made film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    touching and incredible profound movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bruno-ferreira382
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/11/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Hana-bi is visual poetry, it says so much without using words.it is brilliantly directed because the movie delivers such an intense mood,the music by joe hisaishi also plays an important role in this moody film.But what it really makes the movie so profound and moving it's minimalist style, all the characters in the movie show very little emotion and yet takeshi kitano makes the film so touching by only showing the sea, the sky,the flowers, the paintings,along with joe hisaishi music.the true power of the film is that it doesn't say very much in terms of speaking,but it says a lot with its stunning images and music.I recommend this to all who want see an introspective,profound and thought provoking film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Great film though not for everybody
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    nexxit
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/10/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I only once happened to get my fingers on Kitanos movie "Brother", which got me into checking out his other movies. So i got Hana Bi since it had a lot of good reviews. I can actually understand people, that mostly watch action flicks, getting bored by this film, but for those more into poetic films, this is just the thing for you. While short on dialog, the movie is stronger on the body language of all the characters... sometimes there isn't any dialog for more than 6 minutes or so, where you just have to watch in order to understand what he is trying to tell us... For me it the movie was a bit depressing and sometimes hard to follow, but i still enjoyed it a lot. But as i said, this movie is not for everyone.... The movie is about a cop in Japan who leaves the police to spend more time with his wife who is dying of cancer, and if that was not enough to bare with, he also lost a kid and his partner gets shot and paralyzed on the job. Now he has to deal with all these tragedies at the same time... So if you want a comparison, if you liked movies like "21 grams" for example, you will love this movie!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A collision of beauty and destruction
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ackstasis
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/8/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Takeshi Kitano's 'Hana-Bi' is something of an oddity. True to his previous efforts as director, the film contains its fair share of shockingly-graphic violence, and yet at its heart lies a touching tale of love, loyalty and devotion. For the entire running time, Kitano (who, aside from directing, also wrote and starred in the film) treads a perilously fine line between the two thematic extremes; it is an intricate balancing act that, if attempted by a less-talented filmmaker, might very possibly have turned into a complete cinematic disaster. Nevertheless, the director manages to pinpoint this perfect centre of balance, and the clash of beauty and violence combines to create a jarring amalgamation of conflicting emotional responses. We, as the audience, as simultaneously repulsed and entranced; as a whole, 'Hana-bi' is one of the most beautiful film experiences of the last decade or so. The title of the film itself acknowledges these opposing visual styles. Whilst the Japanese word 'Hanabi' translates to 'Fireworks' (the title under which it was released in the United States), the addition of the hyphen to the title ('Hana-bi') emphasises two individual components of the word, which translate respectively into "Fire" and "Flower," the collision of destruction and beauty/renewal. Much of the film concerns a cop named Yoshitaka Nishi (Kitano), who is forced to retire after a shooting on the job leaves his partner, Horibe (Ren Osugi), paralysed, alone and confined to a wheelchair. All the while, Nishi is still coming to terms with the impending loss of his wife, Miyuki (Kayoko Kishimoto), who is slowly dying from leukemia. As any grieving husband might do in such a situation, Nishi decides to quietly rob a bank, and he then uses most of the proceeds to fund a final loving family holiday for his ailing partner. The scenes between Nishi and his wife are among the most touching I've ever witnessed. Miyuki has only two lines in the entire film, and so the couple spend most of their time in complete silence and quiet reflection, and yet you can truly sense the affection that they both have for each other. Their love is completely unspoken, and this makes it all the more touching when Miyuki does finally speak. Another touching character is Horibe, the loyal police force partner whose crippling injury leaves him alone and depressed. After attempting suicide, Horibe receives painting materials in the mail, and he commits his emotions to canvas, finally uncovering a reason for his continued existence (importantly, the artwork we see in the film was actually created by Kitano in 1994, after a near-fatal motorcycle accident). The film's phenomenally moving soundtrack was composed by renowned Japanese composer Joe Hisaishi, in his fourth collaboration with the director. There are very few negative criticisms that can be said of 'Hana-bi.' One possible item is that the film's unusual flashback structure made some plot-points difficult to follow, and I'm still unsure of which cop's lonesome widow Nishi was in the habit of visiting. However, that's the only critique that springs straight to mind. All in all, 'Hana-bi' is a gloriously assorted blend of violence, love and gentle humour, and a first viewing is not likely to be forgotten in a hurry.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    an existential ode to violence
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    badtothebono
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/8/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    So, it has come to this. In the top-rated comment on this flick, somebody says "Nishi is an honorable man". Really? This is a guy who mainly kills and maims people in the movie. He takes a short break to rob a bank. Honorable? How would you like your kids to go to school with the kids of someone who calls that honorable? Wait, there's more! The person also says "we can tell he's constantly thinking." How can we do that? Well, do you know that joke "How can you tell when a CEO/politician/lawyer is lying?" ... "His/her lips move." Well, Nishi's lips never move, so I guess that means he is thinking. Of course, this is existentialism to warm the hearts of the cult of victimization. Existentalism supposedly stresses that an individual take responsibility for the consequences of one's acts. Not Nishi. Borrow money from the yakuza. What, they want it back? Kill them. The cops find out. Kill yourself and your wife. Really honorable.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Just one name:Takeshi Kitano
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    johnny-08
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/6/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is fourth movie that I watched from Takeshi Kitano and I have to say that I'm a little disappointed with this one.I know that this is probably his most awarding movie but I don't think this is his best.Far from there.I find "Dolls" his greatest achievement.Don't get me wrong "Hana-bi" is very good movie but I expected something better.It's because Kitano put so high standards and sometimes it is hard to achieve them. The plot is about Yoshitaka Nishi who is cop and his wife is dying of Leukemia.His partner gets shot in the job and he ends up in a wheel chair.Nishi is trying to help him because he feels that somehow he's guilty for what happened.Soon Nishi leaves police so he can spend more time with his wife.All his life he did wright things and know he has to do all wrong things so he can survive.He soon sinks deeper and deeper in his problems that are leading to tragedy. I liked the plot but this isn't nothing new.What is new is Kitano's way in filming this one.His camera is excellent and that part is very good but something about this movie as whole didn't fit perfectly to me.I don't know what that is but "Dolls" are better to me.I'm repeating myself so I'll quit know.Just one more thing;fans of Kitano won't be disappointed with this movie and also this movie is a great way to become a fan of this great film-maker.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Love, painting and poetry...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ivanbmm
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I don't gave 10 because there is some dose of violence in this movie to my taste. However, fading away this violence there is one of the most beautiful stories of love, painting and poetry that I've ever seen. I keep scanning movie forums, looking for these kind of movies. In my view, they are felt with more down-to-earth love stories, which I am finding rare to find now-a-days. The closer I can get from Hana-bi is Poetry by Chang-dong Lee. The reason I love both is the same. They are full of beautiful metaphors to give colour to such trivial stories, realistic characters like Nishi (Takeshi Kitano) and off course, poetic visuals. Hana-bi is worth watching for poetry lovers.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Explosions in the sky
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    lionelduffy
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/12/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is a perfectly judged movie. The peerless Takeshi Kitano moves almost wordlessly through this film conveying moments of genuine tenderness alongside vengeful violence. The mastery with which he alternates between the tender and the brutal without ever losing the pathos of his character Nishi's situation is stunning. As ever Kitano reaches for the simplistic as opposed to the bombastic - admirable for a movie peopled with comic book violent yakuza and characters shattered by the unfairness of life's mandatory dealing of the cards. Telling the story in violent flashback, Kitano balances his tale with a beautiful understated romanticism laced with comic tenderness. This is the film the deft editor, visionary director, multifaceted actor and comic genius was born to make.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Too slow and "deep" at times but mostly emotionally engaging and impacting
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bob the moo
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/7/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Nishi is a cop who is very good at his job but whose personal life is impacted with loss  a dead child and now a dying wife. When his partner is put in a wheelchair by a criminal and another officer is shot dead, Nishi finds himself plagued by guilt over his part in it all. Blaming himself Nishi tries to do the right thing by his partner Horibe and the widow of cop, while also trying to salvage some happiness in what remains of his time with his wife. I came back to Takeshi Kitano about the same time as I left the Movies You Should See podcast. I left it because I don't think it is as good as it could be and at times offers no real insight into a film other than describing "bits" however I give them a mention because they reminded me that I had only ever seen one or two of Kitano's films and that it had been some time since I had even seen those. So it was that after watching Brother, my rental site threw me Hana-Bi and I was looking forward to it due to the praise on this site and indeed the podcast itself. The expectation was not unjustified as Hana-Bi is a film of pain and beauty that is well worth seeing even if it is not the image of perfection that some would have you believe. That statement is bound to attract a low vote on IMDb but what can I tell you? That it was slow and quiet is not a problem for me but it is a feeling you get watching the film and it is not helped by some scenes feeling irrelevant within the context of the story. This is not a real killer but I felt that the slow pace needed support and seeing two minor characters argue about a fender bender (for example) saw my interest dip and the slow pace start to be felt. Otherwise though, the silence and pace suits the material and the style of the film. The violence is quite subdued (in regards what you actually see) because it occurs in the edit of the action  so the actual impact is mostly unseen. It doesn't matter though because the main thrust of the film is less the outward violence but the internal suffering of all the characters. The film does wear this aspect a little heavily at times and some will feel that some sequences are right on the edge of being pretentious and there is no point in denying that it does walk this line here and there. However for the majority it is a really well observed and emotionally engaging story built on the silent but emotive presence of Kitano as writer, director and star. As writer he has, it could be argued, left a lot to the actual making process itself since the script must have been a few pages. As director he sets the pace and I like the way his static style works within this story but it is his work as actor that always mystifies and impresses me. How he can convey so much while also appearing to be doing nothing at all I'm not sure but it somehow works and fits his style in other disciplines. He is well supported by Kishimoto, with whom he has genuine chemistry without betraying his character's nature. Osugi is not that great and it is with his character that I found the film close to being pretentious, not the actor's fault of course but I never felt for him as I did for Nishi. Hana-Bi is very slow and quiet and I can totally understand why some viewers will throw it in very early on. However sticking with it reveals a film that manages to be violent, introspective and emotionally engaging at the same time, all wrapped in the style of Kitano, who is creative across the board.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An overlooked masterpiece from the 90s
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    TimothyFarrell
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/12/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Hana-bi" may appear to be a standard cop action thriller from a simple plot description, but nothing could be further from the truth. Takashi Kitano's masterpiece is a slow moving meditation on human nature. Its violent at moments to be sure, but the "action" consists of short bursts of gun play that are stripped of any romanticism. They're all the more effective because of how sparingly they're employed. If anything, Kitano has much more in common with Yasujiro Ozu than John Woo. Kitano has fashioned a fascinating character study, one whose actual meaning is very abstract and difficult to decipher. The film's subtlety requires multiple viewings to fully appreciate. The film has a transcendental nature whose beauty is difficult to describe in words. Kitano is both a masterclass director and actor. He's best known as a stand-up comedian in Japan, which is odd because of the amount of seriousness he invests in both his positions. His lead performance is tough but has an amount of unexpected depth. Hes truly one of cinema's most charismatic performers, and he has this amazing presence despite the minimal dialog. His direction is slowly paced, but perfect. Not a single moment is wasted in this film. "Hana-bi" is one of the 90's most overlooked masterpieces, a decade known for its lack of depth or subtlety. (9/10)
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A man by the sea with or without his wife
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Christian
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/11/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Takeshi Kitano not only writes, acts in, directs and edits this meaningful fable, he also paints the artworks that are a strong element of the film. Kitano is supposedly known for his violence, but this movie has more to do about the repercussion of violence--and about life and death in general--than showing actual violent scenes. The violence is there, bursts of explosive violence, but it is short and strategically edited. Nishi, the protagonist, sees his partners die or get injured in the line of duty. One of them, Horibe, becomes wheel-chair-bound. His wife leaves him and he contemplates life and death staring at the horizon beyond the sea. He starts to paint to express himself and save himself from boredom and sorrow. Nishi, sick of his work leaves the police force to spend some time with his dying wife. The doctor just released her from the hospital and she does not have much time left... Kitano chooses to focus on the underlying emotions rather than dialogue as most of the scenes with his wife are silent. At first, this is unnerving, but slowly, as the movie progress, we understand that there is nothing left to stay. The score of the movie is its strongest point. Accomplished composer, Joe Hisaishi (who worked with Kitano on other projects as well as with Miyazaki's animated films) outdoes himself with poignant classical music that, unlike Nishi, speaks volume. He would win the Award of the Japanese Academy for this. Some good cinematography can also be observed at times. Kitano's paintings are interesting and vibrant. They add yet another level of complexity to this intriguing piece of film. All in all, a very well made film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    touching and incredible profound movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bruno-ferreira382
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/11/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Hana-bi is visual poetry, it says so much without using words.it is brilliantly directed because the movie delivers such an intense mood,the music by joe hisaishi also plays an important role in this moody film.But what it really makes the movie so profound and moving it's minimalist style, all the characters in the movie show very little emotion and yet takeshi kitano makes the film so touching by only showing the sea, the sky,the flowers, the paintings,along with joe hisaishi music.the true power of the film is that it doesn't say very much in terms of speaking,but it says a lot with its stunning images and music.I recommend this to all who want see an introspective,profound and thought provoking film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Great film though not for everybody
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    nexxit
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/10/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I only once happened to get my fingers on Kitanos movie "Brother", which got me into checking out his other movies. So i got Hana Bi since it had a lot of good reviews. I can actually understand people, that mostly watch action flicks, getting bored by this film, but for those more into poetic films, this is just the thing for you. While short on dialog, the movie is stronger on the body language of all the characters... sometimes there isn't any dialog for more than 6 minutes or so, where you just have to watch in order to understand what he is trying to tell us... For me it the movie was a bit depressing and sometimes hard to follow, but i still enjoyed it a lot. But as i said, this movie is not for everyone.... The movie is about a cop in Japan who leaves the police to spend more time with his wife who is dying of cancer, and if that was not enough to bare with, he also lost a kid and his partner gets shot and paralyzed on the job. Now he has to deal with all these tragedies at the same time... So if you want a comparison, if you liked movies like "21 grams" for example, you will love this movie!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A collision of beauty and destruction
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ackstasis
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/8/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Takeshi Kitano's 'Hana-Bi' is something of an oddity. True to his previous efforts as director, the film contains its fair share of shockingly-graphic violence, and yet at its heart lies a touching tale of love, loyalty and devotion. For the entire running time, Kitano (who, aside from directing, also wrote and starred in the film) treads a perilously fine line between the two thematic extremes; it is an intricate balancing act that, if attempted by a less-talented filmmaker, might very possibly have turned into a complete cinematic disaster. Nevertheless, the director manages to pinpoint this perfect centre of balance, and the clash of beauty and violence combines to create a jarring amalgamation of conflicting emotional responses. We, as the audience, as simultaneously repulsed and entranced; as a whole, 'Hana-bi' is one of the most beautiful film experiences of the last decade or so. The title of the film itself acknowledges these opposing visual styles. Whilst the Japanese word 'Hanabi' translates to 'Fireworks' (the title under which it was released in the United States), the addition of the hyphen to the title ('Hana-bi') emphasises two individual components of the word, which translate respectively into "Fire" and "Flower," the collision of destruction and beauty/renewal. Much of the film concerns a cop named Yoshitaka Nishi (Kitano), who is forced to retire after a shooting on the job leaves his partner, Horibe (Ren Osugi), paralysed, alone and confined to a wheelchair. All the while, Nishi is still coming to terms with the impending loss of his wife, Miyuki (Kayoko Kishimoto), who is slowly dying from leukemia. As any grieving husband might do in such a situation, Nishi decides to quietly rob a bank, and he then uses most of the proceeds to fund a final loving family holiday for his ailing partner. The scenes between Nishi and his wife are among the most touching I've ever witnessed. Miyuki has only two lines in the entire film, and so the couple spend most of their time in complete silence and quiet reflection, and yet you can truly sense the affection that they both have for each other. Their love is completely unspoken, and this makes it all the more touching when Miyuki does finally speak. Another touching character is Horibe, the loyal police force partner whose crippling injury leaves him alone and depressed. After attempting suicide, Horibe receives painting materials in the mail, and he commits his emotions to canvas, finally uncovering a reason for his continued existence (importantly, the artwork we see in the film was actually created by Kitano in 1994, after a near-fatal motorcycle accident). The film's phenomenally moving soundtrack was composed by renowned Japanese composer Joe Hisaishi, in his fourth collaboration with the director. There are very few negative criticisms that can be said of 'Hana-bi.' One possible item is that the film's unusual flashback structure made some plot-points difficult to follow, and I'm still unsure of which cop's lonesome widow Nishi was in the habit of visiting. However, that's the only critique that springs straight to mind. All in all, 'Hana-bi' is a gloriously assorted blend of violence, love and gentle humour, and a first viewing is not likely to be forgotten in a hurry.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    an existential ode to violence
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    badtothebono
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/8/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    So, it has come to this. In the top-rated comment on this flick, somebody says "Nishi is an honorable man". Really? This is a guy who mainly kills and maims people in the movie. He takes a short break to rob a bank. Honorable? How would you like your kids to go to school with the kids of someone who calls that honorable? Wait, there's more! The person also says "we can tell he's constantly thinking." How can we do that? Well, do you know that joke "How can you tell when a CEO/politician/lawyer is lying?" ... "His/her lips move." Well, Nishi's lips never move, so I guess that means he is thinking. Of course, this is existentialism to warm the hearts of the cult of victimization. Existentalism supposedly stresses that an individual take responsibility for the consequences of one's acts. Not Nishi. Borrow money from the yakuza. What, they want it back? Kill them. The cops find out. Kill yourself and your wife. Really honorable.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Just one name:Takeshi Kitano
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    johnny-08
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/6/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is fourth movie that I watched from Takeshi Kitano and I have to say that I'm a little disappointed with this one.I know that this is probably his most awarding movie but I don't think this is his best.Far from there.I find "Dolls" his greatest achievement.Don't get me wrong "Hana-bi" is very good movie but I expected something better.It's because Kitano put so high standards and sometimes it is hard to achieve them. The plot is about Yoshitaka Nishi who is cop and his wife is dying of Leukemia.His partner gets shot in the job and he ends up in a wheel chair.Nishi is trying to help him because he feels that somehow he's guilty for what happened.Soon Nishi leaves police so he can spend more time with his wife.All his life he did wright things and know he has to do all wrong things so he can survive.He soon sinks deeper and deeper in his problems that are leading to tragedy. I liked the plot but this isn't nothing new.What is new is Kitano's way in filming this one.His camera is excellent and that part is very good but something about this movie as whole didn't fit perfectly to me.I don't know what that is but "Dolls" are better to me.I'm repeating myself so I'll quit know.Just one more thing;fans of Kitano won't be disappointed with this movie and also this movie is a great way to become a fan of this great film-maker.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Love, painting and poetry...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ivanbmm
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I don't gave 10 because there is some dose of violence in this movie to my taste. However, fading away this violence there is one of the most beautiful stories of love, painting and poetry that I've ever seen. I keep scanning movie forums, looking for these kind of movies. In my view, they are felt with more down-to-earth love stories, which I am finding rare to find now-a-days. The closer I can get from Hana-bi is Poetry by Chang-dong Lee. The reason I love both is the same. They are full of beautiful metaphors to give colour to such trivial stories, realistic characters like Nishi (Takeshi Kitano) and off course, poetic visuals. Hana-bi is worth watching for poetry lovers.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Explosions in the sky
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    lionelduffy
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/12/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is a perfectly judged movie. The peerless Takeshi Kitano moves almost wordlessly through this film conveying moments of genuine tenderness alongside vengeful violence. The mastery with which he alternates between the tender and the brutal without ever losing the pathos of his character Nishi's situation is stunning. As ever Kitano reaches for the simplistic as opposed to the bombastic - admirable for a movie peopled with comic book violent yakuza and characters shattered by the unfairness of life's mandatory dealing of the cards. Telling the story in violent flashback, Kitano balances his tale with a beautiful understated romanticism laced with comic tenderness. This is the film the deft editor, visionary director, multifaceted actor and comic genius was born to make.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Too slow and "deep" at times but mostly emotionally engaging and impacting
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bob the moo
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/7/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Nishi is a cop who is very good at his job but whose personal life is impacted with loss  a dead child and now a dying wife. When his partner is put in a wheelchair by a criminal and another officer is shot dead, Nishi finds himself plagued by guilt over his part in it all. Blaming himself Nishi tries to do the right thing by his partner Horibe and the widow of cop, while also trying to salvage some happiness in what remains of his time with his wife. I came back to Takeshi Kitano about the same time as I left the Movies You Should See podcast. I left it because I don't think it is as good as it could be and at times offers no real insight into a film other than describing "bits" however I give them a mention because they reminded me that I had only ever seen one or two of Kitano's films and that it had been some time since I had even seen those. So it was that after watching Brother, my rental site threw me Hana-Bi and I was looking forward to it due to the praise on this site and indeed the podcast itself. The expectation was not unjustified as Hana-Bi is a film of pain and beauty that is well worth seeing even if it is not the image of perfection that some would have you believe. That statement is bound to attract a low vote on IMDb but what can I tell you? That it was slow and quiet is not a problem for me but it is a feeling you get watching the film and it is not helped by some scenes feeling irrelevant within the context of the story. This is not a real killer but I felt that the slow pace needed support and seeing two minor characters argue about a fender bender (for example) saw my interest dip and the slow pace start to be felt. Otherwise though, the silence and pace suits the material and the style of the film. The violence is quite subdued (in regards what you actually see) because it occurs in the edit of the action  so the actual impact is mostly unseen. It doesn't matter though because the main thrust of the film is less the outward violence but the internal suffering of all the characters. The film does wear this aspect a little heavily at times and some will feel that some sequences are right on the edge of being pretentious and there is no point in denying that it does walk this line here and there. However for the majority it is a really well observed and emotionally engaging story built on the silent but emotive presence of Kitano as writer, director and star. As writer he has, it could be argued, left a lot to the actual making process itself since the script must have been a few pages. As director he sets the pace and I like the way his static style works within this story but it is his work as actor that always mystifies and impresses me. How he can convey so much while also appearing to be doing nothing at all I'm not sure but it somehow works and fits his style in other disciplines. He is well supported by Kishimoto, with whom he has genuine chemistry without betraying his character's nature. Osugi is not that great and it is with his character that I found the film close to being pretentious, not the actor's fault of course but I never felt for him as I did for Nishi. Hana-Bi is very slow and quiet and I can totally understand why some viewers will throw it in very early on. However sticking with it reveals a film that manages to be violent, introspective and emotionally engaging at the same time, all wrapped in the style of Kitano, who is creative across the board.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An overlooked masterpiece from the 90s
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    TimothyFarrell
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/12/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Hana-bi" may appear to be a standard cop action thriller from a simple plot description, but nothing could be further from the truth. Takashi Kitano's masterpiece is a slow moving meditation on human nature. Its violent at moments to be sure, but the "action" consists of short bursts of gun play that are stripped of any romanticism. They're all the more effective because of how sparingly they're employed. If anything, Kitano has much more in common with Yasujiro Ozu than John Woo. Kitano has fashioned a fascinating character study, one whose actual meaning is very abstract and difficult to decipher. The film's subtlety requires multiple viewings to fully appreciate. The film has a transcendental nature whose beauty is difficult to describe in words. Kitano is both a masterclass director and actor. He's best known as a stand-up comedian in Japan, which is odd because of the amount of seriousness he invests in both his positions. His lead performance is tough but has an amount of unexpected depth. Hes truly one of cinema's most charismatic performers, and he has this amazing presence despite the minimal dialog. His direction is slowly paced, but perfect. Not a single moment is wasted in this film. "Hana-bi" is one of the 90's most overlooked masterpieces, a decade known for its lack of depth or subtlety. (9/10)
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A man by the sea with or without his wife
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Christian
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/11/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Takeshi Kitano not only writes, acts in, directs and edits this meaningful fable, he also paints the artworks that are a strong element of the film. Kitano is supposedly known for his violence, but this movie has more to do about the repercussion of violence--and about life and death in general--than showing actual violent scenes. The violence is there, bursts of explosive violence, but it is short and strategically edited. Nishi, the protagonist, sees his partners die or get injured in the line of duty. One of them, Horibe, becomes wheel-chair-bound. His wife leaves him and he contemplates life and death staring at the horizon beyond the sea. He starts to paint to express himself and save himself from boredom and sorrow. Nishi, sick of his work leaves the police force to spend some time with his dying wife. The doctor just released her from the hospital and she does not have much time left... Kitano chooses to focus on the underlying emotions rather than dialogue as most of the scenes with his wife are silent. At first, this is unnerving, but slowly, as the movie progress, we understand that there is nothing left to stay. The score of the movie is its strongest point. Accomplished composer, Joe Hisaishi (who worked with Kitano on other projects as well as with Miyazaki's animated films) outdoes himself with poignant classical music that, unlike Nishi, speaks volume. He would win the Award of the Japanese Academy for this. Some good cinematography can also be observed at times. Kitano's paintings are interesting and vibrant. They add yet another level of complexity to this intriguing piece of film. All in all, a very well made film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    touching and incredible profound movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bruno-ferreira382
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/11/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Hana-bi is visual poetry, it says so much without using words.it is brilliantly directed because the movie delivers such an intense mood,the music by joe hisaishi also plays an important role in this moody film.But what it really makes the movie so profound and moving it's minimalist style, all the characters in the movie show very little emotion and yet takeshi kitano makes the film so touching by only showing the sea, the sky,the flowers, the paintings,along with joe hisaishi music.the true power of the film is that it doesn't say very much in terms of speaking,but it says a lot with its stunning images and music.I recommend this to all who want see an introspective,profound and thought provoking film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Great film though not for everybody
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    nexxit
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/10/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I only once happened to get my fingers on Kitanos movie "Brother", which got me into checking out his other movies. So i got Hana Bi since it had a lot of good reviews. I can actually understand people, that mostly watch action flicks, getting bored by this film, but for those more into poetic films, this is just the thing for you. While short on dialog, the movie is stronger on the body language of all the characters... sometimes there isn't any dialog for more than 6 minutes or so, where you just have to watch in order to understand what he is trying to tell us... For me it the movie was a bit depressing and sometimes hard to follow, but i still enjoyed it a lot. But as i said, this movie is not for everyone.... The movie is about a cop in Japan who leaves the police to spend more time with his wife who is dying of cancer, and if that was not enough to bare with, he also lost a kid and his partner gets shot and paralyzed on the job. Now he has to deal with all these tragedies at the same time... So if you want a comparison, if you liked movies like "21 grams" for example, you will love this movie!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A collision of beauty and destruction
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ackstasis
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/8/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Takeshi Kitano's 'Hana-Bi' is something of an oddity. True to his previous efforts as director, the film contains its fair share of shockingly-graphic violence, and yet at its heart lies a touching tale of love, loyalty and devotion. For the entire running time, Kitano (who, aside from directing, also wrote and starred in the film) treads a perilously fine line between the two thematic extremes; it is an intricate balancing act that, if attempted by a less-talented filmmaker, might very possibly have turned into a complete cinematic disaster. Nevertheless, the director manages to pinpoint this perfect centre of balance, and the clash of beauty and violence combines to create a jarring amalgamation of conflicting emotional responses. We, as the audience, as simultaneously repulsed and entranced; as a whole, 'Hana-bi' is one of the most beautiful film experiences of the last decade or so. The title of the film itself acknowledges these opposing visual styles. Whilst the Japanese word 'Hanabi' translates to 'Fireworks' (the title under which it was released in the United States), the addition of the hyphen to the title ('Hana-bi') emphasises two individual components of the word, which translate respectively into "Fire" and "Flower," the collision of destruction and beauty/renewal. Much of the film concerns a cop named Yoshitaka Nishi (Kitano), who is forced to retire after a shooting on the job leaves his partner, Horibe (Ren Osugi), paralysed, alone and confined to a wheelchair. All the while, Nishi is still coming to terms with the impending loss of his wife, Miyuki (Kayoko Kishimoto), who is slowly dying from leukemia. As any grieving husband might do in such a situation, Nishi decides to quietly rob a bank, and he then uses most of the proceeds to fund a final loving family holiday for his ailing partner. The scenes between Nishi and his wife are among the most touching I've ever witnessed. Miyuki has only two lines in the entire film, and so the couple spend most of their time in complete silence and quiet reflection, and yet you can truly sense the affection that they both have for each other. Their love is completely unspoken, and this makes it all the more touching when Miyuki does finally speak. Another touching character is Horibe, the loyal police force partner whose crippling injury leaves him alone and depressed. After attempting suicide, Horibe receives painting materials in the mail, and he commits his emotions to canvas, finally uncovering a reason for his continued existence (importantly, the artwork we see in the film was actually created by Kitano in 1994, after a near-fatal motorcycle accident). The film's phenomenally moving soundtrack was composed by renowned Japanese composer Joe Hisaishi, in his fourth collaboration with the director. There are very few negative criticisms that can be said of 'Hana-bi.' One possible item is that the film's unusual flashback structure made some plot-points difficult to follow, and I'm still unsure of which cop's lonesome widow Nishi was in the habit of visiting. However, that's the only critique that springs straight to mind. All in all, 'Hana-bi' is a gloriously assorted blend of violence, love and gentle humour, and a first viewing is not likely to be forgotten in a hurry.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    an existential ode to violence
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    badtothebono
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/8/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    So, it has come to this. In the top-rated comment on this flick, somebody says "Nishi is an honorable man". Really? This is a guy who mainly kills and maims people in the movie. He takes a short break to rob a bank. Honorable? How would you like your kids to go to school with the kids of someone who calls that honorable? Wait, there's more! The person also says "we can tell he's constantly thinking." How can we do that? Well, do you know that joke "How can you tell when a CEO/politician/lawyer is lying?" ... "His/her lips move." Well, Nishi's lips never move, so I guess that means he is thinking. Of course, this is existentialism to warm the hearts of the cult of victimization. Existentalism supposedly stresses that an individual take responsibility for the consequences of one's acts. Not Nishi. Borrow money from the yakuza. What, they want it back? Kill them. The cops find out. Kill yourself and your wife. Really honorable.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Just one name:Takeshi Kitano
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    johnny-08
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/6/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is fourth movie that I watched from Takeshi Kitano and I have to say that I'm a little disappointed with this one.I know that this is probably his most awarding movie but I don't think this is his best.Far from there.I find "Dolls" his greatest achievement.Don't get me wrong "Hana-bi" is very good movie but I expected something better.It's because Kitano put so high standards and sometimes it is hard to achieve them. The plot is about Yoshitaka Nishi who is cop and his wife is dying of Leukemia.His partner gets shot in the job and he ends up in a wheel chair.Nishi is trying to help him because he feels that somehow he's guilty for what happened.Soon Nishi leaves police so he can spend more time with his wife.All his life he did wright things and know he has to do all wrong things so he can survive.He soon sinks deeper and deeper in his problems that are leading to tragedy. I liked the plot but this isn't nothing new.What is new is Kitano's way in filming this one.His camera is excellent and that part is very good but something about this movie as whole didn't fit perfectly to me.I don't know what that is but "Dolls" are better to me.I'm repeating myself so I'll quit know.Just one more thing;fans of Kitano won't be disappointed with this movie and also this movie is a great way to become a fan of this great film-maker.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Love, painting and poetry...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ivanbmm
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I don't gave 10 because there is some dose of violence in this movie to my taste. However, fading away this violence there is one of the most beautiful stories of love, painting and poetry that I've ever seen. I keep scanning movie forums, looking for these kind of movies. In my view, they are felt with more down-to-earth love stories, which I am finding rare to find now-a-days. The closer I can get from Hana-bi is Poetry by Chang-dong Lee. The reason I love both is the same. They are full of beautiful metaphors to give colour to such trivial stories, realistic characters like Nishi (Takeshi Kitano) and off course, poetic visuals. Hana-bi is worth watching for poetry lovers.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Explosions in the sky
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    lionelduffy
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/12/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is a perfectly judged movie. The peerless Takeshi Kitano moves almost wordlessly through this film conveying moments of genuine tenderness alongside vengeful violence. The mastery with which he alternates between the tender and the brutal without ever losing the pathos of his character Nishi's situation is stunning. As ever Kitano reaches for the simplistic as opposed to the bombastic - admirable for a movie peopled with comic book violent yakuza and characters shattered by the unfairness of life's mandatory dealing of the cards. Telling the story in violent flashback, Kitano balances his tale with a beautiful understated romanticism laced with comic tenderness. This is the film the deft editor, visionary director, multifaceted actor and comic genius was born to make.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Too slow and "deep" at times but mostly emotionally engaging and impacting
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bob the moo
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/7/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Nishi is a cop who is very good at his job but whose personal life is impacted with loss  a dead child and now a dying wife. When his partner is put in a wheelchair by a criminal and another officer is shot dead, Nishi finds himself plagued by guilt over his part in it all. Blaming himself Nishi tries to do the right thing by his partner Horibe and the widow of cop, while also trying to salvage some happiness in what remains of his time with his wife. I came back to Takeshi Kitano about the same time as I left the Movies You Should See podcast. I left it because I don't think it is as good as it could be and at times offers no real insight into a film other than describing "bits" however I give them a mention because they reminded me that I had only ever seen one or two of Kitano's films and that it had been some time since I had even seen those. So it was that after watching Brother, my rental site threw me Hana-Bi and I was looking forward to it due to the praise on this site and indeed the podcast itself. The expectation was not unjustified as Hana-Bi is a film of pain and beauty that is well worth seeing even if it is not the image of perfection that some would have you believe. That statement is bound to attract a low vote on IMDb but what can I tell you? That it was slow and quiet is not a problem for me but it is a feeling you get watching the film and it is not helped by some scenes feeling irrelevant within the context of the story. This is not a real killer but I felt that the slow pace needed support and seeing two minor characters argue about a fender bender (for example) saw my interest dip and the slow pace start to be felt. Otherwise though, the silence and pace suits the material and the style of the film. The violence is quite subdued (in regards what you actually see) because it occurs in the edit of the action  so the actual impact is mostly unseen. It doesn't matter though because the main thrust of the film is less the outward violence but the internal suffering of all the characters. The film does wear this aspect a little heavily at times and some will feel that some sequences are right on the edge of being pretentious and there is no point in denying that it does walk this line here and there. However for the majority it is a really well observed and emotionally engaging story built on the silent but emotive presence of Kitano as writer, director and star. As writer he has, it could be argued, left a lot to the actual making process itself since the script must have been a few pages. As director he sets the pace and I like the way his static style works within this story but it is his work as actor that always mystifies and impresses me. How he can convey so much while also appearing to be doing nothing at all I'm not sure but it somehow works and fits his style in other disciplines. He is well supported by Kishimoto, with whom he has genuine chemistry without betraying his character's nature. Osugi is not that great and it is with his character that I found the film close to being pretentious, not the actor's fault of course but I never felt for him as I did for Nishi. Hana-Bi is very slow and quiet and I can totally understand why some viewers will throw it in very early on. However sticking with it reveals a film that manages to be violent, introspective and emotionally engaging at the same time, all wrapped in the style of Kitano, who is creative across the board.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An overlooked masterpiece from the 90s
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    TimothyFarrell
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/12/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Hana-bi" may appear to be a standard cop action thriller from a simple plot description, but nothing could be further from the truth. Takashi Kitano's masterpiece is a slow moving meditation on human nature. Its violent at moments to be sure, but the "action" consists of short bursts of gun play that are stripped of any romanticism. They're all the more effective because of how sparingly they're employed. If anything, Kitano has much more in common with Yasujiro Ozu than John Woo. Kitano has fashioned a fascinating character study, one whose actual meaning is very abstract and difficult to decipher. The film's subtlety requires multiple viewings to fully appreciate. The film has a transcendental nature whose beauty is difficult to describe in words. Kitano is both a masterclass director and actor. He's best known as a stand-up comedian in Japan, which is odd because of the amount of seriousness he invests in both his positions. His lead performance is tough but has an amount of unexpected depth. Hes truly one of cinema's most charismatic performers, and he has this amazing presence despite the minimal dialog. His direction is slowly paced, but perfect. Not a single moment is wasted in this film. "Hana-bi" is one of the 90's most overlooked masterpieces, a decade known for its lack of depth or subtlety. (9/10)
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A man by the sea with or without his wife
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Christian
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/11/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Takeshi Kitano not only writes, acts in, directs and edits this meaningful fable, he also paints the artworks that are a strong element of the film. Kitano is supposedly known for his violence, but this movie has more to do about the repercussion of violence--and about life and death in general--than showing actual violent scenes. The violence is there, bursts of explosive violence, but it is short and strategically edited. Nishi, the protagonist, sees his partners die or get injured in the line of duty. One of them, Horibe, becomes wheel-chair-bound. His wife leaves him and he contemplates life and death staring at the horizon beyond the sea. He starts to paint to express himself and save himself from boredom and sorrow. Nishi, sick of his work leaves the police force to spend some time with his dying wife. The doctor just released her from the hospital and she does not have much time left... Kitano chooses to focus on the underlying emotions rather than dialogue as most of the scenes with his wife are silent. At first, this is unnerving, but slowly, as the movie progress, we understand that there is nothing left to stay. The score of the movie is its strongest point. Accomplished composer, Joe Hisaishi (who worked with Kitano on other projects as well as with Miyazaki's animated films) outdoes himself with poignant classical music that, unlike Nishi, speaks volume. He would win the Award of the Japanese Academy for this. Some good cinematography can also be observed at times. Kitano's paintings are interesting and vibrant. They add yet another level of complexity to this intriguing piece of film. All in all, a very well made film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    touching and incredible profound movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bruno-ferreira382
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/11/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Hana-bi is visual poetry, it says so much without using words.it is brilliantly directed because the movie delivers such an intense mood,the music by joe hisaishi also plays an important role in this moody film.But what it really makes the movie so profound and moving it's minimalist style, all the characters in the movie show very little emotion and yet takeshi kitano makes the film so touching by only showing the sea, the sky,the flowers, the paintings,along with joe hisaishi music.the true power of the film is that it doesn't say very much in terms of speaking,but it says a lot with its stunning images and music.I recommend this to all who want see an introspective,profound and thought provoking film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Great film though not for everybody
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    nexxit
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/10/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I only once happened to get my fingers on Kitanos movie "Brother", which got me into checking out his other movies. So i got Hana Bi since it had a lot of good reviews. I can actually understand people, that mostly watch action flicks, getting bored by this film, but for those more into poetic films, this is just the thing for you. While short on dialog, the movie is stronger on the body language of all the characters... sometimes there isn't any dialog for more than 6 minutes or so, where you just have to watch in order to understand what he is trying to tell us... For me it the movie was a bit depressing and sometimes hard to follow, but i still enjoyed it a lot. But as i said, this movie is not for everyone.... The movie is about a cop in Japan who leaves the police to spend more time with his wife who is dying of cancer, and if that was not enough to bare with, he also lost a kid and his partner gets shot and paralyzed on the job. Now he has to deal with all these tragedies at the same time... So if you want a comparison, if you liked movies like "21 grams" for example, you will love this movie!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A collision of beauty and destruction
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ackstasis
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/8/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Takeshi Kitano's 'Hana-Bi' is something of an oddity. True to his previous efforts as director, the film contains its fair share of shockingly-graphic violence, and yet at its heart lies a touching tale of love, loyalty and devotion. For the entire running time, Kitano (who, aside from directing, also wrote and starred in the film) treads a perilously fine line between the two thematic extremes; it is an intricate balancing act that, if attempted by a less-talented filmmaker, might very possibly have turned into a complete cinematic disaster. Nevertheless, the director manages to pinpoint this perfect centre of balance, and the clash of beauty and violence combines to create a jarring amalgamation of conflicting emotional responses. We, as the audience, as simultaneously repulsed and entranced; as a whole, 'Hana-bi' is one of the most beautiful film experiences of the last decade or so. The title of the film itself acknowledges these opposing visual styles. Whilst the Japanese word 'Hanabi' translates to 'Fireworks' (the title under which it was released in the United States), the addition of the hyphen to the title ('Hana-bi') emphasises two individual components of the word, which translate respectively into "Fire" and "Flower," the collision of destruction and beauty/renewal. Much of the film concerns a cop named Yoshitaka Nishi (Kitano), who is forced to retire after a shooting on the job leaves his partner, Horibe (Ren Osugi), paralysed, alone and confined to a wheelchair. All the while, Nishi is still coming to terms with the impending loss of his wife, Miyuki (Kayoko Kishimoto), who is slowly dying from leukemia. As any grieving husband might do in such a situation, Nishi decides to quietly rob a bank, and he then uses most of the proceeds to fund a final loving family holiday for his ailing partner. The scenes between Nishi and his wife are among the most touching I've ever witnessed. Miyuki has only two lines in the entire film, and so the couple spend most of their time in complete silence and quiet reflection, and yet you can truly sense the affection that they both have for each other. Their love is completely unspoken, and this makes it all the more touching when Miyuki does finally speak. Another touching character is Horibe, the loyal police force partner whose crippling injury leaves him alone and depressed. After attempting suicide, Horibe receives painting materials in the mail, and he commits his emotions to canvas, finally uncovering a reason for his continued existence (importantly, the artwork we see in the film was actually created by Kitano in 1994, after a near-fatal motorcycle accident). The film's phenomenally moving soundtrack was composed by renowned Japanese composer Joe Hisaishi, in his fourth collaboration with the director. There are very few negative criticisms that can be said of 'Hana-bi.' One possible item is that the film's unusual flashback structure made some plot-points difficult to follow, and I'm still unsure of which cop's lonesome widow Nishi was in the habit of visiting. However, that's the only critique that springs straight to mind. All in all, 'Hana-bi' is a gloriously assorted blend of violence, love and gentle humour, and a first viewing is not likely to be forgotten in a hurry.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    an existential ode to violence
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    badtothebono
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/8/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    So, it has come to this. In the top-rated comment on this flick, somebody says "Nishi is an honorable man". Really? This is a guy who mainly kills and maims people in the movie. He takes a short break to rob a bank. Honorable? How would you like your kids to go to school with the kids of someone who calls that honorable? Wait, there's more! The person also says "we can tell he's constantly thinking." How can we do that? Well, do you know that joke "How can you tell when a CEO/politician/lawyer is lying?" ... "His/her lips move." Well, Nishi's lips never move, so I guess that means he is thinking. Of course, this is existentialism to warm the hearts of the cult of victimization. Existentalism supposedly stresses that an individual take responsibility for the consequences of one's acts. Not Nishi. Borrow money from the yakuza. What, they want it back? Kill them. The cops find out. Kill yourself and your wife. Really honorable.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Just one name:Takeshi Kitano
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    johnny-08
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/6/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is fourth movie that I watched from Takeshi Kitano and I have to say that I'm a little disappointed with this one.I know that this is probably his most awarding movie but I don't think this is his best.Far from there.I find "Dolls" his greatest achievement.Don't get me wrong "Hana-bi" is very good movie but I expected something better.It's because Kitano put so high standards and sometimes it is hard to achieve them. The plot is about Yoshitaka Nishi who is cop and his wife is dying of Leukemia.His partner gets shot in the job and he ends up in a wheel chair.Nishi is trying to help him because he feels that somehow he's guilty for what happened.Soon Nishi leaves police so he can spend more time with his wife.All his life he did wright things and know he has to do all wrong things so he can survive.He soon sinks deeper and deeper in his problems that are leading to tragedy. I liked the plot but this isn't nothing new.What is new is Kitano's way in filming this one.His camera is excellent and that part is very good but something about this movie as whole didn't fit perfectly to me.I don't know what that is but "Dolls" are better to me.I'm repeating myself so I'll quit know.Just one more thing;fans of Kitano won't be disappointed with this movie and also this movie is a great way to become a fan of this great film-maker.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Love, painting and poetry...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ivanbmm
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I don't gave 10 because there is some dose of violence in this movie to my taste. However, fading away this violence there is one of the most beautiful stories of love, painting and poetry that I've ever seen. I keep scanning movie forums, looking for these kind of movies. In my view, they are felt with more down-to-earth love stories, which I am finding rare to find now-a-days. The closer I can get from Hana-bi is Poetry by Chang-dong Lee. The reason I love both is the same. They are full of beautiful metaphors to give colour to such trivial stories, realistic characters like Nishi (Takeshi Kitano) and off course, poetic visuals. Hana-bi is worth watching for poetry lovers.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Explosions in the sky
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    lionelduffy
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/12/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is a perfectly judged movie. The peerless Takeshi Kitano moves almost wordlessly through this film conveying moments of genuine tenderness alongside vengeful violence. The mastery with which he alternates between the tender and the brutal without ever losing the pathos of his character Nishi's situation is stunning. As ever Kitano reaches for the simplistic as opposed to the bombastic - admirable for a movie peopled with comic book violent yakuza and characters shattered by the unfairness of life's mandatory dealing of the cards. Telling the story in violent flashback, Kitano balances his tale with a beautiful understated romanticism laced with comic tenderness. This is the film the deft editor, visionary director, multifaceted actor and comic genius was born to make.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Too slow and "deep" at times but mostly emotionally engaging and impacting
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bob the moo
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/7/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Nishi is a cop who is very good at his job but whose personal life is impacted with loss  a dead child and now a dying wife. When his partner is put in a wheelchair by a criminal and another officer is shot dead, Nishi finds himself plagued by guilt over his part in it all. Blaming himself Nishi tries to do the right thing by his partner Horibe and the widow of cop, while also trying to salvage some happiness in what remains of his time with his wife. I came back to Takeshi Kitano about the same time as I left the Movies You Should See podcast. I left it because I don't think it is as good as it could be and at times offers no real insight into a film other than describing "bits" however I give them a mention because they reminded me that I had only ever seen one or two of Kitano's films and that it had been some time since I had even seen those. So it was that after watching Brother, my rental site threw me Hana-Bi and I was looking forward to it due to the praise on this site and indeed the podcast itself. The expectation was not unjustified as Hana-Bi is a film of pain and beauty that is well worth seeing even if it is not the image of perfection that some would have you believe. That statement is bound to attract a low vote on IMDb but what can I tell you? That it was slow and quiet is not a problem for me but it is a feeling you get watching the film and it is not helped by some scenes feeling irrelevant within the context of the story. This is not a real killer but I felt that the slow pace needed support and seeing two minor characters argue about a fender bender (for example) saw my interest dip and the slow pace start to be felt. Otherwise though, the silence and pace suits the material and the style of the film. The violence is quite subdued (in regards what you actually see) because it occurs in the edit of the action  so the actual impact is mostly unseen. It doesn't matter though because the main thrust of the film is less the outward violence but the internal suffering of all the characters. The film does wear this aspect a little heavily at times and some will feel that some sequences are right on the edge of being pretentious and there is no point in denying that it does walk this line here and there. However for the majority it is a really well observed and emotionally engaging story built on the silent but emotive presence of Kitano as writer, director and star. As writer he has, it could be argued, left a lot to the actual making process itself since the script must have been a few pages. As director he sets the pace and I like the way his static style works within this story but it is his work as actor that always mystifies and impresses me. How he can convey so much while also appearing to be doing nothing at all I'm not sure but it somehow works and fits his style in other disciplines. He is well supported by Kishimoto, with whom he has genuine chemistry without betraying his character's nature. Osugi is not that great and it is with his character that I found the film close to being pretentious, not the actor's fault of course but I never felt for him as I did for Nishi. Hana-Bi is very slow and quiet and I can totally understand why some viewers will throw it in very early on. However sticking with it reveals a film that manages to be violent, introspective and emotionally engaging at the same time, all wrapped in the style of Kitano, who is creative across the board.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An overlooked masterpiece from the 90s
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    TimothyFarrell
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/12/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Hana-bi" may appear to be a standard cop action thriller from a simple plot description, but nothing could be further from the truth. Takashi Kitano's masterpiece is a slow moving meditation on human nature. Its violent at moments to be sure, but the "action" consists of short bursts of gun play that are stripped of any romanticism. They're all the more effective because of how sparingly they're employed. If anything, Kitano has much more in common with Yasujiro Ozu than John Woo. Kitano has fashioned a fascinating character study, one whose actual meaning is very abstract and difficult to decipher. The film's subtlety requires multiple viewings to fully appreciate. The film has a transcendental nature whose beauty is difficult to describe in words. Kitano is both a masterclass director and actor. He's best known as a stand-up comedian in Japan, which is odd because of the amount of seriousness he invests in both his positions. His lead performance is tough but has an amount of unexpected depth. Hes truly one of cinema's most charismatic performers, and he has this amazing presence despite the minimal dialog. His direction is slowly paced, but perfect. Not a single moment is wasted in this film. "Hana-bi" is one of the 90's most overlooked masterpieces, a decade known for its lack of depth or subtlety. (9/10)
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A man by the sea with or without his wife
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Christian
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/11/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Takeshi Kitano not only writes, acts in, directs and edits this meaningful fable, he also paints the artworks that are a strong element of the film. Kitano is supposedly known for his violence, but this movie has more to do about the repercussion of violence--and about life and death in general--than showing actual violent scenes. The violence is there, bursts of explosive violence, but it is short and strategically edited. Nishi, the protagonist, sees his partners die or get injured in the line of duty. One of them, Horibe, becomes wheel-chair-bound. His wife leaves him and he contemplates life and death staring at the horizon beyond the sea. He starts to paint to express himself and save himself from boredom and sorrow. Nishi, sick of his work leaves the police force to spend some time with his dying wife. The doctor just released her from the hospital and she does not have much time left... Kitano chooses to focus on the underlying emotions rather than dialogue as most of the scenes with his wife are silent. At first, this is unnerving, but slowly, as the movie progress, we understand that there is nothing left to stay. The score of the movie is its strongest point. Accomplished composer, Joe Hisaishi (who worked with Kitano on other projects as well as with Miyazaki's animated films) outdoes himself with poignant classical music that, unlike Nishi, speaks volume. He would win the Award of the Japanese Academy for this. Some good cinematography can also be observed at times. Kitano's paintings are interesting and vibrant. They add yet another level of complexity to this intriguing piece of film. All in all, a very well made film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    touching and incredible profound movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bruno-ferreira382
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/11/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Hana-bi is visual poetry, it says so much without using words.it is brilliantly directed because the movie delivers such an intense mood,the music by joe hisaishi also plays an important role in this moody film.But what it really makes the movie so profound and moving it's minimalist style, all the characters in the movie show very little emotion and yet takeshi kitano makes the film so touching by only showing the sea, the sky,the flowers, the paintings,along with joe hisaishi music.the true power of the film is that it doesn't say very much in terms of speaking,but it says a lot with its stunning images and music.I recommend this to all who want see an introspective,profound and thought provoking film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Great film though not for everybody
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    nexxit
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/10/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I only once happened to get my fingers on Kitanos movie "Brother", which got me into checking out his other movies. So i got Hana Bi since it had a lot of good reviews. I can actually understand people, that mostly watch action flicks, getting bored by this film, but for those more into poetic films, this is just the thing for you. While short on dialog, the movie is stronger on the body language of all the characters... sometimes there isn't any dialog for more than 6 minutes or so, where you just have to watch in order to understand what he is trying to tell us... For me it the movie was a bit depressing and sometimes hard to follow, but i still enjoyed it a lot. But as i said, this movie is not for everyone.... The movie is about a cop in Japan who leaves the police to spend more time with his wife who is dying of cancer, and if that was not enough to bare with, he also lost a kid and his partner gets shot and paralyzed on the job. Now he has to deal with all these tragedies at the same time... So if you want a comparison, if you liked movies like "21 grams" for example, you will love this movie!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A collision of beauty and destruction
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ackstasis
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/8/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Takeshi Kitano's 'Hana-Bi' is something of an oddity. True to his previous efforts as director, the film contains its fair share of shockingly-graphic violence, and yet at its heart lies a touching tale of love, loyalty and devotion. For the entire running time, Kitano (who, aside from directing, also wrote and starred in the film) treads a perilously fine line between the two thematic extremes; it is an intricate balancing act that, if attempted by a less-talented filmmaker, might very possibly have turned into a complete cinematic disaster. Nevertheless, the director manages to pinpoint this perfect centre of balance, and the clash of beauty and violence combines to create a jarring amalgamation of conflicting emotional responses. We, as the audience, as simultaneously repulsed and entranced; as a whole, 'Hana-bi' is one of the most beautiful film experiences of the last decade or so. The title of the film itself acknowledges these opposing visual styles. Whilst the Japanese word 'Hanabi' translates to 'Fireworks' (the title under which it was released in the United States), the addition of the hyphen to the title ('Hana-bi') emphasises two individual components of the word, which translate respectively into "Fire" and "Flower," the collision of destruction and beauty/renewal. Much of the film concerns a cop named Yoshitaka Nishi (Kitano), who is forced to retire after a shooting on the job leaves his partner, Horibe (Ren Osugi), paralysed, alone and confined to a wheelchair. All the while, Nishi is still coming to terms with the impending loss of his wife, Miyuki (Kayoko Kishimoto), who is slowly dying from leukemia. As any grieving husband might do in such a situation, Nishi decides to quietly rob a bank, and he then uses most of the proceeds to fund a final loving family holiday for his ailing partner. The scenes between Nishi and his wife are among the most touching I've ever witnessed. Miyuki has only two lines in the entire film, and so the couple spend most of their time in complete silence and quiet reflection, and yet you can truly sense the affection that they both have for each other. Their love is completely unspoken, and this makes it all the more touching when Miyuki does finally speak. Another touching character is Horibe, the loyal police force partner whose crippling injury leaves him alone and depressed. After attempting suicide, Horibe receives painting materials in the mail, and he commits his emotions to canvas, finally uncovering a reason for his continued existence (importantly, the artwork we see in the film was actually created by Kitano in 1994, after a near-fatal motorcycle accident). The film's phenomenally moving soundtrack was composed by renowned Japanese composer Joe Hisaishi, in his fourth collaboration with the director. There are very few negative criticisms that can be said of 'Hana-bi.' One possible item is that the film's unusual flashback structure made some plot-points difficult to follow, and I'm still unsure of which cop's lonesome widow Nishi was in the habit of visiting. However, that's the only critique that springs straight to mind. All in all, 'Hana-bi' is a gloriously assorted blend of violence, love and gentle humour, and a first viewing is not likely to be forgotten in a hurry.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    an existential ode to violence
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    badtothebono
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/8/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    So, it has come to this. In the top-rated comment on this flick, somebody says "Nishi is an honorable man". Really? This is a guy who mainly kills and maims people in the movie. He takes a short break to rob a bank. Honorable? How would you like your kids to go to school with the kids of someone who calls that honorable? Wait, there's more! The person also says "we can tell he's constantly thinking." How can we do that? Well, do you know that joke "How can you tell when a CEO/politician/lawyer is lying?" ... "His/her lips move." Well, Nishi's lips never move, so I guess that means he is thinking. Of course, this is existentialism to warm the hearts of the cult of victimization. Existentalism supposedly stresses that an individual take responsibility for the consequences of one's acts. Not Nishi. Borrow money from the yakuza. What, they want it back? Kill them. The cops find out. Kill yourself and your wife. Really honorable.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Just one name:Takeshi Kitano
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    johnny-08
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/6/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is fourth movie that I watched from Takeshi Kitano and I have to say that I'm a little disappointed with this one.I know that this is probably his most awarding movie but I don't think this is his best.Far from there.I find "Dolls" his greatest achievement.Don't get me wrong "Hana-bi" is very good movie but I expected something better.It's because Kitano put so high standards and sometimes it is hard to achieve them. The plot is about Yoshitaka Nishi who is cop and his wife is dying of Leukemia.His partner gets shot in the job and he ends up in a wheel chair.Nishi is trying to help him because he feels that somehow he's guilty for what happened.Soon Nishi leaves police so he can spend more time with his wife.All his life he did wright things and know he has to do all wrong things so he can survive.He soon sinks deeper and deeper in his problems that are leading to tragedy. I liked the plot but this isn't nothing new.What is new is Kitano's way in filming this one.His camera is excellent and that part is very good but something about this movie as whole didn't fit perfectly to me.I don't know what that is but "Dolls" are better to me.I'm repeating myself so I'll quit know.Just one more thing;fans of Kitano won't be disappointed with this movie and also this movie is a great way to become a fan of this great film-maker.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Love, painting and poetry...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ivanbmm
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I don't gave 10 because there is some dose of violence in this movie to my taste. However, fading away this violence there is one of the most beautiful stories of love, painting and poetry that I've ever seen. I keep scanning movie forums, looking for these kind of movies. In my view, they are felt with more down-to-earth love stories, which I am finding rare to find now-a-days. The closer I can get from Hana-bi is Poetry by Chang-dong Lee. The reason I love both is the same. They are full of beautiful metaphors to give colour to such trivial stories, realistic characters like Nishi (Takeshi Kitano) and off course, poetic visuals. Hana-bi is worth watching for poetry lovers.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Explosions in the sky
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    lionelduffy
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/12/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is a perfectly judged movie. The peerless Takeshi Kitano moves almost wordlessly through this film conveying moments of genuine tenderness alongside vengeful violence. The mastery with which he alternates between the tender and the brutal without ever losing the pathos of his character Nishi's situation is stunning. As ever Kitano reaches for the simplistic as opposed to the bombastic - admirable for a movie peopled with comic book violent yakuza and characters shattered by the unfairness of life's mandatory dealing of the cards. Telling the story in violent flashback, Kitano balances his tale with a beautiful understated romanticism laced with comic tenderness. This is the film the deft editor, visionary director, multifaceted actor and comic genius was born to make.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Too slow and "deep" at times but mostly emotionally engaging and impacting
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bob the moo
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/7/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Nishi is a cop who is very good at his job but whose personal life is impacted with loss  a dead child and now a dying wife. When his partner is put in a wheelchair by a criminal and another officer is shot dead, Nishi finds himself plagued by guilt over his part in it all. Blaming himself Nishi tries to do the right thing by his partner Horibe and the widow of cop, while also trying to salvage some happiness in what remains of his time with his wife. I came back to Takeshi Kitano about the same time as I left the Movies You Should See podcast. I left it because I don't think it is as good as it could be and at times offers no real insight into a film other than describing "bits" however I give them a mention because they reminded me that I had only ever seen one or two of Kitano's films and that it had been some time since I had even seen those. So it was that after watching Brother, my rental site threw me Hana-Bi and I was looking forward to it due to the praise on this site and indeed the podcast itself. The expectation was not unjustified as Hana-Bi is a film of pain and beauty that is well worth seeing even if it is not the image of perfection that some would have you believe. That statement is bound to attract a low vote on IMDb but what can I tell you? That it was slow and quiet is not a problem for me but it is a feeling you get watching the film and it is not helped by some scenes feeling irrelevant within the context of the story. This is not a real killer but I felt that the slow pace needed support and seeing two minor characters argue about a fender bender (for example) saw my interest dip and the slow pace start to be felt. Otherwise though, the silence and pace suits the material and the style of the film. The violence is quite subdued (in regards what you actually see) because it occurs in the edit of the action  so the actual impact is mostly unseen. It doesn't matter though because the main thrust of the film is less the outward violence but the internal suffering of all the characters. The film does wear this aspect a little heavily at times and some will feel that some sequences are right on the edge of being pretentious and there is no point in denying that it does walk this line here and there. However for the majority it is a really well observed and emotionally engaging story built on the silent but emotive presence of Kitano as writer, director and star. As writer he has, it could be argued, left a lot to the actual making process itself since the script must have been a few pages. As director he sets the pace and I like the way his static style works within this story but it is his work as actor that always mystifies and impresses me. How he can convey so much while also appearing to be doing nothing at all I'm not sure but it somehow works and fits his style in other disciplines. He is well supported by Kishimoto, with whom he has genuine chemistry without betraying his character's nature. Osugi is not that great and it is with his character that I found the film close to being pretentious, not the actor's fault of course but I never felt for him as I did for Nishi. Hana-Bi is very slow and quiet and I can totally understand why some viewers will throw it in very early on. However sticking with it reveals a film that manages to be violent, introspective and emotionally engaging at the same time, all wrapped in the style of Kitano, who is creative across the board.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An overlooked masterpiece from the 90s
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    TimothyFarrell
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/12/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Hana-bi" may appear to be a standard cop action thriller from a simple plot description, but nothing could be further from the truth. Takashi Kitano's masterpiece is a slow moving meditation on human nature. Its violent at moments to be sure, but the "action" consists of short bursts of gun play that are stripped of any romanticism. They're all the more effective because of how sparingly they're employed. If anything, Kitano has much more in common with Yasujiro Ozu than John Woo. Kitano has fashioned a fascinating character study, one whose actual meaning is very abstract and difficult to decipher. The film's subtlety requires multiple viewings to fully appreciate. The film has a transcendental nature whose beauty is difficult to describe in words. Kitano is both a masterclass director and actor. He's best known as a stand-up comedian in Japan, which is odd because of the amount of seriousness he invests in both his positions. His lead performance is tough but has an amount of unexpected depth. Hes truly one of cinema's most charismatic performers, and he has this amazing presence despite the minimal dialog. His direction is slowly paced, but perfect. Not a single moment is wasted in this film. "Hana-bi" is one of the 90's most overlooked masterpieces, a decade known for its lack of depth or subtlety. (9/10)
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A man by the sea with or without his wife
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Christian
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/11/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Takeshi Kitano not only writes, acts in, directs and edits this meaningful fable, he also paints the artworks that are a strong element of the film. Kitano is supposedly known for his violence, but this movie has more to do about the repercussion of violence--and about life and death in general--than showing actual violent scenes. The violence is there, bursts of explosive violence, but it is short and strategically edited. Nishi, the protagonist, sees his partners die or get injured in the line of duty. One of them, Horibe, becomes wheel-chair-bound. His wife leaves him and he contemplates life and death staring at the horizon beyond the sea. He starts to paint to express himself and save himself from boredom and sorrow. Nishi, sick of his work leaves the police force to spend some time with his dying wife. The doctor just released her from the hospital and she does not have much time left... Kitano chooses to focus on the underlying emotions rather than dialogue as most of the scenes with his wife are silent. At first, this is unnerving, but slowly, as the movie progress, we understand that there is nothing left to stay. The score of the movie is its strongest point. Accomplished composer, Joe Hisaishi (who worked with Kitano on other projects as well as with Miyazaki's animated films) outdoes himself with poignant classical music that, unlike Nishi, speaks volume. He would win the Award of the Japanese Academy for this. Some good cinematography can also be observed at times. Kitano's paintings are interesting and vibrant. They add yet another level of complexity to this intriguing piece of film. All in all, a very well made film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    touching and incredible profound movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bruno-ferreira382
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/11/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Hana-bi is visual poetry, it says so much without using words.it is brilliantly directed because the movie delivers such an intense mood,the music by joe hisaishi also plays an important role in this moody film.But what it really makes the movie so profound and moving it's minimalist style, all the characters in the movie show very little emotion and yet takeshi kitano makes the film so touching by only showing the sea, the sky,the flowers, the paintings,along with joe hisaishi music.the true power of the film is that it doesn't say very much in terms of speaking,but it says a lot with its stunning images and music.I recommend this to all who want see an introspective,profound and thought provoking film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Great film though not for everybody
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    nexxit
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/10/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I only once happened to get my fingers on Kitanos movie "Brother", which got me into checking out his other movies. So i got Hana Bi since it had a lot of good reviews. I can actually understand people, that mostly watch action flicks, getting bored by this film, but for those more into poetic films, this is just the thing for you. While short on dialog, the movie is stronger on the body language of all the characters... sometimes there isn't any dialog for more than 6 minutes or so, where you just have to watch in order to understand what he is trying to tell us... For me it the movie was a bit depressing and sometimes hard to follow, but i still enjoyed it a lot. But as i said, this movie is not for everyone.... The movie is about a cop in Japan who leaves the police to spend more time with his wife who is dying of cancer, and if that was not enough to bare with, he also lost a kid and his partner gets shot and paralyzed on the job. Now he has to deal with all these tragedies at the same time... So if you want a comparison, if you liked movies like "21 grams" for example, you will love this movie!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A collision of beauty and destruction
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ackstasis
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/8/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Takeshi Kitano's 'Hana-Bi' is something of an oddity. True to his previous efforts as director, the film contains its fair share of shockingly-graphic violence, and yet at its heart lies a touching tale of love, loyalty and devotion. For the entire running time, Kitano (who, aside from directing, also wrote and starred in the film) treads a perilously fine line between the two thematic extremes; it is an intricate balancing act that, if attempted by a less-talented filmmaker, might very possibly have turned into a complete cinematic disaster. Nevertheless, the director manages to pinpoint this perfect centre of balance, and the clash of beauty and violence combines to create a jarring amalgamation of conflicting emotional responses. We, as the audience, as simultaneously repulsed and entranced; as a whole, 'Hana-bi' is one of the most beautiful film experiences of the last decade or so. The title of the film itself acknowledges these opposing visual styles. Whilst the Japanese word 'Hanabi' translates to 'Fireworks' (the title under which it was released in the United States), the addition of the hyphen to the title ('Hana-bi') emphasises two individual components of the word, which translate respectively into "Fire" and "Flower," the collision of destruction and beauty/renewal. Much of the film concerns a cop named Yoshitaka Nishi (Kitano), who is forced to retire after a shooting on the job leaves his partner, Horibe (Ren Osugi), paralysed, alone and confined to a wheelchair. All the while, Nishi is still coming to terms with the impending loss of his wife, Miyuki (Kayoko Kishimoto), who is slowly dying from leukemia. As any grieving husband might do in such a situation, Nishi decides to quietly rob a bank, and he then uses most of the proceeds to fund a final loving family holiday for his ailing partner. The scenes between Nishi and his wife are among the most touching I've ever witnessed. Miyuki has only two lines in the entire film, and so the couple spend most of their time in complete silence and quiet reflection, and yet you can truly sense the affection that they both have for each other. Their love is completely unspoken, and this makes it all the more touching when Miyuki does finally speak. Another touching character is Horibe, the loyal police force partner whose crippling injury leaves him alone and depressed. After attempting suicide, Horibe receives painting materials in the mail, and he commits his emotions to canvas, finally uncovering a reason for his continued existence (importantly, the artwork we see in the film was actually created by Kitano in 1994, after a near-fatal motorcycle accident). The film's phenomenally moving soundtrack was composed by renowned Japanese composer Joe Hisaishi, in his fourth collaboration with the director. There are very few negative criticisms that can be said of 'Hana-bi.' One possible item is that the film's unusual flashback structure made some plot-points difficult to follow, and I'm still unsure of which cop's lonesome widow Nishi was in the habit of visiting. However, that's the only critique that springs straight to mind. All in all, 'Hana-bi' is a gloriously assorted blend of violence, love and gentle humour, and a first viewing is not likely to be forgotten in a hurry.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    an existential ode to violence
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    badtothebono
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/8/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    So, it has come to this. In the top-rated comment on this flick, somebody says "Nishi is an honorable man". Really? This is a guy who mainly kills and maims people in the movie. He takes a short break to rob a bank. Honorable? How would you like your kids to go to school with the kids of someone who calls that honorable? Wait, there's more! The person also says "we can tell he's constantly thinking." How can we do that? Well, do you know that joke "How can you tell when a CEO/politician/lawyer is lying?" ... "His/her lips move." Well, Nishi's lips never move, so I guess that means he is thinking. Of course, this is existentialism to warm the hearts of the cult of victimization. Existentalism supposedly stresses that an individual take responsibility for the consequences of one's acts. Not Nishi. Borrow money from the yakuza. What, they want it back? Kill them. The cops find out. Kill yourself and your wife. Really honorable.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Just one name:Takeshi Kitano
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    johnny-08
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/6/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is fourth movie that I watched from Takeshi Kitano and I have to say that I'm a little disappointed with this one.I know that this is probably his most awarding movie but I don't think this is his best.Far from there.I find "Dolls" his greatest achievement.Don't get me wrong "Hana-bi" is very good movie but I expected something better.It's because Kitano put so high standards and sometimes it is hard to achieve them. The plot is about Yoshitaka Nishi who is cop and his wife is dying of Leukemia.His partner gets shot in the job and he ends up in a wheel chair.Nishi is trying to help him because he feels that somehow he's guilty for what happened.Soon Nishi leaves police so he can spend more time with his wife.All his life he did wright things and know he has to do all wrong things so he can survive.He soon sinks deeper and deeper in his problems that are leading to tragedy. I liked the plot but this isn't nothing new.What is new is Kitano's way in filming this one.His camera is excellent and that part is very good but something about this movie as whole didn't fit perfectly to me.I don't know what that is but "Dolls" are better to me.I'm repeating myself so I'll quit know.Just one more thing;fans of Kitano won't be disappointed with this movie and also this movie is a great way to become a fan of this great film-maker.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Love, painting and poetry...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ivanbmm
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I don't gave 10 because there is some dose of violence in this movie to my taste. However, fading away this violence there is one of the most beautiful stories of love, painting and poetry that I've ever seen. I keep scanning movie forums, looking for these kind of movies. In my view, they are felt with more down-to-earth love stories, which I am finding rare to find now-a-days. The closer I can get from Hana-bi is Poetry by Chang-dong Lee. The reason I love both is the same. They are full of beautiful metaphors to give colour to such trivial stories, realistic characters like Nishi (Takeshi Kitano) and off course, poetic visuals. Hana-bi is worth watching for poetry lovers.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Explosions in the sky
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    lionelduffy
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/12/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is a perfectly judged movie. The peerless Takeshi Kitano moves almost wordlessly through this film conveying moments of genuine tenderness alongside vengeful violence. The mastery with which he alternates between the tender and the brutal without ever losing the pathos of his character Nishi's situation is stunning. As ever Kitano reaches for the simplistic as opposed to the bombastic - admirable for a movie peopled with comic book violent yakuza and characters shattered by the unfairness of life's mandatory dealing of the cards. Telling the story in violent flashback, Kitano balances his tale with a beautiful understated romanticism laced with comic tenderness. This is the film the deft editor, visionary director, multifaceted actor and comic genius was born to make.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Too slow and "deep" at times but mostly emotionally engaging and impacting
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bob the moo
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/7/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Nishi is a cop who is very good at his job but whose personal life is impacted with loss  a dead child and now a dying wife. When his partner is put in a wheelchair by a criminal and another officer is shot dead, Nishi finds himself plagued by guilt over his part in it all. Blaming himself Nishi tries to do the right thing by his partner Horibe and the widow of cop, while also trying to salvage some happiness in what remains of his time with his wife. I came back to Takeshi Kitano about the same time as I left the Movies You Should See podcast. I left it because I don't think it is as good as it could be and at times offers no real insight into a film other than describing "bits" however I give them a mention because they reminded me that I had only ever seen one or two of Kitano's films and that it had been some time since I had even seen those. So it was that after watching Brother, my rental site threw me Hana-Bi and I was looking forward to it due to the praise on this site and indeed the podcast itself. The expectation was not unjustified as Hana-Bi is a film of pain and beauty that is well worth seeing even if it is not the image of perfection that some would have you believe. That statement is bound to attract a low vote on IMDb but what can I tell you? That it was slow and quiet is not a problem for me but it is a feeling you get watching the film and it is not helped by some scenes feeling irrelevant within the context of the story. This is not a real killer but I felt that the slow pace needed support and seeing two minor characters argue about a fender bender (for example) saw my interest dip and the slow pace start to be felt. Otherwise though, the silence and pace suits the material and the style of the film. The violence is quite subdued (in regards what you actually see) because it occurs in the edit of the action  so the actual impact is mostly unseen. It doesn't matter though because the main thrust of the film is less the outward violence but the internal suffering of all the characters. The film does wear this aspect a little heavily at times and some will feel that some sequences are right on the edge of being pretentious and there is no point in denying that it does walk this line here and there. However for the majority it is a really well observed and emotionally engaging story built on the silent but emotive presence of Kitano as writer, director and star. As writer he has, it could be argued, left a lot to the actual making process itself since the script must have been a few pages. As director he sets the pace and I like the way his static style works within this story but it is his work as actor that always mystifies and impresses me. How he can convey so much while also appearing to be doing nothing at all I'm not sure but it somehow works and fits his style in other disciplines. He is well supported by Kishimoto, with whom he has genuine chemistry without betraying his character's nature. Osugi is not that great and it is with his character that I found the film close to being pretentious, not the actor's fault of course but I never felt for him as I did for Nishi. Hana-Bi is very slow and quiet and I can totally understand why some viewers will throw it in very early on. However sticking with it reveals a film that manages to be violent, introspective and emotionally engaging at the same time, all wrapped in the style of Kitano, who is creative across the board.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An overlooked masterpiece from the 90s
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    TimothyFarrell
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/12/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Hana-bi" may appear to be a standard cop action thriller from a simple plot description, but nothing could be further from the truth. Takashi Kitano's masterpiece is a slow moving meditation on human nature. Its violent at moments to be sure, but the "action" consists of short bursts of gun play that are stripped of any romanticism. They're all the more effective because of how sparingly they're employed. If anything, Kitano has much more in common with Yasujiro Ozu than John Woo. Kitano has fashioned a fascinating character study, one whose actual meaning is very abstract and difficult to decipher. The film's subtlety requires multiple viewings to fully appreciate. The film has a transcendental nature whose beauty is difficult to describe in words. Kitano is both a masterclass director and actor. He's best known as a stand-up comedian in Japan, which is odd because of the amount of seriousness he invests in both his positions. His lead performance is tough but has an amount of unexpected depth. Hes truly one of cinema's most charismatic performers, and he has this amazing presence despite the minimal dialog. His direction is slowly paced, but perfect. Not a single moment is wasted in this film. "Hana-bi" is one of the 90's most overlooked masterpieces, a decade known for its lack of depth or subtlety. (9/10)
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A man by the sea with or without his wife
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Christian
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/11/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Takeshi Kitano not only writes, acts in, directs and edits this meaningful fable, he also paints the artworks that are a strong element of the film. Kitano is supposedly known for his violence, but this movie has more to do about the repercussion of violence--and about life and death in general--than showing actual violent scenes. The violence is there, bursts of explosive violence, but it is short and strategically edited. Nishi, the protagonist, sees his partners die or get injured in the line of duty. One of them, Horibe, becomes wheel-chair-bound. His wife leaves him and he contemplates life and death staring at the horizon beyond the sea. He starts to paint to express himself and save himself from boredom and sorrow. Nishi, sick of his work leaves the police force to spend some time with his dying wife. The doctor just released her from the hospital and she does not have much time left... Kitano chooses to focus on the underlying emotions rather than dialogue as most of the scenes with his wife are silent. At first, this is unnerving, but slowly, as the movie progress, we understand that there is nothing left to stay. The score of the movie is its strongest point. Accomplished composer, Joe Hisaishi (who worked with Kitano on other projects as well as with Miyazaki's animated films) outdoes himself with poignant classical music that, unlike Nishi, speaks volume. He would win the Award of the Japanese Academy for this. Some good cinematography can also be observed at times. Kitano's paintings are interesting and vibrant. They add yet another level of complexity to this intriguing piece of film. All in all, a very well made film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    touching and incredible profound movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bruno-ferreira382
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/11/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Hana-bi is visual poetry, it says so much without using words.it is brilliantly directed because the movie delivers such an intense mood,the music by joe hisaishi also plays an important role in this moody film.But what it really makes the movie so profound and moving it's minimalist style, all the characters in the movie show very little emotion and yet takeshi kitano makes the film so touching by only showing the sea, the sky,the flowers, the paintings,along with joe hisaishi music.the true power of the film is that it doesn't say very much in terms of speaking,but it says a lot with its stunning images and music.I recommend this to all who want see an introspective,profound and thought provoking film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Great film though not for everybody
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    nexxit
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/10/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I only once happened to get my fingers on Kitanos movie "Brother", which got me into checking out his other movies. So i got Hana Bi since it had a lot of good reviews. I can actually understand people, that mostly watch action flicks, getting bored by this film, but for those more into poetic films, this is just the thing for you. While short on dialog, the movie is stronger on the body language of all the characters... sometimes there isn't any dialog for more than 6 minutes or so, where you just have to watch in order to understand what he is trying to tell us... For me it the movie was a bit depressing and sometimes hard to follow, but i still enjoyed it a lot. But as i said, this movie is not for everyone.... The movie is about a cop in Japan who leaves the police to spend more time with his wife who is dying of cancer, and if that was not enough to bare with, he also lost a kid and his partner gets shot and paralyzed on the job. Now he has to deal with all these tragedies at the same time... So if you want a comparison, if you liked movies like "21 grams" for example, you will love this movie!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A collision of beauty and destruction
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ackstasis
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/8/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Takeshi Kitano's 'Hana-Bi' is something of an oddity. True to his previous efforts as director, the film contains its fair share of shockingly-graphic violence, and yet at its heart lies a touching tale of love, loyalty and devotion. For the entire running time, Kitano (who, aside from directing, also wrote and starred in the film) treads a perilously fine line between the two thematic extremes; it is an intricate balancing act that, if attempted by a less-talented filmmaker, might very possibly have turned into a complete cinematic disaster. Nevertheless, the director manages to pinpoint this perfect centre of balance, and the clash of beauty and violence combines to create a jarring amalgamation of conflicting emotional responses. We, as the audience, as simultaneously repulsed and entranced; as a whole, 'Hana-bi' is one of the most beautiful film experiences of the last decade or so. The title of the film itself acknowledges these opposing visual styles. Whilst the Japanese word 'Hanabi' translates to 'Fireworks' (the title under which it was released in the United States), the addition of the hyphen to the title ('Hana-bi') emphasises two individual components of the word, which translate respectively into "Fire" and "Flower," the collision of destruction and beauty/renewal. Much of the film concerns a cop named Yoshitaka Nishi (Kitano), who is forced to retire after a shooting on the job leaves his partner, Horibe (Ren Osugi), paralysed, alone and confined to a wheelchair. All the while, Nishi is still coming to terms with the impending loss of his wife, Miyuki (Kayoko Kishimoto), who is slowly dying from leukemia. As any grieving husband might do in such a situation, Nishi decides to quietly rob a bank, and he then uses most of the proceeds to fund a final loving family holiday for his ailing partner. The scenes between Nishi and his wife are among the most touching I've ever witnessed. Miyuki has only two lines in the entire film, and so the couple spend most of their time in complete silence and quiet reflection, and yet you can truly sense the affection that they both have for each other. Their love is completely unspoken, and this makes it all the more touching when Miyuki does finally speak. Another touching character is Horibe, the loyal police force partner whose crippling injury leaves him alone and depressed. After attempting suicide, Horibe receives painting materials in the mail, and he commits his emotions to canvas, finally uncovering a reason for his continued existence (importantly, the artwork we see in the film was actually created by Kitano in 1994, after a near-fatal motorcycle accident). The film's phenomenally moving soundtrack was composed by renowned Japanese composer Joe Hisaishi, in his fourth collaboration with the director. There are very few negative criticisms that can be said of 'Hana-bi.' One possible item is that the film's unusual flashback structure made some plot-points difficult to follow, and I'm still unsure of which cop's lonesome widow Nishi was in the habit of visiting. However, that's the only critique that springs straight to mind. All in all, 'Hana-bi' is a gloriously assorted blend of violence, love and gentle humour, and a first viewing is not likely to be forgotten in a hurry.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    an existential ode to violence
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    badtothebono
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/8/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    So, it has come to this. In the top-rated comment on this flick, somebody says "Nishi is an honorable man". Really? This is a guy who mainly kills and maims people in the movie. He takes a short break to rob a bank. Honorable? How would you like your kids to go to school with the kids of someone who calls that honorable? Wait, there's more! The person also says "we can tell he's constantly thinking." How can we do that? Well, do you know that joke "How can you tell when a CEO/politician/lawyer is lying?" ... "His/her lips move." Well, Nishi's lips never move, so I guess that means he is thinking. Of course, this is existentialism to warm the hearts of the cult of victimization. Existentalism supposedly stresses that an individual take responsibility for the consequences of one's acts. Not Nishi. Borrow money from the yakuza. What, they want it back? Kill them. The cops find out. Kill yourself and your wife. Really honorable.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Just one name:Takeshi Kitano
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    johnny-08
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/6/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is fourth movie that I watched from Takeshi Kitano and I have to say that I'm a little disappointed with this one.I know that this is probably his most awarding movie but I don't think this is his best.Far from there.I find "Dolls" his greatest achievement.Don't get me wrong "Hana-bi" is very good movie but I expected something better.It's because Kitano put so high standards and sometimes it is hard to achieve them. The plot is about Yoshitaka Nishi who is cop and his wife is dying of Leukemia.His partner gets shot in the job and he ends up in a wheel chair.Nishi is trying to help him because he feels that somehow he's guilty for what happened.Soon Nishi leaves police so he can spend more time with his wife.All his life he did wright things and know he has to do all wrong things so he can survive.He soon sinks deeper and deeper in his problems that are leading to tragedy. I liked the plot but this isn't nothing new.What is new is Kitano's way in filming this one.His camera is excellent and that part is very good but something about this movie as whole didn't fit perfectly to me.I don't know what that is but "Dolls" are better to me.I'm repeating myself so I'll quit know.Just one more thing;fans of Kitano won't be disappointed with this movie and also this movie is a great way to become a fan of this great film-maker.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Love, painting and poetry...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ivanbmm
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I don't gave 10 because there is some dose of violence in this movie to my taste. However, fading away this violence there is one of the most beautiful stories of love, painting and poetry that I've ever seen. I keep scanning movie forums, looking for these kind of movies. In my view, they are felt with more down-to-earth love stories, which I am finding rare to find now-a-days. The closer I can get from Hana-bi is Poetry by Chang-dong Lee. The reason I love both is the same. They are full of beautiful metaphors to give colour to such trivial stories, realistic characters like Nishi (Takeshi Kitano) and off course, poetic visuals. Hana-bi is worth watching for poetry lovers.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Explosions in the sky
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    lionelduffy
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/12/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is a perfectly judged movie. The peerless Takeshi Kitano moves almost wordlessly through this film conveying moments of genuine tenderness alongside vengeful violence. The mastery with which he alternates between the tender and the brutal without ever losing the pathos of his character Nishi's situation is stunning. As ever Kitano reaches for the simplistic as opposed to the bombastic - admirable for a movie peopled with comic book violent yakuza and characters shattered by the unfairness of life's mandatory dealing of the cards. Telling the story in violent flashback, Kitano balances his tale with a beautiful understated romanticism laced with comic tenderness. This is the film the deft editor, visionary director, multifaceted actor and comic genius was born to make.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Too slow and "deep" at times but mostly emotionally engaging and impacting
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bob the moo
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/7/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Nishi is a cop who is very good at his job but whose personal life is impacted with loss  a dead child and now a dying wife. When his partner is put in a wheelchair by a criminal and another officer is shot dead, Nishi finds himself plagued by guilt over his part in it all. Blaming himself Nishi tries to do the right thing by his partner Horibe and the widow of cop, while also trying to salvage some happiness in what remains of his time with his wife. I came back to Takeshi Kitano about the same time as I left the Movies You Should See podcast. I left it because I don't think it is as good as it could be and at times offers no real insight into a film other than describing "bits" however I give them a mention because they reminded me that I had only ever seen one or two of Kitano's films and that it had been some time since I had even seen those. So it was that after watching Brother, my rental site threw me Hana-Bi and I was looking forward to it due to the praise on this site and indeed the podcast itself. The expectation was not unjustified as Hana-Bi is a film of pain and beauty that is well worth seeing even if it is not the image of perfection that some would have you believe. That statement is bound to attract a low vote on IMDb but what can I tell you? That it was slow and quiet is not a problem for me but it is a feeling you get watching the film and it is not helped by some scenes feeling irrelevant within the context of the story. This is not a real killer but I felt that the slow pace needed support and seeing two minor characters argue about a fender bender (for example) saw my interest dip and the slow pace start to be felt. Otherwise though, the silence and pace suits the material and the style of the film. The violence is quite subdued (in regards what you actually see) because it occurs in the edit of the action  so the actual impact is mostly unseen. It doesn't matter though because the main thrust of the film is less the outward violence but the internal suffering of all the characters. The film does wear this aspect a little heavily at times and some will feel that some sequences are right on the edge of being pretentious and there is no point in denying that it does walk this line here and there. However for the majority it is a really well observed and emotionally engaging story built on the silent but emotive presence of Kitano as writer, director and star. As writer he has, it could be argued, left a lot to the actual making process itself since the script must have been a few pages. As director he sets the pace and I like the way his static style works within this story but it is his work as actor that always mystifies and impresses me. How he can convey so much while also appearing to be doing nothing at all I'm not sure but it somehow works and fits his style in other disciplines. He is well supported by Kishimoto, with whom he has genuine chemistry without betraying his character's nature. Osugi is not that great and it is with his character that I found the film close to being pretentious, not the actor's fault of course but I never felt for him as I did for Nishi. Hana-Bi is very slow and quiet and I can totally understand why some viewers will throw it in very early on. However sticking with it reveals a film that manages to be violent, introspective and emotionally engaging at the same time, all wrapped in the style of Kitano, who is creative across the board.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An overlooked masterpiece from the 90s
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    TimothyFarrell
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/12/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Hana-bi" may appear to be a standard cop action thriller from a simple plot description, but nothing could be further from the truth. Takashi Kitano's masterpiece is a slow moving meditation on human nature. Its violent at moments to be sure, but the "action" consists of short bursts of gun play that are stripped of any romanticism. They're all the more effective because of how sparingly they're employed. If anything, Kitano has much more in common with Yasujiro Ozu than John Woo. Kitano has fashioned a fascinating character study, one whose actual meaning is very abstract and difficult to decipher. The film's subtlety requires multiple viewings to fully appreciate. The film has a transcendental nature whose beauty is difficult to describe in words. Kitano is both a masterclass director and actor. He's best known as a stand-up comedian in Japan, which is odd because of the amount of seriousness he invests in both his positions. His lead performance is tough but has an amount of unexpected depth. Hes truly one of cinema's most charismatic performers, and he has this amazing presence despite the minimal dialog. His direction is slowly paced, but perfect. Not a single moment is wasted in this film. "Hana-bi" is one of the 90's most overlooked masterpieces, a decade known for its lack of depth or subtlety. (9/10)
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A man by the sea with or without his wife
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Christian
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/11/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Takeshi Kitano not only writes, acts in, directs and edits this meaningful fable, he also paints the artworks that are a strong element of the film. Kitano is supposedly known for his violence, but this movie has more to do about the repercussion of violence--and about life and death in general--than showing actual violent scenes. The violence is there, bursts of explosive violence, but it is short and strategically edited. Nishi, the protagonist, sees his partners die or get injured in the line of duty. One of them, Horibe, becomes wheel-chair-bound. His wife leaves him and he contemplates life and death staring at the horizon beyond the sea. He starts to paint to express himself and save himself from boredom and sorrow. Nishi, sick of his work leaves the police force to spend some time with his dying wife. The doctor just released her from the hospital and she does not have much time left... Kitano chooses to focus on the underlying emotions rather than dialogue as most of the scenes with his wife are silent. At first, this is unnerving, but slowly, as the movie progress, we understand that there is nothing left to stay. The score of the movie is its strongest point. Accomplished composer, Joe Hisaishi (who worked with Kitano on other projects as well as with Miyazaki's animated films) outdoes himself with poignant classical music that, unlike Nishi, speaks volume. He would win the Award of the Japanese Academy for this. Some good cinematography can also be observed at times. Kitano's paintings are interesting and vibrant. They add yet another level of complexity to this intriguing piece of film. All in all, a very well made film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    touching and incredible profound movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bruno-ferreira382
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/11/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Hana-bi is visual poetry, it says so much without using words.it is brilliantly directed because the movie delivers such an intense mood,the music by joe hisaishi also plays an important role in this moody film.But what it really makes the movie so profound and moving it's minimalist style, all the characters in the movie show very little emotion and yet takeshi kitano makes the film so touching by only showing the sea, the sky,the flowers, the paintings,along with joe hisaishi music.the true power of the film is that it doesn't say very much in terms of speaking,but it says a lot with its stunning images and music.I recommend this to all who want see an introspective,profound and thought provoking film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Great film though not for everybody
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    nexxit
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/10/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I only once happened to get my fingers on Kitanos movie "Brother", which got me into checking out his other movies. So i got Hana Bi since it had a lot of good reviews. I can actually understand people, that mostly watch action flicks, getting bored by this film, but for those more into poetic films, this is just the thing for you. While short on dialog, the movie is stronger on the body language of all the characters... sometimes there isn't any dialog for more than 6 minutes or so, where you just have to watch in order to understand what he is trying to tell us... For me it the movie was a bit depressing and sometimes hard to follow, but i still enjoyed it a lot. But as i said, this movie is not for everyone.... The movie is about a cop in Japan who leaves the police to spend more time with his wife who is dying of cancer, and if that was not enough to bare with, he also lost a kid and his partner gets shot and paralyzed on the job. Now he has to deal with all these tragedies at the same time... So if you want a comparison, if you liked movies like "21 grams" for example, you will love this movie!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A collision of beauty and destruction
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ackstasis
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/8/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Takeshi Kitano's 'Hana-Bi' is something of an oddity. True to his previous efforts as director, the film contains its fair share of shockingly-graphic violence, and yet at its heart lies a touching tale of love, loyalty and devotion. For the entire running time, Kitano (who, aside from directing, also wrote and starred in the film) treads a perilously fine line between the two thematic extremes; it is an intricate balancing act that, if attempted by a less-talented filmmaker, might very possibly have turned into a complete cinematic disaster. Nevertheless, the director manages to pinpoint this perfect centre of balance, and the clash of beauty and violence combines to create a jarring amalgamation of conflicting emotional responses. We, as the audience, as simultaneously repulsed and entranced; as a whole, 'Hana-bi' is one of the most beautiful film experiences of the last decade or so. The title of the film itself acknowledges these opposing visual styles. Whilst the Japanese word 'Hanabi' translates to 'Fireworks' (the title under which it was released in the United States), the addition of the hyphen to the title ('Hana-bi') emphasises two individual components of the word, which translate respectively into "Fire" and "Flower," the collision of destruction and beauty/renewal. Much of the film concerns a cop named Yoshitaka Nishi (Kitano), who is forced to retire after a shooting on the job leaves his partner, Horibe (Ren Osugi), paralysed, alone and confined to a wheelchair. All the while, Nishi is still coming to terms with the impending loss of his wife, Miyuki (Kayoko Kishimoto), who is slowly dying from leukemia. As any grieving husband might do in such a situation, Nishi decides to quietly rob a bank, and he then uses most of the proceeds to fund a final loving family holiday for his ailing partner. The scenes between Nishi and his wife are among the most touching I've ever witnessed. Miyuki has only two lines in the entire film, and so the couple spend most of their time in complete silence and quiet reflection, and yet you can truly sense the affection that they both have for each other. Their love is completely unspoken, and this makes it all the more touching when Miyuki does finally speak. Another touching character is Horibe, the loyal police force partner whose crippling injury leaves him alone and depressed. After attempting suicide, Horibe receives painting materials in the mail, and he commits his emotions to canvas, finally uncovering a reason for his continued existence (importantly, the artwork we see in the film was actually created by Kitano in 1994, after a near-fatal motorcycle accident). The film's phenomenally moving soundtrack was composed by renowned Japanese composer Joe Hisaishi, in his fourth collaboration with the director. There are very few negative criticisms that can be said of 'Hana-bi.' One possible item is that the film's unusual flashback structure made some plot-points difficult to follow, and I'm still unsure of which cop's lonesome widow Nishi was in the habit of visiting. However, that's the only critique that springs straight to mind. All in all, 'Hana-bi' is a gloriously assorted blend of violence, love and gentle humour, and a first viewing is not likely to be forgotten in a hurry.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    an existential ode to violence
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    badtothebono
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/8/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    So, it has come to this. In the top-rated comment on this flick, somebody says "Nishi is an honorable man". Really? This is a guy who mainly kills and maims people in the movie. He takes a short break to rob a bank. Honorable? How would you like your kids to go to school with the kids of someone who calls that honorable? Wait, there's more! The person also says "we can tell he's constantly thinking." How can we do that? Well, do you know that joke "How can you tell when a CEO/politician/lawyer is lying?" ... "His/her lips move." Well, Nishi's lips never move, so I guess that means he is thinking. Of course, this is existentialism to warm the hearts of the cult of victimization. Existentalism supposedly stresses that an individual take responsibility for the consequences of one's acts. Not Nishi. Borrow money from the yakuza. What, they want it back? Kill them. The cops find out. Kill yourself and your wife. Really honorable.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Just one name:Takeshi Kitano
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    johnny-08
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/6/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is fourth movie that I watched from Takeshi Kitano and I have to say that I'm a little disappointed with this one.I know that this is probably his most awarding movie but I don't think this is his best.Far from there.I find "Dolls" his greatest achievement.Don't get me wrong "Hana-bi" is very good movie but I expected something better.It's because Kitano put so high standards and sometimes it is hard to achieve them. The plot is about Yoshitaka Nishi who is cop and his wife is dying of Leukemia.His partner gets shot in the job and he ends up in a wheel chair.Nishi is trying to help him because he feels that somehow he's guilty for what happened.Soon Nishi leaves police so he can spend more time with his wife.All his life he did wright things and know he has to do all wrong things so he can survive.He soon sinks deeper and deeper in his problems that are leading to tragedy. I liked the plot but this isn't nothing new.What is new is Kitano's way in filming this one.His camera is excellent and that part is very good but something about this movie as whole didn't fit perfectly to me.I don't know what that is but "Dolls" are better to me.I'm repeating myself so I'll quit know.Just one more thing;fans of Kitano won't be disappointed with this movie and also this movie is a great way to become a fan of this great film-maker.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Love, painting and poetry...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ivanbmm
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I don't gave 10 because there is some dose of violence in this movie to my taste. However, fading away this violence there is one of the most beautiful stories of love, painting and poetry that I've ever seen. I keep scanning movie forums, looking for these kind of movies. In my view, they are felt with more down-to-earth love stories, which I am finding rare to find now-a-days. The closer I can get from Hana-bi is Poetry by Chang-dong Lee. The reason I love both is the same. They are full of beautiful metaphors to give colour to such trivial stories, realistic characters like Nishi (Takeshi Kitano) and off course, poetic visuals. Hana-bi is worth watching for poetry lovers.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Explosions in the sky
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    lionelduffy
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/12/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is a perfectly judged movie. The peerless Takeshi Kitano moves almost wordlessly through this film conveying moments of genuine tenderness alongside vengeful violence. The mastery with which he alternates between the tender and the brutal without ever losing the pathos of his character Nishi's situation is stunning. As ever Kitano reaches for the simplistic as opposed to the bombastic - admirable for a movie peopled with comic book violent yakuza and characters shattered by the unfairness of life's mandatory dealing of the cards. Telling the story in violent flashback, Kitano balances his tale with a beautiful understated romanticism laced with comic tenderness. This is the film the deft editor, visionary director, multifaceted actor and comic genius was born to make.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Too slow and "deep" at times but mostly emotionally engaging and impacting
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bob the moo
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/7/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Nishi is a cop who is very good at his job but whose personal life is impacted with loss  a dead child and now a dying wife. When his partner is put in a wheelchair by a criminal and another officer is shot dead, Nishi finds himself plagued by guilt over his part in it all. Blaming himself Nishi tries to do the right thing by his partner Horibe and the widow of cop, while also trying to salvage some happiness in what remains of his time with his wife. I came back to Takeshi Kitano about the same time as I left the Movies You Should See podcast. I left it because I don't think it is as good as it could be and at times offers no real insight into a film other than describing "bits" however I give them a mention because they reminded me that I had only ever seen one or two of Kitano's films and that it had been some time since I had even seen those. So it was that after watching Brother, my rental site threw me Hana-Bi and I was looking forward to it due to the praise on this site and indeed the podcast itself. The expectation was not unjustified as Hana-Bi is a film of pain and beauty that is well worth seeing even if it is not the image of perfection that some would have you believe. That statement is bound to attract a low vote on IMDb but what can I tell you? That it was slow and quiet is not a problem for me but it is a feeling you get watching the film and it is not helped by some scenes feeling irrelevant within the context of the story. This is not a real killer but I felt that the slow pace needed support and seeing two minor characters argue about a fender bender (for example) saw my interest dip and the slow pace start to be felt. Otherwise though, the silence and pace suits the material and the style of the film. The violence is quite subdued (in regards what you actually see) because it occurs in the edit of the action  so the actual impact is mostly unseen. It doesn't matter though because the main thrust of the film is less the outward violence but the internal suffering of all the characters. The film does wear this aspect a little heavily at times and some will feel that some sequences are right on the edge of being pretentious and there is no point in denying that it does walk this line here and there. However for the majority it is a really well observed and emotionally engaging story built on the silent but emotive presence of Kitano as writer, director and star. As writer he has, it could be argued, left a lot to the actual making process itself since the script must have been a few pages. As director he sets the pace and I like the way his static style works within this story but it is his work as actor that always mystifies and impresses me. How he can convey so much while also appearing to be doing nothing at all I'm not sure but it somehow works and fits his style in other disciplines. He is well supported by Kishimoto, with whom he has genuine chemistry without betraying his character's nature. Osugi is not that great and it is with his character that I found the film close to being pretentious, not the actor's fault of course but I never felt for him as I did for Nishi. Hana-Bi is very slow and quiet and I can totally understand why some viewers will throw it in very early on. However sticking with it reveals a film that manages to be violent, introspective and emotionally engaging at the same time, all wrapped in the style of Kitano, who is creative across the board.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An overlooked masterpiece from the 90s
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    TimothyFarrell
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/12/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Hana-bi" may appear to be a standard cop action thriller from a simple plot description, but nothing could be further from the truth. Takashi Kitano's masterpiece is a slow moving meditation on human nature. Its violent at moments to be sure, but the "action" consists of short bursts of gun play that are stripped of any romanticism. They're all the more effective because of how sparingly they're employed. If anything, Kitano has much more in common with Yasujiro Ozu than John Woo. Kitano has fashioned a fascinating character study, one whose actual meaning is very abstract and difficult to decipher. The film's subtlety requires multiple viewings to fully appreciate. The film has a transcendental nature whose beauty is difficult to describe in words. Kitano is both a masterclass director and actor. He's best known as a stand-up comedian in Japan, which is odd because of the amount of seriousness he invests in both his positions. His lead performance is tough but has an amount of unexpected depth. Hes truly one of cinema's most charismatic performers, and he has this amazing presence despite the minimal dialog. His direction is slowly paced, but perfect. Not a single moment is wasted in this film. "Hana-bi" is one of the 90's most overlooked masterpieces, a decade known for its lack of depth or subtlety. (9/10)
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A man by the sea with or without his wife
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Christian
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/11/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Takeshi Kitano not only writes, acts in, directs and edits this meaningful fable, he also paints the artworks that are a strong element of the film. Kitano is supposedly known for his violence, but this movie has more to do about the repercussion of violence--and about life and death in general--than showing actual violent scenes. The violence is there, bursts of explosive violence, but it is short and strategically edited. Nishi, the protagonist, sees his partners die or get injured in the line of duty. One of them, Horibe, becomes wheel-chair-bound. His wife leaves him and he contemplates life and death staring at the horizon beyond the sea. He starts to paint to express himself and save himself from boredom and sorrow. Nishi, sick of his work leaves the police force to spend some time with his dying wife. The doctor just released her from the hospital and she does not have much time left... Kitano chooses to focus on the underlying emotions rather than dialogue as most of the scenes with his wife are silent. At first, this is unnerving, but slowly, as the movie progress, we understand that there is nothing left to stay. The score of the movie is its strongest point. Accomplished composer, Joe Hisaishi (who worked with Kitano on other projects as well as with Miyazaki's animated films) outdoes himself with poignant classical music that, unlike Nishi, speaks volume. He would win the Award of the Japanese Academy for this. Some good cinematography can also be observed at times. Kitano's paintings are interesting and vibrant. They add yet another level of complexity to this intriguing piece of film. All in all, a very well made film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    touching and incredible profound movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bruno-ferreira382
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/11/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Hana-bi is visual poetry, it says so much without using words.it is brilliantly directed because the movie delivers such an intense mood,the music by joe hisaishi also plays an important role in this moody film.But what it really makes the movie so profound and moving it's minimalist style, all the characters in the movie show very little emotion and yet takeshi kitano makes the film so touching by only showing the sea, the sky,the flowers, the paintings,along with joe hisaishi music.the true power of the film is that it doesn't say very much in terms of speaking,but it says a lot with its stunning images and music.I recommend this to all who want see an introspective,profound and thought provoking film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Great film though not for everybody
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    nexxit
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/10/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I only once happened to get my fingers on Kitanos movie "Brother", which got me into checking out his other movies. So i got Hana Bi since it had a lot of good reviews. I can actually understand people, that mostly watch action flicks, getting bored by this film, but for those more into poetic films, this is just the thing for you. While short on dialog, the movie is stronger on the body language of all the characters... sometimes there isn't any dialog for more than 6 minutes or so, where you just have to watch in order to understand what he is trying to tell us... For me it the movie was a bit depressing and sometimes hard to follow, but i still enjoyed it a lot. But as i said, this movie is not for everyone.... The movie is about a cop in Japan who leaves the police to spend more time with his wife who is dying of cancer, and if that was not enough to bare with, he also lost a kid and his partner gets shot and paralyzed on the job. Now he has to deal with all these tragedies at the same time... So if you want a comparison, if you liked movies like "21 grams" for example, you will love this movie!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A collision of beauty and destruction
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ackstasis
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/8/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Takeshi Kitano's 'Hana-Bi' is something of an oddity. True to his previous efforts as director, the film contains its fair share of shockingly-graphic violence, and yet at its heart lies a touching tale of love, loyalty and devotion. For the entire running time, Kitano (who, aside from directing, also wrote and starred in the film) treads a perilously fine line between the two thematic extremes; it is an intricate balancing act that, if attempted by a less-talented filmmaker, might very possibly have turned into a complete cinematic disaster. Nevertheless, the director manages to pinpoint this perfect centre of balance, and the clash of beauty and violence combines to create a jarring amalgamation of conflicting emotional responses. We, as the audience, as simultaneously repulsed and entranced; as a whole, 'Hana-bi' is one of the most beautiful film experiences of the last decade or so. The title of the film itself acknowledges these opposing visual styles. Whilst the Japanese word 'Hanabi' translates to 'Fireworks' (the title under which it was released in the United States), the addition of the hyphen to the title ('Hana-bi') emphasises two individual components of the word, which translate respectively into "Fire" and "Flower," the collision of destruction and beauty/renewal. Much of the film concerns a cop named Yoshitaka Nishi (Kitano), who is forced to retire after a shooting on the job leaves his partner, Horibe (Ren Osugi), paralysed, alone and confined to a wheelchair. All the while, Nishi is still coming to terms with the impending loss of his wife, Miyuki (Kayoko Kishimoto), who is slowly dying from leukemia. As any grieving husband might do in such a situation, Nishi decides to quietly rob a bank, and he then uses most of the proceeds to fund a final loving family holiday for his ailing partner. The scenes between Nishi and his wife are among the most touching I've ever witnessed. Miyuki has only two lines in the entire film, and so the couple spend most of their time in complete silence and quiet reflection, and yet you can truly sense the affection that they both have for each other. Their love is completely unspoken, and this makes it all the more touching when Miyuki does finally speak. Another touching character is Horibe, the loyal police force partner whose crippling injury leaves him alone and depressed. After attempting suicide, Horibe receives painting materials in the mail, and he commits his emotions to canvas, finally uncovering a reason for his continued existence (importantly, the artwork we see in the film was actually created by Kitano in 1994, after a near-fatal motorcycle accident). The film's phenomenally moving soundtrack was composed by renowned Japanese composer Joe Hisaishi, in his fourth collaboration with the director. There are very few negative criticisms that can be said of 'Hana-bi.' One possible item is that the film's unusual flashback structure made some plot-points difficult to follow, and I'm still unsure of which cop's lonesome widow Nishi was in the habit of visiting. However, that's the only critique that springs straight to mind. All in all, 'Hana-bi' is a gloriously assorted blend of violence, love and gentle humour, and a first viewing is not likely to be forgotten in a hurry.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    an existential ode to violence
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    badtothebono
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/8/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    So, it has come to this. In the top-rated comment on this flick, somebody says "Nishi is an honorable man". Really? This is a guy who mainly kills and maims people in the movie. He takes a short break to rob a bank. Honorable? How would you like your kids to go to school with the kids of someone who calls that honorable? Wait, there's more! The person also says "we can tell he's constantly thinking." How can we do that? Well, do you know that joke "How can you tell when a CEO/politician/lawyer is lying?" ... "His/her lips move." Well, Nishi's lips never move, so I guess that means he is thinking. Of course, this is existentialism to warm the hearts of the cult of victimization. Existentalism supposedly stresses that an individual take responsibility for the consequences of one's acts. Not Nishi. Borrow money from the yakuza. What, they want it back? Kill them. The cops find out. Kill yourself and your wife. Really honorable.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Just one name:Takeshi Kitano
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    johnny-08
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/6/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is fourth movie that I watched from Takeshi Kitano and I have to say that I'm a little disappointed with this one.I know that this is probably his most awarding movie but I don't think this is his best.Far from there.I find "Dolls" his greatest achievement.Don't get me wrong "Hana-bi" is very good movie but I expected something better.It's because Kitano put so high standards and sometimes it is hard to achieve them. The plot is about Yoshitaka Nishi who is cop and his wife is dying of Leukemia.His partner gets shot in the job and he ends up in a wheel chair.Nishi is trying to help him because he feels that somehow he's guilty for what happened.Soon Nishi leaves police so he can spend more time with his wife.All his life he did wright things and know he has to do all wrong things so he can survive.He soon sinks deeper and deeper in his problems that are leading to tragedy. I liked the plot but this isn't nothing new.What is new is Kitano's way in filming this one.His camera is excellent and that part is very good but something about this movie as whole didn't fit perfectly to me.I don't know what that is but "Dolls" are better to me.I'm repeating myself so I'll quit know.Just one more thing;fans of Kitano won't be disappointed with this movie and also this movie is a great way to become a fan of this great film-maker.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
 </reviews>
</filme>
