<filme>
 <id>
  165
 </id>
 <imdburl>
  http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0091288
 </imdburl>
 <ano>
  1986
 </ano>
 <titulo>
  Jean de Florette
 </titulo>
 <rating>
  7.9
 </rating>
 <sinopse>
  A greedy landowner and his backward nephew conspire to block the only water source for an adjoining property in order to bankrupt the owner and force him to sell.
 </sinopse>
 <storyline>
  In a rural French village an old man and his only remaining relative cast their covetous eyes on an adjoining vacant property. They need its spring water for growing their flowers, so are dismayed to hear the man who has inherited it is moving in. They block up the spring and watch as their new neighbour tries to keep his crops watered from wells far afield through the hot summer. Though they see his desperate efforts are breaking his health and his wife and daughter's hearts they think only of getting the water.
 </storyline>
 <generos>
  <genero>
   Drama
  </genero>
 </generos>
 <keywords>
  <keyword>
   water
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   spring
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   flower
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   entrepreneurship
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   heritage
  </keyword>
 </keywords>
 <diretores>
  <diretor>
   Claude Berri
  </diretor>
 </diretores>
 <escritores>
  <escritor>
   Claude Berri
  </escritor>
  <escritor>
   G&eacute;rard Brach
  </escritor>
 </escritores>
 <atores>
  <ator>
   Yves Montand
  </ator>
  <ator>
   G&eacute;rard Depardieu
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Daniel Auteuil
  </ator>
 </atores>
 <reviews>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Enjoy the wonderful surroundings and relax
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Luigi Di Pilla
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The surroundings near Aubagne in the Bouche Du Rh&ocirc;ne in France are wonderfully shot. The story by Marcel Pagnol is well adapted that takes step by step a dramatic end. All the actors did a fine Job and I am curious to see part two "Manon La Source". The sceneries in the time after the second world war are well built and developed. I recommend you to watch it in the original south french dialect with English subtitles. I spent an enjoyable and relaxing Saturday night with my wife. Don't miss the other great movie from the writer Pagnol called La Fille Du Pusatier. Please read my critic on IMDb. Final vote: 8/10.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Flawless
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    yeltzmanmatt
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is a beautifully told tale of a hunchback who moves from the town to the country when he inherits a farm. The cinematography is brilliant and the languid pace of the movie suits this perfectly. The acting is out of the top drawer especially from Yves Montand and Daniel Autiel who are mesmerising as the farmers intent on grabbing Gerard Depardieu's land. Depardieu is also in fine form as the hunchback who although bombastic and stubborn eventually evokes a deal of sympathy. It is hard to fault this film on any level and it absorbs you from the start to the finale. Although you can watch the film on it's own the subsequent Manon Des Sources ( another fine film) concludes the story in full. I have known a fair few people who don't like foreign language films who have watched this and every one has enjoyed it. This is a French classic not to be missed.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Rare gem.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    (Draco2-0)
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I just watched Jean De Florrete and it was great, very rare for me to say this but I was not once bored or restless during the entire movie. Jean De Florrete, about this French farmer who moves onto his uncle's land and decides it would be profitable to grow flowers. But in order to grow a enough flowers to make a profit they'll need more water than they have available. Their neighbor has an untapped underground spring. The farmer and his uncle go over to negotiate buying the land with the spring on it. Unfortunately for them their neighbor hates the uncle, and when they offer to buy some of his land the uncle and him get into a fight and during the bustle his head suffers a fatal blow against a rock and he dies almost instantaneously. The whole ordeal took place by a tree, so the farmer and his uncle make it look like the old man fell from the tree and hit his head. They think the land will be theirs but a relative of the neighbor, a hunchback, moves onto the property. The uncle offers to buy the land from him but the hunchback wants to use it for raising rabbits and growing squash. Fascinating to watch the triumphs and failures of the hunchback as he goes about trying to fulfill his dream, always with a happy upbeat attitude. The thing that amazed me about the movie would be just how simple the actual plot feels. There are no huge twists, no distracting sub-plots, not much happens for most of the movie until the last 15 minutes; despite that it manages to grab the viewers attention wonderfully and it doesn't let it go until the credits roll either. Unless you hate French movies. I highly recommend Jean De Floret.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Jean de Florette / Manon of the Spring
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    runamokprods
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/7/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Two part film, that was 1st released as two separate features. Terrific telling of a complex story of intertwined farming families in rural France in the early part of the 20th century. The acting is mostly of the highest order. Yves Montand, one of the most suave men in history is completely believable as a rough hewn, self-centered farmer, Gerard Depardieu, also cast against type, as a gentle, educated city born man trying to make it as a farmer also is astounding. Almost as good is Daniel Auteuil as Montand's not-very-bright son. Only Emmanuelle Beart, gorgeous though she may be, doesn't quite convince me as the wild woman of the fields. Some of it is performance, some of it is how perfect she looks. The story is wonderful in a Dickensian sort of way, with clues and character elements showing up early, only to pay off three hours later. I love the first part even more, somehow it feels more truly tragic and dense, the 2nd part just a bit too neat by the end. But still a grand, intelligent, great looking entertainment.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "Remarkably narrated and invariably moving..."
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Sindre Kaspersen
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/3/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    French actor, producer, screenwriter and director Claude Berri's twelfth feature film which he co-wrote with French screenwriter G&eacute;rard Brach (1927-2006) is an adaptation of a novel, "L'Eau des Collines - Jean de Florette and Manon des Sources" (1964) by French author, playwright and filmmaker Marcel Pagnol (1895-1974), which was inspired by true events. It was shot on numerous locations in the Vaucluse department of Provence in the southeast of France and is part of a duology which was succeeded by "Manon des Sources" (1986). It tells the story about Ugolin Soubeyran who one summer after having served his time in World War I returns to his home in rural Provence where he is welcomed by his highly revered uncle Cesar Le Papet Soubeyran. Back at his home place in the highlands, Ugolin initiates a planned project which involves growing plants, but soon discovers that he is going to need a water resource to keep his enterprise afloat. He let's Papet in on his new activity and the old man is eager to help his nephew, but his good intentions get's the better of him and leads to fatal consequences. Though having their plan ruined they are dead set on finding a way to gain their obstacle, so when a man from the village named Jean Cadoret moves in to his newly inherited property with his wife Aim&egrave;e and their adolescent daughter Manon, the two farmers decides to mislead him. Subtly and acutely directed by French filmmaker Claude Berri (1934-2009) and with it's ardent and naturalistic milieu depictions and efficient narrative structure, this historic period piece, at the time the most expensive French film in French history, draws a throughout engaging portrayal of a kind-hearted and loving husband and father with an urban background who whilst struggling to create a good life for himself and his family in a rural area at the turn of the twentieth century, becomes a victim of deception and prejudice. This mid-1980s co-production between France, Italy and Switzerland, known as part of a movement in France during the 1980s called "heritage cinema" which mainly consisted of costume dramas, has a powerful score by French composer and arranger Jean-Claude Petit, based on Italian composer Giuseppe Verdi's Italian opera "The Force of Destiny" (1862), which reinforces the films pivotal atmosphere. Produced by French producers Pierre Grunstein and Alain Poir&eacute; (1917-2000) and notable for it's wonderful production design by production designer Bernard V&eacute;zat and cinematography by French director and cinematographer Bruno Nuytten, this character-driven and dialog-driven countryside epic which examines themes like interpersonal relations, greed, faith and the distinctions between human goodness and human cruelty is impelled by the splendid acting performances by French actor and producer G&eacute;rard Depardieu, Italian-born French actor and singer Yves Montand (1921-1991) and French actor, director and screenwriter Daniel Auteuil. A remarkably narrated and invariably moving drama which gained, among several other awards, the BAFTA Film Award for Best Film, Best cinematography Bruno Nuytten, Best Adapted Screenplay Claude Berri and G&eacute;rard Brach and Best Supporting Actor Daniel Auteuil at the 41st British Academy Film Awards in 1988, the NBR Award for Best Foreign Language Film at the National Board of Review of Motion Pictures Awards in 1987 and the C&eacute;sar Award for Best Actor Daniel Auteuil at the 13th C&eacute;sar Awards in 1987.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Slow but beautiful
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    billcr12
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Gerard Depardieu is Jean de Florette, a simple, hard working landowner and farmer who grows and sells flowers and also raises rabbits for food. Some of Jean's neighbors would like to buy his land but Jean refuses to sell to them. They then find the main spring nearby and plug it with cement to prevent water from reaching the farm. Jean has to travel a good distance to carry large containers to his farm. He later gets badly injured and they take advantage of the situation quickly. This is a simple and slow moving drama which looks like a painting come to life. It is followed by the equally masterful "Manon of the Spring."
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    J'adore!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    TheLittleSongbird
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Having been so blown away by Cyrano De Bergerac, I also watched Jean De Florette, also starring Gerard Depardieu. Jean De Florette is a very different film, but every bit as fantastic. Depardieu is very endearing in a performance that has in his career only been surpassed by Cyrano De Bergerac to me. Yves Montand and Daniel Auteuil are also outstanding as the scheming Soubeyrans. The acting is not Jean De Florette's only good asset. This is an example of a film where everything works. The story is beautifully paced and evocative, the script is witty and very cinematic, the cinematography shimmers, the scenery is breathtaking, the music is lively yet again very understated and the direction does wonderfully in capturing the pace of the seasons changing and Provence's unique atmosphere. All in all, I love this movie just as much as Cyrano De Bergerac, and I am watching Manon of the Spring(and loving it) even as we speak. 10/10 Bethany Cox
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A personal all-time favorite
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    olyrye
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/12/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is an epic film(s). (It must really be seen with Manon of the Spring, which is not a sequel but really the second part of the movie.) The photography, music, acting, writing, are top notch. A must see for any film buff. Full of eye and ear candy! It really stirred an emotional response in me, especially at the end. So many great movies flounder at the conclusion. This one delivers! It deals with the themes of family loyalty, miscommunication, love, betrayal, failure, and persistence in the face of catastrophe. But most importantly it deals with almost impossible redemption. This is a great movie to watch with your spouse or partner. It is equally appealing to both men and women and is a great film for a movie date!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Qualifies as a classic Greek tragedy.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    zjerunk
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/7/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I have many favorites, and this is one of the cr&egrave;me de la cr&egrave;me. This is a visually stunning film more like beautiful photographic montage. It is simple, tragic story well told, unlike many of today's plots - implausibly lame, suffering on a CGI crutch for 85 minutes. The simple story is about enduring truths which have been the mainstay of the Greek classics and Shakespeare: Our human strengths, our failings, our virtues, and our vices. The story may be a fiction, but its kernel is not. It is stories and story telling like this which has kept our rapt attention for four thousand years. First we should understand that this film is only the first half the novel by Marcel Pagnol which would have been too long as a single film, and out of necessity, was shot as two. The second half is titled, Manon of the Spring. Neither film stands alone as satisfactory because, obviously, it would be incomplete, and naturally, is also important that the two halves be viewed in sequence. For a fairly dispassionate pr&eacute;cis of the plots, I suggest reading the ones on Wikipedia, so I won't be repetitive here. I also recommend reading the boards for comments and discussions. JdF & MotS were both shot at the same time in 1986 with a budget of $17 million making it/them the biggest budget French films up to that time. JdF grossed $86M worldwide, and of that sum, only $4.9M was from the USA. MotS grossed $56M worldwide, of which only $3.9M was from the USA. In other words, culture films are not a good fit for the American viewing audience, and the gross revenue numbers bear this out. The rest of the world seems to bear out this conclusion. Foreign language films rarely do well in the USA for the simple reason that the vast majority of the viewing audience are unilingual anglophones who do not wish to burden themselves with having to work at "understanding" their entertainment - they wish to merely consume it. If it requires the work of reading subtitles or thought, it becomes unpalatable. This film requires your attention and thought! But to be fair to the US viewers, the subtitles are at times incomplete or inaccurate, and unlike the spoken word, they do not convey the emphasis or importance of certain bits of dialogue well. The plot is woven steadily throughout the film, so the viewers with no understanding at all of the French language are missing essential dialogue, and therefore plot. The bottom line is this: You will either be entranced by these two films and love them, or you will be bored by the first 15 minutes, and you'll translate that into "bad film." If your highest quality level of reading is Marvel comics then I suggest you stay away from this one. However, I recall years ago walking into a video store where this was playing on all the monitors. All the patrons in the store, ranging in age from 5 to 75 years, were standing transfixed watching this film. There was something magical about it!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Agonising; enrapturing and taut all-at-once period piece, detailing the struggles of two sets of farm-set family units at evens and odds with one another.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    johnnyboyz (j_l_h_m@yahoo.co.uk)
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/1/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Has farming, indeed agriculture in general, ever been as cinematic as it is in Claude Berri's Jean de Florette? The joy is in observing the rather articulate nuances that the characters must undertake when particular farming tasks require particular tools and items for a job at hand; the film eventually coming to resemble a tale about a man most probably as alien to farming as the audience and enjoying it as much as we enjoy watching his taking up of this challenge. The farming within the film, in its specificities revolving around the planning; the predicting; the techniques and the use of certain items and animals for certain events, is as intrinsic as the film's core study of greed and the capitalist infused garnering of an industrial item, an item which will bring large amounts of personal wealth and riches, eventually at the expense of others. The film eventually coming to form a remarkably executed, heart breakingly tragic, blackly comic, devilishly well put together period drama from France well worth checking out. The film begins with a young man named Ugolin (Auteuil) returning home to the South of France, and his uncle's farm, having served time with the French army; the soundtrack a dry and sleepy orchestral tune suggesting much in the way of travels and tiredness, only momentarily breaking off into louder bursts of a much more positive tone as he nears home. Upon arriving home, Ugolin takes clear glee in rushing to a small patch of soil on the grounds and unwrapping a plant of some kind so he may observe it; something he appears to enjoy more than being reconciled with his uncle after such a stretch of time and furthermore suggesting an inclination towards agricultural work, his dream eventually revealed to be one of which revolves around the growing and selling of flowers for a living. His uncle is Cesar (Montand), an elderly man whom demands Ugolin find a wife and have children in the near future so that the land may be passed down and kept within the family; his other eye on a stretch of land lying nearby to his own, a stretch functional enough as it stands and with a natural spring beneath it capable of escalating the quality of the goods that only Cesar knows of, but a stretch already owned by a man no way willing to just sell up. Berri spends a good deal of time with these two farmers, their dreams; their positions and their core characteristics filling up most of the film's opening act. We come to like them during this early part and their blackly funny misadventures as well as their dry observations on life and newfound situations which open up as a result of other events. We side with young Ugolin, this simple young man whom has only just returned from national service and wishes to move into floristry. It is only when the titular Jean of Florette arrives, in the form of G&eacute;rard Depardieu, that we see the true nature of them; Jean being the rightful heir to that of the land when Cesar and Ugolin accidentally-on-purpose murder the owner of the land thus bringing Jean into the equation following a string of other legal complications with the rightful land owner. Jean and his family of wife Aimee (Elisabeth Depardieu) and young daughter Manon (Mazurowna) are not used to such surroundings; their previous incarnation of living in a more urbanite locale ill preparing them for what they come into contact with here, the beauty and calmness of the locale coming to resemble mere surface featurettes as those within plot and brew. The obvious distinctions between themselves and those more attributed to the land arrive in the form of their clear differences in clothing, as well as their talk of things of a more cultured nature, namely the opera, as on occasion Aimee breaks out int chorus of song to Jean's own harmonica tunes. What unfolds is a game of cat and mouse and hope and frustration between the two farmers, in Ugolin and Cesar, and the Florettes whom hang around much to the annoyance of their neighbours whom still want the land, know of its true flourishing nature and retain the spring as their secret. Jean's gradual coming around to realise how wondrous and how magnificent the locale is, and how enthralling the individual tasks and procedures which make up farming echoes our own coming around to feel similarly towards the film. Just as agricultural activity is fresh to that of Jean, the arrival of he and his family acts as a fresh and very crisp presence within the film to that of the audience; the very gradual bringing of the audience around on Berri's behalf to have us see the two original farmers as cruel and calculating businessmen as this initial outsider and his family capture our hearts, is outstanding. The film is a really well executed drama, a wonderful piece persistently flicking from tone to tone and character to character in perfect tandem; a film working on a level of family drama, fish out of water storytelling and dark comedy culminating in something quite special.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Enjoy the wonderful surroundings and relax
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Luigi Di Pilla
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The surroundings near Aubagne in the Bouche Du Rh&ocirc;ne in France are wonderfully shot. The story by Marcel Pagnol is well adapted that takes step by step a dramatic end. All the actors did a fine Job and I am curious to see part two "Manon La Source". The sceneries in the time after the second world war are well built and developed. I recommend you to watch it in the original south french dialect with English subtitles. I spent an enjoyable and relaxing Saturday night with my wife. Don't miss the other great movie from the writer Pagnol called La Fille Du Pusatier. Please read my critic on IMDb. Final vote: 8/10.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Flawless
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    yeltzmanmatt
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is a beautifully told tale of a hunchback who moves from the town to the country when he inherits a farm. The cinematography is brilliant and the languid pace of the movie suits this perfectly. The acting is out of the top drawer especially from Yves Montand and Daniel Autiel who are mesmerising as the farmers intent on grabbing Gerard Depardieu's land. Depardieu is also in fine form as the hunchback who although bombastic and stubborn eventually evokes a deal of sympathy. It is hard to fault this film on any level and it absorbs you from the start to the finale. Although you can watch the film on it's own the subsequent Manon Des Sources ( another fine film) concludes the story in full. I have known a fair few people who don't like foreign language films who have watched this and every one has enjoyed it. This is a French classic not to be missed.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Rare gem.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    (Draco2-0)
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I just watched Jean De Florrete and it was great, very rare for me to say this but I was not once bored or restless during the entire movie. Jean De Florrete, about this French farmer who moves onto his uncle's land and decides it would be profitable to grow flowers. But in order to grow a enough flowers to make a profit they'll need more water than they have available. Their neighbor has an untapped underground spring. The farmer and his uncle go over to negotiate buying the land with the spring on it. Unfortunately for them their neighbor hates the uncle, and when they offer to buy some of his land the uncle and him get into a fight and during the bustle his head suffers a fatal blow against a rock and he dies almost instantaneously. The whole ordeal took place by a tree, so the farmer and his uncle make it look like the old man fell from the tree and hit his head. They think the land will be theirs but a relative of the neighbor, a hunchback, moves onto the property. The uncle offers to buy the land from him but the hunchback wants to use it for raising rabbits and growing squash. Fascinating to watch the triumphs and failures of the hunchback as he goes about trying to fulfill his dream, always with a happy upbeat attitude. The thing that amazed me about the movie would be just how simple the actual plot feels. There are no huge twists, no distracting sub-plots, not much happens for most of the movie until the last 15 minutes; despite that it manages to grab the viewers attention wonderfully and it doesn't let it go until the credits roll either. Unless you hate French movies. I highly recommend Jean De Floret.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Jean de Florette / Manon of the Spring
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    runamokprods
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/7/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Two part film, that was 1st released as two separate features. Terrific telling of a complex story of intertwined farming families in rural France in the early part of the 20th century. The acting is mostly of the highest order. Yves Montand, one of the most suave men in history is completely believable as a rough hewn, self-centered farmer, Gerard Depardieu, also cast against type, as a gentle, educated city born man trying to make it as a farmer also is astounding. Almost as good is Daniel Auteuil as Montand's not-very-bright son. Only Emmanuelle Beart, gorgeous though she may be, doesn't quite convince me as the wild woman of the fields. Some of it is performance, some of it is how perfect she looks. The story is wonderful in a Dickensian sort of way, with clues and character elements showing up early, only to pay off three hours later. I love the first part even more, somehow it feels more truly tragic and dense, the 2nd part just a bit too neat by the end. But still a grand, intelligent, great looking entertainment.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "Remarkably narrated and invariably moving..."
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Sindre Kaspersen
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/3/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    French actor, producer, screenwriter and director Claude Berri's twelfth feature film which he co-wrote with French screenwriter G&eacute;rard Brach (1927-2006) is an adaptation of a novel, "L'Eau des Collines - Jean de Florette and Manon des Sources" (1964) by French author, playwright and filmmaker Marcel Pagnol (1895-1974), which was inspired by true events. It was shot on numerous locations in the Vaucluse department of Provence in the southeast of France and is part of a duology which was succeeded by "Manon des Sources" (1986). It tells the story about Ugolin Soubeyran who one summer after having served his time in World War I returns to his home in rural Provence where he is welcomed by his highly revered uncle Cesar Le Papet Soubeyran. Back at his home place in the highlands, Ugolin initiates a planned project which involves growing plants, but soon discovers that he is going to need a water resource to keep his enterprise afloat. He let's Papet in on his new activity and the old man is eager to help his nephew, but his good intentions get's the better of him and leads to fatal consequences. Though having their plan ruined they are dead set on finding a way to gain their obstacle, so when a man from the village named Jean Cadoret moves in to his newly inherited property with his wife Aim&egrave;e and their adolescent daughter Manon, the two farmers decides to mislead him. Subtly and acutely directed by French filmmaker Claude Berri (1934-2009) and with it's ardent and naturalistic milieu depictions and efficient narrative structure, this historic period piece, at the time the most expensive French film in French history, draws a throughout engaging portrayal of a kind-hearted and loving husband and father with an urban background who whilst struggling to create a good life for himself and his family in a rural area at the turn of the twentieth century, becomes a victim of deception and prejudice. This mid-1980s co-production between France, Italy and Switzerland, known as part of a movement in France during the 1980s called "heritage cinema" which mainly consisted of costume dramas, has a powerful score by French composer and arranger Jean-Claude Petit, based on Italian composer Giuseppe Verdi's Italian opera "The Force of Destiny" (1862), which reinforces the films pivotal atmosphere. Produced by French producers Pierre Grunstein and Alain Poir&eacute; (1917-2000) and notable for it's wonderful production design by production designer Bernard V&eacute;zat and cinematography by French director and cinematographer Bruno Nuytten, this character-driven and dialog-driven countryside epic which examines themes like interpersonal relations, greed, faith and the distinctions between human goodness and human cruelty is impelled by the splendid acting performances by French actor and producer G&eacute;rard Depardieu, Italian-born French actor and singer Yves Montand (1921-1991) and French actor, director and screenwriter Daniel Auteuil. A remarkably narrated and invariably moving drama which gained, among several other awards, the BAFTA Film Award for Best Film, Best cinematography Bruno Nuytten, Best Adapted Screenplay Claude Berri and G&eacute;rard Brach and Best Supporting Actor Daniel Auteuil at the 41st British Academy Film Awards in 1988, the NBR Award for Best Foreign Language Film at the National Board of Review of Motion Pictures Awards in 1987 and the C&eacute;sar Award for Best Actor Daniel Auteuil at the 13th C&eacute;sar Awards in 1987.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Slow but beautiful
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    billcr12
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Gerard Depardieu is Jean de Florette, a simple, hard working landowner and farmer who grows and sells flowers and also raises rabbits for food. Some of Jean's neighbors would like to buy his land but Jean refuses to sell to them. They then find the main spring nearby and plug it with cement to prevent water from reaching the farm. Jean has to travel a good distance to carry large containers to his farm. He later gets badly injured and they take advantage of the situation quickly. This is a simple and slow moving drama which looks like a painting come to life. It is followed by the equally masterful "Manon of the Spring."
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    J'adore!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    TheLittleSongbird
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Having been so blown away by Cyrano De Bergerac, I also watched Jean De Florette, also starring Gerard Depardieu. Jean De Florette is a very different film, but every bit as fantastic. Depardieu is very endearing in a performance that has in his career only been surpassed by Cyrano De Bergerac to me. Yves Montand and Daniel Auteuil are also outstanding as the scheming Soubeyrans. The acting is not Jean De Florette's only good asset. This is an example of a film where everything works. The story is beautifully paced and evocative, the script is witty and very cinematic, the cinematography shimmers, the scenery is breathtaking, the music is lively yet again very understated and the direction does wonderfully in capturing the pace of the seasons changing and Provence's unique atmosphere. All in all, I love this movie just as much as Cyrano De Bergerac, and I am watching Manon of the Spring(and loving it) even as we speak. 10/10 Bethany Cox
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A personal all-time favorite
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    olyrye
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/12/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is an epic film(s). (It must really be seen with Manon of the Spring, which is not a sequel but really the second part of the movie.) The photography, music, acting, writing, are top notch. A must see for any film buff. Full of eye and ear candy! It really stirred an emotional response in me, especially at the end. So many great movies flounder at the conclusion. This one delivers! It deals with the themes of family loyalty, miscommunication, love, betrayal, failure, and persistence in the face of catastrophe. But most importantly it deals with almost impossible redemption. This is a great movie to watch with your spouse or partner. It is equally appealing to both men and women and is a great film for a movie date!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Qualifies as a classic Greek tragedy.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    zjerunk
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/7/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I have many favorites, and this is one of the cr&egrave;me de la cr&egrave;me. This is a visually stunning film more like beautiful photographic montage. It is simple, tragic story well told, unlike many of today's plots - implausibly lame, suffering on a CGI crutch for 85 minutes. The simple story is about enduring truths which have been the mainstay of the Greek classics and Shakespeare: Our human strengths, our failings, our virtues, and our vices. The story may be a fiction, but its kernel is not. It is stories and story telling like this which has kept our rapt attention for four thousand years. First we should understand that this film is only the first half the novel by Marcel Pagnol which would have been too long as a single film, and out of necessity, was shot as two. The second half is titled, Manon of the Spring. Neither film stands alone as satisfactory because, obviously, it would be incomplete, and naturally, is also important that the two halves be viewed in sequence. For a fairly dispassionate pr&eacute;cis of the plots, I suggest reading the ones on Wikipedia, so I won't be repetitive here. I also recommend reading the boards for comments and discussions. JdF & MotS were both shot at the same time in 1986 with a budget of $17 million making it/them the biggest budget French films up to that time. JdF grossed $86M worldwide, and of that sum, only $4.9M was from the USA. MotS grossed $56M worldwide, of which only $3.9M was from the USA. In other words, culture films are not a good fit for the American viewing audience, and the gross revenue numbers bear this out. The rest of the world seems to bear out this conclusion. Foreign language films rarely do well in the USA for the simple reason that the vast majority of the viewing audience are unilingual anglophones who do not wish to burden themselves with having to work at "understanding" their entertainment - they wish to merely consume it. If it requires the work of reading subtitles or thought, it becomes unpalatable. This film requires your attention and thought! But to be fair to the US viewers, the subtitles are at times incomplete or inaccurate, and unlike the spoken word, they do not convey the emphasis or importance of certain bits of dialogue well. The plot is woven steadily throughout the film, so the viewers with no understanding at all of the French language are missing essential dialogue, and therefore plot. The bottom line is this: You will either be entranced by these two films and love them, or you will be bored by the first 15 minutes, and you'll translate that into "bad film." If your highest quality level of reading is Marvel comics then I suggest you stay away from this one. However, I recall years ago walking into a video store where this was playing on all the monitors. All the patrons in the store, ranging in age from 5 to 75 years, were standing transfixed watching this film. There was something magical about it!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Agonising; enrapturing and taut all-at-once period piece, detailing the struggles of two sets of farm-set family units at evens and odds with one another.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    johnnyboyz (j_l_h_m@yahoo.co.uk)
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/1/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Has farming, indeed agriculture in general, ever been as cinematic as it is in Claude Berri's Jean de Florette? The joy is in observing the rather articulate nuances that the characters must undertake when particular farming tasks require particular tools and items for a job at hand; the film eventually coming to resemble a tale about a man most probably as alien to farming as the audience and enjoying it as much as we enjoy watching his taking up of this challenge. The farming within the film, in its specificities revolving around the planning; the predicting; the techniques and the use of certain items and animals for certain events, is as intrinsic as the film's core study of greed and the capitalist infused garnering of an industrial item, an item which will bring large amounts of personal wealth and riches, eventually at the expense of others. The film eventually coming to form a remarkably executed, heart breakingly tragic, blackly comic, devilishly well put together period drama from France well worth checking out. The film begins with a young man named Ugolin (Auteuil) returning home to the South of France, and his uncle's farm, having served time with the French army; the soundtrack a dry and sleepy orchestral tune suggesting much in the way of travels and tiredness, only momentarily breaking off into louder bursts of a much more positive tone as he nears home. Upon arriving home, Ugolin takes clear glee in rushing to a small patch of soil on the grounds and unwrapping a plant of some kind so he may observe it; something he appears to enjoy more than being reconciled with his uncle after such a stretch of time and furthermore suggesting an inclination towards agricultural work, his dream eventually revealed to be one of which revolves around the growing and selling of flowers for a living. His uncle is Cesar (Montand), an elderly man whom demands Ugolin find a wife and have children in the near future so that the land may be passed down and kept within the family; his other eye on a stretch of land lying nearby to his own, a stretch functional enough as it stands and with a natural spring beneath it capable of escalating the quality of the goods that only Cesar knows of, but a stretch already owned by a man no way willing to just sell up. Berri spends a good deal of time with these two farmers, their dreams; their positions and their core characteristics filling up most of the film's opening act. We come to like them during this early part and their blackly funny misadventures as well as their dry observations on life and newfound situations which open up as a result of other events. We side with young Ugolin, this simple young man whom has only just returned from national service and wishes to move into floristry. It is only when the titular Jean of Florette arrives, in the form of G&eacute;rard Depardieu, that we see the true nature of them; Jean being the rightful heir to that of the land when Cesar and Ugolin accidentally-on-purpose murder the owner of the land thus bringing Jean into the equation following a string of other legal complications with the rightful land owner. Jean and his family of wife Aimee (Elisabeth Depardieu) and young daughter Manon (Mazurowna) are not used to such surroundings; their previous incarnation of living in a more urbanite locale ill preparing them for what they come into contact with here, the beauty and calmness of the locale coming to resemble mere surface featurettes as those within plot and brew. The obvious distinctions between themselves and those more attributed to the land arrive in the form of their clear differences in clothing, as well as their talk of things of a more cultured nature, namely the opera, as on occasion Aimee breaks out int chorus of song to Jean's own harmonica tunes. What unfolds is a game of cat and mouse and hope and frustration between the two farmers, in Ugolin and Cesar, and the Florettes whom hang around much to the annoyance of their neighbours whom still want the land, know of its true flourishing nature and retain the spring as their secret. Jean's gradual coming around to realise how wondrous and how magnificent the locale is, and how enthralling the individual tasks and procedures which make up farming echoes our own coming around to feel similarly towards the film. Just as agricultural activity is fresh to that of Jean, the arrival of he and his family acts as a fresh and very crisp presence within the film to that of the audience; the very gradual bringing of the audience around on Berri's behalf to have us see the two original farmers as cruel and calculating businessmen as this initial outsider and his family capture our hearts, is outstanding. The film is a really well executed drama, a wonderful piece persistently flicking from tone to tone and character to character in perfect tandem; a film working on a level of family drama, fish out of water storytelling and dark comedy culminating in something quite special.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Enjoy the wonderful surroundings and relax
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Luigi Di Pilla
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The surroundings near Aubagne in the Bouche Du Rh&ocirc;ne in France are wonderfully shot. The story by Marcel Pagnol is well adapted that takes step by step a dramatic end. All the actors did a fine Job and I am curious to see part two "Manon La Source". The sceneries in the time after the second world war are well built and developed. I recommend you to watch it in the original south french dialect with English subtitles. I spent an enjoyable and relaxing Saturday night with my wife. Don't miss the other great movie from the writer Pagnol called La Fille Du Pusatier. Please read my critic on IMDb. Final vote: 8/10.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Flawless
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    yeltzmanmatt
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is a beautifully told tale of a hunchback who moves from the town to the country when he inherits a farm. The cinematography is brilliant and the languid pace of the movie suits this perfectly. The acting is out of the top drawer especially from Yves Montand and Daniel Autiel who are mesmerising as the farmers intent on grabbing Gerard Depardieu's land. Depardieu is also in fine form as the hunchback who although bombastic and stubborn eventually evokes a deal of sympathy. It is hard to fault this film on any level and it absorbs you from the start to the finale. Although you can watch the film on it's own the subsequent Manon Des Sources ( another fine film) concludes the story in full. I have known a fair few people who don't like foreign language films who have watched this and every one has enjoyed it. This is a French classic not to be missed.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Rare gem.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    (Draco2-0)
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I just watched Jean De Florrete and it was great, very rare for me to say this but I was not once bored or restless during the entire movie. Jean De Florrete, about this French farmer who moves onto his uncle's land and decides it would be profitable to grow flowers. But in order to grow a enough flowers to make a profit they'll need more water than they have available. Their neighbor has an untapped underground spring. The farmer and his uncle go over to negotiate buying the land with the spring on it. Unfortunately for them their neighbor hates the uncle, and when they offer to buy some of his land the uncle and him get into a fight and during the bustle his head suffers a fatal blow against a rock and he dies almost instantaneously. The whole ordeal took place by a tree, so the farmer and his uncle make it look like the old man fell from the tree and hit his head. They think the land will be theirs but a relative of the neighbor, a hunchback, moves onto the property. The uncle offers to buy the land from him but the hunchback wants to use it for raising rabbits and growing squash. Fascinating to watch the triumphs and failures of the hunchback as he goes about trying to fulfill his dream, always with a happy upbeat attitude. The thing that amazed me about the movie would be just how simple the actual plot feels. There are no huge twists, no distracting sub-plots, not much happens for most of the movie until the last 15 minutes; despite that it manages to grab the viewers attention wonderfully and it doesn't let it go until the credits roll either. Unless you hate French movies. I highly recommend Jean De Floret.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Jean de Florette / Manon of the Spring
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    runamokprods
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/7/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Two part film, that was 1st released as two separate features. Terrific telling of a complex story of intertwined farming families in rural France in the early part of the 20th century. The acting is mostly of the highest order. Yves Montand, one of the most suave men in history is completely believable as a rough hewn, self-centered farmer, Gerard Depardieu, also cast against type, as a gentle, educated city born man trying to make it as a farmer also is astounding. Almost as good is Daniel Auteuil as Montand's not-very-bright son. Only Emmanuelle Beart, gorgeous though she may be, doesn't quite convince me as the wild woman of the fields. Some of it is performance, some of it is how perfect she looks. The story is wonderful in a Dickensian sort of way, with clues and character elements showing up early, only to pay off three hours later. I love the first part even more, somehow it feels more truly tragic and dense, the 2nd part just a bit too neat by the end. But still a grand, intelligent, great looking entertainment.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "Remarkably narrated and invariably moving..."
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Sindre Kaspersen
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/3/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    French actor, producer, screenwriter and director Claude Berri's twelfth feature film which he co-wrote with French screenwriter G&eacute;rard Brach (1927-2006) is an adaptation of a novel, "L'Eau des Collines - Jean de Florette and Manon des Sources" (1964) by French author, playwright and filmmaker Marcel Pagnol (1895-1974), which was inspired by true events. It was shot on numerous locations in the Vaucluse department of Provence in the southeast of France and is part of a duology which was succeeded by "Manon des Sources" (1986). It tells the story about Ugolin Soubeyran who one summer after having served his time in World War I returns to his home in rural Provence where he is welcomed by his highly revered uncle Cesar Le Papet Soubeyran. Back at his home place in the highlands, Ugolin initiates a planned project which involves growing plants, but soon discovers that he is going to need a water resource to keep his enterprise afloat. He let's Papet in on his new activity and the old man is eager to help his nephew, but his good intentions get's the better of him and leads to fatal consequences. Though having their plan ruined they are dead set on finding a way to gain their obstacle, so when a man from the village named Jean Cadoret moves in to his newly inherited property with his wife Aim&egrave;e and their adolescent daughter Manon, the two farmers decides to mislead him. Subtly and acutely directed by French filmmaker Claude Berri (1934-2009) and with it's ardent and naturalistic milieu depictions and efficient narrative structure, this historic period piece, at the time the most expensive French film in French history, draws a throughout engaging portrayal of a kind-hearted and loving husband and father with an urban background who whilst struggling to create a good life for himself and his family in a rural area at the turn of the twentieth century, becomes a victim of deception and prejudice. This mid-1980s co-production between France, Italy and Switzerland, known as part of a movement in France during the 1980s called "heritage cinema" which mainly consisted of costume dramas, has a powerful score by French composer and arranger Jean-Claude Petit, based on Italian composer Giuseppe Verdi's Italian opera "The Force of Destiny" (1862), which reinforces the films pivotal atmosphere. Produced by French producers Pierre Grunstein and Alain Poir&eacute; (1917-2000) and notable for it's wonderful production design by production designer Bernard V&eacute;zat and cinematography by French director and cinematographer Bruno Nuytten, this character-driven and dialog-driven countryside epic which examines themes like interpersonal relations, greed, faith and the distinctions between human goodness and human cruelty is impelled by the splendid acting performances by French actor and producer G&eacute;rard Depardieu, Italian-born French actor and singer Yves Montand (1921-1991) and French actor, director and screenwriter Daniel Auteuil. A remarkably narrated and invariably moving drama which gained, among several other awards, the BAFTA Film Award for Best Film, Best cinematography Bruno Nuytten, Best Adapted Screenplay Claude Berri and G&eacute;rard Brach and Best Supporting Actor Daniel Auteuil at the 41st British Academy Film Awards in 1988, the NBR Award for Best Foreign Language Film at the National Board of Review of Motion Pictures Awards in 1987 and the C&eacute;sar Award for Best Actor Daniel Auteuil at the 13th C&eacute;sar Awards in 1987.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Slow but beautiful
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    billcr12
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Gerard Depardieu is Jean de Florette, a simple, hard working landowner and farmer who grows and sells flowers and also raises rabbits for food. Some of Jean's neighbors would like to buy his land but Jean refuses to sell to them. They then find the main spring nearby and plug it with cement to prevent water from reaching the farm. Jean has to travel a good distance to carry large containers to his farm. He later gets badly injured and they take advantage of the situation quickly. This is a simple and slow moving drama which looks like a painting come to life. It is followed by the equally masterful "Manon of the Spring."
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    J'adore!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    TheLittleSongbird
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Having been so blown away by Cyrano De Bergerac, I also watched Jean De Florette, also starring Gerard Depardieu. Jean De Florette is a very different film, but every bit as fantastic. Depardieu is very endearing in a performance that has in his career only been surpassed by Cyrano De Bergerac to me. Yves Montand and Daniel Auteuil are also outstanding as the scheming Soubeyrans. The acting is not Jean De Florette's only good asset. This is an example of a film where everything works. The story is beautifully paced and evocative, the script is witty and very cinematic, the cinematography shimmers, the scenery is breathtaking, the music is lively yet again very understated and the direction does wonderfully in capturing the pace of the seasons changing and Provence's unique atmosphere. All in all, I love this movie just as much as Cyrano De Bergerac, and I am watching Manon of the Spring(and loving it) even as we speak. 10/10 Bethany Cox
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A personal all-time favorite
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    olyrye
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/12/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is an epic film(s). (It must really be seen with Manon of the Spring, which is not a sequel but really the second part of the movie.) The photography, music, acting, writing, are top notch. A must see for any film buff. Full of eye and ear candy! It really stirred an emotional response in me, especially at the end. So many great movies flounder at the conclusion. This one delivers! It deals with the themes of family loyalty, miscommunication, love, betrayal, failure, and persistence in the face of catastrophe. But most importantly it deals with almost impossible redemption. This is a great movie to watch with your spouse or partner. It is equally appealing to both men and women and is a great film for a movie date!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Qualifies as a classic Greek tragedy.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    zjerunk
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/7/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I have many favorites, and this is one of the cr&egrave;me de la cr&egrave;me. This is a visually stunning film more like beautiful photographic montage. It is simple, tragic story well told, unlike many of today's plots - implausibly lame, suffering on a CGI crutch for 85 minutes. The simple story is about enduring truths which have been the mainstay of the Greek classics and Shakespeare: Our human strengths, our failings, our virtues, and our vices. The story may be a fiction, but its kernel is not. It is stories and story telling like this which has kept our rapt attention for four thousand years. First we should understand that this film is only the first half the novel by Marcel Pagnol which would have been too long as a single film, and out of necessity, was shot as two. The second half is titled, Manon of the Spring. Neither film stands alone as satisfactory because, obviously, it would be incomplete, and naturally, is also important that the two halves be viewed in sequence. For a fairly dispassionate pr&eacute;cis of the plots, I suggest reading the ones on Wikipedia, so I won't be repetitive here. I also recommend reading the boards for comments and discussions. JdF & MotS were both shot at the same time in 1986 with a budget of $17 million making it/them the biggest budget French films up to that time. JdF grossed $86M worldwide, and of that sum, only $4.9M was from the USA. MotS grossed $56M worldwide, of which only $3.9M was from the USA. In other words, culture films are not a good fit for the American viewing audience, and the gross revenue numbers bear this out. The rest of the world seems to bear out this conclusion. Foreign language films rarely do well in the USA for the simple reason that the vast majority of the viewing audience are unilingual anglophones who do not wish to burden themselves with having to work at "understanding" their entertainment - they wish to merely consume it. If it requires the work of reading subtitles or thought, it becomes unpalatable. This film requires your attention and thought! But to be fair to the US viewers, the subtitles are at times incomplete or inaccurate, and unlike the spoken word, they do not convey the emphasis or importance of certain bits of dialogue well. The plot is woven steadily throughout the film, so the viewers with no understanding at all of the French language are missing essential dialogue, and therefore plot. The bottom line is this: You will either be entranced by these two films and love them, or you will be bored by the first 15 minutes, and you'll translate that into "bad film." If your highest quality level of reading is Marvel comics then I suggest you stay away from this one. However, I recall years ago walking into a video store where this was playing on all the monitors. All the patrons in the store, ranging in age from 5 to 75 years, were standing transfixed watching this film. There was something magical about it!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Agonising; enrapturing and taut all-at-once period piece, detailing the struggles of two sets of farm-set family units at evens and odds with one another.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    johnnyboyz (j_l_h_m@yahoo.co.uk)
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/1/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Has farming, indeed agriculture in general, ever been as cinematic as it is in Claude Berri's Jean de Florette? The joy is in observing the rather articulate nuances that the characters must undertake when particular farming tasks require particular tools and items for a job at hand; the film eventually coming to resemble a tale about a man most probably as alien to farming as the audience and enjoying it as much as we enjoy watching his taking up of this challenge. The farming within the film, in its specificities revolving around the planning; the predicting; the techniques and the use of certain items and animals for certain events, is as intrinsic as the film's core study of greed and the capitalist infused garnering of an industrial item, an item which will bring large amounts of personal wealth and riches, eventually at the expense of others. The film eventually coming to form a remarkably executed, heart breakingly tragic, blackly comic, devilishly well put together period drama from France well worth checking out. The film begins with a young man named Ugolin (Auteuil) returning home to the South of France, and his uncle's farm, having served time with the French army; the soundtrack a dry and sleepy orchestral tune suggesting much in the way of travels and tiredness, only momentarily breaking off into louder bursts of a much more positive tone as he nears home. Upon arriving home, Ugolin takes clear glee in rushing to a small patch of soil on the grounds and unwrapping a plant of some kind so he may observe it; something he appears to enjoy more than being reconciled with his uncle after such a stretch of time and furthermore suggesting an inclination towards agricultural work, his dream eventually revealed to be one of which revolves around the growing and selling of flowers for a living. His uncle is Cesar (Montand), an elderly man whom demands Ugolin find a wife and have children in the near future so that the land may be passed down and kept within the family; his other eye on a stretch of land lying nearby to his own, a stretch functional enough as it stands and with a natural spring beneath it capable of escalating the quality of the goods that only Cesar knows of, but a stretch already owned by a man no way willing to just sell up. Berri spends a good deal of time with these two farmers, their dreams; their positions and their core characteristics filling up most of the film's opening act. We come to like them during this early part and their blackly funny misadventures as well as their dry observations on life and newfound situations which open up as a result of other events. We side with young Ugolin, this simple young man whom has only just returned from national service and wishes to move into floristry. It is only when the titular Jean of Florette arrives, in the form of G&eacute;rard Depardieu, that we see the true nature of them; Jean being the rightful heir to that of the land when Cesar and Ugolin accidentally-on-purpose murder the owner of the land thus bringing Jean into the equation following a string of other legal complications with the rightful land owner. Jean and his family of wife Aimee (Elisabeth Depardieu) and young daughter Manon (Mazurowna) are not used to such surroundings; their previous incarnation of living in a more urbanite locale ill preparing them for what they come into contact with here, the beauty and calmness of the locale coming to resemble mere surface featurettes as those within plot and brew. The obvious distinctions between themselves and those more attributed to the land arrive in the form of their clear differences in clothing, as well as their talk of things of a more cultured nature, namely the opera, as on occasion Aimee breaks out int chorus of song to Jean's own harmonica tunes. What unfolds is a game of cat and mouse and hope and frustration between the two farmers, in Ugolin and Cesar, and the Florettes whom hang around much to the annoyance of their neighbours whom still want the land, know of its true flourishing nature and retain the spring as their secret. Jean's gradual coming around to realise how wondrous and how magnificent the locale is, and how enthralling the individual tasks and procedures which make up farming echoes our own coming around to feel similarly towards the film. Just as agricultural activity is fresh to that of Jean, the arrival of he and his family acts as a fresh and very crisp presence within the film to that of the audience; the very gradual bringing of the audience around on Berri's behalf to have us see the two original farmers as cruel and calculating businessmen as this initial outsider and his family capture our hearts, is outstanding. The film is a really well executed drama, a wonderful piece persistently flicking from tone to tone and character to character in perfect tandem; a film working on a level of family drama, fish out of water storytelling and dark comedy culminating in something quite special.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Enjoy the wonderful surroundings and relax
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Luigi Di Pilla
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The surroundings near Aubagne in the Bouche Du Rh&ocirc;ne in France are wonderfully shot. The story by Marcel Pagnol is well adapted that takes step by step a dramatic end. All the actors did a fine Job and I am curious to see part two "Manon La Source". The sceneries in the time after the second world war are well built and developed. I recommend you to watch it in the original south french dialect with English subtitles. I spent an enjoyable and relaxing Saturday night with my wife. Don't miss the other great movie from the writer Pagnol called La Fille Du Pusatier. Please read my critic on IMDb. Final vote: 8/10.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Flawless
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    yeltzmanmatt
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is a beautifully told tale of a hunchback who moves from the town to the country when he inherits a farm. The cinematography is brilliant and the languid pace of the movie suits this perfectly. The acting is out of the top drawer especially from Yves Montand and Daniel Autiel who are mesmerising as the farmers intent on grabbing Gerard Depardieu's land. Depardieu is also in fine form as the hunchback who although bombastic and stubborn eventually evokes a deal of sympathy. It is hard to fault this film on any level and it absorbs you from the start to the finale. Although you can watch the film on it's own the subsequent Manon Des Sources ( another fine film) concludes the story in full. I have known a fair few people who don't like foreign language films who have watched this and every one has enjoyed it. This is a French classic not to be missed.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Rare gem.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    (Draco2-0)
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I just watched Jean De Florrete and it was great, very rare for me to say this but I was not once bored or restless during the entire movie. Jean De Florrete, about this French farmer who moves onto his uncle's land and decides it would be profitable to grow flowers. But in order to grow a enough flowers to make a profit they'll need more water than they have available. Their neighbor has an untapped underground spring. The farmer and his uncle go over to negotiate buying the land with the spring on it. Unfortunately for them their neighbor hates the uncle, and when they offer to buy some of his land the uncle and him get into a fight and during the bustle his head suffers a fatal blow against a rock and he dies almost instantaneously. The whole ordeal took place by a tree, so the farmer and his uncle make it look like the old man fell from the tree and hit his head. They think the land will be theirs but a relative of the neighbor, a hunchback, moves onto the property. The uncle offers to buy the land from him but the hunchback wants to use it for raising rabbits and growing squash. Fascinating to watch the triumphs and failures of the hunchback as he goes about trying to fulfill his dream, always with a happy upbeat attitude. The thing that amazed me about the movie would be just how simple the actual plot feels. There are no huge twists, no distracting sub-plots, not much happens for most of the movie until the last 15 minutes; despite that it manages to grab the viewers attention wonderfully and it doesn't let it go until the credits roll either. Unless you hate French movies. I highly recommend Jean De Floret.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Jean de Florette / Manon of the Spring
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    runamokprods
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/7/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Two part film, that was 1st released as two separate features. Terrific telling of a complex story of intertwined farming families in rural France in the early part of the 20th century. The acting is mostly of the highest order. Yves Montand, one of the most suave men in history is completely believable as a rough hewn, self-centered farmer, Gerard Depardieu, also cast against type, as a gentle, educated city born man trying to make it as a farmer also is astounding. Almost as good is Daniel Auteuil as Montand's not-very-bright son. Only Emmanuelle Beart, gorgeous though she may be, doesn't quite convince me as the wild woman of the fields. Some of it is performance, some of it is how perfect she looks. The story is wonderful in a Dickensian sort of way, with clues and character elements showing up early, only to pay off three hours later. I love the first part even more, somehow it feels more truly tragic and dense, the 2nd part just a bit too neat by the end. But still a grand, intelligent, great looking entertainment.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "Remarkably narrated and invariably moving..."
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Sindre Kaspersen
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/3/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    French actor, producer, screenwriter and director Claude Berri's twelfth feature film which he co-wrote with French screenwriter G&eacute;rard Brach (1927-2006) is an adaptation of a novel, "L'Eau des Collines - Jean de Florette and Manon des Sources" (1964) by French author, playwright and filmmaker Marcel Pagnol (1895-1974), which was inspired by true events. It was shot on numerous locations in the Vaucluse department of Provence in the southeast of France and is part of a duology which was succeeded by "Manon des Sources" (1986). It tells the story about Ugolin Soubeyran who one summer after having served his time in World War I returns to his home in rural Provence where he is welcomed by his highly revered uncle Cesar Le Papet Soubeyran. Back at his home place in the highlands, Ugolin initiates a planned project which involves growing plants, but soon discovers that he is going to need a water resource to keep his enterprise afloat. He let's Papet in on his new activity and the old man is eager to help his nephew, but his good intentions get's the better of him and leads to fatal consequences. Though having their plan ruined they are dead set on finding a way to gain their obstacle, so when a man from the village named Jean Cadoret moves in to his newly inherited property with his wife Aim&egrave;e and their adolescent daughter Manon, the two farmers decides to mislead him. Subtly and acutely directed by French filmmaker Claude Berri (1934-2009) and with it's ardent and naturalistic milieu depictions and efficient narrative structure, this historic period piece, at the time the most expensive French film in French history, draws a throughout engaging portrayal of a kind-hearted and loving husband and father with an urban background who whilst struggling to create a good life for himself and his family in a rural area at the turn of the twentieth century, becomes a victim of deception and prejudice. This mid-1980s co-production between France, Italy and Switzerland, known as part of a movement in France during the 1980s called "heritage cinema" which mainly consisted of costume dramas, has a powerful score by French composer and arranger Jean-Claude Petit, based on Italian composer Giuseppe Verdi's Italian opera "The Force of Destiny" (1862), which reinforces the films pivotal atmosphere. Produced by French producers Pierre Grunstein and Alain Poir&eacute; (1917-2000) and notable for it's wonderful production design by production designer Bernard V&eacute;zat and cinematography by French director and cinematographer Bruno Nuytten, this character-driven and dialog-driven countryside epic which examines themes like interpersonal relations, greed, faith and the distinctions between human goodness and human cruelty is impelled by the splendid acting performances by French actor and producer G&eacute;rard Depardieu, Italian-born French actor and singer Yves Montand (1921-1991) and French actor, director and screenwriter Daniel Auteuil. A remarkably narrated and invariably moving drama which gained, among several other awards, the BAFTA Film Award for Best Film, Best cinematography Bruno Nuytten, Best Adapted Screenplay Claude Berri and G&eacute;rard Brach and Best Supporting Actor Daniel Auteuil at the 41st British Academy Film Awards in 1988, the NBR Award for Best Foreign Language Film at the National Board of Review of Motion Pictures Awards in 1987 and the C&eacute;sar Award for Best Actor Daniel Auteuil at the 13th C&eacute;sar Awards in 1987.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Slow but beautiful
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    billcr12
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Gerard Depardieu is Jean de Florette, a simple, hard working landowner and farmer who grows and sells flowers and also raises rabbits for food. Some of Jean's neighbors would like to buy his land but Jean refuses to sell to them. They then find the main spring nearby and plug it with cement to prevent water from reaching the farm. Jean has to travel a good distance to carry large containers to his farm. He later gets badly injured and they take advantage of the situation quickly. This is a simple and slow moving drama which looks like a painting come to life. It is followed by the equally masterful "Manon of the Spring."
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    J'adore!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    TheLittleSongbird
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Having been so blown away by Cyrano De Bergerac, I also watched Jean De Florette, also starring Gerard Depardieu. Jean De Florette is a very different film, but every bit as fantastic. Depardieu is very endearing in a performance that has in his career only been surpassed by Cyrano De Bergerac to me. Yves Montand and Daniel Auteuil are also outstanding as the scheming Soubeyrans. The acting is not Jean De Florette's only good asset. This is an example of a film where everything works. The story is beautifully paced and evocative, the script is witty and very cinematic, the cinematography shimmers, the scenery is breathtaking, the music is lively yet again very understated and the direction does wonderfully in capturing the pace of the seasons changing and Provence's unique atmosphere. All in all, I love this movie just as much as Cyrano De Bergerac, and I am watching Manon of the Spring(and loving it) even as we speak. 10/10 Bethany Cox
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A personal all-time favorite
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    olyrye
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/12/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is an epic film(s). (It must really be seen with Manon of the Spring, which is not a sequel but really the second part of the movie.) The photography, music, acting, writing, are top notch. A must see for any film buff. Full of eye and ear candy! It really stirred an emotional response in me, especially at the end. So many great movies flounder at the conclusion. This one delivers! It deals with the themes of family loyalty, miscommunication, love, betrayal, failure, and persistence in the face of catastrophe. But most importantly it deals with almost impossible redemption. This is a great movie to watch with your spouse or partner. It is equally appealing to both men and women and is a great film for a movie date!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Qualifies as a classic Greek tragedy.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    zjerunk
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/7/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I have many favorites, and this is one of the cr&egrave;me de la cr&egrave;me. This is a visually stunning film more like beautiful photographic montage. It is simple, tragic story well told, unlike many of today's plots - implausibly lame, suffering on a CGI crutch for 85 minutes. The simple story is about enduring truths which have been the mainstay of the Greek classics and Shakespeare: Our human strengths, our failings, our virtues, and our vices. The story may be a fiction, but its kernel is not. It is stories and story telling like this which has kept our rapt attention for four thousand years. First we should understand that this film is only the first half the novel by Marcel Pagnol which would have been too long as a single film, and out of necessity, was shot as two. The second half is titled, Manon of the Spring. Neither film stands alone as satisfactory because, obviously, it would be incomplete, and naturally, is also important that the two halves be viewed in sequence. For a fairly dispassionate pr&eacute;cis of the plots, I suggest reading the ones on Wikipedia, so I won't be repetitive here. I also recommend reading the boards for comments and discussions. JdF & MotS were both shot at the same time in 1986 with a budget of $17 million making it/them the biggest budget French films up to that time. JdF grossed $86M worldwide, and of that sum, only $4.9M was from the USA. MotS grossed $56M worldwide, of which only $3.9M was from the USA. In other words, culture films are not a good fit for the American viewing audience, and the gross revenue numbers bear this out. The rest of the world seems to bear out this conclusion. Foreign language films rarely do well in the USA for the simple reason that the vast majority of the viewing audience are unilingual anglophones who do not wish to burden themselves with having to work at "understanding" their entertainment - they wish to merely consume it. If it requires the work of reading subtitles or thought, it becomes unpalatable. This film requires your attention and thought! But to be fair to the US viewers, the subtitles are at times incomplete or inaccurate, and unlike the spoken word, they do not convey the emphasis or importance of certain bits of dialogue well. The plot is woven steadily throughout the film, so the viewers with no understanding at all of the French language are missing essential dialogue, and therefore plot. The bottom line is this: You will either be entranced by these two films and love them, or you will be bored by the first 15 minutes, and you'll translate that into "bad film." If your highest quality level of reading is Marvel comics then I suggest you stay away from this one. However, I recall years ago walking into a video store where this was playing on all the monitors. All the patrons in the store, ranging in age from 5 to 75 years, were standing transfixed watching this film. There was something magical about it!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Agonising; enrapturing and taut all-at-once period piece, detailing the struggles of two sets of farm-set family units at evens and odds with one another.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    johnnyboyz (j_l_h_m@yahoo.co.uk)
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/1/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Has farming, indeed agriculture in general, ever been as cinematic as it is in Claude Berri's Jean de Florette? The joy is in observing the rather articulate nuances that the characters must undertake when particular farming tasks require particular tools and items for a job at hand; the film eventually coming to resemble a tale about a man most probably as alien to farming as the audience and enjoying it as much as we enjoy watching his taking up of this challenge. The farming within the film, in its specificities revolving around the planning; the predicting; the techniques and the use of certain items and animals for certain events, is as intrinsic as the film's core study of greed and the capitalist infused garnering of an industrial item, an item which will bring large amounts of personal wealth and riches, eventually at the expense of others. The film eventually coming to form a remarkably executed, heart breakingly tragic, blackly comic, devilishly well put together period drama from France well worth checking out. The film begins with a young man named Ugolin (Auteuil) returning home to the South of France, and his uncle's farm, having served time with the French army; the soundtrack a dry and sleepy orchestral tune suggesting much in the way of travels and tiredness, only momentarily breaking off into louder bursts of a much more positive tone as he nears home. Upon arriving home, Ugolin takes clear glee in rushing to a small patch of soil on the grounds and unwrapping a plant of some kind so he may observe it; something he appears to enjoy more than being reconciled with his uncle after such a stretch of time and furthermore suggesting an inclination towards agricultural work, his dream eventually revealed to be one of which revolves around the growing and selling of flowers for a living. His uncle is Cesar (Montand), an elderly man whom demands Ugolin find a wife and have children in the near future so that the land may be passed down and kept within the family; his other eye on a stretch of land lying nearby to his own, a stretch functional enough as it stands and with a natural spring beneath it capable of escalating the quality of the goods that only Cesar knows of, but a stretch already owned by a man no way willing to just sell up. Berri spends a good deal of time with these two farmers, their dreams; their positions and their core characteristics filling up most of the film's opening act. We come to like them during this early part and their blackly funny misadventures as well as their dry observations on life and newfound situations which open up as a result of other events. We side with young Ugolin, this simple young man whom has only just returned from national service and wishes to move into floristry. It is only when the titular Jean of Florette arrives, in the form of G&eacute;rard Depardieu, that we see the true nature of them; Jean being the rightful heir to that of the land when Cesar and Ugolin accidentally-on-purpose murder the owner of the land thus bringing Jean into the equation following a string of other legal complications with the rightful land owner. Jean and his family of wife Aimee (Elisabeth Depardieu) and young daughter Manon (Mazurowna) are not used to such surroundings; their previous incarnation of living in a more urbanite locale ill preparing them for what they come into contact with here, the beauty and calmness of the locale coming to resemble mere surface featurettes as those within plot and brew. The obvious distinctions between themselves and those more attributed to the land arrive in the form of their clear differences in clothing, as well as their talk of things of a more cultured nature, namely the opera, as on occasion Aimee breaks out int chorus of song to Jean's own harmonica tunes. What unfolds is a game of cat and mouse and hope and frustration between the two farmers, in Ugolin and Cesar, and the Florettes whom hang around much to the annoyance of their neighbours whom still want the land, know of its true flourishing nature and retain the spring as their secret. Jean's gradual coming around to realise how wondrous and how magnificent the locale is, and how enthralling the individual tasks and procedures which make up farming echoes our own coming around to feel similarly towards the film. Just as agricultural activity is fresh to that of Jean, the arrival of he and his family acts as a fresh and very crisp presence within the film to that of the audience; the very gradual bringing of the audience around on Berri's behalf to have us see the two original farmers as cruel and calculating businessmen as this initial outsider and his family capture our hearts, is outstanding. The film is a really well executed drama, a wonderful piece persistently flicking from tone to tone and character to character in perfect tandem; a film working on a level of family drama, fish out of water storytelling and dark comedy culminating in something quite special.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Enjoy the wonderful surroundings and relax
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Luigi Di Pilla
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The surroundings near Aubagne in the Bouche Du Rh&ocirc;ne in France are wonderfully shot. The story by Marcel Pagnol is well adapted that takes step by step a dramatic end. All the actors did a fine Job and I am curious to see part two "Manon La Source". The sceneries in the time after the second world war are well built and developed. I recommend you to watch it in the original south french dialect with English subtitles. I spent an enjoyable and relaxing Saturday night with my wife. Don't miss the other great movie from the writer Pagnol called La Fille Du Pusatier. Please read my critic on IMDb. Final vote: 8/10.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Flawless
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    yeltzmanmatt
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is a beautifully told tale of a hunchback who moves from the town to the country when he inherits a farm. The cinematography is brilliant and the languid pace of the movie suits this perfectly. The acting is out of the top drawer especially from Yves Montand and Daniel Autiel who are mesmerising as the farmers intent on grabbing Gerard Depardieu's land. Depardieu is also in fine form as the hunchback who although bombastic and stubborn eventually evokes a deal of sympathy. It is hard to fault this film on any level and it absorbs you from the start to the finale. Although you can watch the film on it's own the subsequent Manon Des Sources ( another fine film) concludes the story in full. I have known a fair few people who don't like foreign language films who have watched this and every one has enjoyed it. This is a French classic not to be missed.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Rare gem.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    (Draco2-0)
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I just watched Jean De Florrete and it was great, very rare for me to say this but I was not once bored or restless during the entire movie. Jean De Florrete, about this French farmer who moves onto his uncle's land and decides it would be profitable to grow flowers. But in order to grow a enough flowers to make a profit they'll need more water than they have available. Their neighbor has an untapped underground spring. The farmer and his uncle go over to negotiate buying the land with the spring on it. Unfortunately for them their neighbor hates the uncle, and when they offer to buy some of his land the uncle and him get into a fight and during the bustle his head suffers a fatal blow against a rock and he dies almost instantaneously. The whole ordeal took place by a tree, so the farmer and his uncle make it look like the old man fell from the tree and hit his head. They think the land will be theirs but a relative of the neighbor, a hunchback, moves onto the property. The uncle offers to buy the land from him but the hunchback wants to use it for raising rabbits and growing squash. Fascinating to watch the triumphs and failures of the hunchback as he goes about trying to fulfill his dream, always with a happy upbeat attitude. The thing that amazed me about the movie would be just how simple the actual plot feels. There are no huge twists, no distracting sub-plots, not much happens for most of the movie until the last 15 minutes; despite that it manages to grab the viewers attention wonderfully and it doesn't let it go until the credits roll either. Unless you hate French movies. I highly recommend Jean De Floret.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Jean de Florette / Manon of the Spring
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    runamokprods
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/7/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Two part film, that was 1st released as two separate features. Terrific telling of a complex story of intertwined farming families in rural France in the early part of the 20th century. The acting is mostly of the highest order. Yves Montand, one of the most suave men in history is completely believable as a rough hewn, self-centered farmer, Gerard Depardieu, also cast against type, as a gentle, educated city born man trying to make it as a farmer also is astounding. Almost as good is Daniel Auteuil as Montand's not-very-bright son. Only Emmanuelle Beart, gorgeous though she may be, doesn't quite convince me as the wild woman of the fields. Some of it is performance, some of it is how perfect she looks. The story is wonderful in a Dickensian sort of way, with clues and character elements showing up early, only to pay off three hours later. I love the first part even more, somehow it feels more truly tragic and dense, the 2nd part just a bit too neat by the end. But still a grand, intelligent, great looking entertainment.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "Remarkably narrated and invariably moving..."
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Sindre Kaspersen
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/3/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    French actor, producer, screenwriter and director Claude Berri's twelfth feature film which he co-wrote with French screenwriter G&eacute;rard Brach (1927-2006) is an adaptation of a novel, "L'Eau des Collines - Jean de Florette and Manon des Sources" (1964) by French author, playwright and filmmaker Marcel Pagnol (1895-1974), which was inspired by true events. It was shot on numerous locations in the Vaucluse department of Provence in the southeast of France and is part of a duology which was succeeded by "Manon des Sources" (1986). It tells the story about Ugolin Soubeyran who one summer after having served his time in World War I returns to his home in rural Provence where he is welcomed by his highly revered uncle Cesar Le Papet Soubeyran. Back at his home place in the highlands, Ugolin initiates a planned project which involves growing plants, but soon discovers that he is going to need a water resource to keep his enterprise afloat. He let's Papet in on his new activity and the old man is eager to help his nephew, but his good intentions get's the better of him and leads to fatal consequences. Though having their plan ruined they are dead set on finding a way to gain their obstacle, so when a man from the village named Jean Cadoret moves in to his newly inherited property with his wife Aim&egrave;e and their adolescent daughter Manon, the two farmers decides to mislead him. Subtly and acutely directed by French filmmaker Claude Berri (1934-2009) and with it's ardent and naturalistic milieu depictions and efficient narrative structure, this historic period piece, at the time the most expensive French film in French history, draws a throughout engaging portrayal of a kind-hearted and loving husband and father with an urban background who whilst struggling to create a good life for himself and his family in a rural area at the turn of the twentieth century, becomes a victim of deception and prejudice. This mid-1980s co-production between France, Italy and Switzerland, known as part of a movement in France during the 1980s called "heritage cinema" which mainly consisted of costume dramas, has a powerful score by French composer and arranger Jean-Claude Petit, based on Italian composer Giuseppe Verdi's Italian opera "The Force of Destiny" (1862), which reinforces the films pivotal atmosphere. Produced by French producers Pierre Grunstein and Alain Poir&eacute; (1917-2000) and notable for it's wonderful production design by production designer Bernard V&eacute;zat and cinematography by French director and cinematographer Bruno Nuytten, this character-driven and dialog-driven countryside epic which examines themes like interpersonal relations, greed, faith and the distinctions between human goodness and human cruelty is impelled by the splendid acting performances by French actor and producer G&eacute;rard Depardieu, Italian-born French actor and singer Yves Montand (1921-1991) and French actor, director and screenwriter Daniel Auteuil. A remarkably narrated and invariably moving drama which gained, among several other awards, the BAFTA Film Award for Best Film, Best cinematography Bruno Nuytten, Best Adapted Screenplay Claude Berri and G&eacute;rard Brach and Best Supporting Actor Daniel Auteuil at the 41st British Academy Film Awards in 1988, the NBR Award for Best Foreign Language Film at the National Board of Review of Motion Pictures Awards in 1987 and the C&eacute;sar Award for Best Actor Daniel Auteuil at the 13th C&eacute;sar Awards in 1987.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Slow but beautiful
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    billcr12
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Gerard Depardieu is Jean de Florette, a simple, hard working landowner and farmer who grows and sells flowers and also raises rabbits for food. Some of Jean's neighbors would like to buy his land but Jean refuses to sell to them. They then find the main spring nearby and plug it with cement to prevent water from reaching the farm. Jean has to travel a good distance to carry large containers to his farm. He later gets badly injured and they take advantage of the situation quickly. This is a simple and slow moving drama which looks like a painting come to life. It is followed by the equally masterful "Manon of the Spring."
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    J'adore!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    TheLittleSongbird
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Having been so blown away by Cyrano De Bergerac, I also watched Jean De Florette, also starring Gerard Depardieu. Jean De Florette is a very different film, but every bit as fantastic. Depardieu is very endearing in a performance that has in his career only been surpassed by Cyrano De Bergerac to me. Yves Montand and Daniel Auteuil are also outstanding as the scheming Soubeyrans. The acting is not Jean De Florette's only good asset. This is an example of a film where everything works. The story is beautifully paced and evocative, the script is witty and very cinematic, the cinematography shimmers, the scenery is breathtaking, the music is lively yet again very understated and the direction does wonderfully in capturing the pace of the seasons changing and Provence's unique atmosphere. All in all, I love this movie just as much as Cyrano De Bergerac, and I am watching Manon of the Spring(and loving it) even as we speak. 10/10 Bethany Cox
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A personal all-time favorite
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    olyrye
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/12/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is an epic film(s). (It must really be seen with Manon of the Spring, which is not a sequel but really the second part of the movie.) The photography, music, acting, writing, are top notch. A must see for any film buff. Full of eye and ear candy! It really stirred an emotional response in me, especially at the end. So many great movies flounder at the conclusion. This one delivers! It deals with the themes of family loyalty, miscommunication, love, betrayal, failure, and persistence in the face of catastrophe. But most importantly it deals with almost impossible redemption. This is a great movie to watch with your spouse or partner. It is equally appealing to both men and women and is a great film for a movie date!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Qualifies as a classic Greek tragedy.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    zjerunk
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/7/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I have many favorites, and this is one of the cr&egrave;me de la cr&egrave;me. This is a visually stunning film more like beautiful photographic montage. It is simple, tragic story well told, unlike many of today's plots - implausibly lame, suffering on a CGI crutch for 85 minutes. The simple story is about enduring truths which have been the mainstay of the Greek classics and Shakespeare: Our human strengths, our failings, our virtues, and our vices. The story may be a fiction, but its kernel is not. It is stories and story telling like this which has kept our rapt attention for four thousand years. First we should understand that this film is only the first half the novel by Marcel Pagnol which would have been too long as a single film, and out of necessity, was shot as two. The second half is titled, Manon of the Spring. Neither film stands alone as satisfactory because, obviously, it would be incomplete, and naturally, is also important that the two halves be viewed in sequence. For a fairly dispassionate pr&eacute;cis of the plots, I suggest reading the ones on Wikipedia, so I won't be repetitive here. I also recommend reading the boards for comments and discussions. JdF & MotS were both shot at the same time in 1986 with a budget of $17 million making it/them the biggest budget French films up to that time. JdF grossed $86M worldwide, and of that sum, only $4.9M was from the USA. MotS grossed $56M worldwide, of which only $3.9M was from the USA. In other words, culture films are not a good fit for the American viewing audience, and the gross revenue numbers bear this out. The rest of the world seems to bear out this conclusion. Foreign language films rarely do well in the USA for the simple reason that the vast majority of the viewing audience are unilingual anglophones who do not wish to burden themselves with having to work at "understanding" their entertainment - they wish to merely consume it. If it requires the work of reading subtitles or thought, it becomes unpalatable. This film requires your attention and thought! But to be fair to the US viewers, the subtitles are at times incomplete or inaccurate, and unlike the spoken word, they do not convey the emphasis or importance of certain bits of dialogue well. The plot is woven steadily throughout the film, so the viewers with no understanding at all of the French language are missing essential dialogue, and therefore plot. The bottom line is this: You will either be entranced by these two films and love them, or you will be bored by the first 15 minutes, and you'll translate that into "bad film." If your highest quality level of reading is Marvel comics then I suggest you stay away from this one. However, I recall years ago walking into a video store where this was playing on all the monitors. All the patrons in the store, ranging in age from 5 to 75 years, were standing transfixed watching this film. There was something magical about it!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Agonising; enrapturing and taut all-at-once period piece, detailing the struggles of two sets of farm-set family units at evens and odds with one another.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    johnnyboyz (j_l_h_m@yahoo.co.uk)
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/1/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Has farming, indeed agriculture in general, ever been as cinematic as it is in Claude Berri's Jean de Florette? The joy is in observing the rather articulate nuances that the characters must undertake when particular farming tasks require particular tools and items for a job at hand; the film eventually coming to resemble a tale about a man most probably as alien to farming as the audience and enjoying it as much as we enjoy watching his taking up of this challenge. The farming within the film, in its specificities revolving around the planning; the predicting; the techniques and the use of certain items and animals for certain events, is as intrinsic as the film's core study of greed and the capitalist infused garnering of an industrial item, an item which will bring large amounts of personal wealth and riches, eventually at the expense of others. The film eventually coming to form a remarkably executed, heart breakingly tragic, blackly comic, devilishly well put together period drama from France well worth checking out. The film begins with a young man named Ugolin (Auteuil) returning home to the South of France, and his uncle's farm, having served time with the French army; the soundtrack a dry and sleepy orchestral tune suggesting much in the way of travels and tiredness, only momentarily breaking off into louder bursts of a much more positive tone as he nears home. Upon arriving home, Ugolin takes clear glee in rushing to a small patch of soil on the grounds and unwrapping a plant of some kind so he may observe it; something he appears to enjoy more than being reconciled with his uncle after such a stretch of time and furthermore suggesting an inclination towards agricultural work, his dream eventually revealed to be one of which revolves around the growing and selling of flowers for a living. His uncle is Cesar (Montand), an elderly man whom demands Ugolin find a wife and have children in the near future so that the land may be passed down and kept within the family; his other eye on a stretch of land lying nearby to his own, a stretch functional enough as it stands and with a natural spring beneath it capable of escalating the quality of the goods that only Cesar knows of, but a stretch already owned by a man no way willing to just sell up. Berri spends a good deal of time with these two farmers, their dreams; their positions and their core characteristics filling up most of the film's opening act. We come to like them during this early part and their blackly funny misadventures as well as their dry observations on life and newfound situations which open up as a result of other events. We side with young Ugolin, this simple young man whom has only just returned from national service and wishes to move into floristry. It is only when the titular Jean of Florette arrives, in the form of G&eacute;rard Depardieu, that we see the true nature of them; Jean being the rightful heir to that of the land when Cesar and Ugolin accidentally-on-purpose murder the owner of the land thus bringing Jean into the equation following a string of other legal complications with the rightful land owner. Jean and his family of wife Aimee (Elisabeth Depardieu) and young daughter Manon (Mazurowna) are not used to such surroundings; their previous incarnation of living in a more urbanite locale ill preparing them for what they come into contact with here, the beauty and calmness of the locale coming to resemble mere surface featurettes as those within plot and brew. The obvious distinctions between themselves and those more attributed to the land arrive in the form of their clear differences in clothing, as well as their talk of things of a more cultured nature, namely the opera, as on occasion Aimee breaks out int chorus of song to Jean's own harmonica tunes. What unfolds is a game of cat and mouse and hope and frustration between the two farmers, in Ugolin and Cesar, and the Florettes whom hang around much to the annoyance of their neighbours whom still want the land, know of its true flourishing nature and retain the spring as their secret. Jean's gradual coming around to realise how wondrous and how magnificent the locale is, and how enthralling the individual tasks and procedures which make up farming echoes our own coming around to feel similarly towards the film. Just as agricultural activity is fresh to that of Jean, the arrival of he and his family acts as a fresh and very crisp presence within the film to that of the audience; the very gradual bringing of the audience around on Berri's behalf to have us see the two original farmers as cruel and calculating businessmen as this initial outsider and his family capture our hearts, is outstanding. The film is a really well executed drama, a wonderful piece persistently flicking from tone to tone and character to character in perfect tandem; a film working on a level of family drama, fish out of water storytelling and dark comedy culminating in something quite special.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Enjoy the wonderful surroundings and relax
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Luigi Di Pilla
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The surroundings near Aubagne in the Bouche Du Rh&ocirc;ne in France are wonderfully shot. The story by Marcel Pagnol is well adapted that takes step by step a dramatic end. All the actors did a fine Job and I am curious to see part two "Manon La Source". The sceneries in the time after the second world war are well built and developed. I recommend you to watch it in the original south french dialect with English subtitles. I spent an enjoyable and relaxing Saturday night with my wife. Don't miss the other great movie from the writer Pagnol called La Fille Du Pusatier. Please read my critic on IMDb. Final vote: 8/10.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Flawless
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    yeltzmanmatt
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is a beautifully told tale of a hunchback who moves from the town to the country when he inherits a farm. The cinematography is brilliant and the languid pace of the movie suits this perfectly. The acting is out of the top drawer especially from Yves Montand and Daniel Autiel who are mesmerising as the farmers intent on grabbing Gerard Depardieu's land. Depardieu is also in fine form as the hunchback who although bombastic and stubborn eventually evokes a deal of sympathy. It is hard to fault this film on any level and it absorbs you from the start to the finale. Although you can watch the film on it's own the subsequent Manon Des Sources ( another fine film) concludes the story in full. I have known a fair few people who don't like foreign language films who have watched this and every one has enjoyed it. This is a French classic not to be missed.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Rare gem.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    (Draco2-0)
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I just watched Jean De Florrete and it was great, very rare for me to say this but I was not once bored or restless during the entire movie. Jean De Florrete, about this French farmer who moves onto his uncle's land and decides it would be profitable to grow flowers. But in order to grow a enough flowers to make a profit they'll need more water than they have available. Their neighbor has an untapped underground spring. The farmer and his uncle go over to negotiate buying the land with the spring on it. Unfortunately for them their neighbor hates the uncle, and when they offer to buy some of his land the uncle and him get into a fight and during the bustle his head suffers a fatal blow against a rock and he dies almost instantaneously. The whole ordeal took place by a tree, so the farmer and his uncle make it look like the old man fell from the tree and hit his head. They think the land will be theirs but a relative of the neighbor, a hunchback, moves onto the property. The uncle offers to buy the land from him but the hunchback wants to use it for raising rabbits and growing squash. Fascinating to watch the triumphs and failures of the hunchback as he goes about trying to fulfill his dream, always with a happy upbeat attitude. The thing that amazed me about the movie would be just how simple the actual plot feels. There are no huge twists, no distracting sub-plots, not much happens for most of the movie until the last 15 minutes; despite that it manages to grab the viewers attention wonderfully and it doesn't let it go until the credits roll either. Unless you hate French movies. I highly recommend Jean De Floret.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Jean de Florette / Manon of the Spring
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    runamokprods
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/7/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Two part film, that was 1st released as two separate features. Terrific telling of a complex story of intertwined farming families in rural France in the early part of the 20th century. The acting is mostly of the highest order. Yves Montand, one of the most suave men in history is completely believable as a rough hewn, self-centered farmer, Gerard Depardieu, also cast against type, as a gentle, educated city born man trying to make it as a farmer also is astounding. Almost as good is Daniel Auteuil as Montand's not-very-bright son. Only Emmanuelle Beart, gorgeous though she may be, doesn't quite convince me as the wild woman of the fields. Some of it is performance, some of it is how perfect she looks. The story is wonderful in a Dickensian sort of way, with clues and character elements showing up early, only to pay off three hours later. I love the first part even more, somehow it feels more truly tragic and dense, the 2nd part just a bit too neat by the end. But still a grand, intelligent, great looking entertainment.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "Remarkably narrated and invariably moving..."
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Sindre Kaspersen
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/3/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    French actor, producer, screenwriter and director Claude Berri's twelfth feature film which he co-wrote with French screenwriter G&eacute;rard Brach (1927-2006) is an adaptation of a novel, "L'Eau des Collines - Jean de Florette and Manon des Sources" (1964) by French author, playwright and filmmaker Marcel Pagnol (1895-1974), which was inspired by true events. It was shot on numerous locations in the Vaucluse department of Provence in the southeast of France and is part of a duology which was succeeded by "Manon des Sources" (1986). It tells the story about Ugolin Soubeyran who one summer after having served his time in World War I returns to his home in rural Provence where he is welcomed by his highly revered uncle Cesar Le Papet Soubeyran. Back at his home place in the highlands, Ugolin initiates a planned project which involves growing plants, but soon discovers that he is going to need a water resource to keep his enterprise afloat. He let's Papet in on his new activity and the old man is eager to help his nephew, but his good intentions get's the better of him and leads to fatal consequences. Though having their plan ruined they are dead set on finding a way to gain their obstacle, so when a man from the village named Jean Cadoret moves in to his newly inherited property with his wife Aim&egrave;e and their adolescent daughter Manon, the two farmers decides to mislead him. Subtly and acutely directed by French filmmaker Claude Berri (1934-2009) and with it's ardent and naturalistic milieu depictions and efficient narrative structure, this historic period piece, at the time the most expensive French film in French history, draws a throughout engaging portrayal of a kind-hearted and loving husband and father with an urban background who whilst struggling to create a good life for himself and his family in a rural area at the turn of the twentieth century, becomes a victim of deception and prejudice. This mid-1980s co-production between France, Italy and Switzerland, known as part of a movement in France during the 1980s called "heritage cinema" which mainly consisted of costume dramas, has a powerful score by French composer and arranger Jean-Claude Petit, based on Italian composer Giuseppe Verdi's Italian opera "The Force of Destiny" (1862), which reinforces the films pivotal atmosphere. Produced by French producers Pierre Grunstein and Alain Poir&eacute; (1917-2000) and notable for it's wonderful production design by production designer Bernard V&eacute;zat and cinematography by French director and cinematographer Bruno Nuytten, this character-driven and dialog-driven countryside epic which examines themes like interpersonal relations, greed, faith and the distinctions between human goodness and human cruelty is impelled by the splendid acting performances by French actor and producer G&eacute;rard Depardieu, Italian-born French actor and singer Yves Montand (1921-1991) and French actor, director and screenwriter Daniel Auteuil. A remarkably narrated and invariably moving drama which gained, among several other awards, the BAFTA Film Award for Best Film, Best cinematography Bruno Nuytten, Best Adapted Screenplay Claude Berri and G&eacute;rard Brach and Best Supporting Actor Daniel Auteuil at the 41st British Academy Film Awards in 1988, the NBR Award for Best Foreign Language Film at the National Board of Review of Motion Pictures Awards in 1987 and the C&eacute;sar Award for Best Actor Daniel Auteuil at the 13th C&eacute;sar Awards in 1987.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Slow but beautiful
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    billcr12
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Gerard Depardieu is Jean de Florette, a simple, hard working landowner and farmer who grows and sells flowers and also raises rabbits for food. Some of Jean's neighbors would like to buy his land but Jean refuses to sell to them. They then find the main spring nearby and plug it with cement to prevent water from reaching the farm. Jean has to travel a good distance to carry large containers to his farm. He later gets badly injured and they take advantage of the situation quickly. This is a simple and slow moving drama which looks like a painting come to life. It is followed by the equally masterful "Manon of the Spring."
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    J'adore!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    TheLittleSongbird
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Having been so blown away by Cyrano De Bergerac, I also watched Jean De Florette, also starring Gerard Depardieu. Jean De Florette is a very different film, but every bit as fantastic. Depardieu is very endearing in a performance that has in his career only been surpassed by Cyrano De Bergerac to me. Yves Montand and Daniel Auteuil are also outstanding as the scheming Soubeyrans. The acting is not Jean De Florette's only good asset. This is an example of a film where everything works. The story is beautifully paced and evocative, the script is witty and very cinematic, the cinematography shimmers, the scenery is breathtaking, the music is lively yet again very understated and the direction does wonderfully in capturing the pace of the seasons changing and Provence's unique atmosphere. All in all, I love this movie just as much as Cyrano De Bergerac, and I am watching Manon of the Spring(and loving it) even as we speak. 10/10 Bethany Cox
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A personal all-time favorite
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    olyrye
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/12/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is an epic film(s). (It must really be seen with Manon of the Spring, which is not a sequel but really the second part of the movie.) The photography, music, acting, writing, are top notch. A must see for any film buff. Full of eye and ear candy! It really stirred an emotional response in me, especially at the end. So many great movies flounder at the conclusion. This one delivers! It deals with the themes of family loyalty, miscommunication, love, betrayal, failure, and persistence in the face of catastrophe. But most importantly it deals with almost impossible redemption. This is a great movie to watch with your spouse or partner. It is equally appealing to both men and women and is a great film for a movie date!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Qualifies as a classic Greek tragedy.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    zjerunk
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/7/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I have many favorites, and this is one of the cr&egrave;me de la cr&egrave;me. This is a visually stunning film more like beautiful photographic montage. It is simple, tragic story well told, unlike many of today's plots - implausibly lame, suffering on a CGI crutch for 85 minutes. The simple story is about enduring truths which have been the mainstay of the Greek classics and Shakespeare: Our human strengths, our failings, our virtues, and our vices. The story may be a fiction, but its kernel is not. It is stories and story telling like this which has kept our rapt attention for four thousand years. First we should understand that this film is only the first half the novel by Marcel Pagnol which would have been too long as a single film, and out of necessity, was shot as two. The second half is titled, Manon of the Spring. Neither film stands alone as satisfactory because, obviously, it would be incomplete, and naturally, is also important that the two halves be viewed in sequence. For a fairly dispassionate pr&eacute;cis of the plots, I suggest reading the ones on Wikipedia, so I won't be repetitive here. I also recommend reading the boards for comments and discussions. JdF & MotS were both shot at the same time in 1986 with a budget of $17 million making it/them the biggest budget French films up to that time. JdF grossed $86M worldwide, and of that sum, only $4.9M was from the USA. MotS grossed $56M worldwide, of which only $3.9M was from the USA. In other words, culture films are not a good fit for the American viewing audience, and the gross revenue numbers bear this out. The rest of the world seems to bear out this conclusion. Foreign language films rarely do well in the USA for the simple reason that the vast majority of the viewing audience are unilingual anglophones who do not wish to burden themselves with having to work at "understanding" their entertainment - they wish to merely consume it. If it requires the work of reading subtitles or thought, it becomes unpalatable. This film requires your attention and thought! But to be fair to the US viewers, the subtitles are at times incomplete or inaccurate, and unlike the spoken word, they do not convey the emphasis or importance of certain bits of dialogue well. The plot is woven steadily throughout the film, so the viewers with no understanding at all of the French language are missing essential dialogue, and therefore plot. The bottom line is this: You will either be entranced by these two films and love them, or you will be bored by the first 15 minutes, and you'll translate that into "bad film." If your highest quality level of reading is Marvel comics then I suggest you stay away from this one. However, I recall years ago walking into a video store where this was playing on all the monitors. All the patrons in the store, ranging in age from 5 to 75 years, were standing transfixed watching this film. There was something magical about it!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Agonising; enrapturing and taut all-at-once period piece, detailing the struggles of two sets of farm-set family units at evens and odds with one another.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    johnnyboyz (j_l_h_m@yahoo.co.uk)
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/1/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Has farming, indeed agriculture in general, ever been as cinematic as it is in Claude Berri's Jean de Florette? The joy is in observing the rather articulate nuances that the characters must undertake when particular farming tasks require particular tools and items for a job at hand; the film eventually coming to resemble a tale about a man most probably as alien to farming as the audience and enjoying it as much as we enjoy watching his taking up of this challenge. The farming within the film, in its specificities revolving around the planning; the predicting; the techniques and the use of certain items and animals for certain events, is as intrinsic as the film's core study of greed and the capitalist infused garnering of an industrial item, an item which will bring large amounts of personal wealth and riches, eventually at the expense of others. The film eventually coming to form a remarkably executed, heart breakingly tragic, blackly comic, devilishly well put together period drama from France well worth checking out. The film begins with a young man named Ugolin (Auteuil) returning home to the South of France, and his uncle's farm, having served time with the French army; the soundtrack a dry and sleepy orchestral tune suggesting much in the way of travels and tiredness, only momentarily breaking off into louder bursts of a much more positive tone as he nears home. Upon arriving home, Ugolin takes clear glee in rushing to a small patch of soil on the grounds and unwrapping a plant of some kind so he may observe it; something he appears to enjoy more than being reconciled with his uncle after such a stretch of time and furthermore suggesting an inclination towards agricultural work, his dream eventually revealed to be one of which revolves around the growing and selling of flowers for a living. His uncle is Cesar (Montand), an elderly man whom demands Ugolin find a wife and have children in the near future so that the land may be passed down and kept within the family; his other eye on a stretch of land lying nearby to his own, a stretch functional enough as it stands and with a natural spring beneath it capable of escalating the quality of the goods that only Cesar knows of, but a stretch already owned by a man no way willing to just sell up. Berri spends a good deal of time with these two farmers, their dreams; their positions and their core characteristics filling up most of the film's opening act. We come to like them during this early part and their blackly funny misadventures as well as their dry observations on life and newfound situations which open up as a result of other events. We side with young Ugolin, this simple young man whom has only just returned from national service and wishes to move into floristry. It is only when the titular Jean of Florette arrives, in the form of G&eacute;rard Depardieu, that we see the true nature of them; Jean being the rightful heir to that of the land when Cesar and Ugolin accidentally-on-purpose murder the owner of the land thus bringing Jean into the equation following a string of other legal complications with the rightful land owner. Jean and his family of wife Aimee (Elisabeth Depardieu) and young daughter Manon (Mazurowna) are not used to such surroundings; their previous incarnation of living in a more urbanite locale ill preparing them for what they come into contact with here, the beauty and calmness of the locale coming to resemble mere surface featurettes as those within plot and brew. The obvious distinctions between themselves and those more attributed to the land arrive in the form of their clear differences in clothing, as well as their talk of things of a more cultured nature, namely the opera, as on occasion Aimee breaks out int chorus of song to Jean's own harmonica tunes. What unfolds is a game of cat and mouse and hope and frustration between the two farmers, in Ugolin and Cesar, and the Florettes whom hang around much to the annoyance of their neighbours whom still want the land, know of its true flourishing nature and retain the spring as their secret. Jean's gradual coming around to realise how wondrous and how magnificent the locale is, and how enthralling the individual tasks and procedures which make up farming echoes our own coming around to feel similarly towards the film. Just as agricultural activity is fresh to that of Jean, the arrival of he and his family acts as a fresh and very crisp presence within the film to that of the audience; the very gradual bringing of the audience around on Berri's behalf to have us see the two original farmers as cruel and calculating businessmen as this initial outsider and his family capture our hearts, is outstanding. The film is a really well executed drama, a wonderful piece persistently flicking from tone to tone and character to character in perfect tandem; a film working on a level of family drama, fish out of water storytelling and dark comedy culminating in something quite special.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Enjoy the wonderful surroundings and relax
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Luigi Di Pilla
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The surroundings near Aubagne in the Bouche Du Rh&ocirc;ne in France are wonderfully shot. The story by Marcel Pagnol is well adapted that takes step by step a dramatic end. All the actors did a fine Job and I am curious to see part two "Manon La Source". The sceneries in the time after the second world war are well built and developed. I recommend you to watch it in the original south french dialect with English subtitles. I spent an enjoyable and relaxing Saturday night with my wife. Don't miss the other great movie from the writer Pagnol called La Fille Du Pusatier. Please read my critic on IMDb. Final vote: 8/10.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Flawless
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    yeltzmanmatt
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is a beautifully told tale of a hunchback who moves from the town to the country when he inherits a farm. The cinematography is brilliant and the languid pace of the movie suits this perfectly. The acting is out of the top drawer especially from Yves Montand and Daniel Autiel who are mesmerising as the farmers intent on grabbing Gerard Depardieu's land. Depardieu is also in fine form as the hunchback who although bombastic and stubborn eventually evokes a deal of sympathy. It is hard to fault this film on any level and it absorbs you from the start to the finale. Although you can watch the film on it's own the subsequent Manon Des Sources ( another fine film) concludes the story in full. I have known a fair few people who don't like foreign language films who have watched this and every one has enjoyed it. This is a French classic not to be missed.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Rare gem.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    (Draco2-0)
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I just watched Jean De Florrete and it was great, very rare for me to say this but I was not once bored or restless during the entire movie. Jean De Florrete, about this French farmer who moves onto his uncle's land and decides it would be profitable to grow flowers. But in order to grow a enough flowers to make a profit they'll need more water than they have available. Their neighbor has an untapped underground spring. The farmer and his uncle go over to negotiate buying the land with the spring on it. Unfortunately for them their neighbor hates the uncle, and when they offer to buy some of his land the uncle and him get into a fight and during the bustle his head suffers a fatal blow against a rock and he dies almost instantaneously. The whole ordeal took place by a tree, so the farmer and his uncle make it look like the old man fell from the tree and hit his head. They think the land will be theirs but a relative of the neighbor, a hunchback, moves onto the property. The uncle offers to buy the land from him but the hunchback wants to use it for raising rabbits and growing squash. Fascinating to watch the triumphs and failures of the hunchback as he goes about trying to fulfill his dream, always with a happy upbeat attitude. The thing that amazed me about the movie would be just how simple the actual plot feels. There are no huge twists, no distracting sub-plots, not much happens for most of the movie until the last 15 minutes; despite that it manages to grab the viewers attention wonderfully and it doesn't let it go until the credits roll either. Unless you hate French movies. I highly recommend Jean De Floret.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Jean de Florette / Manon of the Spring
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    runamokprods
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/7/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Two part film, that was 1st released as two separate features. Terrific telling of a complex story of intertwined farming families in rural France in the early part of the 20th century. The acting is mostly of the highest order. Yves Montand, one of the most suave men in history is completely believable as a rough hewn, self-centered farmer, Gerard Depardieu, also cast against type, as a gentle, educated city born man trying to make it as a farmer also is astounding. Almost as good is Daniel Auteuil as Montand's not-very-bright son. Only Emmanuelle Beart, gorgeous though she may be, doesn't quite convince me as the wild woman of the fields. Some of it is performance, some of it is how perfect she looks. The story is wonderful in a Dickensian sort of way, with clues and character elements showing up early, only to pay off three hours later. I love the first part even more, somehow it feels more truly tragic and dense, the 2nd part just a bit too neat by the end. But still a grand, intelligent, great looking entertainment.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "Remarkably narrated and invariably moving..."
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Sindre Kaspersen
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/3/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    French actor, producer, screenwriter and director Claude Berri's twelfth feature film which he co-wrote with French screenwriter G&eacute;rard Brach (1927-2006) is an adaptation of a novel, "L'Eau des Collines - Jean de Florette and Manon des Sources" (1964) by French author, playwright and filmmaker Marcel Pagnol (1895-1974), which was inspired by true events. It was shot on numerous locations in the Vaucluse department of Provence in the southeast of France and is part of a duology which was succeeded by "Manon des Sources" (1986). It tells the story about Ugolin Soubeyran who one summer after having served his time in World War I returns to his home in rural Provence where he is welcomed by his highly revered uncle Cesar Le Papet Soubeyran. Back at his home place in the highlands, Ugolin initiates a planned project which involves growing plants, but soon discovers that he is going to need a water resource to keep his enterprise afloat. He let's Papet in on his new activity and the old man is eager to help his nephew, but his good intentions get's the better of him and leads to fatal consequences. Though having their plan ruined they are dead set on finding a way to gain their obstacle, so when a man from the village named Jean Cadoret moves in to his newly inherited property with his wife Aim&egrave;e and their adolescent daughter Manon, the two farmers decides to mislead him. Subtly and acutely directed by French filmmaker Claude Berri (1934-2009) and with it's ardent and naturalistic milieu depictions and efficient narrative structure, this historic period piece, at the time the most expensive French film in French history, draws a throughout engaging portrayal of a kind-hearted and loving husband and father with an urban background who whilst struggling to create a good life for himself and his family in a rural area at the turn of the twentieth century, becomes a victim of deception and prejudice. This mid-1980s co-production between France, Italy and Switzerland, known as part of a movement in France during the 1980s called "heritage cinema" which mainly consisted of costume dramas, has a powerful score by French composer and arranger Jean-Claude Petit, based on Italian composer Giuseppe Verdi's Italian opera "The Force of Destiny" (1862), which reinforces the films pivotal atmosphere. Produced by French producers Pierre Grunstein and Alain Poir&eacute; (1917-2000) and notable for it's wonderful production design by production designer Bernard V&eacute;zat and cinematography by French director and cinematographer Bruno Nuytten, this character-driven and dialog-driven countryside epic which examines themes like interpersonal relations, greed, faith and the distinctions between human goodness and human cruelty is impelled by the splendid acting performances by French actor and producer G&eacute;rard Depardieu, Italian-born French actor and singer Yves Montand (1921-1991) and French actor, director and screenwriter Daniel Auteuil. A remarkably narrated and invariably moving drama which gained, among several other awards, the BAFTA Film Award for Best Film, Best cinematography Bruno Nuytten, Best Adapted Screenplay Claude Berri and G&eacute;rard Brach and Best Supporting Actor Daniel Auteuil at the 41st British Academy Film Awards in 1988, the NBR Award for Best Foreign Language Film at the National Board of Review of Motion Pictures Awards in 1987 and the C&eacute;sar Award for Best Actor Daniel Auteuil at the 13th C&eacute;sar Awards in 1987.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Slow but beautiful
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    billcr12
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Gerard Depardieu is Jean de Florette, a simple, hard working landowner and farmer who grows and sells flowers and also raises rabbits for food. Some of Jean's neighbors would like to buy his land but Jean refuses to sell to them. They then find the main spring nearby and plug it with cement to prevent water from reaching the farm. Jean has to travel a good distance to carry large containers to his farm. He later gets badly injured and they take advantage of the situation quickly. This is a simple and slow moving drama which looks like a painting come to life. It is followed by the equally masterful "Manon of the Spring."
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    J'adore!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    TheLittleSongbird
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Having been so blown away by Cyrano De Bergerac, I also watched Jean De Florette, also starring Gerard Depardieu. Jean De Florette is a very different film, but every bit as fantastic. Depardieu is very endearing in a performance that has in his career only been surpassed by Cyrano De Bergerac to me. Yves Montand and Daniel Auteuil are also outstanding as the scheming Soubeyrans. The acting is not Jean De Florette's only good asset. This is an example of a film where everything works. The story is beautifully paced and evocative, the script is witty and very cinematic, the cinematography shimmers, the scenery is breathtaking, the music is lively yet again very understated and the direction does wonderfully in capturing the pace of the seasons changing and Provence's unique atmosphere. All in all, I love this movie just as much as Cyrano De Bergerac, and I am watching Manon of the Spring(and loving it) even as we speak. 10/10 Bethany Cox
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A personal all-time favorite
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    olyrye
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/12/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is an epic film(s). (It must really be seen with Manon of the Spring, which is not a sequel but really the second part of the movie.) The photography, music, acting, writing, are top notch. A must see for any film buff. Full of eye and ear candy! It really stirred an emotional response in me, especially at the end. So many great movies flounder at the conclusion. This one delivers! It deals with the themes of family loyalty, miscommunication, love, betrayal, failure, and persistence in the face of catastrophe. But most importantly it deals with almost impossible redemption. This is a great movie to watch with your spouse or partner. It is equally appealing to both men and women and is a great film for a movie date!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Qualifies as a classic Greek tragedy.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    zjerunk
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/7/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I have many favorites, and this is one of the cr&egrave;me de la cr&egrave;me. This is a visually stunning film more like beautiful photographic montage. It is simple, tragic story well told, unlike many of today's plots - implausibly lame, suffering on a CGI crutch for 85 minutes. The simple story is about enduring truths which have been the mainstay of the Greek classics and Shakespeare: Our human strengths, our failings, our virtues, and our vices. The story may be a fiction, but its kernel is not. It is stories and story telling like this which has kept our rapt attention for four thousand years. First we should understand that this film is only the first half the novel by Marcel Pagnol which would have been too long as a single film, and out of necessity, was shot as two. The second half is titled, Manon of the Spring. Neither film stands alone as satisfactory because, obviously, it would be incomplete, and naturally, is also important that the two halves be viewed in sequence. For a fairly dispassionate pr&eacute;cis of the plots, I suggest reading the ones on Wikipedia, so I won't be repetitive here. I also recommend reading the boards for comments and discussions. JdF & MotS were both shot at the same time in 1986 with a budget of $17 million making it/them the biggest budget French films up to that time. JdF grossed $86M worldwide, and of that sum, only $4.9M was from the USA. MotS grossed $56M worldwide, of which only $3.9M was from the USA. In other words, culture films are not a good fit for the American viewing audience, and the gross revenue numbers bear this out. The rest of the world seems to bear out this conclusion. Foreign language films rarely do well in the USA for the simple reason that the vast majority of the viewing audience are unilingual anglophones who do not wish to burden themselves with having to work at "understanding" their entertainment - they wish to merely consume it. If it requires the work of reading subtitles or thought, it becomes unpalatable. This film requires your attention and thought! But to be fair to the US viewers, the subtitles are at times incomplete or inaccurate, and unlike the spoken word, they do not convey the emphasis or importance of certain bits of dialogue well. The plot is woven steadily throughout the film, so the viewers with no understanding at all of the French language are missing essential dialogue, and therefore plot. The bottom line is this: You will either be entranced by these two films and love them, or you will be bored by the first 15 minutes, and you'll translate that into "bad film." If your highest quality level of reading is Marvel comics then I suggest you stay away from this one. However, I recall years ago walking into a video store where this was playing on all the monitors. All the patrons in the store, ranging in age from 5 to 75 years, were standing transfixed watching this film. There was something magical about it!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Agonising; enrapturing and taut all-at-once period piece, detailing the struggles of two sets of farm-set family units at evens and odds with one another.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    johnnyboyz (j_l_h_m@yahoo.co.uk)
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/1/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Has farming, indeed agriculture in general, ever been as cinematic as it is in Claude Berri's Jean de Florette? The joy is in observing the rather articulate nuances that the characters must undertake when particular farming tasks require particular tools and items for a job at hand; the film eventually coming to resemble a tale about a man most probably as alien to farming as the audience and enjoying it as much as we enjoy watching his taking up of this challenge. The farming within the film, in its specificities revolving around the planning; the predicting; the techniques and the use of certain items and animals for certain events, is as intrinsic as the film's core study of greed and the capitalist infused garnering of an industrial item, an item which will bring large amounts of personal wealth and riches, eventually at the expense of others. The film eventually coming to form a remarkably executed, heart breakingly tragic, blackly comic, devilishly well put together period drama from France well worth checking out. The film begins with a young man named Ugolin (Auteuil) returning home to the South of France, and his uncle's farm, having served time with the French army; the soundtrack a dry and sleepy orchestral tune suggesting much in the way of travels and tiredness, only momentarily breaking off into louder bursts of a much more positive tone as he nears home. Upon arriving home, Ugolin takes clear glee in rushing to a small patch of soil on the grounds and unwrapping a plant of some kind so he may observe it; something he appears to enjoy more than being reconciled with his uncle after such a stretch of time and furthermore suggesting an inclination towards agricultural work, his dream eventually revealed to be one of which revolves around the growing and selling of flowers for a living. His uncle is Cesar (Montand), an elderly man whom demands Ugolin find a wife and have children in the near future so that the land may be passed down and kept within the family; his other eye on a stretch of land lying nearby to his own, a stretch functional enough as it stands and with a natural spring beneath it capable of escalating the quality of the goods that only Cesar knows of, but a stretch already owned by a man no way willing to just sell up. Berri spends a good deal of time with these two farmers, their dreams; their positions and their core characteristics filling up most of the film's opening act. We come to like them during this early part and their blackly funny misadventures as well as their dry observations on life and newfound situations which open up as a result of other events. We side with young Ugolin, this simple young man whom has only just returned from national service and wishes to move into floristry. It is only when the titular Jean of Florette arrives, in the form of G&eacute;rard Depardieu, that we see the true nature of them; Jean being the rightful heir to that of the land when Cesar and Ugolin accidentally-on-purpose murder the owner of the land thus bringing Jean into the equation following a string of other legal complications with the rightful land owner. Jean and his family of wife Aimee (Elisabeth Depardieu) and young daughter Manon (Mazurowna) are not used to such surroundings; their previous incarnation of living in a more urbanite locale ill preparing them for what they come into contact with here, the beauty and calmness of the locale coming to resemble mere surface featurettes as those within plot and brew. The obvious distinctions between themselves and those more attributed to the land arrive in the form of their clear differences in clothing, as well as their talk of things of a more cultured nature, namely the opera, as on occasion Aimee breaks out int chorus of song to Jean's own harmonica tunes. What unfolds is a game of cat and mouse and hope and frustration between the two farmers, in Ugolin and Cesar, and the Florettes whom hang around much to the annoyance of their neighbours whom still want the land, know of its true flourishing nature and retain the spring as their secret. Jean's gradual coming around to realise how wondrous and how magnificent the locale is, and how enthralling the individual tasks and procedures which make up farming echoes our own coming around to feel similarly towards the film. Just as agricultural activity is fresh to that of Jean, the arrival of he and his family acts as a fresh and very crisp presence within the film to that of the audience; the very gradual bringing of the audience around on Berri's behalf to have us see the two original farmers as cruel and calculating businessmen as this initial outsider and his family capture our hearts, is outstanding. The film is a really well executed drama, a wonderful piece persistently flicking from tone to tone and character to character in perfect tandem; a film working on a level of family drama, fish out of water storytelling and dark comedy culminating in something quite special.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Enjoy the wonderful surroundings and relax
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Luigi Di Pilla
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The surroundings near Aubagne in the Bouche Du Rh&ocirc;ne in France are wonderfully shot. The story by Marcel Pagnol is well adapted that takes step by step a dramatic end. All the actors did a fine Job and I am curious to see part two "Manon La Source". The sceneries in the time after the second world war are well built and developed. I recommend you to watch it in the original south french dialect with English subtitles. I spent an enjoyable and relaxing Saturday night with my wife. Don't miss the other great movie from the writer Pagnol called La Fille Du Pusatier. Please read my critic on IMDb. Final vote: 8/10.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Flawless
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    yeltzmanmatt
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is a beautifully told tale of a hunchback who moves from the town to the country when he inherits a farm. The cinematography is brilliant and the languid pace of the movie suits this perfectly. The acting is out of the top drawer especially from Yves Montand and Daniel Autiel who are mesmerising as the farmers intent on grabbing Gerard Depardieu's land. Depardieu is also in fine form as the hunchback who although bombastic and stubborn eventually evokes a deal of sympathy. It is hard to fault this film on any level and it absorbs you from the start to the finale. Although you can watch the film on it's own the subsequent Manon Des Sources ( another fine film) concludes the story in full. I have known a fair few people who don't like foreign language films who have watched this and every one has enjoyed it. This is a French classic not to be missed.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Rare gem.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    (Draco2-0)
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I just watched Jean De Florrete and it was great, very rare for me to say this but I was not once bored or restless during the entire movie. Jean De Florrete, about this French farmer who moves onto his uncle's land and decides it would be profitable to grow flowers. But in order to grow a enough flowers to make a profit they'll need more water than they have available. Their neighbor has an untapped underground spring. The farmer and his uncle go over to negotiate buying the land with the spring on it. Unfortunately for them their neighbor hates the uncle, and when they offer to buy some of his land the uncle and him get into a fight and during the bustle his head suffers a fatal blow against a rock and he dies almost instantaneously. The whole ordeal took place by a tree, so the farmer and his uncle make it look like the old man fell from the tree and hit his head. They think the land will be theirs but a relative of the neighbor, a hunchback, moves onto the property. The uncle offers to buy the land from him but the hunchback wants to use it for raising rabbits and growing squash. Fascinating to watch the triumphs and failures of the hunchback as he goes about trying to fulfill his dream, always with a happy upbeat attitude. The thing that amazed me about the movie would be just how simple the actual plot feels. There are no huge twists, no distracting sub-plots, not much happens for most of the movie until the last 15 minutes; despite that it manages to grab the viewers attention wonderfully and it doesn't let it go until the credits roll either. Unless you hate French movies. I highly recommend Jean De Floret.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Jean de Florette / Manon of the Spring
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    runamokprods
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/7/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Two part film, that was 1st released as two separate features. Terrific telling of a complex story of intertwined farming families in rural France in the early part of the 20th century. The acting is mostly of the highest order. Yves Montand, one of the most suave men in history is completely believable as a rough hewn, self-centered farmer, Gerard Depardieu, also cast against type, as a gentle, educated city born man trying to make it as a farmer also is astounding. Almost as good is Daniel Auteuil as Montand's not-very-bright son. Only Emmanuelle Beart, gorgeous though she may be, doesn't quite convince me as the wild woman of the fields. Some of it is performance, some of it is how perfect she looks. The story is wonderful in a Dickensian sort of way, with clues and character elements showing up early, only to pay off three hours later. I love the first part even more, somehow it feels more truly tragic and dense, the 2nd part just a bit too neat by the end. But still a grand, intelligent, great looking entertainment.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "Remarkably narrated and invariably moving..."
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Sindre Kaspersen
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/3/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    French actor, producer, screenwriter and director Claude Berri's twelfth feature film which he co-wrote with French screenwriter G&eacute;rard Brach (1927-2006) is an adaptation of a novel, "L'Eau des Collines - Jean de Florette and Manon des Sources" (1964) by French author, playwright and filmmaker Marcel Pagnol (1895-1974), which was inspired by true events. It was shot on numerous locations in the Vaucluse department of Provence in the southeast of France and is part of a duology which was succeeded by "Manon des Sources" (1986). It tells the story about Ugolin Soubeyran who one summer after having served his time in World War I returns to his home in rural Provence where he is welcomed by his highly revered uncle Cesar Le Papet Soubeyran. Back at his home place in the highlands, Ugolin initiates a planned project which involves growing plants, but soon discovers that he is going to need a water resource to keep his enterprise afloat. He let's Papet in on his new activity and the old man is eager to help his nephew, but his good intentions get's the better of him and leads to fatal consequences. Though having their plan ruined they are dead set on finding a way to gain their obstacle, so when a man from the village named Jean Cadoret moves in to his newly inherited property with his wife Aim&egrave;e and their adolescent daughter Manon, the two farmers decides to mislead him. Subtly and acutely directed by French filmmaker Claude Berri (1934-2009) and with it's ardent and naturalistic milieu depictions and efficient narrative structure, this historic period piece, at the time the most expensive French film in French history, draws a throughout engaging portrayal of a kind-hearted and loving husband and father with an urban background who whilst struggling to create a good life for himself and his family in a rural area at the turn of the twentieth century, becomes a victim of deception and prejudice. This mid-1980s co-production between France, Italy and Switzerland, known as part of a movement in France during the 1980s called "heritage cinema" which mainly consisted of costume dramas, has a powerful score by French composer and arranger Jean-Claude Petit, based on Italian composer Giuseppe Verdi's Italian opera "The Force of Destiny" (1862), which reinforces the films pivotal atmosphere. Produced by French producers Pierre Grunstein and Alain Poir&eacute; (1917-2000) and notable for it's wonderful production design by production designer Bernard V&eacute;zat and cinematography by French director and cinematographer Bruno Nuytten, this character-driven and dialog-driven countryside epic which examines themes like interpersonal relations, greed, faith and the distinctions between human goodness and human cruelty is impelled by the splendid acting performances by French actor and producer G&eacute;rard Depardieu, Italian-born French actor and singer Yves Montand (1921-1991) and French actor, director and screenwriter Daniel Auteuil. A remarkably narrated and invariably moving drama which gained, among several other awards, the BAFTA Film Award for Best Film, Best cinematography Bruno Nuytten, Best Adapted Screenplay Claude Berri and G&eacute;rard Brach and Best Supporting Actor Daniel Auteuil at the 41st British Academy Film Awards in 1988, the NBR Award for Best Foreign Language Film at the National Board of Review of Motion Pictures Awards in 1987 and the C&eacute;sar Award for Best Actor Daniel Auteuil at the 13th C&eacute;sar Awards in 1987.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Slow but beautiful
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    billcr12
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Gerard Depardieu is Jean de Florette, a simple, hard working landowner and farmer who grows and sells flowers and also raises rabbits for food. Some of Jean's neighbors would like to buy his land but Jean refuses to sell to them. They then find the main spring nearby and plug it with cement to prevent water from reaching the farm. Jean has to travel a good distance to carry large containers to his farm. He later gets badly injured and they take advantage of the situation quickly. This is a simple and slow moving drama which looks like a painting come to life. It is followed by the equally masterful "Manon of the Spring."
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    J'adore!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    TheLittleSongbird
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Having been so blown away by Cyrano De Bergerac, I also watched Jean De Florette, also starring Gerard Depardieu. Jean De Florette is a very different film, but every bit as fantastic. Depardieu is very endearing in a performance that has in his career only been surpassed by Cyrano De Bergerac to me. Yves Montand and Daniel Auteuil are also outstanding as the scheming Soubeyrans. The acting is not Jean De Florette's only good asset. This is an example of a film where everything works. The story is beautifully paced and evocative, the script is witty and very cinematic, the cinematography shimmers, the scenery is breathtaking, the music is lively yet again very understated and the direction does wonderfully in capturing the pace of the seasons changing and Provence's unique atmosphere. All in all, I love this movie just as much as Cyrano De Bergerac, and I am watching Manon of the Spring(and loving it) even as we speak. 10/10 Bethany Cox
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A personal all-time favorite
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    olyrye
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/12/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is an epic film(s). (It must really be seen with Manon of the Spring, which is not a sequel but really the second part of the movie.) The photography, music, acting, writing, are top notch. A must see for any film buff. Full of eye and ear candy! It really stirred an emotional response in me, especially at the end. So many great movies flounder at the conclusion. This one delivers! It deals with the themes of family loyalty, miscommunication, love, betrayal, failure, and persistence in the face of catastrophe. But most importantly it deals with almost impossible redemption. This is a great movie to watch with your spouse or partner. It is equally appealing to both men and women and is a great film for a movie date!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Qualifies as a classic Greek tragedy.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    zjerunk
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/7/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I have many favorites, and this is one of the cr&egrave;me de la cr&egrave;me. This is a visually stunning film more like beautiful photographic montage. It is simple, tragic story well told, unlike many of today's plots - implausibly lame, suffering on a CGI crutch for 85 minutes. The simple story is about enduring truths which have been the mainstay of the Greek classics and Shakespeare: Our human strengths, our failings, our virtues, and our vices. The story may be a fiction, but its kernel is not. It is stories and story telling like this which has kept our rapt attention for four thousand years. First we should understand that this film is only the first half the novel by Marcel Pagnol which would have been too long as a single film, and out of necessity, was shot as two. The second half is titled, Manon of the Spring. Neither film stands alone as satisfactory because, obviously, it would be incomplete, and naturally, is also important that the two halves be viewed in sequence. For a fairly dispassionate pr&eacute;cis of the plots, I suggest reading the ones on Wikipedia, so I won't be repetitive here. I also recommend reading the boards for comments and discussions. JdF & MotS were both shot at the same time in 1986 with a budget of $17 million making it/them the biggest budget French films up to that time. JdF grossed $86M worldwide, and of that sum, only $4.9M was from the USA. MotS grossed $56M worldwide, of which only $3.9M was from the USA. In other words, culture films are not a good fit for the American viewing audience, and the gross revenue numbers bear this out. The rest of the world seems to bear out this conclusion. Foreign language films rarely do well in the USA for the simple reason that the vast majority of the viewing audience are unilingual anglophones who do not wish to burden themselves with having to work at "understanding" their entertainment - they wish to merely consume it. If it requires the work of reading subtitles or thought, it becomes unpalatable. This film requires your attention and thought! But to be fair to the US viewers, the subtitles are at times incomplete or inaccurate, and unlike the spoken word, they do not convey the emphasis or importance of certain bits of dialogue well. The plot is woven steadily throughout the film, so the viewers with no understanding at all of the French language are missing essential dialogue, and therefore plot. The bottom line is this: You will either be entranced by these two films and love them, or you will be bored by the first 15 minutes, and you'll translate that into "bad film." If your highest quality level of reading is Marvel comics then I suggest you stay away from this one. However, I recall years ago walking into a video store where this was playing on all the monitors. All the patrons in the store, ranging in age from 5 to 75 years, were standing transfixed watching this film. There was something magical about it!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Agonising; enrapturing and taut all-at-once period piece, detailing the struggles of two sets of farm-set family units at evens and odds with one another.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    johnnyboyz (j_l_h_m@yahoo.co.uk)
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/1/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Has farming, indeed agriculture in general, ever been as cinematic as it is in Claude Berri's Jean de Florette? The joy is in observing the rather articulate nuances that the characters must undertake when particular farming tasks require particular tools and items for a job at hand; the film eventually coming to resemble a tale about a man most probably as alien to farming as the audience and enjoying it as much as we enjoy watching his taking up of this challenge. The farming within the film, in its specificities revolving around the planning; the predicting; the techniques and the use of certain items and animals for certain events, is as intrinsic as the film's core study of greed and the capitalist infused garnering of an industrial item, an item which will bring large amounts of personal wealth and riches, eventually at the expense of others. The film eventually coming to form a remarkably executed, heart breakingly tragic, blackly comic, devilishly well put together period drama from France well worth checking out. The film begins with a young man named Ugolin (Auteuil) returning home to the South of France, and his uncle's farm, having served time with the French army; the soundtrack a dry and sleepy orchestral tune suggesting much in the way of travels and tiredness, only momentarily breaking off into louder bursts of a much more positive tone as he nears home. Upon arriving home, Ugolin takes clear glee in rushing to a small patch of soil on the grounds and unwrapping a plant of some kind so he may observe it; something he appears to enjoy more than being reconciled with his uncle after such a stretch of time and furthermore suggesting an inclination towards agricultural work, his dream eventually revealed to be one of which revolves around the growing and selling of flowers for a living. His uncle is Cesar (Montand), an elderly man whom demands Ugolin find a wife and have children in the near future so that the land may be passed down and kept within the family; his other eye on a stretch of land lying nearby to his own, a stretch functional enough as it stands and with a natural spring beneath it capable of escalating the quality of the goods that only Cesar knows of, but a stretch already owned by a man no way willing to just sell up. Berri spends a good deal of time with these two farmers, their dreams; their positions and their core characteristics filling up most of the film's opening act. We come to like them during this early part and their blackly funny misadventures as well as their dry observations on life and newfound situations which open up as a result of other events. We side with young Ugolin, this simple young man whom has only just returned from national service and wishes to move into floristry. It is only when the titular Jean of Florette arrives, in the form of G&eacute;rard Depardieu, that we see the true nature of them; Jean being the rightful heir to that of the land when Cesar and Ugolin accidentally-on-purpose murder the owner of the land thus bringing Jean into the equation following a string of other legal complications with the rightful land owner. Jean and his family of wife Aimee (Elisabeth Depardieu) and young daughter Manon (Mazurowna) are not used to such surroundings; their previous incarnation of living in a more urbanite locale ill preparing them for what they come into contact with here, the beauty and calmness of the locale coming to resemble mere surface featurettes as those within plot and brew. The obvious distinctions between themselves and those more attributed to the land arrive in the form of their clear differences in clothing, as well as their talk of things of a more cultured nature, namely the opera, as on occasion Aimee breaks out int chorus of song to Jean's own harmonica tunes. What unfolds is a game of cat and mouse and hope and frustration between the two farmers, in Ugolin and Cesar, and the Florettes whom hang around much to the annoyance of their neighbours whom still want the land, know of its true flourishing nature and retain the spring as their secret. Jean's gradual coming around to realise how wondrous and how magnificent the locale is, and how enthralling the individual tasks and procedures which make up farming echoes our own coming around to feel similarly towards the film. Just as agricultural activity is fresh to that of Jean, the arrival of he and his family acts as a fresh and very crisp presence within the film to that of the audience; the very gradual bringing of the audience around on Berri's behalf to have us see the two original farmers as cruel and calculating businessmen as this initial outsider and his family capture our hearts, is outstanding. The film is a really well executed drama, a wonderful piece persistently flicking from tone to tone and character to character in perfect tandem; a film working on a level of family drama, fish out of water storytelling and dark comedy culminating in something quite special.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Enjoy the wonderful surroundings and relax
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Luigi Di Pilla
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The surroundings near Aubagne in the Bouche Du Rh&ocirc;ne in France are wonderfully shot. The story by Marcel Pagnol is well adapted that takes step by step a dramatic end. All the actors did a fine Job and I am curious to see part two "Manon La Source". The sceneries in the time after the second world war are well built and developed. I recommend you to watch it in the original south french dialect with English subtitles. I spent an enjoyable and relaxing Saturday night with my wife. Don't miss the other great movie from the writer Pagnol called La Fille Du Pusatier. Please read my critic on IMDb. Final vote: 8/10.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Flawless
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    yeltzmanmatt
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is a beautifully told tale of a hunchback who moves from the town to the country when he inherits a farm. The cinematography is brilliant and the languid pace of the movie suits this perfectly. The acting is out of the top drawer especially from Yves Montand and Daniel Autiel who are mesmerising as the farmers intent on grabbing Gerard Depardieu's land. Depardieu is also in fine form as the hunchback who although bombastic and stubborn eventually evokes a deal of sympathy. It is hard to fault this film on any level and it absorbs you from the start to the finale. Although you can watch the film on it's own the subsequent Manon Des Sources ( another fine film) concludes the story in full. I have known a fair few people who don't like foreign language films who have watched this and every one has enjoyed it. This is a French classic not to be missed.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Rare gem.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    (Draco2-0)
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I just watched Jean De Florrete and it was great, very rare for me to say this but I was not once bored or restless during the entire movie. Jean De Florrete, about this French farmer who moves onto his uncle's land and decides it would be profitable to grow flowers. But in order to grow a enough flowers to make a profit they'll need more water than they have available. Their neighbor has an untapped underground spring. The farmer and his uncle go over to negotiate buying the land with the spring on it. Unfortunately for them their neighbor hates the uncle, and when they offer to buy some of his land the uncle and him get into a fight and during the bustle his head suffers a fatal blow against a rock and he dies almost instantaneously. The whole ordeal took place by a tree, so the farmer and his uncle make it look like the old man fell from the tree and hit his head. They think the land will be theirs but a relative of the neighbor, a hunchback, moves onto the property. The uncle offers to buy the land from him but the hunchback wants to use it for raising rabbits and growing squash. Fascinating to watch the triumphs and failures of the hunchback as he goes about trying to fulfill his dream, always with a happy upbeat attitude. The thing that amazed me about the movie would be just how simple the actual plot feels. There are no huge twists, no distracting sub-plots, not much happens for most of the movie until the last 15 minutes; despite that it manages to grab the viewers attention wonderfully and it doesn't let it go until the credits roll either. Unless you hate French movies. I highly recommend Jean De Floret.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Jean de Florette / Manon of the Spring
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    runamokprods
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/7/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Two part film, that was 1st released as two separate features. Terrific telling of a complex story of intertwined farming families in rural France in the early part of the 20th century. The acting is mostly of the highest order. Yves Montand, one of the most suave men in history is completely believable as a rough hewn, self-centered farmer, Gerard Depardieu, also cast against type, as a gentle, educated city born man trying to make it as a farmer also is astounding. Almost as good is Daniel Auteuil as Montand's not-very-bright son. Only Emmanuelle Beart, gorgeous though she may be, doesn't quite convince me as the wild woman of the fields. Some of it is performance, some of it is how perfect she looks. The story is wonderful in a Dickensian sort of way, with clues and character elements showing up early, only to pay off three hours later. I love the first part even more, somehow it feels more truly tragic and dense, the 2nd part just a bit too neat by the end. But still a grand, intelligent, great looking entertainment.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "Remarkably narrated and invariably moving..."
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Sindre Kaspersen
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/3/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    French actor, producer, screenwriter and director Claude Berri's twelfth feature film which he co-wrote with French screenwriter G&eacute;rard Brach (1927-2006) is an adaptation of a novel, "L'Eau des Collines - Jean de Florette and Manon des Sources" (1964) by French author, playwright and filmmaker Marcel Pagnol (1895-1974), which was inspired by true events. It was shot on numerous locations in the Vaucluse department of Provence in the southeast of France and is part of a duology which was succeeded by "Manon des Sources" (1986). It tells the story about Ugolin Soubeyran who one summer after having served his time in World War I returns to his home in rural Provence where he is welcomed by his highly revered uncle Cesar Le Papet Soubeyran. Back at his home place in the highlands, Ugolin initiates a planned project which involves growing plants, but soon discovers that he is going to need a water resource to keep his enterprise afloat. He let's Papet in on his new activity and the old man is eager to help his nephew, but his good intentions get's the better of him and leads to fatal consequences. Though having their plan ruined they are dead set on finding a way to gain their obstacle, so when a man from the village named Jean Cadoret moves in to his newly inherited property with his wife Aim&egrave;e and their adolescent daughter Manon, the two farmers decides to mislead him. Subtly and acutely directed by French filmmaker Claude Berri (1934-2009) and with it's ardent and naturalistic milieu depictions and efficient narrative structure, this historic period piece, at the time the most expensive French film in French history, draws a throughout engaging portrayal of a kind-hearted and loving husband and father with an urban background who whilst struggling to create a good life for himself and his family in a rural area at the turn of the twentieth century, becomes a victim of deception and prejudice. This mid-1980s co-production between France, Italy and Switzerland, known as part of a movement in France during the 1980s called "heritage cinema" which mainly consisted of costume dramas, has a powerful score by French composer and arranger Jean-Claude Petit, based on Italian composer Giuseppe Verdi's Italian opera "The Force of Destiny" (1862), which reinforces the films pivotal atmosphere. Produced by French producers Pierre Grunstein and Alain Poir&eacute; (1917-2000) and notable for it's wonderful production design by production designer Bernard V&eacute;zat and cinematography by French director and cinematographer Bruno Nuytten, this character-driven and dialog-driven countryside epic which examines themes like interpersonal relations, greed, faith and the distinctions between human goodness and human cruelty is impelled by the splendid acting performances by French actor and producer G&eacute;rard Depardieu, Italian-born French actor and singer Yves Montand (1921-1991) and French actor, director and screenwriter Daniel Auteuil. A remarkably narrated and invariably moving drama which gained, among several other awards, the BAFTA Film Award for Best Film, Best cinematography Bruno Nuytten, Best Adapted Screenplay Claude Berri and G&eacute;rard Brach and Best Supporting Actor Daniel Auteuil at the 41st British Academy Film Awards in 1988, the NBR Award for Best Foreign Language Film at the National Board of Review of Motion Pictures Awards in 1987 and the C&eacute;sar Award for Best Actor Daniel Auteuil at the 13th C&eacute;sar Awards in 1987.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Slow but beautiful
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    billcr12
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Gerard Depardieu is Jean de Florette, a simple, hard working landowner and farmer who grows and sells flowers and also raises rabbits for food. Some of Jean's neighbors would like to buy his land but Jean refuses to sell to them. They then find the main spring nearby and plug it with cement to prevent water from reaching the farm. Jean has to travel a good distance to carry large containers to his farm. He later gets badly injured and they take advantage of the situation quickly. This is a simple and slow moving drama which looks like a painting come to life. It is followed by the equally masterful "Manon of the Spring."
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    J'adore!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    TheLittleSongbird
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Having been so blown away by Cyrano De Bergerac, I also watched Jean De Florette, also starring Gerard Depardieu. Jean De Florette is a very different film, but every bit as fantastic. Depardieu is very endearing in a performance that has in his career only been surpassed by Cyrano De Bergerac to me. Yves Montand and Daniel Auteuil are also outstanding as the scheming Soubeyrans. The acting is not Jean De Florette's only good asset. This is an example of a film where everything works. The story is beautifully paced and evocative, the script is witty and very cinematic, the cinematography shimmers, the scenery is breathtaking, the music is lively yet again very understated and the direction does wonderfully in capturing the pace of the seasons changing and Provence's unique atmosphere. All in all, I love this movie just as much as Cyrano De Bergerac, and I am watching Manon of the Spring(and loving it) even as we speak. 10/10 Bethany Cox
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A personal all-time favorite
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    olyrye
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/12/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is an epic film(s). (It must really be seen with Manon of the Spring, which is not a sequel but really the second part of the movie.) The photography, music, acting, writing, are top notch. A must see for any film buff. Full of eye and ear candy! It really stirred an emotional response in me, especially at the end. So many great movies flounder at the conclusion. This one delivers! It deals with the themes of family loyalty, miscommunication, love, betrayal, failure, and persistence in the face of catastrophe. But most importantly it deals with almost impossible redemption. This is a great movie to watch with your spouse or partner. It is equally appealing to both men and women and is a great film for a movie date!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Qualifies as a classic Greek tragedy.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    zjerunk
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/7/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I have many favorites, and this is one of the cr&egrave;me de la cr&egrave;me. This is a visually stunning film more like beautiful photographic montage. It is simple, tragic story well told, unlike many of today's plots - implausibly lame, suffering on a CGI crutch for 85 minutes. The simple story is about enduring truths which have been the mainstay of the Greek classics and Shakespeare: Our human strengths, our failings, our virtues, and our vices. The story may be a fiction, but its kernel is not. It is stories and story telling like this which has kept our rapt attention for four thousand years. First we should understand that this film is only the first half the novel by Marcel Pagnol which would have been too long as a single film, and out of necessity, was shot as two. The second half is titled, Manon of the Spring. Neither film stands alone as satisfactory because, obviously, it would be incomplete, and naturally, is also important that the two halves be viewed in sequence. For a fairly dispassionate pr&eacute;cis of the plots, I suggest reading the ones on Wikipedia, so I won't be repetitive here. I also recommend reading the boards for comments and discussions. JdF & MotS were both shot at the same time in 1986 with a budget of $17 million making it/them the biggest budget French films up to that time. JdF grossed $86M worldwide, and of that sum, only $4.9M was from the USA. MotS grossed $56M worldwide, of which only $3.9M was from the USA. In other words, culture films are not a good fit for the American viewing audience, and the gross revenue numbers bear this out. The rest of the world seems to bear out this conclusion. Foreign language films rarely do well in the USA for the simple reason that the vast majority of the viewing audience are unilingual anglophones who do not wish to burden themselves with having to work at "understanding" their entertainment - they wish to merely consume it. If it requires the work of reading subtitles or thought, it becomes unpalatable. This film requires your attention and thought! But to be fair to the US viewers, the subtitles are at times incomplete or inaccurate, and unlike the spoken word, they do not convey the emphasis or importance of certain bits of dialogue well. The plot is woven steadily throughout the film, so the viewers with no understanding at all of the French language are missing essential dialogue, and therefore plot. The bottom line is this: You will either be entranced by these two films and love them, or you will be bored by the first 15 minutes, and you'll translate that into "bad film." If your highest quality level of reading is Marvel comics then I suggest you stay away from this one. However, I recall years ago walking into a video store where this was playing on all the monitors. All the patrons in the store, ranging in age from 5 to 75 years, were standing transfixed watching this film. There was something magical about it!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Agonising; enrapturing and taut all-at-once period piece, detailing the struggles of two sets of farm-set family units at evens and odds with one another.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    johnnyboyz (j_l_h_m@yahoo.co.uk)
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/1/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Has farming, indeed agriculture in general, ever been as cinematic as it is in Claude Berri's Jean de Florette? The joy is in observing the rather articulate nuances that the characters must undertake when particular farming tasks require particular tools and items for a job at hand; the film eventually coming to resemble a tale about a man most probably as alien to farming as the audience and enjoying it as much as we enjoy watching his taking up of this challenge. The farming within the film, in its specificities revolving around the planning; the predicting; the techniques and the use of certain items and animals for certain events, is as intrinsic as the film's core study of greed and the capitalist infused garnering of an industrial item, an item which will bring large amounts of personal wealth and riches, eventually at the expense of others. The film eventually coming to form a remarkably executed, heart breakingly tragic, blackly comic, devilishly well put together period drama from France well worth checking out. The film begins with a young man named Ugolin (Auteuil) returning home to the South of France, and his uncle's farm, having served time with the French army; the soundtrack a dry and sleepy orchestral tune suggesting much in the way of travels and tiredness, only momentarily breaking off into louder bursts of a much more positive tone as he nears home. Upon arriving home, Ugolin takes clear glee in rushing to a small patch of soil on the grounds and unwrapping a plant of some kind so he may observe it; something he appears to enjoy more than being reconciled with his uncle after such a stretch of time and furthermore suggesting an inclination towards agricultural work, his dream eventually revealed to be one of which revolves around the growing and selling of flowers for a living. His uncle is Cesar (Montand), an elderly man whom demands Ugolin find a wife and have children in the near future so that the land may be passed down and kept within the family; his other eye on a stretch of land lying nearby to his own, a stretch functional enough as it stands and with a natural spring beneath it capable of escalating the quality of the goods that only Cesar knows of, but a stretch already owned by a man no way willing to just sell up. Berri spends a good deal of time with these two farmers, their dreams; their positions and their core characteristics filling up most of the film's opening act. We come to like them during this early part and their blackly funny misadventures as well as their dry observations on life and newfound situations which open up as a result of other events. We side with young Ugolin, this simple young man whom has only just returned from national service and wishes to move into floristry. It is only when the titular Jean of Florette arrives, in the form of G&eacute;rard Depardieu, that we see the true nature of them; Jean being the rightful heir to that of the land when Cesar and Ugolin accidentally-on-purpose murder the owner of the land thus bringing Jean into the equation following a string of other legal complications with the rightful land owner. Jean and his family of wife Aimee (Elisabeth Depardieu) and young daughter Manon (Mazurowna) are not used to such surroundings; their previous incarnation of living in a more urbanite locale ill preparing them for what they come into contact with here, the beauty and calmness of the locale coming to resemble mere surface featurettes as those within plot and brew. The obvious distinctions between themselves and those more attributed to the land arrive in the form of their clear differences in clothing, as well as their talk of things of a more cultured nature, namely the opera, as on occasion Aimee breaks out int chorus of song to Jean's own harmonica tunes. What unfolds is a game of cat and mouse and hope and frustration between the two farmers, in Ugolin and Cesar, and the Florettes whom hang around much to the annoyance of their neighbours whom still want the land, know of its true flourishing nature and retain the spring as their secret. Jean's gradual coming around to realise how wondrous and how magnificent the locale is, and how enthralling the individual tasks and procedures which make up farming echoes our own coming around to feel similarly towards the film. Just as agricultural activity is fresh to that of Jean, the arrival of he and his family acts as a fresh and very crisp presence within the film to that of the audience; the very gradual bringing of the audience around on Berri's behalf to have us see the two original farmers as cruel and calculating businessmen as this initial outsider and his family capture our hearts, is outstanding. The film is a really well executed drama, a wonderful piece persistently flicking from tone to tone and character to character in perfect tandem; a film working on a level of family drama, fish out of water storytelling and dark comedy culminating in something quite special.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
 </reviews>
</filme>
