<filme>
 <id>
  166
 </id>
 <imdburl>
  http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0091480
 </imdburl>
 <ano>
  1986
 </ano>
 <titulo>
  A Vingan&ccedil;a de Manon
 </titulo>
 <rating>
  7.9
 </rating>
 <sinopse>
  A beautiful but shy shepherdess plots vengeance on the men whose greedy conspiracy to acquire her her father's land caused his death years earlier.
 </sinopse>
 <storyline>
  In this, the sequel to Jean de Florette, Manon (Beart) has grown into a beautiful young shepherdess living in the idyllic Provencal countryside. She determines to take revenge upon the men responsible for the death of her father in the first film.
 </storyline>
 <generos>
  <genero>
   Drama
  </genero>
 </generos>
 <keywords>
  <keyword>
   spring
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   shepherdess
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   water
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   revenge
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   goatherd
  </keyword>
 </keywords>
 <diretores>
  <diretor>
   Claude Berri
  </diretor>
 </diretores>
 <escritores>
  <escritor>
   Claude Berri
  </escritor>
  <escritor>
   G&eacute;rard Brach
  </escritor>
 </escritores>
 <atores>
  <ator>
   Yves Montand
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Emmanuelle B&eacute;art
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Daniel Auteuil
  </ator>
 </atores>
 <reviews>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Dramatic sequel with a great Yves Montand
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Luigi Di Pilla
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This part two sticks dramatically to the first one. The wonderful girl Emmanuelle B&eacute;art delivered an interesting performance. Yves Montand did a great job here showing all the repertoire of this psychological character profile. He was really a great actor, chapeau. But Daniel Auteuil was also very credibly in this role until the end. Bravo. Finally, Claude Berri directed again like a master. Thank you for these two very nice films. Don't expect a fast paced story because it has a slow but surprising countdown. For all that likes the surroundings South of France this is a rich experience to not miss. See also the other highlight La Fille du Pusatier from the same writer Marcel Pagnol. Vote: 8/10.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Jean de Florette / Manon of the Spring
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    runamokprods
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/7/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Two part film, that was 1st released as two separate features. Terrific telling of a complex story of intertwined farming families in rural France in the early part of the 20th century. The acting is mostly of the highest order. Yves Montand, one of the most suave men in history is completely believable as a rough hewn, self-centered farmer, Gerard Depardieu, also cast against type, as a gentle, educated city born man trying to make it as a farmer also is astounding. Almost as good is Daniel Auteuil as Montand's not-very-bright son. Only Emmanuelle Beart, gorgeous though she may be, doesn't quite convince me as the wild woman of the fields. Some of it is performance, some of it is how perfect she looks. The story is wonderful in a Dickensian sort of way, with clues and character elements showing up early, only to pay off three hours later. I love the first part even more, somehow it feels more truly tragic and dense, the 2nd part just a bit too neat by the end. But still a grand, intelligent, great looking entertainment.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "Memorable, moving and humane..."
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Sindre Kaspersen
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/3/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    French actor, producer, screenwriter and director Claude Berri's thirteenth feature film which he co-wrote with French screenwriter G&egrave;rard Brach (1927-2006) is an adaptation of a novel, "L'Eau des Collines - Jean de Florette and Manon des Sources" (1964) by French author, playwright and filmmaker Marcel Pagnol (1895-1974), which was inspired by true events. It was shot on numerous locations in the Vaucluse department of Provence in the southeast of France and is part of a duo logy which was preceded by "Jean De Florette" (1986). It tells the story about Manon Cadoret who still lives in the highlands of Provence ten years after her and her mother Aime&eacute; had to sell their property to Cesar Le Papet Soubeyran and his nephew Ugolin Soubeyran. Manon has become a shepherd girl and lives a quiet life, but when she one summer day encounters Ugolin who now is a successful farmer, bad memories are awakened. Struck by the now grown up Manon who he has not seen since she was a little girl, Ugolin falls head over heels in love with her. But Manon still remembers what he and his uncle did to her family, and she has found a way to reveal their secret. Like the first part of this epic story, this continuation is subtly and acutely directed by French filmmaker Claude Berri (1934-2009) and with it's ardent milieu depictions and efficient narrative structure, it draws an incessantly engaging portrayal of a young French woman who has been waiting several years to get justice for what happened to her family a decade earlier in time. This reverent sequel from the mid-1980s, produced by French producers Pierre Grunstein and Alain Poir&eacute; (1917-2000), is a co-production between France, Italy and Switzerland and has a powerful score by French composer Jean-Claude Petit, based on Italian composer Giuseppe Verdi's Italian opera "The Force of Destiny" (1862), which reinforces the film's atmosphere. Notable for it's wonderful production design by production designer Bernard V&eacute;zat and cinematography by French director and cinematographer Bruno Nuytten which is as present here as in the first segment, this historical period drama becomes an in-depth study of character that examines themes such as family relations, faith, morality and love, and is impelled by Yves Montand, Emmanuelle B&eacute;art and Daniel Auteuil's compassionate acting performances. A memorable, moving and humane film which gained, among other awards, the C&eacute;sar Award for best supporting actress Emmanuelle B&eacute;art at the 13th C&eacute;sar Awards in 1987 and the KCFCC Award for Best Foreign Language Film at the Kansas City Film Critics Circle Awards in 1988.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Beautiful sequel to Jean de Florette
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    billcr12
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Emmanuelle Beart is Manon, the beautiful daughter of Jean de Florette from the film of the same name which continues the story of the farmer who was tricked out of his land by unscrupulous neighbors. Beart as Manon is breathtakingly gorgeous, perfectly cast as a shepherdess who while leading a flock of sheep and bathing in the nude is looked upon by the son of the man who destroyed her fathers life. Manon discovers the secret and plots revenge on the evil doers. Manon manages to pay back the people who did her father wrong in this equally picturesque and emotional follow up to Jean de Florette. I would recommend watching the two films one after the other.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    How to do revenge!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    brimon28
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    When this film was released in Australia, it preceded the release of 'Jean de Florette', the first episode in what really is a continuing tale. Therefore, viewers were mystified by the story, even if they were impressed by the performances. 'Jean de Florette' appeared some months later, too late for cineastes to see Manon again. Luckily, the two are now being presented as a package, giving filmgoers a chance to see the two in the correct order. The result is very impressive indeed. The French continue to give us lessons in movie-making, and this duo was a change from the New Wave that showed us all how movies can be made. Emotions are to the fore, and Manon has revenge imprinted on it. 'Jean de Florette' gave us a hint, as the young Manon listens - and sees. She doesn't say much, but her face tells us that she is thinking through a resolution. I'm reminded of Nicole Kidman, in 'Dogville'. The character, Grace, is put upon by the locals, just as is Manon. The American treatment of revenge is different, with a different kind of violence. Dogville's conclusion is shocking and heart-rending; Whether you regard Emmanuelle Beart's face as more expressive than Nicole Kidman's is probably a very personal thing. But Manon's cold fury is a cinematic masterpiece, and we are well-prepared for the finale. This movie is so good I've no desire to read the book!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Amazing film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    TheLittleSongbird
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Having adored Jean De Florette, of which Manon of the Spring(or Manon Des Sources) follows on from, I found this film every bit as amazing. Once again the cinematography shimmers and the scenery is some of the best I have seen in any film. There is also a haunting score, a compelling story and a genuinely moving script, and Berri's direction is paced perfectly to suit life under the scorching sun. The performances are every bit as impressive, Emmanuelle Beart is alluring and very believable, and Yves Montand and Daniel Auteuil are once again outstanding, particularly Auteuil when he tries to atone. Overall, an amazing and I think poignant film. 10/10 Bethany Cox
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Really is a masterpiece, just watch it.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    1200 mr
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/8/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    no doubt its a masterpiece. movies like these cannot be produced on a regular base, its a beauty for all those people who are sick of today's computer effects based movies. Water, jungle, flowers, rocks, natural atmosphere and a beautiful face (Emmanuelle B&eacute;art) what else u want in a movie. Though she does not show too much of her assets (there is very brief scene of nudity) but her beauty was on peak in 1986. Emmanuelle is totally irresistible in this movie. story is excellent, all actors performed very well their characters and this is why its overall rating is above 8. I watched it in french luckily subtitles were available in English and after watching this i thought where the hell was this before, i should have seen this before.So guys don't wait and just watch dis classic.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Qualifies as a classic Greek tragedy.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    zjerunk
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/7/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I have many favorites, and this is one of the cr&egrave;me de la cr&egrave;me. This is a visually stunning film more like beautiful photographic montage. It is simple, tragic story well told, unlike many of today's plots - implausibly lame, suffering on a CGI crutch for 85 minutes. The simple story is about enduring truths which have been the mainstay of the Greek classics and Shakespeare: Our human strengths, our failings, our virtues, and our vices. The story may be a fiction, but its kernel is not. It is stories and story telling like this which has kept our rapt attention for four thousand years. First we should understand that this film is NOT A SEQUEL, but the second half the novel by Marcel Pagnol which would have been too long as a single film, and out of necessity, was shot as two. The first half is titled, Jean de Florette. Neither film stands alone as satisfactory because, obviously, it would be incomplete, and naturally, is also important that the two halves be viewed in sequence. For a fairly dispassionate pr&eacute;cis of the plots, I suggest reading the ones on Wikipedia and the discussion boards, so I won't be repetitive here. JdF & MotS were both shot at the same time in 1986 with a budget of $17 million making it/them the biggest budget French films up to that time. JdF grossed $86M worldwide, and of that sum, only $4.9M was from the USA. MotS grossed $56M worldwide, of which only $3.9M was from the USA. In other words, culture films are not a good fit for the American viewing audience, and the gross revenue numbers bear this out. The rest of the world seems to bear out this conclusion. Foreign language films rarely do well in the USA for the simple reason that the vast majority of the viewing audience are unilingual anglophones who do not wish to burden themselves with having to work at "understanding" their entertainment - they wish to merely consume it. If it requires the work of reading subtitles or thought, it becomes unpalatable. This film requires your attention and thought! But to be fair to the US viewers, the subtitles are at times incomplete or inaccurate, and unlike the spoken word, they do not convey the emphasis or importance of certain bits of dialogue well. The plot is woven steadily throughout the film, so the viewers with no understanding at all of the French language are missing essential dialogue, and therefore plot. The bottom line is this: You will either be entranced by these two films and love them, or you will be bored by the first 15 minutes, and you'll translate that into "bad film." If your highest quality level of reading is Marvel comics then I suggest you stay away from this one. However, I recall years ago walking into a video store where this was playing on all the monitors. All the patrons in the store, ranging in age from 5 to 75 years, were standing transfixed watching this film. There was something magical about it!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Excellent conclusion to Jean de Florette
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Red-Barracuda
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/7/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Manon des Sources is the second part of Jean de Florette. It's important to point out that it is a continuation of the story not a sequel. It takes on the narrative ten years down the line where Papet and Ugolin are reaping the benefits of cheating Jean from his land. Meanwhile Jean's daughter Manon (the beautiful Emmanuele B&eacute;art) roams the surrounding hills with her herd of goats - a constant reminder to the two men of the terrible injustice they committed against her and her family. To make matters a little more complicated Ugolin falls in love with this now gorgeous young woman, while she in turn falls for a local teacher. Manon still understandably holds a huge grudge against the men who she knows were indirectly responsible for her father's death, and the villagers too who she discovers knew of the scheming but did nothing. When she discovers the source of the water that feeds the village her revenge is set into motion... As a pair of movies Jean de Florette and Manon des Sources are a terrific example of the French heritage film. These movies play upon notions of nostalgia for a bygone era in France. The rural setting is beautifully evoked but more importantly the storyline is consistently strong and compelling, with great performances from all actors across both movies. If anything Manon des Sources is the greater of the two films, as it essentially satisfyingly concludes the storyline and gives the closure that we the audience want. The villains meet suitable ends and Manon herself finds true happiness. This summary may seem very hackneyed to anyone who has not seen them but these movies are handled with such a beautiful touch that their traditional narratives seem perfect. That said, the ending does provide us with a great little twist in a magnificent scene between Papet and a blind woman called Delphine. This revelatory scene in a graveyard offers a whole new dimension to the film and adds to the overall whole immeasurably. Jean de Florette and Manos des Sources are I suppose old fashioned movies in many respects. But they are old fashioned in the best ways. They offer quality cinema without patronising the viewer and have enough twists and turns and emotional involvement to satisfy the most jaded of cinema fans. A definite treat.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    payback is a bitch
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Michael Neumann
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/12/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The second half of Claude Berri's elegant two-part Proven&ccedil;al epic shares with 'Jean de Florette' the same sun washed, arid landscapes, the same rich tapestry of events, and many of the same hardy peasant characters. Here again is the unscrupulous landowner Le Papet and his weak-willed simpleton nephew Ugolin, along with the beautiful but untamed Manon, now grown to womanhood and living wild in the hills, where she decides to fight water with water (or a lack of it) by blocking the source of the vital spring supplying the nearby village. The sequel ties up all the narrative threads left dangling at the end of the earlier film (and as a result is more plot-heavy than its predecessor), but Manon's revenge against the men who (indirectly) murdered her father isn't as sweet as it should have been. After driving the love struck Ugolin to suicide (by simply ignoring his pathetic advances), she virtually disappears from the story, leaving Le Papet to a fate of his own design, outlined in some lumpy exposition before the heartbreaking conclusion. The rich local flavor and surprising unpretentiousness make it a worthwhile and often moving drama, but despite the title the film belongs to Yves Montand and Daniel Auteuil. Emmanuelle B&eacute;art, as Manon, doesn't have more than a dozen lines of dialogue, and her fashion model looks are a distraction.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Dramatic sequel with a great Yves Montand
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Luigi Di Pilla
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This part two sticks dramatically to the first one. The wonderful girl Emmanuelle B&eacute;art delivered an interesting performance. Yves Montand did a great job here showing all the repertoire of this psychological character profile. He was really a great actor, chapeau. But Daniel Auteuil was also very credibly in this role until the end. Bravo. Finally, Claude Berri directed again like a master. Thank you for these two very nice films. Don't expect a fast paced story because it has a slow but surprising countdown. For all that likes the surroundings South of France this is a rich experience to not miss. See also the other highlight La Fille du Pusatier from the same writer Marcel Pagnol. Vote: 8/10.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Jean de Florette / Manon of the Spring
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    runamokprods
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/7/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Two part film, that was 1st released as two separate features. Terrific telling of a complex story of intertwined farming families in rural France in the early part of the 20th century. The acting is mostly of the highest order. Yves Montand, one of the most suave men in history is completely believable as a rough hewn, self-centered farmer, Gerard Depardieu, also cast against type, as a gentle, educated city born man trying to make it as a farmer also is astounding. Almost as good is Daniel Auteuil as Montand's not-very-bright son. Only Emmanuelle Beart, gorgeous though she may be, doesn't quite convince me as the wild woman of the fields. Some of it is performance, some of it is how perfect she looks. The story is wonderful in a Dickensian sort of way, with clues and character elements showing up early, only to pay off three hours later. I love the first part even more, somehow it feels more truly tragic and dense, the 2nd part just a bit too neat by the end. But still a grand, intelligent, great looking entertainment.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "Memorable, moving and humane..."
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Sindre Kaspersen
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/3/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    French actor, producer, screenwriter and director Claude Berri's thirteenth feature film which he co-wrote with French screenwriter G&egrave;rard Brach (1927-2006) is an adaptation of a novel, "L'Eau des Collines - Jean de Florette and Manon des Sources" (1964) by French author, playwright and filmmaker Marcel Pagnol (1895-1974), which was inspired by true events. It was shot on numerous locations in the Vaucluse department of Provence in the southeast of France and is part of a duo logy which was preceded by "Jean De Florette" (1986). It tells the story about Manon Cadoret who still lives in the highlands of Provence ten years after her and her mother Aime&eacute; had to sell their property to Cesar Le Papet Soubeyran and his nephew Ugolin Soubeyran. Manon has become a shepherd girl and lives a quiet life, but when she one summer day encounters Ugolin who now is a successful farmer, bad memories are awakened. Struck by the now grown up Manon who he has not seen since she was a little girl, Ugolin falls head over heels in love with her. But Manon still remembers what he and his uncle did to her family, and she has found a way to reveal their secret. Like the first part of this epic story, this continuation is subtly and acutely directed by French filmmaker Claude Berri (1934-2009) and with it's ardent milieu depictions and efficient narrative structure, it draws an incessantly engaging portrayal of a young French woman who has been waiting several years to get justice for what happened to her family a decade earlier in time. This reverent sequel from the mid-1980s, produced by French producers Pierre Grunstein and Alain Poir&eacute; (1917-2000), is a co-production between France, Italy and Switzerland and has a powerful score by French composer Jean-Claude Petit, based on Italian composer Giuseppe Verdi's Italian opera "The Force of Destiny" (1862), which reinforces the film's atmosphere. Notable for it's wonderful production design by production designer Bernard V&eacute;zat and cinematography by French director and cinematographer Bruno Nuytten which is as present here as in the first segment, this historical period drama becomes an in-depth study of character that examines themes such as family relations, faith, morality and love, and is impelled by Yves Montand, Emmanuelle B&eacute;art and Daniel Auteuil's compassionate acting performances. A memorable, moving and humane film which gained, among other awards, the C&eacute;sar Award for best supporting actress Emmanuelle B&eacute;art at the 13th C&eacute;sar Awards in 1987 and the KCFCC Award for Best Foreign Language Film at the Kansas City Film Critics Circle Awards in 1988.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Beautiful sequel to Jean de Florette
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    billcr12
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Emmanuelle Beart is Manon, the beautiful daughter of Jean de Florette from the film of the same name which continues the story of the farmer who was tricked out of his land by unscrupulous neighbors. Beart as Manon is breathtakingly gorgeous, perfectly cast as a shepherdess who while leading a flock of sheep and bathing in the nude is looked upon by the son of the man who destroyed her fathers life. Manon discovers the secret and plots revenge on the evil doers. Manon manages to pay back the people who did her father wrong in this equally picturesque and emotional follow up to Jean de Florette. I would recommend watching the two films one after the other.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    How to do revenge!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    brimon28
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    When this film was released in Australia, it preceded the release of 'Jean de Florette', the first episode in what really is a continuing tale. Therefore, viewers were mystified by the story, even if they were impressed by the performances. 'Jean de Florette' appeared some months later, too late for cineastes to see Manon again. Luckily, the two are now being presented as a package, giving filmgoers a chance to see the two in the correct order. The result is very impressive indeed. The French continue to give us lessons in movie-making, and this duo was a change from the New Wave that showed us all how movies can be made. Emotions are to the fore, and Manon has revenge imprinted on it. 'Jean de Florette' gave us a hint, as the young Manon listens - and sees. She doesn't say much, but her face tells us that she is thinking through a resolution. I'm reminded of Nicole Kidman, in 'Dogville'. The character, Grace, is put upon by the locals, just as is Manon. The American treatment of revenge is different, with a different kind of violence. Dogville's conclusion is shocking and heart-rending; Whether you regard Emmanuelle Beart's face as more expressive than Nicole Kidman's is probably a very personal thing. But Manon's cold fury is a cinematic masterpiece, and we are well-prepared for the finale. This movie is so good I've no desire to read the book!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Amazing film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    TheLittleSongbird
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Having adored Jean De Florette, of which Manon of the Spring(or Manon Des Sources) follows on from, I found this film every bit as amazing. Once again the cinematography shimmers and the scenery is some of the best I have seen in any film. There is also a haunting score, a compelling story and a genuinely moving script, and Berri's direction is paced perfectly to suit life under the scorching sun. The performances are every bit as impressive, Emmanuelle Beart is alluring and very believable, and Yves Montand and Daniel Auteuil are once again outstanding, particularly Auteuil when he tries to atone. Overall, an amazing and I think poignant film. 10/10 Bethany Cox
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Really is a masterpiece, just watch it.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    1200 mr
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/8/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    no doubt its a masterpiece. movies like these cannot be produced on a regular base, its a beauty for all those people who are sick of today's computer effects based movies. Water, jungle, flowers, rocks, natural atmosphere and a beautiful face (Emmanuelle B&eacute;art) what else u want in a movie. Though she does not show too much of her assets (there is very brief scene of nudity) but her beauty was on peak in 1986. Emmanuelle is totally irresistible in this movie. story is excellent, all actors performed very well their characters and this is why its overall rating is above 8. I watched it in french luckily subtitles were available in English and after watching this i thought where the hell was this before, i should have seen this before.So guys don't wait and just watch dis classic.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Qualifies as a classic Greek tragedy.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    zjerunk
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/7/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I have many favorites, and this is one of the cr&egrave;me de la cr&egrave;me. This is a visually stunning film more like beautiful photographic montage. It is simple, tragic story well told, unlike many of today's plots - implausibly lame, suffering on a CGI crutch for 85 minutes. The simple story is about enduring truths which have been the mainstay of the Greek classics and Shakespeare: Our human strengths, our failings, our virtues, and our vices. The story may be a fiction, but its kernel is not. It is stories and story telling like this which has kept our rapt attention for four thousand years. First we should understand that this film is NOT A SEQUEL, but the second half the novel by Marcel Pagnol which would have been too long as a single film, and out of necessity, was shot as two. The first half is titled, Jean de Florette. Neither film stands alone as satisfactory because, obviously, it would be incomplete, and naturally, is also important that the two halves be viewed in sequence. For a fairly dispassionate pr&eacute;cis of the plots, I suggest reading the ones on Wikipedia and the discussion boards, so I won't be repetitive here. JdF & MotS were both shot at the same time in 1986 with a budget of $17 million making it/them the biggest budget French films up to that time. JdF grossed $86M worldwide, and of that sum, only $4.9M was from the USA. MotS grossed $56M worldwide, of which only $3.9M was from the USA. In other words, culture films are not a good fit for the American viewing audience, and the gross revenue numbers bear this out. The rest of the world seems to bear out this conclusion. Foreign language films rarely do well in the USA for the simple reason that the vast majority of the viewing audience are unilingual anglophones who do not wish to burden themselves with having to work at "understanding" their entertainment - they wish to merely consume it. If it requires the work of reading subtitles or thought, it becomes unpalatable. This film requires your attention and thought! But to be fair to the US viewers, the subtitles are at times incomplete or inaccurate, and unlike the spoken word, they do not convey the emphasis or importance of certain bits of dialogue well. The plot is woven steadily throughout the film, so the viewers with no understanding at all of the French language are missing essential dialogue, and therefore plot. The bottom line is this: You will either be entranced by these two films and love them, or you will be bored by the first 15 minutes, and you'll translate that into "bad film." If your highest quality level of reading is Marvel comics then I suggest you stay away from this one. However, I recall years ago walking into a video store where this was playing on all the monitors. All the patrons in the store, ranging in age from 5 to 75 years, were standing transfixed watching this film. There was something magical about it!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Excellent conclusion to Jean de Florette
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Red-Barracuda
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/7/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Manon des Sources is the second part of Jean de Florette. It's important to point out that it is a continuation of the story not a sequel. It takes on the narrative ten years down the line where Papet and Ugolin are reaping the benefits of cheating Jean from his land. Meanwhile Jean's daughter Manon (the beautiful Emmanuele B&eacute;art) roams the surrounding hills with her herd of goats - a constant reminder to the two men of the terrible injustice they committed against her and her family. To make matters a little more complicated Ugolin falls in love with this now gorgeous young woman, while she in turn falls for a local teacher. Manon still understandably holds a huge grudge against the men who she knows were indirectly responsible for her father's death, and the villagers too who she discovers knew of the scheming but did nothing. When she discovers the source of the water that feeds the village her revenge is set into motion... As a pair of movies Jean de Florette and Manon des Sources are a terrific example of the French heritage film. These movies play upon notions of nostalgia for a bygone era in France. The rural setting is beautifully evoked but more importantly the storyline is consistently strong and compelling, with great performances from all actors across both movies. If anything Manon des Sources is the greater of the two films, as it essentially satisfyingly concludes the storyline and gives the closure that we the audience want. The villains meet suitable ends and Manon herself finds true happiness. This summary may seem very hackneyed to anyone who has not seen them but these movies are handled with such a beautiful touch that their traditional narratives seem perfect. That said, the ending does provide us with a great little twist in a magnificent scene between Papet and a blind woman called Delphine. This revelatory scene in a graveyard offers a whole new dimension to the film and adds to the overall whole immeasurably. Jean de Florette and Manos des Sources are I suppose old fashioned movies in many respects. But they are old fashioned in the best ways. They offer quality cinema without patronising the viewer and have enough twists and turns and emotional involvement to satisfy the most jaded of cinema fans. A definite treat.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    payback is a bitch
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Michael Neumann
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/12/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The second half of Claude Berri's elegant two-part Proven&ccedil;al epic shares with 'Jean de Florette' the same sun washed, arid landscapes, the same rich tapestry of events, and many of the same hardy peasant characters. Here again is the unscrupulous landowner Le Papet and his weak-willed simpleton nephew Ugolin, along with the beautiful but untamed Manon, now grown to womanhood and living wild in the hills, where she decides to fight water with water (or a lack of it) by blocking the source of the vital spring supplying the nearby village. The sequel ties up all the narrative threads left dangling at the end of the earlier film (and as a result is more plot-heavy than its predecessor), but Manon's revenge against the men who (indirectly) murdered her father isn't as sweet as it should have been. After driving the love struck Ugolin to suicide (by simply ignoring his pathetic advances), she virtually disappears from the story, leaving Le Papet to a fate of his own design, outlined in some lumpy exposition before the heartbreaking conclusion. The rich local flavor and surprising unpretentiousness make it a worthwhile and often moving drama, but despite the title the film belongs to Yves Montand and Daniel Auteuil. Emmanuelle B&eacute;art, as Manon, doesn't have more than a dozen lines of dialogue, and her fashion model looks are a distraction.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Dramatic sequel with a great Yves Montand
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Luigi Di Pilla
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This part two sticks dramatically to the first one. The wonderful girl Emmanuelle B&eacute;art delivered an interesting performance. Yves Montand did a great job here showing all the repertoire of this psychological character profile. He was really a great actor, chapeau. But Daniel Auteuil was also very credibly in this role until the end. Bravo. Finally, Claude Berri directed again like a master. Thank you for these two very nice films. Don't expect a fast paced story because it has a slow but surprising countdown. For all that likes the surroundings South of France this is a rich experience to not miss. See also the other highlight La Fille du Pusatier from the same writer Marcel Pagnol. Vote: 8/10.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Jean de Florette / Manon of the Spring
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    runamokprods
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/7/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Two part film, that was 1st released as two separate features. Terrific telling of a complex story of intertwined farming families in rural France in the early part of the 20th century. The acting is mostly of the highest order. Yves Montand, one of the most suave men in history is completely believable as a rough hewn, self-centered farmer, Gerard Depardieu, also cast against type, as a gentle, educated city born man trying to make it as a farmer also is astounding. Almost as good is Daniel Auteuil as Montand's not-very-bright son. Only Emmanuelle Beart, gorgeous though she may be, doesn't quite convince me as the wild woman of the fields. Some of it is performance, some of it is how perfect she looks. The story is wonderful in a Dickensian sort of way, with clues and character elements showing up early, only to pay off three hours later. I love the first part even more, somehow it feels more truly tragic and dense, the 2nd part just a bit too neat by the end. But still a grand, intelligent, great looking entertainment.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "Memorable, moving and humane..."
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Sindre Kaspersen
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/3/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    French actor, producer, screenwriter and director Claude Berri's thirteenth feature film which he co-wrote with French screenwriter G&egrave;rard Brach (1927-2006) is an adaptation of a novel, "L'Eau des Collines - Jean de Florette and Manon des Sources" (1964) by French author, playwright and filmmaker Marcel Pagnol (1895-1974), which was inspired by true events. It was shot on numerous locations in the Vaucluse department of Provence in the southeast of France and is part of a duo logy which was preceded by "Jean De Florette" (1986). It tells the story about Manon Cadoret who still lives in the highlands of Provence ten years after her and her mother Aime&eacute; had to sell their property to Cesar Le Papet Soubeyran and his nephew Ugolin Soubeyran. Manon has become a shepherd girl and lives a quiet life, but when she one summer day encounters Ugolin who now is a successful farmer, bad memories are awakened. Struck by the now grown up Manon who he has not seen since she was a little girl, Ugolin falls head over heels in love with her. But Manon still remembers what he and his uncle did to her family, and she has found a way to reveal their secret. Like the first part of this epic story, this continuation is subtly and acutely directed by French filmmaker Claude Berri (1934-2009) and with it's ardent milieu depictions and efficient narrative structure, it draws an incessantly engaging portrayal of a young French woman who has been waiting several years to get justice for what happened to her family a decade earlier in time. This reverent sequel from the mid-1980s, produced by French producers Pierre Grunstein and Alain Poir&eacute; (1917-2000), is a co-production between France, Italy and Switzerland and has a powerful score by French composer Jean-Claude Petit, based on Italian composer Giuseppe Verdi's Italian opera "The Force of Destiny" (1862), which reinforces the film's atmosphere. Notable for it's wonderful production design by production designer Bernard V&eacute;zat and cinematography by French director and cinematographer Bruno Nuytten which is as present here as in the first segment, this historical period drama becomes an in-depth study of character that examines themes such as family relations, faith, morality and love, and is impelled by Yves Montand, Emmanuelle B&eacute;art and Daniel Auteuil's compassionate acting performances. A memorable, moving and humane film which gained, among other awards, the C&eacute;sar Award for best supporting actress Emmanuelle B&eacute;art at the 13th C&eacute;sar Awards in 1987 and the KCFCC Award for Best Foreign Language Film at the Kansas City Film Critics Circle Awards in 1988.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Beautiful sequel to Jean de Florette
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    billcr12
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Emmanuelle Beart is Manon, the beautiful daughter of Jean de Florette from the film of the same name which continues the story of the farmer who was tricked out of his land by unscrupulous neighbors. Beart as Manon is breathtakingly gorgeous, perfectly cast as a shepherdess who while leading a flock of sheep and bathing in the nude is looked upon by the son of the man who destroyed her fathers life. Manon discovers the secret and plots revenge on the evil doers. Manon manages to pay back the people who did her father wrong in this equally picturesque and emotional follow up to Jean de Florette. I would recommend watching the two films one after the other.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    How to do revenge!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    brimon28
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    When this film was released in Australia, it preceded the release of 'Jean de Florette', the first episode in what really is a continuing tale. Therefore, viewers were mystified by the story, even if they were impressed by the performances. 'Jean de Florette' appeared some months later, too late for cineastes to see Manon again. Luckily, the two are now being presented as a package, giving filmgoers a chance to see the two in the correct order. The result is very impressive indeed. The French continue to give us lessons in movie-making, and this duo was a change from the New Wave that showed us all how movies can be made. Emotions are to the fore, and Manon has revenge imprinted on it. 'Jean de Florette' gave us a hint, as the young Manon listens - and sees. She doesn't say much, but her face tells us that she is thinking through a resolution. I'm reminded of Nicole Kidman, in 'Dogville'. The character, Grace, is put upon by the locals, just as is Manon. The American treatment of revenge is different, with a different kind of violence. Dogville's conclusion is shocking and heart-rending; Whether you regard Emmanuelle Beart's face as more expressive than Nicole Kidman's is probably a very personal thing. But Manon's cold fury is a cinematic masterpiece, and we are well-prepared for the finale. This movie is so good I've no desire to read the book!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Amazing film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    TheLittleSongbird
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Having adored Jean De Florette, of which Manon of the Spring(or Manon Des Sources) follows on from, I found this film every bit as amazing. Once again the cinematography shimmers and the scenery is some of the best I have seen in any film. There is also a haunting score, a compelling story and a genuinely moving script, and Berri's direction is paced perfectly to suit life under the scorching sun. The performances are every bit as impressive, Emmanuelle Beart is alluring and very believable, and Yves Montand and Daniel Auteuil are once again outstanding, particularly Auteuil when he tries to atone. Overall, an amazing and I think poignant film. 10/10 Bethany Cox
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Really is a masterpiece, just watch it.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    1200 mr
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/8/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    no doubt its a masterpiece. movies like these cannot be produced on a regular base, its a beauty for all those people who are sick of today's computer effects based movies. Water, jungle, flowers, rocks, natural atmosphere and a beautiful face (Emmanuelle B&eacute;art) what else u want in a movie. Though she does not show too much of her assets (there is very brief scene of nudity) but her beauty was on peak in 1986. Emmanuelle is totally irresistible in this movie. story is excellent, all actors performed very well their characters and this is why its overall rating is above 8. I watched it in french luckily subtitles were available in English and after watching this i thought where the hell was this before, i should have seen this before.So guys don't wait and just watch dis classic.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Qualifies as a classic Greek tragedy.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    zjerunk
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/7/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I have many favorites, and this is one of the cr&egrave;me de la cr&egrave;me. This is a visually stunning film more like beautiful photographic montage. It is simple, tragic story well told, unlike many of today's plots - implausibly lame, suffering on a CGI crutch for 85 minutes. The simple story is about enduring truths which have been the mainstay of the Greek classics and Shakespeare: Our human strengths, our failings, our virtues, and our vices. The story may be a fiction, but its kernel is not. It is stories and story telling like this which has kept our rapt attention for four thousand years. First we should understand that this film is NOT A SEQUEL, but the second half the novel by Marcel Pagnol which would have been too long as a single film, and out of necessity, was shot as two. The first half is titled, Jean de Florette. Neither film stands alone as satisfactory because, obviously, it would be incomplete, and naturally, is also important that the two halves be viewed in sequence. For a fairly dispassionate pr&eacute;cis of the plots, I suggest reading the ones on Wikipedia and the discussion boards, so I won't be repetitive here. JdF & MotS were both shot at the same time in 1986 with a budget of $17 million making it/them the biggest budget French films up to that time. JdF grossed $86M worldwide, and of that sum, only $4.9M was from the USA. MotS grossed $56M worldwide, of which only $3.9M was from the USA. In other words, culture films are not a good fit for the American viewing audience, and the gross revenue numbers bear this out. The rest of the world seems to bear out this conclusion. Foreign language films rarely do well in the USA for the simple reason that the vast majority of the viewing audience are unilingual anglophones who do not wish to burden themselves with having to work at "understanding" their entertainment - they wish to merely consume it. If it requires the work of reading subtitles or thought, it becomes unpalatable. This film requires your attention and thought! But to be fair to the US viewers, the subtitles are at times incomplete or inaccurate, and unlike the spoken word, they do not convey the emphasis or importance of certain bits of dialogue well. The plot is woven steadily throughout the film, so the viewers with no understanding at all of the French language are missing essential dialogue, and therefore plot. The bottom line is this: You will either be entranced by these two films and love them, or you will be bored by the first 15 minutes, and you'll translate that into "bad film." If your highest quality level of reading is Marvel comics then I suggest you stay away from this one. However, I recall years ago walking into a video store where this was playing on all the monitors. All the patrons in the store, ranging in age from 5 to 75 years, were standing transfixed watching this film. There was something magical about it!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Excellent conclusion to Jean de Florette
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Red-Barracuda
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/7/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Manon des Sources is the second part of Jean de Florette. It's important to point out that it is a continuation of the story not a sequel. It takes on the narrative ten years down the line where Papet and Ugolin are reaping the benefits of cheating Jean from his land. Meanwhile Jean's daughter Manon (the beautiful Emmanuele B&eacute;art) roams the surrounding hills with her herd of goats - a constant reminder to the two men of the terrible injustice they committed against her and her family. To make matters a little more complicated Ugolin falls in love with this now gorgeous young woman, while she in turn falls for a local teacher. Manon still understandably holds a huge grudge against the men who she knows were indirectly responsible for her father's death, and the villagers too who she discovers knew of the scheming but did nothing. When she discovers the source of the water that feeds the village her revenge is set into motion... As a pair of movies Jean de Florette and Manon des Sources are a terrific example of the French heritage film. These movies play upon notions of nostalgia for a bygone era in France. The rural setting is beautifully evoked but more importantly the storyline is consistently strong and compelling, with great performances from all actors across both movies. If anything Manon des Sources is the greater of the two films, as it essentially satisfyingly concludes the storyline and gives the closure that we the audience want. The villains meet suitable ends and Manon herself finds true happiness. This summary may seem very hackneyed to anyone who has not seen them but these movies are handled with such a beautiful touch that their traditional narratives seem perfect. That said, the ending does provide us with a great little twist in a magnificent scene between Papet and a blind woman called Delphine. This revelatory scene in a graveyard offers a whole new dimension to the film and adds to the overall whole immeasurably. Jean de Florette and Manos des Sources are I suppose old fashioned movies in many respects. But they are old fashioned in the best ways. They offer quality cinema without patronising the viewer and have enough twists and turns and emotional involvement to satisfy the most jaded of cinema fans. A definite treat.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    payback is a bitch
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Michael Neumann
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/12/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The second half of Claude Berri's elegant two-part Proven&ccedil;al epic shares with 'Jean de Florette' the same sun washed, arid landscapes, the same rich tapestry of events, and many of the same hardy peasant characters. Here again is the unscrupulous landowner Le Papet and his weak-willed simpleton nephew Ugolin, along with the beautiful but untamed Manon, now grown to womanhood and living wild in the hills, where she decides to fight water with water (or a lack of it) by blocking the source of the vital spring supplying the nearby village. The sequel ties up all the narrative threads left dangling at the end of the earlier film (and as a result is more plot-heavy than its predecessor), but Manon's revenge against the men who (indirectly) murdered her father isn't as sweet as it should have been. After driving the love struck Ugolin to suicide (by simply ignoring his pathetic advances), she virtually disappears from the story, leaving Le Papet to a fate of his own design, outlined in some lumpy exposition before the heartbreaking conclusion. The rich local flavor and surprising unpretentiousness make it a worthwhile and often moving drama, but despite the title the film belongs to Yves Montand and Daniel Auteuil. Emmanuelle B&eacute;art, as Manon, doesn't have more than a dozen lines of dialogue, and her fashion model looks are a distraction.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Dramatic sequel with a great Yves Montand
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Luigi Di Pilla
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This part two sticks dramatically to the first one. The wonderful girl Emmanuelle B&eacute;art delivered an interesting performance. Yves Montand did a great job here showing all the repertoire of this psychological character profile. He was really a great actor, chapeau. But Daniel Auteuil was also very credibly in this role until the end. Bravo. Finally, Claude Berri directed again like a master. Thank you for these two very nice films. Don't expect a fast paced story because it has a slow but surprising countdown. For all that likes the surroundings South of France this is a rich experience to not miss. See also the other highlight La Fille du Pusatier from the same writer Marcel Pagnol. Vote: 8/10.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Jean de Florette / Manon of the Spring
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    runamokprods
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/7/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Two part film, that was 1st released as two separate features. Terrific telling of a complex story of intertwined farming families in rural France in the early part of the 20th century. The acting is mostly of the highest order. Yves Montand, one of the most suave men in history is completely believable as a rough hewn, self-centered farmer, Gerard Depardieu, also cast against type, as a gentle, educated city born man trying to make it as a farmer also is astounding. Almost as good is Daniel Auteuil as Montand's not-very-bright son. Only Emmanuelle Beart, gorgeous though she may be, doesn't quite convince me as the wild woman of the fields. Some of it is performance, some of it is how perfect she looks. The story is wonderful in a Dickensian sort of way, with clues and character elements showing up early, only to pay off three hours later. I love the first part even more, somehow it feels more truly tragic and dense, the 2nd part just a bit too neat by the end. But still a grand, intelligent, great looking entertainment.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "Memorable, moving and humane..."
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Sindre Kaspersen
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/3/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    French actor, producer, screenwriter and director Claude Berri's thirteenth feature film which he co-wrote with French screenwriter G&egrave;rard Brach (1927-2006) is an adaptation of a novel, "L'Eau des Collines - Jean de Florette and Manon des Sources" (1964) by French author, playwright and filmmaker Marcel Pagnol (1895-1974), which was inspired by true events. It was shot on numerous locations in the Vaucluse department of Provence in the southeast of France and is part of a duo logy which was preceded by "Jean De Florette" (1986). It tells the story about Manon Cadoret who still lives in the highlands of Provence ten years after her and her mother Aime&eacute; had to sell their property to Cesar Le Papet Soubeyran and his nephew Ugolin Soubeyran. Manon has become a shepherd girl and lives a quiet life, but when she one summer day encounters Ugolin who now is a successful farmer, bad memories are awakened. Struck by the now grown up Manon who he has not seen since she was a little girl, Ugolin falls head over heels in love with her. But Manon still remembers what he and his uncle did to her family, and she has found a way to reveal their secret. Like the first part of this epic story, this continuation is subtly and acutely directed by French filmmaker Claude Berri (1934-2009) and with it's ardent milieu depictions and efficient narrative structure, it draws an incessantly engaging portrayal of a young French woman who has been waiting several years to get justice for what happened to her family a decade earlier in time. This reverent sequel from the mid-1980s, produced by French producers Pierre Grunstein and Alain Poir&eacute; (1917-2000), is a co-production between France, Italy and Switzerland and has a powerful score by French composer Jean-Claude Petit, based on Italian composer Giuseppe Verdi's Italian opera "The Force of Destiny" (1862), which reinforces the film's atmosphere. Notable for it's wonderful production design by production designer Bernard V&eacute;zat and cinematography by French director and cinematographer Bruno Nuytten which is as present here as in the first segment, this historical period drama becomes an in-depth study of character that examines themes such as family relations, faith, morality and love, and is impelled by Yves Montand, Emmanuelle B&eacute;art and Daniel Auteuil's compassionate acting performances. A memorable, moving and humane film which gained, among other awards, the C&eacute;sar Award for best supporting actress Emmanuelle B&eacute;art at the 13th C&eacute;sar Awards in 1987 and the KCFCC Award for Best Foreign Language Film at the Kansas City Film Critics Circle Awards in 1988.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Beautiful sequel to Jean de Florette
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    billcr12
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Emmanuelle Beart is Manon, the beautiful daughter of Jean de Florette from the film of the same name which continues the story of the farmer who was tricked out of his land by unscrupulous neighbors. Beart as Manon is breathtakingly gorgeous, perfectly cast as a shepherdess who while leading a flock of sheep and bathing in the nude is looked upon by the son of the man who destroyed her fathers life. Manon discovers the secret and plots revenge on the evil doers. Manon manages to pay back the people who did her father wrong in this equally picturesque and emotional follow up to Jean de Florette. I would recommend watching the two films one after the other.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    How to do revenge!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    brimon28
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    When this film was released in Australia, it preceded the release of 'Jean de Florette', the first episode in what really is a continuing tale. Therefore, viewers were mystified by the story, even if they were impressed by the performances. 'Jean de Florette' appeared some months later, too late for cineastes to see Manon again. Luckily, the two are now being presented as a package, giving filmgoers a chance to see the two in the correct order. The result is very impressive indeed. The French continue to give us lessons in movie-making, and this duo was a change from the New Wave that showed us all how movies can be made. Emotions are to the fore, and Manon has revenge imprinted on it. 'Jean de Florette' gave us a hint, as the young Manon listens - and sees. She doesn't say much, but her face tells us that she is thinking through a resolution. I'm reminded of Nicole Kidman, in 'Dogville'. The character, Grace, is put upon by the locals, just as is Manon. The American treatment of revenge is different, with a different kind of violence. Dogville's conclusion is shocking and heart-rending; Whether you regard Emmanuelle Beart's face as more expressive than Nicole Kidman's is probably a very personal thing. But Manon's cold fury is a cinematic masterpiece, and we are well-prepared for the finale. This movie is so good I've no desire to read the book!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Amazing film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    TheLittleSongbird
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Having adored Jean De Florette, of which Manon of the Spring(or Manon Des Sources) follows on from, I found this film every bit as amazing. Once again the cinematography shimmers and the scenery is some of the best I have seen in any film. There is also a haunting score, a compelling story and a genuinely moving script, and Berri's direction is paced perfectly to suit life under the scorching sun. The performances are every bit as impressive, Emmanuelle Beart is alluring and very believable, and Yves Montand and Daniel Auteuil are once again outstanding, particularly Auteuil when he tries to atone. Overall, an amazing and I think poignant film. 10/10 Bethany Cox
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Really is a masterpiece, just watch it.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    1200 mr
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/8/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    no doubt its a masterpiece. movies like these cannot be produced on a regular base, its a beauty for all those people who are sick of today's computer effects based movies. Water, jungle, flowers, rocks, natural atmosphere and a beautiful face (Emmanuelle B&eacute;art) what else u want in a movie. Though she does not show too much of her assets (there is very brief scene of nudity) but her beauty was on peak in 1986. Emmanuelle is totally irresistible in this movie. story is excellent, all actors performed very well their characters and this is why its overall rating is above 8. I watched it in french luckily subtitles were available in English and after watching this i thought where the hell was this before, i should have seen this before.So guys don't wait and just watch dis classic.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Qualifies as a classic Greek tragedy.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    zjerunk
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/7/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I have many favorites, and this is one of the cr&egrave;me de la cr&egrave;me. This is a visually stunning film more like beautiful photographic montage. It is simple, tragic story well told, unlike many of today's plots - implausibly lame, suffering on a CGI crutch for 85 minutes. The simple story is about enduring truths which have been the mainstay of the Greek classics and Shakespeare: Our human strengths, our failings, our virtues, and our vices. The story may be a fiction, but its kernel is not. It is stories and story telling like this which has kept our rapt attention for four thousand years. First we should understand that this film is NOT A SEQUEL, but the second half the novel by Marcel Pagnol which would have been too long as a single film, and out of necessity, was shot as two. The first half is titled, Jean de Florette. Neither film stands alone as satisfactory because, obviously, it would be incomplete, and naturally, is also important that the two halves be viewed in sequence. For a fairly dispassionate pr&eacute;cis of the plots, I suggest reading the ones on Wikipedia and the discussion boards, so I won't be repetitive here. JdF & MotS were both shot at the same time in 1986 with a budget of $17 million making it/them the biggest budget French films up to that time. JdF grossed $86M worldwide, and of that sum, only $4.9M was from the USA. MotS grossed $56M worldwide, of which only $3.9M was from the USA. In other words, culture films are not a good fit for the American viewing audience, and the gross revenue numbers bear this out. The rest of the world seems to bear out this conclusion. Foreign language films rarely do well in the USA for the simple reason that the vast majority of the viewing audience are unilingual anglophones who do not wish to burden themselves with having to work at "understanding" their entertainment - they wish to merely consume it. If it requires the work of reading subtitles or thought, it becomes unpalatable. This film requires your attention and thought! But to be fair to the US viewers, the subtitles are at times incomplete or inaccurate, and unlike the spoken word, they do not convey the emphasis or importance of certain bits of dialogue well. The plot is woven steadily throughout the film, so the viewers with no understanding at all of the French language are missing essential dialogue, and therefore plot. The bottom line is this: You will either be entranced by these two films and love them, or you will be bored by the first 15 minutes, and you'll translate that into "bad film." If your highest quality level of reading is Marvel comics then I suggest you stay away from this one. However, I recall years ago walking into a video store where this was playing on all the monitors. All the patrons in the store, ranging in age from 5 to 75 years, were standing transfixed watching this film. There was something magical about it!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Excellent conclusion to Jean de Florette
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Red-Barracuda
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/7/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Manon des Sources is the second part of Jean de Florette. It's important to point out that it is a continuation of the story not a sequel. It takes on the narrative ten years down the line where Papet and Ugolin are reaping the benefits of cheating Jean from his land. Meanwhile Jean's daughter Manon (the beautiful Emmanuele B&eacute;art) roams the surrounding hills with her herd of goats - a constant reminder to the two men of the terrible injustice they committed against her and her family. To make matters a little more complicated Ugolin falls in love with this now gorgeous young woman, while she in turn falls for a local teacher. Manon still understandably holds a huge grudge against the men who she knows were indirectly responsible for her father's death, and the villagers too who she discovers knew of the scheming but did nothing. When she discovers the source of the water that feeds the village her revenge is set into motion... As a pair of movies Jean de Florette and Manon des Sources are a terrific example of the French heritage film. These movies play upon notions of nostalgia for a bygone era in France. The rural setting is beautifully evoked but more importantly the storyline is consistently strong and compelling, with great performances from all actors across both movies. If anything Manon des Sources is the greater of the two films, as it essentially satisfyingly concludes the storyline and gives the closure that we the audience want. The villains meet suitable ends and Manon herself finds true happiness. This summary may seem very hackneyed to anyone who has not seen them but these movies are handled with such a beautiful touch that their traditional narratives seem perfect. That said, the ending does provide us with a great little twist in a magnificent scene between Papet and a blind woman called Delphine. This revelatory scene in a graveyard offers a whole new dimension to the film and adds to the overall whole immeasurably. Jean de Florette and Manos des Sources are I suppose old fashioned movies in many respects. But they are old fashioned in the best ways. They offer quality cinema without patronising the viewer and have enough twists and turns and emotional involvement to satisfy the most jaded of cinema fans. A definite treat.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    payback is a bitch
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Michael Neumann
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/12/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The second half of Claude Berri's elegant two-part Proven&ccedil;al epic shares with 'Jean de Florette' the same sun washed, arid landscapes, the same rich tapestry of events, and many of the same hardy peasant characters. Here again is the unscrupulous landowner Le Papet and his weak-willed simpleton nephew Ugolin, along with the beautiful but untamed Manon, now grown to womanhood and living wild in the hills, where she decides to fight water with water (or a lack of it) by blocking the source of the vital spring supplying the nearby village. The sequel ties up all the narrative threads left dangling at the end of the earlier film (and as a result is more plot-heavy than its predecessor), but Manon's revenge against the men who (indirectly) murdered her father isn't as sweet as it should have been. After driving the love struck Ugolin to suicide (by simply ignoring his pathetic advances), she virtually disappears from the story, leaving Le Papet to a fate of his own design, outlined in some lumpy exposition before the heartbreaking conclusion. The rich local flavor and surprising unpretentiousness make it a worthwhile and often moving drama, but despite the title the film belongs to Yves Montand and Daniel Auteuil. Emmanuelle B&eacute;art, as Manon, doesn't have more than a dozen lines of dialogue, and her fashion model looks are a distraction.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Dramatic sequel with a great Yves Montand
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Luigi Di Pilla
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This part two sticks dramatically to the first one. The wonderful girl Emmanuelle B&eacute;art delivered an interesting performance. Yves Montand did a great job here showing all the repertoire of this psychological character profile. He was really a great actor, chapeau. But Daniel Auteuil was also very credibly in this role until the end. Bravo. Finally, Claude Berri directed again like a master. Thank you for these two very nice films. Don't expect a fast paced story because it has a slow but surprising countdown. For all that likes the surroundings South of France this is a rich experience to not miss. See also the other highlight La Fille du Pusatier from the same writer Marcel Pagnol. Vote: 8/10.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Jean de Florette / Manon of the Spring
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    runamokprods
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/7/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Two part film, that was 1st released as two separate features. Terrific telling of a complex story of intertwined farming families in rural France in the early part of the 20th century. The acting is mostly of the highest order. Yves Montand, one of the most suave men in history is completely believable as a rough hewn, self-centered farmer, Gerard Depardieu, also cast against type, as a gentle, educated city born man trying to make it as a farmer also is astounding. Almost as good is Daniel Auteuil as Montand's not-very-bright son. Only Emmanuelle Beart, gorgeous though she may be, doesn't quite convince me as the wild woman of the fields. Some of it is performance, some of it is how perfect she looks. The story is wonderful in a Dickensian sort of way, with clues and character elements showing up early, only to pay off three hours later. I love the first part even more, somehow it feels more truly tragic and dense, the 2nd part just a bit too neat by the end. But still a grand, intelligent, great looking entertainment.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "Memorable, moving and humane..."
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Sindre Kaspersen
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/3/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    French actor, producer, screenwriter and director Claude Berri's thirteenth feature film which he co-wrote with French screenwriter G&egrave;rard Brach (1927-2006) is an adaptation of a novel, "L'Eau des Collines - Jean de Florette and Manon des Sources" (1964) by French author, playwright and filmmaker Marcel Pagnol (1895-1974), which was inspired by true events. It was shot on numerous locations in the Vaucluse department of Provence in the southeast of France and is part of a duo logy which was preceded by "Jean De Florette" (1986). It tells the story about Manon Cadoret who still lives in the highlands of Provence ten years after her and her mother Aime&eacute; had to sell their property to Cesar Le Papet Soubeyran and his nephew Ugolin Soubeyran. Manon has become a shepherd girl and lives a quiet life, but when she one summer day encounters Ugolin who now is a successful farmer, bad memories are awakened. Struck by the now grown up Manon who he has not seen since she was a little girl, Ugolin falls head over heels in love with her. But Manon still remembers what he and his uncle did to her family, and she has found a way to reveal their secret. Like the first part of this epic story, this continuation is subtly and acutely directed by French filmmaker Claude Berri (1934-2009) and with it's ardent milieu depictions and efficient narrative structure, it draws an incessantly engaging portrayal of a young French woman who has been waiting several years to get justice for what happened to her family a decade earlier in time. This reverent sequel from the mid-1980s, produced by French producers Pierre Grunstein and Alain Poir&eacute; (1917-2000), is a co-production between France, Italy and Switzerland and has a powerful score by French composer Jean-Claude Petit, based on Italian composer Giuseppe Verdi's Italian opera "The Force of Destiny" (1862), which reinforces the film's atmosphere. Notable for it's wonderful production design by production designer Bernard V&eacute;zat and cinematography by French director and cinematographer Bruno Nuytten which is as present here as in the first segment, this historical period drama becomes an in-depth study of character that examines themes such as family relations, faith, morality and love, and is impelled by Yves Montand, Emmanuelle B&eacute;art and Daniel Auteuil's compassionate acting performances. A memorable, moving and humane film which gained, among other awards, the C&eacute;sar Award for best supporting actress Emmanuelle B&eacute;art at the 13th C&eacute;sar Awards in 1987 and the KCFCC Award for Best Foreign Language Film at the Kansas City Film Critics Circle Awards in 1988.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Beautiful sequel to Jean de Florette
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    billcr12
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Emmanuelle Beart is Manon, the beautiful daughter of Jean de Florette from the film of the same name which continues the story of the farmer who was tricked out of his land by unscrupulous neighbors. Beart as Manon is breathtakingly gorgeous, perfectly cast as a shepherdess who while leading a flock of sheep and bathing in the nude is looked upon by the son of the man who destroyed her fathers life. Manon discovers the secret and plots revenge on the evil doers. Manon manages to pay back the people who did her father wrong in this equally picturesque and emotional follow up to Jean de Florette. I would recommend watching the two films one after the other.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    How to do revenge!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    brimon28
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    When this film was released in Australia, it preceded the release of 'Jean de Florette', the first episode in what really is a continuing tale. Therefore, viewers were mystified by the story, even if they were impressed by the performances. 'Jean de Florette' appeared some months later, too late for cineastes to see Manon again. Luckily, the two are now being presented as a package, giving filmgoers a chance to see the two in the correct order. The result is very impressive indeed. The French continue to give us lessons in movie-making, and this duo was a change from the New Wave that showed us all how movies can be made. Emotions are to the fore, and Manon has revenge imprinted on it. 'Jean de Florette' gave us a hint, as the young Manon listens - and sees. She doesn't say much, but her face tells us that she is thinking through a resolution. I'm reminded of Nicole Kidman, in 'Dogville'. The character, Grace, is put upon by the locals, just as is Manon. The American treatment of revenge is different, with a different kind of violence. Dogville's conclusion is shocking and heart-rending; Whether you regard Emmanuelle Beart's face as more expressive than Nicole Kidman's is probably a very personal thing. But Manon's cold fury is a cinematic masterpiece, and we are well-prepared for the finale. This movie is so good I've no desire to read the book!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Amazing film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    TheLittleSongbird
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Having adored Jean De Florette, of which Manon of the Spring(or Manon Des Sources) follows on from, I found this film every bit as amazing. Once again the cinematography shimmers and the scenery is some of the best I have seen in any film. There is also a haunting score, a compelling story and a genuinely moving script, and Berri's direction is paced perfectly to suit life under the scorching sun. The performances are every bit as impressive, Emmanuelle Beart is alluring and very believable, and Yves Montand and Daniel Auteuil are once again outstanding, particularly Auteuil when he tries to atone. Overall, an amazing and I think poignant film. 10/10 Bethany Cox
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Really is a masterpiece, just watch it.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    1200 mr
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/8/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    no doubt its a masterpiece. movies like these cannot be produced on a regular base, its a beauty for all those people who are sick of today's computer effects based movies. Water, jungle, flowers, rocks, natural atmosphere and a beautiful face (Emmanuelle B&eacute;art) what else u want in a movie. Though she does not show too much of her assets (there is very brief scene of nudity) but her beauty was on peak in 1986. Emmanuelle is totally irresistible in this movie. story is excellent, all actors performed very well their characters and this is why its overall rating is above 8. I watched it in french luckily subtitles were available in English and after watching this i thought where the hell was this before, i should have seen this before.So guys don't wait and just watch dis classic.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Qualifies as a classic Greek tragedy.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    zjerunk
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/7/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I have many favorites, and this is one of the cr&egrave;me de la cr&egrave;me. This is a visually stunning film more like beautiful photographic montage. It is simple, tragic story well told, unlike many of today's plots - implausibly lame, suffering on a CGI crutch for 85 minutes. The simple story is about enduring truths which have been the mainstay of the Greek classics and Shakespeare: Our human strengths, our failings, our virtues, and our vices. The story may be a fiction, but its kernel is not. It is stories and story telling like this which has kept our rapt attention for four thousand years. First we should understand that this film is NOT A SEQUEL, but the second half the novel by Marcel Pagnol which would have been too long as a single film, and out of necessity, was shot as two. The first half is titled, Jean de Florette. Neither film stands alone as satisfactory because, obviously, it would be incomplete, and naturally, is also important that the two halves be viewed in sequence. For a fairly dispassionate pr&eacute;cis of the plots, I suggest reading the ones on Wikipedia and the discussion boards, so I won't be repetitive here. JdF & MotS were both shot at the same time in 1986 with a budget of $17 million making it/them the biggest budget French films up to that time. JdF grossed $86M worldwide, and of that sum, only $4.9M was from the USA. MotS grossed $56M worldwide, of which only $3.9M was from the USA. In other words, culture films are not a good fit for the American viewing audience, and the gross revenue numbers bear this out. The rest of the world seems to bear out this conclusion. Foreign language films rarely do well in the USA for the simple reason that the vast majority of the viewing audience are unilingual anglophones who do not wish to burden themselves with having to work at "understanding" their entertainment - they wish to merely consume it. If it requires the work of reading subtitles or thought, it becomes unpalatable. This film requires your attention and thought! But to be fair to the US viewers, the subtitles are at times incomplete or inaccurate, and unlike the spoken word, they do not convey the emphasis or importance of certain bits of dialogue well. The plot is woven steadily throughout the film, so the viewers with no understanding at all of the French language are missing essential dialogue, and therefore plot. The bottom line is this: You will either be entranced by these two films and love them, or you will be bored by the first 15 minutes, and you'll translate that into "bad film." If your highest quality level of reading is Marvel comics then I suggest you stay away from this one. However, I recall years ago walking into a video store where this was playing on all the monitors. All the patrons in the store, ranging in age from 5 to 75 years, were standing transfixed watching this film. There was something magical about it!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Excellent conclusion to Jean de Florette
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Red-Barracuda
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/7/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Manon des Sources is the second part of Jean de Florette. It's important to point out that it is a continuation of the story not a sequel. It takes on the narrative ten years down the line where Papet and Ugolin are reaping the benefits of cheating Jean from his land. Meanwhile Jean's daughter Manon (the beautiful Emmanuele B&eacute;art) roams the surrounding hills with her herd of goats - a constant reminder to the two men of the terrible injustice they committed against her and her family. To make matters a little more complicated Ugolin falls in love with this now gorgeous young woman, while she in turn falls for a local teacher. Manon still understandably holds a huge grudge against the men who she knows were indirectly responsible for her father's death, and the villagers too who she discovers knew of the scheming but did nothing. When she discovers the source of the water that feeds the village her revenge is set into motion... As a pair of movies Jean de Florette and Manon des Sources are a terrific example of the French heritage film. These movies play upon notions of nostalgia for a bygone era in France. The rural setting is beautifully evoked but more importantly the storyline is consistently strong and compelling, with great performances from all actors across both movies. If anything Manon des Sources is the greater of the two films, as it essentially satisfyingly concludes the storyline and gives the closure that we the audience want. The villains meet suitable ends and Manon herself finds true happiness. This summary may seem very hackneyed to anyone who has not seen them but these movies are handled with such a beautiful touch that their traditional narratives seem perfect. That said, the ending does provide us with a great little twist in a magnificent scene between Papet and a blind woman called Delphine. This revelatory scene in a graveyard offers a whole new dimension to the film and adds to the overall whole immeasurably. Jean de Florette and Manos des Sources are I suppose old fashioned movies in many respects. But they are old fashioned in the best ways. They offer quality cinema without patronising the viewer and have enough twists and turns and emotional involvement to satisfy the most jaded of cinema fans. A definite treat.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    payback is a bitch
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Michael Neumann
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/12/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The second half of Claude Berri's elegant two-part Proven&ccedil;al epic shares with 'Jean de Florette' the same sun washed, arid landscapes, the same rich tapestry of events, and many of the same hardy peasant characters. Here again is the unscrupulous landowner Le Papet and his weak-willed simpleton nephew Ugolin, along with the beautiful but untamed Manon, now grown to womanhood and living wild in the hills, where she decides to fight water with water (or a lack of it) by blocking the source of the vital spring supplying the nearby village. The sequel ties up all the narrative threads left dangling at the end of the earlier film (and as a result is more plot-heavy than its predecessor), but Manon's revenge against the men who (indirectly) murdered her father isn't as sweet as it should have been. After driving the love struck Ugolin to suicide (by simply ignoring his pathetic advances), she virtually disappears from the story, leaving Le Papet to a fate of his own design, outlined in some lumpy exposition before the heartbreaking conclusion. The rich local flavor and surprising unpretentiousness make it a worthwhile and often moving drama, but despite the title the film belongs to Yves Montand and Daniel Auteuil. Emmanuelle B&eacute;art, as Manon, doesn't have more than a dozen lines of dialogue, and her fashion model looks are a distraction.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Dramatic sequel with a great Yves Montand
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Luigi Di Pilla
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This part two sticks dramatically to the first one. The wonderful girl Emmanuelle B&eacute;art delivered an interesting performance. Yves Montand did a great job here showing all the repertoire of this psychological character profile. He was really a great actor, chapeau. But Daniel Auteuil was also very credibly in this role until the end. Bravo. Finally, Claude Berri directed again like a master. Thank you for these two very nice films. Don't expect a fast paced story because it has a slow but surprising countdown. For all that likes the surroundings South of France this is a rich experience to not miss. See also the other highlight La Fille du Pusatier from the same writer Marcel Pagnol. Vote: 8/10.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Jean de Florette / Manon of the Spring
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    runamokprods
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/7/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Two part film, that was 1st released as two separate features. Terrific telling of a complex story of intertwined farming families in rural France in the early part of the 20th century. The acting is mostly of the highest order. Yves Montand, one of the most suave men in history is completely believable as a rough hewn, self-centered farmer, Gerard Depardieu, also cast against type, as a gentle, educated city born man trying to make it as a farmer also is astounding. Almost as good is Daniel Auteuil as Montand's not-very-bright son. Only Emmanuelle Beart, gorgeous though she may be, doesn't quite convince me as the wild woman of the fields. Some of it is performance, some of it is how perfect she looks. The story is wonderful in a Dickensian sort of way, with clues and character elements showing up early, only to pay off three hours later. I love the first part even more, somehow it feels more truly tragic and dense, the 2nd part just a bit too neat by the end. But still a grand, intelligent, great looking entertainment.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "Memorable, moving and humane..."
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Sindre Kaspersen
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/3/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    French actor, producer, screenwriter and director Claude Berri's thirteenth feature film which he co-wrote with French screenwriter G&egrave;rard Brach (1927-2006) is an adaptation of a novel, "L'Eau des Collines - Jean de Florette and Manon des Sources" (1964) by French author, playwright and filmmaker Marcel Pagnol (1895-1974), which was inspired by true events. It was shot on numerous locations in the Vaucluse department of Provence in the southeast of France and is part of a duo logy which was preceded by "Jean De Florette" (1986). It tells the story about Manon Cadoret who still lives in the highlands of Provence ten years after her and her mother Aime&eacute; had to sell their property to Cesar Le Papet Soubeyran and his nephew Ugolin Soubeyran. Manon has become a shepherd girl and lives a quiet life, but when she one summer day encounters Ugolin who now is a successful farmer, bad memories are awakened. Struck by the now grown up Manon who he has not seen since she was a little girl, Ugolin falls head over heels in love with her. But Manon still remembers what he and his uncle did to her family, and she has found a way to reveal their secret. Like the first part of this epic story, this continuation is subtly and acutely directed by French filmmaker Claude Berri (1934-2009) and with it's ardent milieu depictions and efficient narrative structure, it draws an incessantly engaging portrayal of a young French woman who has been waiting several years to get justice for what happened to her family a decade earlier in time. This reverent sequel from the mid-1980s, produced by French producers Pierre Grunstein and Alain Poir&eacute; (1917-2000), is a co-production between France, Italy and Switzerland and has a powerful score by French composer Jean-Claude Petit, based on Italian composer Giuseppe Verdi's Italian opera "The Force of Destiny" (1862), which reinforces the film's atmosphere. Notable for it's wonderful production design by production designer Bernard V&eacute;zat and cinematography by French director and cinematographer Bruno Nuytten which is as present here as in the first segment, this historical period drama becomes an in-depth study of character that examines themes such as family relations, faith, morality and love, and is impelled by Yves Montand, Emmanuelle B&eacute;art and Daniel Auteuil's compassionate acting performances. A memorable, moving and humane film which gained, among other awards, the C&eacute;sar Award for best supporting actress Emmanuelle B&eacute;art at the 13th C&eacute;sar Awards in 1987 and the KCFCC Award for Best Foreign Language Film at the Kansas City Film Critics Circle Awards in 1988.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Beautiful sequel to Jean de Florette
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    billcr12
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Emmanuelle Beart is Manon, the beautiful daughter of Jean de Florette from the film of the same name which continues the story of the farmer who was tricked out of his land by unscrupulous neighbors. Beart as Manon is breathtakingly gorgeous, perfectly cast as a shepherdess who while leading a flock of sheep and bathing in the nude is looked upon by the son of the man who destroyed her fathers life. Manon discovers the secret and plots revenge on the evil doers. Manon manages to pay back the people who did her father wrong in this equally picturesque and emotional follow up to Jean de Florette. I would recommend watching the two films one after the other.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    How to do revenge!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    brimon28
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    When this film was released in Australia, it preceded the release of 'Jean de Florette', the first episode in what really is a continuing tale. Therefore, viewers were mystified by the story, even if they were impressed by the performances. 'Jean de Florette' appeared some months later, too late for cineastes to see Manon again. Luckily, the two are now being presented as a package, giving filmgoers a chance to see the two in the correct order. The result is very impressive indeed. The French continue to give us lessons in movie-making, and this duo was a change from the New Wave that showed us all how movies can be made. Emotions are to the fore, and Manon has revenge imprinted on it. 'Jean de Florette' gave us a hint, as the young Manon listens - and sees. She doesn't say much, but her face tells us that she is thinking through a resolution. I'm reminded of Nicole Kidman, in 'Dogville'. The character, Grace, is put upon by the locals, just as is Manon. The American treatment of revenge is different, with a different kind of violence. Dogville's conclusion is shocking and heart-rending; Whether you regard Emmanuelle Beart's face as more expressive than Nicole Kidman's is probably a very personal thing. But Manon's cold fury is a cinematic masterpiece, and we are well-prepared for the finale. This movie is so good I've no desire to read the book!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Amazing film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    TheLittleSongbird
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Having adored Jean De Florette, of which Manon of the Spring(or Manon Des Sources) follows on from, I found this film every bit as amazing. Once again the cinematography shimmers and the scenery is some of the best I have seen in any film. There is also a haunting score, a compelling story and a genuinely moving script, and Berri's direction is paced perfectly to suit life under the scorching sun. The performances are every bit as impressive, Emmanuelle Beart is alluring and very believable, and Yves Montand and Daniel Auteuil are once again outstanding, particularly Auteuil when he tries to atone. Overall, an amazing and I think poignant film. 10/10 Bethany Cox
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Really is a masterpiece, just watch it.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    1200 mr
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/8/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    no doubt its a masterpiece. movies like these cannot be produced on a regular base, its a beauty for all those people who are sick of today's computer effects based movies. Water, jungle, flowers, rocks, natural atmosphere and a beautiful face (Emmanuelle B&eacute;art) what else u want in a movie. Though she does not show too much of her assets (there is very brief scene of nudity) but her beauty was on peak in 1986. Emmanuelle is totally irresistible in this movie. story is excellent, all actors performed very well their characters and this is why its overall rating is above 8. I watched it in french luckily subtitles were available in English and after watching this i thought where the hell was this before, i should have seen this before.So guys don't wait and just watch dis classic.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Qualifies as a classic Greek tragedy.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    zjerunk
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/7/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I have many favorites, and this is one of the cr&egrave;me de la cr&egrave;me. This is a visually stunning film more like beautiful photographic montage. It is simple, tragic story well told, unlike many of today's plots - implausibly lame, suffering on a CGI crutch for 85 minutes. The simple story is about enduring truths which have been the mainstay of the Greek classics and Shakespeare: Our human strengths, our failings, our virtues, and our vices. The story may be a fiction, but its kernel is not. It is stories and story telling like this which has kept our rapt attention for four thousand years. First we should understand that this film is NOT A SEQUEL, but the second half the novel by Marcel Pagnol which would have been too long as a single film, and out of necessity, was shot as two. The first half is titled, Jean de Florette. Neither film stands alone as satisfactory because, obviously, it would be incomplete, and naturally, is also important that the two halves be viewed in sequence. For a fairly dispassionate pr&eacute;cis of the plots, I suggest reading the ones on Wikipedia and the discussion boards, so I won't be repetitive here. JdF & MotS were both shot at the same time in 1986 with a budget of $17 million making it/them the biggest budget French films up to that time. JdF grossed $86M worldwide, and of that sum, only $4.9M was from the USA. MotS grossed $56M worldwide, of which only $3.9M was from the USA. In other words, culture films are not a good fit for the American viewing audience, and the gross revenue numbers bear this out. The rest of the world seems to bear out this conclusion. Foreign language films rarely do well in the USA for the simple reason that the vast majority of the viewing audience are unilingual anglophones who do not wish to burden themselves with having to work at "understanding" their entertainment - they wish to merely consume it. If it requires the work of reading subtitles or thought, it becomes unpalatable. This film requires your attention and thought! But to be fair to the US viewers, the subtitles are at times incomplete or inaccurate, and unlike the spoken word, they do not convey the emphasis or importance of certain bits of dialogue well. The plot is woven steadily throughout the film, so the viewers with no understanding at all of the French language are missing essential dialogue, and therefore plot. The bottom line is this: You will either be entranced by these two films and love them, or you will be bored by the first 15 minutes, and you'll translate that into "bad film." If your highest quality level of reading is Marvel comics then I suggest you stay away from this one. However, I recall years ago walking into a video store where this was playing on all the monitors. All the patrons in the store, ranging in age from 5 to 75 years, were standing transfixed watching this film. There was something magical about it!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Excellent conclusion to Jean de Florette
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Red-Barracuda
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/7/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Manon des Sources is the second part of Jean de Florette. It's important to point out that it is a continuation of the story not a sequel. It takes on the narrative ten years down the line where Papet and Ugolin are reaping the benefits of cheating Jean from his land. Meanwhile Jean's daughter Manon (the beautiful Emmanuele B&eacute;art) roams the surrounding hills with her herd of goats - a constant reminder to the two men of the terrible injustice they committed against her and her family. To make matters a little more complicated Ugolin falls in love with this now gorgeous young woman, while she in turn falls for a local teacher. Manon still understandably holds a huge grudge against the men who she knows were indirectly responsible for her father's death, and the villagers too who she discovers knew of the scheming but did nothing. When she discovers the source of the water that feeds the village her revenge is set into motion... As a pair of movies Jean de Florette and Manon des Sources are a terrific example of the French heritage film. These movies play upon notions of nostalgia for a bygone era in France. The rural setting is beautifully evoked but more importantly the storyline is consistently strong and compelling, with great performances from all actors across both movies. If anything Manon des Sources is the greater of the two films, as it essentially satisfyingly concludes the storyline and gives the closure that we the audience want. The villains meet suitable ends and Manon herself finds true happiness. This summary may seem very hackneyed to anyone who has not seen them but these movies are handled with such a beautiful touch that their traditional narratives seem perfect. That said, the ending does provide us with a great little twist in a magnificent scene between Papet and a blind woman called Delphine. This revelatory scene in a graveyard offers a whole new dimension to the film and adds to the overall whole immeasurably. Jean de Florette and Manos des Sources are I suppose old fashioned movies in many respects. But they are old fashioned in the best ways. They offer quality cinema without patronising the viewer and have enough twists and turns and emotional involvement to satisfy the most jaded of cinema fans. A definite treat.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    payback is a bitch
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Michael Neumann
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/12/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The second half of Claude Berri's elegant two-part Proven&ccedil;al epic shares with 'Jean de Florette' the same sun washed, arid landscapes, the same rich tapestry of events, and many of the same hardy peasant characters. Here again is the unscrupulous landowner Le Papet and his weak-willed simpleton nephew Ugolin, along with the beautiful but untamed Manon, now grown to womanhood and living wild in the hills, where she decides to fight water with water (or a lack of it) by blocking the source of the vital spring supplying the nearby village. The sequel ties up all the narrative threads left dangling at the end of the earlier film (and as a result is more plot-heavy than its predecessor), but Manon's revenge against the men who (indirectly) murdered her father isn't as sweet as it should have been. After driving the love struck Ugolin to suicide (by simply ignoring his pathetic advances), she virtually disappears from the story, leaving Le Papet to a fate of his own design, outlined in some lumpy exposition before the heartbreaking conclusion. The rich local flavor and surprising unpretentiousness make it a worthwhile and often moving drama, but despite the title the film belongs to Yves Montand and Daniel Auteuil. Emmanuelle B&eacute;art, as Manon, doesn't have more than a dozen lines of dialogue, and her fashion model looks are a distraction.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Dramatic sequel with a great Yves Montand
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Luigi Di Pilla
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This part two sticks dramatically to the first one. The wonderful girl Emmanuelle B&eacute;art delivered an interesting performance. Yves Montand did a great job here showing all the repertoire of this psychological character profile. He was really a great actor, chapeau. But Daniel Auteuil was also very credibly in this role until the end. Bravo. Finally, Claude Berri directed again like a master. Thank you for these two very nice films. Don't expect a fast paced story because it has a slow but surprising countdown. For all that likes the surroundings South of France this is a rich experience to not miss. See also the other highlight La Fille du Pusatier from the same writer Marcel Pagnol. Vote: 8/10.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Jean de Florette / Manon of the Spring
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    runamokprods
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/7/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Two part film, that was 1st released as two separate features. Terrific telling of a complex story of intertwined farming families in rural France in the early part of the 20th century. The acting is mostly of the highest order. Yves Montand, one of the most suave men in history is completely believable as a rough hewn, self-centered farmer, Gerard Depardieu, also cast against type, as a gentle, educated city born man trying to make it as a farmer also is astounding. Almost as good is Daniel Auteuil as Montand's not-very-bright son. Only Emmanuelle Beart, gorgeous though she may be, doesn't quite convince me as the wild woman of the fields. Some of it is performance, some of it is how perfect she looks. The story is wonderful in a Dickensian sort of way, with clues and character elements showing up early, only to pay off three hours later. I love the first part even more, somehow it feels more truly tragic and dense, the 2nd part just a bit too neat by the end. But still a grand, intelligent, great looking entertainment.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "Memorable, moving and humane..."
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Sindre Kaspersen
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/3/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    French actor, producer, screenwriter and director Claude Berri's thirteenth feature film which he co-wrote with French screenwriter G&egrave;rard Brach (1927-2006) is an adaptation of a novel, "L'Eau des Collines - Jean de Florette and Manon des Sources" (1964) by French author, playwright and filmmaker Marcel Pagnol (1895-1974), which was inspired by true events. It was shot on numerous locations in the Vaucluse department of Provence in the southeast of France and is part of a duo logy which was preceded by "Jean De Florette" (1986). It tells the story about Manon Cadoret who still lives in the highlands of Provence ten years after her and her mother Aime&eacute; had to sell their property to Cesar Le Papet Soubeyran and his nephew Ugolin Soubeyran. Manon has become a shepherd girl and lives a quiet life, but when she one summer day encounters Ugolin who now is a successful farmer, bad memories are awakened. Struck by the now grown up Manon who he has not seen since she was a little girl, Ugolin falls head over heels in love with her. But Manon still remembers what he and his uncle did to her family, and she has found a way to reveal their secret. Like the first part of this epic story, this continuation is subtly and acutely directed by French filmmaker Claude Berri (1934-2009) and with it's ardent milieu depictions and efficient narrative structure, it draws an incessantly engaging portrayal of a young French woman who has been waiting several years to get justice for what happened to her family a decade earlier in time. This reverent sequel from the mid-1980s, produced by French producers Pierre Grunstein and Alain Poir&eacute; (1917-2000), is a co-production between France, Italy and Switzerland and has a powerful score by French composer Jean-Claude Petit, based on Italian composer Giuseppe Verdi's Italian opera "The Force of Destiny" (1862), which reinforces the film's atmosphere. Notable for it's wonderful production design by production designer Bernard V&eacute;zat and cinematography by French director and cinematographer Bruno Nuytten which is as present here as in the first segment, this historical period drama becomes an in-depth study of character that examines themes such as family relations, faith, morality and love, and is impelled by Yves Montand, Emmanuelle B&eacute;art and Daniel Auteuil's compassionate acting performances. A memorable, moving and humane film which gained, among other awards, the C&eacute;sar Award for best supporting actress Emmanuelle B&eacute;art at the 13th C&eacute;sar Awards in 1987 and the KCFCC Award for Best Foreign Language Film at the Kansas City Film Critics Circle Awards in 1988.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Beautiful sequel to Jean de Florette
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    billcr12
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Emmanuelle Beart is Manon, the beautiful daughter of Jean de Florette from the film of the same name which continues the story of the farmer who was tricked out of his land by unscrupulous neighbors. Beart as Manon is breathtakingly gorgeous, perfectly cast as a shepherdess who while leading a flock of sheep and bathing in the nude is looked upon by the son of the man who destroyed her fathers life. Manon discovers the secret and plots revenge on the evil doers. Manon manages to pay back the people who did her father wrong in this equally picturesque and emotional follow up to Jean de Florette. I would recommend watching the two films one after the other.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    How to do revenge!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    brimon28
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    When this film was released in Australia, it preceded the release of 'Jean de Florette', the first episode in what really is a continuing tale. Therefore, viewers were mystified by the story, even if they were impressed by the performances. 'Jean de Florette' appeared some months later, too late for cineastes to see Manon again. Luckily, the two are now being presented as a package, giving filmgoers a chance to see the two in the correct order. The result is very impressive indeed. The French continue to give us lessons in movie-making, and this duo was a change from the New Wave that showed us all how movies can be made. Emotions are to the fore, and Manon has revenge imprinted on it. 'Jean de Florette' gave us a hint, as the young Manon listens - and sees. She doesn't say much, but her face tells us that she is thinking through a resolution. I'm reminded of Nicole Kidman, in 'Dogville'. The character, Grace, is put upon by the locals, just as is Manon. The American treatment of revenge is different, with a different kind of violence. Dogville's conclusion is shocking and heart-rending; Whether you regard Emmanuelle Beart's face as more expressive than Nicole Kidman's is probably a very personal thing. But Manon's cold fury is a cinematic masterpiece, and we are well-prepared for the finale. This movie is so good I've no desire to read the book!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Amazing film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    TheLittleSongbird
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Having adored Jean De Florette, of which Manon of the Spring(or Manon Des Sources) follows on from, I found this film every bit as amazing. Once again the cinematography shimmers and the scenery is some of the best I have seen in any film. There is also a haunting score, a compelling story and a genuinely moving script, and Berri's direction is paced perfectly to suit life under the scorching sun. The performances are every bit as impressive, Emmanuelle Beart is alluring and very believable, and Yves Montand and Daniel Auteuil are once again outstanding, particularly Auteuil when he tries to atone. Overall, an amazing and I think poignant film. 10/10 Bethany Cox
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Really is a masterpiece, just watch it.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    1200 mr
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/8/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    no doubt its a masterpiece. movies like these cannot be produced on a regular base, its a beauty for all those people who are sick of today's computer effects based movies. Water, jungle, flowers, rocks, natural atmosphere and a beautiful face (Emmanuelle B&eacute;art) what else u want in a movie. Though she does not show too much of her assets (there is very brief scene of nudity) but her beauty was on peak in 1986. Emmanuelle is totally irresistible in this movie. story is excellent, all actors performed very well their characters and this is why its overall rating is above 8. I watched it in french luckily subtitles were available in English and after watching this i thought where the hell was this before, i should have seen this before.So guys don't wait and just watch dis classic.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Qualifies as a classic Greek tragedy.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    zjerunk
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/7/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I have many favorites, and this is one of the cr&egrave;me de la cr&egrave;me. This is a visually stunning film more like beautiful photographic montage. It is simple, tragic story well told, unlike many of today's plots - implausibly lame, suffering on a CGI crutch for 85 minutes. The simple story is about enduring truths which have been the mainstay of the Greek classics and Shakespeare: Our human strengths, our failings, our virtues, and our vices. The story may be a fiction, but its kernel is not. It is stories and story telling like this which has kept our rapt attention for four thousand years. First we should understand that this film is NOT A SEQUEL, but the second half the novel by Marcel Pagnol which would have been too long as a single film, and out of necessity, was shot as two. The first half is titled, Jean de Florette. Neither film stands alone as satisfactory because, obviously, it would be incomplete, and naturally, is also important that the two halves be viewed in sequence. For a fairly dispassionate pr&eacute;cis of the plots, I suggest reading the ones on Wikipedia and the discussion boards, so I won't be repetitive here. JdF & MotS were both shot at the same time in 1986 with a budget of $17 million making it/them the biggest budget French films up to that time. JdF grossed $86M worldwide, and of that sum, only $4.9M was from the USA. MotS grossed $56M worldwide, of which only $3.9M was from the USA. In other words, culture films are not a good fit for the American viewing audience, and the gross revenue numbers bear this out. The rest of the world seems to bear out this conclusion. Foreign language films rarely do well in the USA for the simple reason that the vast majority of the viewing audience are unilingual anglophones who do not wish to burden themselves with having to work at "understanding" their entertainment - they wish to merely consume it. If it requires the work of reading subtitles or thought, it becomes unpalatable. This film requires your attention and thought! But to be fair to the US viewers, the subtitles are at times incomplete or inaccurate, and unlike the spoken word, they do not convey the emphasis or importance of certain bits of dialogue well. The plot is woven steadily throughout the film, so the viewers with no understanding at all of the French language are missing essential dialogue, and therefore plot. The bottom line is this: You will either be entranced by these two films and love them, or you will be bored by the first 15 minutes, and you'll translate that into "bad film." If your highest quality level of reading is Marvel comics then I suggest you stay away from this one. However, I recall years ago walking into a video store where this was playing on all the monitors. All the patrons in the store, ranging in age from 5 to 75 years, were standing transfixed watching this film. There was something magical about it!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Excellent conclusion to Jean de Florette
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Red-Barracuda
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/7/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Manon des Sources is the second part of Jean de Florette. It's important to point out that it is a continuation of the story not a sequel. It takes on the narrative ten years down the line where Papet and Ugolin are reaping the benefits of cheating Jean from his land. Meanwhile Jean's daughter Manon (the beautiful Emmanuele B&eacute;art) roams the surrounding hills with her herd of goats - a constant reminder to the two men of the terrible injustice they committed against her and her family. To make matters a little more complicated Ugolin falls in love with this now gorgeous young woman, while she in turn falls for a local teacher. Manon still understandably holds a huge grudge against the men who she knows were indirectly responsible for her father's death, and the villagers too who she discovers knew of the scheming but did nothing. When she discovers the source of the water that feeds the village her revenge is set into motion... As a pair of movies Jean de Florette and Manon des Sources are a terrific example of the French heritage film. These movies play upon notions of nostalgia for a bygone era in France. The rural setting is beautifully evoked but more importantly the storyline is consistently strong and compelling, with great performances from all actors across both movies. If anything Manon des Sources is the greater of the two films, as it essentially satisfyingly concludes the storyline and gives the closure that we the audience want. The villains meet suitable ends and Manon herself finds true happiness. This summary may seem very hackneyed to anyone who has not seen them but these movies are handled with such a beautiful touch that their traditional narratives seem perfect. That said, the ending does provide us with a great little twist in a magnificent scene between Papet and a blind woman called Delphine. This revelatory scene in a graveyard offers a whole new dimension to the film and adds to the overall whole immeasurably. Jean de Florette and Manos des Sources are I suppose old fashioned movies in many respects. But they are old fashioned in the best ways. They offer quality cinema without patronising the viewer and have enough twists and turns and emotional involvement to satisfy the most jaded of cinema fans. A definite treat.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    payback is a bitch
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Michael Neumann
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/12/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The second half of Claude Berri's elegant two-part Proven&ccedil;al epic shares with 'Jean de Florette' the same sun washed, arid landscapes, the same rich tapestry of events, and many of the same hardy peasant characters. Here again is the unscrupulous landowner Le Papet and his weak-willed simpleton nephew Ugolin, along with the beautiful but untamed Manon, now grown to womanhood and living wild in the hills, where she decides to fight water with water (or a lack of it) by blocking the source of the vital spring supplying the nearby village. The sequel ties up all the narrative threads left dangling at the end of the earlier film (and as a result is more plot-heavy than its predecessor), but Manon's revenge against the men who (indirectly) murdered her father isn't as sweet as it should have been. After driving the love struck Ugolin to suicide (by simply ignoring his pathetic advances), she virtually disappears from the story, leaving Le Papet to a fate of his own design, outlined in some lumpy exposition before the heartbreaking conclusion. The rich local flavor and surprising unpretentiousness make it a worthwhile and often moving drama, but despite the title the film belongs to Yves Montand and Daniel Auteuil. Emmanuelle B&eacute;art, as Manon, doesn't have more than a dozen lines of dialogue, and her fashion model looks are a distraction.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
 </reviews>
</filme>
