<filme>
 <id>
  170
 </id>
 <imdburl>
  http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0095765
 </imdburl>
 <ano>
  1988
 </ano>
 <titulo>
  Cinema Paradiso
 </titulo>
 <rating>
  8.4
 </rating>
 <sinopse>
  A filmmaker recalls his childhood, when he fell in love with the movies at his village's theater and formed a deep friendship with the theater's projectionist.
 </sinopse>
 <storyline>
  A famous film director remembers his childhood at the Cinema Paradiso where Alfredo, the projectionist, first brought about his love of films. He returns home to his Sicilian village for the first time after almost 30 years and is reminded of his first love, Elena, who disappeared from his life before he left for Rome.
 </storyline>
 <generos>
  <genero>
   Drama
  </genero>
 </generos>
 <keywords>
  <keyword>
   boy
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   village
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   love
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   cinema
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   friendship
  </keyword>
 </keywords>
 <diretores>
  <diretor>
   Giuseppe Tornatore
  </diretor>
 </diretores>
 <escritores>
  <escritor>
   Giuseppe Tornatore
  </escritor>
  <escritor>
   Vanna Paoli
  </escritor>
 </escritores>
 <atores>
  <ator>
   Philippe Noiret
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Enzo Cannavale
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Antonella Attili
  </ator>
 </atores>
 <reviews>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Charming details don't add up to a great film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    dmayo-911-597432
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    *** This review may contain spoilers *** It would be best to see this film without knowing how warmly it was welcomed by critics and viewers at the time, or how many people still take it to their hearts. It does hold many charms in its details, but when it tries to give us a story of Life and Love it becomes banal and contrived. It also takes an oddly careless approach to the aging of its characters. Nuovo Cinema Paradiso opens with a framing story in which a middle-aged man hears that someone named Alfredo has died in his hometown and begins recalling his childhood. In the flashbacks that form the main body of the film, the setting is a town in Sicily in the decade following World War II. A small boy is irresistibly drawn to the local cinema, a world of enchantment, and to its projection booth, the heart of that world. He befriends the projectionist, Alfredo. Alfredo discourages the boy, Toto, from following in his footsteps as a projectionist and eventually encourages him to pursue his love of movies on a grander scale. We're soon prepared to learn that the grown Toto who is recollecting these things has become a famous director. In the first phase of the flashbacks, we follow little Toto in his childish peccadilloes while following the community in its avid response to movie magic (a funny exception being the gritty social realism of post-war Italian cinema, which proves as impenetrable to Sicilians as to much of the world beyond). This phase ends with the cinema destroyed by fire and Alfredo rescued by Toto but blinded for life. The Toto of the second phase is apparently in his late teens, perhaps twenty by the end of the flashback. Childish peccadilloes have given way to amateur film-making, running the projector at the rebuilt cinema, and love at first sight with a girl whose social position poses an obstacle -- in effect, a princess. As always, the life of the community and that of the film are centered on the shared joys of escape in a darkened cinema. Toto's personal life is disrupted by a period of military training, after which he finds that he can't pick up where he left off. He loses touch with Elena, his love, who has moved away. Finally, he takes Alfredo's advice and leaves town himself to make his way in the world. Very well, but it's unbelievable that he then absolutely neglects his mother for thirty years, even to the point of not returning her phone calls, although they were on good terms when he left. The only reason seems to be that the film requires a complete break with home so that the middle-aged Toto can feel he's stepping into a past world when he returns for Alfredo's funeral. Still more unbelievable is the casting of characters at different ages. The twentyish Toto is distinctly short, but the fiftyish Toto towers over everyone else in the funeral procession. Conversely, his mother changes from a tall young woman to a tiny old one. Then there is the aging of characters who are played by the same actors throughout. Alfredo's wife, who was middle-aged in the first place, only turns gray-haired and gray-faced while the transformation (by casting) of Toto's younger mother rivals that of the queen in Snow White. Indeed, slapping gray paint on actors -- while removing an obvious hairpiece from one -- is all the movie magic Tornatore offers in the framing story. Is he trying to tell us that he has decided to wash his hands of film-making as a labor of love? The many delightful moments in Nuovo Cinema Paradiso are really just so many vignettes strung together in the abrupt, sometimes bewildering manner of the 1980s. To the extent that these moments achieve a unified effect, they suggest the benign human comedy of Rene Clair. Yet they are mixed with stink-bombs of bad taste that would have puzzled Clair as to this director's intent. That, too, is a mark of the 1980s. It may be best to look for the appeal of this film in the ways in which it differs from most other films of the 1980s and many since. It does come down on the side of benign human comedy. It does cherish the magic of Golden Age film-making, even as that magic slips through its fingers. It does become an oasis of entertainment if you come upon it in a personal desert of dissatisfaction with films generally. The trouble is that if you have had the good fortune to drink from the springs of Rene Clair and other masters, Nuovo Cinema Paradiso turns out to be a mirage.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An ode to cinema, dream and emotions
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    lucio7
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Don't approach the movie with your logic part of the brain switched on. Yes, as someone said there are some flaws relative to how realistic it can be, but that doesn't matter because you'd be missing the point. Just let yourself go and enjoy this celebration of cinema, dream and emotions and this piece of art will bring you on a lovely spiritual trip. I loved it. P.S.: Sorry IMDb, but I was able to say everything I wanted to say without the mandatory 10 lines of text. I really love your website but you should pass this message to the management: quantity doesn't make quality.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An amazing, thought-provoking, deeply-insightful, emotionally-riveting winner!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    voniapeng
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Well. Wow. Let me absorb this all for a moment. Alright. So that was... one of the best films I have seen in who knows how long. It is definitely on my all-time favorites list. Such an amazing film about film... but so, so much more. It is about friendships- the very best two people can share. The multitude of ways one person, one place, one passion can change your life for eternity; without which you would be a different person altogether. This film makes me want to experience the small town life that I never have, in any way before- to have so many people who know you so well; who grew up with you or watched you grow up; who can be proud of everything you have become; who love you in ways people who have not known you since you were a baby; A place where you can return decades later to find that everything has been the same after all these years, yet, at the same time, changed. This film inspires in me a love of films than span lifetime(s) in a way that very few others have. This film makes me think about so many things: redemption, regret, love, hope, friendships, trust, appreciation; how clinging to the past can be such a rewardingly bad tendency, how so many things we have no power over are so blatantly unfair, how, in the name of love, the most difficult decisions are inevitable made. I would kill to have a friendship like Toto & 's. I am regrettably obligated to clarify that, however. Alfredo's decision regarding Toto & Elena made me so upset that... I didn't know whether I could like his character anymore. His decision and actions were out of place, mean, and wrong. In the end, though, I suppose I can only say I respect Alfredo less, as I know, in his heart, he wanted what he felt was best for Toto. I emphasize, what he felt. And that's my point exactly. Because it was not his place and therefore not his right to do what he did- his sincere care and love for Toto irrelevant in this case- although mitigating the severity of his wrong. I agree that in some ways what evolved was best for Toto- but for his career. And I am an adamant believer that love is always the No. One priority in these lives of ours. At the end of the day, financial woes, careers, daily nuisances aside, love is what matters at the end of the day; at the end of a lifetime. Toto shares this philosophy, as made obvious several times. Secondly, why in heaven's name didn't the two of them rekindle their rare, genuine love at the end? I understand that some things in life can become too late t retrieve, but, again, I agree with Toto- they should have resumed it. I know neither of them ever loved anyone else, vows or not, anywhere near as powerfully. And, despite what I may say, contrary to all logic, I wish for a love like Toto & Elena's. As the saying goes, "It is better to have loved and lost than to have never loved at all." I understand that times were different then, but, perhaps unfairly, I am upset with Elena. For not choosing true love over her family's unreasonable demands (although she did redeem herself). For not agreeing to set things right at the end. The only other issue I have is with the plausibility of some specific details. First, falling in love without ever talking, at first sight? And then Elena reciprocating, but, almost even more unbelievably, only after watching him wait outside her place for a year? Secondly, Toto's devotion to waiting outside is as unbelievable as the "soldier's" to the princess. Men like that could and would not ever exist. I would have identified so much more had it been more realistic. "Of course I remember you..." "Life is not what you see in films... Life is much harder." Amen to that. So extremely, heart-breakingly sadly.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Infinitely Innocent
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    karl-sokhn
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    We all have had moments when we seemed to cling to past sensations or childhood memories, we feel a certain comfort re invoking these thoughts into mind. That is exactly what Cinema Paradiso portrays in an almost 3 hour long movie all through which you don't budge. Allow me to explain : The past is an ambiguous word but to clarify, let's consider the past as the numerous events that lead to NOW, the present. Having said that, the movie is a picture perfect depiction of the influence of the past on one's present and future. Childhood, teenage crisis, first love, the search for one's roots etc.. I shall detail these headlines. This movie represents the main character Salvatore Di Vita,a bright little kid who, never met or had any kind of interaction with his father(a soldier in the Italian army). And Alfredo, an old man with no kids who takes care of film reels in the Cinema Paradiso. (The only downside of the Cinema Paradiso was that films were censored and scenes involving physical contact were cut from the reels). Many actions lead their relationship to strengthen throughout the movie even though their bond had an inherent tendency to grow because each of them found in the other what he was lacking. Alfredo soon becomes the father figure Salvatore longed for as a kid and the little boy starts seeking counsel with the elder in matters that he couldn't understand. He becomes the prominent person that represents Salvatore's childhood along with the Cinema Paradiso, the place where Salvatore cultivated a love for Cinematography. And finally Elena, Salvatore's one true love draws the final stroke on this amazing portrait : Giancaldo, Salvatore's home village. Outer Circumstances force Elena and Salvatore to be separated, and their attempts to communicate fall on deaf ears and they lose all kinds of contact. A while after that Alfredo's counsel leads Salvatore(Toto) to leave the cradle of his childhood in order to pursue his dreams. He returns several years after to attend Alfredo's funeral and starts to rediscover Giancaldo from an other point of view and is finally able to make peace with his past with Alfredo's posthumous help. Finally i would like to add that the movie has an air of innocence to it and an immensely frivolous atmosphere giving all the characters' feelings a sincerity that i have never seen in any other movie.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Italian classic
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    silva-w-pius
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This heart warming and uplifting film takes us on a nostalgic adventure into our youths, through the innocent and untainted eyes of a young boy, who still sees the world for all its beauty and promise, even throughout the birth and death of a picture palace that holds so much lure and magic to him. Cinema paradiso is regarded as not only one of the greatest Italian films ever exported, but one of the greatest foreign films ever! But I would strongly disagree, as far as to say it is an insult to label this majestic testament to the beauty life, as just a foreign film! It's more than that, much more. A story told in flash backs, from the perspective of a highly successful film maker in his 40's (Salvatore Cascio). Upon receiving a call from his mother to inform him that his child hood hero had unfortunately died, it forces him to recount his entire youth. Telling the story of a young Salvatore living in a run down, poverty stricken and grim war-torn, post ww2 Sicilian village with his baby sister and his harassed mother who is as free with a slap as with a hug. But finding refuge from all the pain and misery, in a cinema paradiso, a local picture hall, provides him with an idyllic paradise where his love for cinema and adventures can run free. There he soon strikes up an unshakable life long bond with a aging projectionist, serving as a father figure and confidante, then after a fire robes him of his sight, Alfredo (Philippe Noriet) encourages Salvatore to take over at the new paradiso, but eventually he would push the now young 18 year old Salvatore, tainted by his first heartbreak by his true love Elena(Agnese Nano), out of the confines of this dead beat village, to a world waiting to be explored and conquered , Only returning 30 years later, to witness the burial of Alfredo and the demolition of the cinema paradiso. Giuseppe Tornatore provides us with a poignant and almost, spiritual reminder of how the simple things that we held so delicately in are youths can almost be forgotten and misplace in our older years, as we replace the magic with vain perceptions of success and obsession with money, when we should actually try and reconnect with our youths, and again enjoy the personal cinema experience that promises so much. As soon as the end titles rolled by, I couldn't help but feel sad, as a big cinema paradiso shaped whole was left in my heart. Cinema paradiso is a film that stirs up a lot of home truths, a great watch for brave individuals.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A film for movie fans.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Thanos Alfie
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Nuovo Cinema Paradiso is a movie for movie and cinema fans. In this movie you will understand the true meaning of love of the cinema. When I saw this movie I loved it because I think it represents the love for films that every movie fan has. I liked very much the performance of Salvatore Cascio as young "Salvatore 'Tot&ograve;' Di Vita" and of course the performance of Phillpe Noiret as "Alfredo". I also liked very much the true love between Marco Leonardi/Jacques Perrin as a teenager and adult "Salvatore 'Tot&ograve;' Di Vita" and Agnese Nano / Brigitte Fossey as a teenager and as adult Elena Mendola. I saw the extended movie of 155 minutes and not the "cut" movie of 121 minutes and I think that it worth it, I did not get bored for even a minute instead of it I really liked it!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Lotsa pathos, little substance
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    George Aar
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is a pleasant enough movie, I guess. But really not noteworthy in any substantial way. There's a movie theatre that is obviously a set. There's a whole stable of stock characters and lots of forced emotion, but there's just no meat on the bones. And then there's all those questions unanswered. Why did little Toto (who's a really cute little kid) act out towards everyone, no matter how hard they tried to befriend him? Why did Toto's mother treat him so poorly and beat him so much? Why did Toto's father leave? Why did Toto's girlfriend leave? How could Toto be so much in love with a girl he didn't even know? What happened to his girlfriend? Why did he never come back to his hometown? Why did his life end up so apparently empty and unsatisfying? And there's more I haven't even touched on. All of those questions and no answers are even attempted for any of them. All there is is a token tearful scene here and there and a few oddball philosophical parables and the rest of the script is basically left blank. I found it rather odd. Odd and unfulfilling. I think most people would expect more from a story.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    love of a life time
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Che 19c94
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I am the kind of person that usually never tears up for a movie, but here i just can't help it. Cinema Paradiso is one of those rare movies you just have to see. And if you are a movie fan yourself, like i am, the movie would quickly be at heart. The best thing about foreign films is that you never know the actors since you have never seen them in any other movie. It is as if your watching real people go by their lives. This is the kind of movie that everybody has to see. I don't know why this movie has an R rating but the version I saw, the original 1988 version, is suitable for everyone. ENJOY
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A masterpiece: Watch it to understand, why!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mike-world1
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Among the best movies, I ever saw....for a change, don't know whether I call it drama, romance, inspiration or depressing or what...but have to say that in the last 60 minutes, I incessantly cried...I've seen some wonderful movies, but this is among the best...direction: flawless and a class-apart, cast: nothing could have been better, sets: perfectly suit the story, and story-line: quite different... the way movie moves just keeps us engrossed, without being able to anticipate what is going to happen, specially in the last one hour...maybe it tells what life is, or helps to find a reflection of our life stories...and that's how we feel connected... overall, a must watch for those, who really enjoy quality movies!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "There are only ghosts here."
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Degree7
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Passion inspires great art in a young Toto, but as his age shifts, so does his perspective on his life machinations in a small Sicilian community. With the help of the local theatre projectionist, Alfredo, he is able to recognize his potential and move out into a wider world. But what keeps this film from simply being a sentimental ode to Italian cinema, is the reflection of a much older Toro coming to terms with the sacrifices he has made to become the man he is. Were they mistakes? Or are his past regrets still threatening to cloak his accomplishments as an individual? Despite a somewhat obtrusive score by Ennio Morriconne, this film sends a strong message about life reevaluation, and how past decisions can segue into the present, in often unexpected, but beautiful ways. A small gem of a film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Charming details don't add up to a great film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    dmayo-911-597432
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    *** This review may contain spoilers *** It would be best to see this film without knowing how warmly it was welcomed by critics and viewers at the time, or how many people still take it to their hearts. It does hold many charms in its details, but when it tries to give us a story of Life and Love it becomes banal and contrived. It also takes an oddly careless approach to the aging of its characters. Nuovo Cinema Paradiso opens with a framing story in which a middle-aged man hears that someone named Alfredo has died in his hometown and begins recalling his childhood. In the flashbacks that form the main body of the film, the setting is a town in Sicily in the decade following World War II. A small boy is irresistibly drawn to the local cinema, a world of enchantment, and to its projection booth, the heart of that world. He befriends the projectionist, Alfredo. Alfredo discourages the boy, Toto, from following in his footsteps as a projectionist and eventually encourages him to pursue his love of movies on a grander scale. We're soon prepared to learn that the grown Toto who is recollecting these things has become a famous director. In the first phase of the flashbacks, we follow little Toto in his childish peccadilloes while following the community in its avid response to movie magic (a funny exception being the gritty social realism of post-war Italian cinema, which proves as impenetrable to Sicilians as to much of the world beyond). This phase ends with the cinema destroyed by fire and Alfredo rescued by Toto but blinded for life. The Toto of the second phase is apparently in his late teens, perhaps twenty by the end of the flashback. Childish peccadilloes have given way to amateur film-making, running the projector at the rebuilt cinema, and love at first sight with a girl whose social position poses an obstacle -- in effect, a princess. As always, the life of the community and that of the film are centered on the shared joys of escape in a darkened cinema. Toto's personal life is disrupted by a period of military training, after which he finds that he can't pick up where he left off. He loses touch with Elena, his love, who has moved away. Finally, he takes Alfredo's advice and leaves town himself to make his way in the world. Very well, but it's unbelievable that he then absolutely neglects his mother for thirty years, even to the point of not returning her phone calls, although they were on good terms when he left. The only reason seems to be that the film requires a complete break with home so that the middle-aged Toto can feel he's stepping into a past world when he returns for Alfredo's funeral. Still more unbelievable is the casting of characters at different ages. The twentyish Toto is distinctly short, but the fiftyish Toto towers over everyone else in the funeral procession. Conversely, his mother changes from a tall young woman to a tiny old one. Then there is the aging of characters who are played by the same actors throughout. Alfredo's wife, who was middle-aged in the first place, only turns gray-haired and gray-faced while the transformation (by casting) of Toto's younger mother rivals that of the queen in Snow White. Indeed, slapping gray paint on actors -- while removing an obvious hairpiece from one -- is all the movie magic Tornatore offers in the framing story. Is he trying to tell us that he has decided to wash his hands of film-making as a labor of love? The many delightful moments in Nuovo Cinema Paradiso are really just so many vignettes strung together in the abrupt, sometimes bewildering manner of the 1980s. To the extent that these moments achieve a unified effect, they suggest the benign human comedy of Rene Clair. Yet they are mixed with stink-bombs of bad taste that would have puzzled Clair as to this director's intent. That, too, is a mark of the 1980s. It may be best to look for the appeal of this film in the ways in which it differs from most other films of the 1980s and many since. It does come down on the side of benign human comedy. It does cherish the magic of Golden Age film-making, even as that magic slips through its fingers. It does become an oasis of entertainment if you come upon it in a personal desert of dissatisfaction with films generally. The trouble is that if you have had the good fortune to drink from the springs of Rene Clair and other masters, Nuovo Cinema Paradiso turns out to be a mirage.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An ode to cinema, dream and emotions
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    lucio7
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Don't approach the movie with your logic part of the brain switched on. Yes, as someone said there are some flaws relative to how realistic it can be, but that doesn't matter because you'd be missing the point. Just let yourself go and enjoy this celebration of cinema, dream and emotions and this piece of art will bring you on a lovely spiritual trip. I loved it. P.S.: Sorry IMDb, but I was able to say everything I wanted to say without the mandatory 10 lines of text. I really love your website but you should pass this message to the management: quantity doesn't make quality.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An amazing, thought-provoking, deeply-insightful, emotionally-riveting winner!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    voniapeng
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Well. Wow. Let me absorb this all for a moment. Alright. So that was... one of the best films I have seen in who knows how long. It is definitely on my all-time favorites list. Such an amazing film about film... but so, so much more. It is about friendships- the very best two people can share. The multitude of ways one person, one place, one passion can change your life for eternity; without which you would be a different person altogether. This film makes me want to experience the small town life that I never have, in any way before- to have so many people who know you so well; who grew up with you or watched you grow up; who can be proud of everything you have become; who love you in ways people who have not known you since you were a baby; A place where you can return decades later to find that everything has been the same after all these years, yet, at the same time, changed. This film inspires in me a love of films than span lifetime(s) in a way that very few others have. This film makes me think about so many things: redemption, regret, love, hope, friendships, trust, appreciation; how clinging to the past can be such a rewardingly bad tendency, how so many things we have no power over are so blatantly unfair, how, in the name of love, the most difficult decisions are inevitable made. I would kill to have a friendship like Toto & 's. I am regrettably obligated to clarify that, however. Alfredo's decision regarding Toto & Elena made me so upset that... I didn't know whether I could like his character anymore. His decision and actions were out of place, mean, and wrong. In the end, though, I suppose I can only say I respect Alfredo less, as I know, in his heart, he wanted what he felt was best for Toto. I emphasize, what he felt. And that's my point exactly. Because it was not his place and therefore not his right to do what he did- his sincere care and love for Toto irrelevant in this case- although mitigating the severity of his wrong. I agree that in some ways what evolved was best for Toto- but for his career. And I am an adamant believer that love is always the No. One priority in these lives of ours. At the end of the day, financial woes, careers, daily nuisances aside, love is what matters at the end of the day; at the end of a lifetime. Toto shares this philosophy, as made obvious several times. Secondly, why in heaven's name didn't the two of them rekindle their rare, genuine love at the end? I understand that some things in life can become too late t retrieve, but, again, I agree with Toto- they should have resumed it. I know neither of them ever loved anyone else, vows or not, anywhere near as powerfully. And, despite what I may say, contrary to all logic, I wish for a love like Toto & Elena's. As the saying goes, "It is better to have loved and lost than to have never loved at all." I understand that times were different then, but, perhaps unfairly, I am upset with Elena. For not choosing true love over her family's unreasonable demands (although she did redeem herself). For not agreeing to set things right at the end. The only other issue I have is with the plausibility of some specific details. First, falling in love without ever talking, at first sight? And then Elena reciprocating, but, almost even more unbelievably, only after watching him wait outside her place for a year? Secondly, Toto's devotion to waiting outside is as unbelievable as the "soldier's" to the princess. Men like that could and would not ever exist. I would have identified so much more had it been more realistic. "Of course I remember you..." "Life is not what you see in films... Life is much harder." Amen to that. So extremely, heart-breakingly sadly.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Infinitely Innocent
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    karl-sokhn
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    We all have had moments when we seemed to cling to past sensations or childhood memories, we feel a certain comfort re invoking these thoughts into mind. That is exactly what Cinema Paradiso portrays in an almost 3 hour long movie all through which you don't budge. Allow me to explain : The past is an ambiguous word but to clarify, let's consider the past as the numerous events that lead to NOW, the present. Having said that, the movie is a picture perfect depiction of the influence of the past on one's present and future. Childhood, teenage crisis, first love, the search for one's roots etc.. I shall detail these headlines. This movie represents the main character Salvatore Di Vita,a bright little kid who, never met or had any kind of interaction with his father(a soldier in the Italian army). And Alfredo, an old man with no kids who takes care of film reels in the Cinema Paradiso. (The only downside of the Cinema Paradiso was that films were censored and scenes involving physical contact were cut from the reels). Many actions lead their relationship to strengthen throughout the movie even though their bond had an inherent tendency to grow because each of them found in the other what he was lacking. Alfredo soon becomes the father figure Salvatore longed for as a kid and the little boy starts seeking counsel with the elder in matters that he couldn't understand. He becomes the prominent person that represents Salvatore's childhood along with the Cinema Paradiso, the place where Salvatore cultivated a love for Cinematography. And finally Elena, Salvatore's one true love draws the final stroke on this amazing portrait : Giancaldo, Salvatore's home village. Outer Circumstances force Elena and Salvatore to be separated, and their attempts to communicate fall on deaf ears and they lose all kinds of contact. A while after that Alfredo's counsel leads Salvatore(Toto) to leave the cradle of his childhood in order to pursue his dreams. He returns several years after to attend Alfredo's funeral and starts to rediscover Giancaldo from an other point of view and is finally able to make peace with his past with Alfredo's posthumous help. Finally i would like to add that the movie has an air of innocence to it and an immensely frivolous atmosphere giving all the characters' feelings a sincerity that i have never seen in any other movie.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Italian classic
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    silva-w-pius
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This heart warming and uplifting film takes us on a nostalgic adventure into our youths, through the innocent and untainted eyes of a young boy, who still sees the world for all its beauty and promise, even throughout the birth and death of a picture palace that holds so much lure and magic to him. Cinema paradiso is regarded as not only one of the greatest Italian films ever exported, but one of the greatest foreign films ever! But I would strongly disagree, as far as to say it is an insult to label this majestic testament to the beauty life, as just a foreign film! It's more than that, much more. A story told in flash backs, from the perspective of a highly successful film maker in his 40's (Salvatore Cascio). Upon receiving a call from his mother to inform him that his child hood hero had unfortunately died, it forces him to recount his entire youth. Telling the story of a young Salvatore living in a run down, poverty stricken and grim war-torn, post ww2 Sicilian village with his baby sister and his harassed mother who is as free with a slap as with a hug. But finding refuge from all the pain and misery, in a cinema paradiso, a local picture hall, provides him with an idyllic paradise where his love for cinema and adventures can run free. There he soon strikes up an unshakable life long bond with a aging projectionist, serving as a father figure and confidante, then after a fire robes him of his sight, Alfredo (Philippe Noriet) encourages Salvatore to take over at the new paradiso, but eventually he would push the now young 18 year old Salvatore, tainted by his first heartbreak by his true love Elena(Agnese Nano), out of the confines of this dead beat village, to a world waiting to be explored and conquered , Only returning 30 years later, to witness the burial of Alfredo and the demolition of the cinema paradiso. Giuseppe Tornatore provides us with a poignant and almost, spiritual reminder of how the simple things that we held so delicately in are youths can almost be forgotten and misplace in our older years, as we replace the magic with vain perceptions of success and obsession with money, when we should actually try and reconnect with our youths, and again enjoy the personal cinema experience that promises so much. As soon as the end titles rolled by, I couldn't help but feel sad, as a big cinema paradiso shaped whole was left in my heart. Cinema paradiso is a film that stirs up a lot of home truths, a great watch for brave individuals.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A film for movie fans.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Thanos Alfie
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Nuovo Cinema Paradiso is a movie for movie and cinema fans. In this movie you will understand the true meaning of love of the cinema. When I saw this movie I loved it because I think it represents the love for films that every movie fan has. I liked very much the performance of Salvatore Cascio as young "Salvatore 'Tot&ograve;' Di Vita" and of course the performance of Phillpe Noiret as "Alfredo". I also liked very much the true love between Marco Leonardi/Jacques Perrin as a teenager and adult "Salvatore 'Tot&ograve;' Di Vita" and Agnese Nano / Brigitte Fossey as a teenager and as adult Elena Mendola. I saw the extended movie of 155 minutes and not the "cut" movie of 121 minutes and I think that it worth it, I did not get bored for even a minute instead of it I really liked it!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Lotsa pathos, little substance
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    George Aar
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is a pleasant enough movie, I guess. But really not noteworthy in any substantial way. There's a movie theatre that is obviously a set. There's a whole stable of stock characters and lots of forced emotion, but there's just no meat on the bones. And then there's all those questions unanswered. Why did little Toto (who's a really cute little kid) act out towards everyone, no matter how hard they tried to befriend him? Why did Toto's mother treat him so poorly and beat him so much? Why did Toto's father leave? Why did Toto's girlfriend leave? How could Toto be so much in love with a girl he didn't even know? What happened to his girlfriend? Why did he never come back to his hometown? Why did his life end up so apparently empty and unsatisfying? And there's more I haven't even touched on. All of those questions and no answers are even attempted for any of them. All there is is a token tearful scene here and there and a few oddball philosophical parables and the rest of the script is basically left blank. I found it rather odd. Odd and unfulfilling. I think most people would expect more from a story.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    love of a life time
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Che 19c94
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I am the kind of person that usually never tears up for a movie, but here i just can't help it. Cinema Paradiso is one of those rare movies you just have to see. And if you are a movie fan yourself, like i am, the movie would quickly be at heart. The best thing about foreign films is that you never know the actors since you have never seen them in any other movie. It is as if your watching real people go by their lives. This is the kind of movie that everybody has to see. I don't know why this movie has an R rating but the version I saw, the original 1988 version, is suitable for everyone. ENJOY
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A masterpiece: Watch it to understand, why!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mike-world1
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Among the best movies, I ever saw....for a change, don't know whether I call it drama, romance, inspiration or depressing or what...but have to say that in the last 60 minutes, I incessantly cried...I've seen some wonderful movies, but this is among the best...direction: flawless and a class-apart, cast: nothing could have been better, sets: perfectly suit the story, and story-line: quite different... the way movie moves just keeps us engrossed, without being able to anticipate what is going to happen, specially in the last one hour...maybe it tells what life is, or helps to find a reflection of our life stories...and that's how we feel connected... overall, a must watch for those, who really enjoy quality movies!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "There are only ghosts here."
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Degree7
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Passion inspires great art in a young Toto, but as his age shifts, so does his perspective on his life machinations in a small Sicilian community. With the help of the local theatre projectionist, Alfredo, he is able to recognize his potential and move out into a wider world. But what keeps this film from simply being a sentimental ode to Italian cinema, is the reflection of a much older Toro coming to terms with the sacrifices he has made to become the man he is. Were they mistakes? Or are his past regrets still threatening to cloak his accomplishments as an individual? Despite a somewhat obtrusive score by Ennio Morriconne, this film sends a strong message about life reevaluation, and how past decisions can segue into the present, in often unexpected, but beautiful ways. A small gem of a film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Charming details don't add up to a great film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    dmayo-911-597432
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    *** This review may contain spoilers *** It would be best to see this film without knowing how warmly it was welcomed by critics and viewers at the time, or how many people still take it to their hearts. It does hold many charms in its details, but when it tries to give us a story of Life and Love it becomes banal and contrived. It also takes an oddly careless approach to the aging of its characters. Nuovo Cinema Paradiso opens with a framing story in which a middle-aged man hears that someone named Alfredo has died in his hometown and begins recalling his childhood. In the flashbacks that form the main body of the film, the setting is a town in Sicily in the decade following World War II. A small boy is irresistibly drawn to the local cinema, a world of enchantment, and to its projection booth, the heart of that world. He befriends the projectionist, Alfredo. Alfredo discourages the boy, Toto, from following in his footsteps as a projectionist and eventually encourages him to pursue his love of movies on a grander scale. We're soon prepared to learn that the grown Toto who is recollecting these things has become a famous director. In the first phase of the flashbacks, we follow little Toto in his childish peccadilloes while following the community in its avid response to movie magic (a funny exception being the gritty social realism of post-war Italian cinema, which proves as impenetrable to Sicilians as to much of the world beyond). This phase ends with the cinema destroyed by fire and Alfredo rescued by Toto but blinded for life. The Toto of the second phase is apparently in his late teens, perhaps twenty by the end of the flashback. Childish peccadilloes have given way to amateur film-making, running the projector at the rebuilt cinema, and love at first sight with a girl whose social position poses an obstacle -- in effect, a princess. As always, the life of the community and that of the film are centered on the shared joys of escape in a darkened cinema. Toto's personal life is disrupted by a period of military training, after which he finds that he can't pick up where he left off. He loses touch with Elena, his love, who has moved away. Finally, he takes Alfredo's advice and leaves town himself to make his way in the world. Very well, but it's unbelievable that he then absolutely neglects his mother for thirty years, even to the point of not returning her phone calls, although they were on good terms when he left. The only reason seems to be that the film requires a complete break with home so that the middle-aged Toto can feel he's stepping into a past world when he returns for Alfredo's funeral. Still more unbelievable is the casting of characters at different ages. The twentyish Toto is distinctly short, but the fiftyish Toto towers over everyone else in the funeral procession. Conversely, his mother changes from a tall young woman to a tiny old one. Then there is the aging of characters who are played by the same actors throughout. Alfredo's wife, who was middle-aged in the first place, only turns gray-haired and gray-faced while the transformation (by casting) of Toto's younger mother rivals that of the queen in Snow White. Indeed, slapping gray paint on actors -- while removing an obvious hairpiece from one -- is all the movie magic Tornatore offers in the framing story. Is he trying to tell us that he has decided to wash his hands of film-making as a labor of love? The many delightful moments in Nuovo Cinema Paradiso are really just so many vignettes strung together in the abrupt, sometimes bewildering manner of the 1980s. To the extent that these moments achieve a unified effect, they suggest the benign human comedy of Rene Clair. Yet they are mixed with stink-bombs of bad taste that would have puzzled Clair as to this director's intent. That, too, is a mark of the 1980s. It may be best to look for the appeal of this film in the ways in which it differs from most other films of the 1980s and many since. It does come down on the side of benign human comedy. It does cherish the magic of Golden Age film-making, even as that magic slips through its fingers. It does become an oasis of entertainment if you come upon it in a personal desert of dissatisfaction with films generally. The trouble is that if you have had the good fortune to drink from the springs of Rene Clair and other masters, Nuovo Cinema Paradiso turns out to be a mirage.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An ode to cinema, dream and emotions
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    lucio7
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Don't approach the movie with your logic part of the brain switched on. Yes, as someone said there are some flaws relative to how realistic it can be, but that doesn't matter because you'd be missing the point. Just let yourself go and enjoy this celebration of cinema, dream and emotions and this piece of art will bring you on a lovely spiritual trip. I loved it. P.S.: Sorry IMDb, but I was able to say everything I wanted to say without the mandatory 10 lines of text. I really love your website but you should pass this message to the management: quantity doesn't make quality.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An amazing, thought-provoking, deeply-insightful, emotionally-riveting winner!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    voniapeng
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Well. Wow. Let me absorb this all for a moment. Alright. So that was... one of the best films I have seen in who knows how long. It is definitely on my all-time favorites list. Such an amazing film about film... but so, so much more. It is about friendships- the very best two people can share. The multitude of ways one person, one place, one passion can change your life for eternity; without which you would be a different person altogether. This film makes me want to experience the small town life that I never have, in any way before- to have so many people who know you so well; who grew up with you or watched you grow up; who can be proud of everything you have become; who love you in ways people who have not known you since you were a baby; A place where you can return decades later to find that everything has been the same after all these years, yet, at the same time, changed. This film inspires in me a love of films than span lifetime(s) in a way that very few others have. This film makes me think about so many things: redemption, regret, love, hope, friendships, trust, appreciation; how clinging to the past can be such a rewardingly bad tendency, how so many things we have no power over are so blatantly unfair, how, in the name of love, the most difficult decisions are inevitable made. I would kill to have a friendship like Toto & 's. I am regrettably obligated to clarify that, however. Alfredo's decision regarding Toto & Elena made me so upset that... I didn't know whether I could like his character anymore. His decision and actions were out of place, mean, and wrong. In the end, though, I suppose I can only say I respect Alfredo less, as I know, in his heart, he wanted what he felt was best for Toto. I emphasize, what he felt. And that's my point exactly. Because it was not his place and therefore not his right to do what he did- his sincere care and love for Toto irrelevant in this case- although mitigating the severity of his wrong. I agree that in some ways what evolved was best for Toto- but for his career. And I am an adamant believer that love is always the No. One priority in these lives of ours. At the end of the day, financial woes, careers, daily nuisances aside, love is what matters at the end of the day; at the end of a lifetime. Toto shares this philosophy, as made obvious several times. Secondly, why in heaven's name didn't the two of them rekindle their rare, genuine love at the end? I understand that some things in life can become too late t retrieve, but, again, I agree with Toto- they should have resumed it. I know neither of them ever loved anyone else, vows or not, anywhere near as powerfully. And, despite what I may say, contrary to all logic, I wish for a love like Toto & Elena's. As the saying goes, "It is better to have loved and lost than to have never loved at all." I understand that times were different then, but, perhaps unfairly, I am upset with Elena. For not choosing true love over her family's unreasonable demands (although she did redeem herself). For not agreeing to set things right at the end. The only other issue I have is with the plausibility of some specific details. First, falling in love without ever talking, at first sight? And then Elena reciprocating, but, almost even more unbelievably, only after watching him wait outside her place for a year? Secondly, Toto's devotion to waiting outside is as unbelievable as the "soldier's" to the princess. Men like that could and would not ever exist. I would have identified so much more had it been more realistic. "Of course I remember you..." "Life is not what you see in films... Life is much harder." Amen to that. So extremely, heart-breakingly sadly.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Infinitely Innocent
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    karl-sokhn
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    We all have had moments when we seemed to cling to past sensations or childhood memories, we feel a certain comfort re invoking these thoughts into mind. That is exactly what Cinema Paradiso portrays in an almost 3 hour long movie all through which you don't budge. Allow me to explain : The past is an ambiguous word but to clarify, let's consider the past as the numerous events that lead to NOW, the present. Having said that, the movie is a picture perfect depiction of the influence of the past on one's present and future. Childhood, teenage crisis, first love, the search for one's roots etc.. I shall detail these headlines. This movie represents the main character Salvatore Di Vita,a bright little kid who, never met or had any kind of interaction with his father(a soldier in the Italian army). And Alfredo, an old man with no kids who takes care of film reels in the Cinema Paradiso. (The only downside of the Cinema Paradiso was that films were censored and scenes involving physical contact were cut from the reels). Many actions lead their relationship to strengthen throughout the movie even though their bond had an inherent tendency to grow because each of them found in the other what he was lacking. Alfredo soon becomes the father figure Salvatore longed for as a kid and the little boy starts seeking counsel with the elder in matters that he couldn't understand. He becomes the prominent person that represents Salvatore's childhood along with the Cinema Paradiso, the place where Salvatore cultivated a love for Cinematography. And finally Elena, Salvatore's one true love draws the final stroke on this amazing portrait : Giancaldo, Salvatore's home village. Outer Circumstances force Elena and Salvatore to be separated, and their attempts to communicate fall on deaf ears and they lose all kinds of contact. A while after that Alfredo's counsel leads Salvatore(Toto) to leave the cradle of his childhood in order to pursue his dreams. He returns several years after to attend Alfredo's funeral and starts to rediscover Giancaldo from an other point of view and is finally able to make peace with his past with Alfredo's posthumous help. Finally i would like to add that the movie has an air of innocence to it and an immensely frivolous atmosphere giving all the characters' feelings a sincerity that i have never seen in any other movie.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Italian classic
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    silva-w-pius
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This heart warming and uplifting film takes us on a nostalgic adventure into our youths, through the innocent and untainted eyes of a young boy, who still sees the world for all its beauty and promise, even throughout the birth and death of a picture palace that holds so much lure and magic to him. Cinema paradiso is regarded as not only one of the greatest Italian films ever exported, but one of the greatest foreign films ever! But I would strongly disagree, as far as to say it is an insult to label this majestic testament to the beauty life, as just a foreign film! It's more than that, much more. A story told in flash backs, from the perspective of a highly successful film maker in his 40's (Salvatore Cascio). Upon receiving a call from his mother to inform him that his child hood hero had unfortunately died, it forces him to recount his entire youth. Telling the story of a young Salvatore living in a run down, poverty stricken and grim war-torn, post ww2 Sicilian village with his baby sister and his harassed mother who is as free with a slap as with a hug. But finding refuge from all the pain and misery, in a cinema paradiso, a local picture hall, provides him with an idyllic paradise where his love for cinema and adventures can run free. There he soon strikes up an unshakable life long bond with a aging projectionist, serving as a father figure and confidante, then after a fire robes him of his sight, Alfredo (Philippe Noriet) encourages Salvatore to take over at the new paradiso, but eventually he would push the now young 18 year old Salvatore, tainted by his first heartbreak by his true love Elena(Agnese Nano), out of the confines of this dead beat village, to a world waiting to be explored and conquered , Only returning 30 years later, to witness the burial of Alfredo and the demolition of the cinema paradiso. Giuseppe Tornatore provides us with a poignant and almost, spiritual reminder of how the simple things that we held so delicately in are youths can almost be forgotten and misplace in our older years, as we replace the magic with vain perceptions of success and obsession with money, when we should actually try and reconnect with our youths, and again enjoy the personal cinema experience that promises so much. As soon as the end titles rolled by, I couldn't help but feel sad, as a big cinema paradiso shaped whole was left in my heart. Cinema paradiso is a film that stirs up a lot of home truths, a great watch for brave individuals.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A film for movie fans.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Thanos Alfie
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Nuovo Cinema Paradiso is a movie for movie and cinema fans. In this movie you will understand the true meaning of love of the cinema. When I saw this movie I loved it because I think it represents the love for films that every movie fan has. I liked very much the performance of Salvatore Cascio as young "Salvatore 'Tot&ograve;' Di Vita" and of course the performance of Phillpe Noiret as "Alfredo". I also liked very much the true love between Marco Leonardi/Jacques Perrin as a teenager and adult "Salvatore 'Tot&ograve;' Di Vita" and Agnese Nano / Brigitte Fossey as a teenager and as adult Elena Mendola. I saw the extended movie of 155 minutes and not the "cut" movie of 121 minutes and I think that it worth it, I did not get bored for even a minute instead of it I really liked it!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Lotsa pathos, little substance
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    George Aar
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is a pleasant enough movie, I guess. But really not noteworthy in any substantial way. There's a movie theatre that is obviously a set. There's a whole stable of stock characters and lots of forced emotion, but there's just no meat on the bones. And then there's all those questions unanswered. Why did little Toto (who's a really cute little kid) act out towards everyone, no matter how hard they tried to befriend him? Why did Toto's mother treat him so poorly and beat him so much? Why did Toto's father leave? Why did Toto's girlfriend leave? How could Toto be so much in love with a girl he didn't even know? What happened to his girlfriend? Why did he never come back to his hometown? Why did his life end up so apparently empty and unsatisfying? And there's more I haven't even touched on. All of those questions and no answers are even attempted for any of them. All there is is a token tearful scene here and there and a few oddball philosophical parables and the rest of the script is basically left blank. I found it rather odd. Odd and unfulfilling. I think most people would expect more from a story.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    love of a life time
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Che 19c94
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I am the kind of person that usually never tears up for a movie, but here i just can't help it. Cinema Paradiso is one of those rare movies you just have to see. And if you are a movie fan yourself, like i am, the movie would quickly be at heart. The best thing about foreign films is that you never know the actors since you have never seen them in any other movie. It is as if your watching real people go by their lives. This is the kind of movie that everybody has to see. I don't know why this movie has an R rating but the version I saw, the original 1988 version, is suitable for everyone. ENJOY
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A masterpiece: Watch it to understand, why!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mike-world1
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Among the best movies, I ever saw....for a change, don't know whether I call it drama, romance, inspiration or depressing or what...but have to say that in the last 60 minutes, I incessantly cried...I've seen some wonderful movies, but this is among the best...direction: flawless and a class-apart, cast: nothing could have been better, sets: perfectly suit the story, and story-line: quite different... the way movie moves just keeps us engrossed, without being able to anticipate what is going to happen, specially in the last one hour...maybe it tells what life is, or helps to find a reflection of our life stories...and that's how we feel connected... overall, a must watch for those, who really enjoy quality movies!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "There are only ghosts here."
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Degree7
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Passion inspires great art in a young Toto, but as his age shifts, so does his perspective on his life machinations in a small Sicilian community. With the help of the local theatre projectionist, Alfredo, he is able to recognize his potential and move out into a wider world. But what keeps this film from simply being a sentimental ode to Italian cinema, is the reflection of a much older Toro coming to terms with the sacrifices he has made to become the man he is. Were they mistakes? Or are his past regrets still threatening to cloak his accomplishments as an individual? Despite a somewhat obtrusive score by Ennio Morriconne, this film sends a strong message about life reevaluation, and how past decisions can segue into the present, in often unexpected, but beautiful ways. A small gem of a film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Charming details don't add up to a great film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    dmayo-911-597432
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    *** This review may contain spoilers *** It would be best to see this film without knowing how warmly it was welcomed by critics and viewers at the time, or how many people still take it to their hearts. It does hold many charms in its details, but when it tries to give us a story of Life and Love it becomes banal and contrived. It also takes an oddly careless approach to the aging of its characters. Nuovo Cinema Paradiso opens with a framing story in which a middle-aged man hears that someone named Alfredo has died in his hometown and begins recalling his childhood. In the flashbacks that form the main body of the film, the setting is a town in Sicily in the decade following World War II. A small boy is irresistibly drawn to the local cinema, a world of enchantment, and to its projection booth, the heart of that world. He befriends the projectionist, Alfredo. Alfredo discourages the boy, Toto, from following in his footsteps as a projectionist and eventually encourages him to pursue his love of movies on a grander scale. We're soon prepared to learn that the grown Toto who is recollecting these things has become a famous director. In the first phase of the flashbacks, we follow little Toto in his childish peccadilloes while following the community in its avid response to movie magic (a funny exception being the gritty social realism of post-war Italian cinema, which proves as impenetrable to Sicilians as to much of the world beyond). This phase ends with the cinema destroyed by fire and Alfredo rescued by Toto but blinded for life. The Toto of the second phase is apparently in his late teens, perhaps twenty by the end of the flashback. Childish peccadilloes have given way to amateur film-making, running the projector at the rebuilt cinema, and love at first sight with a girl whose social position poses an obstacle -- in effect, a princess. As always, the life of the community and that of the film are centered on the shared joys of escape in a darkened cinema. Toto's personal life is disrupted by a period of military training, after which he finds that he can't pick up where he left off. He loses touch with Elena, his love, who has moved away. Finally, he takes Alfredo's advice and leaves town himself to make his way in the world. Very well, but it's unbelievable that he then absolutely neglects his mother for thirty years, even to the point of not returning her phone calls, although they were on good terms when he left. The only reason seems to be that the film requires a complete break with home so that the middle-aged Toto can feel he's stepping into a past world when he returns for Alfredo's funeral. Still more unbelievable is the casting of characters at different ages. The twentyish Toto is distinctly short, but the fiftyish Toto towers over everyone else in the funeral procession. Conversely, his mother changes from a tall young woman to a tiny old one. Then there is the aging of characters who are played by the same actors throughout. Alfredo's wife, who was middle-aged in the first place, only turns gray-haired and gray-faced while the transformation (by casting) of Toto's younger mother rivals that of the queen in Snow White. Indeed, slapping gray paint on actors -- while removing an obvious hairpiece from one -- is all the movie magic Tornatore offers in the framing story. Is he trying to tell us that he has decided to wash his hands of film-making as a labor of love? The many delightful moments in Nuovo Cinema Paradiso are really just so many vignettes strung together in the abrupt, sometimes bewildering manner of the 1980s. To the extent that these moments achieve a unified effect, they suggest the benign human comedy of Rene Clair. Yet they are mixed with stink-bombs of bad taste that would have puzzled Clair as to this director's intent. That, too, is a mark of the 1980s. It may be best to look for the appeal of this film in the ways in which it differs from most other films of the 1980s and many since. It does come down on the side of benign human comedy. It does cherish the magic of Golden Age film-making, even as that magic slips through its fingers. It does become an oasis of entertainment if you come upon it in a personal desert of dissatisfaction with films generally. The trouble is that if you have had the good fortune to drink from the springs of Rene Clair and other masters, Nuovo Cinema Paradiso turns out to be a mirage.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An ode to cinema, dream and emotions
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    lucio7
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Don't approach the movie with your logic part of the brain switched on. Yes, as someone said there are some flaws relative to how realistic it can be, but that doesn't matter because you'd be missing the point. Just let yourself go and enjoy this celebration of cinema, dream and emotions and this piece of art will bring you on a lovely spiritual trip. I loved it. P.S.: Sorry IMDb, but I was able to say everything I wanted to say without the mandatory 10 lines of text. I really love your website but you should pass this message to the management: quantity doesn't make quality.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An amazing, thought-provoking, deeply-insightful, emotionally-riveting winner!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    voniapeng
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Well. Wow. Let me absorb this all for a moment. Alright. So that was... one of the best films I have seen in who knows how long. It is definitely on my all-time favorites list. Such an amazing film about film... but so, so much more. It is about friendships- the very best two people can share. The multitude of ways one person, one place, one passion can change your life for eternity; without which you would be a different person altogether. This film makes me want to experience the small town life that I never have, in any way before- to have so many people who know you so well; who grew up with you or watched you grow up; who can be proud of everything you have become; who love you in ways people who have not known you since you were a baby; A place where you can return decades later to find that everything has been the same after all these years, yet, at the same time, changed. This film inspires in me a love of films than span lifetime(s) in a way that very few others have. This film makes me think about so many things: redemption, regret, love, hope, friendships, trust, appreciation; how clinging to the past can be such a rewardingly bad tendency, how so many things we have no power over are so blatantly unfair, how, in the name of love, the most difficult decisions are inevitable made. I would kill to have a friendship like Toto & 's. I am regrettably obligated to clarify that, however. Alfredo's decision regarding Toto & Elena made me so upset that... I didn't know whether I could like his character anymore. His decision and actions were out of place, mean, and wrong. In the end, though, I suppose I can only say I respect Alfredo less, as I know, in his heart, he wanted what he felt was best for Toto. I emphasize, what he felt. And that's my point exactly. Because it was not his place and therefore not his right to do what he did- his sincere care and love for Toto irrelevant in this case- although mitigating the severity of his wrong. I agree that in some ways what evolved was best for Toto- but for his career. And I am an adamant believer that love is always the No. One priority in these lives of ours. At the end of the day, financial woes, careers, daily nuisances aside, love is what matters at the end of the day; at the end of a lifetime. Toto shares this philosophy, as made obvious several times. Secondly, why in heaven's name didn't the two of them rekindle their rare, genuine love at the end? I understand that some things in life can become too late t retrieve, but, again, I agree with Toto- they should have resumed it. I know neither of them ever loved anyone else, vows or not, anywhere near as powerfully. And, despite what I may say, contrary to all logic, I wish for a love like Toto & Elena's. As the saying goes, "It is better to have loved and lost than to have never loved at all." I understand that times were different then, but, perhaps unfairly, I am upset with Elena. For not choosing true love over her family's unreasonable demands (although she did redeem herself). For not agreeing to set things right at the end. The only other issue I have is with the plausibility of some specific details. First, falling in love without ever talking, at first sight? And then Elena reciprocating, but, almost even more unbelievably, only after watching him wait outside her place for a year? Secondly, Toto's devotion to waiting outside is as unbelievable as the "soldier's" to the princess. Men like that could and would not ever exist. I would have identified so much more had it been more realistic. "Of course I remember you..." "Life is not what you see in films... Life is much harder." Amen to that. So extremely, heart-breakingly sadly.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Infinitely Innocent
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    karl-sokhn
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    We all have had moments when we seemed to cling to past sensations or childhood memories, we feel a certain comfort re invoking these thoughts into mind. That is exactly what Cinema Paradiso portrays in an almost 3 hour long movie all through which you don't budge. Allow me to explain : The past is an ambiguous word but to clarify, let's consider the past as the numerous events that lead to NOW, the present. Having said that, the movie is a picture perfect depiction of the influence of the past on one's present and future. Childhood, teenage crisis, first love, the search for one's roots etc.. I shall detail these headlines. This movie represents the main character Salvatore Di Vita,a bright little kid who, never met or had any kind of interaction with his father(a soldier in the Italian army). And Alfredo, an old man with no kids who takes care of film reels in the Cinema Paradiso. (The only downside of the Cinema Paradiso was that films were censored and scenes involving physical contact were cut from the reels). Many actions lead their relationship to strengthen throughout the movie even though their bond had an inherent tendency to grow because each of them found in the other what he was lacking. Alfredo soon becomes the father figure Salvatore longed for as a kid and the little boy starts seeking counsel with the elder in matters that he couldn't understand. He becomes the prominent person that represents Salvatore's childhood along with the Cinema Paradiso, the place where Salvatore cultivated a love for Cinematography. And finally Elena, Salvatore's one true love draws the final stroke on this amazing portrait : Giancaldo, Salvatore's home village. Outer Circumstances force Elena and Salvatore to be separated, and their attempts to communicate fall on deaf ears and they lose all kinds of contact. A while after that Alfredo's counsel leads Salvatore(Toto) to leave the cradle of his childhood in order to pursue his dreams. He returns several years after to attend Alfredo's funeral and starts to rediscover Giancaldo from an other point of view and is finally able to make peace with his past with Alfredo's posthumous help. Finally i would like to add that the movie has an air of innocence to it and an immensely frivolous atmosphere giving all the characters' feelings a sincerity that i have never seen in any other movie.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Italian classic
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    silva-w-pius
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This heart warming and uplifting film takes us on a nostalgic adventure into our youths, through the innocent and untainted eyes of a young boy, who still sees the world for all its beauty and promise, even throughout the birth and death of a picture palace that holds so much lure and magic to him. Cinema paradiso is regarded as not only one of the greatest Italian films ever exported, but one of the greatest foreign films ever! But I would strongly disagree, as far as to say it is an insult to label this majestic testament to the beauty life, as just a foreign film! It's more than that, much more. A story told in flash backs, from the perspective of a highly successful film maker in his 40's (Salvatore Cascio). Upon receiving a call from his mother to inform him that his child hood hero had unfortunately died, it forces him to recount his entire youth. Telling the story of a young Salvatore living in a run down, poverty stricken and grim war-torn, post ww2 Sicilian village with his baby sister and his harassed mother who is as free with a slap as with a hug. But finding refuge from all the pain and misery, in a cinema paradiso, a local picture hall, provides him with an idyllic paradise where his love for cinema and adventures can run free. There he soon strikes up an unshakable life long bond with a aging projectionist, serving as a father figure and confidante, then after a fire robes him of his sight, Alfredo (Philippe Noriet) encourages Salvatore to take over at the new paradiso, but eventually he would push the now young 18 year old Salvatore, tainted by his first heartbreak by his true love Elena(Agnese Nano), out of the confines of this dead beat village, to a world waiting to be explored and conquered , Only returning 30 years later, to witness the burial of Alfredo and the demolition of the cinema paradiso. Giuseppe Tornatore provides us with a poignant and almost, spiritual reminder of how the simple things that we held so delicately in are youths can almost be forgotten and misplace in our older years, as we replace the magic with vain perceptions of success and obsession with money, when we should actually try and reconnect with our youths, and again enjoy the personal cinema experience that promises so much. As soon as the end titles rolled by, I couldn't help but feel sad, as a big cinema paradiso shaped whole was left in my heart. Cinema paradiso is a film that stirs up a lot of home truths, a great watch for brave individuals.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A film for movie fans.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Thanos Alfie
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Nuovo Cinema Paradiso is a movie for movie and cinema fans. In this movie you will understand the true meaning of love of the cinema. When I saw this movie I loved it because I think it represents the love for films that every movie fan has. I liked very much the performance of Salvatore Cascio as young "Salvatore 'Tot&ograve;' Di Vita" and of course the performance of Phillpe Noiret as "Alfredo". I also liked very much the true love between Marco Leonardi/Jacques Perrin as a teenager and adult "Salvatore 'Tot&ograve;' Di Vita" and Agnese Nano / Brigitte Fossey as a teenager and as adult Elena Mendola. I saw the extended movie of 155 minutes and not the "cut" movie of 121 minutes and I think that it worth it, I did not get bored for even a minute instead of it I really liked it!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Lotsa pathos, little substance
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    George Aar
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is a pleasant enough movie, I guess. But really not noteworthy in any substantial way. There's a movie theatre that is obviously a set. There's a whole stable of stock characters and lots of forced emotion, but there's just no meat on the bones. And then there's all those questions unanswered. Why did little Toto (who's a really cute little kid) act out towards everyone, no matter how hard they tried to befriend him? Why did Toto's mother treat him so poorly and beat him so much? Why did Toto's father leave? Why did Toto's girlfriend leave? How could Toto be so much in love with a girl he didn't even know? What happened to his girlfriend? Why did he never come back to his hometown? Why did his life end up so apparently empty and unsatisfying? And there's more I haven't even touched on. All of those questions and no answers are even attempted for any of them. All there is is a token tearful scene here and there and a few oddball philosophical parables and the rest of the script is basically left blank. I found it rather odd. Odd and unfulfilling. I think most people would expect more from a story.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    love of a life time
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Che 19c94
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I am the kind of person that usually never tears up for a movie, but here i just can't help it. Cinema Paradiso is one of those rare movies you just have to see. And if you are a movie fan yourself, like i am, the movie would quickly be at heart. The best thing about foreign films is that you never know the actors since you have never seen them in any other movie. It is as if your watching real people go by their lives. This is the kind of movie that everybody has to see. I don't know why this movie has an R rating but the version I saw, the original 1988 version, is suitable for everyone. ENJOY
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A masterpiece: Watch it to understand, why!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mike-world1
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Among the best movies, I ever saw....for a change, don't know whether I call it drama, romance, inspiration or depressing or what...but have to say that in the last 60 minutes, I incessantly cried...I've seen some wonderful movies, but this is among the best...direction: flawless and a class-apart, cast: nothing could have been better, sets: perfectly suit the story, and story-line: quite different... the way movie moves just keeps us engrossed, without being able to anticipate what is going to happen, specially in the last one hour...maybe it tells what life is, or helps to find a reflection of our life stories...and that's how we feel connected... overall, a must watch for those, who really enjoy quality movies!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "There are only ghosts here."
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Degree7
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Passion inspires great art in a young Toto, but as his age shifts, so does his perspective on his life machinations in a small Sicilian community. With the help of the local theatre projectionist, Alfredo, he is able to recognize his potential and move out into a wider world. But what keeps this film from simply being a sentimental ode to Italian cinema, is the reflection of a much older Toro coming to terms with the sacrifices he has made to become the man he is. Were they mistakes? Or are his past regrets still threatening to cloak his accomplishments as an individual? Despite a somewhat obtrusive score by Ennio Morriconne, this film sends a strong message about life reevaluation, and how past decisions can segue into the present, in often unexpected, but beautiful ways. A small gem of a film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Charming details don't add up to a great film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    dmayo-911-597432
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    *** This review may contain spoilers *** It would be best to see this film without knowing how warmly it was welcomed by critics and viewers at the time, or how many people still take it to their hearts. It does hold many charms in its details, but when it tries to give us a story of Life and Love it becomes banal and contrived. It also takes an oddly careless approach to the aging of its characters. Nuovo Cinema Paradiso opens with a framing story in which a middle-aged man hears that someone named Alfredo has died in his hometown and begins recalling his childhood. In the flashbacks that form the main body of the film, the setting is a town in Sicily in the decade following World War II. A small boy is irresistibly drawn to the local cinema, a world of enchantment, and to its projection booth, the heart of that world. He befriends the projectionist, Alfredo. Alfredo discourages the boy, Toto, from following in his footsteps as a projectionist and eventually encourages him to pursue his love of movies on a grander scale. We're soon prepared to learn that the grown Toto who is recollecting these things has become a famous director. In the first phase of the flashbacks, we follow little Toto in his childish peccadilloes while following the community in its avid response to movie magic (a funny exception being the gritty social realism of post-war Italian cinema, which proves as impenetrable to Sicilians as to much of the world beyond). This phase ends with the cinema destroyed by fire and Alfredo rescued by Toto but blinded for life. The Toto of the second phase is apparently in his late teens, perhaps twenty by the end of the flashback. Childish peccadilloes have given way to amateur film-making, running the projector at the rebuilt cinema, and love at first sight with a girl whose social position poses an obstacle -- in effect, a princess. As always, the life of the community and that of the film are centered on the shared joys of escape in a darkened cinema. Toto's personal life is disrupted by a period of military training, after which he finds that he can't pick up where he left off. He loses touch with Elena, his love, who has moved away. Finally, he takes Alfredo's advice and leaves town himself to make his way in the world. Very well, but it's unbelievable that he then absolutely neglects his mother for thirty years, even to the point of not returning her phone calls, although they were on good terms when he left. The only reason seems to be that the film requires a complete break with home so that the middle-aged Toto can feel he's stepping into a past world when he returns for Alfredo's funeral. Still more unbelievable is the casting of characters at different ages. The twentyish Toto is distinctly short, but the fiftyish Toto towers over everyone else in the funeral procession. Conversely, his mother changes from a tall young woman to a tiny old one. Then there is the aging of characters who are played by the same actors throughout. Alfredo's wife, who was middle-aged in the first place, only turns gray-haired and gray-faced while the transformation (by casting) of Toto's younger mother rivals that of the queen in Snow White. Indeed, slapping gray paint on actors -- while removing an obvious hairpiece from one -- is all the movie magic Tornatore offers in the framing story. Is he trying to tell us that he has decided to wash his hands of film-making as a labor of love? The many delightful moments in Nuovo Cinema Paradiso are really just so many vignettes strung together in the abrupt, sometimes bewildering manner of the 1980s. To the extent that these moments achieve a unified effect, they suggest the benign human comedy of Rene Clair. Yet they are mixed with stink-bombs of bad taste that would have puzzled Clair as to this director's intent. That, too, is a mark of the 1980s. It may be best to look for the appeal of this film in the ways in which it differs from most other films of the 1980s and many since. It does come down on the side of benign human comedy. It does cherish the magic of Golden Age film-making, even as that magic slips through its fingers. It does become an oasis of entertainment if you come upon it in a personal desert of dissatisfaction with films generally. The trouble is that if you have had the good fortune to drink from the springs of Rene Clair and other masters, Nuovo Cinema Paradiso turns out to be a mirage.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An ode to cinema, dream and emotions
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    lucio7
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Don't approach the movie with your logic part of the brain switched on. Yes, as someone said there are some flaws relative to how realistic it can be, but that doesn't matter because you'd be missing the point. Just let yourself go and enjoy this celebration of cinema, dream and emotions and this piece of art will bring you on a lovely spiritual trip. I loved it. P.S.: Sorry IMDb, but I was able to say everything I wanted to say without the mandatory 10 lines of text. I really love your website but you should pass this message to the management: quantity doesn't make quality.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An amazing, thought-provoking, deeply-insightful, emotionally-riveting winner!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    voniapeng
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Well. Wow. Let me absorb this all for a moment. Alright. So that was... one of the best films I have seen in who knows how long. It is definitely on my all-time favorites list. Such an amazing film about film... but so, so much more. It is about friendships- the very best two people can share. The multitude of ways one person, one place, one passion can change your life for eternity; without which you would be a different person altogether. This film makes me want to experience the small town life that I never have, in any way before- to have so many people who know you so well; who grew up with you or watched you grow up; who can be proud of everything you have become; who love you in ways people who have not known you since you were a baby; A place where you can return decades later to find that everything has been the same after all these years, yet, at the same time, changed. This film inspires in me a love of films than span lifetime(s) in a way that very few others have. This film makes me think about so many things: redemption, regret, love, hope, friendships, trust, appreciation; how clinging to the past can be such a rewardingly bad tendency, how so many things we have no power over are so blatantly unfair, how, in the name of love, the most difficult decisions are inevitable made. I would kill to have a friendship like Toto & 's. I am regrettably obligated to clarify that, however. Alfredo's decision regarding Toto & Elena made me so upset that... I didn't know whether I could like his character anymore. His decision and actions were out of place, mean, and wrong. In the end, though, I suppose I can only say I respect Alfredo less, as I know, in his heart, he wanted what he felt was best for Toto. I emphasize, what he felt. And that's my point exactly. Because it was not his place and therefore not his right to do what he did- his sincere care and love for Toto irrelevant in this case- although mitigating the severity of his wrong. I agree that in some ways what evolved was best for Toto- but for his career. And I am an adamant believer that love is always the No. One priority in these lives of ours. At the end of the day, financial woes, careers, daily nuisances aside, love is what matters at the end of the day; at the end of a lifetime. Toto shares this philosophy, as made obvious several times. Secondly, why in heaven's name didn't the two of them rekindle their rare, genuine love at the end? I understand that some things in life can become too late t retrieve, but, again, I agree with Toto- they should have resumed it. I know neither of them ever loved anyone else, vows or not, anywhere near as powerfully. And, despite what I may say, contrary to all logic, I wish for a love like Toto & Elena's. As the saying goes, "It is better to have loved and lost than to have never loved at all." I understand that times were different then, but, perhaps unfairly, I am upset with Elena. For not choosing true love over her family's unreasonable demands (although she did redeem herself). For not agreeing to set things right at the end. The only other issue I have is with the plausibility of some specific details. First, falling in love without ever talking, at first sight? And then Elena reciprocating, but, almost even more unbelievably, only after watching him wait outside her place for a year? Secondly, Toto's devotion to waiting outside is as unbelievable as the "soldier's" to the princess. Men like that could and would not ever exist. I would have identified so much more had it been more realistic. "Of course I remember you..." "Life is not what you see in films... Life is much harder." Amen to that. So extremely, heart-breakingly sadly.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Infinitely Innocent
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    karl-sokhn
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    We all have had moments when we seemed to cling to past sensations or childhood memories, we feel a certain comfort re invoking these thoughts into mind. That is exactly what Cinema Paradiso portrays in an almost 3 hour long movie all through which you don't budge. Allow me to explain : The past is an ambiguous word but to clarify, let's consider the past as the numerous events that lead to NOW, the present. Having said that, the movie is a picture perfect depiction of the influence of the past on one's present and future. Childhood, teenage crisis, first love, the search for one's roots etc.. I shall detail these headlines. This movie represents the main character Salvatore Di Vita,a bright little kid who, never met or had any kind of interaction with his father(a soldier in the Italian army). And Alfredo, an old man with no kids who takes care of film reels in the Cinema Paradiso. (The only downside of the Cinema Paradiso was that films were censored and scenes involving physical contact were cut from the reels). Many actions lead their relationship to strengthen throughout the movie even though their bond had an inherent tendency to grow because each of them found in the other what he was lacking. Alfredo soon becomes the father figure Salvatore longed for as a kid and the little boy starts seeking counsel with the elder in matters that he couldn't understand. He becomes the prominent person that represents Salvatore's childhood along with the Cinema Paradiso, the place where Salvatore cultivated a love for Cinematography. And finally Elena, Salvatore's one true love draws the final stroke on this amazing portrait : Giancaldo, Salvatore's home village. Outer Circumstances force Elena and Salvatore to be separated, and their attempts to communicate fall on deaf ears and they lose all kinds of contact. A while after that Alfredo's counsel leads Salvatore(Toto) to leave the cradle of his childhood in order to pursue his dreams. He returns several years after to attend Alfredo's funeral and starts to rediscover Giancaldo from an other point of view and is finally able to make peace with his past with Alfredo's posthumous help. Finally i would like to add that the movie has an air of innocence to it and an immensely frivolous atmosphere giving all the characters' feelings a sincerity that i have never seen in any other movie.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Italian classic
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    silva-w-pius
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This heart warming and uplifting film takes us on a nostalgic adventure into our youths, through the innocent and untainted eyes of a young boy, who still sees the world for all its beauty and promise, even throughout the birth and death of a picture palace that holds so much lure and magic to him. Cinema paradiso is regarded as not only one of the greatest Italian films ever exported, but one of the greatest foreign films ever! But I would strongly disagree, as far as to say it is an insult to label this majestic testament to the beauty life, as just a foreign film! It's more than that, much more. A story told in flash backs, from the perspective of a highly successful film maker in his 40's (Salvatore Cascio). Upon receiving a call from his mother to inform him that his child hood hero had unfortunately died, it forces him to recount his entire youth. Telling the story of a young Salvatore living in a run down, poverty stricken and grim war-torn, post ww2 Sicilian village with his baby sister and his harassed mother who is as free with a slap as with a hug. But finding refuge from all the pain and misery, in a cinema paradiso, a local picture hall, provides him with an idyllic paradise where his love for cinema and adventures can run free. There he soon strikes up an unshakable life long bond with a aging projectionist, serving as a father figure and confidante, then after a fire robes him of his sight, Alfredo (Philippe Noriet) encourages Salvatore to take over at the new paradiso, but eventually he would push the now young 18 year old Salvatore, tainted by his first heartbreak by his true love Elena(Agnese Nano), out of the confines of this dead beat village, to a world waiting to be explored and conquered , Only returning 30 years later, to witness the burial of Alfredo and the demolition of the cinema paradiso. Giuseppe Tornatore provides us with a poignant and almost, spiritual reminder of how the simple things that we held so delicately in are youths can almost be forgotten and misplace in our older years, as we replace the magic with vain perceptions of success and obsession with money, when we should actually try and reconnect with our youths, and again enjoy the personal cinema experience that promises so much. As soon as the end titles rolled by, I couldn't help but feel sad, as a big cinema paradiso shaped whole was left in my heart. Cinema paradiso is a film that stirs up a lot of home truths, a great watch for brave individuals.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A film for movie fans.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Thanos Alfie
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Nuovo Cinema Paradiso is a movie for movie and cinema fans. In this movie you will understand the true meaning of love of the cinema. When I saw this movie I loved it because I think it represents the love for films that every movie fan has. I liked very much the performance of Salvatore Cascio as young "Salvatore 'Tot&ograve;' Di Vita" and of course the performance of Phillpe Noiret as "Alfredo". I also liked very much the true love between Marco Leonardi/Jacques Perrin as a teenager and adult "Salvatore 'Tot&ograve;' Di Vita" and Agnese Nano / Brigitte Fossey as a teenager and as adult Elena Mendola. I saw the extended movie of 155 minutes and not the "cut" movie of 121 minutes and I think that it worth it, I did not get bored for even a minute instead of it I really liked it!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Lotsa pathos, little substance
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    George Aar
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is a pleasant enough movie, I guess. But really not noteworthy in any substantial way. There's a movie theatre that is obviously a set. There's a whole stable of stock characters and lots of forced emotion, but there's just no meat on the bones. And then there's all those questions unanswered. Why did little Toto (who's a really cute little kid) act out towards everyone, no matter how hard they tried to befriend him? Why did Toto's mother treat him so poorly and beat him so much? Why did Toto's father leave? Why did Toto's girlfriend leave? How could Toto be so much in love with a girl he didn't even know? What happened to his girlfriend? Why did he never come back to his hometown? Why did his life end up so apparently empty and unsatisfying? And there's more I haven't even touched on. All of those questions and no answers are even attempted for any of them. All there is is a token tearful scene here and there and a few oddball philosophical parables and the rest of the script is basically left blank. I found it rather odd. Odd and unfulfilling. I think most people would expect more from a story.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    love of a life time
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Che 19c94
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I am the kind of person that usually never tears up for a movie, but here i just can't help it. Cinema Paradiso is one of those rare movies you just have to see. And if you are a movie fan yourself, like i am, the movie would quickly be at heart. The best thing about foreign films is that you never know the actors since you have never seen them in any other movie. It is as if your watching real people go by their lives. This is the kind of movie that everybody has to see. I don't know why this movie has an R rating but the version I saw, the original 1988 version, is suitable for everyone. ENJOY
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A masterpiece: Watch it to understand, why!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mike-world1
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Among the best movies, I ever saw....for a change, don't know whether I call it drama, romance, inspiration or depressing or what...but have to say that in the last 60 minutes, I incessantly cried...I've seen some wonderful movies, but this is among the best...direction: flawless and a class-apart, cast: nothing could have been better, sets: perfectly suit the story, and story-line: quite different... the way movie moves just keeps us engrossed, without being able to anticipate what is going to happen, specially in the last one hour...maybe it tells what life is, or helps to find a reflection of our life stories...and that's how we feel connected... overall, a must watch for those, who really enjoy quality movies!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "There are only ghosts here."
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Degree7
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Passion inspires great art in a young Toto, but as his age shifts, so does his perspective on his life machinations in a small Sicilian community. With the help of the local theatre projectionist, Alfredo, he is able to recognize his potential and move out into a wider world. But what keeps this film from simply being a sentimental ode to Italian cinema, is the reflection of a much older Toro coming to terms with the sacrifices he has made to become the man he is. Were they mistakes? Or are his past regrets still threatening to cloak his accomplishments as an individual? Despite a somewhat obtrusive score by Ennio Morriconne, this film sends a strong message about life reevaluation, and how past decisions can segue into the present, in often unexpected, but beautiful ways. A small gem of a film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Charming details don't add up to a great film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    dmayo-911-597432
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    *** This review may contain spoilers *** It would be best to see this film without knowing how warmly it was welcomed by critics and viewers at the time, or how many people still take it to their hearts. It does hold many charms in its details, but when it tries to give us a story of Life and Love it becomes banal and contrived. It also takes an oddly careless approach to the aging of its characters. Nuovo Cinema Paradiso opens with a framing story in which a middle-aged man hears that someone named Alfredo has died in his hometown and begins recalling his childhood. In the flashbacks that form the main body of the film, the setting is a town in Sicily in the decade following World War II. A small boy is irresistibly drawn to the local cinema, a world of enchantment, and to its projection booth, the heart of that world. He befriends the projectionist, Alfredo. Alfredo discourages the boy, Toto, from following in his footsteps as a projectionist and eventually encourages him to pursue his love of movies on a grander scale. We're soon prepared to learn that the grown Toto who is recollecting these things has become a famous director. In the first phase of the flashbacks, we follow little Toto in his childish peccadilloes while following the community in its avid response to movie magic (a funny exception being the gritty social realism of post-war Italian cinema, which proves as impenetrable to Sicilians as to much of the world beyond). This phase ends with the cinema destroyed by fire and Alfredo rescued by Toto but blinded for life. The Toto of the second phase is apparently in his late teens, perhaps twenty by the end of the flashback. Childish peccadilloes have given way to amateur film-making, running the projector at the rebuilt cinema, and love at first sight with a girl whose social position poses an obstacle -- in effect, a princess. As always, the life of the community and that of the film are centered on the shared joys of escape in a darkened cinema. Toto's personal life is disrupted by a period of military training, after which he finds that he can't pick up where he left off. He loses touch with Elena, his love, who has moved away. Finally, he takes Alfredo's advice and leaves town himself to make his way in the world. Very well, but it's unbelievable that he then absolutely neglects his mother for thirty years, even to the point of not returning her phone calls, although they were on good terms when he left. The only reason seems to be that the film requires a complete break with home so that the middle-aged Toto can feel he's stepping into a past world when he returns for Alfredo's funeral. Still more unbelievable is the casting of characters at different ages. The twentyish Toto is distinctly short, but the fiftyish Toto towers over everyone else in the funeral procession. Conversely, his mother changes from a tall young woman to a tiny old one. Then there is the aging of characters who are played by the same actors throughout. Alfredo's wife, who was middle-aged in the first place, only turns gray-haired and gray-faced while the transformation (by casting) of Toto's younger mother rivals that of the queen in Snow White. Indeed, slapping gray paint on actors -- while removing an obvious hairpiece from one -- is all the movie magic Tornatore offers in the framing story. Is he trying to tell us that he has decided to wash his hands of film-making as a labor of love? The many delightful moments in Nuovo Cinema Paradiso are really just so many vignettes strung together in the abrupt, sometimes bewildering manner of the 1980s. To the extent that these moments achieve a unified effect, they suggest the benign human comedy of Rene Clair. Yet they are mixed with stink-bombs of bad taste that would have puzzled Clair as to this director's intent. That, too, is a mark of the 1980s. It may be best to look for the appeal of this film in the ways in which it differs from most other films of the 1980s and many since. It does come down on the side of benign human comedy. It does cherish the magic of Golden Age film-making, even as that magic slips through its fingers. It does become an oasis of entertainment if you come upon it in a personal desert of dissatisfaction with films generally. The trouble is that if you have had the good fortune to drink from the springs of Rene Clair and other masters, Nuovo Cinema Paradiso turns out to be a mirage.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An ode to cinema, dream and emotions
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    lucio7
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Don't approach the movie with your logic part of the brain switched on. Yes, as someone said there are some flaws relative to how realistic it can be, but that doesn't matter because you'd be missing the point. Just let yourself go and enjoy this celebration of cinema, dream and emotions and this piece of art will bring you on a lovely spiritual trip. I loved it. P.S.: Sorry IMDb, but I was able to say everything I wanted to say without the mandatory 10 lines of text. I really love your website but you should pass this message to the management: quantity doesn't make quality.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An amazing, thought-provoking, deeply-insightful, emotionally-riveting winner!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    voniapeng
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Well. Wow. Let me absorb this all for a moment. Alright. So that was... one of the best films I have seen in who knows how long. It is definitely on my all-time favorites list. Such an amazing film about film... but so, so much more. It is about friendships- the very best two people can share. The multitude of ways one person, one place, one passion can change your life for eternity; without which you would be a different person altogether. This film makes me want to experience the small town life that I never have, in any way before- to have so many people who know you so well; who grew up with you or watched you grow up; who can be proud of everything you have become; who love you in ways people who have not known you since you were a baby; A place where you can return decades later to find that everything has been the same after all these years, yet, at the same time, changed. This film inspires in me a love of films than span lifetime(s) in a way that very few others have. This film makes me think about so many things: redemption, regret, love, hope, friendships, trust, appreciation; how clinging to the past can be such a rewardingly bad tendency, how so many things we have no power over are so blatantly unfair, how, in the name of love, the most difficult decisions are inevitable made. I would kill to have a friendship like Toto & 's. I am regrettably obligated to clarify that, however. Alfredo's decision regarding Toto & Elena made me so upset that... I didn't know whether I could like his character anymore. His decision and actions were out of place, mean, and wrong. In the end, though, I suppose I can only say I respect Alfredo less, as I know, in his heart, he wanted what he felt was best for Toto. I emphasize, what he felt. And that's my point exactly. Because it was not his place and therefore not his right to do what he did- his sincere care and love for Toto irrelevant in this case- although mitigating the severity of his wrong. I agree that in some ways what evolved was best for Toto- but for his career. And I am an adamant believer that love is always the No. One priority in these lives of ours. At the end of the day, financial woes, careers, daily nuisances aside, love is what matters at the end of the day; at the end of a lifetime. Toto shares this philosophy, as made obvious several times. Secondly, why in heaven's name didn't the two of them rekindle their rare, genuine love at the end? I understand that some things in life can become too late t retrieve, but, again, I agree with Toto- they should have resumed it. I know neither of them ever loved anyone else, vows or not, anywhere near as powerfully. And, despite what I may say, contrary to all logic, I wish for a love like Toto & Elena's. As the saying goes, "It is better to have loved and lost than to have never loved at all." I understand that times were different then, but, perhaps unfairly, I am upset with Elena. For not choosing true love over her family's unreasonable demands (although she did redeem herself). For not agreeing to set things right at the end. The only other issue I have is with the plausibility of some specific details. First, falling in love without ever talking, at first sight? And then Elena reciprocating, but, almost even more unbelievably, only after watching him wait outside her place for a year? Secondly, Toto's devotion to waiting outside is as unbelievable as the "soldier's" to the princess. Men like that could and would not ever exist. I would have identified so much more had it been more realistic. "Of course I remember you..." "Life is not what you see in films... Life is much harder." Amen to that. So extremely, heart-breakingly sadly.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Infinitely Innocent
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    karl-sokhn
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    We all have had moments when we seemed to cling to past sensations or childhood memories, we feel a certain comfort re invoking these thoughts into mind. That is exactly what Cinema Paradiso portrays in an almost 3 hour long movie all through which you don't budge. Allow me to explain : The past is an ambiguous word but to clarify, let's consider the past as the numerous events that lead to NOW, the present. Having said that, the movie is a picture perfect depiction of the influence of the past on one's present and future. Childhood, teenage crisis, first love, the search for one's roots etc.. I shall detail these headlines. This movie represents the main character Salvatore Di Vita,a bright little kid who, never met or had any kind of interaction with his father(a soldier in the Italian army). And Alfredo, an old man with no kids who takes care of film reels in the Cinema Paradiso. (The only downside of the Cinema Paradiso was that films were censored and scenes involving physical contact were cut from the reels). Many actions lead their relationship to strengthen throughout the movie even though their bond had an inherent tendency to grow because each of them found in the other what he was lacking. Alfredo soon becomes the father figure Salvatore longed for as a kid and the little boy starts seeking counsel with the elder in matters that he couldn't understand. He becomes the prominent person that represents Salvatore's childhood along with the Cinema Paradiso, the place where Salvatore cultivated a love for Cinematography. And finally Elena, Salvatore's one true love draws the final stroke on this amazing portrait : Giancaldo, Salvatore's home village. Outer Circumstances force Elena and Salvatore to be separated, and their attempts to communicate fall on deaf ears and they lose all kinds of contact. A while after that Alfredo's counsel leads Salvatore(Toto) to leave the cradle of his childhood in order to pursue his dreams. He returns several years after to attend Alfredo's funeral and starts to rediscover Giancaldo from an other point of view and is finally able to make peace with his past with Alfredo's posthumous help. Finally i would like to add that the movie has an air of innocence to it and an immensely frivolous atmosphere giving all the characters' feelings a sincerity that i have never seen in any other movie.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Italian classic
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    silva-w-pius
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This heart warming and uplifting film takes us on a nostalgic adventure into our youths, through the innocent and untainted eyes of a young boy, who still sees the world for all its beauty and promise, even throughout the birth and death of a picture palace that holds so much lure and magic to him. Cinema paradiso is regarded as not only one of the greatest Italian films ever exported, but one of the greatest foreign films ever! But I would strongly disagree, as far as to say it is an insult to label this majestic testament to the beauty life, as just a foreign film! It's more than that, much more. A story told in flash backs, from the perspective of a highly successful film maker in his 40's (Salvatore Cascio). Upon receiving a call from his mother to inform him that his child hood hero had unfortunately died, it forces him to recount his entire youth. Telling the story of a young Salvatore living in a run down, poverty stricken and grim war-torn, post ww2 Sicilian village with his baby sister and his harassed mother who is as free with a slap as with a hug. But finding refuge from all the pain and misery, in a cinema paradiso, a local picture hall, provides him with an idyllic paradise where his love for cinema and adventures can run free. There he soon strikes up an unshakable life long bond with a aging projectionist, serving as a father figure and confidante, then after a fire robes him of his sight, Alfredo (Philippe Noriet) encourages Salvatore to take over at the new paradiso, but eventually he would push the now young 18 year old Salvatore, tainted by his first heartbreak by his true love Elena(Agnese Nano), out of the confines of this dead beat village, to a world waiting to be explored and conquered , Only returning 30 years later, to witness the burial of Alfredo and the demolition of the cinema paradiso. Giuseppe Tornatore provides us with a poignant and almost, spiritual reminder of how the simple things that we held so delicately in are youths can almost be forgotten and misplace in our older years, as we replace the magic with vain perceptions of success and obsession with money, when we should actually try and reconnect with our youths, and again enjoy the personal cinema experience that promises so much. As soon as the end titles rolled by, I couldn't help but feel sad, as a big cinema paradiso shaped whole was left in my heart. Cinema paradiso is a film that stirs up a lot of home truths, a great watch for brave individuals.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A film for movie fans.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Thanos Alfie
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Nuovo Cinema Paradiso is a movie for movie and cinema fans. In this movie you will understand the true meaning of love of the cinema. When I saw this movie I loved it because I think it represents the love for films that every movie fan has. I liked very much the performance of Salvatore Cascio as young "Salvatore 'Tot&ograve;' Di Vita" and of course the performance of Phillpe Noiret as "Alfredo". I also liked very much the true love between Marco Leonardi/Jacques Perrin as a teenager and adult "Salvatore 'Tot&ograve;' Di Vita" and Agnese Nano / Brigitte Fossey as a teenager and as adult Elena Mendola. I saw the extended movie of 155 minutes and not the "cut" movie of 121 minutes and I think that it worth it, I did not get bored for even a minute instead of it I really liked it!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Lotsa pathos, little substance
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    George Aar
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is a pleasant enough movie, I guess. But really not noteworthy in any substantial way. There's a movie theatre that is obviously a set. There's a whole stable of stock characters and lots of forced emotion, but there's just no meat on the bones. And then there's all those questions unanswered. Why did little Toto (who's a really cute little kid) act out towards everyone, no matter how hard they tried to befriend him? Why did Toto's mother treat him so poorly and beat him so much? Why did Toto's father leave? Why did Toto's girlfriend leave? How could Toto be so much in love with a girl he didn't even know? What happened to his girlfriend? Why did he never come back to his hometown? Why did his life end up so apparently empty and unsatisfying? And there's more I haven't even touched on. All of those questions and no answers are even attempted for any of them. All there is is a token tearful scene here and there and a few oddball philosophical parables and the rest of the script is basically left blank. I found it rather odd. Odd and unfulfilling. I think most people would expect more from a story.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    love of a life time
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Che 19c94
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I am the kind of person that usually never tears up for a movie, but here i just can't help it. Cinema Paradiso is one of those rare movies you just have to see. And if you are a movie fan yourself, like i am, the movie would quickly be at heart. The best thing about foreign films is that you never know the actors since you have never seen them in any other movie. It is as if your watching real people go by their lives. This is the kind of movie that everybody has to see. I don't know why this movie has an R rating but the version I saw, the original 1988 version, is suitable for everyone. ENJOY
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A masterpiece: Watch it to understand, why!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mike-world1
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Among the best movies, I ever saw....for a change, don't know whether I call it drama, romance, inspiration or depressing or what...but have to say that in the last 60 minutes, I incessantly cried...I've seen some wonderful movies, but this is among the best...direction: flawless and a class-apart, cast: nothing could have been better, sets: perfectly suit the story, and story-line: quite different... the way movie moves just keeps us engrossed, without being able to anticipate what is going to happen, specially in the last one hour...maybe it tells what life is, or helps to find a reflection of our life stories...and that's how we feel connected... overall, a must watch for those, who really enjoy quality movies!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "There are only ghosts here."
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Degree7
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Passion inspires great art in a young Toto, but as his age shifts, so does his perspective on his life machinations in a small Sicilian community. With the help of the local theatre projectionist, Alfredo, he is able to recognize his potential and move out into a wider world. But what keeps this film from simply being a sentimental ode to Italian cinema, is the reflection of a much older Toro coming to terms with the sacrifices he has made to become the man he is. Were they mistakes? Or are his past regrets still threatening to cloak his accomplishments as an individual? Despite a somewhat obtrusive score by Ennio Morriconne, this film sends a strong message about life reevaluation, and how past decisions can segue into the present, in often unexpected, but beautiful ways. A small gem of a film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Charming details don't add up to a great film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    dmayo-911-597432
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    *** This review may contain spoilers *** It would be best to see this film without knowing how warmly it was welcomed by critics and viewers at the time, or how many people still take it to their hearts. It does hold many charms in its details, but when it tries to give us a story of Life and Love it becomes banal and contrived. It also takes an oddly careless approach to the aging of its characters. Nuovo Cinema Paradiso opens with a framing story in which a middle-aged man hears that someone named Alfredo has died in his hometown and begins recalling his childhood. In the flashbacks that form the main body of the film, the setting is a town in Sicily in the decade following World War II. A small boy is irresistibly drawn to the local cinema, a world of enchantment, and to its projection booth, the heart of that world. He befriends the projectionist, Alfredo. Alfredo discourages the boy, Toto, from following in his footsteps as a projectionist and eventually encourages him to pursue his love of movies on a grander scale. We're soon prepared to learn that the grown Toto who is recollecting these things has become a famous director. In the first phase of the flashbacks, we follow little Toto in his childish peccadilloes while following the community in its avid response to movie magic (a funny exception being the gritty social realism of post-war Italian cinema, which proves as impenetrable to Sicilians as to much of the world beyond). This phase ends with the cinema destroyed by fire and Alfredo rescued by Toto but blinded for life. The Toto of the second phase is apparently in his late teens, perhaps twenty by the end of the flashback. Childish peccadilloes have given way to amateur film-making, running the projector at the rebuilt cinema, and love at first sight with a girl whose social position poses an obstacle -- in effect, a princess. As always, the life of the community and that of the film are centered on the shared joys of escape in a darkened cinema. Toto's personal life is disrupted by a period of military training, after which he finds that he can't pick up where he left off. He loses touch with Elena, his love, who has moved away. Finally, he takes Alfredo's advice and leaves town himself to make his way in the world. Very well, but it's unbelievable that he then absolutely neglects his mother for thirty years, even to the point of not returning her phone calls, although they were on good terms when he left. The only reason seems to be that the film requires a complete break with home so that the middle-aged Toto can feel he's stepping into a past world when he returns for Alfredo's funeral. Still more unbelievable is the casting of characters at different ages. The twentyish Toto is distinctly short, but the fiftyish Toto towers over everyone else in the funeral procession. Conversely, his mother changes from a tall young woman to a tiny old one. Then there is the aging of characters who are played by the same actors throughout. Alfredo's wife, who was middle-aged in the first place, only turns gray-haired and gray-faced while the transformation (by casting) of Toto's younger mother rivals that of the queen in Snow White. Indeed, slapping gray paint on actors -- while removing an obvious hairpiece from one -- is all the movie magic Tornatore offers in the framing story. Is he trying to tell us that he has decided to wash his hands of film-making as a labor of love? The many delightful moments in Nuovo Cinema Paradiso are really just so many vignettes strung together in the abrupt, sometimes bewildering manner of the 1980s. To the extent that these moments achieve a unified effect, they suggest the benign human comedy of Rene Clair. Yet they are mixed with stink-bombs of bad taste that would have puzzled Clair as to this director's intent. That, too, is a mark of the 1980s. It may be best to look for the appeal of this film in the ways in which it differs from most other films of the 1980s and many since. It does come down on the side of benign human comedy. It does cherish the magic of Golden Age film-making, even as that magic slips through its fingers. It does become an oasis of entertainment if you come upon it in a personal desert of dissatisfaction with films generally. The trouble is that if you have had the good fortune to drink from the springs of Rene Clair and other masters, Nuovo Cinema Paradiso turns out to be a mirage.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An ode to cinema, dream and emotions
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    lucio7
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Don't approach the movie with your logic part of the brain switched on. Yes, as someone said there are some flaws relative to how realistic it can be, but that doesn't matter because you'd be missing the point. Just let yourself go and enjoy this celebration of cinema, dream and emotions and this piece of art will bring you on a lovely spiritual trip. I loved it. P.S.: Sorry IMDb, but I was able to say everything I wanted to say without the mandatory 10 lines of text. I really love your website but you should pass this message to the management: quantity doesn't make quality.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An amazing, thought-provoking, deeply-insightful, emotionally-riveting winner!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    voniapeng
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Well. Wow. Let me absorb this all for a moment. Alright. So that was... one of the best films I have seen in who knows how long. It is definitely on my all-time favorites list. Such an amazing film about film... but so, so much more. It is about friendships- the very best two people can share. The multitude of ways one person, one place, one passion can change your life for eternity; without which you would be a different person altogether. This film makes me want to experience the small town life that I never have, in any way before- to have so many people who know you so well; who grew up with you or watched you grow up; who can be proud of everything you have become; who love you in ways people who have not known you since you were a baby; A place where you can return decades later to find that everything has been the same after all these years, yet, at the same time, changed. This film inspires in me a love of films than span lifetime(s) in a way that very few others have. This film makes me think about so many things: redemption, regret, love, hope, friendships, trust, appreciation; how clinging to the past can be such a rewardingly bad tendency, how so many things we have no power over are so blatantly unfair, how, in the name of love, the most difficult decisions are inevitable made. I would kill to have a friendship like Toto & 's. I am regrettably obligated to clarify that, however. Alfredo's decision regarding Toto & Elena made me so upset that... I didn't know whether I could like his character anymore. His decision and actions were out of place, mean, and wrong. In the end, though, I suppose I can only say I respect Alfredo less, as I know, in his heart, he wanted what he felt was best for Toto. I emphasize, what he felt. And that's my point exactly. Because it was not his place and therefore not his right to do what he did- his sincere care and love for Toto irrelevant in this case- although mitigating the severity of his wrong. I agree that in some ways what evolved was best for Toto- but for his career. And I am an adamant believer that love is always the No. One priority in these lives of ours. At the end of the day, financial woes, careers, daily nuisances aside, love is what matters at the end of the day; at the end of a lifetime. Toto shares this philosophy, as made obvious several times. Secondly, why in heaven's name didn't the two of them rekindle their rare, genuine love at the end? I understand that some things in life can become too late t retrieve, but, again, I agree with Toto- they should have resumed it. I know neither of them ever loved anyone else, vows or not, anywhere near as powerfully. And, despite what I may say, contrary to all logic, I wish for a love like Toto & Elena's. As the saying goes, "It is better to have loved and lost than to have never loved at all." I understand that times were different then, but, perhaps unfairly, I am upset with Elena. For not choosing true love over her family's unreasonable demands (although she did redeem herself). For not agreeing to set things right at the end. The only other issue I have is with the plausibility of some specific details. First, falling in love without ever talking, at first sight? And then Elena reciprocating, but, almost even more unbelievably, only after watching him wait outside her place for a year? Secondly, Toto's devotion to waiting outside is as unbelievable as the "soldier's" to the princess. Men like that could and would not ever exist. I would have identified so much more had it been more realistic. "Of course I remember you..." "Life is not what you see in films... Life is much harder." Amen to that. So extremely, heart-breakingly sadly.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Infinitely Innocent
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    karl-sokhn
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    We all have had moments when we seemed to cling to past sensations or childhood memories, we feel a certain comfort re invoking these thoughts into mind. That is exactly what Cinema Paradiso portrays in an almost 3 hour long movie all through which you don't budge. Allow me to explain : The past is an ambiguous word but to clarify, let's consider the past as the numerous events that lead to NOW, the present. Having said that, the movie is a picture perfect depiction of the influence of the past on one's present and future. Childhood, teenage crisis, first love, the search for one's roots etc.. I shall detail these headlines. This movie represents the main character Salvatore Di Vita,a bright little kid who, never met or had any kind of interaction with his father(a soldier in the Italian army). And Alfredo, an old man with no kids who takes care of film reels in the Cinema Paradiso. (The only downside of the Cinema Paradiso was that films were censored and scenes involving physical contact were cut from the reels). Many actions lead their relationship to strengthen throughout the movie even though their bond had an inherent tendency to grow because each of them found in the other what he was lacking. Alfredo soon becomes the father figure Salvatore longed for as a kid and the little boy starts seeking counsel with the elder in matters that he couldn't understand. He becomes the prominent person that represents Salvatore's childhood along with the Cinema Paradiso, the place where Salvatore cultivated a love for Cinematography. And finally Elena, Salvatore's one true love draws the final stroke on this amazing portrait : Giancaldo, Salvatore's home village. Outer Circumstances force Elena and Salvatore to be separated, and their attempts to communicate fall on deaf ears and they lose all kinds of contact. A while after that Alfredo's counsel leads Salvatore(Toto) to leave the cradle of his childhood in order to pursue his dreams. He returns several years after to attend Alfredo's funeral and starts to rediscover Giancaldo from an other point of view and is finally able to make peace with his past with Alfredo's posthumous help. Finally i would like to add that the movie has an air of innocence to it and an immensely frivolous atmosphere giving all the characters' feelings a sincerity that i have never seen in any other movie.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Italian classic
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    silva-w-pius
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This heart warming and uplifting film takes us on a nostalgic adventure into our youths, through the innocent and untainted eyes of a young boy, who still sees the world for all its beauty and promise, even throughout the birth and death of a picture palace that holds so much lure and magic to him. Cinema paradiso is regarded as not only one of the greatest Italian films ever exported, but one of the greatest foreign films ever! But I would strongly disagree, as far as to say it is an insult to label this majestic testament to the beauty life, as just a foreign film! It's more than that, much more. A story told in flash backs, from the perspective of a highly successful film maker in his 40's (Salvatore Cascio). Upon receiving a call from his mother to inform him that his child hood hero had unfortunately died, it forces him to recount his entire youth. Telling the story of a young Salvatore living in a run down, poverty stricken and grim war-torn, post ww2 Sicilian village with his baby sister and his harassed mother who is as free with a slap as with a hug. But finding refuge from all the pain and misery, in a cinema paradiso, a local picture hall, provides him with an idyllic paradise where his love for cinema and adventures can run free. There he soon strikes up an unshakable life long bond with a aging projectionist, serving as a father figure and confidante, then after a fire robes him of his sight, Alfredo (Philippe Noriet) encourages Salvatore to take over at the new paradiso, but eventually he would push the now young 18 year old Salvatore, tainted by his first heartbreak by his true love Elena(Agnese Nano), out of the confines of this dead beat village, to a world waiting to be explored and conquered , Only returning 30 years later, to witness the burial of Alfredo and the demolition of the cinema paradiso. Giuseppe Tornatore provides us with a poignant and almost, spiritual reminder of how the simple things that we held so delicately in are youths can almost be forgotten and misplace in our older years, as we replace the magic with vain perceptions of success and obsession with money, when we should actually try and reconnect with our youths, and again enjoy the personal cinema experience that promises so much. As soon as the end titles rolled by, I couldn't help but feel sad, as a big cinema paradiso shaped whole was left in my heart. Cinema paradiso is a film that stirs up a lot of home truths, a great watch for brave individuals.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A film for movie fans.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Thanos Alfie
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Nuovo Cinema Paradiso is a movie for movie and cinema fans. In this movie you will understand the true meaning of love of the cinema. When I saw this movie I loved it because I think it represents the love for films that every movie fan has. I liked very much the performance of Salvatore Cascio as young "Salvatore 'Tot&ograve;' Di Vita" and of course the performance of Phillpe Noiret as "Alfredo". I also liked very much the true love between Marco Leonardi/Jacques Perrin as a teenager and adult "Salvatore 'Tot&ograve;' Di Vita" and Agnese Nano / Brigitte Fossey as a teenager and as adult Elena Mendola. I saw the extended movie of 155 minutes and not the "cut" movie of 121 minutes and I think that it worth it, I did not get bored for even a minute instead of it I really liked it!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Lotsa pathos, little substance
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    George Aar
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is a pleasant enough movie, I guess. But really not noteworthy in any substantial way. There's a movie theatre that is obviously a set. There's a whole stable of stock characters and lots of forced emotion, but there's just no meat on the bones. And then there's all those questions unanswered. Why did little Toto (who's a really cute little kid) act out towards everyone, no matter how hard they tried to befriend him? Why did Toto's mother treat him so poorly and beat him so much? Why did Toto's father leave? Why did Toto's girlfriend leave? How could Toto be so much in love with a girl he didn't even know? What happened to his girlfriend? Why did he never come back to his hometown? Why did his life end up so apparently empty and unsatisfying? And there's more I haven't even touched on. All of those questions and no answers are even attempted for any of them. All there is is a token tearful scene here and there and a few oddball philosophical parables and the rest of the script is basically left blank. I found it rather odd. Odd and unfulfilling. I think most people would expect more from a story.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    love of a life time
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Che 19c94
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I am the kind of person that usually never tears up for a movie, but here i just can't help it. Cinema Paradiso is one of those rare movies you just have to see. And if you are a movie fan yourself, like i am, the movie would quickly be at heart. The best thing about foreign films is that you never know the actors since you have never seen them in any other movie. It is as if your watching real people go by their lives. This is the kind of movie that everybody has to see. I don't know why this movie has an R rating but the version I saw, the original 1988 version, is suitable for everyone. ENJOY
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A masterpiece: Watch it to understand, why!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mike-world1
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Among the best movies, I ever saw....for a change, don't know whether I call it drama, romance, inspiration or depressing or what...but have to say that in the last 60 minutes, I incessantly cried...I've seen some wonderful movies, but this is among the best...direction: flawless and a class-apart, cast: nothing could have been better, sets: perfectly suit the story, and story-line: quite different... the way movie moves just keeps us engrossed, without being able to anticipate what is going to happen, specially in the last one hour...maybe it tells what life is, or helps to find a reflection of our life stories...and that's how we feel connected... overall, a must watch for those, who really enjoy quality movies!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "There are only ghosts here."
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Degree7
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Passion inspires great art in a young Toto, but as his age shifts, so does his perspective on his life machinations in a small Sicilian community. With the help of the local theatre projectionist, Alfredo, he is able to recognize his potential and move out into a wider world. But what keeps this film from simply being a sentimental ode to Italian cinema, is the reflection of a much older Toro coming to terms with the sacrifices he has made to become the man he is. Were they mistakes? Or are his past regrets still threatening to cloak his accomplishments as an individual? Despite a somewhat obtrusive score by Ennio Morriconne, this film sends a strong message about life reevaluation, and how past decisions can segue into the present, in often unexpected, but beautiful ways. A small gem of a film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Charming details don't add up to a great film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    dmayo-911-597432
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    *** This review may contain spoilers *** It would be best to see this film without knowing how warmly it was welcomed by critics and viewers at the time, or how many people still take it to their hearts. It does hold many charms in its details, but when it tries to give us a story of Life and Love it becomes banal and contrived. It also takes an oddly careless approach to the aging of its characters. Nuovo Cinema Paradiso opens with a framing story in which a middle-aged man hears that someone named Alfredo has died in his hometown and begins recalling his childhood. In the flashbacks that form the main body of the film, the setting is a town in Sicily in the decade following World War II. A small boy is irresistibly drawn to the local cinema, a world of enchantment, and to its projection booth, the heart of that world. He befriends the projectionist, Alfredo. Alfredo discourages the boy, Toto, from following in his footsteps as a projectionist and eventually encourages him to pursue his love of movies on a grander scale. We're soon prepared to learn that the grown Toto who is recollecting these things has become a famous director. In the first phase of the flashbacks, we follow little Toto in his childish peccadilloes while following the community in its avid response to movie magic (a funny exception being the gritty social realism of post-war Italian cinema, which proves as impenetrable to Sicilians as to much of the world beyond). This phase ends with the cinema destroyed by fire and Alfredo rescued by Toto but blinded for life. The Toto of the second phase is apparently in his late teens, perhaps twenty by the end of the flashback. Childish peccadilloes have given way to amateur film-making, running the projector at the rebuilt cinema, and love at first sight with a girl whose social position poses an obstacle -- in effect, a princess. As always, the life of the community and that of the film are centered on the shared joys of escape in a darkened cinema. Toto's personal life is disrupted by a period of military training, after which he finds that he can't pick up where he left off. He loses touch with Elena, his love, who has moved away. Finally, he takes Alfredo's advice and leaves town himself to make his way in the world. Very well, but it's unbelievable that he then absolutely neglects his mother for thirty years, even to the point of not returning her phone calls, although they were on good terms when he left. The only reason seems to be that the film requires a complete break with home so that the middle-aged Toto can feel he's stepping into a past world when he returns for Alfredo's funeral. Still more unbelievable is the casting of characters at different ages. The twentyish Toto is distinctly short, but the fiftyish Toto towers over everyone else in the funeral procession. Conversely, his mother changes from a tall young woman to a tiny old one. Then there is the aging of characters who are played by the same actors throughout. Alfredo's wife, who was middle-aged in the first place, only turns gray-haired and gray-faced while the transformation (by casting) of Toto's younger mother rivals that of the queen in Snow White. Indeed, slapping gray paint on actors -- while removing an obvious hairpiece from one -- is all the movie magic Tornatore offers in the framing story. Is he trying to tell us that he has decided to wash his hands of film-making as a labor of love? The many delightful moments in Nuovo Cinema Paradiso are really just so many vignettes strung together in the abrupt, sometimes bewildering manner of the 1980s. To the extent that these moments achieve a unified effect, they suggest the benign human comedy of Rene Clair. Yet they are mixed with stink-bombs of bad taste that would have puzzled Clair as to this director's intent. That, too, is a mark of the 1980s. It may be best to look for the appeal of this film in the ways in which it differs from most other films of the 1980s and many since. It does come down on the side of benign human comedy. It does cherish the magic of Golden Age film-making, even as that magic slips through its fingers. It does become an oasis of entertainment if you come upon it in a personal desert of dissatisfaction with films generally. The trouble is that if you have had the good fortune to drink from the springs of Rene Clair and other masters, Nuovo Cinema Paradiso turns out to be a mirage.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An ode to cinema, dream and emotions
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    lucio7
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Don't approach the movie with your logic part of the brain switched on. Yes, as someone said there are some flaws relative to how realistic it can be, but that doesn't matter because you'd be missing the point. Just let yourself go and enjoy this celebration of cinema, dream and emotions and this piece of art will bring you on a lovely spiritual trip. I loved it. P.S.: Sorry IMDb, but I was able to say everything I wanted to say without the mandatory 10 lines of text. I really love your website but you should pass this message to the management: quantity doesn't make quality.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An amazing, thought-provoking, deeply-insightful, emotionally-riveting winner!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    voniapeng
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Well. Wow. Let me absorb this all for a moment. Alright. So that was... one of the best films I have seen in who knows how long. It is definitely on my all-time favorites list. Such an amazing film about film... but so, so much more. It is about friendships- the very best two people can share. The multitude of ways one person, one place, one passion can change your life for eternity; without which you would be a different person altogether. This film makes me want to experience the small town life that I never have, in any way before- to have so many people who know you so well; who grew up with you or watched you grow up; who can be proud of everything you have become; who love you in ways people who have not known you since you were a baby; A place where you can return decades later to find that everything has been the same after all these years, yet, at the same time, changed. This film inspires in me a love of films than span lifetime(s) in a way that very few others have. This film makes me think about so many things: redemption, regret, love, hope, friendships, trust, appreciation; how clinging to the past can be such a rewardingly bad tendency, how so many things we have no power over are so blatantly unfair, how, in the name of love, the most difficult decisions are inevitable made. I would kill to have a friendship like Toto & 's. I am regrettably obligated to clarify that, however. Alfredo's decision regarding Toto & Elena made me so upset that... I didn't know whether I could like his character anymore. His decision and actions were out of place, mean, and wrong. In the end, though, I suppose I can only say I respect Alfredo less, as I know, in his heart, he wanted what he felt was best for Toto. I emphasize, what he felt. And that's my point exactly. Because it was not his place and therefore not his right to do what he did- his sincere care and love for Toto irrelevant in this case- although mitigating the severity of his wrong. I agree that in some ways what evolved was best for Toto- but for his career. And I am an adamant believer that love is always the No. One priority in these lives of ours. At the end of the day, financial woes, careers, daily nuisances aside, love is what matters at the end of the day; at the end of a lifetime. Toto shares this philosophy, as made obvious several times. Secondly, why in heaven's name didn't the two of them rekindle their rare, genuine love at the end? I understand that some things in life can become too late t retrieve, but, again, I agree with Toto- they should have resumed it. I know neither of them ever loved anyone else, vows or not, anywhere near as powerfully. And, despite what I may say, contrary to all logic, I wish for a love like Toto & Elena's. As the saying goes, "It is better to have loved and lost than to have never loved at all." I understand that times were different then, but, perhaps unfairly, I am upset with Elena. For not choosing true love over her family's unreasonable demands (although she did redeem herself). For not agreeing to set things right at the end. The only other issue I have is with the plausibility of some specific details. First, falling in love without ever talking, at first sight? And then Elena reciprocating, but, almost even more unbelievably, only after watching him wait outside her place for a year? Secondly, Toto's devotion to waiting outside is as unbelievable as the "soldier's" to the princess. Men like that could and would not ever exist. I would have identified so much more had it been more realistic. "Of course I remember you..." "Life is not what you see in films... Life is much harder." Amen to that. So extremely, heart-breakingly sadly.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Infinitely Innocent
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    karl-sokhn
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    We all have had moments when we seemed to cling to past sensations or childhood memories, we feel a certain comfort re invoking these thoughts into mind. That is exactly what Cinema Paradiso portrays in an almost 3 hour long movie all through which you don't budge. Allow me to explain : The past is an ambiguous word but to clarify, let's consider the past as the numerous events that lead to NOW, the present. Having said that, the movie is a picture perfect depiction of the influence of the past on one's present and future. Childhood, teenage crisis, first love, the search for one's roots etc.. I shall detail these headlines. This movie represents the main character Salvatore Di Vita,a bright little kid who, never met or had any kind of interaction with his father(a soldier in the Italian army). And Alfredo, an old man with no kids who takes care of film reels in the Cinema Paradiso. (The only downside of the Cinema Paradiso was that films were censored and scenes involving physical contact were cut from the reels). Many actions lead their relationship to strengthen throughout the movie even though their bond had an inherent tendency to grow because each of them found in the other what he was lacking. Alfredo soon becomes the father figure Salvatore longed for as a kid and the little boy starts seeking counsel with the elder in matters that he couldn't understand. He becomes the prominent person that represents Salvatore's childhood along with the Cinema Paradiso, the place where Salvatore cultivated a love for Cinematography. And finally Elena, Salvatore's one true love draws the final stroke on this amazing portrait : Giancaldo, Salvatore's home village. Outer Circumstances force Elena and Salvatore to be separated, and their attempts to communicate fall on deaf ears and they lose all kinds of contact. A while after that Alfredo's counsel leads Salvatore(Toto) to leave the cradle of his childhood in order to pursue his dreams. He returns several years after to attend Alfredo's funeral and starts to rediscover Giancaldo from an other point of view and is finally able to make peace with his past with Alfredo's posthumous help. Finally i would like to add that the movie has an air of innocence to it and an immensely frivolous atmosphere giving all the characters' feelings a sincerity that i have never seen in any other movie.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Italian classic
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    silva-w-pius
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This heart warming and uplifting film takes us on a nostalgic adventure into our youths, through the innocent and untainted eyes of a young boy, who still sees the world for all its beauty and promise, even throughout the birth and death of a picture palace that holds so much lure and magic to him. Cinema paradiso is regarded as not only one of the greatest Italian films ever exported, but one of the greatest foreign films ever! But I would strongly disagree, as far as to say it is an insult to label this majestic testament to the beauty life, as just a foreign film! It's more than that, much more. A story told in flash backs, from the perspective of a highly successful film maker in his 40's (Salvatore Cascio). Upon receiving a call from his mother to inform him that his child hood hero had unfortunately died, it forces him to recount his entire youth. Telling the story of a young Salvatore living in a run down, poverty stricken and grim war-torn, post ww2 Sicilian village with his baby sister and his harassed mother who is as free with a slap as with a hug. But finding refuge from all the pain and misery, in a cinema paradiso, a local picture hall, provides him with an idyllic paradise where his love for cinema and adventures can run free. There he soon strikes up an unshakable life long bond with a aging projectionist, serving as a father figure and confidante, then after a fire robes him of his sight, Alfredo (Philippe Noriet) encourages Salvatore to take over at the new paradiso, but eventually he would push the now young 18 year old Salvatore, tainted by his first heartbreak by his true love Elena(Agnese Nano), out of the confines of this dead beat village, to a world waiting to be explored and conquered , Only returning 30 years later, to witness the burial of Alfredo and the demolition of the cinema paradiso. Giuseppe Tornatore provides us with a poignant and almost, spiritual reminder of how the simple things that we held so delicately in are youths can almost be forgotten and misplace in our older years, as we replace the magic with vain perceptions of success and obsession with money, when we should actually try and reconnect with our youths, and again enjoy the personal cinema experience that promises so much. As soon as the end titles rolled by, I couldn't help but feel sad, as a big cinema paradiso shaped whole was left in my heart. Cinema paradiso is a film that stirs up a lot of home truths, a great watch for brave individuals.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A film for movie fans.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Thanos Alfie
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Nuovo Cinema Paradiso is a movie for movie and cinema fans. In this movie you will understand the true meaning of love of the cinema. When I saw this movie I loved it because I think it represents the love for films that every movie fan has. I liked very much the performance of Salvatore Cascio as young "Salvatore 'Tot&ograve;' Di Vita" and of course the performance of Phillpe Noiret as "Alfredo". I also liked very much the true love between Marco Leonardi/Jacques Perrin as a teenager and adult "Salvatore 'Tot&ograve;' Di Vita" and Agnese Nano / Brigitte Fossey as a teenager and as adult Elena Mendola. I saw the extended movie of 155 minutes and not the "cut" movie of 121 minutes and I think that it worth it, I did not get bored for even a minute instead of it I really liked it!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Lotsa pathos, little substance
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    George Aar
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is a pleasant enough movie, I guess. But really not noteworthy in any substantial way. There's a movie theatre that is obviously a set. There's a whole stable of stock characters and lots of forced emotion, but there's just no meat on the bones. And then there's all those questions unanswered. Why did little Toto (who's a really cute little kid) act out towards everyone, no matter how hard they tried to befriend him? Why did Toto's mother treat him so poorly and beat him so much? Why did Toto's father leave? Why did Toto's girlfriend leave? How could Toto be so much in love with a girl he didn't even know? What happened to his girlfriend? Why did he never come back to his hometown? Why did his life end up so apparently empty and unsatisfying? And there's more I haven't even touched on. All of those questions and no answers are even attempted for any of them. All there is is a token tearful scene here and there and a few oddball philosophical parables and the rest of the script is basically left blank. I found it rather odd. Odd and unfulfilling. I think most people would expect more from a story.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    love of a life time
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Che 19c94
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I am the kind of person that usually never tears up for a movie, but here i just can't help it. Cinema Paradiso is one of those rare movies you just have to see. And if you are a movie fan yourself, like i am, the movie would quickly be at heart. The best thing about foreign films is that you never know the actors since you have never seen them in any other movie. It is as if your watching real people go by their lives. This is the kind of movie that everybody has to see. I don't know why this movie has an R rating but the version I saw, the original 1988 version, is suitable for everyone. ENJOY
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A masterpiece: Watch it to understand, why!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mike-world1
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Among the best movies, I ever saw....for a change, don't know whether I call it drama, romance, inspiration or depressing or what...but have to say that in the last 60 minutes, I incessantly cried...I've seen some wonderful movies, but this is among the best...direction: flawless and a class-apart, cast: nothing could have been better, sets: perfectly suit the story, and story-line: quite different... the way movie moves just keeps us engrossed, without being able to anticipate what is going to happen, specially in the last one hour...maybe it tells what life is, or helps to find a reflection of our life stories...and that's how we feel connected... overall, a must watch for those, who really enjoy quality movies!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "There are only ghosts here."
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Degree7
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Passion inspires great art in a young Toto, but as his age shifts, so does his perspective on his life machinations in a small Sicilian community. With the help of the local theatre projectionist, Alfredo, he is able to recognize his potential and move out into a wider world. But what keeps this film from simply being a sentimental ode to Italian cinema, is the reflection of a much older Toro coming to terms with the sacrifices he has made to become the man he is. Were they mistakes? Or are his past regrets still threatening to cloak his accomplishments as an individual? Despite a somewhat obtrusive score by Ennio Morriconne, this film sends a strong message about life reevaluation, and how past decisions can segue into the present, in often unexpected, but beautiful ways. A small gem of a film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Charming details don't add up to a great film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    dmayo-911-597432
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    *** This review may contain spoilers *** It would be best to see this film without knowing how warmly it was welcomed by critics and viewers at the time, or how many people still take it to their hearts. It does hold many charms in its details, but when it tries to give us a story of Life and Love it becomes banal and contrived. It also takes an oddly careless approach to the aging of its characters. Nuovo Cinema Paradiso opens with a framing story in which a middle-aged man hears that someone named Alfredo has died in his hometown and begins recalling his childhood. In the flashbacks that form the main body of the film, the setting is a town in Sicily in the decade following World War II. A small boy is irresistibly drawn to the local cinema, a world of enchantment, and to its projection booth, the heart of that world. He befriends the projectionist, Alfredo. Alfredo discourages the boy, Toto, from following in his footsteps as a projectionist and eventually encourages him to pursue his love of movies on a grander scale. We're soon prepared to learn that the grown Toto who is recollecting these things has become a famous director. In the first phase of the flashbacks, we follow little Toto in his childish peccadilloes while following the community in its avid response to movie magic (a funny exception being the gritty social realism of post-war Italian cinema, which proves as impenetrable to Sicilians as to much of the world beyond). This phase ends with the cinema destroyed by fire and Alfredo rescued by Toto but blinded for life. The Toto of the second phase is apparently in his late teens, perhaps twenty by the end of the flashback. Childish peccadilloes have given way to amateur film-making, running the projector at the rebuilt cinema, and love at first sight with a girl whose social position poses an obstacle -- in effect, a princess. As always, the life of the community and that of the film are centered on the shared joys of escape in a darkened cinema. Toto's personal life is disrupted by a period of military training, after which he finds that he can't pick up where he left off. He loses touch with Elena, his love, who has moved away. Finally, he takes Alfredo's advice and leaves town himself to make his way in the world. Very well, but it's unbelievable that he then absolutely neglects his mother for thirty years, even to the point of not returning her phone calls, although they were on good terms when he left. The only reason seems to be that the film requires a complete break with home so that the middle-aged Toto can feel he's stepping into a past world when he returns for Alfredo's funeral. Still more unbelievable is the casting of characters at different ages. The twentyish Toto is distinctly short, but the fiftyish Toto towers over everyone else in the funeral procession. Conversely, his mother changes from a tall young woman to a tiny old one. Then there is the aging of characters who are played by the same actors throughout. Alfredo's wife, who was middle-aged in the first place, only turns gray-haired and gray-faced while the transformation (by casting) of Toto's younger mother rivals that of the queen in Snow White. Indeed, slapping gray paint on actors -- while removing an obvious hairpiece from one -- is all the movie magic Tornatore offers in the framing story. Is he trying to tell us that he has decided to wash his hands of film-making as a labor of love? The many delightful moments in Nuovo Cinema Paradiso are really just so many vignettes strung together in the abrupt, sometimes bewildering manner of the 1980s. To the extent that these moments achieve a unified effect, they suggest the benign human comedy of Rene Clair. Yet they are mixed with stink-bombs of bad taste that would have puzzled Clair as to this director's intent. That, too, is a mark of the 1980s. It may be best to look for the appeal of this film in the ways in which it differs from most other films of the 1980s and many since. It does come down on the side of benign human comedy. It does cherish the magic of Golden Age film-making, even as that magic slips through its fingers. It does become an oasis of entertainment if you come upon it in a personal desert of dissatisfaction with films generally. The trouble is that if you have had the good fortune to drink from the springs of Rene Clair and other masters, Nuovo Cinema Paradiso turns out to be a mirage.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An ode to cinema, dream and emotions
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    lucio7
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Don't approach the movie with your logic part of the brain switched on. Yes, as someone said there are some flaws relative to how realistic it can be, but that doesn't matter because you'd be missing the point. Just let yourself go and enjoy this celebration of cinema, dream and emotions and this piece of art will bring you on a lovely spiritual trip. I loved it. P.S.: Sorry IMDb, but I was able to say everything I wanted to say without the mandatory 10 lines of text. I really love your website but you should pass this message to the management: quantity doesn't make quality.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An amazing, thought-provoking, deeply-insightful, emotionally-riveting winner!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    voniapeng
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Well. Wow. Let me absorb this all for a moment. Alright. So that was... one of the best films I have seen in who knows how long. It is definitely on my all-time favorites list. Such an amazing film about film... but so, so much more. It is about friendships- the very best two people can share. The multitude of ways one person, one place, one passion can change your life for eternity; without which you would be a different person altogether. This film makes me want to experience the small town life that I never have, in any way before- to have so many people who know you so well; who grew up with you or watched you grow up; who can be proud of everything you have become; who love you in ways people who have not known you since you were a baby; A place where you can return decades later to find that everything has been the same after all these years, yet, at the same time, changed. This film inspires in me a love of films than span lifetime(s) in a way that very few others have. This film makes me think about so many things: redemption, regret, love, hope, friendships, trust, appreciation; how clinging to the past can be such a rewardingly bad tendency, how so many things we have no power over are so blatantly unfair, how, in the name of love, the most difficult decisions are inevitable made. I would kill to have a friendship like Toto & 's. I am regrettably obligated to clarify that, however. Alfredo's decision regarding Toto & Elena made me so upset that... I didn't know whether I could like his character anymore. His decision and actions were out of place, mean, and wrong. In the end, though, I suppose I can only say I respect Alfredo less, as I know, in his heart, he wanted what he felt was best for Toto. I emphasize, what he felt. And that's my point exactly. Because it was not his place and therefore not his right to do what he did- his sincere care and love for Toto irrelevant in this case- although mitigating the severity of his wrong. I agree that in some ways what evolved was best for Toto- but for his career. And I am an adamant believer that love is always the No. One priority in these lives of ours. At the end of the day, financial woes, careers, daily nuisances aside, love is what matters at the end of the day; at the end of a lifetime. Toto shares this philosophy, as made obvious several times. Secondly, why in heaven's name didn't the two of them rekindle their rare, genuine love at the end? I understand that some things in life can become too late t retrieve, but, again, I agree with Toto- they should have resumed it. I know neither of them ever loved anyone else, vows or not, anywhere near as powerfully. And, despite what I may say, contrary to all logic, I wish for a love like Toto & Elena's. As the saying goes, "It is better to have loved and lost than to have never loved at all." I understand that times were different then, but, perhaps unfairly, I am upset with Elena. For not choosing true love over her family's unreasonable demands (although she did redeem herself). For not agreeing to set things right at the end. The only other issue I have is with the plausibility of some specific details. First, falling in love without ever talking, at first sight? And then Elena reciprocating, but, almost even more unbelievably, only after watching him wait outside her place for a year? Secondly, Toto's devotion to waiting outside is as unbelievable as the "soldier's" to the princess. Men like that could and would not ever exist. I would have identified so much more had it been more realistic. "Of course I remember you..." "Life is not what you see in films... Life is much harder." Amen to that. So extremely, heart-breakingly sadly.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Infinitely Innocent
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    karl-sokhn
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    We all have had moments when we seemed to cling to past sensations or childhood memories, we feel a certain comfort re invoking these thoughts into mind. That is exactly what Cinema Paradiso portrays in an almost 3 hour long movie all through which you don't budge. Allow me to explain : The past is an ambiguous word but to clarify, let's consider the past as the numerous events that lead to NOW, the present. Having said that, the movie is a picture perfect depiction of the influence of the past on one's present and future. Childhood, teenage crisis, first love, the search for one's roots etc.. I shall detail these headlines. This movie represents the main character Salvatore Di Vita,a bright little kid who, never met or had any kind of interaction with his father(a soldier in the Italian army). And Alfredo, an old man with no kids who takes care of film reels in the Cinema Paradiso. (The only downside of the Cinema Paradiso was that films were censored and scenes involving physical contact were cut from the reels). Many actions lead their relationship to strengthen throughout the movie even though their bond had an inherent tendency to grow because each of them found in the other what he was lacking. Alfredo soon becomes the father figure Salvatore longed for as a kid and the little boy starts seeking counsel with the elder in matters that he couldn't understand. He becomes the prominent person that represents Salvatore's childhood along with the Cinema Paradiso, the place where Salvatore cultivated a love for Cinematography. And finally Elena, Salvatore's one true love draws the final stroke on this amazing portrait : Giancaldo, Salvatore's home village. Outer Circumstances force Elena and Salvatore to be separated, and their attempts to communicate fall on deaf ears and they lose all kinds of contact. A while after that Alfredo's counsel leads Salvatore(Toto) to leave the cradle of his childhood in order to pursue his dreams. He returns several years after to attend Alfredo's funeral and starts to rediscover Giancaldo from an other point of view and is finally able to make peace with his past with Alfredo's posthumous help. Finally i would like to add that the movie has an air of innocence to it and an immensely frivolous atmosphere giving all the characters' feelings a sincerity that i have never seen in any other movie.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Italian classic
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    silva-w-pius
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This heart warming and uplifting film takes us on a nostalgic adventure into our youths, through the innocent and untainted eyes of a young boy, who still sees the world for all its beauty and promise, even throughout the birth and death of a picture palace that holds so much lure and magic to him. Cinema paradiso is regarded as not only one of the greatest Italian films ever exported, but one of the greatest foreign films ever! But I would strongly disagree, as far as to say it is an insult to label this majestic testament to the beauty life, as just a foreign film! It's more than that, much more. A story told in flash backs, from the perspective of a highly successful film maker in his 40's (Salvatore Cascio). Upon receiving a call from his mother to inform him that his child hood hero had unfortunately died, it forces him to recount his entire youth. Telling the story of a young Salvatore living in a run down, poverty stricken and grim war-torn, post ww2 Sicilian village with his baby sister and his harassed mother who is as free with a slap as with a hug. But finding refuge from all the pain and misery, in a cinema paradiso, a local picture hall, provides him with an idyllic paradise where his love for cinema and adventures can run free. There he soon strikes up an unshakable life long bond with a aging projectionist, serving as a father figure and confidante, then after a fire robes him of his sight, Alfredo (Philippe Noriet) encourages Salvatore to take over at the new paradiso, but eventually he would push the now young 18 year old Salvatore, tainted by his first heartbreak by his true love Elena(Agnese Nano), out of the confines of this dead beat village, to a world waiting to be explored and conquered , Only returning 30 years later, to witness the burial of Alfredo and the demolition of the cinema paradiso. Giuseppe Tornatore provides us with a poignant and almost, spiritual reminder of how the simple things that we held so delicately in are youths can almost be forgotten and misplace in our older years, as we replace the magic with vain perceptions of success and obsession with money, when we should actually try and reconnect with our youths, and again enjoy the personal cinema experience that promises so much. As soon as the end titles rolled by, I couldn't help but feel sad, as a big cinema paradiso shaped whole was left in my heart. Cinema paradiso is a film that stirs up a lot of home truths, a great watch for brave individuals.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A film for movie fans.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Thanos Alfie
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Nuovo Cinema Paradiso is a movie for movie and cinema fans. In this movie you will understand the true meaning of love of the cinema. When I saw this movie I loved it because I think it represents the love for films that every movie fan has. I liked very much the performance of Salvatore Cascio as young "Salvatore 'Tot&ograve;' Di Vita" and of course the performance of Phillpe Noiret as "Alfredo". I also liked very much the true love between Marco Leonardi/Jacques Perrin as a teenager and adult "Salvatore 'Tot&ograve;' Di Vita" and Agnese Nano / Brigitte Fossey as a teenager and as adult Elena Mendola. I saw the extended movie of 155 minutes and not the "cut" movie of 121 minutes and I think that it worth it, I did not get bored for even a minute instead of it I really liked it!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Lotsa pathos, little substance
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    George Aar
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is a pleasant enough movie, I guess. But really not noteworthy in any substantial way. There's a movie theatre that is obviously a set. There's a whole stable of stock characters and lots of forced emotion, but there's just no meat on the bones. And then there's all those questions unanswered. Why did little Toto (who's a really cute little kid) act out towards everyone, no matter how hard they tried to befriend him? Why did Toto's mother treat him so poorly and beat him so much? Why did Toto's father leave? Why did Toto's girlfriend leave? How could Toto be so much in love with a girl he didn't even know? What happened to his girlfriend? Why did he never come back to his hometown? Why did his life end up so apparently empty and unsatisfying? And there's more I haven't even touched on. All of those questions and no answers are even attempted for any of them. All there is is a token tearful scene here and there and a few oddball philosophical parables and the rest of the script is basically left blank. I found it rather odd. Odd and unfulfilling. I think most people would expect more from a story.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    love of a life time
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Che 19c94
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I am the kind of person that usually never tears up for a movie, but here i just can't help it. Cinema Paradiso is one of those rare movies you just have to see. And if you are a movie fan yourself, like i am, the movie would quickly be at heart. The best thing about foreign films is that you never know the actors since you have never seen them in any other movie. It is as if your watching real people go by their lives. This is the kind of movie that everybody has to see. I don't know why this movie has an R rating but the version I saw, the original 1988 version, is suitable for everyone. ENJOY
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A masterpiece: Watch it to understand, why!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mike-world1
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Among the best movies, I ever saw....for a change, don't know whether I call it drama, romance, inspiration or depressing or what...but have to say that in the last 60 minutes, I incessantly cried...I've seen some wonderful movies, but this is among the best...direction: flawless and a class-apart, cast: nothing could have been better, sets: perfectly suit the story, and story-line: quite different... the way movie moves just keeps us engrossed, without being able to anticipate what is going to happen, specially in the last one hour...maybe it tells what life is, or helps to find a reflection of our life stories...and that's how we feel connected... overall, a must watch for those, who really enjoy quality movies!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "There are only ghosts here."
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Degree7
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Passion inspires great art in a young Toto, but as his age shifts, so does his perspective on his life machinations in a small Sicilian community. With the help of the local theatre projectionist, Alfredo, he is able to recognize his potential and move out into a wider world. But what keeps this film from simply being a sentimental ode to Italian cinema, is the reflection of a much older Toro coming to terms with the sacrifices he has made to become the man he is. Were they mistakes? Or are his past regrets still threatening to cloak his accomplishments as an individual? Despite a somewhat obtrusive score by Ennio Morriconne, this film sends a strong message about life reevaluation, and how past decisions can segue into the present, in often unexpected, but beautiful ways. A small gem of a film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Charming details don't add up to a great film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    dmayo-911-597432
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    *** This review may contain spoilers *** It would be best to see this film without knowing how warmly it was welcomed by critics and viewers at the time, or how many people still take it to their hearts. It does hold many charms in its details, but when it tries to give us a story of Life and Love it becomes banal and contrived. It also takes an oddly careless approach to the aging of its characters. Nuovo Cinema Paradiso opens with a framing story in which a middle-aged man hears that someone named Alfredo has died in his hometown and begins recalling his childhood. In the flashbacks that form the main body of the film, the setting is a town in Sicily in the decade following World War II. A small boy is irresistibly drawn to the local cinema, a world of enchantment, and to its projection booth, the heart of that world. He befriends the projectionist, Alfredo. Alfredo discourages the boy, Toto, from following in his footsteps as a projectionist and eventually encourages him to pursue his love of movies on a grander scale. We're soon prepared to learn that the grown Toto who is recollecting these things has become a famous director. In the first phase of the flashbacks, we follow little Toto in his childish peccadilloes while following the community in its avid response to movie magic (a funny exception being the gritty social realism of post-war Italian cinema, which proves as impenetrable to Sicilians as to much of the world beyond). This phase ends with the cinema destroyed by fire and Alfredo rescued by Toto but blinded for life. The Toto of the second phase is apparently in his late teens, perhaps twenty by the end of the flashback. Childish peccadilloes have given way to amateur film-making, running the projector at the rebuilt cinema, and love at first sight with a girl whose social position poses an obstacle -- in effect, a princess. As always, the life of the community and that of the film are centered on the shared joys of escape in a darkened cinema. Toto's personal life is disrupted by a period of military training, after which he finds that he can't pick up where he left off. He loses touch with Elena, his love, who has moved away. Finally, he takes Alfredo's advice and leaves town himself to make his way in the world. Very well, but it's unbelievable that he then absolutely neglects his mother for thirty years, even to the point of not returning her phone calls, although they were on good terms when he left. The only reason seems to be that the film requires a complete break with home so that the middle-aged Toto can feel he's stepping into a past world when he returns for Alfredo's funeral. Still more unbelievable is the casting of characters at different ages. The twentyish Toto is distinctly short, but the fiftyish Toto towers over everyone else in the funeral procession. Conversely, his mother changes from a tall young woman to a tiny old one. Then there is the aging of characters who are played by the same actors throughout. Alfredo's wife, who was middle-aged in the first place, only turns gray-haired and gray-faced while the transformation (by casting) of Toto's younger mother rivals that of the queen in Snow White. Indeed, slapping gray paint on actors -- while removing an obvious hairpiece from one -- is all the movie magic Tornatore offers in the framing story. Is he trying to tell us that he has decided to wash his hands of film-making as a labor of love? The many delightful moments in Nuovo Cinema Paradiso are really just so many vignettes strung together in the abrupt, sometimes bewildering manner of the 1980s. To the extent that these moments achieve a unified effect, they suggest the benign human comedy of Rene Clair. Yet they are mixed with stink-bombs of bad taste that would have puzzled Clair as to this director's intent. That, too, is a mark of the 1980s. It may be best to look for the appeal of this film in the ways in which it differs from most other films of the 1980s and many since. It does come down on the side of benign human comedy. It does cherish the magic of Golden Age film-making, even as that magic slips through its fingers. It does become an oasis of entertainment if you come upon it in a personal desert of dissatisfaction with films generally. The trouble is that if you have had the good fortune to drink from the springs of Rene Clair and other masters, Nuovo Cinema Paradiso turns out to be a mirage.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An ode to cinema, dream and emotions
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    lucio7
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Don't approach the movie with your logic part of the brain switched on. Yes, as someone said there are some flaws relative to how realistic it can be, but that doesn't matter because you'd be missing the point. Just let yourself go and enjoy this celebration of cinema, dream and emotions and this piece of art will bring you on a lovely spiritual trip. I loved it. P.S.: Sorry IMDb, but I was able to say everything I wanted to say without the mandatory 10 lines of text. I really love your website but you should pass this message to the management: quantity doesn't make quality.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An amazing, thought-provoking, deeply-insightful, emotionally-riveting winner!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    voniapeng
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Well. Wow. Let me absorb this all for a moment. Alright. So that was... one of the best films I have seen in who knows how long. It is definitely on my all-time favorites list. Such an amazing film about film... but so, so much more. It is about friendships- the very best two people can share. The multitude of ways one person, one place, one passion can change your life for eternity; without which you would be a different person altogether. This film makes me want to experience the small town life that I never have, in any way before- to have so many people who know you so well; who grew up with you or watched you grow up; who can be proud of everything you have become; who love you in ways people who have not known you since you were a baby; A place where you can return decades later to find that everything has been the same after all these years, yet, at the same time, changed. This film inspires in me a love of films than span lifetime(s) in a way that very few others have. This film makes me think about so many things: redemption, regret, love, hope, friendships, trust, appreciation; how clinging to the past can be such a rewardingly bad tendency, how so many things we have no power over are so blatantly unfair, how, in the name of love, the most difficult decisions are inevitable made. I would kill to have a friendship like Toto & 's. I am regrettably obligated to clarify that, however. Alfredo's decision regarding Toto & Elena made me so upset that... I didn't know whether I could like his character anymore. His decision and actions were out of place, mean, and wrong. In the end, though, I suppose I can only say I respect Alfredo less, as I know, in his heart, he wanted what he felt was best for Toto. I emphasize, what he felt. And that's my point exactly. Because it was not his place and therefore not his right to do what he did- his sincere care and love for Toto irrelevant in this case- although mitigating the severity of his wrong. I agree that in some ways what evolved was best for Toto- but for his career. And I am an adamant believer that love is always the No. One priority in these lives of ours. At the end of the day, financial woes, careers, daily nuisances aside, love is what matters at the end of the day; at the end of a lifetime. Toto shares this philosophy, as made obvious several times. Secondly, why in heaven's name didn't the two of them rekindle their rare, genuine love at the end? I understand that some things in life can become too late t retrieve, but, again, I agree with Toto- they should have resumed it. I know neither of them ever loved anyone else, vows or not, anywhere near as powerfully. And, despite what I may say, contrary to all logic, I wish for a love like Toto & Elena's. As the saying goes, "It is better to have loved and lost than to have never loved at all." I understand that times were different then, but, perhaps unfairly, I am upset with Elena. For not choosing true love over her family's unreasonable demands (although she did redeem herself). For not agreeing to set things right at the end. The only other issue I have is with the plausibility of some specific details. First, falling in love without ever talking, at first sight? And then Elena reciprocating, but, almost even more unbelievably, only after watching him wait outside her place for a year? Secondly, Toto's devotion to waiting outside is as unbelievable as the "soldier's" to the princess. Men like that could and would not ever exist. I would have identified so much more had it been more realistic. "Of course I remember you..." "Life is not what you see in films... Life is much harder." Amen to that. So extremely, heart-breakingly sadly.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Infinitely Innocent
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    karl-sokhn
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    We all have had moments when we seemed to cling to past sensations or childhood memories, we feel a certain comfort re invoking these thoughts into mind. That is exactly what Cinema Paradiso portrays in an almost 3 hour long movie all through which you don't budge. Allow me to explain : The past is an ambiguous word but to clarify, let's consider the past as the numerous events that lead to NOW, the present. Having said that, the movie is a picture perfect depiction of the influence of the past on one's present and future. Childhood, teenage crisis, first love, the search for one's roots etc.. I shall detail these headlines. This movie represents the main character Salvatore Di Vita,a bright little kid who, never met or had any kind of interaction with his father(a soldier in the Italian army). And Alfredo, an old man with no kids who takes care of film reels in the Cinema Paradiso. (The only downside of the Cinema Paradiso was that films were censored and scenes involving physical contact were cut from the reels). Many actions lead their relationship to strengthen throughout the movie even though their bond had an inherent tendency to grow because each of them found in the other what he was lacking. Alfredo soon becomes the father figure Salvatore longed for as a kid and the little boy starts seeking counsel with the elder in matters that he couldn't understand. He becomes the prominent person that represents Salvatore's childhood along with the Cinema Paradiso, the place where Salvatore cultivated a love for Cinematography. And finally Elena, Salvatore's one true love draws the final stroke on this amazing portrait : Giancaldo, Salvatore's home village. Outer Circumstances force Elena and Salvatore to be separated, and their attempts to communicate fall on deaf ears and they lose all kinds of contact. A while after that Alfredo's counsel leads Salvatore(Toto) to leave the cradle of his childhood in order to pursue his dreams. He returns several years after to attend Alfredo's funeral and starts to rediscover Giancaldo from an other point of view and is finally able to make peace with his past with Alfredo's posthumous help. Finally i would like to add that the movie has an air of innocence to it and an immensely frivolous atmosphere giving all the characters' feelings a sincerity that i have never seen in any other movie.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Italian classic
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    silva-w-pius
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This heart warming and uplifting film takes us on a nostalgic adventure into our youths, through the innocent and untainted eyes of a young boy, who still sees the world for all its beauty and promise, even throughout the birth and death of a picture palace that holds so much lure and magic to him. Cinema paradiso is regarded as not only one of the greatest Italian films ever exported, but one of the greatest foreign films ever! But I would strongly disagree, as far as to say it is an insult to label this majestic testament to the beauty life, as just a foreign film! It's more than that, much more. A story told in flash backs, from the perspective of a highly successful film maker in his 40's (Salvatore Cascio). Upon receiving a call from his mother to inform him that his child hood hero had unfortunately died, it forces him to recount his entire youth. Telling the story of a young Salvatore living in a run down, poverty stricken and grim war-torn, post ww2 Sicilian village with his baby sister and his harassed mother who is as free with a slap as with a hug. But finding refuge from all the pain and misery, in a cinema paradiso, a local picture hall, provides him with an idyllic paradise where his love for cinema and adventures can run free. There he soon strikes up an unshakable life long bond with a aging projectionist, serving as a father figure and confidante, then after a fire robes him of his sight, Alfredo (Philippe Noriet) encourages Salvatore to take over at the new paradiso, but eventually he would push the now young 18 year old Salvatore, tainted by his first heartbreak by his true love Elena(Agnese Nano), out of the confines of this dead beat village, to a world waiting to be explored and conquered , Only returning 30 years later, to witness the burial of Alfredo and the demolition of the cinema paradiso. Giuseppe Tornatore provides us with a poignant and almost, spiritual reminder of how the simple things that we held so delicately in are youths can almost be forgotten and misplace in our older years, as we replace the magic with vain perceptions of success and obsession with money, when we should actually try and reconnect with our youths, and again enjoy the personal cinema experience that promises so much. As soon as the end titles rolled by, I couldn't help but feel sad, as a big cinema paradiso shaped whole was left in my heart. Cinema paradiso is a film that stirs up a lot of home truths, a great watch for brave individuals.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A film for movie fans.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Thanos Alfie
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Nuovo Cinema Paradiso is a movie for movie and cinema fans. In this movie you will understand the true meaning of love of the cinema. When I saw this movie I loved it because I think it represents the love for films that every movie fan has. I liked very much the performance of Salvatore Cascio as young "Salvatore 'Tot&ograve;' Di Vita" and of course the performance of Phillpe Noiret as "Alfredo". I also liked very much the true love between Marco Leonardi/Jacques Perrin as a teenager and adult "Salvatore 'Tot&ograve;' Di Vita" and Agnese Nano / Brigitte Fossey as a teenager and as adult Elena Mendola. I saw the extended movie of 155 minutes and not the "cut" movie of 121 minutes and I think that it worth it, I did not get bored for even a minute instead of it I really liked it!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Lotsa pathos, little substance
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    George Aar
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is a pleasant enough movie, I guess. But really not noteworthy in any substantial way. There's a movie theatre that is obviously a set. There's a whole stable of stock characters and lots of forced emotion, but there's just no meat on the bones. And then there's all those questions unanswered. Why did little Toto (who's a really cute little kid) act out towards everyone, no matter how hard they tried to befriend him? Why did Toto's mother treat him so poorly and beat him so much? Why did Toto's father leave? Why did Toto's girlfriend leave? How could Toto be so much in love with a girl he didn't even know? What happened to his girlfriend? Why did he never come back to his hometown? Why did his life end up so apparently empty and unsatisfying? And there's more I haven't even touched on. All of those questions and no answers are even attempted for any of them. All there is is a token tearful scene here and there and a few oddball philosophical parables and the rest of the script is basically left blank. I found it rather odd. Odd and unfulfilling. I think most people would expect more from a story.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    love of a life time
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Che 19c94
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I am the kind of person that usually never tears up for a movie, but here i just can't help it. Cinema Paradiso is one of those rare movies you just have to see. And if you are a movie fan yourself, like i am, the movie would quickly be at heart. The best thing about foreign films is that you never know the actors since you have never seen them in any other movie. It is as if your watching real people go by their lives. This is the kind of movie that everybody has to see. I don't know why this movie has an R rating but the version I saw, the original 1988 version, is suitable for everyone. ENJOY
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A masterpiece: Watch it to understand, why!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mike-world1
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Among the best movies, I ever saw....for a change, don't know whether I call it drama, romance, inspiration or depressing or what...but have to say that in the last 60 minutes, I incessantly cried...I've seen some wonderful movies, but this is among the best...direction: flawless and a class-apart, cast: nothing could have been better, sets: perfectly suit the story, and story-line: quite different... the way movie moves just keeps us engrossed, without being able to anticipate what is going to happen, specially in the last one hour...maybe it tells what life is, or helps to find a reflection of our life stories...and that's how we feel connected... overall, a must watch for those, who really enjoy quality movies!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "There are only ghosts here."
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Degree7
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Passion inspires great art in a young Toto, but as his age shifts, so does his perspective on his life machinations in a small Sicilian community. With the help of the local theatre projectionist, Alfredo, he is able to recognize his potential and move out into a wider world. But what keeps this film from simply being a sentimental ode to Italian cinema, is the reflection of a much older Toro coming to terms with the sacrifices he has made to become the man he is. Were they mistakes? Or are his past regrets still threatening to cloak his accomplishments as an individual? Despite a somewhat obtrusive score by Ennio Morriconne, this film sends a strong message about life reevaluation, and how past decisions can segue into the present, in often unexpected, but beautiful ways. A small gem of a film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
 </reviews>
</filme>
