<filme>
 <id>
  173
 </id>
 <imdburl>
  http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0093779
 </imdburl>
 <ano>
  1987
 </ano>
 <titulo>
  A Princesa Prometida
 </titulo>
 <rating>
  8.1
 </rating>
 <sinopse>
  A classic fairy tale, with swordplay, giants, an evil prince, a beautiful princess, and yes, some kissing (as read by a kindly grandfather).
 </sinopse>
 <storyline>
  A kindly grandfather sits down with his ill grandson and reads him a story. The story is one that has been passed down from father to son for generations. As the grandfather reads the story, the action comes alive. The story is a classic tale of love and adventure as the beautiful Buttercup, engaged to the odious Prince Humperdinck, is kidnapped and held against her will in order to start a war, It is up to Westley (her childhood beau, now returned as the Dread Pirate Roberts) to save her. On the way he meets a thief and his hired helpers, an accomplished swordsman and a huge, super strong giant, both of whom become Westley's companions in his quest.
 </storyline>
 <generos>
  <genero>
   Adventure
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Comedy
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Family
  </genero>
 </generos>
 <keywords>
  <keyword>
   prince
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   pirate
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   swamp
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   giant
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   princess
  </keyword>
 </keywords>
 <diretores>
  <diretor>
   Rob Reiner
  </diretor>
 </diretores>
 <escritores>
  <escritor>
   William Goldman
  </escritor>
 </escritores>
 <atores>
  <ator>
   Cary Elwes
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Mandy Patinkin
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Robin Wright
  </ator>
 </atores>
 <reviews>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Fabulously witty entertainment
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    nac-mac-feegle71
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I was just reading through the reviews of this while watching it again. I had to add to them, not to agree with fellow lovers but to rebut the flaws in the reviews of the haters. People are saying it's vacuous ( okay, my word not theirs) and highly flawed. They've missed the point. Clearly the special effects are deliberately bad, as is the name Buttercup. Much of the humor is located in its tongue-in-cheek cheesiness. The dialogue is incredibly corny, not because the writing is poor but because it's just that clever. The actors deliver the lines perfectly and together, they all make this film laugh out loud funny. The story within a story format is great and Peter Falk's delivery of his lines is spot on. The bad guys are deliciously bad, the albino's glorious and Billy Crystal steals the show. You don't need to have seen this back in the 80s to love it. I was introduced to it in the late 90s and a friend introduced one of her mates to it just this year. He loved it. You have to approach this film in the right spirit. If you do, it's a hilarious ride. So it's not a feminist triumph. Who would expect it to be? Since when are fairy tales full of women doing it for themselves? There are actually some nice messages in the film about loyalty, love and sportsmanship but it's not designed as a commentary on human nature so stop looking for that and just enjoy the wonderful characterisation, the humor, the deliberate ridiculousness ( I mean, honing a dagger on a rounded rock -really?!) and the memorable (and highly quotable) lines. It's smarter than it looks.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Hated it.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Rachel Ashton
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I really did not see the appeal in this film - maybe it's because I first watched at the age of 19 rather than a lot younger. I didn't think there was much of a plot, and there seemed to be no relationship ever forming between the two lovers. I literally could not believe I'd wasted an hour and a half watching this alongside two friends who had grown up with it and adored it. Honestly I think I would probably have enjoyed it a lot more if I'd seen it when younger and grown up with it. Seeing it as a young adult just made me hate the whole thing and want to criticise every aspect of the film. I don't plan on ever watching it again and if you are also a first-time watcher at a later age I can't imagine you'd see what the hype about it is either.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Sexist pile of garbage
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mthessian
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Hated the Princess Bride. It is a sexist pile of garbage.. Of course the woman in the movie should wait for years in vacuous idiocy for her "True Love" to rescue her instead of actually doing anything. And when it's revealed that her "True Love" is still alive the only action she takes is attempted suicide. Very good roll model for young women. I guess it takes a woman who can actually take care of herself instead of waiting for Prince Charming to get this. I can't tell you how anti female this movie is. If you think women are just window dressing for male revenge and hero fantasies this is the flick for you. If you think women can actually think and act for themselves and not sit around forever to wait to be rescued, give this a pass.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Perfect Fit
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Maddie Anderson
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie is the all time family movie. The kids will love it, the parents will love it, everyone does! This is a great "prince" and princess story. A grandfather is telling his ill grandson a story. As he is telling the story, the characters come to life. They go through many things throughout the film, including: torture, climbing up a cliff, sword fights, hardships, battles, huge rats, and crashing the big wedding! In the end the Pirate gets the girl and they live happily ever after. The Dreaded Pirate Roberts (played by Cary Elwes)is so captivating to watch! His character is dreamy, and so funny! Princess Buttercup ( Robin Wright)is beautiful and so endearing. Inigo Montoua (Mandy Patinkin)is such a fun character to watch and listen to! This is such a fun film for the whole family to watch! This is a great sick day movie, hard day movie, and just an everyday movie! This is a very funny story that
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    As You Wish
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Tina Chan (chmpgnrose)
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I LOVE this movie from William Goldman's 1973 excellent book converted into a movie. A princess who is also a bride to be, how clever is a combination two who employees a farmhand, Westley. The handsome Westley always appease his woman with a response: "as you wish" and he reveals his love for her. This movie is every girl (no matter how old) romance. With a happy ending as narrated by a grandfather told to his very ill grandson, it depicts fantasy and the subtle ness of love. I am willing to watch this movie again and again. This movie is a classic that rivals in the silver screen with 1987's "Dirty Dancing" which both have love and romance in their respective plots.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Clever and fun fantasy film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Pihlaja
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    One of the most well-known and respected fantasy films and for a good reason. The Princess Bride is a genre-defining film that has endured the test of time beautifully and still stands as one of the best adventure films and the one film you should see if you're interested in swashbuckler films. What I like the most about this film is its unpredictability. Sure, it's an adventure film aimed for all audiences, so the good guys are going to win and all that, but the way they go about accomplishing that task is what makes this film enjoyable. You're never sure what's going to happen next, the characters are very creative and there are a lot of them, the plot twists come right out of nowhere and the humorous tongue-in-cheek tone ties it all together. There is drama and high stages, yes, but it's still an adventure film and meant to be enjoyed with a smile on your face. The story develops rather erratically, going from one scene to another with very few tie-ins, but in this case it works, because the whole film is told more like a fairy tale than a typical story. So it's more of a preference of style than a flaw. If I were to nitpick, I'd say that the frame story involving a grandfather reading his grandson a book while he lies sick in bed is not as interesting as the actual story and sometimes the kid's interruptions in the story come at the worst possible times. This is only a nitpick, however, because the banter between these two is actually quite humorous, which keeps it from becoming an annoyance. It'd be interesting to see just how well the actual adventure would flow without the frame story, just for comparison. I like this film, I like a lot. It has a strong story, it's fun and charming without being immature, its characters are great, it has a lot of memorable dialogues and as a whole it's just bursting with imagination. One of the best adventure films I've ever seen and well worth your time, whoever you happen to be.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I Am Not Left-Handed ...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ShootingShark
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    In the Kingdom of Florin, the beautiful Buttercup is heartbroken when her true love Westley is killed by pirates. Five years later, she is betrothed to Prince Humperdinck, but she does not love him. When she is abruptly kidnapped by three bandits who are then pursued by a mysterious masked man, it appears that all is not what it seems ... Some movies just seem to hit all the right notes, and The Princess Bride is one of them. It works both as a pure fairytale of love and adventure, but also as a wryly tongue-in-cheek comedy, and it has just the right balance of action, humour, romance and intrigue to suit everyone; a true family film if ever there was. The best word to describe it is delightful. With its deliberately old-fashioned tone it may not be the most original story, but it's so full of inventive scenes, crazy characters and hilarious lines that it just sweeps you away right from the start and makes you cheer for the heroes. It features a truly wonderful cast, with the then relatively unknown Elwes and Wright both great in the leads, Guest a wonderfully sneaky six-fingered villain and rib-tickling supporting roles from Shawn, Falk, Crystal and Cook. Perhaps best of all though are the unlikely pairing of Patinkin and Andr&eacute; as the desperadoes-turned-good-guy-buddies Montoya and Fezzik; Patinkin is simply perfect as the revenge-seeking swordsman and this is pretty much the only movie where you can see the late great Andr&eacute; Roussimoff, who stood seven-foot-four, was a legendary wrestler, and who gives an incredibly gentle and charming performance. I love adventure movies; I always have and I always will. Whether it's Robin Hood, Tarzan, Indiana Jones or whoever takes your fancy, cinema was made for thrills and spills, and this is a terrific example of how to do it right. It's packed with great scenes - the as-you-wish opening, Fezzik's rhymes, the dual between Westley and Montoya, the deadly game with the poisoned chalice, the Pit of Despair, Miracle Max, storming the castle ("If only we had a wheelbarrow !"), Montoya's triumph, many more. It's also one of those movies where all the technical elements are unobtrusively brilliant. This is particularly true of the charming acoustic score by Mark Knopfler (the guitarist/singer of rock band Dire Straits), but the photography, costumes and sets are all first-rate. Brilliantly written by the near-legendary Hollywood screenwriter William Goldman (Butch Cassidy And The Sundance Kid, All The President's Men), though the movie itself was funded independently and shot in England. All of Rob Reiner's movies are good, but four he made in the mid-to-late eighties - This Is Spinal Tap, Stand By Me, The Princess Bride and Misery - are all just outstanding and outstandingly different, and The Princess Bride is perhaps the best of these. Don't miss it, and if you have young children, make sure they see it too.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Whimsical and Charming
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    GouramiWatcher
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The book was long and boring, but the film was the sheer opposite. Funny and strongly written, The Princess Bride is a wonderful movie, despite its low effects. Buttercup (Robin Wright) falls in love with a poor man named Wesley (Carey Elwes) and are together until his death by the Dread Pirate Roberts. Buttercup is then engaged to Prince Humperdinck, a selfish man who wishes to start a war. She does not love him, however, because Wesley is the true owner of her heart. She is then captured by three men who claim to be circus performers but is recaptured by "The Man in Black" who turns out to be Wesley, who inherited the ship of his captor. Buttercup is later whisked away from her wedding by the two surviving kidnappers and Wesley, free to be together for the rest of their lives.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Story about a book which is really about storytelling
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Marc Israel
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Yes, there's the fairy tale double coated in delicious dialog and salacious characters played beyond the realm of silliness but it's the story of true love that conquers all and is the cohesive constant. True Love conquers all, and allows for our story to play out in this fictitious land of yore. This only happens because of the indulgent set up of our good guys and bad guys full of lore, secrets, personal histories and ambitions. Smart, worthy and yet silly. Director Rob Reiner keeps us both on track with his talented cast and in sync through the Grandfather-Grandson aside, and therefore the absurd story is not so "inconceivable". Another favorite due to its quotable dialog and characters cemented in our hearts.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The opening and the main soundtrack - brilliant!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Zaid Mansur
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    How this made it to the top 250 I do not know. If the movie was made in the 70s I would consider giving it a better rating. Im well aware that the main-focus of the movie is the story-telling and therefore it's made a bit sloppy on purpose - I hope. The movie could've been done a lot better and still maintain the good storytelling. I also think that the director could've done a better job in making the viewer feel more with the characters - make the passion more passionate, the hate and lust for revenge more hateful and lusting. The only things convincing in the movie were: The main soundtrack, a sound that gave me buttterflies during the first commence of the two main characters, and thrills in the end. Truly deserving of the Oscar that year. The character of Miracle-MAX - hilarious, his sarcasm is a warm welcome. "...and while you're at it why don't you go ahead and give a nice papercut and pour some lemonjuice on it" - best quote of the movie and made me laugh out loud And the first 6-7 minutes of the movie - brilliant!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Fabulously witty entertainment
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    nac-mac-feegle71
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I was just reading through the reviews of this while watching it again. I had to add to them, not to agree with fellow lovers but to rebut the flaws in the reviews of the haters. People are saying it's vacuous ( okay, my word not theirs) and highly flawed. They've missed the point. Clearly the special effects are deliberately bad, as is the name Buttercup. Much of the humor is located in its tongue-in-cheek cheesiness. The dialogue is incredibly corny, not because the writing is poor but because it's just that clever. The actors deliver the lines perfectly and together, they all make this film laugh out loud funny. The story within a story format is great and Peter Falk's delivery of his lines is spot on. The bad guys are deliciously bad, the albino's glorious and Billy Crystal steals the show. You don't need to have seen this back in the 80s to love it. I was introduced to it in the late 90s and a friend introduced one of her mates to it just this year. He loved it. You have to approach this film in the right spirit. If you do, it's a hilarious ride. So it's not a feminist triumph. Who would expect it to be? Since when are fairy tales full of women doing it for themselves? There are actually some nice messages in the film about loyalty, love and sportsmanship but it's not designed as a commentary on human nature so stop looking for that and just enjoy the wonderful characterisation, the humor, the deliberate ridiculousness ( I mean, honing a dagger on a rounded rock -really?!) and the memorable (and highly quotable) lines. It's smarter than it looks.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Hated it.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Rachel Ashton
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I really did not see the appeal in this film - maybe it's because I first watched at the age of 19 rather than a lot younger. I didn't think there was much of a plot, and there seemed to be no relationship ever forming between the two lovers. I literally could not believe I'd wasted an hour and a half watching this alongside two friends who had grown up with it and adored it. Honestly I think I would probably have enjoyed it a lot more if I'd seen it when younger and grown up with it. Seeing it as a young adult just made me hate the whole thing and want to criticise every aspect of the film. I don't plan on ever watching it again and if you are also a first-time watcher at a later age I can't imagine you'd see what the hype about it is either.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Sexist pile of garbage
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mthessian
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Hated the Princess Bride. It is a sexist pile of garbage.. Of course the woman in the movie should wait for years in vacuous idiocy for her "True Love" to rescue her instead of actually doing anything. And when it's revealed that her "True Love" is still alive the only action she takes is attempted suicide. Very good roll model for young women. I guess it takes a woman who can actually take care of herself instead of waiting for Prince Charming to get this. I can't tell you how anti female this movie is. If you think women are just window dressing for male revenge and hero fantasies this is the flick for you. If you think women can actually think and act for themselves and not sit around forever to wait to be rescued, give this a pass.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Perfect Fit
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Maddie Anderson
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie is the all time family movie. The kids will love it, the parents will love it, everyone does! This is a great "prince" and princess story. A grandfather is telling his ill grandson a story. As he is telling the story, the characters come to life. They go through many things throughout the film, including: torture, climbing up a cliff, sword fights, hardships, battles, huge rats, and crashing the big wedding! In the end the Pirate gets the girl and they live happily ever after. The Dreaded Pirate Roberts (played by Cary Elwes)is so captivating to watch! His character is dreamy, and so funny! Princess Buttercup ( Robin Wright)is beautiful and so endearing. Inigo Montoua (Mandy Patinkin)is such a fun character to watch and listen to! This is such a fun film for the whole family to watch! This is a great sick day movie, hard day movie, and just an everyday movie! This is a very funny story that
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    As You Wish
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Tina Chan (chmpgnrose)
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I LOVE this movie from William Goldman's 1973 excellent book converted into a movie. A princess who is also a bride to be, how clever is a combination two who employees a farmhand, Westley. The handsome Westley always appease his woman with a response: "as you wish" and he reveals his love for her. This movie is every girl (no matter how old) romance. With a happy ending as narrated by a grandfather told to his very ill grandson, it depicts fantasy and the subtle ness of love. I am willing to watch this movie again and again. This movie is a classic that rivals in the silver screen with 1987's "Dirty Dancing" which both have love and romance in their respective plots.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Clever and fun fantasy film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Pihlaja
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    One of the most well-known and respected fantasy films and for a good reason. The Princess Bride is a genre-defining film that has endured the test of time beautifully and still stands as one of the best adventure films and the one film you should see if you're interested in swashbuckler films. What I like the most about this film is its unpredictability. Sure, it's an adventure film aimed for all audiences, so the good guys are going to win and all that, but the way they go about accomplishing that task is what makes this film enjoyable. You're never sure what's going to happen next, the characters are very creative and there are a lot of them, the plot twists come right out of nowhere and the humorous tongue-in-cheek tone ties it all together. There is drama and high stages, yes, but it's still an adventure film and meant to be enjoyed with a smile on your face. The story develops rather erratically, going from one scene to another with very few tie-ins, but in this case it works, because the whole film is told more like a fairy tale than a typical story. So it's more of a preference of style than a flaw. If I were to nitpick, I'd say that the frame story involving a grandfather reading his grandson a book while he lies sick in bed is not as interesting as the actual story and sometimes the kid's interruptions in the story come at the worst possible times. This is only a nitpick, however, because the banter between these two is actually quite humorous, which keeps it from becoming an annoyance. It'd be interesting to see just how well the actual adventure would flow without the frame story, just for comparison. I like this film, I like a lot. It has a strong story, it's fun and charming without being immature, its characters are great, it has a lot of memorable dialogues and as a whole it's just bursting with imagination. One of the best adventure films I've ever seen and well worth your time, whoever you happen to be.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I Am Not Left-Handed ...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ShootingShark
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    In the Kingdom of Florin, the beautiful Buttercup is heartbroken when her true love Westley is killed by pirates. Five years later, she is betrothed to Prince Humperdinck, but she does not love him. When she is abruptly kidnapped by three bandits who are then pursued by a mysterious masked man, it appears that all is not what it seems ... Some movies just seem to hit all the right notes, and The Princess Bride is one of them. It works both as a pure fairytale of love and adventure, but also as a wryly tongue-in-cheek comedy, and it has just the right balance of action, humour, romance and intrigue to suit everyone; a true family film if ever there was. The best word to describe it is delightful. With its deliberately old-fashioned tone it may not be the most original story, but it's so full of inventive scenes, crazy characters and hilarious lines that it just sweeps you away right from the start and makes you cheer for the heroes. It features a truly wonderful cast, with the then relatively unknown Elwes and Wright both great in the leads, Guest a wonderfully sneaky six-fingered villain and rib-tickling supporting roles from Shawn, Falk, Crystal and Cook. Perhaps best of all though are the unlikely pairing of Patinkin and Andr&eacute; as the desperadoes-turned-good-guy-buddies Montoya and Fezzik; Patinkin is simply perfect as the revenge-seeking swordsman and this is pretty much the only movie where you can see the late great Andr&eacute; Roussimoff, who stood seven-foot-four, was a legendary wrestler, and who gives an incredibly gentle and charming performance. I love adventure movies; I always have and I always will. Whether it's Robin Hood, Tarzan, Indiana Jones or whoever takes your fancy, cinema was made for thrills and spills, and this is a terrific example of how to do it right. It's packed with great scenes - the as-you-wish opening, Fezzik's rhymes, the dual between Westley and Montoya, the deadly game with the poisoned chalice, the Pit of Despair, Miracle Max, storming the castle ("If only we had a wheelbarrow !"), Montoya's triumph, many more. It's also one of those movies where all the technical elements are unobtrusively brilliant. This is particularly true of the charming acoustic score by Mark Knopfler (the guitarist/singer of rock band Dire Straits), but the photography, costumes and sets are all first-rate. Brilliantly written by the near-legendary Hollywood screenwriter William Goldman (Butch Cassidy And The Sundance Kid, All The President's Men), though the movie itself was funded independently and shot in England. All of Rob Reiner's movies are good, but four he made in the mid-to-late eighties - This Is Spinal Tap, Stand By Me, The Princess Bride and Misery - are all just outstanding and outstandingly different, and The Princess Bride is perhaps the best of these. Don't miss it, and if you have young children, make sure they see it too.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Whimsical and Charming
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    GouramiWatcher
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The book was long and boring, but the film was the sheer opposite. Funny and strongly written, The Princess Bride is a wonderful movie, despite its low effects. Buttercup (Robin Wright) falls in love with a poor man named Wesley (Carey Elwes) and are together until his death by the Dread Pirate Roberts. Buttercup is then engaged to Prince Humperdinck, a selfish man who wishes to start a war. She does not love him, however, because Wesley is the true owner of her heart. She is then captured by three men who claim to be circus performers but is recaptured by "The Man in Black" who turns out to be Wesley, who inherited the ship of his captor. Buttercup is later whisked away from her wedding by the two surviving kidnappers and Wesley, free to be together for the rest of their lives.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Story about a book which is really about storytelling
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Marc Israel
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Yes, there's the fairy tale double coated in delicious dialog and salacious characters played beyond the realm of silliness but it's the story of true love that conquers all and is the cohesive constant. True Love conquers all, and allows for our story to play out in this fictitious land of yore. This only happens because of the indulgent set up of our good guys and bad guys full of lore, secrets, personal histories and ambitions. Smart, worthy and yet silly. Director Rob Reiner keeps us both on track with his talented cast and in sync through the Grandfather-Grandson aside, and therefore the absurd story is not so "inconceivable". Another favorite due to its quotable dialog and characters cemented in our hearts.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The opening and the main soundtrack - brilliant!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Zaid Mansur
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    How this made it to the top 250 I do not know. If the movie was made in the 70s I would consider giving it a better rating. Im well aware that the main-focus of the movie is the story-telling and therefore it's made a bit sloppy on purpose - I hope. The movie could've been done a lot better and still maintain the good storytelling. I also think that the director could've done a better job in making the viewer feel more with the characters - make the passion more passionate, the hate and lust for revenge more hateful and lusting. The only things convincing in the movie were: The main soundtrack, a sound that gave me buttterflies during the first commence of the two main characters, and thrills in the end. Truly deserving of the Oscar that year. The character of Miracle-MAX - hilarious, his sarcasm is a warm welcome. "...and while you're at it why don't you go ahead and give a nice papercut and pour some lemonjuice on it" - best quote of the movie and made me laugh out loud And the first 6-7 minutes of the movie - brilliant!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Fabulously witty entertainment
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    nac-mac-feegle71
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I was just reading through the reviews of this while watching it again. I had to add to them, not to agree with fellow lovers but to rebut the flaws in the reviews of the haters. People are saying it's vacuous ( okay, my word not theirs) and highly flawed. They've missed the point. Clearly the special effects are deliberately bad, as is the name Buttercup. Much of the humor is located in its tongue-in-cheek cheesiness. The dialogue is incredibly corny, not because the writing is poor but because it's just that clever. The actors deliver the lines perfectly and together, they all make this film laugh out loud funny. The story within a story format is great and Peter Falk's delivery of his lines is spot on. The bad guys are deliciously bad, the albino's glorious and Billy Crystal steals the show. You don't need to have seen this back in the 80s to love it. I was introduced to it in the late 90s and a friend introduced one of her mates to it just this year. He loved it. You have to approach this film in the right spirit. If you do, it's a hilarious ride. So it's not a feminist triumph. Who would expect it to be? Since when are fairy tales full of women doing it for themselves? There are actually some nice messages in the film about loyalty, love and sportsmanship but it's not designed as a commentary on human nature so stop looking for that and just enjoy the wonderful characterisation, the humor, the deliberate ridiculousness ( I mean, honing a dagger on a rounded rock -really?!) and the memorable (and highly quotable) lines. It's smarter than it looks.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Hated it.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Rachel Ashton
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I really did not see the appeal in this film - maybe it's because I first watched at the age of 19 rather than a lot younger. I didn't think there was much of a plot, and there seemed to be no relationship ever forming between the two lovers. I literally could not believe I'd wasted an hour and a half watching this alongside two friends who had grown up with it and adored it. Honestly I think I would probably have enjoyed it a lot more if I'd seen it when younger and grown up with it. Seeing it as a young adult just made me hate the whole thing and want to criticise every aspect of the film. I don't plan on ever watching it again and if you are also a first-time watcher at a later age I can't imagine you'd see what the hype about it is either.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Sexist pile of garbage
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mthessian
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Hated the Princess Bride. It is a sexist pile of garbage.. Of course the woman in the movie should wait for years in vacuous idiocy for her "True Love" to rescue her instead of actually doing anything. And when it's revealed that her "True Love" is still alive the only action she takes is attempted suicide. Very good roll model for young women. I guess it takes a woman who can actually take care of herself instead of waiting for Prince Charming to get this. I can't tell you how anti female this movie is. If you think women are just window dressing for male revenge and hero fantasies this is the flick for you. If you think women can actually think and act for themselves and not sit around forever to wait to be rescued, give this a pass.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Perfect Fit
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Maddie Anderson
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie is the all time family movie. The kids will love it, the parents will love it, everyone does! This is a great "prince" and princess story. A grandfather is telling his ill grandson a story. As he is telling the story, the characters come to life. They go through many things throughout the film, including: torture, climbing up a cliff, sword fights, hardships, battles, huge rats, and crashing the big wedding! In the end the Pirate gets the girl and they live happily ever after. The Dreaded Pirate Roberts (played by Cary Elwes)is so captivating to watch! His character is dreamy, and so funny! Princess Buttercup ( Robin Wright)is beautiful and so endearing. Inigo Montoua (Mandy Patinkin)is such a fun character to watch and listen to! This is such a fun film for the whole family to watch! This is a great sick day movie, hard day movie, and just an everyday movie! This is a very funny story that
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    As You Wish
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Tina Chan (chmpgnrose)
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I LOVE this movie from William Goldman's 1973 excellent book converted into a movie. A princess who is also a bride to be, how clever is a combination two who employees a farmhand, Westley. The handsome Westley always appease his woman with a response: "as you wish" and he reveals his love for her. This movie is every girl (no matter how old) romance. With a happy ending as narrated by a grandfather told to his very ill grandson, it depicts fantasy and the subtle ness of love. I am willing to watch this movie again and again. This movie is a classic that rivals in the silver screen with 1987's "Dirty Dancing" which both have love and romance in their respective plots.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Clever and fun fantasy film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Pihlaja
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    One of the most well-known and respected fantasy films and for a good reason. The Princess Bride is a genre-defining film that has endured the test of time beautifully and still stands as one of the best adventure films and the one film you should see if you're interested in swashbuckler films. What I like the most about this film is its unpredictability. Sure, it's an adventure film aimed for all audiences, so the good guys are going to win and all that, but the way they go about accomplishing that task is what makes this film enjoyable. You're never sure what's going to happen next, the characters are very creative and there are a lot of them, the plot twists come right out of nowhere and the humorous tongue-in-cheek tone ties it all together. There is drama and high stages, yes, but it's still an adventure film and meant to be enjoyed with a smile on your face. The story develops rather erratically, going from one scene to another with very few tie-ins, but in this case it works, because the whole film is told more like a fairy tale than a typical story. So it's more of a preference of style than a flaw. If I were to nitpick, I'd say that the frame story involving a grandfather reading his grandson a book while he lies sick in bed is not as interesting as the actual story and sometimes the kid's interruptions in the story come at the worst possible times. This is only a nitpick, however, because the banter between these two is actually quite humorous, which keeps it from becoming an annoyance. It'd be interesting to see just how well the actual adventure would flow without the frame story, just for comparison. I like this film, I like a lot. It has a strong story, it's fun and charming without being immature, its characters are great, it has a lot of memorable dialogues and as a whole it's just bursting with imagination. One of the best adventure films I've ever seen and well worth your time, whoever you happen to be.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I Am Not Left-Handed ...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ShootingShark
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    In the Kingdom of Florin, the beautiful Buttercup is heartbroken when her true love Westley is killed by pirates. Five years later, she is betrothed to Prince Humperdinck, but she does not love him. When she is abruptly kidnapped by three bandits who are then pursued by a mysterious masked man, it appears that all is not what it seems ... Some movies just seem to hit all the right notes, and The Princess Bride is one of them. It works both as a pure fairytale of love and adventure, but also as a wryly tongue-in-cheek comedy, and it has just the right balance of action, humour, romance and intrigue to suit everyone; a true family film if ever there was. The best word to describe it is delightful. With its deliberately old-fashioned tone it may not be the most original story, but it's so full of inventive scenes, crazy characters and hilarious lines that it just sweeps you away right from the start and makes you cheer for the heroes. It features a truly wonderful cast, with the then relatively unknown Elwes and Wright both great in the leads, Guest a wonderfully sneaky six-fingered villain and rib-tickling supporting roles from Shawn, Falk, Crystal and Cook. Perhaps best of all though are the unlikely pairing of Patinkin and Andr&eacute; as the desperadoes-turned-good-guy-buddies Montoya and Fezzik; Patinkin is simply perfect as the revenge-seeking swordsman and this is pretty much the only movie where you can see the late great Andr&eacute; Roussimoff, who stood seven-foot-four, was a legendary wrestler, and who gives an incredibly gentle and charming performance. I love adventure movies; I always have and I always will. Whether it's Robin Hood, Tarzan, Indiana Jones or whoever takes your fancy, cinema was made for thrills and spills, and this is a terrific example of how to do it right. It's packed with great scenes - the as-you-wish opening, Fezzik's rhymes, the dual between Westley and Montoya, the deadly game with the poisoned chalice, the Pit of Despair, Miracle Max, storming the castle ("If only we had a wheelbarrow !"), Montoya's triumph, many more. It's also one of those movies where all the technical elements are unobtrusively brilliant. This is particularly true of the charming acoustic score by Mark Knopfler (the guitarist/singer of rock band Dire Straits), but the photography, costumes and sets are all first-rate. Brilliantly written by the near-legendary Hollywood screenwriter William Goldman (Butch Cassidy And The Sundance Kid, All The President's Men), though the movie itself was funded independently and shot in England. All of Rob Reiner's movies are good, but four he made in the mid-to-late eighties - This Is Spinal Tap, Stand By Me, The Princess Bride and Misery - are all just outstanding and outstandingly different, and The Princess Bride is perhaps the best of these. Don't miss it, and if you have young children, make sure they see it too.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Whimsical and Charming
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    GouramiWatcher
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The book was long and boring, but the film was the sheer opposite. Funny and strongly written, The Princess Bride is a wonderful movie, despite its low effects. Buttercup (Robin Wright) falls in love with a poor man named Wesley (Carey Elwes) and are together until his death by the Dread Pirate Roberts. Buttercup is then engaged to Prince Humperdinck, a selfish man who wishes to start a war. She does not love him, however, because Wesley is the true owner of her heart. She is then captured by three men who claim to be circus performers but is recaptured by "The Man in Black" who turns out to be Wesley, who inherited the ship of his captor. Buttercup is later whisked away from her wedding by the two surviving kidnappers and Wesley, free to be together for the rest of their lives.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Story about a book which is really about storytelling
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Marc Israel
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Yes, there's the fairy tale double coated in delicious dialog and salacious characters played beyond the realm of silliness but it's the story of true love that conquers all and is the cohesive constant. True Love conquers all, and allows for our story to play out in this fictitious land of yore. This only happens because of the indulgent set up of our good guys and bad guys full of lore, secrets, personal histories and ambitions. Smart, worthy and yet silly. Director Rob Reiner keeps us both on track with his talented cast and in sync through the Grandfather-Grandson aside, and therefore the absurd story is not so "inconceivable". Another favorite due to its quotable dialog and characters cemented in our hearts.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The opening and the main soundtrack - brilliant!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Zaid Mansur
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    How this made it to the top 250 I do not know. If the movie was made in the 70s I would consider giving it a better rating. Im well aware that the main-focus of the movie is the story-telling and therefore it's made a bit sloppy on purpose - I hope. The movie could've been done a lot better and still maintain the good storytelling. I also think that the director could've done a better job in making the viewer feel more with the characters - make the passion more passionate, the hate and lust for revenge more hateful and lusting. The only things convincing in the movie were: The main soundtrack, a sound that gave me buttterflies during the first commence of the two main characters, and thrills in the end. Truly deserving of the Oscar that year. The character of Miracle-MAX - hilarious, his sarcasm is a warm welcome. "...and while you're at it why don't you go ahead and give a nice papercut and pour some lemonjuice on it" - best quote of the movie and made me laugh out loud And the first 6-7 minutes of the movie - brilliant!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Fabulously witty entertainment
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    nac-mac-feegle71
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I was just reading through the reviews of this while watching it again. I had to add to them, not to agree with fellow lovers but to rebut the flaws in the reviews of the haters. People are saying it's vacuous ( okay, my word not theirs) and highly flawed. They've missed the point. Clearly the special effects are deliberately bad, as is the name Buttercup. Much of the humor is located in its tongue-in-cheek cheesiness. The dialogue is incredibly corny, not because the writing is poor but because it's just that clever. The actors deliver the lines perfectly and together, they all make this film laugh out loud funny. The story within a story format is great and Peter Falk's delivery of his lines is spot on. The bad guys are deliciously bad, the albino's glorious and Billy Crystal steals the show. You don't need to have seen this back in the 80s to love it. I was introduced to it in the late 90s and a friend introduced one of her mates to it just this year. He loved it. You have to approach this film in the right spirit. If you do, it's a hilarious ride. So it's not a feminist triumph. Who would expect it to be? Since when are fairy tales full of women doing it for themselves? There are actually some nice messages in the film about loyalty, love and sportsmanship but it's not designed as a commentary on human nature so stop looking for that and just enjoy the wonderful characterisation, the humor, the deliberate ridiculousness ( I mean, honing a dagger on a rounded rock -really?!) and the memorable (and highly quotable) lines. It's smarter than it looks.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Hated it.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Rachel Ashton
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I really did not see the appeal in this film - maybe it's because I first watched at the age of 19 rather than a lot younger. I didn't think there was much of a plot, and there seemed to be no relationship ever forming between the two lovers. I literally could not believe I'd wasted an hour and a half watching this alongside two friends who had grown up with it and adored it. Honestly I think I would probably have enjoyed it a lot more if I'd seen it when younger and grown up with it. Seeing it as a young adult just made me hate the whole thing and want to criticise every aspect of the film. I don't plan on ever watching it again and if you are also a first-time watcher at a later age I can't imagine you'd see what the hype about it is either.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Sexist pile of garbage
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mthessian
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Hated the Princess Bride. It is a sexist pile of garbage.. Of course the woman in the movie should wait for years in vacuous idiocy for her "True Love" to rescue her instead of actually doing anything. And when it's revealed that her "True Love" is still alive the only action she takes is attempted suicide. Very good roll model for young women. I guess it takes a woman who can actually take care of herself instead of waiting for Prince Charming to get this. I can't tell you how anti female this movie is. If you think women are just window dressing for male revenge and hero fantasies this is the flick for you. If you think women can actually think and act for themselves and not sit around forever to wait to be rescued, give this a pass.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Perfect Fit
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Maddie Anderson
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie is the all time family movie. The kids will love it, the parents will love it, everyone does! This is a great "prince" and princess story. A grandfather is telling his ill grandson a story. As he is telling the story, the characters come to life. They go through many things throughout the film, including: torture, climbing up a cliff, sword fights, hardships, battles, huge rats, and crashing the big wedding! In the end the Pirate gets the girl and they live happily ever after. The Dreaded Pirate Roberts (played by Cary Elwes)is so captivating to watch! His character is dreamy, and so funny! Princess Buttercup ( Robin Wright)is beautiful and so endearing. Inigo Montoua (Mandy Patinkin)is such a fun character to watch and listen to! This is such a fun film for the whole family to watch! This is a great sick day movie, hard day movie, and just an everyday movie! This is a very funny story that
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    As You Wish
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Tina Chan (chmpgnrose)
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I LOVE this movie from William Goldman's 1973 excellent book converted into a movie. A princess who is also a bride to be, how clever is a combination two who employees a farmhand, Westley. The handsome Westley always appease his woman with a response: "as you wish" and he reveals his love for her. This movie is every girl (no matter how old) romance. With a happy ending as narrated by a grandfather told to his very ill grandson, it depicts fantasy and the subtle ness of love. I am willing to watch this movie again and again. This movie is a classic that rivals in the silver screen with 1987's "Dirty Dancing" which both have love and romance in their respective plots.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Clever and fun fantasy film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Pihlaja
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    One of the most well-known and respected fantasy films and for a good reason. The Princess Bride is a genre-defining film that has endured the test of time beautifully and still stands as one of the best adventure films and the one film you should see if you're interested in swashbuckler films. What I like the most about this film is its unpredictability. Sure, it's an adventure film aimed for all audiences, so the good guys are going to win and all that, but the way they go about accomplishing that task is what makes this film enjoyable. You're never sure what's going to happen next, the characters are very creative and there are a lot of them, the plot twists come right out of nowhere and the humorous tongue-in-cheek tone ties it all together. There is drama and high stages, yes, but it's still an adventure film and meant to be enjoyed with a smile on your face. The story develops rather erratically, going from one scene to another with very few tie-ins, but in this case it works, because the whole film is told more like a fairy tale than a typical story. So it's more of a preference of style than a flaw. If I were to nitpick, I'd say that the frame story involving a grandfather reading his grandson a book while he lies sick in bed is not as interesting as the actual story and sometimes the kid's interruptions in the story come at the worst possible times. This is only a nitpick, however, because the banter between these two is actually quite humorous, which keeps it from becoming an annoyance. It'd be interesting to see just how well the actual adventure would flow without the frame story, just for comparison. I like this film, I like a lot. It has a strong story, it's fun and charming without being immature, its characters are great, it has a lot of memorable dialogues and as a whole it's just bursting with imagination. One of the best adventure films I've ever seen and well worth your time, whoever you happen to be.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I Am Not Left-Handed ...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ShootingShark
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    In the Kingdom of Florin, the beautiful Buttercup is heartbroken when her true love Westley is killed by pirates. Five years later, she is betrothed to Prince Humperdinck, but she does not love him. When she is abruptly kidnapped by three bandits who are then pursued by a mysterious masked man, it appears that all is not what it seems ... Some movies just seem to hit all the right notes, and The Princess Bride is one of them. It works both as a pure fairytale of love and adventure, but also as a wryly tongue-in-cheek comedy, and it has just the right balance of action, humour, romance and intrigue to suit everyone; a true family film if ever there was. The best word to describe it is delightful. With its deliberately old-fashioned tone it may not be the most original story, but it's so full of inventive scenes, crazy characters and hilarious lines that it just sweeps you away right from the start and makes you cheer for the heroes. It features a truly wonderful cast, with the then relatively unknown Elwes and Wright both great in the leads, Guest a wonderfully sneaky six-fingered villain and rib-tickling supporting roles from Shawn, Falk, Crystal and Cook. Perhaps best of all though are the unlikely pairing of Patinkin and Andr&eacute; as the desperadoes-turned-good-guy-buddies Montoya and Fezzik; Patinkin is simply perfect as the revenge-seeking swordsman and this is pretty much the only movie where you can see the late great Andr&eacute; Roussimoff, who stood seven-foot-four, was a legendary wrestler, and who gives an incredibly gentle and charming performance. I love adventure movies; I always have and I always will. Whether it's Robin Hood, Tarzan, Indiana Jones or whoever takes your fancy, cinema was made for thrills and spills, and this is a terrific example of how to do it right. It's packed with great scenes - the as-you-wish opening, Fezzik's rhymes, the dual between Westley and Montoya, the deadly game with the poisoned chalice, the Pit of Despair, Miracle Max, storming the castle ("If only we had a wheelbarrow !"), Montoya's triumph, many more. It's also one of those movies where all the technical elements are unobtrusively brilliant. This is particularly true of the charming acoustic score by Mark Knopfler (the guitarist/singer of rock band Dire Straits), but the photography, costumes and sets are all first-rate. Brilliantly written by the near-legendary Hollywood screenwriter William Goldman (Butch Cassidy And The Sundance Kid, All The President's Men), though the movie itself was funded independently and shot in England. All of Rob Reiner's movies are good, but four he made in the mid-to-late eighties - This Is Spinal Tap, Stand By Me, The Princess Bride and Misery - are all just outstanding and outstandingly different, and The Princess Bride is perhaps the best of these. Don't miss it, and if you have young children, make sure they see it too.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Whimsical and Charming
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    GouramiWatcher
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The book was long and boring, but the film was the sheer opposite. Funny and strongly written, The Princess Bride is a wonderful movie, despite its low effects. Buttercup (Robin Wright) falls in love with a poor man named Wesley (Carey Elwes) and are together until his death by the Dread Pirate Roberts. Buttercup is then engaged to Prince Humperdinck, a selfish man who wishes to start a war. She does not love him, however, because Wesley is the true owner of her heart. She is then captured by three men who claim to be circus performers but is recaptured by "The Man in Black" who turns out to be Wesley, who inherited the ship of his captor. Buttercup is later whisked away from her wedding by the two surviving kidnappers and Wesley, free to be together for the rest of their lives.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Story about a book which is really about storytelling
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Marc Israel
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Yes, there's the fairy tale double coated in delicious dialog and salacious characters played beyond the realm of silliness but it's the story of true love that conquers all and is the cohesive constant. True Love conquers all, and allows for our story to play out in this fictitious land of yore. This only happens because of the indulgent set up of our good guys and bad guys full of lore, secrets, personal histories and ambitions. Smart, worthy and yet silly. Director Rob Reiner keeps us both on track with his talented cast and in sync through the Grandfather-Grandson aside, and therefore the absurd story is not so "inconceivable". Another favorite due to its quotable dialog and characters cemented in our hearts.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The opening and the main soundtrack - brilliant!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Zaid Mansur
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    How this made it to the top 250 I do not know. If the movie was made in the 70s I would consider giving it a better rating. Im well aware that the main-focus of the movie is the story-telling and therefore it's made a bit sloppy on purpose - I hope. The movie could've been done a lot better and still maintain the good storytelling. I also think that the director could've done a better job in making the viewer feel more with the characters - make the passion more passionate, the hate and lust for revenge more hateful and lusting. The only things convincing in the movie were: The main soundtrack, a sound that gave me buttterflies during the first commence of the two main characters, and thrills in the end. Truly deserving of the Oscar that year. The character of Miracle-MAX - hilarious, his sarcasm is a warm welcome. "...and while you're at it why don't you go ahead and give a nice papercut and pour some lemonjuice on it" - best quote of the movie and made me laugh out loud And the first 6-7 minutes of the movie - brilliant!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Fabulously witty entertainment
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    nac-mac-feegle71
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I was just reading through the reviews of this while watching it again. I had to add to them, not to agree with fellow lovers but to rebut the flaws in the reviews of the haters. People are saying it's vacuous ( okay, my word not theirs) and highly flawed. They've missed the point. Clearly the special effects are deliberately bad, as is the name Buttercup. Much of the humor is located in its tongue-in-cheek cheesiness. The dialogue is incredibly corny, not because the writing is poor but because it's just that clever. The actors deliver the lines perfectly and together, they all make this film laugh out loud funny. The story within a story format is great and Peter Falk's delivery of his lines is spot on. The bad guys are deliciously bad, the albino's glorious and Billy Crystal steals the show. You don't need to have seen this back in the 80s to love it. I was introduced to it in the late 90s and a friend introduced one of her mates to it just this year. He loved it. You have to approach this film in the right spirit. If you do, it's a hilarious ride. So it's not a feminist triumph. Who would expect it to be? Since when are fairy tales full of women doing it for themselves? There are actually some nice messages in the film about loyalty, love and sportsmanship but it's not designed as a commentary on human nature so stop looking for that and just enjoy the wonderful characterisation, the humor, the deliberate ridiculousness ( I mean, honing a dagger on a rounded rock -really?!) and the memorable (and highly quotable) lines. It's smarter than it looks.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Hated it.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Rachel Ashton
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I really did not see the appeal in this film - maybe it's because I first watched at the age of 19 rather than a lot younger. I didn't think there was much of a plot, and there seemed to be no relationship ever forming between the two lovers. I literally could not believe I'd wasted an hour and a half watching this alongside two friends who had grown up with it and adored it. Honestly I think I would probably have enjoyed it a lot more if I'd seen it when younger and grown up with it. Seeing it as a young adult just made me hate the whole thing and want to criticise every aspect of the film. I don't plan on ever watching it again and if you are also a first-time watcher at a later age I can't imagine you'd see what the hype about it is either.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Sexist pile of garbage
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mthessian
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Hated the Princess Bride. It is a sexist pile of garbage.. Of course the woman in the movie should wait for years in vacuous idiocy for her "True Love" to rescue her instead of actually doing anything. And when it's revealed that her "True Love" is still alive the only action she takes is attempted suicide. Very good roll model for young women. I guess it takes a woman who can actually take care of herself instead of waiting for Prince Charming to get this. I can't tell you how anti female this movie is. If you think women are just window dressing for male revenge and hero fantasies this is the flick for you. If you think women can actually think and act for themselves and not sit around forever to wait to be rescued, give this a pass.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Perfect Fit
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Maddie Anderson
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie is the all time family movie. The kids will love it, the parents will love it, everyone does! This is a great "prince" and princess story. A grandfather is telling his ill grandson a story. As he is telling the story, the characters come to life. They go through many things throughout the film, including: torture, climbing up a cliff, sword fights, hardships, battles, huge rats, and crashing the big wedding! In the end the Pirate gets the girl and they live happily ever after. The Dreaded Pirate Roberts (played by Cary Elwes)is so captivating to watch! His character is dreamy, and so funny! Princess Buttercup ( Robin Wright)is beautiful and so endearing. Inigo Montoua (Mandy Patinkin)is such a fun character to watch and listen to! This is such a fun film for the whole family to watch! This is a great sick day movie, hard day movie, and just an everyday movie! This is a very funny story that
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    As You Wish
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Tina Chan (chmpgnrose)
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I LOVE this movie from William Goldman's 1973 excellent book converted into a movie. A princess who is also a bride to be, how clever is a combination two who employees a farmhand, Westley. The handsome Westley always appease his woman with a response: "as you wish" and he reveals his love for her. This movie is every girl (no matter how old) romance. With a happy ending as narrated by a grandfather told to his very ill grandson, it depicts fantasy and the subtle ness of love. I am willing to watch this movie again and again. This movie is a classic that rivals in the silver screen with 1987's "Dirty Dancing" which both have love and romance in their respective plots.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Clever and fun fantasy film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Pihlaja
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    One of the most well-known and respected fantasy films and for a good reason. The Princess Bride is a genre-defining film that has endured the test of time beautifully and still stands as one of the best adventure films and the one film you should see if you're interested in swashbuckler films. What I like the most about this film is its unpredictability. Sure, it's an adventure film aimed for all audiences, so the good guys are going to win and all that, but the way they go about accomplishing that task is what makes this film enjoyable. You're never sure what's going to happen next, the characters are very creative and there are a lot of them, the plot twists come right out of nowhere and the humorous tongue-in-cheek tone ties it all together. There is drama and high stages, yes, but it's still an adventure film and meant to be enjoyed with a smile on your face. The story develops rather erratically, going from one scene to another with very few tie-ins, but in this case it works, because the whole film is told more like a fairy tale than a typical story. So it's more of a preference of style than a flaw. If I were to nitpick, I'd say that the frame story involving a grandfather reading his grandson a book while he lies sick in bed is not as interesting as the actual story and sometimes the kid's interruptions in the story come at the worst possible times. This is only a nitpick, however, because the banter between these two is actually quite humorous, which keeps it from becoming an annoyance. It'd be interesting to see just how well the actual adventure would flow without the frame story, just for comparison. I like this film, I like a lot. It has a strong story, it's fun and charming without being immature, its characters are great, it has a lot of memorable dialogues and as a whole it's just bursting with imagination. One of the best adventure films I've ever seen and well worth your time, whoever you happen to be.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I Am Not Left-Handed ...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ShootingShark
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    In the Kingdom of Florin, the beautiful Buttercup is heartbroken when her true love Westley is killed by pirates. Five years later, she is betrothed to Prince Humperdinck, but she does not love him. When she is abruptly kidnapped by three bandits who are then pursued by a mysterious masked man, it appears that all is not what it seems ... Some movies just seem to hit all the right notes, and The Princess Bride is one of them. It works both as a pure fairytale of love and adventure, but also as a wryly tongue-in-cheek comedy, and it has just the right balance of action, humour, romance and intrigue to suit everyone; a true family film if ever there was. The best word to describe it is delightful. With its deliberately old-fashioned tone it may not be the most original story, but it's so full of inventive scenes, crazy characters and hilarious lines that it just sweeps you away right from the start and makes you cheer for the heroes. It features a truly wonderful cast, with the then relatively unknown Elwes and Wright both great in the leads, Guest a wonderfully sneaky six-fingered villain and rib-tickling supporting roles from Shawn, Falk, Crystal and Cook. Perhaps best of all though are the unlikely pairing of Patinkin and Andr&eacute; as the desperadoes-turned-good-guy-buddies Montoya and Fezzik; Patinkin is simply perfect as the revenge-seeking swordsman and this is pretty much the only movie where you can see the late great Andr&eacute; Roussimoff, who stood seven-foot-four, was a legendary wrestler, and who gives an incredibly gentle and charming performance. I love adventure movies; I always have and I always will. Whether it's Robin Hood, Tarzan, Indiana Jones or whoever takes your fancy, cinema was made for thrills and spills, and this is a terrific example of how to do it right. It's packed with great scenes - the as-you-wish opening, Fezzik's rhymes, the dual between Westley and Montoya, the deadly game with the poisoned chalice, the Pit of Despair, Miracle Max, storming the castle ("If only we had a wheelbarrow !"), Montoya's triumph, many more. It's also one of those movies where all the technical elements are unobtrusively brilliant. This is particularly true of the charming acoustic score by Mark Knopfler (the guitarist/singer of rock band Dire Straits), but the photography, costumes and sets are all first-rate. Brilliantly written by the near-legendary Hollywood screenwriter William Goldman (Butch Cassidy And The Sundance Kid, All The President's Men), though the movie itself was funded independently and shot in England. All of Rob Reiner's movies are good, but four he made in the mid-to-late eighties - This Is Spinal Tap, Stand By Me, The Princess Bride and Misery - are all just outstanding and outstandingly different, and The Princess Bride is perhaps the best of these. Don't miss it, and if you have young children, make sure they see it too.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Whimsical and Charming
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    GouramiWatcher
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The book was long and boring, but the film was the sheer opposite. Funny and strongly written, The Princess Bride is a wonderful movie, despite its low effects. Buttercup (Robin Wright) falls in love with a poor man named Wesley (Carey Elwes) and are together until his death by the Dread Pirate Roberts. Buttercup is then engaged to Prince Humperdinck, a selfish man who wishes to start a war. She does not love him, however, because Wesley is the true owner of her heart. She is then captured by three men who claim to be circus performers but is recaptured by "The Man in Black" who turns out to be Wesley, who inherited the ship of his captor. Buttercup is later whisked away from her wedding by the two surviving kidnappers and Wesley, free to be together for the rest of their lives.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Story about a book which is really about storytelling
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Marc Israel
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Yes, there's the fairy tale double coated in delicious dialog and salacious characters played beyond the realm of silliness but it's the story of true love that conquers all and is the cohesive constant. True Love conquers all, and allows for our story to play out in this fictitious land of yore. This only happens because of the indulgent set up of our good guys and bad guys full of lore, secrets, personal histories and ambitions. Smart, worthy and yet silly. Director Rob Reiner keeps us both on track with his talented cast and in sync through the Grandfather-Grandson aside, and therefore the absurd story is not so "inconceivable". Another favorite due to its quotable dialog and characters cemented in our hearts.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The opening and the main soundtrack - brilliant!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Zaid Mansur
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    How this made it to the top 250 I do not know. If the movie was made in the 70s I would consider giving it a better rating. Im well aware that the main-focus of the movie is the story-telling and therefore it's made a bit sloppy on purpose - I hope. The movie could've been done a lot better and still maintain the good storytelling. I also think that the director could've done a better job in making the viewer feel more with the characters - make the passion more passionate, the hate and lust for revenge more hateful and lusting. The only things convincing in the movie were: The main soundtrack, a sound that gave me buttterflies during the first commence of the two main characters, and thrills in the end. Truly deserving of the Oscar that year. The character of Miracle-MAX - hilarious, his sarcasm is a warm welcome. "...and while you're at it why don't you go ahead and give a nice papercut and pour some lemonjuice on it" - best quote of the movie and made me laugh out loud And the first 6-7 minutes of the movie - brilliant!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Fabulously witty entertainment
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    nac-mac-feegle71
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I was just reading through the reviews of this while watching it again. I had to add to them, not to agree with fellow lovers but to rebut the flaws in the reviews of the haters. People are saying it's vacuous ( okay, my word not theirs) and highly flawed. They've missed the point. Clearly the special effects are deliberately bad, as is the name Buttercup. Much of the humor is located in its tongue-in-cheek cheesiness. The dialogue is incredibly corny, not because the writing is poor but because it's just that clever. The actors deliver the lines perfectly and together, they all make this film laugh out loud funny. The story within a story format is great and Peter Falk's delivery of his lines is spot on. The bad guys are deliciously bad, the albino's glorious and Billy Crystal steals the show. You don't need to have seen this back in the 80s to love it. I was introduced to it in the late 90s and a friend introduced one of her mates to it just this year. He loved it. You have to approach this film in the right spirit. If you do, it's a hilarious ride. So it's not a feminist triumph. Who would expect it to be? Since when are fairy tales full of women doing it for themselves? There are actually some nice messages in the film about loyalty, love and sportsmanship but it's not designed as a commentary on human nature so stop looking for that and just enjoy the wonderful characterisation, the humor, the deliberate ridiculousness ( I mean, honing a dagger on a rounded rock -really?!) and the memorable (and highly quotable) lines. It's smarter than it looks.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Hated it.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Rachel Ashton
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I really did not see the appeal in this film - maybe it's because I first watched at the age of 19 rather than a lot younger. I didn't think there was much of a plot, and there seemed to be no relationship ever forming between the two lovers. I literally could not believe I'd wasted an hour and a half watching this alongside two friends who had grown up with it and adored it. Honestly I think I would probably have enjoyed it a lot more if I'd seen it when younger and grown up with it. Seeing it as a young adult just made me hate the whole thing and want to criticise every aspect of the film. I don't plan on ever watching it again and if you are also a first-time watcher at a later age I can't imagine you'd see what the hype about it is either.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Sexist pile of garbage
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mthessian
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Hated the Princess Bride. It is a sexist pile of garbage.. Of course the woman in the movie should wait for years in vacuous idiocy for her "True Love" to rescue her instead of actually doing anything. And when it's revealed that her "True Love" is still alive the only action she takes is attempted suicide. Very good roll model for young women. I guess it takes a woman who can actually take care of herself instead of waiting for Prince Charming to get this. I can't tell you how anti female this movie is. If you think women are just window dressing for male revenge and hero fantasies this is the flick for you. If you think women can actually think and act for themselves and not sit around forever to wait to be rescued, give this a pass.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Perfect Fit
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Maddie Anderson
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie is the all time family movie. The kids will love it, the parents will love it, everyone does! This is a great "prince" and princess story. A grandfather is telling his ill grandson a story. As he is telling the story, the characters come to life. They go through many things throughout the film, including: torture, climbing up a cliff, sword fights, hardships, battles, huge rats, and crashing the big wedding! In the end the Pirate gets the girl and they live happily ever after. The Dreaded Pirate Roberts (played by Cary Elwes)is so captivating to watch! His character is dreamy, and so funny! Princess Buttercup ( Robin Wright)is beautiful and so endearing. Inigo Montoua (Mandy Patinkin)is such a fun character to watch and listen to! This is such a fun film for the whole family to watch! This is a great sick day movie, hard day movie, and just an everyday movie! This is a very funny story that
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    As You Wish
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Tina Chan (chmpgnrose)
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I LOVE this movie from William Goldman's 1973 excellent book converted into a movie. A princess who is also a bride to be, how clever is a combination two who employees a farmhand, Westley. The handsome Westley always appease his woman with a response: "as you wish" and he reveals his love for her. This movie is every girl (no matter how old) romance. With a happy ending as narrated by a grandfather told to his very ill grandson, it depicts fantasy and the subtle ness of love. I am willing to watch this movie again and again. This movie is a classic that rivals in the silver screen with 1987's "Dirty Dancing" which both have love and romance in their respective plots.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Clever and fun fantasy film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Pihlaja
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    One of the most well-known and respected fantasy films and for a good reason. The Princess Bride is a genre-defining film that has endured the test of time beautifully and still stands as one of the best adventure films and the one film you should see if you're interested in swashbuckler films. What I like the most about this film is its unpredictability. Sure, it's an adventure film aimed for all audiences, so the good guys are going to win and all that, but the way they go about accomplishing that task is what makes this film enjoyable. You're never sure what's going to happen next, the characters are very creative and there are a lot of them, the plot twists come right out of nowhere and the humorous tongue-in-cheek tone ties it all together. There is drama and high stages, yes, but it's still an adventure film and meant to be enjoyed with a smile on your face. The story develops rather erratically, going from one scene to another with very few tie-ins, but in this case it works, because the whole film is told more like a fairy tale than a typical story. So it's more of a preference of style than a flaw. If I were to nitpick, I'd say that the frame story involving a grandfather reading his grandson a book while he lies sick in bed is not as interesting as the actual story and sometimes the kid's interruptions in the story come at the worst possible times. This is only a nitpick, however, because the banter between these two is actually quite humorous, which keeps it from becoming an annoyance. It'd be interesting to see just how well the actual adventure would flow without the frame story, just for comparison. I like this film, I like a lot. It has a strong story, it's fun and charming without being immature, its characters are great, it has a lot of memorable dialogues and as a whole it's just bursting with imagination. One of the best adventure films I've ever seen and well worth your time, whoever you happen to be.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I Am Not Left-Handed ...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ShootingShark
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    In the Kingdom of Florin, the beautiful Buttercup is heartbroken when her true love Westley is killed by pirates. Five years later, she is betrothed to Prince Humperdinck, but she does not love him. When she is abruptly kidnapped by three bandits who are then pursued by a mysterious masked man, it appears that all is not what it seems ... Some movies just seem to hit all the right notes, and The Princess Bride is one of them. It works both as a pure fairytale of love and adventure, but also as a wryly tongue-in-cheek comedy, and it has just the right balance of action, humour, romance and intrigue to suit everyone; a true family film if ever there was. The best word to describe it is delightful. With its deliberately old-fashioned tone it may not be the most original story, but it's so full of inventive scenes, crazy characters and hilarious lines that it just sweeps you away right from the start and makes you cheer for the heroes. It features a truly wonderful cast, with the then relatively unknown Elwes and Wright both great in the leads, Guest a wonderfully sneaky six-fingered villain and rib-tickling supporting roles from Shawn, Falk, Crystal and Cook. Perhaps best of all though are the unlikely pairing of Patinkin and Andr&eacute; as the desperadoes-turned-good-guy-buddies Montoya and Fezzik; Patinkin is simply perfect as the revenge-seeking swordsman and this is pretty much the only movie where you can see the late great Andr&eacute; Roussimoff, who stood seven-foot-four, was a legendary wrestler, and who gives an incredibly gentle and charming performance. I love adventure movies; I always have and I always will. Whether it's Robin Hood, Tarzan, Indiana Jones or whoever takes your fancy, cinema was made for thrills and spills, and this is a terrific example of how to do it right. It's packed with great scenes - the as-you-wish opening, Fezzik's rhymes, the dual between Westley and Montoya, the deadly game with the poisoned chalice, the Pit of Despair, Miracle Max, storming the castle ("If only we had a wheelbarrow !"), Montoya's triumph, many more. It's also one of those movies where all the technical elements are unobtrusively brilliant. This is particularly true of the charming acoustic score by Mark Knopfler (the guitarist/singer of rock band Dire Straits), but the photography, costumes and sets are all first-rate. Brilliantly written by the near-legendary Hollywood screenwriter William Goldman (Butch Cassidy And The Sundance Kid, All The President's Men), though the movie itself was funded independently and shot in England. All of Rob Reiner's movies are good, but four he made in the mid-to-late eighties - This Is Spinal Tap, Stand By Me, The Princess Bride and Misery - are all just outstanding and outstandingly different, and The Princess Bride is perhaps the best of these. Don't miss it, and if you have young children, make sure they see it too.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Whimsical and Charming
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    GouramiWatcher
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The book was long and boring, but the film was the sheer opposite. Funny and strongly written, The Princess Bride is a wonderful movie, despite its low effects. Buttercup (Robin Wright) falls in love with a poor man named Wesley (Carey Elwes) and are together until his death by the Dread Pirate Roberts. Buttercup is then engaged to Prince Humperdinck, a selfish man who wishes to start a war. She does not love him, however, because Wesley is the true owner of her heart. She is then captured by three men who claim to be circus performers but is recaptured by "The Man in Black" who turns out to be Wesley, who inherited the ship of his captor. Buttercup is later whisked away from her wedding by the two surviving kidnappers and Wesley, free to be together for the rest of their lives.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Story about a book which is really about storytelling
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Marc Israel
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Yes, there's the fairy tale double coated in delicious dialog and salacious characters played beyond the realm of silliness but it's the story of true love that conquers all and is the cohesive constant. True Love conquers all, and allows for our story to play out in this fictitious land of yore. This only happens because of the indulgent set up of our good guys and bad guys full of lore, secrets, personal histories and ambitions. Smart, worthy and yet silly. Director Rob Reiner keeps us both on track with his talented cast and in sync through the Grandfather-Grandson aside, and therefore the absurd story is not so "inconceivable". Another favorite due to its quotable dialog and characters cemented in our hearts.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The opening and the main soundtrack - brilliant!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Zaid Mansur
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    How this made it to the top 250 I do not know. If the movie was made in the 70s I would consider giving it a better rating. Im well aware that the main-focus of the movie is the story-telling and therefore it's made a bit sloppy on purpose - I hope. The movie could've been done a lot better and still maintain the good storytelling. I also think that the director could've done a better job in making the viewer feel more with the characters - make the passion more passionate, the hate and lust for revenge more hateful and lusting. The only things convincing in the movie were: The main soundtrack, a sound that gave me buttterflies during the first commence of the two main characters, and thrills in the end. Truly deserving of the Oscar that year. The character of Miracle-MAX - hilarious, his sarcasm is a warm welcome. "...and while you're at it why don't you go ahead and give a nice papercut and pour some lemonjuice on it" - best quote of the movie and made me laugh out loud And the first 6-7 minutes of the movie - brilliant!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Fabulously witty entertainment
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    nac-mac-feegle71
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I was just reading through the reviews of this while watching it again. I had to add to them, not to agree with fellow lovers but to rebut the flaws in the reviews of the haters. People are saying it's vacuous ( okay, my word not theirs) and highly flawed. They've missed the point. Clearly the special effects are deliberately bad, as is the name Buttercup. Much of the humor is located in its tongue-in-cheek cheesiness. The dialogue is incredibly corny, not because the writing is poor but because it's just that clever. The actors deliver the lines perfectly and together, they all make this film laugh out loud funny. The story within a story format is great and Peter Falk's delivery of his lines is spot on. The bad guys are deliciously bad, the albino's glorious and Billy Crystal steals the show. You don't need to have seen this back in the 80s to love it. I was introduced to it in the late 90s and a friend introduced one of her mates to it just this year. He loved it. You have to approach this film in the right spirit. If you do, it's a hilarious ride. So it's not a feminist triumph. Who would expect it to be? Since when are fairy tales full of women doing it for themselves? There are actually some nice messages in the film about loyalty, love and sportsmanship but it's not designed as a commentary on human nature so stop looking for that and just enjoy the wonderful characterisation, the humor, the deliberate ridiculousness ( I mean, honing a dagger on a rounded rock -really?!) and the memorable (and highly quotable) lines. It's smarter than it looks.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Hated it.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Rachel Ashton
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I really did not see the appeal in this film - maybe it's because I first watched at the age of 19 rather than a lot younger. I didn't think there was much of a plot, and there seemed to be no relationship ever forming between the two lovers. I literally could not believe I'd wasted an hour and a half watching this alongside two friends who had grown up with it and adored it. Honestly I think I would probably have enjoyed it a lot more if I'd seen it when younger and grown up with it. Seeing it as a young adult just made me hate the whole thing and want to criticise every aspect of the film. I don't plan on ever watching it again and if you are also a first-time watcher at a later age I can't imagine you'd see what the hype about it is either.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Sexist pile of garbage
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mthessian
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Hated the Princess Bride. It is a sexist pile of garbage.. Of course the woman in the movie should wait for years in vacuous idiocy for her "True Love" to rescue her instead of actually doing anything. And when it's revealed that her "True Love" is still alive the only action she takes is attempted suicide. Very good roll model for young women. I guess it takes a woman who can actually take care of herself instead of waiting for Prince Charming to get this. I can't tell you how anti female this movie is. If you think women are just window dressing for male revenge and hero fantasies this is the flick for you. If you think women can actually think and act for themselves and not sit around forever to wait to be rescued, give this a pass.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Perfect Fit
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Maddie Anderson
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie is the all time family movie. The kids will love it, the parents will love it, everyone does! This is a great "prince" and princess story. A grandfather is telling his ill grandson a story. As he is telling the story, the characters come to life. They go through many things throughout the film, including: torture, climbing up a cliff, sword fights, hardships, battles, huge rats, and crashing the big wedding! In the end the Pirate gets the girl and they live happily ever after. The Dreaded Pirate Roberts (played by Cary Elwes)is so captivating to watch! His character is dreamy, and so funny! Princess Buttercup ( Robin Wright)is beautiful and so endearing. Inigo Montoua (Mandy Patinkin)is such a fun character to watch and listen to! This is such a fun film for the whole family to watch! This is a great sick day movie, hard day movie, and just an everyday movie! This is a very funny story that
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    As You Wish
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Tina Chan (chmpgnrose)
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I LOVE this movie from William Goldman's 1973 excellent book converted into a movie. A princess who is also a bride to be, how clever is a combination two who employees a farmhand, Westley. The handsome Westley always appease his woman with a response: "as you wish" and he reveals his love for her. This movie is every girl (no matter how old) romance. With a happy ending as narrated by a grandfather told to his very ill grandson, it depicts fantasy and the subtle ness of love. I am willing to watch this movie again and again. This movie is a classic that rivals in the silver screen with 1987's "Dirty Dancing" which both have love and romance in their respective plots.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Clever and fun fantasy film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Pihlaja
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    One of the most well-known and respected fantasy films and for a good reason. The Princess Bride is a genre-defining film that has endured the test of time beautifully and still stands as one of the best adventure films and the one film you should see if you're interested in swashbuckler films. What I like the most about this film is its unpredictability. Sure, it's an adventure film aimed for all audiences, so the good guys are going to win and all that, but the way they go about accomplishing that task is what makes this film enjoyable. You're never sure what's going to happen next, the characters are very creative and there are a lot of them, the plot twists come right out of nowhere and the humorous tongue-in-cheek tone ties it all together. There is drama and high stages, yes, but it's still an adventure film and meant to be enjoyed with a smile on your face. The story develops rather erratically, going from one scene to another with very few tie-ins, but in this case it works, because the whole film is told more like a fairy tale than a typical story. So it's more of a preference of style than a flaw. If I were to nitpick, I'd say that the frame story involving a grandfather reading his grandson a book while he lies sick in bed is not as interesting as the actual story and sometimes the kid's interruptions in the story come at the worst possible times. This is only a nitpick, however, because the banter between these two is actually quite humorous, which keeps it from becoming an annoyance. It'd be interesting to see just how well the actual adventure would flow without the frame story, just for comparison. I like this film, I like a lot. It has a strong story, it's fun and charming without being immature, its characters are great, it has a lot of memorable dialogues and as a whole it's just bursting with imagination. One of the best adventure films I've ever seen and well worth your time, whoever you happen to be.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I Am Not Left-Handed ...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ShootingShark
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    In the Kingdom of Florin, the beautiful Buttercup is heartbroken when her true love Westley is killed by pirates. Five years later, she is betrothed to Prince Humperdinck, but she does not love him. When she is abruptly kidnapped by three bandits who are then pursued by a mysterious masked man, it appears that all is not what it seems ... Some movies just seem to hit all the right notes, and The Princess Bride is one of them. It works both as a pure fairytale of love and adventure, but also as a wryly tongue-in-cheek comedy, and it has just the right balance of action, humour, romance and intrigue to suit everyone; a true family film if ever there was. The best word to describe it is delightful. With its deliberately old-fashioned tone it may not be the most original story, but it's so full of inventive scenes, crazy characters and hilarious lines that it just sweeps you away right from the start and makes you cheer for the heroes. It features a truly wonderful cast, with the then relatively unknown Elwes and Wright both great in the leads, Guest a wonderfully sneaky six-fingered villain and rib-tickling supporting roles from Shawn, Falk, Crystal and Cook. Perhaps best of all though are the unlikely pairing of Patinkin and Andr&eacute; as the desperadoes-turned-good-guy-buddies Montoya and Fezzik; Patinkin is simply perfect as the revenge-seeking swordsman and this is pretty much the only movie where you can see the late great Andr&eacute; Roussimoff, who stood seven-foot-four, was a legendary wrestler, and who gives an incredibly gentle and charming performance. I love adventure movies; I always have and I always will. Whether it's Robin Hood, Tarzan, Indiana Jones or whoever takes your fancy, cinema was made for thrills and spills, and this is a terrific example of how to do it right. It's packed with great scenes - the as-you-wish opening, Fezzik's rhymes, the dual between Westley and Montoya, the deadly game with the poisoned chalice, the Pit of Despair, Miracle Max, storming the castle ("If only we had a wheelbarrow !"), Montoya's triumph, many more. It's also one of those movies where all the technical elements are unobtrusively brilliant. This is particularly true of the charming acoustic score by Mark Knopfler (the guitarist/singer of rock band Dire Straits), but the photography, costumes and sets are all first-rate. Brilliantly written by the near-legendary Hollywood screenwriter William Goldman (Butch Cassidy And The Sundance Kid, All The President's Men), though the movie itself was funded independently and shot in England. All of Rob Reiner's movies are good, but four he made in the mid-to-late eighties - This Is Spinal Tap, Stand By Me, The Princess Bride and Misery - are all just outstanding and outstandingly different, and The Princess Bride is perhaps the best of these. Don't miss it, and if you have young children, make sure they see it too.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Whimsical and Charming
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    GouramiWatcher
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The book was long and boring, but the film was the sheer opposite. Funny and strongly written, The Princess Bride is a wonderful movie, despite its low effects. Buttercup (Robin Wright) falls in love with a poor man named Wesley (Carey Elwes) and are together until his death by the Dread Pirate Roberts. Buttercup is then engaged to Prince Humperdinck, a selfish man who wishes to start a war. She does not love him, however, because Wesley is the true owner of her heart. She is then captured by three men who claim to be circus performers but is recaptured by "The Man in Black" who turns out to be Wesley, who inherited the ship of his captor. Buttercup is later whisked away from her wedding by the two surviving kidnappers and Wesley, free to be together for the rest of their lives.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Story about a book which is really about storytelling
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Marc Israel
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Yes, there's the fairy tale double coated in delicious dialog and salacious characters played beyond the realm of silliness but it's the story of true love that conquers all and is the cohesive constant. True Love conquers all, and allows for our story to play out in this fictitious land of yore. This only happens because of the indulgent set up of our good guys and bad guys full of lore, secrets, personal histories and ambitions. Smart, worthy and yet silly. Director Rob Reiner keeps us both on track with his talented cast and in sync through the Grandfather-Grandson aside, and therefore the absurd story is not so "inconceivable". Another favorite due to its quotable dialog and characters cemented in our hearts.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The opening and the main soundtrack - brilliant!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Zaid Mansur
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    How this made it to the top 250 I do not know. If the movie was made in the 70s I would consider giving it a better rating. Im well aware that the main-focus of the movie is the story-telling and therefore it's made a bit sloppy on purpose - I hope. The movie could've been done a lot better and still maintain the good storytelling. I also think that the director could've done a better job in making the viewer feel more with the characters - make the passion more passionate, the hate and lust for revenge more hateful and lusting. The only things convincing in the movie were: The main soundtrack, a sound that gave me buttterflies during the first commence of the two main characters, and thrills in the end. Truly deserving of the Oscar that year. The character of Miracle-MAX - hilarious, his sarcasm is a warm welcome. "...and while you're at it why don't you go ahead and give a nice papercut and pour some lemonjuice on it" - best quote of the movie and made me laugh out loud And the first 6-7 minutes of the movie - brilliant!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Fabulously witty entertainment
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    nac-mac-feegle71
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I was just reading through the reviews of this while watching it again. I had to add to them, not to agree with fellow lovers but to rebut the flaws in the reviews of the haters. People are saying it's vacuous ( okay, my word not theirs) and highly flawed. They've missed the point. Clearly the special effects are deliberately bad, as is the name Buttercup. Much of the humor is located in its tongue-in-cheek cheesiness. The dialogue is incredibly corny, not because the writing is poor but because it's just that clever. The actors deliver the lines perfectly and together, they all make this film laugh out loud funny. The story within a story format is great and Peter Falk's delivery of his lines is spot on. The bad guys are deliciously bad, the albino's glorious and Billy Crystal steals the show. You don't need to have seen this back in the 80s to love it. I was introduced to it in the late 90s and a friend introduced one of her mates to it just this year. He loved it. You have to approach this film in the right spirit. If you do, it's a hilarious ride. So it's not a feminist triumph. Who would expect it to be? Since when are fairy tales full of women doing it for themselves? There are actually some nice messages in the film about loyalty, love and sportsmanship but it's not designed as a commentary on human nature so stop looking for that and just enjoy the wonderful characterisation, the humor, the deliberate ridiculousness ( I mean, honing a dagger on a rounded rock -really?!) and the memorable (and highly quotable) lines. It's smarter than it looks.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Hated it.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Rachel Ashton
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I really did not see the appeal in this film - maybe it's because I first watched at the age of 19 rather than a lot younger. I didn't think there was much of a plot, and there seemed to be no relationship ever forming between the two lovers. I literally could not believe I'd wasted an hour and a half watching this alongside two friends who had grown up with it and adored it. Honestly I think I would probably have enjoyed it a lot more if I'd seen it when younger and grown up with it. Seeing it as a young adult just made me hate the whole thing and want to criticise every aspect of the film. I don't plan on ever watching it again and if you are also a first-time watcher at a later age I can't imagine you'd see what the hype about it is either.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Sexist pile of garbage
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mthessian
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Hated the Princess Bride. It is a sexist pile of garbage.. Of course the woman in the movie should wait for years in vacuous idiocy for her "True Love" to rescue her instead of actually doing anything. And when it's revealed that her "True Love" is still alive the only action she takes is attempted suicide. Very good roll model for young women. I guess it takes a woman who can actually take care of herself instead of waiting for Prince Charming to get this. I can't tell you how anti female this movie is. If you think women are just window dressing for male revenge and hero fantasies this is the flick for you. If you think women can actually think and act for themselves and not sit around forever to wait to be rescued, give this a pass.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Perfect Fit
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Maddie Anderson
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie is the all time family movie. The kids will love it, the parents will love it, everyone does! This is a great "prince" and princess story. A grandfather is telling his ill grandson a story. As he is telling the story, the characters come to life. They go through many things throughout the film, including: torture, climbing up a cliff, sword fights, hardships, battles, huge rats, and crashing the big wedding! In the end the Pirate gets the girl and they live happily ever after. The Dreaded Pirate Roberts (played by Cary Elwes)is so captivating to watch! His character is dreamy, and so funny! Princess Buttercup ( Robin Wright)is beautiful and so endearing. Inigo Montoua (Mandy Patinkin)is such a fun character to watch and listen to! This is such a fun film for the whole family to watch! This is a great sick day movie, hard day movie, and just an everyday movie! This is a very funny story that
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    As You Wish
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Tina Chan (chmpgnrose)
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I LOVE this movie from William Goldman's 1973 excellent book converted into a movie. A princess who is also a bride to be, how clever is a combination two who employees a farmhand, Westley. The handsome Westley always appease his woman with a response: "as you wish" and he reveals his love for her. This movie is every girl (no matter how old) romance. With a happy ending as narrated by a grandfather told to his very ill grandson, it depicts fantasy and the subtle ness of love. I am willing to watch this movie again and again. This movie is a classic that rivals in the silver screen with 1987's "Dirty Dancing" which both have love and romance in their respective plots.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Clever and fun fantasy film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Pihlaja
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    One of the most well-known and respected fantasy films and for a good reason. The Princess Bride is a genre-defining film that has endured the test of time beautifully and still stands as one of the best adventure films and the one film you should see if you're interested in swashbuckler films. What I like the most about this film is its unpredictability. Sure, it's an adventure film aimed for all audiences, so the good guys are going to win and all that, but the way they go about accomplishing that task is what makes this film enjoyable. You're never sure what's going to happen next, the characters are very creative and there are a lot of them, the plot twists come right out of nowhere and the humorous tongue-in-cheek tone ties it all together. There is drama and high stages, yes, but it's still an adventure film and meant to be enjoyed with a smile on your face. The story develops rather erratically, going from one scene to another with very few tie-ins, but in this case it works, because the whole film is told more like a fairy tale than a typical story. So it's more of a preference of style than a flaw. If I were to nitpick, I'd say that the frame story involving a grandfather reading his grandson a book while he lies sick in bed is not as interesting as the actual story and sometimes the kid's interruptions in the story come at the worst possible times. This is only a nitpick, however, because the banter between these two is actually quite humorous, which keeps it from becoming an annoyance. It'd be interesting to see just how well the actual adventure would flow without the frame story, just for comparison. I like this film, I like a lot. It has a strong story, it's fun and charming without being immature, its characters are great, it has a lot of memorable dialogues and as a whole it's just bursting with imagination. One of the best adventure films I've ever seen and well worth your time, whoever you happen to be.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I Am Not Left-Handed ...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ShootingShark
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    In the Kingdom of Florin, the beautiful Buttercup is heartbroken when her true love Westley is killed by pirates. Five years later, she is betrothed to Prince Humperdinck, but she does not love him. When she is abruptly kidnapped by three bandits who are then pursued by a mysterious masked man, it appears that all is not what it seems ... Some movies just seem to hit all the right notes, and The Princess Bride is one of them. It works both as a pure fairytale of love and adventure, but also as a wryly tongue-in-cheek comedy, and it has just the right balance of action, humour, romance and intrigue to suit everyone; a true family film if ever there was. The best word to describe it is delightful. With its deliberately old-fashioned tone it may not be the most original story, but it's so full of inventive scenes, crazy characters and hilarious lines that it just sweeps you away right from the start and makes you cheer for the heroes. It features a truly wonderful cast, with the then relatively unknown Elwes and Wright both great in the leads, Guest a wonderfully sneaky six-fingered villain and rib-tickling supporting roles from Shawn, Falk, Crystal and Cook. Perhaps best of all though are the unlikely pairing of Patinkin and Andr&eacute; as the desperadoes-turned-good-guy-buddies Montoya and Fezzik; Patinkin is simply perfect as the revenge-seeking swordsman and this is pretty much the only movie where you can see the late great Andr&eacute; Roussimoff, who stood seven-foot-four, was a legendary wrestler, and who gives an incredibly gentle and charming performance. I love adventure movies; I always have and I always will. Whether it's Robin Hood, Tarzan, Indiana Jones or whoever takes your fancy, cinema was made for thrills and spills, and this is a terrific example of how to do it right. It's packed with great scenes - the as-you-wish opening, Fezzik's rhymes, the dual between Westley and Montoya, the deadly game with the poisoned chalice, the Pit of Despair, Miracle Max, storming the castle ("If only we had a wheelbarrow !"), Montoya's triumph, many more. It's also one of those movies where all the technical elements are unobtrusively brilliant. This is particularly true of the charming acoustic score by Mark Knopfler (the guitarist/singer of rock band Dire Straits), but the photography, costumes and sets are all first-rate. Brilliantly written by the near-legendary Hollywood screenwriter William Goldman (Butch Cassidy And The Sundance Kid, All The President's Men), though the movie itself was funded independently and shot in England. All of Rob Reiner's movies are good, but four he made in the mid-to-late eighties - This Is Spinal Tap, Stand By Me, The Princess Bride and Misery - are all just outstanding and outstandingly different, and The Princess Bride is perhaps the best of these. Don't miss it, and if you have young children, make sure they see it too.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Whimsical and Charming
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    GouramiWatcher
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The book was long and boring, but the film was the sheer opposite. Funny and strongly written, The Princess Bride is a wonderful movie, despite its low effects. Buttercup (Robin Wright) falls in love with a poor man named Wesley (Carey Elwes) and are together until his death by the Dread Pirate Roberts. Buttercup is then engaged to Prince Humperdinck, a selfish man who wishes to start a war. She does not love him, however, because Wesley is the true owner of her heart. She is then captured by three men who claim to be circus performers but is recaptured by "The Man in Black" who turns out to be Wesley, who inherited the ship of his captor. Buttercup is later whisked away from her wedding by the two surviving kidnappers and Wesley, free to be together for the rest of their lives.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Story about a book which is really about storytelling
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Marc Israel
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Yes, there's the fairy tale double coated in delicious dialog and salacious characters played beyond the realm of silliness but it's the story of true love that conquers all and is the cohesive constant. True Love conquers all, and allows for our story to play out in this fictitious land of yore. This only happens because of the indulgent set up of our good guys and bad guys full of lore, secrets, personal histories and ambitions. Smart, worthy and yet silly. Director Rob Reiner keeps us both on track with his talented cast and in sync through the Grandfather-Grandson aside, and therefore the absurd story is not so "inconceivable". Another favorite due to its quotable dialog and characters cemented in our hearts.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The opening and the main soundtrack - brilliant!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Zaid Mansur
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    How this made it to the top 250 I do not know. If the movie was made in the 70s I would consider giving it a better rating. Im well aware that the main-focus of the movie is the story-telling and therefore it's made a bit sloppy on purpose - I hope. The movie could've been done a lot better and still maintain the good storytelling. I also think that the director could've done a better job in making the viewer feel more with the characters - make the passion more passionate, the hate and lust for revenge more hateful and lusting. The only things convincing in the movie were: The main soundtrack, a sound that gave me buttterflies during the first commence of the two main characters, and thrills in the end. Truly deserving of the Oscar that year. The character of Miracle-MAX - hilarious, his sarcasm is a warm welcome. "...and while you're at it why don't you go ahead and give a nice papercut and pour some lemonjuice on it" - best quote of the movie and made me laugh out loud And the first 6-7 minutes of the movie - brilliant!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Fabulously witty entertainment
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    nac-mac-feegle71
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I was just reading through the reviews of this while watching it again. I had to add to them, not to agree with fellow lovers but to rebut the flaws in the reviews of the haters. People are saying it's vacuous ( okay, my word not theirs) and highly flawed. They've missed the point. Clearly the special effects are deliberately bad, as is the name Buttercup. Much of the humor is located in its tongue-in-cheek cheesiness. The dialogue is incredibly corny, not because the writing is poor but because it's just that clever. The actors deliver the lines perfectly and together, they all make this film laugh out loud funny. The story within a story format is great and Peter Falk's delivery of his lines is spot on. The bad guys are deliciously bad, the albino's glorious and Billy Crystal steals the show. You don't need to have seen this back in the 80s to love it. I was introduced to it in the late 90s and a friend introduced one of her mates to it just this year. He loved it. You have to approach this film in the right spirit. If you do, it's a hilarious ride. So it's not a feminist triumph. Who would expect it to be? Since when are fairy tales full of women doing it for themselves? There are actually some nice messages in the film about loyalty, love and sportsmanship but it's not designed as a commentary on human nature so stop looking for that and just enjoy the wonderful characterisation, the humor, the deliberate ridiculousness ( I mean, honing a dagger on a rounded rock -really?!) and the memorable (and highly quotable) lines. It's smarter than it looks.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Hated it.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Rachel Ashton
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I really did not see the appeal in this film - maybe it's because I first watched at the age of 19 rather than a lot younger. I didn't think there was much of a plot, and there seemed to be no relationship ever forming between the two lovers. I literally could not believe I'd wasted an hour and a half watching this alongside two friends who had grown up with it and adored it. Honestly I think I would probably have enjoyed it a lot more if I'd seen it when younger and grown up with it. Seeing it as a young adult just made me hate the whole thing and want to criticise every aspect of the film. I don't plan on ever watching it again and if you are also a first-time watcher at a later age I can't imagine you'd see what the hype about it is either.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Sexist pile of garbage
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mthessian
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Hated the Princess Bride. It is a sexist pile of garbage.. Of course the woman in the movie should wait for years in vacuous idiocy for her "True Love" to rescue her instead of actually doing anything. And when it's revealed that her "True Love" is still alive the only action she takes is attempted suicide. Very good roll model for young women. I guess it takes a woman who can actually take care of herself instead of waiting for Prince Charming to get this. I can't tell you how anti female this movie is. If you think women are just window dressing for male revenge and hero fantasies this is the flick for you. If you think women can actually think and act for themselves and not sit around forever to wait to be rescued, give this a pass.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Perfect Fit
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Maddie Anderson
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie is the all time family movie. The kids will love it, the parents will love it, everyone does! This is a great "prince" and princess story. A grandfather is telling his ill grandson a story. As he is telling the story, the characters come to life. They go through many things throughout the film, including: torture, climbing up a cliff, sword fights, hardships, battles, huge rats, and crashing the big wedding! In the end the Pirate gets the girl and they live happily ever after. The Dreaded Pirate Roberts (played by Cary Elwes)is so captivating to watch! His character is dreamy, and so funny! Princess Buttercup ( Robin Wright)is beautiful and so endearing. Inigo Montoua (Mandy Patinkin)is such a fun character to watch and listen to! This is such a fun film for the whole family to watch! This is a great sick day movie, hard day movie, and just an everyday movie! This is a very funny story that
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    As You Wish
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Tina Chan (chmpgnrose)
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I LOVE this movie from William Goldman's 1973 excellent book converted into a movie. A princess who is also a bride to be, how clever is a combination two who employees a farmhand, Westley. The handsome Westley always appease his woman with a response: "as you wish" and he reveals his love for her. This movie is every girl (no matter how old) romance. With a happy ending as narrated by a grandfather told to his very ill grandson, it depicts fantasy and the subtle ness of love. I am willing to watch this movie again and again. This movie is a classic that rivals in the silver screen with 1987's "Dirty Dancing" which both have love and romance in their respective plots.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Clever and fun fantasy film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Pihlaja
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    One of the most well-known and respected fantasy films and for a good reason. The Princess Bride is a genre-defining film that has endured the test of time beautifully and still stands as one of the best adventure films and the one film you should see if you're interested in swashbuckler films. What I like the most about this film is its unpredictability. Sure, it's an adventure film aimed for all audiences, so the good guys are going to win and all that, but the way they go about accomplishing that task is what makes this film enjoyable. You're never sure what's going to happen next, the characters are very creative and there are a lot of them, the plot twists come right out of nowhere and the humorous tongue-in-cheek tone ties it all together. There is drama and high stages, yes, but it's still an adventure film and meant to be enjoyed with a smile on your face. The story develops rather erratically, going from one scene to another with very few tie-ins, but in this case it works, because the whole film is told more like a fairy tale than a typical story. So it's more of a preference of style than a flaw. If I were to nitpick, I'd say that the frame story involving a grandfather reading his grandson a book while he lies sick in bed is not as interesting as the actual story and sometimes the kid's interruptions in the story come at the worst possible times. This is only a nitpick, however, because the banter between these two is actually quite humorous, which keeps it from becoming an annoyance. It'd be interesting to see just how well the actual adventure would flow without the frame story, just for comparison. I like this film, I like a lot. It has a strong story, it's fun and charming without being immature, its characters are great, it has a lot of memorable dialogues and as a whole it's just bursting with imagination. One of the best adventure films I've ever seen and well worth your time, whoever you happen to be.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I Am Not Left-Handed ...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ShootingShark
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    In the Kingdom of Florin, the beautiful Buttercup is heartbroken when her true love Westley is killed by pirates. Five years later, she is betrothed to Prince Humperdinck, but she does not love him. When she is abruptly kidnapped by three bandits who are then pursued by a mysterious masked man, it appears that all is not what it seems ... Some movies just seem to hit all the right notes, and The Princess Bride is one of them. It works both as a pure fairytale of love and adventure, but also as a wryly tongue-in-cheek comedy, and it has just the right balance of action, humour, romance and intrigue to suit everyone; a true family film if ever there was. The best word to describe it is delightful. With its deliberately old-fashioned tone it may not be the most original story, but it's so full of inventive scenes, crazy characters and hilarious lines that it just sweeps you away right from the start and makes you cheer for the heroes. It features a truly wonderful cast, with the then relatively unknown Elwes and Wright both great in the leads, Guest a wonderfully sneaky six-fingered villain and rib-tickling supporting roles from Shawn, Falk, Crystal and Cook. Perhaps best of all though are the unlikely pairing of Patinkin and Andr&eacute; as the desperadoes-turned-good-guy-buddies Montoya and Fezzik; Patinkin is simply perfect as the revenge-seeking swordsman and this is pretty much the only movie where you can see the late great Andr&eacute; Roussimoff, who stood seven-foot-four, was a legendary wrestler, and who gives an incredibly gentle and charming performance. I love adventure movies; I always have and I always will. Whether it's Robin Hood, Tarzan, Indiana Jones or whoever takes your fancy, cinema was made for thrills and spills, and this is a terrific example of how to do it right. It's packed with great scenes - the as-you-wish opening, Fezzik's rhymes, the dual between Westley and Montoya, the deadly game with the poisoned chalice, the Pit of Despair, Miracle Max, storming the castle ("If only we had a wheelbarrow !"), Montoya's triumph, many more. It's also one of those movies where all the technical elements are unobtrusively brilliant. This is particularly true of the charming acoustic score by Mark Knopfler (the guitarist/singer of rock band Dire Straits), but the photography, costumes and sets are all first-rate. Brilliantly written by the near-legendary Hollywood screenwriter William Goldman (Butch Cassidy And The Sundance Kid, All The President's Men), though the movie itself was funded independently and shot in England. All of Rob Reiner's movies are good, but four he made in the mid-to-late eighties - This Is Spinal Tap, Stand By Me, The Princess Bride and Misery - are all just outstanding and outstandingly different, and The Princess Bride is perhaps the best of these. Don't miss it, and if you have young children, make sure they see it too.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Whimsical and Charming
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    GouramiWatcher
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The book was long and boring, but the film was the sheer opposite. Funny and strongly written, The Princess Bride is a wonderful movie, despite its low effects. Buttercup (Robin Wright) falls in love with a poor man named Wesley (Carey Elwes) and are together until his death by the Dread Pirate Roberts. Buttercup is then engaged to Prince Humperdinck, a selfish man who wishes to start a war. She does not love him, however, because Wesley is the true owner of her heart. She is then captured by three men who claim to be circus performers but is recaptured by "The Man in Black" who turns out to be Wesley, who inherited the ship of his captor. Buttercup is later whisked away from her wedding by the two surviving kidnappers and Wesley, free to be together for the rest of their lives.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Story about a book which is really about storytelling
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Marc Israel
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Yes, there's the fairy tale double coated in delicious dialog and salacious characters played beyond the realm of silliness but it's the story of true love that conquers all and is the cohesive constant. True Love conquers all, and allows for our story to play out in this fictitious land of yore. This only happens because of the indulgent set up of our good guys and bad guys full of lore, secrets, personal histories and ambitions. Smart, worthy and yet silly. Director Rob Reiner keeps us both on track with his talented cast and in sync through the Grandfather-Grandson aside, and therefore the absurd story is not so "inconceivable". Another favorite due to its quotable dialog and characters cemented in our hearts.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The opening and the main soundtrack - brilliant!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Zaid Mansur
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    How this made it to the top 250 I do not know. If the movie was made in the 70s I would consider giving it a better rating. Im well aware that the main-focus of the movie is the story-telling and therefore it's made a bit sloppy on purpose - I hope. The movie could've been done a lot better and still maintain the good storytelling. I also think that the director could've done a better job in making the viewer feel more with the characters - make the passion more passionate, the hate and lust for revenge more hateful and lusting. The only things convincing in the movie were: The main soundtrack, a sound that gave me buttterflies during the first commence of the two main characters, and thrills in the end. Truly deserving of the Oscar that year. The character of Miracle-MAX - hilarious, his sarcasm is a warm welcome. "...and while you're at it why don't you go ahead and give a nice papercut and pour some lemonjuice on it" - best quote of the movie and made me laugh out loud And the first 6-7 minutes of the movie - brilliant!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Fabulously witty entertainment
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    nac-mac-feegle71
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I was just reading through the reviews of this while watching it again. I had to add to them, not to agree with fellow lovers but to rebut the flaws in the reviews of the haters. People are saying it's vacuous ( okay, my word not theirs) and highly flawed. They've missed the point. Clearly the special effects are deliberately bad, as is the name Buttercup. Much of the humor is located in its tongue-in-cheek cheesiness. The dialogue is incredibly corny, not because the writing is poor but because it's just that clever. The actors deliver the lines perfectly and together, they all make this film laugh out loud funny. The story within a story format is great and Peter Falk's delivery of his lines is spot on. The bad guys are deliciously bad, the albino's glorious and Billy Crystal steals the show. You don't need to have seen this back in the 80s to love it. I was introduced to it in the late 90s and a friend introduced one of her mates to it just this year. He loved it. You have to approach this film in the right spirit. If you do, it's a hilarious ride. So it's not a feminist triumph. Who would expect it to be? Since when are fairy tales full of women doing it for themselves? There are actually some nice messages in the film about loyalty, love and sportsmanship but it's not designed as a commentary on human nature so stop looking for that and just enjoy the wonderful characterisation, the humor, the deliberate ridiculousness ( I mean, honing a dagger on a rounded rock -really?!) and the memorable (and highly quotable) lines. It's smarter than it looks.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Hated it.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Rachel Ashton
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I really did not see the appeal in this film - maybe it's because I first watched at the age of 19 rather than a lot younger. I didn't think there was much of a plot, and there seemed to be no relationship ever forming between the two lovers. I literally could not believe I'd wasted an hour and a half watching this alongside two friends who had grown up with it and adored it. Honestly I think I would probably have enjoyed it a lot more if I'd seen it when younger and grown up with it. Seeing it as a young adult just made me hate the whole thing and want to criticise every aspect of the film. I don't plan on ever watching it again and if you are also a first-time watcher at a later age I can't imagine you'd see what the hype about it is either.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Sexist pile of garbage
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mthessian
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Hated the Princess Bride. It is a sexist pile of garbage.. Of course the woman in the movie should wait for years in vacuous idiocy for her "True Love" to rescue her instead of actually doing anything. And when it's revealed that her "True Love" is still alive the only action she takes is attempted suicide. Very good roll model for young women. I guess it takes a woman who can actually take care of herself instead of waiting for Prince Charming to get this. I can't tell you how anti female this movie is. If you think women are just window dressing for male revenge and hero fantasies this is the flick for you. If you think women can actually think and act for themselves and not sit around forever to wait to be rescued, give this a pass.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Perfect Fit
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Maddie Anderson
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie is the all time family movie. The kids will love it, the parents will love it, everyone does! This is a great "prince" and princess story. A grandfather is telling his ill grandson a story. As he is telling the story, the characters come to life. They go through many things throughout the film, including: torture, climbing up a cliff, sword fights, hardships, battles, huge rats, and crashing the big wedding! In the end the Pirate gets the girl and they live happily ever after. The Dreaded Pirate Roberts (played by Cary Elwes)is so captivating to watch! His character is dreamy, and so funny! Princess Buttercup ( Robin Wright)is beautiful and so endearing. Inigo Montoua (Mandy Patinkin)is such a fun character to watch and listen to! This is such a fun film for the whole family to watch! This is a great sick day movie, hard day movie, and just an everyday movie! This is a very funny story that
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    As You Wish
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Tina Chan (chmpgnrose)
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I LOVE this movie from William Goldman's 1973 excellent book converted into a movie. A princess who is also a bride to be, how clever is a combination two who employees a farmhand, Westley. The handsome Westley always appease his woman with a response: "as you wish" and he reveals his love for her. This movie is every girl (no matter how old) romance. With a happy ending as narrated by a grandfather told to his very ill grandson, it depicts fantasy and the subtle ness of love. I am willing to watch this movie again and again. This movie is a classic that rivals in the silver screen with 1987's "Dirty Dancing" which both have love and romance in their respective plots.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Clever and fun fantasy film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Pihlaja
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    One of the most well-known and respected fantasy films and for a good reason. The Princess Bride is a genre-defining film that has endured the test of time beautifully and still stands as one of the best adventure films and the one film you should see if you're interested in swashbuckler films. What I like the most about this film is its unpredictability. Sure, it's an adventure film aimed for all audiences, so the good guys are going to win and all that, but the way they go about accomplishing that task is what makes this film enjoyable. You're never sure what's going to happen next, the characters are very creative and there are a lot of them, the plot twists come right out of nowhere and the humorous tongue-in-cheek tone ties it all together. There is drama and high stages, yes, but it's still an adventure film and meant to be enjoyed with a smile on your face. The story develops rather erratically, going from one scene to another with very few tie-ins, but in this case it works, because the whole film is told more like a fairy tale than a typical story. So it's more of a preference of style than a flaw. If I were to nitpick, I'd say that the frame story involving a grandfather reading his grandson a book while he lies sick in bed is not as interesting as the actual story and sometimes the kid's interruptions in the story come at the worst possible times. This is only a nitpick, however, because the banter between these two is actually quite humorous, which keeps it from becoming an annoyance. It'd be interesting to see just how well the actual adventure would flow without the frame story, just for comparison. I like this film, I like a lot. It has a strong story, it's fun and charming without being immature, its characters are great, it has a lot of memorable dialogues and as a whole it's just bursting with imagination. One of the best adventure films I've ever seen and well worth your time, whoever you happen to be.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I Am Not Left-Handed ...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ShootingShark
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    In the Kingdom of Florin, the beautiful Buttercup is heartbroken when her true love Westley is killed by pirates. Five years later, she is betrothed to Prince Humperdinck, but she does not love him. When she is abruptly kidnapped by three bandits who are then pursued by a mysterious masked man, it appears that all is not what it seems ... Some movies just seem to hit all the right notes, and The Princess Bride is one of them. It works both as a pure fairytale of love and adventure, but also as a wryly tongue-in-cheek comedy, and it has just the right balance of action, humour, romance and intrigue to suit everyone; a true family film if ever there was. The best word to describe it is delightful. With its deliberately old-fashioned tone it may not be the most original story, but it's so full of inventive scenes, crazy characters and hilarious lines that it just sweeps you away right from the start and makes you cheer for the heroes. It features a truly wonderful cast, with the then relatively unknown Elwes and Wright both great in the leads, Guest a wonderfully sneaky six-fingered villain and rib-tickling supporting roles from Shawn, Falk, Crystal and Cook. Perhaps best of all though are the unlikely pairing of Patinkin and Andr&eacute; as the desperadoes-turned-good-guy-buddies Montoya and Fezzik; Patinkin is simply perfect as the revenge-seeking swordsman and this is pretty much the only movie where you can see the late great Andr&eacute; Roussimoff, who stood seven-foot-four, was a legendary wrestler, and who gives an incredibly gentle and charming performance. I love adventure movies; I always have and I always will. Whether it's Robin Hood, Tarzan, Indiana Jones or whoever takes your fancy, cinema was made for thrills and spills, and this is a terrific example of how to do it right. It's packed with great scenes - the as-you-wish opening, Fezzik's rhymes, the dual between Westley and Montoya, the deadly game with the poisoned chalice, the Pit of Despair, Miracle Max, storming the castle ("If only we had a wheelbarrow !"), Montoya's triumph, many more. It's also one of those movies where all the technical elements are unobtrusively brilliant. This is particularly true of the charming acoustic score by Mark Knopfler (the guitarist/singer of rock band Dire Straits), but the photography, costumes and sets are all first-rate. Brilliantly written by the near-legendary Hollywood screenwriter William Goldman (Butch Cassidy And The Sundance Kid, All The President's Men), though the movie itself was funded independently and shot in England. All of Rob Reiner's movies are good, but four he made in the mid-to-late eighties - This Is Spinal Tap, Stand By Me, The Princess Bride and Misery - are all just outstanding and outstandingly different, and The Princess Bride is perhaps the best of these. Don't miss it, and if you have young children, make sure they see it too.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Whimsical and Charming
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    GouramiWatcher
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The book was long and boring, but the film was the sheer opposite. Funny and strongly written, The Princess Bride is a wonderful movie, despite its low effects. Buttercup (Robin Wright) falls in love with a poor man named Wesley (Carey Elwes) and are together until his death by the Dread Pirate Roberts. Buttercup is then engaged to Prince Humperdinck, a selfish man who wishes to start a war. She does not love him, however, because Wesley is the true owner of her heart. She is then captured by three men who claim to be circus performers but is recaptured by "The Man in Black" who turns out to be Wesley, who inherited the ship of his captor. Buttercup is later whisked away from her wedding by the two surviving kidnappers and Wesley, free to be together for the rest of their lives.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Story about a book which is really about storytelling
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Marc Israel
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Yes, there's the fairy tale double coated in delicious dialog and salacious characters played beyond the realm of silliness but it's the story of true love that conquers all and is the cohesive constant. True Love conquers all, and allows for our story to play out in this fictitious land of yore. This only happens because of the indulgent set up of our good guys and bad guys full of lore, secrets, personal histories and ambitions. Smart, worthy and yet silly. Director Rob Reiner keeps us both on track with his talented cast and in sync through the Grandfather-Grandson aside, and therefore the absurd story is not so "inconceivable". Another favorite due to its quotable dialog and characters cemented in our hearts.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The opening and the main soundtrack - brilliant!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Zaid Mansur
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    How this made it to the top 250 I do not know. If the movie was made in the 70s I would consider giving it a better rating. Im well aware that the main-focus of the movie is the story-telling and therefore it's made a bit sloppy on purpose - I hope. The movie could've been done a lot better and still maintain the good storytelling. I also think that the director could've done a better job in making the viewer feel more with the characters - make the passion more passionate, the hate and lust for revenge more hateful and lusting. The only things convincing in the movie were: The main soundtrack, a sound that gave me buttterflies during the first commence of the two main characters, and thrills in the end. Truly deserving of the Oscar that year. The character of Miracle-MAX - hilarious, his sarcasm is a warm welcome. "...and while you're at it why don't you go ahead and give a nice papercut and pour some lemonjuice on it" - best quote of the movie and made me laugh out loud And the first 6-7 minutes of the movie - brilliant!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
 </reviews>
</filme>
