<filme>
 <id>
  175
 </id>
 <imdburl>
  http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0088846
 </imdburl>
 <ano>
  1985
 </ano>
 <titulo>
  Brazil: O Filme
 </titulo>
 <rating>
  8.0
 </rating>
 <sinopse>
  A bureaucrat in a retro-future world tries to correct an administrative error and himself becomes an enemy of the state.
 </sinopse>
 <storyline>
  Sam Lowry is a harried technocrat in a futuristic society that is needlessly convoluted and inefficient. He dreams of a life where he can fly away from technology and overpowering bureaucracy, and spend eternity with the woman of his dreams. While trying to rectify the wrongful arrest of one Harry Buttle, Lowry meets the woman he is always chasing in his dreams, Jill Layton. Meanwhile, the bureaucracy has fingered him responsible for a rash of terrorist bombings, and both Sam and Jill's lives are put in danger.
 </storyline>
 <generos>
  <genero>
   Drama
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Fantasy
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Sci-Fi
  </genero>
 </generos>
 <keywords>
  <keyword>
   terrorist
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   bureaucracy
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   dream
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   arrest
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   bureaucrat
  </keyword>
 </keywords>
 <diretores>
  <diretor>
   Terry Gilliam
  </diretor>
 </diretores>
 <escritores>
  <escritor>
   Terry Gilliam
  </escritor>
  <escritor>
   Tom Stoppard
  </escritor>
 </escritores>
 <atores>
  <ator>
   Jonathan Pryce
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Kim Greist
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Robert De Niro
  </ator>
 </atores>
 <reviews>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A rare surrealist film, the best of the Monty Python canon and off-shoots, one of the best movies I've seen
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    berynn-796-758229
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Terry Gilliam's Brazil is set in a deco-style fantasy-noir world blending kitsch fashion and bleak utilitarianism, grey ducting being the most prominent design motif. Sam Lowry (Jonathon Pryce) is a highly competent, guileless functionary in a government ministry, with a dash of charm that hints at the romanticism in his heart. As his dreams propel him away from the comfortable routine, he comes up against the bureaucracy that has hitherto sustained him. Pryce gives perhaps the best performance of his career, comic, fevered, innocent and vulnerable, occasionally suave. The character could so easily have been a typical Python caricature, but with Tom Stoppard on the writing team (with Gilliam), Pryce has a lot of scope and he takes full advantage of it, producing a remarkable performance. The surreal world of Brazil closes in on Lowry as he pursues his vision, the guts of the system spilling out when things go awry. Robert de Niro's handyman terrorist adds gravitas without reneging on the style, and Bob Hoskin's ferocious comedy lends menace to the state system. Kim Greist's portrayal of Jill Layton, Lowry's desire, is more realistic. Although it could well be argued that Greist simply didn't get the style, I found her performance a useful counterpoint. Lowry's dream girl turns out to be more real, more earthed than the world he lives in. While the theme of the film will not be novel for many viewers - it's a realization of the world that often punctures adolescent minds - Brazil evinces the brutal nexus between the passionate individual and the state/status quo through a brilliantly distorted lens that accentuates the conflict. The Pythonesque tone to the look, feel and characterizations of Brazil is taken to its finest, most filmic iteration. There are some fine allusions to classic films for movie buffs, and the design is one of the film's major talking points, but for an 18 year-old lad when I first saw it, I was riven by the inhumanity of protocol, social expectations, rules and regulations in a world dominated by bureaucracy, against the fragility of romance and hope. Similarly themed '1984' might be a more powerful film, but it is also comparatively monochromatic. I barely know how to describe the effectiveness of such an overt, theatrical design that so graphically supports the themes. It is often labeled as a satire but the film is much more than this. A febrile heart emerges from the strong stylization (akin to City of Lost Children), engaging strong feeling as much as intellectual entertainment; a rare feat, owing much to Pryce's characterization. I still remember the intense mood I felt leaving the cinema after watching this nearly 30 years ago. Though Brazil borrows heavily from various styles - film-noir, satire, absurdism, surrealism, thriller, action, romance, art film - it is unique, a masterpiece that creates its own genre. It may not be to everyone's taste, but if you have a yen for something very different from the typical blockbuster, you should absolutely positively give Brazil a try. I recommend the international version, without the last scene cut. (132 or 142 minutes). Gilliam reviled the short version, which robs the story of its poignancy, emasculating the central theme. I give the long version full marks.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An interesting mix of genres, but an uneven experience for me
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Bruno Youn
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I appreciate how Brazil encompasses several genres, being both frightening and funny on different occasions. The film had some nice visuals and I liked Terry Gilliam's vision of this dystopian future. However, I didn't find any of the characters to be so memorable or even likable so I had a tough time relating to any of them. I like the satirical tone of the story, but I thought many scenes seemed pretty goofy and cartoonish, which took me out of the film a little bit. The ending was truly great though, being quite tragic and thought-provoking. Overall, Brazil was an uneven experience for me, but certainly an interesting watch.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A very accurate vision of the modern USA
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jjccxx220
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Being an old man, I surprised myself at not having seen this when it came out. Terry Gilliam was a brilliant member of Monte Python's Flying Circus and I would have been interested in anything he did. Now, viewing it nearly thirty years after it came out, his prescience is amazing. For younger members, the Internet didn't exist for most people until the mid 1990's and personal computers wired together were not common at the time this was made. Except for the appearance of the modern world, he got it right. Today, we live in a surveillance society where we are tracked electronically wherever we are and whatever we do. American police practice the kind of assault and then ask questions more and more, as news reports will show. People are divided into the slaves and the government powers. How does a man survive in such a world? He does what our hero does - works his job, keeps his mouth shut and keeps his head down. Until he sees a vision of the woman in his fantasies in real life, and risks all to find her. Again for younger members, who never heard of the Soviet Union unless they had a rare history teacher, Gilliam's society is like what prevailed in that dictatorship. Never tell the truth except to the police, never share an opinion, never trust anyone. In modern America, we find the Soviet Union gone but its principles have traveled here, courtesy of political correctness. Tell the truth or share your opinion, and there is someone who wants to sue you. Trust the wrong person, of whom there are lots, and live to regret it. Finally, the society depicted in "Brazil" is Obama's idea of utopia. He and his crew are working hard to make it happen, and most Americans are too busy with "Survivor" and "American Idol" to know or care. This movie will be a wake-up call, if nothing else.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Just a fantastic and unforgettable experience.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    SamHarrisdrwho
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    My God, this movie gets everything right. The casting is brilliant the acting superb and the directing, MY GOD THE DIRECTING! The story dives to the very heart of bureaucracy in a terrific way. The character of Sam Lowry is one the best in cinematic history. It's beautiful to dive right into his dreams and find out what makes this character tick. But the visual effects are fantastic there is no point diving into the fantastic visuals and art direction because what hasn't been said? What can I possibly add? The soundtrack is just incredible taking one unforgettable song and making it fit the scene perfectly from being sad to scary to happy in a matter of seconds. THIS MOVIE IS WORTH YOUR TIME! If you have a Blu-Ray player, this is the perfect Blu-ray movie. Quite possibly my favorite cinematic experience.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A funny version of George Orwell's 1984
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    lukehere99
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Terry Gilliam, the only American member of Monty Python, writes and directs this comedic take on George Orwell's 1984. This is basically 1984 but much less boring and with jokes. I'll cut to the chase - Brazil is a masterpiece, reasons for this are about to be pointed out. But just if your wondering the only reason this is called Brazil is because of the song (by Geoff Muldaur) which plays every now and again in random places. The acting in Brazil is very good all round, personally I class the cast as an ensemble but some may disagree. Jonathan Pryce is the main character Sam Lowry who I have always thought is a lot like Arthur Dent from The Hitchhikers Guide To The Galaxy. Robert De Niro is the rebel against society Harry Tuttle and is the most likable character in the movie. Bob Hoskins and Derrick O'Connor are 2 comedic ventilation repair men who come to a very amusing sticky end. Michael Palin (also a member of Monty Python) is Sam's old friend in a surprisingly serious, but very well performed, role. Ian Holm (was he never young) is Sam's boss and friend, Jim Broadbent a creep plastic surgeon nicknamed "the acid man". And finally Kim Greist as Sam's one true love and alleged terrorist. All of these roles are brilliant, funny, well acted and memorable. Brazil possibly has the best plot and story of any movie I have ever seen, even if most of the source material is taken from (the extremely depressing) George Orwell's 1984. Everything is unexpected and definitely not predictable, even the love scenes are unique. terry Gilliam (the director) is of course in the hilarious Monty Python team, who are in my opinion the funniest comedy group ever, so you would expect Brazil to be extremely funny. Unfortunately it's not EXTREMELY funny, I laughed on many occasions but not as much as I would have liked to. But then again how can a movie based on 1984 be that hilarious? Finally the ending - in my opinion Brazil has the best and most effective ending of any movie ever. This is a spoiler free review so I won't reveal what happens, but I will say that it's a surprise and certainly not expected. Overall I will give Brazil 9.0/10 and 4.5 stars, because the humour is not as strong as I expected it to be.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    the stuff of dreams
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    (gsygsy)
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Nothing can fully prepare you for BRAZIL. Maybe it's Cervantes' DON QUIXOTE as dreamed by Franz Kafka then written up by Lawrence Sterne. But that doesn't do justice to Terry Gilliam's cinematic bravura. Gilliam is an extravagant director. His work teems with stuff. He is, in this respect, comparable to Baz Lurhmann, and the comparison is instructive. Lurhmann's work feels confined by his stories, as if he's trying to escape them through visuals. Gilliam's films feel more satisfying, at least to me, because the images ARE the story. This isn't to the taste of every moviegoer, I'm sure, but, if you surrender to it, you'll be taken on a roller-coaster ride: thrilling, scary, exhausting, something you say you never want repeat as you join the queue to do it all over again. It is a dystopian tale, and to that extent has a seriousness of purpose that some might think gets lost beneath the extravagance of what's on screen, but I don't share that view. Gilliam's imagination yields a poetic dreamscape which by-passes rationality. It's an environment that makes the dystopia all the more vivid. Savoring the performances is one way of digesting this rich dish. Playing the discontented hero, Sam Lowry, is Jonathan Pryce, a renowned British stage actor. His is a curious presence, without much charm, but undoubtedly charismatic. A quartet of principal relationships stem from his character: his vain mother, played by wonderful Katherine Helmond; the object of his desire, played flatly but efficiently by Kim Griest; his non-conformist alter-ego played by a brilliantly-cast Robert De Nero, strangely but effectively out of step with everyone else's acting style; and, as Sam's conformist antagonist, Michael Palin, charming and chilling in equal measure. Surrounding this central quintet is an unequalled collection of British character actors, some on screen for merely a few seconds, providing Gilliam with an entirely believable world of eccentrics. Those flashing by include Ann Way, Harold Innocent, John Grillo, Oscar Quitak and Ralph Nossek. In slightly larger roles come Jim Broadbent, Bryan Pringle, Gordon Kaye, Bob Hoskins and (dazzling) Ian Richardson. In fully-fledged support are Barbara Hicks, superb Kathryn Pogson, Ian Holm, Peter Vaughan and, giving heart to the only realistic role in the entire movie, the great Sheila Reid. The production design is amazing, the photography superb, and the editing, which must have been quite a challenge, is a masterclass in tact.The score is a bravura achievement by Michael Kamen, who inventively mutates the old song that gives the film its title. The story is pretty straightforward, even if the telling of it is anything but. The dialogue is peppered with memorable exchanges. There are outstanding set-pieces of comic business. Over and above everything is the imagery. The stuff of dreams, occasionally of nightmares. Helmond's smiling face stretched out to breaking point by Broadbent; De Niro engulfed by flying paper; Holm turned into a speaking pavement; Pryce battling with a faceless giant Samurai; a ghastly dinner at an exploding restaurant; the haunting final shot... BRAZIL is an extraordinary cinematic experience.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of the worst movies I have ever seen
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Dejan K
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I don't understand why this movie is rated so highly. The visuals are good, but that's about it. I almost fell asleep halfway through. Add a predictable storyline and you get an absolute snooze fest. This is the movie to watch if you ever have a hard time falling asleep. Highly recommended for anyone with a sleeping disorder. Brazil will get the job done better than pills. The storyline is mediocre and the "absurdity" in the film is irritating rather than imaginative. I didn't get the film at all. Nothing holds the film together, the ending is predictable (I predicted how it was going to end 30 minutes into the movie), and I feel I wasted two hours of my life that I'm never going to get back. Thanks Brazil.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Puzzling adulation
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    colinfeltham
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I've just watched this for the first time (making my way through the UK Top 100). I wanted to like it but found it just didn't make the impact on me its reviews suggested it would. It's a cross between 1984 and Monty Python, but full of corny, dated (unfunny) humour and slapstick antics. The story is trite - I mean, many of us hate bureaucracy and think it overshadows too much of our lives (I do) but that's not a big enough point to keep anyone's interest for 148 minutes. I liked the music, I got the allusions to other films, but despite the acclaimed surrealism here, I wasn't engaged. I am frankly amazed by the level of its critical acclaim - there are far better films. The 1980s version of 1984 is better in its grimness, for example.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Visually and philosophically, it succeeds. As a movie, it's pretentious and all over the place
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    JavikKatarn
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I'm a big fan of Terry Gilliam's work. His comedic work in Monty Python and many of his feature films including Time Bandits and Twelve Monkeys are classics. Brazil is often regarded as his best work and an artistic masterpiece of merging ideas and symbolism and black humour. Like most cinematic classics, I thought I would enjoy the film. However, the film was overall a dreaded bore with a narrative that was all over the place, two-dimensional characters and an overlong climax albeit a film with some compelling ideas and a nice take on Orwell's 1984. The story of Brazil takes place in the far future where Britain has become a totalitarian fascist state. Sam Lowry is a low-level government employee who constantly dreams of saving a woman. One day, he has to correct an error where a man named Archibald Buttle was imprisoned by the government and killed during an interrogation for being suspected of terrorism when he got confused for Archibald Tuttle due to a fly being jammed in the printer (okay, that's quite funny). He notices that the next door neighbour of the Buttles, Jill Layton, has the same face of the woman in his dreams. When Jill is branded as a terrorist after trying to report the mistake of the man's death. Sam then tries to get a transfer to information retrieval to learn more about Jill. The ideas that Brazil gives out are fundamentally not bad themes. Some if it is taken from 1984 but I liked how Gilliam tried to merge them with a comedic element to them and make an argument about the dangers of the errors bureaucracies make. The art direction in this movie is also pretty impressive. The visuals are a bit dated now (it's clearly got the 80s feel to it) but back then they would've been spectacular. A lot of Fritz Lang's Metropolis is present in them. There are also a few funny and amusing moments in the film but the term 'comedy' doesn't hold much water here for me. Roger Ebert was one of the few critics who disliked Brazil, calling it 'hard to follow', I couldn't put it better myself. The main story to the film shouldn't be much of a pain to understand but most of the film revolves around things just happening. There's no clear focus in the film as to what Gilliam wants to tell, just showing a bunch of random stuff occurring and barely getting explanation. This makes the film come across as a complete bore and hard to sit through even on repeated viewings. I get that the film is meant to be sporadic and a bit peculiar in its approach but I still think it's a real nuisance when you have too much on screen and keep throwing constant crap at you without allowing you to comprehend what is being shown. I also cannot buy the romance between Sam and Jill. When the two properly meet the first time, he randomly tells her that he loves her and that he sees her in his dreams. Seriously, who says that to somebody they've just encountered? The two lack chemistry and the romance is only introduced at the end of the second act, making it come across as rushed and murky. I will give credit to the climax for trying to be shocking in its treatment and is a classic example of a funny 'f@&k you' ending. Brazil has some unique ideas, innovative art direction and even a few moments where the comedy works but is overall a shallow and unfocused film that lacks any heart and coherence. It's already become regarded as a classic and I suppose its unfocused narrative has become appreciated by its fans but it failed to get me sucked in and is a depressing experience overall.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Probably one of my favourite movies ever!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    pepsicolasmileyface
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Brazil is that movie where you either love it or hate it, you either think its stupid or that its mind blowing. Well I loved it, This movie completely blew my mind away. This movie looks stunning, the city and the cinematography probably strike me the most. This movie is original and no one can say that it's not an original movie. All the performances were pretty good. In the end though it's the message in the end that matters is about modern life. It shows how people make things so complicated to make things easier and how bureaucracy is sort of destroying us. It shows us the story of a guy bored of his life and then this big change happens to him and his life suddenly becomes interesting after he sees this woman of his dreams at his job. It shows a world torn apart with ridiculous ways of life and then this spark of hope with this man drowning in all of his life. This movie probably has one of my favourite endings when in his mind he's escaped but in the end he's in a chair half dead. Another thing is that every time you watch this film there's always something new to see and these are the reasons why I love this movie.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A rare surrealist film, the best of the Monty Python canon and off-shoots, one of the best movies I've seen
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    berynn-796-758229
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Terry Gilliam's Brazil is set in a deco-style fantasy-noir world blending kitsch fashion and bleak utilitarianism, grey ducting being the most prominent design motif. Sam Lowry (Jonathon Pryce) is a highly competent, guileless functionary in a government ministry, with a dash of charm that hints at the romanticism in his heart. As his dreams propel him away from the comfortable routine, he comes up against the bureaucracy that has hitherto sustained him. Pryce gives perhaps the best performance of his career, comic, fevered, innocent and vulnerable, occasionally suave. The character could so easily have been a typical Python caricature, but with Tom Stoppard on the writing team (with Gilliam), Pryce has a lot of scope and he takes full advantage of it, producing a remarkable performance. The surreal world of Brazil closes in on Lowry as he pursues his vision, the guts of the system spilling out when things go awry. Robert de Niro's handyman terrorist adds gravitas without reneging on the style, and Bob Hoskin's ferocious comedy lends menace to the state system. Kim Greist's portrayal of Jill Layton, Lowry's desire, is more realistic. Although it could well be argued that Greist simply didn't get the style, I found her performance a useful counterpoint. Lowry's dream girl turns out to be more real, more earthed than the world he lives in. While the theme of the film will not be novel for many viewers - it's a realization of the world that often punctures adolescent minds - Brazil evinces the brutal nexus between the passionate individual and the state/status quo through a brilliantly distorted lens that accentuates the conflict. The Pythonesque tone to the look, feel and characterizations of Brazil is taken to its finest, most filmic iteration. There are some fine allusions to classic films for movie buffs, and the design is one of the film's major talking points, but for an 18 year-old lad when I first saw it, I was riven by the inhumanity of protocol, social expectations, rules and regulations in a world dominated by bureaucracy, against the fragility of romance and hope. Similarly themed '1984' might be a more powerful film, but it is also comparatively monochromatic. I barely know how to describe the effectiveness of such an overt, theatrical design that so graphically supports the themes. It is often labeled as a satire but the film is much more than this. A febrile heart emerges from the strong stylization (akin to City of Lost Children), engaging strong feeling as much as intellectual entertainment; a rare feat, owing much to Pryce's characterization. I still remember the intense mood I felt leaving the cinema after watching this nearly 30 years ago. Though Brazil borrows heavily from various styles - film-noir, satire, absurdism, surrealism, thriller, action, romance, art film - it is unique, a masterpiece that creates its own genre. It may not be to everyone's taste, but if you have a yen for something very different from the typical blockbuster, you should absolutely positively give Brazil a try. I recommend the international version, without the last scene cut. (132 or 142 minutes). Gilliam reviled the short version, which robs the story of its poignancy, emasculating the central theme. I give the long version full marks.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An interesting mix of genres, but an uneven experience for me
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Bruno Youn
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I appreciate how Brazil encompasses several genres, being both frightening and funny on different occasions. The film had some nice visuals and I liked Terry Gilliam's vision of this dystopian future. However, I didn't find any of the characters to be so memorable or even likable so I had a tough time relating to any of them. I like the satirical tone of the story, but I thought many scenes seemed pretty goofy and cartoonish, which took me out of the film a little bit. The ending was truly great though, being quite tragic and thought-provoking. Overall, Brazil was an uneven experience for me, but certainly an interesting watch.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A very accurate vision of the modern USA
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jjccxx220
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Being an old man, I surprised myself at not having seen this when it came out. Terry Gilliam was a brilliant member of Monte Python's Flying Circus and I would have been interested in anything he did. Now, viewing it nearly thirty years after it came out, his prescience is amazing. For younger members, the Internet didn't exist for most people until the mid 1990's and personal computers wired together were not common at the time this was made. Except for the appearance of the modern world, he got it right. Today, we live in a surveillance society where we are tracked electronically wherever we are and whatever we do. American police practice the kind of assault and then ask questions more and more, as news reports will show. People are divided into the slaves and the government powers. How does a man survive in such a world? He does what our hero does - works his job, keeps his mouth shut and keeps his head down. Until he sees a vision of the woman in his fantasies in real life, and risks all to find her. Again for younger members, who never heard of the Soviet Union unless they had a rare history teacher, Gilliam's society is like what prevailed in that dictatorship. Never tell the truth except to the police, never share an opinion, never trust anyone. In modern America, we find the Soviet Union gone but its principles have traveled here, courtesy of political correctness. Tell the truth or share your opinion, and there is someone who wants to sue you. Trust the wrong person, of whom there are lots, and live to regret it. Finally, the society depicted in "Brazil" is Obama's idea of utopia. He and his crew are working hard to make it happen, and most Americans are too busy with "Survivor" and "American Idol" to know or care. This movie will be a wake-up call, if nothing else.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Just a fantastic and unforgettable experience.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    SamHarrisdrwho
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    My God, this movie gets everything right. The casting is brilliant the acting superb and the directing, MY GOD THE DIRECTING! The story dives to the very heart of bureaucracy in a terrific way. The character of Sam Lowry is one the best in cinematic history. It's beautiful to dive right into his dreams and find out what makes this character tick. But the visual effects are fantastic there is no point diving into the fantastic visuals and art direction because what hasn't been said? What can I possibly add? The soundtrack is just incredible taking one unforgettable song and making it fit the scene perfectly from being sad to scary to happy in a matter of seconds. THIS MOVIE IS WORTH YOUR TIME! If you have a Blu-Ray player, this is the perfect Blu-ray movie. Quite possibly my favorite cinematic experience.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A funny version of George Orwell's 1984
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    lukehere99
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Terry Gilliam, the only American member of Monty Python, writes and directs this comedic take on George Orwell's 1984. This is basically 1984 but much less boring and with jokes. I'll cut to the chase - Brazil is a masterpiece, reasons for this are about to be pointed out. But just if your wondering the only reason this is called Brazil is because of the song (by Geoff Muldaur) which plays every now and again in random places. The acting in Brazil is very good all round, personally I class the cast as an ensemble but some may disagree. Jonathan Pryce is the main character Sam Lowry who I have always thought is a lot like Arthur Dent from The Hitchhikers Guide To The Galaxy. Robert De Niro is the rebel against society Harry Tuttle and is the most likable character in the movie. Bob Hoskins and Derrick O'Connor are 2 comedic ventilation repair men who come to a very amusing sticky end. Michael Palin (also a member of Monty Python) is Sam's old friend in a surprisingly serious, but very well performed, role. Ian Holm (was he never young) is Sam's boss and friend, Jim Broadbent a creep plastic surgeon nicknamed "the acid man". And finally Kim Greist as Sam's one true love and alleged terrorist. All of these roles are brilliant, funny, well acted and memorable. Brazil possibly has the best plot and story of any movie I have ever seen, even if most of the source material is taken from (the extremely depressing) George Orwell's 1984. Everything is unexpected and definitely not predictable, even the love scenes are unique. terry Gilliam (the director) is of course in the hilarious Monty Python team, who are in my opinion the funniest comedy group ever, so you would expect Brazil to be extremely funny. Unfortunately it's not EXTREMELY funny, I laughed on many occasions but not as much as I would have liked to. But then again how can a movie based on 1984 be that hilarious? Finally the ending - in my opinion Brazil has the best and most effective ending of any movie ever. This is a spoiler free review so I won't reveal what happens, but I will say that it's a surprise and certainly not expected. Overall I will give Brazil 9.0/10 and 4.5 stars, because the humour is not as strong as I expected it to be.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    the stuff of dreams
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    (gsygsy)
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Nothing can fully prepare you for BRAZIL. Maybe it's Cervantes' DON QUIXOTE as dreamed by Franz Kafka then written up by Lawrence Sterne. But that doesn't do justice to Terry Gilliam's cinematic bravura. Gilliam is an extravagant director. His work teems with stuff. He is, in this respect, comparable to Baz Lurhmann, and the comparison is instructive. Lurhmann's work feels confined by his stories, as if he's trying to escape them through visuals. Gilliam's films feel more satisfying, at least to me, because the images ARE the story. This isn't to the taste of every moviegoer, I'm sure, but, if you surrender to it, you'll be taken on a roller-coaster ride: thrilling, scary, exhausting, something you say you never want repeat as you join the queue to do it all over again. It is a dystopian tale, and to that extent has a seriousness of purpose that some might think gets lost beneath the extravagance of what's on screen, but I don't share that view. Gilliam's imagination yields a poetic dreamscape which by-passes rationality. It's an environment that makes the dystopia all the more vivid. Savoring the performances is one way of digesting this rich dish. Playing the discontented hero, Sam Lowry, is Jonathan Pryce, a renowned British stage actor. His is a curious presence, without much charm, but undoubtedly charismatic. A quartet of principal relationships stem from his character: his vain mother, played by wonderful Katherine Helmond; the object of his desire, played flatly but efficiently by Kim Griest; his non-conformist alter-ego played by a brilliantly-cast Robert De Nero, strangely but effectively out of step with everyone else's acting style; and, as Sam's conformist antagonist, Michael Palin, charming and chilling in equal measure. Surrounding this central quintet is an unequalled collection of British character actors, some on screen for merely a few seconds, providing Gilliam with an entirely believable world of eccentrics. Those flashing by include Ann Way, Harold Innocent, John Grillo, Oscar Quitak and Ralph Nossek. In slightly larger roles come Jim Broadbent, Bryan Pringle, Gordon Kaye, Bob Hoskins and (dazzling) Ian Richardson. In fully-fledged support are Barbara Hicks, superb Kathryn Pogson, Ian Holm, Peter Vaughan and, giving heart to the only realistic role in the entire movie, the great Sheila Reid. The production design is amazing, the photography superb, and the editing, which must have been quite a challenge, is a masterclass in tact.The score is a bravura achievement by Michael Kamen, who inventively mutates the old song that gives the film its title. The story is pretty straightforward, even if the telling of it is anything but. The dialogue is peppered with memorable exchanges. There are outstanding set-pieces of comic business. Over and above everything is the imagery. The stuff of dreams, occasionally of nightmares. Helmond's smiling face stretched out to breaking point by Broadbent; De Niro engulfed by flying paper; Holm turned into a speaking pavement; Pryce battling with a faceless giant Samurai; a ghastly dinner at an exploding restaurant; the haunting final shot... BRAZIL is an extraordinary cinematic experience.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of the worst movies I have ever seen
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Dejan K
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I don't understand why this movie is rated so highly. The visuals are good, but that's about it. I almost fell asleep halfway through. Add a predictable storyline and you get an absolute snooze fest. This is the movie to watch if you ever have a hard time falling asleep. Highly recommended for anyone with a sleeping disorder. Brazil will get the job done better than pills. The storyline is mediocre and the "absurdity" in the film is irritating rather than imaginative. I didn't get the film at all. Nothing holds the film together, the ending is predictable (I predicted how it was going to end 30 minutes into the movie), and I feel I wasted two hours of my life that I'm never going to get back. Thanks Brazil.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Puzzling adulation
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    colinfeltham
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I've just watched this for the first time (making my way through the UK Top 100). I wanted to like it but found it just didn't make the impact on me its reviews suggested it would. It's a cross between 1984 and Monty Python, but full of corny, dated (unfunny) humour and slapstick antics. The story is trite - I mean, many of us hate bureaucracy and think it overshadows too much of our lives (I do) but that's not a big enough point to keep anyone's interest for 148 minutes. I liked the music, I got the allusions to other films, but despite the acclaimed surrealism here, I wasn't engaged. I am frankly amazed by the level of its critical acclaim - there are far better films. The 1980s version of 1984 is better in its grimness, for example.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Visually and philosophically, it succeeds. As a movie, it's pretentious and all over the place
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    JavikKatarn
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I'm a big fan of Terry Gilliam's work. His comedic work in Monty Python and many of his feature films including Time Bandits and Twelve Monkeys are classics. Brazil is often regarded as his best work and an artistic masterpiece of merging ideas and symbolism and black humour. Like most cinematic classics, I thought I would enjoy the film. However, the film was overall a dreaded bore with a narrative that was all over the place, two-dimensional characters and an overlong climax albeit a film with some compelling ideas and a nice take on Orwell's 1984. The story of Brazil takes place in the far future where Britain has become a totalitarian fascist state. Sam Lowry is a low-level government employee who constantly dreams of saving a woman. One day, he has to correct an error where a man named Archibald Buttle was imprisoned by the government and killed during an interrogation for being suspected of terrorism when he got confused for Archibald Tuttle due to a fly being jammed in the printer (okay, that's quite funny). He notices that the next door neighbour of the Buttles, Jill Layton, has the same face of the woman in his dreams. When Jill is branded as a terrorist after trying to report the mistake of the man's death. Sam then tries to get a transfer to information retrieval to learn more about Jill. The ideas that Brazil gives out are fundamentally not bad themes. Some if it is taken from 1984 but I liked how Gilliam tried to merge them with a comedic element to them and make an argument about the dangers of the errors bureaucracies make. The art direction in this movie is also pretty impressive. The visuals are a bit dated now (it's clearly got the 80s feel to it) but back then they would've been spectacular. A lot of Fritz Lang's Metropolis is present in them. There are also a few funny and amusing moments in the film but the term 'comedy' doesn't hold much water here for me. Roger Ebert was one of the few critics who disliked Brazil, calling it 'hard to follow', I couldn't put it better myself. The main story to the film shouldn't be much of a pain to understand but most of the film revolves around things just happening. There's no clear focus in the film as to what Gilliam wants to tell, just showing a bunch of random stuff occurring and barely getting explanation. This makes the film come across as a complete bore and hard to sit through even on repeated viewings. I get that the film is meant to be sporadic and a bit peculiar in its approach but I still think it's a real nuisance when you have too much on screen and keep throwing constant crap at you without allowing you to comprehend what is being shown. I also cannot buy the romance between Sam and Jill. When the two properly meet the first time, he randomly tells her that he loves her and that he sees her in his dreams. Seriously, who says that to somebody they've just encountered? The two lack chemistry and the romance is only introduced at the end of the second act, making it come across as rushed and murky. I will give credit to the climax for trying to be shocking in its treatment and is a classic example of a funny 'f@&k you' ending. Brazil has some unique ideas, innovative art direction and even a few moments where the comedy works but is overall a shallow and unfocused film that lacks any heart and coherence. It's already become regarded as a classic and I suppose its unfocused narrative has become appreciated by its fans but it failed to get me sucked in and is a depressing experience overall.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Probably one of my favourite movies ever!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    pepsicolasmileyface
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Brazil is that movie where you either love it or hate it, you either think its stupid or that its mind blowing. Well I loved it, This movie completely blew my mind away. This movie looks stunning, the city and the cinematography probably strike me the most. This movie is original and no one can say that it's not an original movie. All the performances were pretty good. In the end though it's the message in the end that matters is about modern life. It shows how people make things so complicated to make things easier and how bureaucracy is sort of destroying us. It shows us the story of a guy bored of his life and then this big change happens to him and his life suddenly becomes interesting after he sees this woman of his dreams at his job. It shows a world torn apart with ridiculous ways of life and then this spark of hope with this man drowning in all of his life. This movie probably has one of my favourite endings when in his mind he's escaped but in the end he's in a chair half dead. Another thing is that every time you watch this film there's always something new to see and these are the reasons why I love this movie.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A rare surrealist film, the best of the Monty Python canon and off-shoots, one of the best movies I've seen
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    berynn-796-758229
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Terry Gilliam's Brazil is set in a deco-style fantasy-noir world blending kitsch fashion and bleak utilitarianism, grey ducting being the most prominent design motif. Sam Lowry (Jonathon Pryce) is a highly competent, guileless functionary in a government ministry, with a dash of charm that hints at the romanticism in his heart. As his dreams propel him away from the comfortable routine, he comes up against the bureaucracy that has hitherto sustained him. Pryce gives perhaps the best performance of his career, comic, fevered, innocent and vulnerable, occasionally suave. The character could so easily have been a typical Python caricature, but with Tom Stoppard on the writing team (with Gilliam), Pryce has a lot of scope and he takes full advantage of it, producing a remarkable performance. The surreal world of Brazil closes in on Lowry as he pursues his vision, the guts of the system spilling out when things go awry. Robert de Niro's handyman terrorist adds gravitas without reneging on the style, and Bob Hoskin's ferocious comedy lends menace to the state system. Kim Greist's portrayal of Jill Layton, Lowry's desire, is more realistic. Although it could well be argued that Greist simply didn't get the style, I found her performance a useful counterpoint. Lowry's dream girl turns out to be more real, more earthed than the world he lives in. While the theme of the film will not be novel for many viewers - it's a realization of the world that often punctures adolescent minds - Brazil evinces the brutal nexus between the passionate individual and the state/status quo through a brilliantly distorted lens that accentuates the conflict. The Pythonesque tone to the look, feel and characterizations of Brazil is taken to its finest, most filmic iteration. There are some fine allusions to classic films for movie buffs, and the design is one of the film's major talking points, but for an 18 year-old lad when I first saw it, I was riven by the inhumanity of protocol, social expectations, rules and regulations in a world dominated by bureaucracy, against the fragility of romance and hope. Similarly themed '1984' might be a more powerful film, but it is also comparatively monochromatic. I barely know how to describe the effectiveness of such an overt, theatrical design that so graphically supports the themes. It is often labeled as a satire but the film is much more than this. A febrile heart emerges from the strong stylization (akin to City of Lost Children), engaging strong feeling as much as intellectual entertainment; a rare feat, owing much to Pryce's characterization. I still remember the intense mood I felt leaving the cinema after watching this nearly 30 years ago. Though Brazil borrows heavily from various styles - film-noir, satire, absurdism, surrealism, thriller, action, romance, art film - it is unique, a masterpiece that creates its own genre. It may not be to everyone's taste, but if you have a yen for something very different from the typical blockbuster, you should absolutely positively give Brazil a try. I recommend the international version, without the last scene cut. (132 or 142 minutes). Gilliam reviled the short version, which robs the story of its poignancy, emasculating the central theme. I give the long version full marks.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An interesting mix of genres, but an uneven experience for me
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Bruno Youn
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I appreciate how Brazil encompasses several genres, being both frightening and funny on different occasions. The film had some nice visuals and I liked Terry Gilliam's vision of this dystopian future. However, I didn't find any of the characters to be so memorable or even likable so I had a tough time relating to any of them. I like the satirical tone of the story, but I thought many scenes seemed pretty goofy and cartoonish, which took me out of the film a little bit. The ending was truly great though, being quite tragic and thought-provoking. Overall, Brazil was an uneven experience for me, but certainly an interesting watch.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A very accurate vision of the modern USA
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jjccxx220
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Being an old man, I surprised myself at not having seen this when it came out. Terry Gilliam was a brilliant member of Monte Python's Flying Circus and I would have been interested in anything he did. Now, viewing it nearly thirty years after it came out, his prescience is amazing. For younger members, the Internet didn't exist for most people until the mid 1990's and personal computers wired together were not common at the time this was made. Except for the appearance of the modern world, he got it right. Today, we live in a surveillance society where we are tracked electronically wherever we are and whatever we do. American police practice the kind of assault and then ask questions more and more, as news reports will show. People are divided into the slaves and the government powers. How does a man survive in such a world? He does what our hero does - works his job, keeps his mouth shut and keeps his head down. Until he sees a vision of the woman in his fantasies in real life, and risks all to find her. Again for younger members, who never heard of the Soviet Union unless they had a rare history teacher, Gilliam's society is like what prevailed in that dictatorship. Never tell the truth except to the police, never share an opinion, never trust anyone. In modern America, we find the Soviet Union gone but its principles have traveled here, courtesy of political correctness. Tell the truth or share your opinion, and there is someone who wants to sue you. Trust the wrong person, of whom there are lots, and live to regret it. Finally, the society depicted in "Brazil" is Obama's idea of utopia. He and his crew are working hard to make it happen, and most Americans are too busy with "Survivor" and "American Idol" to know or care. This movie will be a wake-up call, if nothing else.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Just a fantastic and unforgettable experience.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    SamHarrisdrwho
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    My God, this movie gets everything right. The casting is brilliant the acting superb and the directing, MY GOD THE DIRECTING! The story dives to the very heart of bureaucracy in a terrific way. The character of Sam Lowry is one the best in cinematic history. It's beautiful to dive right into his dreams and find out what makes this character tick. But the visual effects are fantastic there is no point diving into the fantastic visuals and art direction because what hasn't been said? What can I possibly add? The soundtrack is just incredible taking one unforgettable song and making it fit the scene perfectly from being sad to scary to happy in a matter of seconds. THIS MOVIE IS WORTH YOUR TIME! If you have a Blu-Ray player, this is the perfect Blu-ray movie. Quite possibly my favorite cinematic experience.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A funny version of George Orwell's 1984
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    lukehere99
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Terry Gilliam, the only American member of Monty Python, writes and directs this comedic take on George Orwell's 1984. This is basically 1984 but much less boring and with jokes. I'll cut to the chase - Brazil is a masterpiece, reasons for this are about to be pointed out. But just if your wondering the only reason this is called Brazil is because of the song (by Geoff Muldaur) which plays every now and again in random places. The acting in Brazil is very good all round, personally I class the cast as an ensemble but some may disagree. Jonathan Pryce is the main character Sam Lowry who I have always thought is a lot like Arthur Dent from The Hitchhikers Guide To The Galaxy. Robert De Niro is the rebel against society Harry Tuttle and is the most likable character in the movie. Bob Hoskins and Derrick O'Connor are 2 comedic ventilation repair men who come to a very amusing sticky end. Michael Palin (also a member of Monty Python) is Sam's old friend in a surprisingly serious, but very well performed, role. Ian Holm (was he never young) is Sam's boss and friend, Jim Broadbent a creep plastic surgeon nicknamed "the acid man". And finally Kim Greist as Sam's one true love and alleged terrorist. All of these roles are brilliant, funny, well acted and memorable. Brazil possibly has the best plot and story of any movie I have ever seen, even if most of the source material is taken from (the extremely depressing) George Orwell's 1984. Everything is unexpected and definitely not predictable, even the love scenes are unique. terry Gilliam (the director) is of course in the hilarious Monty Python team, who are in my opinion the funniest comedy group ever, so you would expect Brazil to be extremely funny. Unfortunately it's not EXTREMELY funny, I laughed on many occasions but not as much as I would have liked to. But then again how can a movie based on 1984 be that hilarious? Finally the ending - in my opinion Brazil has the best and most effective ending of any movie ever. This is a spoiler free review so I won't reveal what happens, but I will say that it's a surprise and certainly not expected. Overall I will give Brazil 9.0/10 and 4.5 stars, because the humour is not as strong as I expected it to be.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    the stuff of dreams
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    (gsygsy)
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Nothing can fully prepare you for BRAZIL. Maybe it's Cervantes' DON QUIXOTE as dreamed by Franz Kafka then written up by Lawrence Sterne. But that doesn't do justice to Terry Gilliam's cinematic bravura. Gilliam is an extravagant director. His work teems with stuff. He is, in this respect, comparable to Baz Lurhmann, and the comparison is instructive. Lurhmann's work feels confined by his stories, as if he's trying to escape them through visuals. Gilliam's films feel more satisfying, at least to me, because the images ARE the story. This isn't to the taste of every moviegoer, I'm sure, but, if you surrender to it, you'll be taken on a roller-coaster ride: thrilling, scary, exhausting, something you say you never want repeat as you join the queue to do it all over again. It is a dystopian tale, and to that extent has a seriousness of purpose that some might think gets lost beneath the extravagance of what's on screen, but I don't share that view. Gilliam's imagination yields a poetic dreamscape which by-passes rationality. It's an environment that makes the dystopia all the more vivid. Savoring the performances is one way of digesting this rich dish. Playing the discontented hero, Sam Lowry, is Jonathan Pryce, a renowned British stage actor. His is a curious presence, without much charm, but undoubtedly charismatic. A quartet of principal relationships stem from his character: his vain mother, played by wonderful Katherine Helmond; the object of his desire, played flatly but efficiently by Kim Griest; his non-conformist alter-ego played by a brilliantly-cast Robert De Nero, strangely but effectively out of step with everyone else's acting style; and, as Sam's conformist antagonist, Michael Palin, charming and chilling in equal measure. Surrounding this central quintet is an unequalled collection of British character actors, some on screen for merely a few seconds, providing Gilliam with an entirely believable world of eccentrics. Those flashing by include Ann Way, Harold Innocent, John Grillo, Oscar Quitak and Ralph Nossek. In slightly larger roles come Jim Broadbent, Bryan Pringle, Gordon Kaye, Bob Hoskins and (dazzling) Ian Richardson. In fully-fledged support are Barbara Hicks, superb Kathryn Pogson, Ian Holm, Peter Vaughan and, giving heart to the only realistic role in the entire movie, the great Sheila Reid. The production design is amazing, the photography superb, and the editing, which must have been quite a challenge, is a masterclass in tact.The score is a bravura achievement by Michael Kamen, who inventively mutates the old song that gives the film its title. The story is pretty straightforward, even if the telling of it is anything but. The dialogue is peppered with memorable exchanges. There are outstanding set-pieces of comic business. Over and above everything is the imagery. The stuff of dreams, occasionally of nightmares. Helmond's smiling face stretched out to breaking point by Broadbent; De Niro engulfed by flying paper; Holm turned into a speaking pavement; Pryce battling with a faceless giant Samurai; a ghastly dinner at an exploding restaurant; the haunting final shot... BRAZIL is an extraordinary cinematic experience.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of the worst movies I have ever seen
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Dejan K
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I don't understand why this movie is rated so highly. The visuals are good, but that's about it. I almost fell asleep halfway through. Add a predictable storyline and you get an absolute snooze fest. This is the movie to watch if you ever have a hard time falling asleep. Highly recommended for anyone with a sleeping disorder. Brazil will get the job done better than pills. The storyline is mediocre and the "absurdity" in the film is irritating rather than imaginative. I didn't get the film at all. Nothing holds the film together, the ending is predictable (I predicted how it was going to end 30 minutes into the movie), and I feel I wasted two hours of my life that I'm never going to get back. Thanks Brazil.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Puzzling adulation
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    colinfeltham
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I've just watched this for the first time (making my way through the UK Top 100). I wanted to like it but found it just didn't make the impact on me its reviews suggested it would. It's a cross between 1984 and Monty Python, but full of corny, dated (unfunny) humour and slapstick antics. The story is trite - I mean, many of us hate bureaucracy and think it overshadows too much of our lives (I do) but that's not a big enough point to keep anyone's interest for 148 minutes. I liked the music, I got the allusions to other films, but despite the acclaimed surrealism here, I wasn't engaged. I am frankly amazed by the level of its critical acclaim - there are far better films. The 1980s version of 1984 is better in its grimness, for example.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Visually and philosophically, it succeeds. As a movie, it's pretentious and all over the place
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    JavikKatarn
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I'm a big fan of Terry Gilliam's work. His comedic work in Monty Python and many of his feature films including Time Bandits and Twelve Monkeys are classics. Brazil is often regarded as his best work and an artistic masterpiece of merging ideas and symbolism and black humour. Like most cinematic classics, I thought I would enjoy the film. However, the film was overall a dreaded bore with a narrative that was all over the place, two-dimensional characters and an overlong climax albeit a film with some compelling ideas and a nice take on Orwell's 1984. The story of Brazil takes place in the far future where Britain has become a totalitarian fascist state. Sam Lowry is a low-level government employee who constantly dreams of saving a woman. One day, he has to correct an error where a man named Archibald Buttle was imprisoned by the government and killed during an interrogation for being suspected of terrorism when he got confused for Archibald Tuttle due to a fly being jammed in the printer (okay, that's quite funny). He notices that the next door neighbour of the Buttles, Jill Layton, has the same face of the woman in his dreams. When Jill is branded as a terrorist after trying to report the mistake of the man's death. Sam then tries to get a transfer to information retrieval to learn more about Jill. The ideas that Brazil gives out are fundamentally not bad themes. Some if it is taken from 1984 but I liked how Gilliam tried to merge them with a comedic element to them and make an argument about the dangers of the errors bureaucracies make. The art direction in this movie is also pretty impressive. The visuals are a bit dated now (it's clearly got the 80s feel to it) but back then they would've been spectacular. A lot of Fritz Lang's Metropolis is present in them. There are also a few funny and amusing moments in the film but the term 'comedy' doesn't hold much water here for me. Roger Ebert was one of the few critics who disliked Brazil, calling it 'hard to follow', I couldn't put it better myself. The main story to the film shouldn't be much of a pain to understand but most of the film revolves around things just happening. There's no clear focus in the film as to what Gilliam wants to tell, just showing a bunch of random stuff occurring and barely getting explanation. This makes the film come across as a complete bore and hard to sit through even on repeated viewings. I get that the film is meant to be sporadic and a bit peculiar in its approach but I still think it's a real nuisance when you have too much on screen and keep throwing constant crap at you without allowing you to comprehend what is being shown. I also cannot buy the romance between Sam and Jill. When the two properly meet the first time, he randomly tells her that he loves her and that he sees her in his dreams. Seriously, who says that to somebody they've just encountered? The two lack chemistry and the romance is only introduced at the end of the second act, making it come across as rushed and murky. I will give credit to the climax for trying to be shocking in its treatment and is a classic example of a funny 'f@&k you' ending. Brazil has some unique ideas, innovative art direction and even a few moments where the comedy works but is overall a shallow and unfocused film that lacks any heart and coherence. It's already become regarded as a classic and I suppose its unfocused narrative has become appreciated by its fans but it failed to get me sucked in and is a depressing experience overall.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Probably one of my favourite movies ever!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    pepsicolasmileyface
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Brazil is that movie where you either love it or hate it, you either think its stupid or that its mind blowing. Well I loved it, This movie completely blew my mind away. This movie looks stunning, the city and the cinematography probably strike me the most. This movie is original and no one can say that it's not an original movie. All the performances were pretty good. In the end though it's the message in the end that matters is about modern life. It shows how people make things so complicated to make things easier and how bureaucracy is sort of destroying us. It shows us the story of a guy bored of his life and then this big change happens to him and his life suddenly becomes interesting after he sees this woman of his dreams at his job. It shows a world torn apart with ridiculous ways of life and then this spark of hope with this man drowning in all of his life. This movie probably has one of my favourite endings when in his mind he's escaped but in the end he's in a chair half dead. Another thing is that every time you watch this film there's always something new to see and these are the reasons why I love this movie.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A rare surrealist film, the best of the Monty Python canon and off-shoots, one of the best movies I've seen
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    berynn-796-758229
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Terry Gilliam's Brazil is set in a deco-style fantasy-noir world blending kitsch fashion and bleak utilitarianism, grey ducting being the most prominent design motif. Sam Lowry (Jonathon Pryce) is a highly competent, guileless functionary in a government ministry, with a dash of charm that hints at the romanticism in his heart. As his dreams propel him away from the comfortable routine, he comes up against the bureaucracy that has hitherto sustained him. Pryce gives perhaps the best performance of his career, comic, fevered, innocent and vulnerable, occasionally suave. The character could so easily have been a typical Python caricature, but with Tom Stoppard on the writing team (with Gilliam), Pryce has a lot of scope and he takes full advantage of it, producing a remarkable performance. The surreal world of Brazil closes in on Lowry as he pursues his vision, the guts of the system spilling out when things go awry. Robert de Niro's handyman terrorist adds gravitas without reneging on the style, and Bob Hoskin's ferocious comedy lends menace to the state system. Kim Greist's portrayal of Jill Layton, Lowry's desire, is more realistic. Although it could well be argued that Greist simply didn't get the style, I found her performance a useful counterpoint. Lowry's dream girl turns out to be more real, more earthed than the world he lives in. While the theme of the film will not be novel for many viewers - it's a realization of the world that often punctures adolescent minds - Brazil evinces the brutal nexus between the passionate individual and the state/status quo through a brilliantly distorted lens that accentuates the conflict. The Pythonesque tone to the look, feel and characterizations of Brazil is taken to its finest, most filmic iteration. There are some fine allusions to classic films for movie buffs, and the design is one of the film's major talking points, but for an 18 year-old lad when I first saw it, I was riven by the inhumanity of protocol, social expectations, rules and regulations in a world dominated by bureaucracy, against the fragility of romance and hope. Similarly themed '1984' might be a more powerful film, but it is also comparatively monochromatic. I barely know how to describe the effectiveness of such an overt, theatrical design that so graphically supports the themes. It is often labeled as a satire but the film is much more than this. A febrile heart emerges from the strong stylization (akin to City of Lost Children), engaging strong feeling as much as intellectual entertainment; a rare feat, owing much to Pryce's characterization. I still remember the intense mood I felt leaving the cinema after watching this nearly 30 years ago. Though Brazil borrows heavily from various styles - film-noir, satire, absurdism, surrealism, thriller, action, romance, art film - it is unique, a masterpiece that creates its own genre. It may not be to everyone's taste, but if you have a yen for something very different from the typical blockbuster, you should absolutely positively give Brazil a try. I recommend the international version, without the last scene cut. (132 or 142 minutes). Gilliam reviled the short version, which robs the story of its poignancy, emasculating the central theme. I give the long version full marks.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An interesting mix of genres, but an uneven experience for me
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Bruno Youn
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I appreciate how Brazil encompasses several genres, being both frightening and funny on different occasions. The film had some nice visuals and I liked Terry Gilliam's vision of this dystopian future. However, I didn't find any of the characters to be so memorable or even likable so I had a tough time relating to any of them. I like the satirical tone of the story, but I thought many scenes seemed pretty goofy and cartoonish, which took me out of the film a little bit. The ending was truly great though, being quite tragic and thought-provoking. Overall, Brazil was an uneven experience for me, but certainly an interesting watch.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A very accurate vision of the modern USA
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jjccxx220
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Being an old man, I surprised myself at not having seen this when it came out. Terry Gilliam was a brilliant member of Monte Python's Flying Circus and I would have been interested in anything he did. Now, viewing it nearly thirty years after it came out, his prescience is amazing. For younger members, the Internet didn't exist for most people until the mid 1990's and personal computers wired together were not common at the time this was made. Except for the appearance of the modern world, he got it right. Today, we live in a surveillance society where we are tracked electronically wherever we are and whatever we do. American police practice the kind of assault and then ask questions more and more, as news reports will show. People are divided into the slaves and the government powers. How does a man survive in such a world? He does what our hero does - works his job, keeps his mouth shut and keeps his head down. Until he sees a vision of the woman in his fantasies in real life, and risks all to find her. Again for younger members, who never heard of the Soviet Union unless they had a rare history teacher, Gilliam's society is like what prevailed in that dictatorship. Never tell the truth except to the police, never share an opinion, never trust anyone. In modern America, we find the Soviet Union gone but its principles have traveled here, courtesy of political correctness. Tell the truth or share your opinion, and there is someone who wants to sue you. Trust the wrong person, of whom there are lots, and live to regret it. Finally, the society depicted in "Brazil" is Obama's idea of utopia. He and his crew are working hard to make it happen, and most Americans are too busy with "Survivor" and "American Idol" to know or care. This movie will be a wake-up call, if nothing else.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Just a fantastic and unforgettable experience.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    SamHarrisdrwho
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    My God, this movie gets everything right. The casting is brilliant the acting superb and the directing, MY GOD THE DIRECTING! The story dives to the very heart of bureaucracy in a terrific way. The character of Sam Lowry is one the best in cinematic history. It's beautiful to dive right into his dreams and find out what makes this character tick. But the visual effects are fantastic there is no point diving into the fantastic visuals and art direction because what hasn't been said? What can I possibly add? The soundtrack is just incredible taking one unforgettable song and making it fit the scene perfectly from being sad to scary to happy in a matter of seconds. THIS MOVIE IS WORTH YOUR TIME! If you have a Blu-Ray player, this is the perfect Blu-ray movie. Quite possibly my favorite cinematic experience.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A funny version of George Orwell's 1984
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    lukehere99
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Terry Gilliam, the only American member of Monty Python, writes and directs this comedic take on George Orwell's 1984. This is basically 1984 but much less boring and with jokes. I'll cut to the chase - Brazil is a masterpiece, reasons for this are about to be pointed out. But just if your wondering the only reason this is called Brazil is because of the song (by Geoff Muldaur) which plays every now and again in random places. The acting in Brazil is very good all round, personally I class the cast as an ensemble but some may disagree. Jonathan Pryce is the main character Sam Lowry who I have always thought is a lot like Arthur Dent from The Hitchhikers Guide To The Galaxy. Robert De Niro is the rebel against society Harry Tuttle and is the most likable character in the movie. Bob Hoskins and Derrick O'Connor are 2 comedic ventilation repair men who come to a very amusing sticky end. Michael Palin (also a member of Monty Python) is Sam's old friend in a surprisingly serious, but very well performed, role. Ian Holm (was he never young) is Sam's boss and friend, Jim Broadbent a creep plastic surgeon nicknamed "the acid man". And finally Kim Greist as Sam's one true love and alleged terrorist. All of these roles are brilliant, funny, well acted and memorable. Brazil possibly has the best plot and story of any movie I have ever seen, even if most of the source material is taken from (the extremely depressing) George Orwell's 1984. Everything is unexpected and definitely not predictable, even the love scenes are unique. terry Gilliam (the director) is of course in the hilarious Monty Python team, who are in my opinion the funniest comedy group ever, so you would expect Brazil to be extremely funny. Unfortunately it's not EXTREMELY funny, I laughed on many occasions but not as much as I would have liked to. But then again how can a movie based on 1984 be that hilarious? Finally the ending - in my opinion Brazil has the best and most effective ending of any movie ever. This is a spoiler free review so I won't reveal what happens, but I will say that it's a surprise and certainly not expected. Overall I will give Brazil 9.0/10 and 4.5 stars, because the humour is not as strong as I expected it to be.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    the stuff of dreams
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    (gsygsy)
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Nothing can fully prepare you for BRAZIL. Maybe it's Cervantes' DON QUIXOTE as dreamed by Franz Kafka then written up by Lawrence Sterne. But that doesn't do justice to Terry Gilliam's cinematic bravura. Gilliam is an extravagant director. His work teems with stuff. He is, in this respect, comparable to Baz Lurhmann, and the comparison is instructive. Lurhmann's work feels confined by his stories, as if he's trying to escape them through visuals. Gilliam's films feel more satisfying, at least to me, because the images ARE the story. This isn't to the taste of every moviegoer, I'm sure, but, if you surrender to it, you'll be taken on a roller-coaster ride: thrilling, scary, exhausting, something you say you never want repeat as you join the queue to do it all over again. It is a dystopian tale, and to that extent has a seriousness of purpose that some might think gets lost beneath the extravagance of what's on screen, but I don't share that view. Gilliam's imagination yields a poetic dreamscape which by-passes rationality. It's an environment that makes the dystopia all the more vivid. Savoring the performances is one way of digesting this rich dish. Playing the discontented hero, Sam Lowry, is Jonathan Pryce, a renowned British stage actor. His is a curious presence, without much charm, but undoubtedly charismatic. A quartet of principal relationships stem from his character: his vain mother, played by wonderful Katherine Helmond; the object of his desire, played flatly but efficiently by Kim Griest; his non-conformist alter-ego played by a brilliantly-cast Robert De Nero, strangely but effectively out of step with everyone else's acting style; and, as Sam's conformist antagonist, Michael Palin, charming and chilling in equal measure. Surrounding this central quintet is an unequalled collection of British character actors, some on screen for merely a few seconds, providing Gilliam with an entirely believable world of eccentrics. Those flashing by include Ann Way, Harold Innocent, John Grillo, Oscar Quitak and Ralph Nossek. In slightly larger roles come Jim Broadbent, Bryan Pringle, Gordon Kaye, Bob Hoskins and (dazzling) Ian Richardson. In fully-fledged support are Barbara Hicks, superb Kathryn Pogson, Ian Holm, Peter Vaughan and, giving heart to the only realistic role in the entire movie, the great Sheila Reid. The production design is amazing, the photography superb, and the editing, which must have been quite a challenge, is a masterclass in tact.The score is a bravura achievement by Michael Kamen, who inventively mutates the old song that gives the film its title. The story is pretty straightforward, even if the telling of it is anything but. The dialogue is peppered with memorable exchanges. There are outstanding set-pieces of comic business. Over and above everything is the imagery. The stuff of dreams, occasionally of nightmares. Helmond's smiling face stretched out to breaking point by Broadbent; De Niro engulfed by flying paper; Holm turned into a speaking pavement; Pryce battling with a faceless giant Samurai; a ghastly dinner at an exploding restaurant; the haunting final shot... BRAZIL is an extraordinary cinematic experience.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of the worst movies I have ever seen
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Dejan K
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I don't understand why this movie is rated so highly. The visuals are good, but that's about it. I almost fell asleep halfway through. Add a predictable storyline and you get an absolute snooze fest. This is the movie to watch if you ever have a hard time falling asleep. Highly recommended for anyone with a sleeping disorder. Brazil will get the job done better than pills. The storyline is mediocre and the "absurdity" in the film is irritating rather than imaginative. I didn't get the film at all. Nothing holds the film together, the ending is predictable (I predicted how it was going to end 30 minutes into the movie), and I feel I wasted two hours of my life that I'm never going to get back. Thanks Brazil.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Puzzling adulation
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    colinfeltham
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I've just watched this for the first time (making my way through the UK Top 100). I wanted to like it but found it just didn't make the impact on me its reviews suggested it would. It's a cross between 1984 and Monty Python, but full of corny, dated (unfunny) humour and slapstick antics. The story is trite - I mean, many of us hate bureaucracy and think it overshadows too much of our lives (I do) but that's not a big enough point to keep anyone's interest for 148 minutes. I liked the music, I got the allusions to other films, but despite the acclaimed surrealism here, I wasn't engaged. I am frankly amazed by the level of its critical acclaim - there are far better films. The 1980s version of 1984 is better in its grimness, for example.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Visually and philosophically, it succeeds. As a movie, it's pretentious and all over the place
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    JavikKatarn
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I'm a big fan of Terry Gilliam's work. His comedic work in Monty Python and many of his feature films including Time Bandits and Twelve Monkeys are classics. Brazil is often regarded as his best work and an artistic masterpiece of merging ideas and symbolism and black humour. Like most cinematic classics, I thought I would enjoy the film. However, the film was overall a dreaded bore with a narrative that was all over the place, two-dimensional characters and an overlong climax albeit a film with some compelling ideas and a nice take on Orwell's 1984. The story of Brazil takes place in the far future where Britain has become a totalitarian fascist state. Sam Lowry is a low-level government employee who constantly dreams of saving a woman. One day, he has to correct an error where a man named Archibald Buttle was imprisoned by the government and killed during an interrogation for being suspected of terrorism when he got confused for Archibald Tuttle due to a fly being jammed in the printer (okay, that's quite funny). He notices that the next door neighbour of the Buttles, Jill Layton, has the same face of the woman in his dreams. When Jill is branded as a terrorist after trying to report the mistake of the man's death. Sam then tries to get a transfer to information retrieval to learn more about Jill. The ideas that Brazil gives out are fundamentally not bad themes. Some if it is taken from 1984 but I liked how Gilliam tried to merge them with a comedic element to them and make an argument about the dangers of the errors bureaucracies make. The art direction in this movie is also pretty impressive. The visuals are a bit dated now (it's clearly got the 80s feel to it) but back then they would've been spectacular. A lot of Fritz Lang's Metropolis is present in them. There are also a few funny and amusing moments in the film but the term 'comedy' doesn't hold much water here for me. Roger Ebert was one of the few critics who disliked Brazil, calling it 'hard to follow', I couldn't put it better myself. The main story to the film shouldn't be much of a pain to understand but most of the film revolves around things just happening. There's no clear focus in the film as to what Gilliam wants to tell, just showing a bunch of random stuff occurring and barely getting explanation. This makes the film come across as a complete bore and hard to sit through even on repeated viewings. I get that the film is meant to be sporadic and a bit peculiar in its approach but I still think it's a real nuisance when you have too much on screen and keep throwing constant crap at you without allowing you to comprehend what is being shown. I also cannot buy the romance between Sam and Jill. When the two properly meet the first time, he randomly tells her that he loves her and that he sees her in his dreams. Seriously, who says that to somebody they've just encountered? The two lack chemistry and the romance is only introduced at the end of the second act, making it come across as rushed and murky. I will give credit to the climax for trying to be shocking in its treatment and is a classic example of a funny 'f@&k you' ending. Brazil has some unique ideas, innovative art direction and even a few moments where the comedy works but is overall a shallow and unfocused film that lacks any heart and coherence. It's already become regarded as a classic and I suppose its unfocused narrative has become appreciated by its fans but it failed to get me sucked in and is a depressing experience overall.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Probably one of my favourite movies ever!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    pepsicolasmileyface
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Brazil is that movie where you either love it or hate it, you either think its stupid or that its mind blowing. Well I loved it, This movie completely blew my mind away. This movie looks stunning, the city and the cinematography probably strike me the most. This movie is original and no one can say that it's not an original movie. All the performances were pretty good. In the end though it's the message in the end that matters is about modern life. It shows how people make things so complicated to make things easier and how bureaucracy is sort of destroying us. It shows us the story of a guy bored of his life and then this big change happens to him and his life suddenly becomes interesting after he sees this woman of his dreams at his job. It shows a world torn apart with ridiculous ways of life and then this spark of hope with this man drowning in all of his life. This movie probably has one of my favourite endings when in his mind he's escaped but in the end he's in a chair half dead. Another thing is that every time you watch this film there's always something new to see and these are the reasons why I love this movie.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A rare surrealist film, the best of the Monty Python canon and off-shoots, one of the best movies I've seen
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    berynn-796-758229
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Terry Gilliam's Brazil is set in a deco-style fantasy-noir world blending kitsch fashion and bleak utilitarianism, grey ducting being the most prominent design motif. Sam Lowry (Jonathon Pryce) is a highly competent, guileless functionary in a government ministry, with a dash of charm that hints at the romanticism in his heart. As his dreams propel him away from the comfortable routine, he comes up against the bureaucracy that has hitherto sustained him. Pryce gives perhaps the best performance of his career, comic, fevered, innocent and vulnerable, occasionally suave. The character could so easily have been a typical Python caricature, but with Tom Stoppard on the writing team (with Gilliam), Pryce has a lot of scope and he takes full advantage of it, producing a remarkable performance. The surreal world of Brazil closes in on Lowry as he pursues his vision, the guts of the system spilling out when things go awry. Robert de Niro's handyman terrorist adds gravitas without reneging on the style, and Bob Hoskin's ferocious comedy lends menace to the state system. Kim Greist's portrayal of Jill Layton, Lowry's desire, is more realistic. Although it could well be argued that Greist simply didn't get the style, I found her performance a useful counterpoint. Lowry's dream girl turns out to be more real, more earthed than the world he lives in. While the theme of the film will not be novel for many viewers - it's a realization of the world that often punctures adolescent minds - Brazil evinces the brutal nexus between the passionate individual and the state/status quo through a brilliantly distorted lens that accentuates the conflict. The Pythonesque tone to the look, feel and characterizations of Brazil is taken to its finest, most filmic iteration. There are some fine allusions to classic films for movie buffs, and the design is one of the film's major talking points, but for an 18 year-old lad when I first saw it, I was riven by the inhumanity of protocol, social expectations, rules and regulations in a world dominated by bureaucracy, against the fragility of romance and hope. Similarly themed '1984' might be a more powerful film, but it is also comparatively monochromatic. I barely know how to describe the effectiveness of such an overt, theatrical design that so graphically supports the themes. It is often labeled as a satire but the film is much more than this. A febrile heart emerges from the strong stylization (akin to City of Lost Children), engaging strong feeling as much as intellectual entertainment; a rare feat, owing much to Pryce's characterization. I still remember the intense mood I felt leaving the cinema after watching this nearly 30 years ago. Though Brazil borrows heavily from various styles - film-noir, satire, absurdism, surrealism, thriller, action, romance, art film - it is unique, a masterpiece that creates its own genre. It may not be to everyone's taste, but if you have a yen for something very different from the typical blockbuster, you should absolutely positively give Brazil a try. I recommend the international version, without the last scene cut. (132 or 142 minutes). Gilliam reviled the short version, which robs the story of its poignancy, emasculating the central theme. I give the long version full marks.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An interesting mix of genres, but an uneven experience for me
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Bruno Youn
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I appreciate how Brazil encompasses several genres, being both frightening and funny on different occasions. The film had some nice visuals and I liked Terry Gilliam's vision of this dystopian future. However, I didn't find any of the characters to be so memorable or even likable so I had a tough time relating to any of them. I like the satirical tone of the story, but I thought many scenes seemed pretty goofy and cartoonish, which took me out of the film a little bit. The ending was truly great though, being quite tragic and thought-provoking. Overall, Brazil was an uneven experience for me, but certainly an interesting watch.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A very accurate vision of the modern USA
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jjccxx220
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Being an old man, I surprised myself at not having seen this when it came out. Terry Gilliam was a brilliant member of Monte Python's Flying Circus and I would have been interested in anything he did. Now, viewing it nearly thirty years after it came out, his prescience is amazing. For younger members, the Internet didn't exist for most people until the mid 1990's and personal computers wired together were not common at the time this was made. Except for the appearance of the modern world, he got it right. Today, we live in a surveillance society where we are tracked electronically wherever we are and whatever we do. American police practice the kind of assault and then ask questions more and more, as news reports will show. People are divided into the slaves and the government powers. How does a man survive in such a world? He does what our hero does - works his job, keeps his mouth shut and keeps his head down. Until he sees a vision of the woman in his fantasies in real life, and risks all to find her. Again for younger members, who never heard of the Soviet Union unless they had a rare history teacher, Gilliam's society is like what prevailed in that dictatorship. Never tell the truth except to the police, never share an opinion, never trust anyone. In modern America, we find the Soviet Union gone but its principles have traveled here, courtesy of political correctness. Tell the truth or share your opinion, and there is someone who wants to sue you. Trust the wrong person, of whom there are lots, and live to regret it. Finally, the society depicted in "Brazil" is Obama's idea of utopia. He and his crew are working hard to make it happen, and most Americans are too busy with "Survivor" and "American Idol" to know or care. This movie will be a wake-up call, if nothing else.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Just a fantastic and unforgettable experience.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    SamHarrisdrwho
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    My God, this movie gets everything right. The casting is brilliant the acting superb and the directing, MY GOD THE DIRECTING! The story dives to the very heart of bureaucracy in a terrific way. The character of Sam Lowry is one the best in cinematic history. It's beautiful to dive right into his dreams and find out what makes this character tick. But the visual effects are fantastic there is no point diving into the fantastic visuals and art direction because what hasn't been said? What can I possibly add? The soundtrack is just incredible taking one unforgettable song and making it fit the scene perfectly from being sad to scary to happy in a matter of seconds. THIS MOVIE IS WORTH YOUR TIME! If you have a Blu-Ray player, this is the perfect Blu-ray movie. Quite possibly my favorite cinematic experience.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A funny version of George Orwell's 1984
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    lukehere99
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Terry Gilliam, the only American member of Monty Python, writes and directs this comedic take on George Orwell's 1984. This is basically 1984 but much less boring and with jokes. I'll cut to the chase - Brazil is a masterpiece, reasons for this are about to be pointed out. But just if your wondering the only reason this is called Brazil is because of the song (by Geoff Muldaur) which plays every now and again in random places. The acting in Brazil is very good all round, personally I class the cast as an ensemble but some may disagree. Jonathan Pryce is the main character Sam Lowry who I have always thought is a lot like Arthur Dent from The Hitchhikers Guide To The Galaxy. Robert De Niro is the rebel against society Harry Tuttle and is the most likable character in the movie. Bob Hoskins and Derrick O'Connor are 2 comedic ventilation repair men who come to a very amusing sticky end. Michael Palin (also a member of Monty Python) is Sam's old friend in a surprisingly serious, but very well performed, role. Ian Holm (was he never young) is Sam's boss and friend, Jim Broadbent a creep plastic surgeon nicknamed "the acid man". And finally Kim Greist as Sam's one true love and alleged terrorist. All of these roles are brilliant, funny, well acted and memorable. Brazil possibly has the best plot and story of any movie I have ever seen, even if most of the source material is taken from (the extremely depressing) George Orwell's 1984. Everything is unexpected and definitely not predictable, even the love scenes are unique. terry Gilliam (the director) is of course in the hilarious Monty Python team, who are in my opinion the funniest comedy group ever, so you would expect Brazil to be extremely funny. Unfortunately it's not EXTREMELY funny, I laughed on many occasions but not as much as I would have liked to. But then again how can a movie based on 1984 be that hilarious? Finally the ending - in my opinion Brazil has the best and most effective ending of any movie ever. This is a spoiler free review so I won't reveal what happens, but I will say that it's a surprise and certainly not expected. Overall I will give Brazil 9.0/10 and 4.5 stars, because the humour is not as strong as I expected it to be.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    the stuff of dreams
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    (gsygsy)
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Nothing can fully prepare you for BRAZIL. Maybe it's Cervantes' DON QUIXOTE as dreamed by Franz Kafka then written up by Lawrence Sterne. But that doesn't do justice to Terry Gilliam's cinematic bravura. Gilliam is an extravagant director. His work teems with stuff. He is, in this respect, comparable to Baz Lurhmann, and the comparison is instructive. Lurhmann's work feels confined by his stories, as if he's trying to escape them through visuals. Gilliam's films feel more satisfying, at least to me, because the images ARE the story. This isn't to the taste of every moviegoer, I'm sure, but, if you surrender to it, you'll be taken on a roller-coaster ride: thrilling, scary, exhausting, something you say you never want repeat as you join the queue to do it all over again. It is a dystopian tale, and to that extent has a seriousness of purpose that some might think gets lost beneath the extravagance of what's on screen, but I don't share that view. Gilliam's imagination yields a poetic dreamscape which by-passes rationality. It's an environment that makes the dystopia all the more vivid. Savoring the performances is one way of digesting this rich dish. Playing the discontented hero, Sam Lowry, is Jonathan Pryce, a renowned British stage actor. His is a curious presence, without much charm, but undoubtedly charismatic. A quartet of principal relationships stem from his character: his vain mother, played by wonderful Katherine Helmond; the object of his desire, played flatly but efficiently by Kim Griest; his non-conformist alter-ego played by a brilliantly-cast Robert De Nero, strangely but effectively out of step with everyone else's acting style; and, as Sam's conformist antagonist, Michael Palin, charming and chilling in equal measure. Surrounding this central quintet is an unequalled collection of British character actors, some on screen for merely a few seconds, providing Gilliam with an entirely believable world of eccentrics. Those flashing by include Ann Way, Harold Innocent, John Grillo, Oscar Quitak and Ralph Nossek. In slightly larger roles come Jim Broadbent, Bryan Pringle, Gordon Kaye, Bob Hoskins and (dazzling) Ian Richardson. In fully-fledged support are Barbara Hicks, superb Kathryn Pogson, Ian Holm, Peter Vaughan and, giving heart to the only realistic role in the entire movie, the great Sheila Reid. The production design is amazing, the photography superb, and the editing, which must have been quite a challenge, is a masterclass in tact.The score is a bravura achievement by Michael Kamen, who inventively mutates the old song that gives the film its title. The story is pretty straightforward, even if the telling of it is anything but. The dialogue is peppered with memorable exchanges. There are outstanding set-pieces of comic business. Over and above everything is the imagery. The stuff of dreams, occasionally of nightmares. Helmond's smiling face stretched out to breaking point by Broadbent; De Niro engulfed by flying paper; Holm turned into a speaking pavement; Pryce battling with a faceless giant Samurai; a ghastly dinner at an exploding restaurant; the haunting final shot... BRAZIL is an extraordinary cinematic experience.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of the worst movies I have ever seen
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Dejan K
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I don't understand why this movie is rated so highly. The visuals are good, but that's about it. I almost fell asleep halfway through. Add a predictable storyline and you get an absolute snooze fest. This is the movie to watch if you ever have a hard time falling asleep. Highly recommended for anyone with a sleeping disorder. Brazil will get the job done better than pills. The storyline is mediocre and the "absurdity" in the film is irritating rather than imaginative. I didn't get the film at all. Nothing holds the film together, the ending is predictable (I predicted how it was going to end 30 minutes into the movie), and I feel I wasted two hours of my life that I'm never going to get back. Thanks Brazil.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Puzzling adulation
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    colinfeltham
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I've just watched this for the first time (making my way through the UK Top 100). I wanted to like it but found it just didn't make the impact on me its reviews suggested it would. It's a cross between 1984 and Monty Python, but full of corny, dated (unfunny) humour and slapstick antics. The story is trite - I mean, many of us hate bureaucracy and think it overshadows too much of our lives (I do) but that's not a big enough point to keep anyone's interest for 148 minutes. I liked the music, I got the allusions to other films, but despite the acclaimed surrealism here, I wasn't engaged. I am frankly amazed by the level of its critical acclaim - there are far better films. The 1980s version of 1984 is better in its grimness, for example.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Visually and philosophically, it succeeds. As a movie, it's pretentious and all over the place
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    JavikKatarn
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I'm a big fan of Terry Gilliam's work. His comedic work in Monty Python and many of his feature films including Time Bandits and Twelve Monkeys are classics. Brazil is often regarded as his best work and an artistic masterpiece of merging ideas and symbolism and black humour. Like most cinematic classics, I thought I would enjoy the film. However, the film was overall a dreaded bore with a narrative that was all over the place, two-dimensional characters and an overlong climax albeit a film with some compelling ideas and a nice take on Orwell's 1984. The story of Brazil takes place in the far future where Britain has become a totalitarian fascist state. Sam Lowry is a low-level government employee who constantly dreams of saving a woman. One day, he has to correct an error where a man named Archibald Buttle was imprisoned by the government and killed during an interrogation for being suspected of terrorism when he got confused for Archibald Tuttle due to a fly being jammed in the printer (okay, that's quite funny). He notices that the next door neighbour of the Buttles, Jill Layton, has the same face of the woman in his dreams. When Jill is branded as a terrorist after trying to report the mistake of the man's death. Sam then tries to get a transfer to information retrieval to learn more about Jill. The ideas that Brazil gives out are fundamentally not bad themes. Some if it is taken from 1984 but I liked how Gilliam tried to merge them with a comedic element to them and make an argument about the dangers of the errors bureaucracies make. The art direction in this movie is also pretty impressive. The visuals are a bit dated now (it's clearly got the 80s feel to it) but back then they would've been spectacular. A lot of Fritz Lang's Metropolis is present in them. There are also a few funny and amusing moments in the film but the term 'comedy' doesn't hold much water here for me. Roger Ebert was one of the few critics who disliked Brazil, calling it 'hard to follow', I couldn't put it better myself. The main story to the film shouldn't be much of a pain to understand but most of the film revolves around things just happening. There's no clear focus in the film as to what Gilliam wants to tell, just showing a bunch of random stuff occurring and barely getting explanation. This makes the film come across as a complete bore and hard to sit through even on repeated viewings. I get that the film is meant to be sporadic and a bit peculiar in its approach but I still think it's a real nuisance when you have too much on screen and keep throwing constant crap at you without allowing you to comprehend what is being shown. I also cannot buy the romance between Sam and Jill. When the two properly meet the first time, he randomly tells her that he loves her and that he sees her in his dreams. Seriously, who says that to somebody they've just encountered? The two lack chemistry and the romance is only introduced at the end of the second act, making it come across as rushed and murky. I will give credit to the climax for trying to be shocking in its treatment and is a classic example of a funny 'f@&k you' ending. Brazil has some unique ideas, innovative art direction and even a few moments where the comedy works but is overall a shallow and unfocused film that lacks any heart and coherence. It's already become regarded as a classic and I suppose its unfocused narrative has become appreciated by its fans but it failed to get me sucked in and is a depressing experience overall.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Probably one of my favourite movies ever!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    pepsicolasmileyface
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Brazil is that movie where you either love it or hate it, you either think its stupid or that its mind blowing. Well I loved it, This movie completely blew my mind away. This movie looks stunning, the city and the cinematography probably strike me the most. This movie is original and no one can say that it's not an original movie. All the performances were pretty good. In the end though it's the message in the end that matters is about modern life. It shows how people make things so complicated to make things easier and how bureaucracy is sort of destroying us. It shows us the story of a guy bored of his life and then this big change happens to him and his life suddenly becomes interesting after he sees this woman of his dreams at his job. It shows a world torn apart with ridiculous ways of life and then this spark of hope with this man drowning in all of his life. This movie probably has one of my favourite endings when in his mind he's escaped but in the end he's in a chair half dead. Another thing is that every time you watch this film there's always something new to see and these are the reasons why I love this movie.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A rare surrealist film, the best of the Monty Python canon and off-shoots, one of the best movies I've seen
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    berynn-796-758229
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Terry Gilliam's Brazil is set in a deco-style fantasy-noir world blending kitsch fashion and bleak utilitarianism, grey ducting being the most prominent design motif. Sam Lowry (Jonathon Pryce) is a highly competent, guileless functionary in a government ministry, with a dash of charm that hints at the romanticism in his heart. As his dreams propel him away from the comfortable routine, he comes up against the bureaucracy that has hitherto sustained him. Pryce gives perhaps the best performance of his career, comic, fevered, innocent and vulnerable, occasionally suave. The character could so easily have been a typical Python caricature, but with Tom Stoppard on the writing team (with Gilliam), Pryce has a lot of scope and he takes full advantage of it, producing a remarkable performance. The surreal world of Brazil closes in on Lowry as he pursues his vision, the guts of the system spilling out when things go awry. Robert de Niro's handyman terrorist adds gravitas without reneging on the style, and Bob Hoskin's ferocious comedy lends menace to the state system. Kim Greist's portrayal of Jill Layton, Lowry's desire, is more realistic. Although it could well be argued that Greist simply didn't get the style, I found her performance a useful counterpoint. Lowry's dream girl turns out to be more real, more earthed than the world he lives in. While the theme of the film will not be novel for many viewers - it's a realization of the world that often punctures adolescent minds - Brazil evinces the brutal nexus between the passionate individual and the state/status quo through a brilliantly distorted lens that accentuates the conflict. The Pythonesque tone to the look, feel and characterizations of Brazil is taken to its finest, most filmic iteration. There are some fine allusions to classic films for movie buffs, and the design is one of the film's major talking points, but for an 18 year-old lad when I first saw it, I was riven by the inhumanity of protocol, social expectations, rules and regulations in a world dominated by bureaucracy, against the fragility of romance and hope. Similarly themed '1984' might be a more powerful film, but it is also comparatively monochromatic. I barely know how to describe the effectiveness of such an overt, theatrical design that so graphically supports the themes. It is often labeled as a satire but the film is much more than this. A febrile heart emerges from the strong stylization (akin to City of Lost Children), engaging strong feeling as much as intellectual entertainment; a rare feat, owing much to Pryce's characterization. I still remember the intense mood I felt leaving the cinema after watching this nearly 30 years ago. Though Brazil borrows heavily from various styles - film-noir, satire, absurdism, surrealism, thriller, action, romance, art film - it is unique, a masterpiece that creates its own genre. It may not be to everyone's taste, but if you have a yen for something very different from the typical blockbuster, you should absolutely positively give Brazil a try. I recommend the international version, without the last scene cut. (132 or 142 minutes). Gilliam reviled the short version, which robs the story of its poignancy, emasculating the central theme. I give the long version full marks.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An interesting mix of genres, but an uneven experience for me
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Bruno Youn
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I appreciate how Brazil encompasses several genres, being both frightening and funny on different occasions. The film had some nice visuals and I liked Terry Gilliam's vision of this dystopian future. However, I didn't find any of the characters to be so memorable or even likable so I had a tough time relating to any of them. I like the satirical tone of the story, but I thought many scenes seemed pretty goofy and cartoonish, which took me out of the film a little bit. The ending was truly great though, being quite tragic and thought-provoking. Overall, Brazil was an uneven experience for me, but certainly an interesting watch.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A very accurate vision of the modern USA
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jjccxx220
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Being an old man, I surprised myself at not having seen this when it came out. Terry Gilliam was a brilliant member of Monte Python's Flying Circus and I would have been interested in anything he did. Now, viewing it nearly thirty years after it came out, his prescience is amazing. For younger members, the Internet didn't exist for most people until the mid 1990's and personal computers wired together were not common at the time this was made. Except for the appearance of the modern world, he got it right. Today, we live in a surveillance society where we are tracked electronically wherever we are and whatever we do. American police practice the kind of assault and then ask questions more and more, as news reports will show. People are divided into the slaves and the government powers. How does a man survive in such a world? He does what our hero does - works his job, keeps his mouth shut and keeps his head down. Until he sees a vision of the woman in his fantasies in real life, and risks all to find her. Again for younger members, who never heard of the Soviet Union unless they had a rare history teacher, Gilliam's society is like what prevailed in that dictatorship. Never tell the truth except to the police, never share an opinion, never trust anyone. In modern America, we find the Soviet Union gone but its principles have traveled here, courtesy of political correctness. Tell the truth or share your opinion, and there is someone who wants to sue you. Trust the wrong person, of whom there are lots, and live to regret it. Finally, the society depicted in "Brazil" is Obama's idea of utopia. He and his crew are working hard to make it happen, and most Americans are too busy with "Survivor" and "American Idol" to know or care. This movie will be a wake-up call, if nothing else.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Just a fantastic and unforgettable experience.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    SamHarrisdrwho
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    My God, this movie gets everything right. The casting is brilliant the acting superb and the directing, MY GOD THE DIRECTING! The story dives to the very heart of bureaucracy in a terrific way. The character of Sam Lowry is one the best in cinematic history. It's beautiful to dive right into his dreams and find out what makes this character tick. But the visual effects are fantastic there is no point diving into the fantastic visuals and art direction because what hasn't been said? What can I possibly add? The soundtrack is just incredible taking one unforgettable song and making it fit the scene perfectly from being sad to scary to happy in a matter of seconds. THIS MOVIE IS WORTH YOUR TIME! If you have a Blu-Ray player, this is the perfect Blu-ray movie. Quite possibly my favorite cinematic experience.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A funny version of George Orwell's 1984
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    lukehere99
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Terry Gilliam, the only American member of Monty Python, writes and directs this comedic take on George Orwell's 1984. This is basically 1984 but much less boring and with jokes. I'll cut to the chase - Brazil is a masterpiece, reasons for this are about to be pointed out. But just if your wondering the only reason this is called Brazil is because of the song (by Geoff Muldaur) which plays every now and again in random places. The acting in Brazil is very good all round, personally I class the cast as an ensemble but some may disagree. Jonathan Pryce is the main character Sam Lowry who I have always thought is a lot like Arthur Dent from The Hitchhikers Guide To The Galaxy. Robert De Niro is the rebel against society Harry Tuttle and is the most likable character in the movie. Bob Hoskins and Derrick O'Connor are 2 comedic ventilation repair men who come to a very amusing sticky end. Michael Palin (also a member of Monty Python) is Sam's old friend in a surprisingly serious, but very well performed, role. Ian Holm (was he never young) is Sam's boss and friend, Jim Broadbent a creep plastic surgeon nicknamed "the acid man". And finally Kim Greist as Sam's one true love and alleged terrorist. All of these roles are brilliant, funny, well acted and memorable. Brazil possibly has the best plot and story of any movie I have ever seen, even if most of the source material is taken from (the extremely depressing) George Orwell's 1984. Everything is unexpected and definitely not predictable, even the love scenes are unique. terry Gilliam (the director) is of course in the hilarious Monty Python team, who are in my opinion the funniest comedy group ever, so you would expect Brazil to be extremely funny. Unfortunately it's not EXTREMELY funny, I laughed on many occasions but not as much as I would have liked to. But then again how can a movie based on 1984 be that hilarious? Finally the ending - in my opinion Brazil has the best and most effective ending of any movie ever. This is a spoiler free review so I won't reveal what happens, but I will say that it's a surprise and certainly not expected. Overall I will give Brazil 9.0/10 and 4.5 stars, because the humour is not as strong as I expected it to be.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    the stuff of dreams
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    (gsygsy)
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Nothing can fully prepare you for BRAZIL. Maybe it's Cervantes' DON QUIXOTE as dreamed by Franz Kafka then written up by Lawrence Sterne. But that doesn't do justice to Terry Gilliam's cinematic bravura. Gilliam is an extravagant director. His work teems with stuff. He is, in this respect, comparable to Baz Lurhmann, and the comparison is instructive. Lurhmann's work feels confined by his stories, as if he's trying to escape them through visuals. Gilliam's films feel more satisfying, at least to me, because the images ARE the story. This isn't to the taste of every moviegoer, I'm sure, but, if you surrender to it, you'll be taken on a roller-coaster ride: thrilling, scary, exhausting, something you say you never want repeat as you join the queue to do it all over again. It is a dystopian tale, and to that extent has a seriousness of purpose that some might think gets lost beneath the extravagance of what's on screen, but I don't share that view. Gilliam's imagination yields a poetic dreamscape which by-passes rationality. It's an environment that makes the dystopia all the more vivid. Savoring the performances is one way of digesting this rich dish. Playing the discontented hero, Sam Lowry, is Jonathan Pryce, a renowned British stage actor. His is a curious presence, without much charm, but undoubtedly charismatic. A quartet of principal relationships stem from his character: his vain mother, played by wonderful Katherine Helmond; the object of his desire, played flatly but efficiently by Kim Griest; his non-conformist alter-ego played by a brilliantly-cast Robert De Nero, strangely but effectively out of step with everyone else's acting style; and, as Sam's conformist antagonist, Michael Palin, charming and chilling in equal measure. Surrounding this central quintet is an unequalled collection of British character actors, some on screen for merely a few seconds, providing Gilliam with an entirely believable world of eccentrics. Those flashing by include Ann Way, Harold Innocent, John Grillo, Oscar Quitak and Ralph Nossek. In slightly larger roles come Jim Broadbent, Bryan Pringle, Gordon Kaye, Bob Hoskins and (dazzling) Ian Richardson. In fully-fledged support are Barbara Hicks, superb Kathryn Pogson, Ian Holm, Peter Vaughan and, giving heart to the only realistic role in the entire movie, the great Sheila Reid. The production design is amazing, the photography superb, and the editing, which must have been quite a challenge, is a masterclass in tact.The score is a bravura achievement by Michael Kamen, who inventively mutates the old song that gives the film its title. The story is pretty straightforward, even if the telling of it is anything but. The dialogue is peppered with memorable exchanges. There are outstanding set-pieces of comic business. Over and above everything is the imagery. The stuff of dreams, occasionally of nightmares. Helmond's smiling face stretched out to breaking point by Broadbent; De Niro engulfed by flying paper; Holm turned into a speaking pavement; Pryce battling with a faceless giant Samurai; a ghastly dinner at an exploding restaurant; the haunting final shot... BRAZIL is an extraordinary cinematic experience.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of the worst movies I have ever seen
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Dejan K
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I don't understand why this movie is rated so highly. The visuals are good, but that's about it. I almost fell asleep halfway through. Add a predictable storyline and you get an absolute snooze fest. This is the movie to watch if you ever have a hard time falling asleep. Highly recommended for anyone with a sleeping disorder. Brazil will get the job done better than pills. The storyline is mediocre and the "absurdity" in the film is irritating rather than imaginative. I didn't get the film at all. Nothing holds the film together, the ending is predictable (I predicted how it was going to end 30 minutes into the movie), and I feel I wasted two hours of my life that I'm never going to get back. Thanks Brazil.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Puzzling adulation
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    colinfeltham
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I've just watched this for the first time (making my way through the UK Top 100). I wanted to like it but found it just didn't make the impact on me its reviews suggested it would. It's a cross between 1984 and Monty Python, but full of corny, dated (unfunny) humour and slapstick antics. The story is trite - I mean, many of us hate bureaucracy and think it overshadows too much of our lives (I do) but that's not a big enough point to keep anyone's interest for 148 minutes. I liked the music, I got the allusions to other films, but despite the acclaimed surrealism here, I wasn't engaged. I am frankly amazed by the level of its critical acclaim - there are far better films. The 1980s version of 1984 is better in its grimness, for example.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Visually and philosophically, it succeeds. As a movie, it's pretentious and all over the place
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    JavikKatarn
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I'm a big fan of Terry Gilliam's work. His comedic work in Monty Python and many of his feature films including Time Bandits and Twelve Monkeys are classics. Brazil is often regarded as his best work and an artistic masterpiece of merging ideas and symbolism and black humour. Like most cinematic classics, I thought I would enjoy the film. However, the film was overall a dreaded bore with a narrative that was all over the place, two-dimensional characters and an overlong climax albeit a film with some compelling ideas and a nice take on Orwell's 1984. The story of Brazil takes place in the far future where Britain has become a totalitarian fascist state. Sam Lowry is a low-level government employee who constantly dreams of saving a woman. One day, he has to correct an error where a man named Archibald Buttle was imprisoned by the government and killed during an interrogation for being suspected of terrorism when he got confused for Archibald Tuttle due to a fly being jammed in the printer (okay, that's quite funny). He notices that the next door neighbour of the Buttles, Jill Layton, has the same face of the woman in his dreams. When Jill is branded as a terrorist after trying to report the mistake of the man's death. Sam then tries to get a transfer to information retrieval to learn more about Jill. The ideas that Brazil gives out are fundamentally not bad themes. Some if it is taken from 1984 but I liked how Gilliam tried to merge them with a comedic element to them and make an argument about the dangers of the errors bureaucracies make. The art direction in this movie is also pretty impressive. The visuals are a bit dated now (it's clearly got the 80s feel to it) but back then they would've been spectacular. A lot of Fritz Lang's Metropolis is present in them. There are also a few funny and amusing moments in the film but the term 'comedy' doesn't hold much water here for me. Roger Ebert was one of the few critics who disliked Brazil, calling it 'hard to follow', I couldn't put it better myself. The main story to the film shouldn't be much of a pain to understand but most of the film revolves around things just happening. There's no clear focus in the film as to what Gilliam wants to tell, just showing a bunch of random stuff occurring and barely getting explanation. This makes the film come across as a complete bore and hard to sit through even on repeated viewings. I get that the film is meant to be sporadic and a bit peculiar in its approach but I still think it's a real nuisance when you have too much on screen and keep throwing constant crap at you without allowing you to comprehend what is being shown. I also cannot buy the romance between Sam and Jill. When the two properly meet the first time, he randomly tells her that he loves her and that he sees her in his dreams. Seriously, who says that to somebody they've just encountered? The two lack chemistry and the romance is only introduced at the end of the second act, making it come across as rushed and murky. I will give credit to the climax for trying to be shocking in its treatment and is a classic example of a funny 'f@&k you' ending. Brazil has some unique ideas, innovative art direction and even a few moments where the comedy works but is overall a shallow and unfocused film that lacks any heart and coherence. It's already become regarded as a classic and I suppose its unfocused narrative has become appreciated by its fans but it failed to get me sucked in and is a depressing experience overall.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Probably one of my favourite movies ever!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    pepsicolasmileyface
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Brazil is that movie where you either love it or hate it, you either think its stupid or that its mind blowing. Well I loved it, This movie completely blew my mind away. This movie looks stunning, the city and the cinematography probably strike me the most. This movie is original and no one can say that it's not an original movie. All the performances were pretty good. In the end though it's the message in the end that matters is about modern life. It shows how people make things so complicated to make things easier and how bureaucracy is sort of destroying us. It shows us the story of a guy bored of his life and then this big change happens to him and his life suddenly becomes interesting after he sees this woman of his dreams at his job. It shows a world torn apart with ridiculous ways of life and then this spark of hope with this man drowning in all of his life. This movie probably has one of my favourite endings when in his mind he's escaped but in the end he's in a chair half dead. Another thing is that every time you watch this film there's always something new to see and these are the reasons why I love this movie.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A rare surrealist film, the best of the Monty Python canon and off-shoots, one of the best movies I've seen
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    berynn-796-758229
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Terry Gilliam's Brazil is set in a deco-style fantasy-noir world blending kitsch fashion and bleak utilitarianism, grey ducting being the most prominent design motif. Sam Lowry (Jonathon Pryce) is a highly competent, guileless functionary in a government ministry, with a dash of charm that hints at the romanticism in his heart. As his dreams propel him away from the comfortable routine, he comes up against the bureaucracy that has hitherto sustained him. Pryce gives perhaps the best performance of his career, comic, fevered, innocent and vulnerable, occasionally suave. The character could so easily have been a typical Python caricature, but with Tom Stoppard on the writing team (with Gilliam), Pryce has a lot of scope and he takes full advantage of it, producing a remarkable performance. The surreal world of Brazil closes in on Lowry as he pursues his vision, the guts of the system spilling out when things go awry. Robert de Niro's handyman terrorist adds gravitas without reneging on the style, and Bob Hoskin's ferocious comedy lends menace to the state system. Kim Greist's portrayal of Jill Layton, Lowry's desire, is more realistic. Although it could well be argued that Greist simply didn't get the style, I found her performance a useful counterpoint. Lowry's dream girl turns out to be more real, more earthed than the world he lives in. While the theme of the film will not be novel for many viewers - it's a realization of the world that often punctures adolescent minds - Brazil evinces the brutal nexus between the passionate individual and the state/status quo through a brilliantly distorted lens that accentuates the conflict. The Pythonesque tone to the look, feel and characterizations of Brazil is taken to its finest, most filmic iteration. There are some fine allusions to classic films for movie buffs, and the design is one of the film's major talking points, but for an 18 year-old lad when I first saw it, I was riven by the inhumanity of protocol, social expectations, rules and regulations in a world dominated by bureaucracy, against the fragility of romance and hope. Similarly themed '1984' might be a more powerful film, but it is also comparatively monochromatic. I barely know how to describe the effectiveness of such an overt, theatrical design that so graphically supports the themes. It is often labeled as a satire but the film is much more than this. A febrile heart emerges from the strong stylization (akin to City of Lost Children), engaging strong feeling as much as intellectual entertainment; a rare feat, owing much to Pryce's characterization. I still remember the intense mood I felt leaving the cinema after watching this nearly 30 years ago. Though Brazil borrows heavily from various styles - film-noir, satire, absurdism, surrealism, thriller, action, romance, art film - it is unique, a masterpiece that creates its own genre. It may not be to everyone's taste, but if you have a yen for something very different from the typical blockbuster, you should absolutely positively give Brazil a try. I recommend the international version, without the last scene cut. (132 or 142 minutes). Gilliam reviled the short version, which robs the story of its poignancy, emasculating the central theme. I give the long version full marks.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An interesting mix of genres, but an uneven experience for me
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Bruno Youn
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I appreciate how Brazil encompasses several genres, being both frightening and funny on different occasions. The film had some nice visuals and I liked Terry Gilliam's vision of this dystopian future. However, I didn't find any of the characters to be so memorable or even likable so I had a tough time relating to any of them. I like the satirical tone of the story, but I thought many scenes seemed pretty goofy and cartoonish, which took me out of the film a little bit. The ending was truly great though, being quite tragic and thought-provoking. Overall, Brazil was an uneven experience for me, but certainly an interesting watch.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A very accurate vision of the modern USA
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jjccxx220
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Being an old man, I surprised myself at not having seen this when it came out. Terry Gilliam was a brilliant member of Monte Python's Flying Circus and I would have been interested in anything he did. Now, viewing it nearly thirty years after it came out, his prescience is amazing. For younger members, the Internet didn't exist for most people until the mid 1990's and personal computers wired together were not common at the time this was made. Except for the appearance of the modern world, he got it right. Today, we live in a surveillance society where we are tracked electronically wherever we are and whatever we do. American police practice the kind of assault and then ask questions more and more, as news reports will show. People are divided into the slaves and the government powers. How does a man survive in such a world? He does what our hero does - works his job, keeps his mouth shut and keeps his head down. Until he sees a vision of the woman in his fantasies in real life, and risks all to find her. Again for younger members, who never heard of the Soviet Union unless they had a rare history teacher, Gilliam's society is like what prevailed in that dictatorship. Never tell the truth except to the police, never share an opinion, never trust anyone. In modern America, we find the Soviet Union gone but its principles have traveled here, courtesy of political correctness. Tell the truth or share your opinion, and there is someone who wants to sue you. Trust the wrong person, of whom there are lots, and live to regret it. Finally, the society depicted in "Brazil" is Obama's idea of utopia. He and his crew are working hard to make it happen, and most Americans are too busy with "Survivor" and "American Idol" to know or care. This movie will be a wake-up call, if nothing else.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Just a fantastic and unforgettable experience.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    SamHarrisdrwho
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    My God, this movie gets everything right. The casting is brilliant the acting superb and the directing, MY GOD THE DIRECTING! The story dives to the very heart of bureaucracy in a terrific way. The character of Sam Lowry is one the best in cinematic history. It's beautiful to dive right into his dreams and find out what makes this character tick. But the visual effects are fantastic there is no point diving into the fantastic visuals and art direction because what hasn't been said? What can I possibly add? The soundtrack is just incredible taking one unforgettable song and making it fit the scene perfectly from being sad to scary to happy in a matter of seconds. THIS MOVIE IS WORTH YOUR TIME! If you have a Blu-Ray player, this is the perfect Blu-ray movie. Quite possibly my favorite cinematic experience.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A funny version of George Orwell's 1984
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    lukehere99
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Terry Gilliam, the only American member of Monty Python, writes and directs this comedic take on George Orwell's 1984. This is basically 1984 but much less boring and with jokes. I'll cut to the chase - Brazil is a masterpiece, reasons for this are about to be pointed out. But just if your wondering the only reason this is called Brazil is because of the song (by Geoff Muldaur) which plays every now and again in random places. The acting in Brazil is very good all round, personally I class the cast as an ensemble but some may disagree. Jonathan Pryce is the main character Sam Lowry who I have always thought is a lot like Arthur Dent from The Hitchhikers Guide To The Galaxy. Robert De Niro is the rebel against society Harry Tuttle and is the most likable character in the movie. Bob Hoskins and Derrick O'Connor are 2 comedic ventilation repair men who come to a very amusing sticky end. Michael Palin (also a member of Monty Python) is Sam's old friend in a surprisingly serious, but very well performed, role. Ian Holm (was he never young) is Sam's boss and friend, Jim Broadbent a creep plastic surgeon nicknamed "the acid man". And finally Kim Greist as Sam's one true love and alleged terrorist. All of these roles are brilliant, funny, well acted and memorable. Brazil possibly has the best plot and story of any movie I have ever seen, even if most of the source material is taken from (the extremely depressing) George Orwell's 1984. Everything is unexpected and definitely not predictable, even the love scenes are unique. terry Gilliam (the director) is of course in the hilarious Monty Python team, who are in my opinion the funniest comedy group ever, so you would expect Brazil to be extremely funny. Unfortunately it's not EXTREMELY funny, I laughed on many occasions but not as much as I would have liked to. But then again how can a movie based on 1984 be that hilarious? Finally the ending - in my opinion Brazil has the best and most effective ending of any movie ever. This is a spoiler free review so I won't reveal what happens, but I will say that it's a surprise and certainly not expected. Overall I will give Brazil 9.0/10 and 4.5 stars, because the humour is not as strong as I expected it to be.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    the stuff of dreams
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    (gsygsy)
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Nothing can fully prepare you for BRAZIL. Maybe it's Cervantes' DON QUIXOTE as dreamed by Franz Kafka then written up by Lawrence Sterne. But that doesn't do justice to Terry Gilliam's cinematic bravura. Gilliam is an extravagant director. His work teems with stuff. He is, in this respect, comparable to Baz Lurhmann, and the comparison is instructive. Lurhmann's work feels confined by his stories, as if he's trying to escape them through visuals. Gilliam's films feel more satisfying, at least to me, because the images ARE the story. This isn't to the taste of every moviegoer, I'm sure, but, if you surrender to it, you'll be taken on a roller-coaster ride: thrilling, scary, exhausting, something you say you never want repeat as you join the queue to do it all over again. It is a dystopian tale, and to that extent has a seriousness of purpose that some might think gets lost beneath the extravagance of what's on screen, but I don't share that view. Gilliam's imagination yields a poetic dreamscape which by-passes rationality. It's an environment that makes the dystopia all the more vivid. Savoring the performances is one way of digesting this rich dish. Playing the discontented hero, Sam Lowry, is Jonathan Pryce, a renowned British stage actor. His is a curious presence, without much charm, but undoubtedly charismatic. A quartet of principal relationships stem from his character: his vain mother, played by wonderful Katherine Helmond; the object of his desire, played flatly but efficiently by Kim Griest; his non-conformist alter-ego played by a brilliantly-cast Robert De Nero, strangely but effectively out of step with everyone else's acting style; and, as Sam's conformist antagonist, Michael Palin, charming and chilling in equal measure. Surrounding this central quintet is an unequalled collection of British character actors, some on screen for merely a few seconds, providing Gilliam with an entirely believable world of eccentrics. Those flashing by include Ann Way, Harold Innocent, John Grillo, Oscar Quitak and Ralph Nossek. In slightly larger roles come Jim Broadbent, Bryan Pringle, Gordon Kaye, Bob Hoskins and (dazzling) Ian Richardson. In fully-fledged support are Barbara Hicks, superb Kathryn Pogson, Ian Holm, Peter Vaughan and, giving heart to the only realistic role in the entire movie, the great Sheila Reid. The production design is amazing, the photography superb, and the editing, which must have been quite a challenge, is a masterclass in tact.The score is a bravura achievement by Michael Kamen, who inventively mutates the old song that gives the film its title. The story is pretty straightforward, even if the telling of it is anything but. The dialogue is peppered with memorable exchanges. There are outstanding set-pieces of comic business. Over and above everything is the imagery. The stuff of dreams, occasionally of nightmares. Helmond's smiling face stretched out to breaking point by Broadbent; De Niro engulfed by flying paper; Holm turned into a speaking pavement; Pryce battling with a faceless giant Samurai; a ghastly dinner at an exploding restaurant; the haunting final shot... BRAZIL is an extraordinary cinematic experience.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of the worst movies I have ever seen
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Dejan K
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I don't understand why this movie is rated so highly. The visuals are good, but that's about it. I almost fell asleep halfway through. Add a predictable storyline and you get an absolute snooze fest. This is the movie to watch if you ever have a hard time falling asleep. Highly recommended for anyone with a sleeping disorder. Brazil will get the job done better than pills. The storyline is mediocre and the "absurdity" in the film is irritating rather than imaginative. I didn't get the film at all. Nothing holds the film together, the ending is predictable (I predicted how it was going to end 30 minutes into the movie), and I feel I wasted two hours of my life that I'm never going to get back. Thanks Brazil.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Puzzling adulation
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    colinfeltham
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I've just watched this for the first time (making my way through the UK Top 100). I wanted to like it but found it just didn't make the impact on me its reviews suggested it would. It's a cross between 1984 and Monty Python, but full of corny, dated (unfunny) humour and slapstick antics. The story is trite - I mean, many of us hate bureaucracy and think it overshadows too much of our lives (I do) but that's not a big enough point to keep anyone's interest for 148 minutes. I liked the music, I got the allusions to other films, but despite the acclaimed surrealism here, I wasn't engaged. I am frankly amazed by the level of its critical acclaim - there are far better films. The 1980s version of 1984 is better in its grimness, for example.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Visually and philosophically, it succeeds. As a movie, it's pretentious and all over the place
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    JavikKatarn
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I'm a big fan of Terry Gilliam's work. His comedic work in Monty Python and many of his feature films including Time Bandits and Twelve Monkeys are classics. Brazil is often regarded as his best work and an artistic masterpiece of merging ideas and symbolism and black humour. Like most cinematic classics, I thought I would enjoy the film. However, the film was overall a dreaded bore with a narrative that was all over the place, two-dimensional characters and an overlong climax albeit a film with some compelling ideas and a nice take on Orwell's 1984. The story of Brazil takes place in the far future where Britain has become a totalitarian fascist state. Sam Lowry is a low-level government employee who constantly dreams of saving a woman. One day, he has to correct an error where a man named Archibald Buttle was imprisoned by the government and killed during an interrogation for being suspected of terrorism when he got confused for Archibald Tuttle due to a fly being jammed in the printer (okay, that's quite funny). He notices that the next door neighbour of the Buttles, Jill Layton, has the same face of the woman in his dreams. When Jill is branded as a terrorist after trying to report the mistake of the man's death. Sam then tries to get a transfer to information retrieval to learn more about Jill. The ideas that Brazil gives out are fundamentally not bad themes. Some if it is taken from 1984 but I liked how Gilliam tried to merge them with a comedic element to them and make an argument about the dangers of the errors bureaucracies make. The art direction in this movie is also pretty impressive. The visuals are a bit dated now (it's clearly got the 80s feel to it) but back then they would've been spectacular. A lot of Fritz Lang's Metropolis is present in them. There are also a few funny and amusing moments in the film but the term 'comedy' doesn't hold much water here for me. Roger Ebert was one of the few critics who disliked Brazil, calling it 'hard to follow', I couldn't put it better myself. The main story to the film shouldn't be much of a pain to understand but most of the film revolves around things just happening. There's no clear focus in the film as to what Gilliam wants to tell, just showing a bunch of random stuff occurring and barely getting explanation. This makes the film come across as a complete bore and hard to sit through even on repeated viewings. I get that the film is meant to be sporadic and a bit peculiar in its approach but I still think it's a real nuisance when you have too much on screen and keep throwing constant crap at you without allowing you to comprehend what is being shown. I also cannot buy the romance between Sam and Jill. When the two properly meet the first time, he randomly tells her that he loves her and that he sees her in his dreams. Seriously, who says that to somebody they've just encountered? The two lack chemistry and the romance is only introduced at the end of the second act, making it come across as rushed and murky. I will give credit to the climax for trying to be shocking in its treatment and is a classic example of a funny 'f@&k you' ending. Brazil has some unique ideas, innovative art direction and even a few moments where the comedy works but is overall a shallow and unfocused film that lacks any heart and coherence. It's already become regarded as a classic and I suppose its unfocused narrative has become appreciated by its fans but it failed to get me sucked in and is a depressing experience overall.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Probably one of my favourite movies ever!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    pepsicolasmileyface
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Brazil is that movie where you either love it or hate it, you either think its stupid or that its mind blowing. Well I loved it, This movie completely blew my mind away. This movie looks stunning, the city and the cinematography probably strike me the most. This movie is original and no one can say that it's not an original movie. All the performances were pretty good. In the end though it's the message in the end that matters is about modern life. It shows how people make things so complicated to make things easier and how bureaucracy is sort of destroying us. It shows us the story of a guy bored of his life and then this big change happens to him and his life suddenly becomes interesting after he sees this woman of his dreams at his job. It shows a world torn apart with ridiculous ways of life and then this spark of hope with this man drowning in all of his life. This movie probably has one of my favourite endings when in his mind he's escaped but in the end he's in a chair half dead. Another thing is that every time you watch this film there's always something new to see and these are the reasons why I love this movie.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A rare surrealist film, the best of the Monty Python canon and off-shoots, one of the best movies I've seen
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    berynn-796-758229
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Terry Gilliam's Brazil is set in a deco-style fantasy-noir world blending kitsch fashion and bleak utilitarianism, grey ducting being the most prominent design motif. Sam Lowry (Jonathon Pryce) is a highly competent, guileless functionary in a government ministry, with a dash of charm that hints at the romanticism in his heart. As his dreams propel him away from the comfortable routine, he comes up against the bureaucracy that has hitherto sustained him. Pryce gives perhaps the best performance of his career, comic, fevered, innocent and vulnerable, occasionally suave. The character could so easily have been a typical Python caricature, but with Tom Stoppard on the writing team (with Gilliam), Pryce has a lot of scope and he takes full advantage of it, producing a remarkable performance. The surreal world of Brazil closes in on Lowry as he pursues his vision, the guts of the system spilling out when things go awry. Robert de Niro's handyman terrorist adds gravitas without reneging on the style, and Bob Hoskin's ferocious comedy lends menace to the state system. Kim Greist's portrayal of Jill Layton, Lowry's desire, is more realistic. Although it could well be argued that Greist simply didn't get the style, I found her performance a useful counterpoint. Lowry's dream girl turns out to be more real, more earthed than the world he lives in. While the theme of the film will not be novel for many viewers - it's a realization of the world that often punctures adolescent minds - Brazil evinces the brutal nexus between the passionate individual and the state/status quo through a brilliantly distorted lens that accentuates the conflict. The Pythonesque tone to the look, feel and characterizations of Brazil is taken to its finest, most filmic iteration. There are some fine allusions to classic films for movie buffs, and the design is one of the film's major talking points, but for an 18 year-old lad when I first saw it, I was riven by the inhumanity of protocol, social expectations, rules and regulations in a world dominated by bureaucracy, against the fragility of romance and hope. Similarly themed '1984' might be a more powerful film, but it is also comparatively monochromatic. I barely know how to describe the effectiveness of such an overt, theatrical design that so graphically supports the themes. It is often labeled as a satire but the film is much more than this. A febrile heart emerges from the strong stylization (akin to City of Lost Children), engaging strong feeling as much as intellectual entertainment; a rare feat, owing much to Pryce's characterization. I still remember the intense mood I felt leaving the cinema after watching this nearly 30 years ago. Though Brazil borrows heavily from various styles - film-noir, satire, absurdism, surrealism, thriller, action, romance, art film - it is unique, a masterpiece that creates its own genre. It may not be to everyone's taste, but if you have a yen for something very different from the typical blockbuster, you should absolutely positively give Brazil a try. I recommend the international version, without the last scene cut. (132 or 142 minutes). Gilliam reviled the short version, which robs the story of its poignancy, emasculating the central theme. I give the long version full marks.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An interesting mix of genres, but an uneven experience for me
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Bruno Youn
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I appreciate how Brazil encompasses several genres, being both frightening and funny on different occasions. The film had some nice visuals and I liked Terry Gilliam's vision of this dystopian future. However, I didn't find any of the characters to be so memorable or even likable so I had a tough time relating to any of them. I like the satirical tone of the story, but I thought many scenes seemed pretty goofy and cartoonish, which took me out of the film a little bit. The ending was truly great though, being quite tragic and thought-provoking. Overall, Brazil was an uneven experience for me, but certainly an interesting watch.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A very accurate vision of the modern USA
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jjccxx220
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Being an old man, I surprised myself at not having seen this when it came out. Terry Gilliam was a brilliant member of Monte Python's Flying Circus and I would have been interested in anything he did. Now, viewing it nearly thirty years after it came out, his prescience is amazing. For younger members, the Internet didn't exist for most people until the mid 1990's and personal computers wired together were not common at the time this was made. Except for the appearance of the modern world, he got it right. Today, we live in a surveillance society where we are tracked electronically wherever we are and whatever we do. American police practice the kind of assault and then ask questions more and more, as news reports will show. People are divided into the slaves and the government powers. How does a man survive in such a world? He does what our hero does - works his job, keeps his mouth shut and keeps his head down. Until he sees a vision of the woman in his fantasies in real life, and risks all to find her. Again for younger members, who never heard of the Soviet Union unless they had a rare history teacher, Gilliam's society is like what prevailed in that dictatorship. Never tell the truth except to the police, never share an opinion, never trust anyone. In modern America, we find the Soviet Union gone but its principles have traveled here, courtesy of political correctness. Tell the truth or share your opinion, and there is someone who wants to sue you. Trust the wrong person, of whom there are lots, and live to regret it. Finally, the society depicted in "Brazil" is Obama's idea of utopia. He and his crew are working hard to make it happen, and most Americans are too busy with "Survivor" and "American Idol" to know or care. This movie will be a wake-up call, if nothing else.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Just a fantastic and unforgettable experience.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    SamHarrisdrwho
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    My God, this movie gets everything right. The casting is brilliant the acting superb and the directing, MY GOD THE DIRECTING! The story dives to the very heart of bureaucracy in a terrific way. The character of Sam Lowry is one the best in cinematic history. It's beautiful to dive right into his dreams and find out what makes this character tick. But the visual effects are fantastic there is no point diving into the fantastic visuals and art direction because what hasn't been said? What can I possibly add? The soundtrack is just incredible taking one unforgettable song and making it fit the scene perfectly from being sad to scary to happy in a matter of seconds. THIS MOVIE IS WORTH YOUR TIME! If you have a Blu-Ray player, this is the perfect Blu-ray movie. Quite possibly my favorite cinematic experience.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A funny version of George Orwell's 1984
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    lukehere99
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Terry Gilliam, the only American member of Monty Python, writes and directs this comedic take on George Orwell's 1984. This is basically 1984 but much less boring and with jokes. I'll cut to the chase - Brazil is a masterpiece, reasons for this are about to be pointed out. But just if your wondering the only reason this is called Brazil is because of the song (by Geoff Muldaur) which plays every now and again in random places. The acting in Brazil is very good all round, personally I class the cast as an ensemble but some may disagree. Jonathan Pryce is the main character Sam Lowry who I have always thought is a lot like Arthur Dent from The Hitchhikers Guide To The Galaxy. Robert De Niro is the rebel against society Harry Tuttle and is the most likable character in the movie. Bob Hoskins and Derrick O'Connor are 2 comedic ventilation repair men who come to a very amusing sticky end. Michael Palin (also a member of Monty Python) is Sam's old friend in a surprisingly serious, but very well performed, role. Ian Holm (was he never young) is Sam's boss and friend, Jim Broadbent a creep plastic surgeon nicknamed "the acid man". And finally Kim Greist as Sam's one true love and alleged terrorist. All of these roles are brilliant, funny, well acted and memorable. Brazil possibly has the best plot and story of any movie I have ever seen, even if most of the source material is taken from (the extremely depressing) George Orwell's 1984. Everything is unexpected and definitely not predictable, even the love scenes are unique. terry Gilliam (the director) is of course in the hilarious Monty Python team, who are in my opinion the funniest comedy group ever, so you would expect Brazil to be extremely funny. Unfortunately it's not EXTREMELY funny, I laughed on many occasions but not as much as I would have liked to. But then again how can a movie based on 1984 be that hilarious? Finally the ending - in my opinion Brazil has the best and most effective ending of any movie ever. This is a spoiler free review so I won't reveal what happens, but I will say that it's a surprise and certainly not expected. Overall I will give Brazil 9.0/10 and 4.5 stars, because the humour is not as strong as I expected it to be.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    the stuff of dreams
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    (gsygsy)
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Nothing can fully prepare you for BRAZIL. Maybe it's Cervantes' DON QUIXOTE as dreamed by Franz Kafka then written up by Lawrence Sterne. But that doesn't do justice to Terry Gilliam's cinematic bravura. Gilliam is an extravagant director. His work teems with stuff. He is, in this respect, comparable to Baz Lurhmann, and the comparison is instructive. Lurhmann's work feels confined by his stories, as if he's trying to escape them through visuals. Gilliam's films feel more satisfying, at least to me, because the images ARE the story. This isn't to the taste of every moviegoer, I'm sure, but, if you surrender to it, you'll be taken on a roller-coaster ride: thrilling, scary, exhausting, something you say you never want repeat as you join the queue to do it all over again. It is a dystopian tale, and to that extent has a seriousness of purpose that some might think gets lost beneath the extravagance of what's on screen, but I don't share that view. Gilliam's imagination yields a poetic dreamscape which by-passes rationality. It's an environment that makes the dystopia all the more vivid. Savoring the performances is one way of digesting this rich dish. Playing the discontented hero, Sam Lowry, is Jonathan Pryce, a renowned British stage actor. His is a curious presence, without much charm, but undoubtedly charismatic. A quartet of principal relationships stem from his character: his vain mother, played by wonderful Katherine Helmond; the object of his desire, played flatly but efficiently by Kim Griest; his non-conformist alter-ego played by a brilliantly-cast Robert De Nero, strangely but effectively out of step with everyone else's acting style; and, as Sam's conformist antagonist, Michael Palin, charming and chilling in equal measure. Surrounding this central quintet is an unequalled collection of British character actors, some on screen for merely a few seconds, providing Gilliam with an entirely believable world of eccentrics. Those flashing by include Ann Way, Harold Innocent, John Grillo, Oscar Quitak and Ralph Nossek. In slightly larger roles come Jim Broadbent, Bryan Pringle, Gordon Kaye, Bob Hoskins and (dazzling) Ian Richardson. In fully-fledged support are Barbara Hicks, superb Kathryn Pogson, Ian Holm, Peter Vaughan and, giving heart to the only realistic role in the entire movie, the great Sheila Reid. The production design is amazing, the photography superb, and the editing, which must have been quite a challenge, is a masterclass in tact.The score is a bravura achievement by Michael Kamen, who inventively mutates the old song that gives the film its title. The story is pretty straightforward, even if the telling of it is anything but. The dialogue is peppered with memorable exchanges. There are outstanding set-pieces of comic business. Over and above everything is the imagery. The stuff of dreams, occasionally of nightmares. Helmond's smiling face stretched out to breaking point by Broadbent; De Niro engulfed by flying paper; Holm turned into a speaking pavement; Pryce battling with a faceless giant Samurai; a ghastly dinner at an exploding restaurant; the haunting final shot... BRAZIL is an extraordinary cinematic experience.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of the worst movies I have ever seen
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Dejan K
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I don't understand why this movie is rated so highly. The visuals are good, but that's about it. I almost fell asleep halfway through. Add a predictable storyline and you get an absolute snooze fest. This is the movie to watch if you ever have a hard time falling asleep. Highly recommended for anyone with a sleeping disorder. Brazil will get the job done better than pills. The storyline is mediocre and the "absurdity" in the film is irritating rather than imaginative. I didn't get the film at all. Nothing holds the film together, the ending is predictable (I predicted how it was going to end 30 minutes into the movie), and I feel I wasted two hours of my life that I'm never going to get back. Thanks Brazil.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Puzzling adulation
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    colinfeltham
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I've just watched this for the first time (making my way through the UK Top 100). I wanted to like it but found it just didn't make the impact on me its reviews suggested it would. It's a cross between 1984 and Monty Python, but full of corny, dated (unfunny) humour and slapstick antics. The story is trite - I mean, many of us hate bureaucracy and think it overshadows too much of our lives (I do) but that's not a big enough point to keep anyone's interest for 148 minutes. I liked the music, I got the allusions to other films, but despite the acclaimed surrealism here, I wasn't engaged. I am frankly amazed by the level of its critical acclaim - there are far better films. The 1980s version of 1984 is better in its grimness, for example.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Visually and philosophically, it succeeds. As a movie, it's pretentious and all over the place
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    JavikKatarn
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I'm a big fan of Terry Gilliam's work. His comedic work in Monty Python and many of his feature films including Time Bandits and Twelve Monkeys are classics. Brazil is often regarded as his best work and an artistic masterpiece of merging ideas and symbolism and black humour. Like most cinematic classics, I thought I would enjoy the film. However, the film was overall a dreaded bore with a narrative that was all over the place, two-dimensional characters and an overlong climax albeit a film with some compelling ideas and a nice take on Orwell's 1984. The story of Brazil takes place in the far future where Britain has become a totalitarian fascist state. Sam Lowry is a low-level government employee who constantly dreams of saving a woman. One day, he has to correct an error where a man named Archibald Buttle was imprisoned by the government and killed during an interrogation for being suspected of terrorism when he got confused for Archibald Tuttle due to a fly being jammed in the printer (okay, that's quite funny). He notices that the next door neighbour of the Buttles, Jill Layton, has the same face of the woman in his dreams. When Jill is branded as a terrorist after trying to report the mistake of the man's death. Sam then tries to get a transfer to information retrieval to learn more about Jill. The ideas that Brazil gives out are fundamentally not bad themes. Some if it is taken from 1984 but I liked how Gilliam tried to merge them with a comedic element to them and make an argument about the dangers of the errors bureaucracies make. The art direction in this movie is also pretty impressive. The visuals are a bit dated now (it's clearly got the 80s feel to it) but back then they would've been spectacular. A lot of Fritz Lang's Metropolis is present in them. There are also a few funny and amusing moments in the film but the term 'comedy' doesn't hold much water here for me. Roger Ebert was one of the few critics who disliked Brazil, calling it 'hard to follow', I couldn't put it better myself. The main story to the film shouldn't be much of a pain to understand but most of the film revolves around things just happening. There's no clear focus in the film as to what Gilliam wants to tell, just showing a bunch of random stuff occurring and barely getting explanation. This makes the film come across as a complete bore and hard to sit through even on repeated viewings. I get that the film is meant to be sporadic and a bit peculiar in its approach but I still think it's a real nuisance when you have too much on screen and keep throwing constant crap at you without allowing you to comprehend what is being shown. I also cannot buy the romance between Sam and Jill. When the two properly meet the first time, he randomly tells her that he loves her and that he sees her in his dreams. Seriously, who says that to somebody they've just encountered? The two lack chemistry and the romance is only introduced at the end of the second act, making it come across as rushed and murky. I will give credit to the climax for trying to be shocking in its treatment and is a classic example of a funny 'f@&k you' ending. Brazil has some unique ideas, innovative art direction and even a few moments where the comedy works but is overall a shallow and unfocused film that lacks any heart and coherence. It's already become regarded as a classic and I suppose its unfocused narrative has become appreciated by its fans but it failed to get me sucked in and is a depressing experience overall.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Probably one of my favourite movies ever!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    pepsicolasmileyface
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Brazil is that movie where you either love it or hate it, you either think its stupid or that its mind blowing. Well I loved it, This movie completely blew my mind away. This movie looks stunning, the city and the cinematography probably strike me the most. This movie is original and no one can say that it's not an original movie. All the performances were pretty good. In the end though it's the message in the end that matters is about modern life. It shows how people make things so complicated to make things easier and how bureaucracy is sort of destroying us. It shows us the story of a guy bored of his life and then this big change happens to him and his life suddenly becomes interesting after he sees this woman of his dreams at his job. It shows a world torn apart with ridiculous ways of life and then this spark of hope with this man drowning in all of his life. This movie probably has one of my favourite endings when in his mind he's escaped but in the end he's in a chair half dead. Another thing is that every time you watch this film there's always something new to see and these are the reasons why I love this movie.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A rare surrealist film, the best of the Monty Python canon and off-shoots, one of the best movies I've seen
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    berynn-796-758229
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Terry Gilliam's Brazil is set in a deco-style fantasy-noir world blending kitsch fashion and bleak utilitarianism, grey ducting being the most prominent design motif. Sam Lowry (Jonathon Pryce) is a highly competent, guileless functionary in a government ministry, with a dash of charm that hints at the romanticism in his heart. As his dreams propel him away from the comfortable routine, he comes up against the bureaucracy that has hitherto sustained him. Pryce gives perhaps the best performance of his career, comic, fevered, innocent and vulnerable, occasionally suave. The character could so easily have been a typical Python caricature, but with Tom Stoppard on the writing team (with Gilliam), Pryce has a lot of scope and he takes full advantage of it, producing a remarkable performance. The surreal world of Brazil closes in on Lowry as he pursues his vision, the guts of the system spilling out when things go awry. Robert de Niro's handyman terrorist adds gravitas without reneging on the style, and Bob Hoskin's ferocious comedy lends menace to the state system. Kim Greist's portrayal of Jill Layton, Lowry's desire, is more realistic. Although it could well be argued that Greist simply didn't get the style, I found her performance a useful counterpoint. Lowry's dream girl turns out to be more real, more earthed than the world he lives in. While the theme of the film will not be novel for many viewers - it's a realization of the world that often punctures adolescent minds - Brazil evinces the brutal nexus between the passionate individual and the state/status quo through a brilliantly distorted lens that accentuates the conflict. The Pythonesque tone to the look, feel and characterizations of Brazil is taken to its finest, most filmic iteration. There are some fine allusions to classic films for movie buffs, and the design is one of the film's major talking points, but for an 18 year-old lad when I first saw it, I was riven by the inhumanity of protocol, social expectations, rules and regulations in a world dominated by bureaucracy, against the fragility of romance and hope. Similarly themed '1984' might be a more powerful film, but it is also comparatively monochromatic. I barely know how to describe the effectiveness of such an overt, theatrical design that so graphically supports the themes. It is often labeled as a satire but the film is much more than this. A febrile heart emerges from the strong stylization (akin to City of Lost Children), engaging strong feeling as much as intellectual entertainment; a rare feat, owing much to Pryce's characterization. I still remember the intense mood I felt leaving the cinema after watching this nearly 30 years ago. Though Brazil borrows heavily from various styles - film-noir, satire, absurdism, surrealism, thriller, action, romance, art film - it is unique, a masterpiece that creates its own genre. It may not be to everyone's taste, but if you have a yen for something very different from the typical blockbuster, you should absolutely positively give Brazil a try. I recommend the international version, without the last scene cut. (132 or 142 minutes). Gilliam reviled the short version, which robs the story of its poignancy, emasculating the central theme. I give the long version full marks.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An interesting mix of genres, but an uneven experience for me
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Bruno Youn
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I appreciate how Brazil encompasses several genres, being both frightening and funny on different occasions. The film had some nice visuals and I liked Terry Gilliam's vision of this dystopian future. However, I didn't find any of the characters to be so memorable or even likable so I had a tough time relating to any of them. I like the satirical tone of the story, but I thought many scenes seemed pretty goofy and cartoonish, which took me out of the film a little bit. The ending was truly great though, being quite tragic and thought-provoking. Overall, Brazil was an uneven experience for me, but certainly an interesting watch.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A very accurate vision of the modern USA
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jjccxx220
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Being an old man, I surprised myself at not having seen this when it came out. Terry Gilliam was a brilliant member of Monte Python's Flying Circus and I would have been interested in anything he did. Now, viewing it nearly thirty years after it came out, his prescience is amazing. For younger members, the Internet didn't exist for most people until the mid 1990's and personal computers wired together were not common at the time this was made. Except for the appearance of the modern world, he got it right. Today, we live in a surveillance society where we are tracked electronically wherever we are and whatever we do. American police practice the kind of assault and then ask questions more and more, as news reports will show. People are divided into the slaves and the government powers. How does a man survive in such a world? He does what our hero does - works his job, keeps his mouth shut and keeps his head down. Until he sees a vision of the woman in his fantasies in real life, and risks all to find her. Again for younger members, who never heard of the Soviet Union unless they had a rare history teacher, Gilliam's society is like what prevailed in that dictatorship. Never tell the truth except to the police, never share an opinion, never trust anyone. In modern America, we find the Soviet Union gone but its principles have traveled here, courtesy of political correctness. Tell the truth or share your opinion, and there is someone who wants to sue you. Trust the wrong person, of whom there are lots, and live to regret it. Finally, the society depicted in "Brazil" is Obama's idea of utopia. He and his crew are working hard to make it happen, and most Americans are too busy with "Survivor" and "American Idol" to know or care. This movie will be a wake-up call, if nothing else.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Just a fantastic and unforgettable experience.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    SamHarrisdrwho
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    My God, this movie gets everything right. The casting is brilliant the acting superb and the directing, MY GOD THE DIRECTING! The story dives to the very heart of bureaucracy in a terrific way. The character of Sam Lowry is one the best in cinematic history. It's beautiful to dive right into his dreams and find out what makes this character tick. But the visual effects are fantastic there is no point diving into the fantastic visuals and art direction because what hasn't been said? What can I possibly add? The soundtrack is just incredible taking one unforgettable song and making it fit the scene perfectly from being sad to scary to happy in a matter of seconds. THIS MOVIE IS WORTH YOUR TIME! If you have a Blu-Ray player, this is the perfect Blu-ray movie. Quite possibly my favorite cinematic experience.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A funny version of George Orwell's 1984
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    lukehere99
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Terry Gilliam, the only American member of Monty Python, writes and directs this comedic take on George Orwell's 1984. This is basically 1984 but much less boring and with jokes. I'll cut to the chase - Brazil is a masterpiece, reasons for this are about to be pointed out. But just if your wondering the only reason this is called Brazil is because of the song (by Geoff Muldaur) which plays every now and again in random places. The acting in Brazil is very good all round, personally I class the cast as an ensemble but some may disagree. Jonathan Pryce is the main character Sam Lowry who I have always thought is a lot like Arthur Dent from The Hitchhikers Guide To The Galaxy. Robert De Niro is the rebel against society Harry Tuttle and is the most likable character in the movie. Bob Hoskins and Derrick O'Connor are 2 comedic ventilation repair men who come to a very amusing sticky end. Michael Palin (also a member of Monty Python) is Sam's old friend in a surprisingly serious, but very well performed, role. Ian Holm (was he never young) is Sam's boss and friend, Jim Broadbent a creep plastic surgeon nicknamed "the acid man". And finally Kim Greist as Sam's one true love and alleged terrorist. All of these roles are brilliant, funny, well acted and memorable. Brazil possibly has the best plot and story of any movie I have ever seen, even if most of the source material is taken from (the extremely depressing) George Orwell's 1984. Everything is unexpected and definitely not predictable, even the love scenes are unique. terry Gilliam (the director) is of course in the hilarious Monty Python team, who are in my opinion the funniest comedy group ever, so you would expect Brazil to be extremely funny. Unfortunately it's not EXTREMELY funny, I laughed on many occasions but not as much as I would have liked to. But then again how can a movie based on 1984 be that hilarious? Finally the ending - in my opinion Brazil has the best and most effective ending of any movie ever. This is a spoiler free review so I won't reveal what happens, but I will say that it's a surprise and certainly not expected. Overall I will give Brazil 9.0/10 and 4.5 stars, because the humour is not as strong as I expected it to be.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    the stuff of dreams
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    (gsygsy)
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Nothing can fully prepare you for BRAZIL. Maybe it's Cervantes' DON QUIXOTE as dreamed by Franz Kafka then written up by Lawrence Sterne. But that doesn't do justice to Terry Gilliam's cinematic bravura. Gilliam is an extravagant director. His work teems with stuff. He is, in this respect, comparable to Baz Lurhmann, and the comparison is instructive. Lurhmann's work feels confined by his stories, as if he's trying to escape them through visuals. Gilliam's films feel more satisfying, at least to me, because the images ARE the story. This isn't to the taste of every moviegoer, I'm sure, but, if you surrender to it, you'll be taken on a roller-coaster ride: thrilling, scary, exhausting, something you say you never want repeat as you join the queue to do it all over again. It is a dystopian tale, and to that extent has a seriousness of purpose that some might think gets lost beneath the extravagance of what's on screen, but I don't share that view. Gilliam's imagination yields a poetic dreamscape which by-passes rationality. It's an environment that makes the dystopia all the more vivid. Savoring the performances is one way of digesting this rich dish. Playing the discontented hero, Sam Lowry, is Jonathan Pryce, a renowned British stage actor. His is a curious presence, without much charm, but undoubtedly charismatic. A quartet of principal relationships stem from his character: his vain mother, played by wonderful Katherine Helmond; the object of his desire, played flatly but efficiently by Kim Griest; his non-conformist alter-ego played by a brilliantly-cast Robert De Nero, strangely but effectively out of step with everyone else's acting style; and, as Sam's conformist antagonist, Michael Palin, charming and chilling in equal measure. Surrounding this central quintet is an unequalled collection of British character actors, some on screen for merely a few seconds, providing Gilliam with an entirely believable world of eccentrics. Those flashing by include Ann Way, Harold Innocent, John Grillo, Oscar Quitak and Ralph Nossek. In slightly larger roles come Jim Broadbent, Bryan Pringle, Gordon Kaye, Bob Hoskins and (dazzling) Ian Richardson. In fully-fledged support are Barbara Hicks, superb Kathryn Pogson, Ian Holm, Peter Vaughan and, giving heart to the only realistic role in the entire movie, the great Sheila Reid. The production design is amazing, the photography superb, and the editing, which must have been quite a challenge, is a masterclass in tact.The score is a bravura achievement by Michael Kamen, who inventively mutates the old song that gives the film its title. The story is pretty straightforward, even if the telling of it is anything but. The dialogue is peppered with memorable exchanges. There are outstanding set-pieces of comic business. Over and above everything is the imagery. The stuff of dreams, occasionally of nightmares. Helmond's smiling face stretched out to breaking point by Broadbent; De Niro engulfed by flying paper; Holm turned into a speaking pavement; Pryce battling with a faceless giant Samurai; a ghastly dinner at an exploding restaurant; the haunting final shot... BRAZIL is an extraordinary cinematic experience.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of the worst movies I have ever seen
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Dejan K
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I don't understand why this movie is rated so highly. The visuals are good, but that's about it. I almost fell asleep halfway through. Add a predictable storyline and you get an absolute snooze fest. This is the movie to watch if you ever have a hard time falling asleep. Highly recommended for anyone with a sleeping disorder. Brazil will get the job done better than pills. The storyline is mediocre and the "absurdity" in the film is irritating rather than imaginative. I didn't get the film at all. Nothing holds the film together, the ending is predictable (I predicted how it was going to end 30 minutes into the movie), and I feel I wasted two hours of my life that I'm never going to get back. Thanks Brazil.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Puzzling adulation
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    colinfeltham
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I've just watched this for the first time (making my way through the UK Top 100). I wanted to like it but found it just didn't make the impact on me its reviews suggested it would. It's a cross between 1984 and Monty Python, but full of corny, dated (unfunny) humour and slapstick antics. The story is trite - I mean, many of us hate bureaucracy and think it overshadows too much of our lives (I do) but that's not a big enough point to keep anyone's interest for 148 minutes. I liked the music, I got the allusions to other films, but despite the acclaimed surrealism here, I wasn't engaged. I am frankly amazed by the level of its critical acclaim - there are far better films. The 1980s version of 1984 is better in its grimness, for example.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Visually and philosophically, it succeeds. As a movie, it's pretentious and all over the place
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    JavikKatarn
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I'm a big fan of Terry Gilliam's work. His comedic work in Monty Python and many of his feature films including Time Bandits and Twelve Monkeys are classics. Brazil is often regarded as his best work and an artistic masterpiece of merging ideas and symbolism and black humour. Like most cinematic classics, I thought I would enjoy the film. However, the film was overall a dreaded bore with a narrative that was all over the place, two-dimensional characters and an overlong climax albeit a film with some compelling ideas and a nice take on Orwell's 1984. The story of Brazil takes place in the far future where Britain has become a totalitarian fascist state. Sam Lowry is a low-level government employee who constantly dreams of saving a woman. One day, he has to correct an error where a man named Archibald Buttle was imprisoned by the government and killed during an interrogation for being suspected of terrorism when he got confused for Archibald Tuttle due to a fly being jammed in the printer (okay, that's quite funny). He notices that the next door neighbour of the Buttles, Jill Layton, has the same face of the woman in his dreams. When Jill is branded as a terrorist after trying to report the mistake of the man's death. Sam then tries to get a transfer to information retrieval to learn more about Jill. The ideas that Brazil gives out are fundamentally not bad themes. Some if it is taken from 1984 but I liked how Gilliam tried to merge them with a comedic element to them and make an argument about the dangers of the errors bureaucracies make. The art direction in this movie is also pretty impressive. The visuals are a bit dated now (it's clearly got the 80s feel to it) but back then they would've been spectacular. A lot of Fritz Lang's Metropolis is present in them. There are also a few funny and amusing moments in the film but the term 'comedy' doesn't hold much water here for me. Roger Ebert was one of the few critics who disliked Brazil, calling it 'hard to follow', I couldn't put it better myself. The main story to the film shouldn't be much of a pain to understand but most of the film revolves around things just happening. There's no clear focus in the film as to what Gilliam wants to tell, just showing a bunch of random stuff occurring and barely getting explanation. This makes the film come across as a complete bore and hard to sit through even on repeated viewings. I get that the film is meant to be sporadic and a bit peculiar in its approach but I still think it's a real nuisance when you have too much on screen and keep throwing constant crap at you without allowing you to comprehend what is being shown. I also cannot buy the romance between Sam and Jill. When the two properly meet the first time, he randomly tells her that he loves her and that he sees her in his dreams. Seriously, who says that to somebody they've just encountered? The two lack chemistry and the romance is only introduced at the end of the second act, making it come across as rushed and murky. I will give credit to the climax for trying to be shocking in its treatment and is a classic example of a funny 'f@&k you' ending. Brazil has some unique ideas, innovative art direction and even a few moments where the comedy works but is overall a shallow and unfocused film that lacks any heart and coherence. It's already become regarded as a classic and I suppose its unfocused narrative has become appreciated by its fans but it failed to get me sucked in and is a depressing experience overall.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Probably one of my favourite movies ever!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    pepsicolasmileyface
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Brazil is that movie where you either love it or hate it, you either think its stupid or that its mind blowing. Well I loved it, This movie completely blew my mind away. This movie looks stunning, the city and the cinematography probably strike me the most. This movie is original and no one can say that it's not an original movie. All the performances were pretty good. In the end though it's the message in the end that matters is about modern life. It shows how people make things so complicated to make things easier and how bureaucracy is sort of destroying us. It shows us the story of a guy bored of his life and then this big change happens to him and his life suddenly becomes interesting after he sees this woman of his dreams at his job. It shows a world torn apart with ridiculous ways of life and then this spark of hope with this man drowning in all of his life. This movie probably has one of my favourite endings when in his mind he's escaped but in the end he's in a chair half dead. Another thing is that every time you watch this film there's always something new to see and these are the reasons why I love this movie.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A rare surrealist film, the best of the Monty Python canon and off-shoots, one of the best movies I've seen
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    berynn-796-758229
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Terry Gilliam's Brazil is set in a deco-style fantasy-noir world blending kitsch fashion and bleak utilitarianism, grey ducting being the most prominent design motif. Sam Lowry (Jonathon Pryce) is a highly competent, guileless functionary in a government ministry, with a dash of charm that hints at the romanticism in his heart. As his dreams propel him away from the comfortable routine, he comes up against the bureaucracy that has hitherto sustained him. Pryce gives perhaps the best performance of his career, comic, fevered, innocent and vulnerable, occasionally suave. The character could so easily have been a typical Python caricature, but with Tom Stoppard on the writing team (with Gilliam), Pryce has a lot of scope and he takes full advantage of it, producing a remarkable performance. The surreal world of Brazil closes in on Lowry as he pursues his vision, the guts of the system spilling out when things go awry. Robert de Niro's handyman terrorist adds gravitas without reneging on the style, and Bob Hoskin's ferocious comedy lends menace to the state system. Kim Greist's portrayal of Jill Layton, Lowry's desire, is more realistic. Although it could well be argued that Greist simply didn't get the style, I found her performance a useful counterpoint. Lowry's dream girl turns out to be more real, more earthed than the world he lives in. While the theme of the film will not be novel for many viewers - it's a realization of the world that often punctures adolescent minds - Brazil evinces the brutal nexus between the passionate individual and the state/status quo through a brilliantly distorted lens that accentuates the conflict. The Pythonesque tone to the look, feel and characterizations of Brazil is taken to its finest, most filmic iteration. There are some fine allusions to classic films for movie buffs, and the design is one of the film's major talking points, but for an 18 year-old lad when I first saw it, I was riven by the inhumanity of protocol, social expectations, rules and regulations in a world dominated by bureaucracy, against the fragility of romance and hope. Similarly themed '1984' might be a more powerful film, but it is also comparatively monochromatic. I barely know how to describe the effectiveness of such an overt, theatrical design that so graphically supports the themes. It is often labeled as a satire but the film is much more than this. A febrile heart emerges from the strong stylization (akin to City of Lost Children), engaging strong feeling as much as intellectual entertainment; a rare feat, owing much to Pryce's characterization. I still remember the intense mood I felt leaving the cinema after watching this nearly 30 years ago. Though Brazil borrows heavily from various styles - film-noir, satire, absurdism, surrealism, thriller, action, romance, art film - it is unique, a masterpiece that creates its own genre. It may not be to everyone's taste, but if you have a yen for something very different from the typical blockbuster, you should absolutely positively give Brazil a try. I recommend the international version, without the last scene cut. (132 or 142 minutes). Gilliam reviled the short version, which robs the story of its poignancy, emasculating the central theme. I give the long version full marks.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An interesting mix of genres, but an uneven experience for me
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Bruno Youn
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I appreciate how Brazil encompasses several genres, being both frightening and funny on different occasions. The film had some nice visuals and I liked Terry Gilliam's vision of this dystopian future. However, I didn't find any of the characters to be so memorable or even likable so I had a tough time relating to any of them. I like the satirical tone of the story, but I thought many scenes seemed pretty goofy and cartoonish, which took me out of the film a little bit. The ending was truly great though, being quite tragic and thought-provoking. Overall, Brazil was an uneven experience for me, but certainly an interesting watch.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A very accurate vision of the modern USA
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jjccxx220
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Being an old man, I surprised myself at not having seen this when it came out. Terry Gilliam was a brilliant member of Monte Python's Flying Circus and I would have been interested in anything he did. Now, viewing it nearly thirty years after it came out, his prescience is amazing. For younger members, the Internet didn't exist for most people until the mid 1990's and personal computers wired together were not common at the time this was made. Except for the appearance of the modern world, he got it right. Today, we live in a surveillance society where we are tracked electronically wherever we are and whatever we do. American police practice the kind of assault and then ask questions more and more, as news reports will show. People are divided into the slaves and the government powers. How does a man survive in such a world? He does what our hero does - works his job, keeps his mouth shut and keeps his head down. Until he sees a vision of the woman in his fantasies in real life, and risks all to find her. Again for younger members, who never heard of the Soviet Union unless they had a rare history teacher, Gilliam's society is like what prevailed in that dictatorship. Never tell the truth except to the police, never share an opinion, never trust anyone. In modern America, we find the Soviet Union gone but its principles have traveled here, courtesy of political correctness. Tell the truth or share your opinion, and there is someone who wants to sue you. Trust the wrong person, of whom there are lots, and live to regret it. Finally, the society depicted in "Brazil" is Obama's idea of utopia. He and his crew are working hard to make it happen, and most Americans are too busy with "Survivor" and "American Idol" to know or care. This movie will be a wake-up call, if nothing else.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Just a fantastic and unforgettable experience.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    SamHarrisdrwho
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    My God, this movie gets everything right. The casting is brilliant the acting superb and the directing, MY GOD THE DIRECTING! The story dives to the very heart of bureaucracy in a terrific way. The character of Sam Lowry is one the best in cinematic history. It's beautiful to dive right into his dreams and find out what makes this character tick. But the visual effects are fantastic there is no point diving into the fantastic visuals and art direction because what hasn't been said? What can I possibly add? The soundtrack is just incredible taking one unforgettable song and making it fit the scene perfectly from being sad to scary to happy in a matter of seconds. THIS MOVIE IS WORTH YOUR TIME! If you have a Blu-Ray player, this is the perfect Blu-ray movie. Quite possibly my favorite cinematic experience.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A funny version of George Orwell's 1984
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    lukehere99
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Terry Gilliam, the only American member of Monty Python, writes and directs this comedic take on George Orwell's 1984. This is basically 1984 but much less boring and with jokes. I'll cut to the chase - Brazil is a masterpiece, reasons for this are about to be pointed out. But just if your wondering the only reason this is called Brazil is because of the song (by Geoff Muldaur) which plays every now and again in random places. The acting in Brazil is very good all round, personally I class the cast as an ensemble but some may disagree. Jonathan Pryce is the main character Sam Lowry who I have always thought is a lot like Arthur Dent from The Hitchhikers Guide To The Galaxy. Robert De Niro is the rebel against society Harry Tuttle and is the most likable character in the movie. Bob Hoskins and Derrick O'Connor are 2 comedic ventilation repair men who come to a very amusing sticky end. Michael Palin (also a member of Monty Python) is Sam's old friend in a surprisingly serious, but very well performed, role. Ian Holm (was he never young) is Sam's boss and friend, Jim Broadbent a creep plastic surgeon nicknamed "the acid man". And finally Kim Greist as Sam's one true love and alleged terrorist. All of these roles are brilliant, funny, well acted and memorable. Brazil possibly has the best plot and story of any movie I have ever seen, even if most of the source material is taken from (the extremely depressing) George Orwell's 1984. Everything is unexpected and definitely not predictable, even the love scenes are unique. terry Gilliam (the director) is of course in the hilarious Monty Python team, who are in my opinion the funniest comedy group ever, so you would expect Brazil to be extremely funny. Unfortunately it's not EXTREMELY funny, I laughed on many occasions but not as much as I would have liked to. But then again how can a movie based on 1984 be that hilarious? Finally the ending - in my opinion Brazil has the best and most effective ending of any movie ever. This is a spoiler free review so I won't reveal what happens, but I will say that it's a surprise and certainly not expected. Overall I will give Brazil 9.0/10 and 4.5 stars, because the humour is not as strong as I expected it to be.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    the stuff of dreams
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    (gsygsy)
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Nothing can fully prepare you for BRAZIL. Maybe it's Cervantes' DON QUIXOTE as dreamed by Franz Kafka then written up by Lawrence Sterne. But that doesn't do justice to Terry Gilliam's cinematic bravura. Gilliam is an extravagant director. His work teems with stuff. He is, in this respect, comparable to Baz Lurhmann, and the comparison is instructive. Lurhmann's work feels confined by his stories, as if he's trying to escape them through visuals. Gilliam's films feel more satisfying, at least to me, because the images ARE the story. This isn't to the taste of every moviegoer, I'm sure, but, if you surrender to it, you'll be taken on a roller-coaster ride: thrilling, scary, exhausting, something you say you never want repeat as you join the queue to do it all over again. It is a dystopian tale, and to that extent has a seriousness of purpose that some might think gets lost beneath the extravagance of what's on screen, but I don't share that view. Gilliam's imagination yields a poetic dreamscape which by-passes rationality. It's an environment that makes the dystopia all the more vivid. Savoring the performances is one way of digesting this rich dish. Playing the discontented hero, Sam Lowry, is Jonathan Pryce, a renowned British stage actor. His is a curious presence, without much charm, but undoubtedly charismatic. A quartet of principal relationships stem from his character: his vain mother, played by wonderful Katherine Helmond; the object of his desire, played flatly but efficiently by Kim Griest; his non-conformist alter-ego played by a brilliantly-cast Robert De Nero, strangely but effectively out of step with everyone else's acting style; and, as Sam's conformist antagonist, Michael Palin, charming and chilling in equal measure. Surrounding this central quintet is an unequalled collection of British character actors, some on screen for merely a few seconds, providing Gilliam with an entirely believable world of eccentrics. Those flashing by include Ann Way, Harold Innocent, John Grillo, Oscar Quitak and Ralph Nossek. In slightly larger roles come Jim Broadbent, Bryan Pringle, Gordon Kaye, Bob Hoskins and (dazzling) Ian Richardson. In fully-fledged support are Barbara Hicks, superb Kathryn Pogson, Ian Holm, Peter Vaughan and, giving heart to the only realistic role in the entire movie, the great Sheila Reid. The production design is amazing, the photography superb, and the editing, which must have been quite a challenge, is a masterclass in tact.The score is a bravura achievement by Michael Kamen, who inventively mutates the old song that gives the film its title. The story is pretty straightforward, even if the telling of it is anything but. The dialogue is peppered with memorable exchanges. There are outstanding set-pieces of comic business. Over and above everything is the imagery. The stuff of dreams, occasionally of nightmares. Helmond's smiling face stretched out to breaking point by Broadbent; De Niro engulfed by flying paper; Holm turned into a speaking pavement; Pryce battling with a faceless giant Samurai; a ghastly dinner at an exploding restaurant; the haunting final shot... BRAZIL is an extraordinary cinematic experience.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of the worst movies I have ever seen
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Dejan K
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I don't understand why this movie is rated so highly. The visuals are good, but that's about it. I almost fell asleep halfway through. Add a predictable storyline and you get an absolute snooze fest. This is the movie to watch if you ever have a hard time falling asleep. Highly recommended for anyone with a sleeping disorder. Brazil will get the job done better than pills. The storyline is mediocre and the "absurdity" in the film is irritating rather than imaginative. I didn't get the film at all. Nothing holds the film together, the ending is predictable (I predicted how it was going to end 30 minutes into the movie), and I feel I wasted two hours of my life that I'm never going to get back. Thanks Brazil.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Puzzling adulation
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    colinfeltham
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I've just watched this for the first time (making my way through the UK Top 100). I wanted to like it but found it just didn't make the impact on me its reviews suggested it would. It's a cross between 1984 and Monty Python, but full of corny, dated (unfunny) humour and slapstick antics. The story is trite - I mean, many of us hate bureaucracy and think it overshadows too much of our lives (I do) but that's not a big enough point to keep anyone's interest for 148 minutes. I liked the music, I got the allusions to other films, but despite the acclaimed surrealism here, I wasn't engaged. I am frankly amazed by the level of its critical acclaim - there are far better films. The 1980s version of 1984 is better in its grimness, for example.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Visually and philosophically, it succeeds. As a movie, it's pretentious and all over the place
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    JavikKatarn
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I'm a big fan of Terry Gilliam's work. His comedic work in Monty Python and many of his feature films including Time Bandits and Twelve Monkeys are classics. Brazil is often regarded as his best work and an artistic masterpiece of merging ideas and symbolism and black humour. Like most cinematic classics, I thought I would enjoy the film. However, the film was overall a dreaded bore with a narrative that was all over the place, two-dimensional characters and an overlong climax albeit a film with some compelling ideas and a nice take on Orwell's 1984. The story of Brazil takes place in the far future where Britain has become a totalitarian fascist state. Sam Lowry is a low-level government employee who constantly dreams of saving a woman. One day, he has to correct an error where a man named Archibald Buttle was imprisoned by the government and killed during an interrogation for being suspected of terrorism when he got confused for Archibald Tuttle due to a fly being jammed in the printer (okay, that's quite funny). He notices that the next door neighbour of the Buttles, Jill Layton, has the same face of the woman in his dreams. When Jill is branded as a terrorist after trying to report the mistake of the man's death. Sam then tries to get a transfer to information retrieval to learn more about Jill. The ideas that Brazil gives out are fundamentally not bad themes. Some if it is taken from 1984 but I liked how Gilliam tried to merge them with a comedic element to them and make an argument about the dangers of the errors bureaucracies make. The art direction in this movie is also pretty impressive. The visuals are a bit dated now (it's clearly got the 80s feel to it) but back then they would've been spectacular. A lot of Fritz Lang's Metropolis is present in them. There are also a few funny and amusing moments in the film but the term 'comedy' doesn't hold much water here for me. Roger Ebert was one of the few critics who disliked Brazil, calling it 'hard to follow', I couldn't put it better myself. The main story to the film shouldn't be much of a pain to understand but most of the film revolves around things just happening. There's no clear focus in the film as to what Gilliam wants to tell, just showing a bunch of random stuff occurring and barely getting explanation. This makes the film come across as a complete bore and hard to sit through even on repeated viewings. I get that the film is meant to be sporadic and a bit peculiar in its approach but I still think it's a real nuisance when you have too much on screen and keep throwing constant crap at you without allowing you to comprehend what is being shown. I also cannot buy the romance between Sam and Jill. When the two properly meet the first time, he randomly tells her that he loves her and that he sees her in his dreams. Seriously, who says that to somebody they've just encountered? The two lack chemistry and the romance is only introduced at the end of the second act, making it come across as rushed and murky. I will give credit to the climax for trying to be shocking in its treatment and is a classic example of a funny 'f@&k you' ending. Brazil has some unique ideas, innovative art direction and even a few moments where the comedy works but is overall a shallow and unfocused film that lacks any heart and coherence. It's already become regarded as a classic and I suppose its unfocused narrative has become appreciated by its fans but it failed to get me sucked in and is a depressing experience overall.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Probably one of my favourite movies ever!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    pepsicolasmileyface
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Brazil is that movie where you either love it or hate it, you either think its stupid or that its mind blowing. Well I loved it, This movie completely blew my mind away. This movie looks stunning, the city and the cinematography probably strike me the most. This movie is original and no one can say that it's not an original movie. All the performances were pretty good. In the end though it's the message in the end that matters is about modern life. It shows how people make things so complicated to make things easier and how bureaucracy is sort of destroying us. It shows us the story of a guy bored of his life and then this big change happens to him and his life suddenly becomes interesting after he sees this woman of his dreams at his job. It shows a world torn apart with ridiculous ways of life and then this spark of hope with this man drowning in all of his life. This movie probably has one of my favourite endings when in his mind he's escaped but in the end he's in a chair half dead. Another thing is that every time you watch this film there's always something new to see and these are the reasons why I love this movie.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
 </reviews>
</filme>
