<filme>
 <id>
  178
 </id>
 <imdburl>
  http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0050083
 </imdburl>
 <ano>
  1957
 </ano>
 <titulo>
  12 Homens e uma Senten&ccedil;a
 </titulo>
 <rating>
  8.9
 </rating>
 <sinopse>
  A dissenting juror in a murder trial slowly manages to convince the others that the case is not as obviously clear as it seemed in court.
 </sinopse>
 <storyline>
  The defense and the prosecution have rested and the jury is filing into the jury room to decide if a young Spanish-American is guilty or innocent of murdering his father. What begins as an open and shut case of murder soon becomes a mini-drama of each of the jurors' prejudices and preconceptions about the trial, the accused, and each other. Based on the play, all of the action takes place on the stage of the jury room.
 </storyline>
 <generos>
  <genero>
   Drama
  </genero>
 </generos>
 <keywords>
  <keyword>
   jury
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   murder
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   trial
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   jury room
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   discussion
  </keyword>
 </keywords>
 <diretores>
  <diretor>
   Sidney Lumet
  </diretor>
 </diretores>
 <escritores>
  <escritor>
   Reginald Rose
  </escritor>
 </escritores>
 <atores>
  <ator>
   Henry Fonda
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Lee J. Cobb
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Martin Balsam
  </ator>
 </atores>
 <reviews>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Masterpiece
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jagar4321
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This film was one of a very few films (<8 films) that I award a perfect 10/10. But what exactly makes a movie 10/10 in my opinion? It has to be a movie that I would watch again and again and realize something new every time. It has to make my mind run to its highest capacity. It has to have acting, dialog, and a story like no other. It has to be something that could be put away for decades at a time and still feel fresh. This film is a perfect 10. Is there any action? no. Does the setting change? no. Is the movie in color? no. So why do I still award it a 10? You must watch it to find out.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Amazing movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    lbmersault
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Amazing film about the complexities of humanity and how some of us can close ourselves to reason at times. The acting is amazing by all the actors. Even the subtle cinematography shines. The director does a great job at creating a tense and claustrophobic mood. The crescendo of the action creates a sense of impending change that characterizes the film. Another interesting concept is that our perceptions can sometimes be so different even when exposed to the same material. We bring our life experiences into making every decision we make and in the case of this film that can have catastrophic results for someone else. The voice of reason will always win in the end.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Rather disorderly than angry
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jgcorrea
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The inflamed comments are probably Pavlovian responses to the movie's politically correct quotient. Quality performers meet deep message. The most obvious flaw in this supposed classic, one of the most super-estimated films in history was as follows: real juries are allowed neither to carry their own experiences nor to consider evidence not presented at trial. If the jury had acted in accordance with the correct legal procedure, there would have been no basis for the plot, therefore no drama, therefore no catharsis. An intriguing theme doesn't always result in a good production. What shall I call a movie including clich&eacute;d, implausible characters, and a foreseeable twist (a 11-to-1 vote changing into 0-to-12)? Juries exist in order to allow the cold letter of the law to be broken, or temporarily suspended. That's what they're all about. That's their raison d'&ecirc;tre. A judge can acquit a suspicious defendant for lack of evidence. A jury may convict him or her for "feeling his or her" guilt. The institution of the jury was thus an historical way to "humanize" lawsuits. If jurors were so one-dimensional, mindless and easy to persuade, courts should certainly keep them afar.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of the Greatest films I have had the pleasure of watching
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    khayaadams
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    There are not many films that can keep you listening intently and watch every move the actors makes but 12 Angry men is one of those movies. Running at an hour and a half and practically the whole one and a half takes place in the back room of a court however never once did I feel bored or uninterested. Each actor brings something to the film, they each play their characters to perfection. Lee J. Cobb in particular plays his character so convincingly one forgets at times that he is acting. This movie goes to show that you don't need fancy effects and expensive sets to create a great film. You just need a great script and superb acting and that what one gets with this film. The plot itself moves along at a pleasing pace. The side talks between the jurors just reinforces the characters that the actors are playing. As I am writing this there has been so news about Jack Klugman being snubbed at the Emmy's and if you watch Mr. Klugman in this film you would understand why people are upset. This has become one of the greatest films I will probably watch and I am saddened that I didn't get to see it sooner.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A masterpiece of acting and filmmaking.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Scott LeBrun (Hey_Sweden)
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Brilliant film version of the televised play, scripted by the plays' author Reginald Rose, and produced by Rose and leading actor Henry Fonda. It's fascinating and compelling, offering memorable showcases to an amazing ensemble. The basic story is solid, but more than that, it's a nice look into a rich variety of characters, each with their own background and reasoning. It's all the more impressive for being a young Sidney Lumets' filmmaking debut; he makes this a highly charged, atmospheric experience. An 18 year old teenager is on trial for murder, and the jury has retired to discuss the case. When things start out, 11 men are ready to convict the boy, and there's one holdout, juror no. eight (Fonda); Fonda doesn't necessarily believe the boy is innocent, but he's passionate in his belief that there's enough *reasonable doubt* in the matter to refrain from voting guilty. He encounters a fair amount of hostility at first, particularly from the excitable juror no. three (Lee J. Cobb), but as the night falls and a storm starts up, he wears down his fellow men a bit at a time, insisting on bringing up facts that he felt weren't adequately explained during the trail. What's so wonderful about "12 Angry Men" is how believable it all is, right down to one juror, the baseball loving juror no. seven (Jack Warden) being willing to change his vote just to get the hell out of there, and the earnest juror no. 11 (George Voskovec) admonishing him for not doing this for the *right* reason. Each actor gets their own chance in the spotlight, and they're all superb. Cobb has the most intense role as a truly stubborn man who's gotten himself personally involved in the case; Ed Begley is equally potent as juror no. 10, another holdout. Martin Balsam, John Fiedler, E.G. Marshall, Jack Klugman, Edward Binns, Joseph Sweeney, and Robert Webber fill out the rest of this powerhouse cast. While the story is quite good dramatically, it's not without some humour, some of it coming from adman Webber. Use of music is sparing, which only adds a sense of realism to the proceedings. One of the most striking moments is when most of the group turns their backs to Begley after he launches into a rather disconcerting rant. Overall, this does deserve to be considered one of the finest American films of all time. It keeps the viewer riveted every step of the way. 10 out of 10.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An absolute masterpiece
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Bruno Youn
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    12 Angry Men is definitely one of the most astonishing dramas I've seen. It has a simple premise, but all the discussions between the jurors were just so captivating and revealing. I liked how they always went back and forth with the case, gathering as many details as possible to find out if there was any room for doubt with the facts presented. Not only director Sidney Lumet masterfully orchestrated an intriguing story filled with little twists, but he also investigated very thoroughly how prejudice and preconceived notions could be in the way of realizing the level of uncertainty of the facts. The performances here were truly remarkable, being another strength of the film. Each juror had unique personality traits and I felt the presence of every single one of them was very important to show interesting characteristics such as indifference, modesty, meticulousness and many others when dealing with the case. If I had to pick my favorite performance of the bunch, it would have to be from Henry Fonda as this persistent and considerate individual who feels the need to talk the case over and over as it's not as obvious as it looks. I really think the other actors were superb as well in their own way though. The fact that each character contributes to adding more depth to the story makes this film such a powerful experience. 12 Angry Men is only my second film from Sidney Lumet, but it certainly ranks among the best of all time and I will be looking forward to seeing more from this brilliant director.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An all time classic
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Ab Siddique
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This trial film tells the story of a jury made up of 12 men as they deliberate the guilt or acquittal of a defendant on the basis of reasonable doubt. This directorial masterpiece by Sydney Lumet is a must watch for all of you. Though the entire movie takes place in a single jury room (with a broken ceiling fan of course) but has got an intoxicating screenplay where several twists and turns awaits you. There's a scene where it starts raining all of a sudden, a scene which brings a fantastic change to the story where you, as an audience, feel like taking a break from the hassle and enjoy rain. Overall, this movie is a must watch and is highly recommended. I cannot discuss much about the story but trust me you won't regret watching it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Really Clever and Realistic Script,
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Dillon Harris
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    12 Angry Men is a unbelievably inspired film with a really well developed storyline and beautiful acting from all twelve men.The movie is literally an hour and a half of twelve members of a jury discussing if a man is guilty or not,it dosen't sound that exciting,but all these characters different personalities and opinions on this man come together so well that its made really enjoyable and intense,the conversations these men have get very deep and they look at every aspect of the night of the murder.I really didn't think it sounded that good but I wanted to watch it since it is so high up on the IMDb Top 250,and rightfully so,there is no movie quite like this one,its really unique.I would highly recommend 12 Angry Men to all moviegoers. A jury of twelve very different men discuss if a man is guilty or not for a murder,but their different opinions make it into a much longer discussion than they expected.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Outstanding movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Aswin Muralidharan
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The film is about jury consisting of 12 people which met for a murder trial. The film starts with just one person who has reasonable doubt that the accused is not guilty. As the film passes he tries to convince others that he may not be guilty. The way the movie is directed is simply outstanding. The movie proceeds with just dialogues. I have never seen any other movie in which a plot has been executed so amazingly. The movie puts most of the modern films to shame. Without much visual effects and technology the plain storytelling style guarantees that any viewer would be enthralled watching it. This is a must watch movie.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    one of the Best classic ever
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    fbawveek
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Great story. Not a big fan of old movies. but this just holds you like a giant magnet. It is impossible to leave the movie until you finish it. Great acting and story. Henry Fonda is excellent as usual. Very captivating throughout. A must watch for any movie lover. You like good movie you must watch it. First time i say this movie as a kid. Didn't get it stopped watching it half way. Than few years back got the DVD in my friend's house and borrowed it watched it and blown away. being a short film maker I learned quite a deal after watching it. by far my favourite henry Fonda movie of all time. will recommend to any one. great movie must see.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Masterpiece
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jagar4321
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This film was one of a very few films (<8 films) that I award a perfect 10/10. But what exactly makes a movie 10/10 in my opinion? It has to be a movie that I would watch again and again and realize something new every time. It has to make my mind run to its highest capacity. It has to have acting, dialog, and a story like no other. It has to be something that could be put away for decades at a time and still feel fresh. This film is a perfect 10. Is there any action? no. Does the setting change? no. Is the movie in color? no. So why do I still award it a 10? You must watch it to find out.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Amazing movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    lbmersault
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Amazing film about the complexities of humanity and how some of us can close ourselves to reason at times. The acting is amazing by all the actors. Even the subtle cinematography shines. The director does a great job at creating a tense and claustrophobic mood. The crescendo of the action creates a sense of impending change that characterizes the film. Another interesting concept is that our perceptions can sometimes be so different even when exposed to the same material. We bring our life experiences into making every decision we make and in the case of this film that can have catastrophic results for someone else. The voice of reason will always win in the end.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Rather disorderly than angry
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jgcorrea
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The inflamed comments are probably Pavlovian responses to the movie's politically correct quotient. Quality performers meet deep message. The most obvious flaw in this supposed classic, one of the most super-estimated films in history was as follows: real juries are allowed neither to carry their own experiences nor to consider evidence not presented at trial. If the jury had acted in accordance with the correct legal procedure, there would have been no basis for the plot, therefore no drama, therefore no catharsis. An intriguing theme doesn't always result in a good production. What shall I call a movie including clich&eacute;d, implausible characters, and a foreseeable twist (a 11-to-1 vote changing into 0-to-12)? Juries exist in order to allow the cold letter of the law to be broken, or temporarily suspended. That's what they're all about. That's their raison d'&ecirc;tre. A judge can acquit a suspicious defendant for lack of evidence. A jury may convict him or her for "feeling his or her" guilt. The institution of the jury was thus an historical way to "humanize" lawsuits. If jurors were so one-dimensional, mindless and easy to persuade, courts should certainly keep them afar.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of the Greatest films I have had the pleasure of watching
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    khayaadams
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    There are not many films that can keep you listening intently and watch every move the actors makes but 12 Angry men is one of those movies. Running at an hour and a half and practically the whole one and a half takes place in the back room of a court however never once did I feel bored or uninterested. Each actor brings something to the film, they each play their characters to perfection. Lee J. Cobb in particular plays his character so convincingly one forgets at times that he is acting. This movie goes to show that you don't need fancy effects and expensive sets to create a great film. You just need a great script and superb acting and that what one gets with this film. The plot itself moves along at a pleasing pace. The side talks between the jurors just reinforces the characters that the actors are playing. As I am writing this there has been so news about Jack Klugman being snubbed at the Emmy's and if you watch Mr. Klugman in this film you would understand why people are upset. This has become one of the greatest films I will probably watch and I am saddened that I didn't get to see it sooner.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A masterpiece of acting and filmmaking.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Scott LeBrun (Hey_Sweden)
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Brilliant film version of the televised play, scripted by the plays' author Reginald Rose, and produced by Rose and leading actor Henry Fonda. It's fascinating and compelling, offering memorable showcases to an amazing ensemble. The basic story is solid, but more than that, it's a nice look into a rich variety of characters, each with their own background and reasoning. It's all the more impressive for being a young Sidney Lumets' filmmaking debut; he makes this a highly charged, atmospheric experience. An 18 year old teenager is on trial for murder, and the jury has retired to discuss the case. When things start out, 11 men are ready to convict the boy, and there's one holdout, juror no. eight (Fonda); Fonda doesn't necessarily believe the boy is innocent, but he's passionate in his belief that there's enough *reasonable doubt* in the matter to refrain from voting guilty. He encounters a fair amount of hostility at first, particularly from the excitable juror no. three (Lee J. Cobb), but as the night falls and a storm starts up, he wears down his fellow men a bit at a time, insisting on bringing up facts that he felt weren't adequately explained during the trail. What's so wonderful about "12 Angry Men" is how believable it all is, right down to one juror, the baseball loving juror no. seven (Jack Warden) being willing to change his vote just to get the hell out of there, and the earnest juror no. 11 (George Voskovec) admonishing him for not doing this for the *right* reason. Each actor gets their own chance in the spotlight, and they're all superb. Cobb has the most intense role as a truly stubborn man who's gotten himself personally involved in the case; Ed Begley is equally potent as juror no. 10, another holdout. Martin Balsam, John Fiedler, E.G. Marshall, Jack Klugman, Edward Binns, Joseph Sweeney, and Robert Webber fill out the rest of this powerhouse cast. While the story is quite good dramatically, it's not without some humour, some of it coming from adman Webber. Use of music is sparing, which only adds a sense of realism to the proceedings. One of the most striking moments is when most of the group turns their backs to Begley after he launches into a rather disconcerting rant. Overall, this does deserve to be considered one of the finest American films of all time. It keeps the viewer riveted every step of the way. 10 out of 10.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An absolute masterpiece
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Bruno Youn
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    12 Angry Men is definitely one of the most astonishing dramas I've seen. It has a simple premise, but all the discussions between the jurors were just so captivating and revealing. I liked how they always went back and forth with the case, gathering as many details as possible to find out if there was any room for doubt with the facts presented. Not only director Sidney Lumet masterfully orchestrated an intriguing story filled with little twists, but he also investigated very thoroughly how prejudice and preconceived notions could be in the way of realizing the level of uncertainty of the facts. The performances here were truly remarkable, being another strength of the film. Each juror had unique personality traits and I felt the presence of every single one of them was very important to show interesting characteristics such as indifference, modesty, meticulousness and many others when dealing with the case. If I had to pick my favorite performance of the bunch, it would have to be from Henry Fonda as this persistent and considerate individual who feels the need to talk the case over and over as it's not as obvious as it looks. I really think the other actors were superb as well in their own way though. The fact that each character contributes to adding more depth to the story makes this film such a powerful experience. 12 Angry Men is only my second film from Sidney Lumet, but it certainly ranks among the best of all time and I will be looking forward to seeing more from this brilliant director.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An all time classic
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Ab Siddique
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This trial film tells the story of a jury made up of 12 men as they deliberate the guilt or acquittal of a defendant on the basis of reasonable doubt. This directorial masterpiece by Sydney Lumet is a must watch for all of you. Though the entire movie takes place in a single jury room (with a broken ceiling fan of course) but has got an intoxicating screenplay where several twists and turns awaits you. There's a scene where it starts raining all of a sudden, a scene which brings a fantastic change to the story where you, as an audience, feel like taking a break from the hassle and enjoy rain. Overall, this movie is a must watch and is highly recommended. I cannot discuss much about the story but trust me you won't regret watching it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Really Clever and Realistic Script,
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Dillon Harris
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    12 Angry Men is a unbelievably inspired film with a really well developed storyline and beautiful acting from all twelve men.The movie is literally an hour and a half of twelve members of a jury discussing if a man is guilty or not,it dosen't sound that exciting,but all these characters different personalities and opinions on this man come together so well that its made really enjoyable and intense,the conversations these men have get very deep and they look at every aspect of the night of the murder.I really didn't think it sounded that good but I wanted to watch it since it is so high up on the IMDb Top 250,and rightfully so,there is no movie quite like this one,its really unique.I would highly recommend 12 Angry Men to all moviegoers. A jury of twelve very different men discuss if a man is guilty or not for a murder,but their different opinions make it into a much longer discussion than they expected.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Outstanding movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Aswin Muralidharan
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The film is about jury consisting of 12 people which met for a murder trial. The film starts with just one person who has reasonable doubt that the accused is not guilty. As the film passes he tries to convince others that he may not be guilty. The way the movie is directed is simply outstanding. The movie proceeds with just dialogues. I have never seen any other movie in which a plot has been executed so amazingly. The movie puts most of the modern films to shame. Without much visual effects and technology the plain storytelling style guarantees that any viewer would be enthralled watching it. This is a must watch movie.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    one of the Best classic ever
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    fbawveek
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Great story. Not a big fan of old movies. but this just holds you like a giant magnet. It is impossible to leave the movie until you finish it. Great acting and story. Henry Fonda is excellent as usual. Very captivating throughout. A must watch for any movie lover. You like good movie you must watch it. First time i say this movie as a kid. Didn't get it stopped watching it half way. Than few years back got the DVD in my friend's house and borrowed it watched it and blown away. being a short film maker I learned quite a deal after watching it. by far my favourite henry Fonda movie of all time. will recommend to any one. great movie must see.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Masterpiece
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jagar4321
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This film was one of a very few films (<8 films) that I award a perfect 10/10. But what exactly makes a movie 10/10 in my opinion? It has to be a movie that I would watch again and again and realize something new every time. It has to make my mind run to its highest capacity. It has to have acting, dialog, and a story like no other. It has to be something that could be put away for decades at a time and still feel fresh. This film is a perfect 10. Is there any action? no. Does the setting change? no. Is the movie in color? no. So why do I still award it a 10? You must watch it to find out.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Amazing movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    lbmersault
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Amazing film about the complexities of humanity and how some of us can close ourselves to reason at times. The acting is amazing by all the actors. Even the subtle cinematography shines. The director does a great job at creating a tense and claustrophobic mood. The crescendo of the action creates a sense of impending change that characterizes the film. Another interesting concept is that our perceptions can sometimes be so different even when exposed to the same material. We bring our life experiences into making every decision we make and in the case of this film that can have catastrophic results for someone else. The voice of reason will always win in the end.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Rather disorderly than angry
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jgcorrea
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The inflamed comments are probably Pavlovian responses to the movie's politically correct quotient. Quality performers meet deep message. The most obvious flaw in this supposed classic, one of the most super-estimated films in history was as follows: real juries are allowed neither to carry their own experiences nor to consider evidence not presented at trial. If the jury had acted in accordance with the correct legal procedure, there would have been no basis for the plot, therefore no drama, therefore no catharsis. An intriguing theme doesn't always result in a good production. What shall I call a movie including clich&eacute;d, implausible characters, and a foreseeable twist (a 11-to-1 vote changing into 0-to-12)? Juries exist in order to allow the cold letter of the law to be broken, or temporarily suspended. That's what they're all about. That's their raison d'&ecirc;tre. A judge can acquit a suspicious defendant for lack of evidence. A jury may convict him or her for "feeling his or her" guilt. The institution of the jury was thus an historical way to "humanize" lawsuits. If jurors were so one-dimensional, mindless and easy to persuade, courts should certainly keep them afar.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of the Greatest films I have had the pleasure of watching
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    khayaadams
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    There are not many films that can keep you listening intently and watch every move the actors makes but 12 Angry men is one of those movies. Running at an hour and a half and practically the whole one and a half takes place in the back room of a court however never once did I feel bored or uninterested. Each actor brings something to the film, they each play their characters to perfection. Lee J. Cobb in particular plays his character so convincingly one forgets at times that he is acting. This movie goes to show that you don't need fancy effects and expensive sets to create a great film. You just need a great script and superb acting and that what one gets with this film. The plot itself moves along at a pleasing pace. The side talks between the jurors just reinforces the characters that the actors are playing. As I am writing this there has been so news about Jack Klugman being snubbed at the Emmy's and if you watch Mr. Klugman in this film you would understand why people are upset. This has become one of the greatest films I will probably watch and I am saddened that I didn't get to see it sooner.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A masterpiece of acting and filmmaking.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Scott LeBrun (Hey_Sweden)
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Brilliant film version of the televised play, scripted by the plays' author Reginald Rose, and produced by Rose and leading actor Henry Fonda. It's fascinating and compelling, offering memorable showcases to an amazing ensemble. The basic story is solid, but more than that, it's a nice look into a rich variety of characters, each with their own background and reasoning. It's all the more impressive for being a young Sidney Lumets' filmmaking debut; he makes this a highly charged, atmospheric experience. An 18 year old teenager is on trial for murder, and the jury has retired to discuss the case. When things start out, 11 men are ready to convict the boy, and there's one holdout, juror no. eight (Fonda); Fonda doesn't necessarily believe the boy is innocent, but he's passionate in his belief that there's enough *reasonable doubt* in the matter to refrain from voting guilty. He encounters a fair amount of hostility at first, particularly from the excitable juror no. three (Lee J. Cobb), but as the night falls and a storm starts up, he wears down his fellow men a bit at a time, insisting on bringing up facts that he felt weren't adequately explained during the trail. What's so wonderful about "12 Angry Men" is how believable it all is, right down to one juror, the baseball loving juror no. seven (Jack Warden) being willing to change his vote just to get the hell out of there, and the earnest juror no. 11 (George Voskovec) admonishing him for not doing this for the *right* reason. Each actor gets their own chance in the spotlight, and they're all superb. Cobb has the most intense role as a truly stubborn man who's gotten himself personally involved in the case; Ed Begley is equally potent as juror no. 10, another holdout. Martin Balsam, John Fiedler, E.G. Marshall, Jack Klugman, Edward Binns, Joseph Sweeney, and Robert Webber fill out the rest of this powerhouse cast. While the story is quite good dramatically, it's not without some humour, some of it coming from adman Webber. Use of music is sparing, which only adds a sense of realism to the proceedings. One of the most striking moments is when most of the group turns their backs to Begley after he launches into a rather disconcerting rant. Overall, this does deserve to be considered one of the finest American films of all time. It keeps the viewer riveted every step of the way. 10 out of 10.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An absolute masterpiece
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Bruno Youn
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    12 Angry Men is definitely one of the most astonishing dramas I've seen. It has a simple premise, but all the discussions between the jurors were just so captivating and revealing. I liked how they always went back and forth with the case, gathering as many details as possible to find out if there was any room for doubt with the facts presented. Not only director Sidney Lumet masterfully orchestrated an intriguing story filled with little twists, but he also investigated very thoroughly how prejudice and preconceived notions could be in the way of realizing the level of uncertainty of the facts. The performances here were truly remarkable, being another strength of the film. Each juror had unique personality traits and I felt the presence of every single one of them was very important to show interesting characteristics such as indifference, modesty, meticulousness and many others when dealing with the case. If I had to pick my favorite performance of the bunch, it would have to be from Henry Fonda as this persistent and considerate individual who feels the need to talk the case over and over as it's not as obvious as it looks. I really think the other actors were superb as well in their own way though. The fact that each character contributes to adding more depth to the story makes this film such a powerful experience. 12 Angry Men is only my second film from Sidney Lumet, but it certainly ranks among the best of all time and I will be looking forward to seeing more from this brilliant director.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An all time classic
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Ab Siddique
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This trial film tells the story of a jury made up of 12 men as they deliberate the guilt or acquittal of a defendant on the basis of reasonable doubt. This directorial masterpiece by Sydney Lumet is a must watch for all of you. Though the entire movie takes place in a single jury room (with a broken ceiling fan of course) but has got an intoxicating screenplay where several twists and turns awaits you. There's a scene where it starts raining all of a sudden, a scene which brings a fantastic change to the story where you, as an audience, feel like taking a break from the hassle and enjoy rain. Overall, this movie is a must watch and is highly recommended. I cannot discuss much about the story but trust me you won't regret watching it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Really Clever and Realistic Script,
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Dillon Harris
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    12 Angry Men is a unbelievably inspired film with a really well developed storyline and beautiful acting from all twelve men.The movie is literally an hour and a half of twelve members of a jury discussing if a man is guilty or not,it dosen't sound that exciting,but all these characters different personalities and opinions on this man come together so well that its made really enjoyable and intense,the conversations these men have get very deep and they look at every aspect of the night of the murder.I really didn't think it sounded that good but I wanted to watch it since it is so high up on the IMDb Top 250,and rightfully so,there is no movie quite like this one,its really unique.I would highly recommend 12 Angry Men to all moviegoers. A jury of twelve very different men discuss if a man is guilty or not for a murder,but their different opinions make it into a much longer discussion than they expected.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Outstanding movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Aswin Muralidharan
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The film is about jury consisting of 12 people which met for a murder trial. The film starts with just one person who has reasonable doubt that the accused is not guilty. As the film passes he tries to convince others that he may not be guilty. The way the movie is directed is simply outstanding. The movie proceeds with just dialogues. I have never seen any other movie in which a plot has been executed so amazingly. The movie puts most of the modern films to shame. Without much visual effects and technology the plain storytelling style guarantees that any viewer would be enthralled watching it. This is a must watch movie.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    one of the Best classic ever
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    fbawveek
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Great story. Not a big fan of old movies. but this just holds you like a giant magnet. It is impossible to leave the movie until you finish it. Great acting and story. Henry Fonda is excellent as usual. Very captivating throughout. A must watch for any movie lover. You like good movie you must watch it. First time i say this movie as a kid. Didn't get it stopped watching it half way. Than few years back got the DVD in my friend's house and borrowed it watched it and blown away. being a short film maker I learned quite a deal after watching it. by far my favourite henry Fonda movie of all time. will recommend to any one. great movie must see.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Masterpiece
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jagar4321
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This film was one of a very few films (<8 films) that I award a perfect 10/10. But what exactly makes a movie 10/10 in my opinion? It has to be a movie that I would watch again and again and realize something new every time. It has to make my mind run to its highest capacity. It has to have acting, dialog, and a story like no other. It has to be something that could be put away for decades at a time and still feel fresh. This film is a perfect 10. Is there any action? no. Does the setting change? no. Is the movie in color? no. So why do I still award it a 10? You must watch it to find out.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Amazing movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    lbmersault
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Amazing film about the complexities of humanity and how some of us can close ourselves to reason at times. The acting is amazing by all the actors. Even the subtle cinematography shines. The director does a great job at creating a tense and claustrophobic mood. The crescendo of the action creates a sense of impending change that characterizes the film. Another interesting concept is that our perceptions can sometimes be so different even when exposed to the same material. We bring our life experiences into making every decision we make and in the case of this film that can have catastrophic results for someone else. The voice of reason will always win in the end.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Rather disorderly than angry
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jgcorrea
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The inflamed comments are probably Pavlovian responses to the movie's politically correct quotient. Quality performers meet deep message. The most obvious flaw in this supposed classic, one of the most super-estimated films in history was as follows: real juries are allowed neither to carry their own experiences nor to consider evidence not presented at trial. If the jury had acted in accordance with the correct legal procedure, there would have been no basis for the plot, therefore no drama, therefore no catharsis. An intriguing theme doesn't always result in a good production. What shall I call a movie including clich&eacute;d, implausible characters, and a foreseeable twist (a 11-to-1 vote changing into 0-to-12)? Juries exist in order to allow the cold letter of the law to be broken, or temporarily suspended. That's what they're all about. That's their raison d'&ecirc;tre. A judge can acquit a suspicious defendant for lack of evidence. A jury may convict him or her for "feeling his or her" guilt. The institution of the jury was thus an historical way to "humanize" lawsuits. If jurors were so one-dimensional, mindless and easy to persuade, courts should certainly keep them afar.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of the Greatest films I have had the pleasure of watching
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    khayaadams
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    There are not many films that can keep you listening intently and watch every move the actors makes but 12 Angry men is one of those movies. Running at an hour and a half and practically the whole one and a half takes place in the back room of a court however never once did I feel bored or uninterested. Each actor brings something to the film, they each play their characters to perfection. Lee J. Cobb in particular plays his character so convincingly one forgets at times that he is acting. This movie goes to show that you don't need fancy effects and expensive sets to create a great film. You just need a great script and superb acting and that what one gets with this film. The plot itself moves along at a pleasing pace. The side talks between the jurors just reinforces the characters that the actors are playing. As I am writing this there has been so news about Jack Klugman being snubbed at the Emmy's and if you watch Mr. Klugman in this film you would understand why people are upset. This has become one of the greatest films I will probably watch and I am saddened that I didn't get to see it sooner.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A masterpiece of acting and filmmaking.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Scott LeBrun (Hey_Sweden)
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Brilliant film version of the televised play, scripted by the plays' author Reginald Rose, and produced by Rose and leading actor Henry Fonda. It's fascinating and compelling, offering memorable showcases to an amazing ensemble. The basic story is solid, but more than that, it's a nice look into a rich variety of characters, each with their own background and reasoning. It's all the more impressive for being a young Sidney Lumets' filmmaking debut; he makes this a highly charged, atmospheric experience. An 18 year old teenager is on trial for murder, and the jury has retired to discuss the case. When things start out, 11 men are ready to convict the boy, and there's one holdout, juror no. eight (Fonda); Fonda doesn't necessarily believe the boy is innocent, but he's passionate in his belief that there's enough *reasonable doubt* in the matter to refrain from voting guilty. He encounters a fair amount of hostility at first, particularly from the excitable juror no. three (Lee J. Cobb), but as the night falls and a storm starts up, he wears down his fellow men a bit at a time, insisting on bringing up facts that he felt weren't adequately explained during the trail. What's so wonderful about "12 Angry Men" is how believable it all is, right down to one juror, the baseball loving juror no. seven (Jack Warden) being willing to change his vote just to get the hell out of there, and the earnest juror no. 11 (George Voskovec) admonishing him for not doing this for the *right* reason. Each actor gets their own chance in the spotlight, and they're all superb. Cobb has the most intense role as a truly stubborn man who's gotten himself personally involved in the case; Ed Begley is equally potent as juror no. 10, another holdout. Martin Balsam, John Fiedler, E.G. Marshall, Jack Klugman, Edward Binns, Joseph Sweeney, and Robert Webber fill out the rest of this powerhouse cast. While the story is quite good dramatically, it's not without some humour, some of it coming from adman Webber. Use of music is sparing, which only adds a sense of realism to the proceedings. One of the most striking moments is when most of the group turns their backs to Begley after he launches into a rather disconcerting rant. Overall, this does deserve to be considered one of the finest American films of all time. It keeps the viewer riveted every step of the way. 10 out of 10.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An absolute masterpiece
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Bruno Youn
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    12 Angry Men is definitely one of the most astonishing dramas I've seen. It has a simple premise, but all the discussions between the jurors were just so captivating and revealing. I liked how they always went back and forth with the case, gathering as many details as possible to find out if there was any room for doubt with the facts presented. Not only director Sidney Lumet masterfully orchestrated an intriguing story filled with little twists, but he also investigated very thoroughly how prejudice and preconceived notions could be in the way of realizing the level of uncertainty of the facts. The performances here were truly remarkable, being another strength of the film. Each juror had unique personality traits and I felt the presence of every single one of them was very important to show interesting characteristics such as indifference, modesty, meticulousness and many others when dealing with the case. If I had to pick my favorite performance of the bunch, it would have to be from Henry Fonda as this persistent and considerate individual who feels the need to talk the case over and over as it's not as obvious as it looks. I really think the other actors were superb as well in their own way though. The fact that each character contributes to adding more depth to the story makes this film such a powerful experience. 12 Angry Men is only my second film from Sidney Lumet, but it certainly ranks among the best of all time and I will be looking forward to seeing more from this brilliant director.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An all time classic
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Ab Siddique
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This trial film tells the story of a jury made up of 12 men as they deliberate the guilt or acquittal of a defendant on the basis of reasonable doubt. This directorial masterpiece by Sydney Lumet is a must watch for all of you. Though the entire movie takes place in a single jury room (with a broken ceiling fan of course) but has got an intoxicating screenplay where several twists and turns awaits you. There's a scene where it starts raining all of a sudden, a scene which brings a fantastic change to the story where you, as an audience, feel like taking a break from the hassle and enjoy rain. Overall, this movie is a must watch and is highly recommended. I cannot discuss much about the story but trust me you won't regret watching it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Really Clever and Realistic Script,
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Dillon Harris
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    12 Angry Men is a unbelievably inspired film with a really well developed storyline and beautiful acting from all twelve men.The movie is literally an hour and a half of twelve members of a jury discussing if a man is guilty or not,it dosen't sound that exciting,but all these characters different personalities and opinions on this man come together so well that its made really enjoyable and intense,the conversations these men have get very deep and they look at every aspect of the night of the murder.I really didn't think it sounded that good but I wanted to watch it since it is so high up on the IMDb Top 250,and rightfully so,there is no movie quite like this one,its really unique.I would highly recommend 12 Angry Men to all moviegoers. A jury of twelve very different men discuss if a man is guilty or not for a murder,but their different opinions make it into a much longer discussion than they expected.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Outstanding movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Aswin Muralidharan
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The film is about jury consisting of 12 people which met for a murder trial. The film starts with just one person who has reasonable doubt that the accused is not guilty. As the film passes he tries to convince others that he may not be guilty. The way the movie is directed is simply outstanding. The movie proceeds with just dialogues. I have never seen any other movie in which a plot has been executed so amazingly. The movie puts most of the modern films to shame. Without much visual effects and technology the plain storytelling style guarantees that any viewer would be enthralled watching it. This is a must watch movie.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    one of the Best classic ever
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    fbawveek
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Great story. Not a big fan of old movies. but this just holds you like a giant magnet. It is impossible to leave the movie until you finish it. Great acting and story. Henry Fonda is excellent as usual. Very captivating throughout. A must watch for any movie lover. You like good movie you must watch it. First time i say this movie as a kid. Didn't get it stopped watching it half way. Than few years back got the DVD in my friend's house and borrowed it watched it and blown away. being a short film maker I learned quite a deal after watching it. by far my favourite henry Fonda movie of all time. will recommend to any one. great movie must see.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Masterpiece
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jagar4321
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This film was one of a very few films (<8 films) that I award a perfect 10/10. But what exactly makes a movie 10/10 in my opinion? It has to be a movie that I would watch again and again and realize something new every time. It has to make my mind run to its highest capacity. It has to have acting, dialog, and a story like no other. It has to be something that could be put away for decades at a time and still feel fresh. This film is a perfect 10. Is there any action? no. Does the setting change? no. Is the movie in color? no. So why do I still award it a 10? You must watch it to find out.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Amazing movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    lbmersault
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Amazing film about the complexities of humanity and how some of us can close ourselves to reason at times. The acting is amazing by all the actors. Even the subtle cinematography shines. The director does a great job at creating a tense and claustrophobic mood. The crescendo of the action creates a sense of impending change that characterizes the film. Another interesting concept is that our perceptions can sometimes be so different even when exposed to the same material. We bring our life experiences into making every decision we make and in the case of this film that can have catastrophic results for someone else. The voice of reason will always win in the end.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Rather disorderly than angry
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jgcorrea
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The inflamed comments are probably Pavlovian responses to the movie's politically correct quotient. Quality performers meet deep message. The most obvious flaw in this supposed classic, one of the most super-estimated films in history was as follows: real juries are allowed neither to carry their own experiences nor to consider evidence not presented at trial. If the jury had acted in accordance with the correct legal procedure, there would have been no basis for the plot, therefore no drama, therefore no catharsis. An intriguing theme doesn't always result in a good production. What shall I call a movie including clich&eacute;d, implausible characters, and a foreseeable twist (a 11-to-1 vote changing into 0-to-12)? Juries exist in order to allow the cold letter of the law to be broken, or temporarily suspended. That's what they're all about. That's their raison d'&ecirc;tre. A judge can acquit a suspicious defendant for lack of evidence. A jury may convict him or her for "feeling his or her" guilt. The institution of the jury was thus an historical way to "humanize" lawsuits. If jurors were so one-dimensional, mindless and easy to persuade, courts should certainly keep them afar.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of the Greatest films I have had the pleasure of watching
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    khayaadams
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    There are not many films that can keep you listening intently and watch every move the actors makes but 12 Angry men is one of those movies. Running at an hour and a half and practically the whole one and a half takes place in the back room of a court however never once did I feel bored or uninterested. Each actor brings something to the film, they each play their characters to perfection. Lee J. Cobb in particular plays his character so convincingly one forgets at times that he is acting. This movie goes to show that you don't need fancy effects and expensive sets to create a great film. You just need a great script and superb acting and that what one gets with this film. The plot itself moves along at a pleasing pace. The side talks between the jurors just reinforces the characters that the actors are playing. As I am writing this there has been so news about Jack Klugman being snubbed at the Emmy's and if you watch Mr. Klugman in this film you would understand why people are upset. This has become one of the greatest films I will probably watch and I am saddened that I didn't get to see it sooner.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A masterpiece of acting and filmmaking.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Scott LeBrun (Hey_Sweden)
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Brilliant film version of the televised play, scripted by the plays' author Reginald Rose, and produced by Rose and leading actor Henry Fonda. It's fascinating and compelling, offering memorable showcases to an amazing ensemble. The basic story is solid, but more than that, it's a nice look into a rich variety of characters, each with their own background and reasoning. It's all the more impressive for being a young Sidney Lumets' filmmaking debut; he makes this a highly charged, atmospheric experience. An 18 year old teenager is on trial for murder, and the jury has retired to discuss the case. When things start out, 11 men are ready to convict the boy, and there's one holdout, juror no. eight (Fonda); Fonda doesn't necessarily believe the boy is innocent, but he's passionate in his belief that there's enough *reasonable doubt* in the matter to refrain from voting guilty. He encounters a fair amount of hostility at first, particularly from the excitable juror no. three (Lee J. Cobb), but as the night falls and a storm starts up, he wears down his fellow men a bit at a time, insisting on bringing up facts that he felt weren't adequately explained during the trail. What's so wonderful about "12 Angry Men" is how believable it all is, right down to one juror, the baseball loving juror no. seven (Jack Warden) being willing to change his vote just to get the hell out of there, and the earnest juror no. 11 (George Voskovec) admonishing him for not doing this for the *right* reason. Each actor gets their own chance in the spotlight, and they're all superb. Cobb has the most intense role as a truly stubborn man who's gotten himself personally involved in the case; Ed Begley is equally potent as juror no. 10, another holdout. Martin Balsam, John Fiedler, E.G. Marshall, Jack Klugman, Edward Binns, Joseph Sweeney, and Robert Webber fill out the rest of this powerhouse cast. While the story is quite good dramatically, it's not without some humour, some of it coming from adman Webber. Use of music is sparing, which only adds a sense of realism to the proceedings. One of the most striking moments is when most of the group turns their backs to Begley after he launches into a rather disconcerting rant. Overall, this does deserve to be considered one of the finest American films of all time. It keeps the viewer riveted every step of the way. 10 out of 10.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An absolute masterpiece
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Bruno Youn
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    12 Angry Men is definitely one of the most astonishing dramas I've seen. It has a simple premise, but all the discussions between the jurors were just so captivating and revealing. I liked how they always went back and forth with the case, gathering as many details as possible to find out if there was any room for doubt with the facts presented. Not only director Sidney Lumet masterfully orchestrated an intriguing story filled with little twists, but he also investigated very thoroughly how prejudice and preconceived notions could be in the way of realizing the level of uncertainty of the facts. The performances here were truly remarkable, being another strength of the film. Each juror had unique personality traits and I felt the presence of every single one of them was very important to show interesting characteristics such as indifference, modesty, meticulousness and many others when dealing with the case. If I had to pick my favorite performance of the bunch, it would have to be from Henry Fonda as this persistent and considerate individual who feels the need to talk the case over and over as it's not as obvious as it looks. I really think the other actors were superb as well in their own way though. The fact that each character contributes to adding more depth to the story makes this film such a powerful experience. 12 Angry Men is only my second film from Sidney Lumet, but it certainly ranks among the best of all time and I will be looking forward to seeing more from this brilliant director.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An all time classic
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Ab Siddique
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This trial film tells the story of a jury made up of 12 men as they deliberate the guilt or acquittal of a defendant on the basis of reasonable doubt. This directorial masterpiece by Sydney Lumet is a must watch for all of you. Though the entire movie takes place in a single jury room (with a broken ceiling fan of course) but has got an intoxicating screenplay where several twists and turns awaits you. There's a scene where it starts raining all of a sudden, a scene which brings a fantastic change to the story where you, as an audience, feel like taking a break from the hassle and enjoy rain. Overall, this movie is a must watch and is highly recommended. I cannot discuss much about the story but trust me you won't regret watching it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Really Clever and Realistic Script,
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Dillon Harris
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    12 Angry Men is a unbelievably inspired film with a really well developed storyline and beautiful acting from all twelve men.The movie is literally an hour and a half of twelve members of a jury discussing if a man is guilty or not,it dosen't sound that exciting,but all these characters different personalities and opinions on this man come together so well that its made really enjoyable and intense,the conversations these men have get very deep and they look at every aspect of the night of the murder.I really didn't think it sounded that good but I wanted to watch it since it is so high up on the IMDb Top 250,and rightfully so,there is no movie quite like this one,its really unique.I would highly recommend 12 Angry Men to all moviegoers. A jury of twelve very different men discuss if a man is guilty or not for a murder,but their different opinions make it into a much longer discussion than they expected.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Outstanding movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Aswin Muralidharan
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The film is about jury consisting of 12 people which met for a murder trial. The film starts with just one person who has reasonable doubt that the accused is not guilty. As the film passes he tries to convince others that he may not be guilty. The way the movie is directed is simply outstanding. The movie proceeds with just dialogues. I have never seen any other movie in which a plot has been executed so amazingly. The movie puts most of the modern films to shame. Without much visual effects and technology the plain storytelling style guarantees that any viewer would be enthralled watching it. This is a must watch movie.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    one of the Best classic ever
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    fbawveek
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Great story. Not a big fan of old movies. but this just holds you like a giant magnet. It is impossible to leave the movie until you finish it. Great acting and story. Henry Fonda is excellent as usual. Very captivating throughout. A must watch for any movie lover. You like good movie you must watch it. First time i say this movie as a kid. Didn't get it stopped watching it half way. Than few years back got the DVD in my friend's house and borrowed it watched it and blown away. being a short film maker I learned quite a deal after watching it. by far my favourite henry Fonda movie of all time. will recommend to any one. great movie must see.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Masterpiece
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jagar4321
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This film was one of a very few films (<8 films) that I award a perfect 10/10. But what exactly makes a movie 10/10 in my opinion? It has to be a movie that I would watch again and again and realize something new every time. It has to make my mind run to its highest capacity. It has to have acting, dialog, and a story like no other. It has to be something that could be put away for decades at a time and still feel fresh. This film is a perfect 10. Is there any action? no. Does the setting change? no. Is the movie in color? no. So why do I still award it a 10? You must watch it to find out.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Amazing movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    lbmersault
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Amazing film about the complexities of humanity and how some of us can close ourselves to reason at times. The acting is amazing by all the actors. Even the subtle cinematography shines. The director does a great job at creating a tense and claustrophobic mood. The crescendo of the action creates a sense of impending change that characterizes the film. Another interesting concept is that our perceptions can sometimes be so different even when exposed to the same material. We bring our life experiences into making every decision we make and in the case of this film that can have catastrophic results for someone else. The voice of reason will always win in the end.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Rather disorderly than angry
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jgcorrea
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The inflamed comments are probably Pavlovian responses to the movie's politically correct quotient. Quality performers meet deep message. The most obvious flaw in this supposed classic, one of the most super-estimated films in history was as follows: real juries are allowed neither to carry their own experiences nor to consider evidence not presented at trial. If the jury had acted in accordance with the correct legal procedure, there would have been no basis for the plot, therefore no drama, therefore no catharsis. An intriguing theme doesn't always result in a good production. What shall I call a movie including clich&eacute;d, implausible characters, and a foreseeable twist (a 11-to-1 vote changing into 0-to-12)? Juries exist in order to allow the cold letter of the law to be broken, or temporarily suspended. That's what they're all about. That's their raison d'&ecirc;tre. A judge can acquit a suspicious defendant for lack of evidence. A jury may convict him or her for "feeling his or her" guilt. The institution of the jury was thus an historical way to "humanize" lawsuits. If jurors were so one-dimensional, mindless and easy to persuade, courts should certainly keep them afar.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of the Greatest films I have had the pleasure of watching
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    khayaadams
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    There are not many films that can keep you listening intently and watch every move the actors makes but 12 Angry men is one of those movies. Running at an hour and a half and practically the whole one and a half takes place in the back room of a court however never once did I feel bored or uninterested. Each actor brings something to the film, they each play their characters to perfection. Lee J. Cobb in particular plays his character so convincingly one forgets at times that he is acting. This movie goes to show that you don't need fancy effects and expensive sets to create a great film. You just need a great script and superb acting and that what one gets with this film. The plot itself moves along at a pleasing pace. The side talks between the jurors just reinforces the characters that the actors are playing. As I am writing this there has been so news about Jack Klugman being snubbed at the Emmy's and if you watch Mr. Klugman in this film you would understand why people are upset. This has become one of the greatest films I will probably watch and I am saddened that I didn't get to see it sooner.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A masterpiece of acting and filmmaking.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Scott LeBrun (Hey_Sweden)
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Brilliant film version of the televised play, scripted by the plays' author Reginald Rose, and produced by Rose and leading actor Henry Fonda. It's fascinating and compelling, offering memorable showcases to an amazing ensemble. The basic story is solid, but more than that, it's a nice look into a rich variety of characters, each with their own background and reasoning. It's all the more impressive for being a young Sidney Lumets' filmmaking debut; he makes this a highly charged, atmospheric experience. An 18 year old teenager is on trial for murder, and the jury has retired to discuss the case. When things start out, 11 men are ready to convict the boy, and there's one holdout, juror no. eight (Fonda); Fonda doesn't necessarily believe the boy is innocent, but he's passionate in his belief that there's enough *reasonable doubt* in the matter to refrain from voting guilty. He encounters a fair amount of hostility at first, particularly from the excitable juror no. three (Lee J. Cobb), but as the night falls and a storm starts up, he wears down his fellow men a bit at a time, insisting on bringing up facts that he felt weren't adequately explained during the trail. What's so wonderful about "12 Angry Men" is how believable it all is, right down to one juror, the baseball loving juror no. seven (Jack Warden) being willing to change his vote just to get the hell out of there, and the earnest juror no. 11 (George Voskovec) admonishing him for not doing this for the *right* reason. Each actor gets their own chance in the spotlight, and they're all superb. Cobb has the most intense role as a truly stubborn man who's gotten himself personally involved in the case; Ed Begley is equally potent as juror no. 10, another holdout. Martin Balsam, John Fiedler, E.G. Marshall, Jack Klugman, Edward Binns, Joseph Sweeney, and Robert Webber fill out the rest of this powerhouse cast. While the story is quite good dramatically, it's not without some humour, some of it coming from adman Webber. Use of music is sparing, which only adds a sense of realism to the proceedings. One of the most striking moments is when most of the group turns their backs to Begley after he launches into a rather disconcerting rant. Overall, this does deserve to be considered one of the finest American films of all time. It keeps the viewer riveted every step of the way. 10 out of 10.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An absolute masterpiece
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Bruno Youn
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    12 Angry Men is definitely one of the most astonishing dramas I've seen. It has a simple premise, but all the discussions between the jurors were just so captivating and revealing. I liked how they always went back and forth with the case, gathering as many details as possible to find out if there was any room for doubt with the facts presented. Not only director Sidney Lumet masterfully orchestrated an intriguing story filled with little twists, but he also investigated very thoroughly how prejudice and preconceived notions could be in the way of realizing the level of uncertainty of the facts. The performances here were truly remarkable, being another strength of the film. Each juror had unique personality traits and I felt the presence of every single one of them was very important to show interesting characteristics such as indifference, modesty, meticulousness and many others when dealing with the case. If I had to pick my favorite performance of the bunch, it would have to be from Henry Fonda as this persistent and considerate individual who feels the need to talk the case over and over as it's not as obvious as it looks. I really think the other actors were superb as well in their own way though. The fact that each character contributes to adding more depth to the story makes this film such a powerful experience. 12 Angry Men is only my second film from Sidney Lumet, but it certainly ranks among the best of all time and I will be looking forward to seeing more from this brilliant director.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An all time classic
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Ab Siddique
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This trial film tells the story of a jury made up of 12 men as they deliberate the guilt or acquittal of a defendant on the basis of reasonable doubt. This directorial masterpiece by Sydney Lumet is a must watch for all of you. Though the entire movie takes place in a single jury room (with a broken ceiling fan of course) but has got an intoxicating screenplay where several twists and turns awaits you. There's a scene where it starts raining all of a sudden, a scene which brings a fantastic change to the story where you, as an audience, feel like taking a break from the hassle and enjoy rain. Overall, this movie is a must watch and is highly recommended. I cannot discuss much about the story but trust me you won't regret watching it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Really Clever and Realistic Script,
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Dillon Harris
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    12 Angry Men is a unbelievably inspired film with a really well developed storyline and beautiful acting from all twelve men.The movie is literally an hour and a half of twelve members of a jury discussing if a man is guilty or not,it dosen't sound that exciting,but all these characters different personalities and opinions on this man come together so well that its made really enjoyable and intense,the conversations these men have get very deep and they look at every aspect of the night of the murder.I really didn't think it sounded that good but I wanted to watch it since it is so high up on the IMDb Top 250,and rightfully so,there is no movie quite like this one,its really unique.I would highly recommend 12 Angry Men to all moviegoers. A jury of twelve very different men discuss if a man is guilty or not for a murder,but their different opinions make it into a much longer discussion than they expected.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Outstanding movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Aswin Muralidharan
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The film is about jury consisting of 12 people which met for a murder trial. The film starts with just one person who has reasonable doubt that the accused is not guilty. As the film passes he tries to convince others that he may not be guilty. The way the movie is directed is simply outstanding. The movie proceeds with just dialogues. I have never seen any other movie in which a plot has been executed so amazingly. The movie puts most of the modern films to shame. Without much visual effects and technology the plain storytelling style guarantees that any viewer would be enthralled watching it. This is a must watch movie.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    one of the Best classic ever
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    fbawveek
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Great story. Not a big fan of old movies. but this just holds you like a giant magnet. It is impossible to leave the movie until you finish it. Great acting and story. Henry Fonda is excellent as usual. Very captivating throughout. A must watch for any movie lover. You like good movie you must watch it. First time i say this movie as a kid. Didn't get it stopped watching it half way. Than few years back got the DVD in my friend's house and borrowed it watched it and blown away. being a short film maker I learned quite a deal after watching it. by far my favourite henry Fonda movie of all time. will recommend to any one. great movie must see.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Masterpiece
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jagar4321
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This film was one of a very few films (<8 films) that I award a perfect 10/10. But what exactly makes a movie 10/10 in my opinion? It has to be a movie that I would watch again and again and realize something new every time. It has to make my mind run to its highest capacity. It has to have acting, dialog, and a story like no other. It has to be something that could be put away for decades at a time and still feel fresh. This film is a perfect 10. Is there any action? no. Does the setting change? no. Is the movie in color? no. So why do I still award it a 10? You must watch it to find out.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Amazing movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    lbmersault
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Amazing film about the complexities of humanity and how some of us can close ourselves to reason at times. The acting is amazing by all the actors. Even the subtle cinematography shines. The director does a great job at creating a tense and claustrophobic mood. The crescendo of the action creates a sense of impending change that characterizes the film. Another interesting concept is that our perceptions can sometimes be so different even when exposed to the same material. We bring our life experiences into making every decision we make and in the case of this film that can have catastrophic results for someone else. The voice of reason will always win in the end.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Rather disorderly than angry
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jgcorrea
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The inflamed comments are probably Pavlovian responses to the movie's politically correct quotient. Quality performers meet deep message. The most obvious flaw in this supposed classic, one of the most super-estimated films in history was as follows: real juries are allowed neither to carry their own experiences nor to consider evidence not presented at trial. If the jury had acted in accordance with the correct legal procedure, there would have been no basis for the plot, therefore no drama, therefore no catharsis. An intriguing theme doesn't always result in a good production. What shall I call a movie including clich&eacute;d, implausible characters, and a foreseeable twist (a 11-to-1 vote changing into 0-to-12)? Juries exist in order to allow the cold letter of the law to be broken, or temporarily suspended. That's what they're all about. That's their raison d'&ecirc;tre. A judge can acquit a suspicious defendant for lack of evidence. A jury may convict him or her for "feeling his or her" guilt. The institution of the jury was thus an historical way to "humanize" lawsuits. If jurors were so one-dimensional, mindless and easy to persuade, courts should certainly keep them afar.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of the Greatest films I have had the pleasure of watching
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    khayaadams
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    There are not many films that can keep you listening intently and watch every move the actors makes but 12 Angry men is one of those movies. Running at an hour and a half and practically the whole one and a half takes place in the back room of a court however never once did I feel bored or uninterested. Each actor brings something to the film, they each play their characters to perfection. Lee J. Cobb in particular plays his character so convincingly one forgets at times that he is acting. This movie goes to show that you don't need fancy effects and expensive sets to create a great film. You just need a great script and superb acting and that what one gets with this film. The plot itself moves along at a pleasing pace. The side talks between the jurors just reinforces the characters that the actors are playing. As I am writing this there has been so news about Jack Klugman being snubbed at the Emmy's and if you watch Mr. Klugman in this film you would understand why people are upset. This has become one of the greatest films I will probably watch and I am saddened that I didn't get to see it sooner.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A masterpiece of acting and filmmaking.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Scott LeBrun (Hey_Sweden)
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Brilliant film version of the televised play, scripted by the plays' author Reginald Rose, and produced by Rose and leading actor Henry Fonda. It's fascinating and compelling, offering memorable showcases to an amazing ensemble. The basic story is solid, but more than that, it's a nice look into a rich variety of characters, each with their own background and reasoning. It's all the more impressive for being a young Sidney Lumets' filmmaking debut; he makes this a highly charged, atmospheric experience. An 18 year old teenager is on trial for murder, and the jury has retired to discuss the case. When things start out, 11 men are ready to convict the boy, and there's one holdout, juror no. eight (Fonda); Fonda doesn't necessarily believe the boy is innocent, but he's passionate in his belief that there's enough *reasonable doubt* in the matter to refrain from voting guilty. He encounters a fair amount of hostility at first, particularly from the excitable juror no. three (Lee J. Cobb), but as the night falls and a storm starts up, he wears down his fellow men a bit at a time, insisting on bringing up facts that he felt weren't adequately explained during the trail. What's so wonderful about "12 Angry Men" is how believable it all is, right down to one juror, the baseball loving juror no. seven (Jack Warden) being willing to change his vote just to get the hell out of there, and the earnest juror no. 11 (George Voskovec) admonishing him for not doing this for the *right* reason. Each actor gets their own chance in the spotlight, and they're all superb. Cobb has the most intense role as a truly stubborn man who's gotten himself personally involved in the case; Ed Begley is equally potent as juror no. 10, another holdout. Martin Balsam, John Fiedler, E.G. Marshall, Jack Klugman, Edward Binns, Joseph Sweeney, and Robert Webber fill out the rest of this powerhouse cast. While the story is quite good dramatically, it's not without some humour, some of it coming from adman Webber. Use of music is sparing, which only adds a sense of realism to the proceedings. One of the most striking moments is when most of the group turns their backs to Begley after he launches into a rather disconcerting rant. Overall, this does deserve to be considered one of the finest American films of all time. It keeps the viewer riveted every step of the way. 10 out of 10.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An absolute masterpiece
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Bruno Youn
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    12 Angry Men is definitely one of the most astonishing dramas I've seen. It has a simple premise, but all the discussions between the jurors were just so captivating and revealing. I liked how they always went back and forth with the case, gathering as many details as possible to find out if there was any room for doubt with the facts presented. Not only director Sidney Lumet masterfully orchestrated an intriguing story filled with little twists, but he also investigated very thoroughly how prejudice and preconceived notions could be in the way of realizing the level of uncertainty of the facts. The performances here were truly remarkable, being another strength of the film. Each juror had unique personality traits and I felt the presence of every single one of them was very important to show interesting characteristics such as indifference, modesty, meticulousness and many others when dealing with the case. If I had to pick my favorite performance of the bunch, it would have to be from Henry Fonda as this persistent and considerate individual who feels the need to talk the case over and over as it's not as obvious as it looks. I really think the other actors were superb as well in their own way though. The fact that each character contributes to adding more depth to the story makes this film such a powerful experience. 12 Angry Men is only my second film from Sidney Lumet, but it certainly ranks among the best of all time and I will be looking forward to seeing more from this brilliant director.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An all time classic
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Ab Siddique
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This trial film tells the story of a jury made up of 12 men as they deliberate the guilt or acquittal of a defendant on the basis of reasonable doubt. This directorial masterpiece by Sydney Lumet is a must watch for all of you. Though the entire movie takes place in a single jury room (with a broken ceiling fan of course) but has got an intoxicating screenplay where several twists and turns awaits you. There's a scene where it starts raining all of a sudden, a scene which brings a fantastic change to the story where you, as an audience, feel like taking a break from the hassle and enjoy rain. Overall, this movie is a must watch and is highly recommended. I cannot discuss much about the story but trust me you won't regret watching it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Really Clever and Realistic Script,
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Dillon Harris
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    12 Angry Men is a unbelievably inspired film with a really well developed storyline and beautiful acting from all twelve men.The movie is literally an hour and a half of twelve members of a jury discussing if a man is guilty or not,it dosen't sound that exciting,but all these characters different personalities and opinions on this man come together so well that its made really enjoyable and intense,the conversations these men have get very deep and they look at every aspect of the night of the murder.I really didn't think it sounded that good but I wanted to watch it since it is so high up on the IMDb Top 250,and rightfully so,there is no movie quite like this one,its really unique.I would highly recommend 12 Angry Men to all moviegoers. A jury of twelve very different men discuss if a man is guilty or not for a murder,but their different opinions make it into a much longer discussion than they expected.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Outstanding movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Aswin Muralidharan
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The film is about jury consisting of 12 people which met for a murder trial. The film starts with just one person who has reasonable doubt that the accused is not guilty. As the film passes he tries to convince others that he may not be guilty. The way the movie is directed is simply outstanding. The movie proceeds with just dialogues. I have never seen any other movie in which a plot has been executed so amazingly. The movie puts most of the modern films to shame. Without much visual effects and technology the plain storytelling style guarantees that any viewer would be enthralled watching it. This is a must watch movie.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    one of the Best classic ever
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    fbawveek
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Great story. Not a big fan of old movies. but this just holds you like a giant magnet. It is impossible to leave the movie until you finish it. Great acting and story. Henry Fonda is excellent as usual. Very captivating throughout. A must watch for any movie lover. You like good movie you must watch it. First time i say this movie as a kid. Didn't get it stopped watching it half way. Than few years back got the DVD in my friend's house and borrowed it watched it and blown away. being a short film maker I learned quite a deal after watching it. by far my favourite henry Fonda movie of all time. will recommend to any one. great movie must see.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Masterpiece
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jagar4321
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This film was one of a very few films (<8 films) that I award a perfect 10/10. But what exactly makes a movie 10/10 in my opinion? It has to be a movie that I would watch again and again and realize something new every time. It has to make my mind run to its highest capacity. It has to have acting, dialog, and a story like no other. It has to be something that could be put away for decades at a time and still feel fresh. This film is a perfect 10. Is there any action? no. Does the setting change? no. Is the movie in color? no. So why do I still award it a 10? You must watch it to find out.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Amazing movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    lbmersault
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Amazing film about the complexities of humanity and how some of us can close ourselves to reason at times. The acting is amazing by all the actors. Even the subtle cinematography shines. The director does a great job at creating a tense and claustrophobic mood. The crescendo of the action creates a sense of impending change that characterizes the film. Another interesting concept is that our perceptions can sometimes be so different even when exposed to the same material. We bring our life experiences into making every decision we make and in the case of this film that can have catastrophic results for someone else. The voice of reason will always win in the end.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Rather disorderly than angry
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jgcorrea
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The inflamed comments are probably Pavlovian responses to the movie's politically correct quotient. Quality performers meet deep message. The most obvious flaw in this supposed classic, one of the most super-estimated films in history was as follows: real juries are allowed neither to carry their own experiences nor to consider evidence not presented at trial. If the jury had acted in accordance with the correct legal procedure, there would have been no basis for the plot, therefore no drama, therefore no catharsis. An intriguing theme doesn't always result in a good production. What shall I call a movie including clich&eacute;d, implausible characters, and a foreseeable twist (a 11-to-1 vote changing into 0-to-12)? Juries exist in order to allow the cold letter of the law to be broken, or temporarily suspended. That's what they're all about. That's their raison d'&ecirc;tre. A judge can acquit a suspicious defendant for lack of evidence. A jury may convict him or her for "feeling his or her" guilt. The institution of the jury was thus an historical way to "humanize" lawsuits. If jurors were so one-dimensional, mindless and easy to persuade, courts should certainly keep them afar.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of the Greatest films I have had the pleasure of watching
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    khayaadams
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    There are not many films that can keep you listening intently and watch every move the actors makes but 12 Angry men is one of those movies. Running at an hour and a half and practically the whole one and a half takes place in the back room of a court however never once did I feel bored or uninterested. Each actor brings something to the film, they each play their characters to perfection. Lee J. Cobb in particular plays his character so convincingly one forgets at times that he is acting. This movie goes to show that you don't need fancy effects and expensive sets to create a great film. You just need a great script and superb acting and that what one gets with this film. The plot itself moves along at a pleasing pace. The side talks between the jurors just reinforces the characters that the actors are playing. As I am writing this there has been so news about Jack Klugman being snubbed at the Emmy's and if you watch Mr. Klugman in this film you would understand why people are upset. This has become one of the greatest films I will probably watch and I am saddened that I didn't get to see it sooner.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A masterpiece of acting and filmmaking.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Scott LeBrun (Hey_Sweden)
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Brilliant film version of the televised play, scripted by the plays' author Reginald Rose, and produced by Rose and leading actor Henry Fonda. It's fascinating and compelling, offering memorable showcases to an amazing ensemble. The basic story is solid, but more than that, it's a nice look into a rich variety of characters, each with their own background and reasoning. It's all the more impressive for being a young Sidney Lumets' filmmaking debut; he makes this a highly charged, atmospheric experience. An 18 year old teenager is on trial for murder, and the jury has retired to discuss the case. When things start out, 11 men are ready to convict the boy, and there's one holdout, juror no. eight (Fonda); Fonda doesn't necessarily believe the boy is innocent, but he's passionate in his belief that there's enough *reasonable doubt* in the matter to refrain from voting guilty. He encounters a fair amount of hostility at first, particularly from the excitable juror no. three (Lee J. Cobb), but as the night falls and a storm starts up, he wears down his fellow men a bit at a time, insisting on bringing up facts that he felt weren't adequately explained during the trail. What's so wonderful about "12 Angry Men" is how believable it all is, right down to one juror, the baseball loving juror no. seven (Jack Warden) being willing to change his vote just to get the hell out of there, and the earnest juror no. 11 (George Voskovec) admonishing him for not doing this for the *right* reason. Each actor gets their own chance in the spotlight, and they're all superb. Cobb has the most intense role as a truly stubborn man who's gotten himself personally involved in the case; Ed Begley is equally potent as juror no. 10, another holdout. Martin Balsam, John Fiedler, E.G. Marshall, Jack Klugman, Edward Binns, Joseph Sweeney, and Robert Webber fill out the rest of this powerhouse cast. While the story is quite good dramatically, it's not without some humour, some of it coming from adman Webber. Use of music is sparing, which only adds a sense of realism to the proceedings. One of the most striking moments is when most of the group turns their backs to Begley after he launches into a rather disconcerting rant. Overall, this does deserve to be considered one of the finest American films of all time. It keeps the viewer riveted every step of the way. 10 out of 10.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An absolute masterpiece
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Bruno Youn
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    12 Angry Men is definitely one of the most astonishing dramas I've seen. It has a simple premise, but all the discussions between the jurors were just so captivating and revealing. I liked how they always went back and forth with the case, gathering as many details as possible to find out if there was any room for doubt with the facts presented. Not only director Sidney Lumet masterfully orchestrated an intriguing story filled with little twists, but he also investigated very thoroughly how prejudice and preconceived notions could be in the way of realizing the level of uncertainty of the facts. The performances here were truly remarkable, being another strength of the film. Each juror had unique personality traits and I felt the presence of every single one of them was very important to show interesting characteristics such as indifference, modesty, meticulousness and many others when dealing with the case. If I had to pick my favorite performance of the bunch, it would have to be from Henry Fonda as this persistent and considerate individual who feels the need to talk the case over and over as it's not as obvious as it looks. I really think the other actors were superb as well in their own way though. The fact that each character contributes to adding more depth to the story makes this film such a powerful experience. 12 Angry Men is only my second film from Sidney Lumet, but it certainly ranks among the best of all time and I will be looking forward to seeing more from this brilliant director.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An all time classic
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Ab Siddique
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This trial film tells the story of a jury made up of 12 men as they deliberate the guilt or acquittal of a defendant on the basis of reasonable doubt. This directorial masterpiece by Sydney Lumet is a must watch for all of you. Though the entire movie takes place in a single jury room (with a broken ceiling fan of course) but has got an intoxicating screenplay where several twists and turns awaits you. There's a scene where it starts raining all of a sudden, a scene which brings a fantastic change to the story where you, as an audience, feel like taking a break from the hassle and enjoy rain. Overall, this movie is a must watch and is highly recommended. I cannot discuss much about the story but trust me you won't regret watching it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Really Clever and Realistic Script,
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Dillon Harris
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    12 Angry Men is a unbelievably inspired film with a really well developed storyline and beautiful acting from all twelve men.The movie is literally an hour and a half of twelve members of a jury discussing if a man is guilty or not,it dosen't sound that exciting,but all these characters different personalities and opinions on this man come together so well that its made really enjoyable and intense,the conversations these men have get very deep and they look at every aspect of the night of the murder.I really didn't think it sounded that good but I wanted to watch it since it is so high up on the IMDb Top 250,and rightfully so,there is no movie quite like this one,its really unique.I would highly recommend 12 Angry Men to all moviegoers. A jury of twelve very different men discuss if a man is guilty or not for a murder,but their different opinions make it into a much longer discussion than they expected.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Outstanding movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Aswin Muralidharan
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The film is about jury consisting of 12 people which met for a murder trial. The film starts with just one person who has reasonable doubt that the accused is not guilty. As the film passes he tries to convince others that he may not be guilty. The way the movie is directed is simply outstanding. The movie proceeds with just dialogues. I have never seen any other movie in which a plot has been executed so amazingly. The movie puts most of the modern films to shame. Without much visual effects and technology the plain storytelling style guarantees that any viewer would be enthralled watching it. This is a must watch movie.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    one of the Best classic ever
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    fbawveek
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Great story. Not a big fan of old movies. but this just holds you like a giant magnet. It is impossible to leave the movie until you finish it. Great acting and story. Henry Fonda is excellent as usual. Very captivating throughout. A must watch for any movie lover. You like good movie you must watch it. First time i say this movie as a kid. Didn't get it stopped watching it half way. Than few years back got the DVD in my friend's house and borrowed it watched it and blown away. being a short film maker I learned quite a deal after watching it. by far my favourite henry Fonda movie of all time. will recommend to any one. great movie must see.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Masterpiece
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jagar4321
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This film was one of a very few films (<8 films) that I award a perfect 10/10. But what exactly makes a movie 10/10 in my opinion? It has to be a movie that I would watch again and again and realize something new every time. It has to make my mind run to its highest capacity. It has to have acting, dialog, and a story like no other. It has to be something that could be put away for decades at a time and still feel fresh. This film is a perfect 10. Is there any action? no. Does the setting change? no. Is the movie in color? no. So why do I still award it a 10? You must watch it to find out.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Amazing movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    lbmersault
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Amazing film about the complexities of humanity and how some of us can close ourselves to reason at times. The acting is amazing by all the actors. Even the subtle cinematography shines. The director does a great job at creating a tense and claustrophobic mood. The crescendo of the action creates a sense of impending change that characterizes the film. Another interesting concept is that our perceptions can sometimes be so different even when exposed to the same material. We bring our life experiences into making every decision we make and in the case of this film that can have catastrophic results for someone else. The voice of reason will always win in the end.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Rather disorderly than angry
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jgcorrea
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The inflamed comments are probably Pavlovian responses to the movie's politically correct quotient. Quality performers meet deep message. The most obvious flaw in this supposed classic, one of the most super-estimated films in history was as follows: real juries are allowed neither to carry their own experiences nor to consider evidence not presented at trial. If the jury had acted in accordance with the correct legal procedure, there would have been no basis for the plot, therefore no drama, therefore no catharsis. An intriguing theme doesn't always result in a good production. What shall I call a movie including clich&eacute;d, implausible characters, and a foreseeable twist (a 11-to-1 vote changing into 0-to-12)? Juries exist in order to allow the cold letter of the law to be broken, or temporarily suspended. That's what they're all about. That's their raison d'&ecirc;tre. A judge can acquit a suspicious defendant for lack of evidence. A jury may convict him or her for "feeling his or her" guilt. The institution of the jury was thus an historical way to "humanize" lawsuits. If jurors were so one-dimensional, mindless and easy to persuade, courts should certainly keep them afar.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of the Greatest films I have had the pleasure of watching
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    khayaadams
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    There are not many films that can keep you listening intently and watch every move the actors makes but 12 Angry men is one of those movies. Running at an hour and a half and practically the whole one and a half takes place in the back room of a court however never once did I feel bored or uninterested. Each actor brings something to the film, they each play their characters to perfection. Lee J. Cobb in particular plays his character so convincingly one forgets at times that he is acting. This movie goes to show that you don't need fancy effects and expensive sets to create a great film. You just need a great script and superb acting and that what one gets with this film. The plot itself moves along at a pleasing pace. The side talks between the jurors just reinforces the characters that the actors are playing. As I am writing this there has been so news about Jack Klugman being snubbed at the Emmy's and if you watch Mr. Klugman in this film you would understand why people are upset. This has become one of the greatest films I will probably watch and I am saddened that I didn't get to see it sooner.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A masterpiece of acting and filmmaking.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Scott LeBrun (Hey_Sweden)
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Brilliant film version of the televised play, scripted by the plays' author Reginald Rose, and produced by Rose and leading actor Henry Fonda. It's fascinating and compelling, offering memorable showcases to an amazing ensemble. The basic story is solid, but more than that, it's a nice look into a rich variety of characters, each with their own background and reasoning. It's all the more impressive for being a young Sidney Lumets' filmmaking debut; he makes this a highly charged, atmospheric experience. An 18 year old teenager is on trial for murder, and the jury has retired to discuss the case. When things start out, 11 men are ready to convict the boy, and there's one holdout, juror no. eight (Fonda); Fonda doesn't necessarily believe the boy is innocent, but he's passionate in his belief that there's enough *reasonable doubt* in the matter to refrain from voting guilty. He encounters a fair amount of hostility at first, particularly from the excitable juror no. three (Lee J. Cobb), but as the night falls and a storm starts up, he wears down his fellow men a bit at a time, insisting on bringing up facts that he felt weren't adequately explained during the trail. What's so wonderful about "12 Angry Men" is how believable it all is, right down to one juror, the baseball loving juror no. seven (Jack Warden) being willing to change his vote just to get the hell out of there, and the earnest juror no. 11 (George Voskovec) admonishing him for not doing this for the *right* reason. Each actor gets their own chance in the spotlight, and they're all superb. Cobb has the most intense role as a truly stubborn man who's gotten himself personally involved in the case; Ed Begley is equally potent as juror no. 10, another holdout. Martin Balsam, John Fiedler, E.G. Marshall, Jack Klugman, Edward Binns, Joseph Sweeney, and Robert Webber fill out the rest of this powerhouse cast. While the story is quite good dramatically, it's not without some humour, some of it coming from adman Webber. Use of music is sparing, which only adds a sense of realism to the proceedings. One of the most striking moments is when most of the group turns their backs to Begley after he launches into a rather disconcerting rant. Overall, this does deserve to be considered one of the finest American films of all time. It keeps the viewer riveted every step of the way. 10 out of 10.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An absolute masterpiece
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Bruno Youn
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    12 Angry Men is definitely one of the most astonishing dramas I've seen. It has a simple premise, but all the discussions between the jurors were just so captivating and revealing. I liked how they always went back and forth with the case, gathering as many details as possible to find out if there was any room for doubt with the facts presented. Not only director Sidney Lumet masterfully orchestrated an intriguing story filled with little twists, but he also investigated very thoroughly how prejudice and preconceived notions could be in the way of realizing the level of uncertainty of the facts. The performances here were truly remarkable, being another strength of the film. Each juror had unique personality traits and I felt the presence of every single one of them was very important to show interesting characteristics such as indifference, modesty, meticulousness and many others when dealing with the case. If I had to pick my favorite performance of the bunch, it would have to be from Henry Fonda as this persistent and considerate individual who feels the need to talk the case over and over as it's not as obvious as it looks. I really think the other actors were superb as well in their own way though. The fact that each character contributes to adding more depth to the story makes this film such a powerful experience. 12 Angry Men is only my second film from Sidney Lumet, but it certainly ranks among the best of all time and I will be looking forward to seeing more from this brilliant director.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An all time classic
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Ab Siddique
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This trial film tells the story of a jury made up of 12 men as they deliberate the guilt or acquittal of a defendant on the basis of reasonable doubt. This directorial masterpiece by Sydney Lumet is a must watch for all of you. Though the entire movie takes place in a single jury room (with a broken ceiling fan of course) but has got an intoxicating screenplay where several twists and turns awaits you. There's a scene where it starts raining all of a sudden, a scene which brings a fantastic change to the story where you, as an audience, feel like taking a break from the hassle and enjoy rain. Overall, this movie is a must watch and is highly recommended. I cannot discuss much about the story but trust me you won't regret watching it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Really Clever and Realistic Script,
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Dillon Harris
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    12 Angry Men is a unbelievably inspired film with a really well developed storyline and beautiful acting from all twelve men.The movie is literally an hour and a half of twelve members of a jury discussing if a man is guilty or not,it dosen't sound that exciting,but all these characters different personalities and opinions on this man come together so well that its made really enjoyable and intense,the conversations these men have get very deep and they look at every aspect of the night of the murder.I really didn't think it sounded that good but I wanted to watch it since it is so high up on the IMDb Top 250,and rightfully so,there is no movie quite like this one,its really unique.I would highly recommend 12 Angry Men to all moviegoers. A jury of twelve very different men discuss if a man is guilty or not for a murder,but their different opinions make it into a much longer discussion than they expected.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Outstanding movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Aswin Muralidharan
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The film is about jury consisting of 12 people which met for a murder trial. The film starts with just one person who has reasonable doubt that the accused is not guilty. As the film passes he tries to convince others that he may not be guilty. The way the movie is directed is simply outstanding. The movie proceeds with just dialogues. I have never seen any other movie in which a plot has been executed so amazingly. The movie puts most of the modern films to shame. Without much visual effects and technology the plain storytelling style guarantees that any viewer would be enthralled watching it. This is a must watch movie.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    one of the Best classic ever
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    fbawveek
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Great story. Not a big fan of old movies. but this just holds you like a giant magnet. It is impossible to leave the movie until you finish it. Great acting and story. Henry Fonda is excellent as usual. Very captivating throughout. A must watch for any movie lover. You like good movie you must watch it. First time i say this movie as a kid. Didn't get it stopped watching it half way. Than few years back got the DVD in my friend's house and borrowed it watched it and blown away. being a short film maker I learned quite a deal after watching it. by far my favourite henry Fonda movie of all time. will recommend to any one. great movie must see.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Masterpiece
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jagar4321
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This film was one of a very few films (<8 films) that I award a perfect 10/10. But what exactly makes a movie 10/10 in my opinion? It has to be a movie that I would watch again and again and realize something new every time. It has to make my mind run to its highest capacity. It has to have acting, dialog, and a story like no other. It has to be something that could be put away for decades at a time and still feel fresh. This film is a perfect 10. Is there any action? no. Does the setting change? no. Is the movie in color? no. So why do I still award it a 10? You must watch it to find out.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Amazing movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    lbmersault
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Amazing film about the complexities of humanity and how some of us can close ourselves to reason at times. The acting is amazing by all the actors. Even the subtle cinematography shines. The director does a great job at creating a tense and claustrophobic mood. The crescendo of the action creates a sense of impending change that characterizes the film. Another interesting concept is that our perceptions can sometimes be so different even when exposed to the same material. We bring our life experiences into making every decision we make and in the case of this film that can have catastrophic results for someone else. The voice of reason will always win in the end.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Rather disorderly than angry
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jgcorrea
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The inflamed comments are probably Pavlovian responses to the movie's politically correct quotient. Quality performers meet deep message. The most obvious flaw in this supposed classic, one of the most super-estimated films in history was as follows: real juries are allowed neither to carry their own experiences nor to consider evidence not presented at trial. If the jury had acted in accordance with the correct legal procedure, there would have been no basis for the plot, therefore no drama, therefore no catharsis. An intriguing theme doesn't always result in a good production. What shall I call a movie including clich&eacute;d, implausible characters, and a foreseeable twist (a 11-to-1 vote changing into 0-to-12)? Juries exist in order to allow the cold letter of the law to be broken, or temporarily suspended. That's what they're all about. That's their raison d'&ecirc;tre. A judge can acquit a suspicious defendant for lack of evidence. A jury may convict him or her for "feeling his or her" guilt. The institution of the jury was thus an historical way to "humanize" lawsuits. If jurors were so one-dimensional, mindless and easy to persuade, courts should certainly keep them afar.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of the Greatest films I have had the pleasure of watching
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    khayaadams
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    There are not many films that can keep you listening intently and watch every move the actors makes but 12 Angry men is one of those movies. Running at an hour and a half and practically the whole one and a half takes place in the back room of a court however never once did I feel bored or uninterested. Each actor brings something to the film, they each play their characters to perfection. Lee J. Cobb in particular plays his character so convincingly one forgets at times that he is acting. This movie goes to show that you don't need fancy effects and expensive sets to create a great film. You just need a great script and superb acting and that what one gets with this film. The plot itself moves along at a pleasing pace. The side talks between the jurors just reinforces the characters that the actors are playing. As I am writing this there has been so news about Jack Klugman being snubbed at the Emmy's and if you watch Mr. Klugman in this film you would understand why people are upset. This has become one of the greatest films I will probably watch and I am saddened that I didn't get to see it sooner.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A masterpiece of acting and filmmaking.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Scott LeBrun (Hey_Sweden)
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Brilliant film version of the televised play, scripted by the plays' author Reginald Rose, and produced by Rose and leading actor Henry Fonda. It's fascinating and compelling, offering memorable showcases to an amazing ensemble. The basic story is solid, but more than that, it's a nice look into a rich variety of characters, each with their own background and reasoning. It's all the more impressive for being a young Sidney Lumets' filmmaking debut; he makes this a highly charged, atmospheric experience. An 18 year old teenager is on trial for murder, and the jury has retired to discuss the case. When things start out, 11 men are ready to convict the boy, and there's one holdout, juror no. eight (Fonda); Fonda doesn't necessarily believe the boy is innocent, but he's passionate in his belief that there's enough *reasonable doubt* in the matter to refrain from voting guilty. He encounters a fair amount of hostility at first, particularly from the excitable juror no. three (Lee J. Cobb), but as the night falls and a storm starts up, he wears down his fellow men a bit at a time, insisting on bringing up facts that he felt weren't adequately explained during the trail. What's so wonderful about "12 Angry Men" is how believable it all is, right down to one juror, the baseball loving juror no. seven (Jack Warden) being willing to change his vote just to get the hell out of there, and the earnest juror no. 11 (George Voskovec) admonishing him for not doing this for the *right* reason. Each actor gets their own chance in the spotlight, and they're all superb. Cobb has the most intense role as a truly stubborn man who's gotten himself personally involved in the case; Ed Begley is equally potent as juror no. 10, another holdout. Martin Balsam, John Fiedler, E.G. Marshall, Jack Klugman, Edward Binns, Joseph Sweeney, and Robert Webber fill out the rest of this powerhouse cast. While the story is quite good dramatically, it's not without some humour, some of it coming from adman Webber. Use of music is sparing, which only adds a sense of realism to the proceedings. One of the most striking moments is when most of the group turns their backs to Begley after he launches into a rather disconcerting rant. Overall, this does deserve to be considered one of the finest American films of all time. It keeps the viewer riveted every step of the way. 10 out of 10.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An absolute masterpiece
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Bruno Youn
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    12 Angry Men is definitely one of the most astonishing dramas I've seen. It has a simple premise, but all the discussions between the jurors were just so captivating and revealing. I liked how they always went back and forth with the case, gathering as many details as possible to find out if there was any room for doubt with the facts presented. Not only director Sidney Lumet masterfully orchestrated an intriguing story filled with little twists, but he also investigated very thoroughly how prejudice and preconceived notions could be in the way of realizing the level of uncertainty of the facts. The performances here were truly remarkable, being another strength of the film. Each juror had unique personality traits and I felt the presence of every single one of them was very important to show interesting characteristics such as indifference, modesty, meticulousness and many others when dealing with the case. If I had to pick my favorite performance of the bunch, it would have to be from Henry Fonda as this persistent and considerate individual who feels the need to talk the case over and over as it's not as obvious as it looks. I really think the other actors were superb as well in their own way though. The fact that each character contributes to adding more depth to the story makes this film such a powerful experience. 12 Angry Men is only my second film from Sidney Lumet, but it certainly ranks among the best of all time and I will be looking forward to seeing more from this brilliant director.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An all time classic
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Ab Siddique
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This trial film tells the story of a jury made up of 12 men as they deliberate the guilt or acquittal of a defendant on the basis of reasonable doubt. This directorial masterpiece by Sydney Lumet is a must watch for all of you. Though the entire movie takes place in a single jury room (with a broken ceiling fan of course) but has got an intoxicating screenplay where several twists and turns awaits you. There's a scene where it starts raining all of a sudden, a scene which brings a fantastic change to the story where you, as an audience, feel like taking a break from the hassle and enjoy rain. Overall, this movie is a must watch and is highly recommended. I cannot discuss much about the story but trust me you won't regret watching it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Really Clever and Realistic Script,
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Dillon Harris
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    12 Angry Men is a unbelievably inspired film with a really well developed storyline and beautiful acting from all twelve men.The movie is literally an hour and a half of twelve members of a jury discussing if a man is guilty or not,it dosen't sound that exciting,but all these characters different personalities and opinions on this man come together so well that its made really enjoyable and intense,the conversations these men have get very deep and they look at every aspect of the night of the murder.I really didn't think it sounded that good but I wanted to watch it since it is so high up on the IMDb Top 250,and rightfully so,there is no movie quite like this one,its really unique.I would highly recommend 12 Angry Men to all moviegoers. A jury of twelve very different men discuss if a man is guilty or not for a murder,but their different opinions make it into a much longer discussion than they expected.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Outstanding movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Aswin Muralidharan
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The film is about jury consisting of 12 people which met for a murder trial. The film starts with just one person who has reasonable doubt that the accused is not guilty. As the film passes he tries to convince others that he may not be guilty. The way the movie is directed is simply outstanding. The movie proceeds with just dialogues. I have never seen any other movie in which a plot has been executed so amazingly. The movie puts most of the modern films to shame. Without much visual effects and technology the plain storytelling style guarantees that any viewer would be enthralled watching it. This is a must watch movie.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    one of the Best classic ever
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    fbawveek
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Great story. Not a big fan of old movies. but this just holds you like a giant magnet. It is impossible to leave the movie until you finish it. Great acting and story. Henry Fonda is excellent as usual. Very captivating throughout. A must watch for any movie lover. You like good movie you must watch it. First time i say this movie as a kid. Didn't get it stopped watching it half way. Than few years back got the DVD in my friend's house and borrowed it watched it and blown away. being a short film maker I learned quite a deal after watching it. by far my favourite henry Fonda movie of all time. will recommend to any one. great movie must see.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
 </reviews>
</filme>
