<filme>
 <id>
  180
 </id>
 <imdburl>
  http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0078788
 </imdburl>
 <ano>
  1979
 </ano>
 <titulo>
  Apocalypse Now
 </titulo>
 <rating>
  8.6
 </rating>
 <sinopse>
  During the U.S.-Viet Nam War, Captain Willard is sent on a dangerous mission into Cambodia to assassinate a renegade colonel who has set himself up as a god among a local tribe.
 </sinopse>
 <storyline>
  It is the height of the war in Vietnam, and U.S. Army Captain Willard is sent by Colonel Lucas and a General to carry out a mission that, officially, 'does not exist - nor will it ever exist'. The mission: To seek out a mysterious Green Beret Colonel, Walter Kurtz, whose army has crossed the border into Cambodia and is conducting hit-and-run missions against the Viet Cong and NVA. The army believes Kurtz has gone completely insane and Willard's job is to eliminate him! Willard, sent up the Nung River on a U.S. Navy patrol boat, discovers that his target is one of the most decorated officers in the U.S. Army. His crew meets up with surfer-type Lt-Colonel Kilgore, head of a U.S Army helicopter cavalry group which eliminates a Viet Cong outpost to provide an entry point into the Nung River. After some hair-raising encounters, in which some of his crew are killed, Willard, Lance and Chef reach Colonel Kurtz's outpost, beyond the Do Lung Bridge. Now, after becoming prisoners of Kurtz, will...
 </storyline>
 <generos>
  <genero>
   Drama
  </genero>
  <genero>
   War
  </genero>
 </generos>
 <keywords>
  <keyword>
   colonel
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   jungle
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   army
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   boat
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   captain
  </keyword>
 </keywords>
 <diretores>
  <diretor>
   Francis Ford Coppola
  </diretor>
 </diretores>
 <escritores>
  <escritor>
   John Milius
  </escritor>
  <escritor>
   Francis Ford Coppola
  </escritor>
 </escritores>
 <atores>
  <ator>
   Martin Sheen
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Marlon Brando
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Robert Duvall
  </ator>
 </atores>
 <reviews>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One Of My Favorite Films
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Alex Krajci
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    1979's Apocalypse Now Is One Of My Favorite Films, I Like It Because Of Francis Ford Coppola's Direction, John Milius And Francis Ford Coppola's Screenplay, The Editing And Vittorio Storaro's Cinematography, This Movie Came Out From The Year Angela And Heath Ledger Were, The Wonder Woman TV Series With Lynda Carter Ended In 1979, 1963 Was 16 Years Old In 1979, This Movie Came Out 34 Years Ago Back In August Of 1979, My Favorite War Film Is 1998's Saving Private Ryan With Tom Hanks, 1972's The Godfather Is My Fourth Favorite Film Of All Time, This Movie Will Be 40 Years Old In 2019, This Movie Was 25 Years Old In 2004.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Fanastic movie, but enjoyment may require your undivided attention...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Kane Yoder (soggybreeches@gmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Let me start by saying I only made this account so I could write a review of Apocalypse Now. I'm out of college now, but I remember watching this movie when I was in high school and I remember boredom and confusion and, truthfully, a lack of interest. I didn't "get" the movie. It was too slow. What was the point? What was the mission? Why weren't they getting on with it at a breakneck speed like in Bond or Bourne or ... you know what I mean. Fast forward to college (I majored in English for the plentiful job prospects ha ha) and studied Heart of Darkness, completely forgetting about Apocalypse Now. Just as many people hate this movie or love it, many people hate the novel by Joseph Conrad or love it. It's slow going and easy to miss the point. I've learned that sometimes we just have to slow our thoughts down to match the pace of the storyteller, instead of trying to outdo him or her. If you enjoy Heart of Darkness then you will enjoy this movie. Even though the era and location is completely different, this movie is almost an expansion on Heart of Darkness. You get more juicy bits of dialogue, you get to fall a little bit deeper into the crevasses of Kurtz's cracked mind. And if you're any bit a sane human being, you'll find yourself strangely comfortable with the violence and cruelty and language of the movie. You don't get the feeling that the screen is hiding anything from you and at the same time there're no morals getting stuffed down your throat. The characters on screen deal with the gruesome details of war in their own ways. Pick whom you agree with. Some you will pity, some you will find hilarious. One question the movie begs: what, in war, is right? The music for this movie serves the setting excellently, at one point the bass thumping two beats like a heartbeat. Some rock and roll from the era prevails (like The Doors's "The End"). All of it to make Martin Sheen's journey utterly foreign, exotic, yet familiar. The visuals in this movie are fantastic. So vibrant and colorful, sometimes it's like a good acid trip. You don't see colors like these in movies nowadays. Watch it and you'll know what I mean. I don't want to say anything about the plot, but here... This movie, even though it is slow, wastes no time with dialogue. A lot of it is voice-over! If you don't pay attention, you'll miss a new development either on the mission, or on the character. (If you fail to understand the characters in this movie, then you will probably not like the movie.) Watch This Movie!! Slow your mind down, try to enjoy it. Give it your undivided attention. Amid all the carnage, callousness, and ruthlessness, you may find a story that is very human, and very close to your soul.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The horrors of war...the horrors of humanity...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    endrit qarolli
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    To summarize this film in one sentence: The best film of all time.This movie does not get enough credit.It is original, dark, meaningful Cappolas best work. After watching this movie for the first time i thought it was bad but it got me wondering so i decided to give it another shot and i was amazed the two hours and a half passed like a second it was truly an experience worth remembering a movie worth watching.Every time the movie starts and Jim Morrison starts singing it gives me goosebumps it just drives me crazy.The speech of Marlon Brando is outstanding, and when Robert Duvall say "I love the smell of napalms in the morning it smells like victory" to me that smells like something wonderfully dark and amazing its about to happen, and this movie is that.A truly astonishing piece of art. The horror...The horror This is the end...
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Flawless Film With Great Buildup and Pacing
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    chrisborg1999
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    To say that Apocalypse Now is good is a major understatement. Even to say it is great is an understatement too. But, a milestone for film making and one of Ford Coppala's best (he has so many though) A very interesting fact is that over 200 hours of film were shot and it too 3 years to edit which you can see very clearly considering that the cinematography and transitions are perfect and nothing is out of place. The musical score fits the tone perfectly and the characters are very well developed I can't give anything away because I can't tell you for everyone interprets this movie differently. But please, I urge you to watch this masterpiece for you to experience how Vietnam War life was like
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    This Is The End...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    AaronCapenBanner
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Francis Ford Coppola directs this fascinating but very strange, unique film about Army Captain Willard(Martin Sheen, fine shell-shocked performance) who is sent "Up River" on a secret mission to assassinate renegade Col. Kurtz(Marlon Brando, bizarre but unforgettable performance) who has apparently gone insane, abandoned his command, and now rules over a primitive people in the remote jungles of Vietnam. Story is far more involved than that though, especially in the expanded directors cut that is much longer, but also fascinating. Willard encounters many strange sights and people(even among his own crew) as he tries to make sense out of the enveloping madness of this war, and his own inner demons. Film is a visual marvel, and holds your attention as it unfolds its increasingly philosophical, even existentialist narrative. May take multiple viewings to fully comprehend, but is worth it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Amazing and great!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bernard-layer
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Strange, fascinating, grandiose, paranoid, overwhelming, epic, disgusting, gigantic! These are the many adjectives that can be used to describe the monument of cinema. The Redux version extended by about 45 minutes, was fully supervised by Francis Coppola for the 20th anniversary of the film and to its operation on DVD. Sequences reintegrated not distort the original about the film. We have the right to more playmates, more madness and especially more Brando, for the benefit of the character Kurtz. Only the sequence of the French plantation (30 minutes alone) is questionable digression because it has the French so naive and causes a break from the narrative. The film, supported by a director prey to megalomania, was brought forth in pain. The sets were ravaged by a storm. Helicopters lent by the army of the country where the shooting took place, were requisitioned to fight against a coup when turning the aerial sequences. Lead actor Martin Sheen, drunk all day long, had a heart attack. The director gave her tray for a whole week for a romantic extramarital under the eyes of his wife incorporated the technical team. Time and on budget were so happily overwhelmed to the point that the production company of Coppola, Zoetrope, went bankrupt and the theatrical release was compromised until his selection at Cannes with a montage done in an emergency. This adventure film is told in the documentary Heart of Darkness dedicated to filming. Palme d'or at Cannes' festival in 1979, Oscar for best photography.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    more of an anti-war movie than a pro-war one
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    scottj471
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I can't argue with anyone who says this movie is good all around. The cast is great, the scenes change well from one to the next, the special effects are good for 1979, and the plot is solid. For some one looking for a movie that is more pro-war this isn't really your trade. With the exception of Robert Duvall's, one of the great cast members, Air Mobile unit and the scenes they performed so nicely. Other than that it's your, unfortunately, typical Vietnam war movie that presents our soldiers as rapists, murderers, drug addicts, and uncommitted freaks who can't be controlled or commanded. Once you get over all that BS you can enjoy this movie to the full. If not, check out We Were Soldiers with Mel Gibson for a realistic war movie.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    a tale of a world teetering on the edge of Darkness
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    silva-w-pius
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    In film it's a very rare occurrence  thus highly sort after, that a film can possess the holy trinity of a combination of a; great script, a legendary director and an almost god like actor. But such is the elusive nature of this endeavour, it never has quite has been attained in the history of film  well that's before a certain masterpiece going by the name of Apocalypse now graced our screens with this almost mythical alliance of this magnitude. The director: Francis Ford Coppola (Godfather trilogy). The story: a tale of a world teetering on the edge of Darkness almost ready to descent into primal madness, as Capt. Willard (Martin Sheen) has to navigate his way through hell on earth to find and kill AWOL Col. Kurtz (The actor:) Marlon Brando (On the Waterfront and Godfather 1) - whose very name is translated into greatness in almost every language known to man. The epic tale of this coming together will probably never happen again or would even have another three components assembled that will ever parallel it. So it something to be marvelled at, as you sits down in your comfortable chair to watch such a spectacle. It has been widely reported from a variety of different sources about the hardship endured by the production team. Such as shooting in a country notorious for typhoons, even at one time the place they were story the film burnt down, but luckily it remained safe, and the little fact that the main character Martin sheen was a supposed alcoholic, and would turn up on set with hangovers. All this helps to perpetuate the legend that is apocalypse now, and the irony that they were facing their own war, just at the same time they were filming it. But what I love most in film, is when bold story and director hold up a mirror to society, penetrating through the shards and illusions of morality and believing that we are able to distinguish between good vs. Evil as if it was between black and white, that we like to delude ourselves with every day, but then when we enter the battlefield it seems our civilised selves gets left behind as lines get blurred. And that is what Apocalypse now does best, it blurs the line. And with lines blurred it not a surprised that the main characters go insane, pretty much anyone would, in the face of a world that turns the world you lived and knew upside down. But my only criticism of film, is the focus of the film, I feel it waved far too much into the obsession of Martin Sheen's character as he tries to find Marlon Brando, when I feel that they could have taken time aside to explore the war from the perspective of the other men accompanying him on his journey, particularly Laurence Fishbuornes character who was just 17, so it would have been interesting to hear things from a black boy fighting in a white man's war. It obvious my stance on the film, that I believe is must see for all, but if the first paragraph wasn't enough to persuade you into watching Apocalypse now, here is another, I would go as far as to say that Vittorio Storaro cinematography was as if watching a walking and talking Picasso piece, such was the extent of the visual art mastery he conjured up in Apocalypse Now, as if he were the offspring of Gandalf and Dumbledore. The final few scenes with Marlon Brando were simply captivating, short but sweet. Vittorio Storaro's blending of darkness and shimmers of light streaking across Brando's face was simply breathtaking, giving Brando an almost god like aura. The scene itself probably belongs hanged up on a wall in the Tate Modern as much as it deserves to be on a film screen. The benchmark for all to follow.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Apocalypse Now - The Best War film ever made?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Daniel Metcalf
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    After I had watched "Psycho" I decided to watch "Apocalypse Now" for similar reasons. Both were two of the highest films on my watch list and recent posts by a member on here persuaded me not to delay my viewings and finally watch them. The work of Hitchcock made me want to see Psycho after immediately falling in love with some of his films, the same can be said of Coppola although I had only seen "The Godfather" it was a film that afterwards I knew I had just watched a masterpiece. "Apocalypse Now" is a film of three thirds (I decided to watch the Redux version, perhaps two halves is more applicable to the original) As the Americans lead by Kiglore approach a Vietnamese village we witness one of the great battle scenes in film history and it's no surprise that Quentin Tarantino rates this film as one of his favourites of all time with the first third something you'd expect to see from the director himself. In the first third, Coppola manages to create one of (if not) the greatest battle scenes in film history. We see the Americans lead by Capt. Kilgore destroy an entire Vietnamese village. Although some may see this seen as maleficent and uneasy due to the sheer amount of bloodshed, the superb performance of Kilgore turns it in to an extremely enjoyable, bizarre and fun scene. We see him turn on music and joking around before killing hundreds of people, then once the men land on ground we see him getting ready to search the waves amidst all the chaos as he produces one of the film's most memorable lines, "I love the spell of napalm in the morning". Robert Duvall creates one of the most memorable and fun characters in film history, someone who flourishes in the setting of war and someone whose insane behaviour will stay in our minds long after viewing. In the middle the film tends to drag more than the other thirds, some of the scenes are justified as we learn more about Captain Kurtz, an ex soldier who has gone insane and set himself up as a God among the local people. At first it seems that we can attempt to justify some of Kurtz actions and can understand why he may have gone crazy, it is not until the finally scenes that the full extent of his command is revealed. Martin Sheen portrays the film's main character, Captain Willard, the narrator of the story and the man sent on the mission to assassinate Kurtz. His morals and attitude towards the various situations are important to the film, at first he feels reluctant to murder a US soldier, where as in the final scenes we see a much more different side to his character upon finally meeting Kurtz. At first we begin to understand why the war would turn someone crazy, after all surely Kilgore himself could be classified as such? Watching the Redux version I can certainly understand the criticisms that people have for the film with two scenes, the second meeting with the playmates and the dinner conversation with the French family seeming odd and out of place as well as lengthening the film without little contribution however it certainly does not make the film worse in anyway and allows use to have a perhaps much needed retrieve from the action filled scenes that come both before and after it. Slight Spoilers in paragraph - I won't say much about the final third in case you have not seen the film (despite the spoiler warning), but once we finally get to the Kurtz compound the scenes that follow are brilliant and horrifying at the same time. Dead bodies dangling around everywhere and decapitated heads provide us with a horrifying setting and the scale of the size, the amount of men under Kurtz command is horrifying in itself. The final scene that involves the sacrifice of a buffalo (which was very much real, adding a shocking and brutal feel to amplify an already dark scene), the final scene in which we see Willard stand facing the entire tribe is brilliant and his pause for a split second is brilliantly captured as he reacts to the perhaps unexpected and once again sees the extent of command Kurtz has set up. The film's sound is also like no other for which it deservedly won an Oscar for, going back to the battle scene the music played helps great a grand joyous feel to the whole situation despite hundreds of deaths, the sound throughout is superb, from the opening sequences to the final scene. Marlon Brando, the film's main star has little time on screen and when he does we barely get to see his face, a deliberate and brave decision that helps build up the mystery and scary character that he is. "Apocalypse Now" is a war film like no other and immediately finds itself as one of my favourites of all time. You may have recently seen by thoughts on "Kramer vs. Kramer" a film produced in the same year and even though I enjoyed it I immediately thought to myself 'surely this wasn't a better film than Apocalypse Now?', like I expected it is in my opinion an injustice how such a film that although good could beat a masterpiece to win the Best Picture award for 1979.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Watched on release in Sheffield 1979
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    intrepid-s-t-88
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It was just an ordinary Saturday afternoon. 15 lads having a few beers and talking about the same stuff we talked about the year before. I suggested going to see this movie. I think most of us knew some of terrible stuff that went on over there. The thing I remember most, is the films ability to keep 15 likely lads quite for the duration, the subdued and thoughtful demeanor of the lads when we emerged from the last panoramic screen venue in Sheffield.The opening scene with the chopper to "The Doors" recombined with the slow-mo swoosh of the copter blades. Awesome....and a prelude to the madness that was Vietnam....and "The Horror....The Horror".I even, maybe,smelled the napalm next morning, and loved it!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One Of My Favorite Films
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Alex Krajci
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    1979's Apocalypse Now Is One Of My Favorite Films, I Like It Because Of Francis Ford Coppola's Direction, John Milius And Francis Ford Coppola's Screenplay, The Editing And Vittorio Storaro's Cinematography, This Movie Came Out From The Year Angela And Heath Ledger Were, The Wonder Woman TV Series With Lynda Carter Ended In 1979, 1963 Was 16 Years Old In 1979, This Movie Came Out 34 Years Ago Back In August Of 1979, My Favorite War Film Is 1998's Saving Private Ryan With Tom Hanks, 1972's The Godfather Is My Fourth Favorite Film Of All Time, This Movie Will Be 40 Years Old In 2019, This Movie Was 25 Years Old In 2004.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Fanastic movie, but enjoyment may require your undivided attention...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Kane Yoder (soggybreeches@gmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Let me start by saying I only made this account so I could write a review of Apocalypse Now. I'm out of college now, but I remember watching this movie when I was in high school and I remember boredom and confusion and, truthfully, a lack of interest. I didn't "get" the movie. It was too slow. What was the point? What was the mission? Why weren't they getting on with it at a breakneck speed like in Bond or Bourne or ... you know what I mean. Fast forward to college (I majored in English for the plentiful job prospects ha ha) and studied Heart of Darkness, completely forgetting about Apocalypse Now. Just as many people hate this movie or love it, many people hate the novel by Joseph Conrad or love it. It's slow going and easy to miss the point. I've learned that sometimes we just have to slow our thoughts down to match the pace of the storyteller, instead of trying to outdo him or her. If you enjoy Heart of Darkness then you will enjoy this movie. Even though the era and location is completely different, this movie is almost an expansion on Heart of Darkness. You get more juicy bits of dialogue, you get to fall a little bit deeper into the crevasses of Kurtz's cracked mind. And if you're any bit a sane human being, you'll find yourself strangely comfortable with the violence and cruelty and language of the movie. You don't get the feeling that the screen is hiding anything from you and at the same time there're no morals getting stuffed down your throat. The characters on screen deal with the gruesome details of war in their own ways. Pick whom you agree with. Some you will pity, some you will find hilarious. One question the movie begs: what, in war, is right? The music for this movie serves the setting excellently, at one point the bass thumping two beats like a heartbeat. Some rock and roll from the era prevails (like The Doors's "The End"). All of it to make Martin Sheen's journey utterly foreign, exotic, yet familiar. The visuals in this movie are fantastic. So vibrant and colorful, sometimes it's like a good acid trip. You don't see colors like these in movies nowadays. Watch it and you'll know what I mean. I don't want to say anything about the plot, but here... This movie, even though it is slow, wastes no time with dialogue. A lot of it is voice-over! If you don't pay attention, you'll miss a new development either on the mission, or on the character. (If you fail to understand the characters in this movie, then you will probably not like the movie.) Watch This Movie!! Slow your mind down, try to enjoy it. Give it your undivided attention. Amid all the carnage, callousness, and ruthlessness, you may find a story that is very human, and very close to your soul.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The horrors of war...the horrors of humanity...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    endrit qarolli
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    To summarize this film in one sentence: The best film of all time.This movie does not get enough credit.It is original, dark, meaningful Cappolas best work. After watching this movie for the first time i thought it was bad but it got me wondering so i decided to give it another shot and i was amazed the two hours and a half passed like a second it was truly an experience worth remembering a movie worth watching.Every time the movie starts and Jim Morrison starts singing it gives me goosebumps it just drives me crazy.The speech of Marlon Brando is outstanding, and when Robert Duvall say "I love the smell of napalms in the morning it smells like victory" to me that smells like something wonderfully dark and amazing its about to happen, and this movie is that.A truly astonishing piece of art. The horror...The horror This is the end...
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Flawless Film With Great Buildup and Pacing
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    chrisborg1999
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    To say that Apocalypse Now is good is a major understatement. Even to say it is great is an understatement too. But, a milestone for film making and one of Ford Coppala's best (he has so many though) A very interesting fact is that over 200 hours of film were shot and it too 3 years to edit which you can see very clearly considering that the cinematography and transitions are perfect and nothing is out of place. The musical score fits the tone perfectly and the characters are very well developed I can't give anything away because I can't tell you for everyone interprets this movie differently. But please, I urge you to watch this masterpiece for you to experience how Vietnam War life was like
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    This Is The End...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    AaronCapenBanner
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Francis Ford Coppola directs this fascinating but very strange, unique film about Army Captain Willard(Martin Sheen, fine shell-shocked performance) who is sent "Up River" on a secret mission to assassinate renegade Col. Kurtz(Marlon Brando, bizarre but unforgettable performance) who has apparently gone insane, abandoned his command, and now rules over a primitive people in the remote jungles of Vietnam. Story is far more involved than that though, especially in the expanded directors cut that is much longer, but also fascinating. Willard encounters many strange sights and people(even among his own crew) as he tries to make sense out of the enveloping madness of this war, and his own inner demons. Film is a visual marvel, and holds your attention as it unfolds its increasingly philosophical, even existentialist narrative. May take multiple viewings to fully comprehend, but is worth it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Amazing and great!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bernard-layer
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Strange, fascinating, grandiose, paranoid, overwhelming, epic, disgusting, gigantic! These are the many adjectives that can be used to describe the monument of cinema. The Redux version extended by about 45 minutes, was fully supervised by Francis Coppola for the 20th anniversary of the film and to its operation on DVD. Sequences reintegrated not distort the original about the film. We have the right to more playmates, more madness and especially more Brando, for the benefit of the character Kurtz. Only the sequence of the French plantation (30 minutes alone) is questionable digression because it has the French so naive and causes a break from the narrative. The film, supported by a director prey to megalomania, was brought forth in pain. The sets were ravaged by a storm. Helicopters lent by the army of the country where the shooting took place, were requisitioned to fight against a coup when turning the aerial sequences. Lead actor Martin Sheen, drunk all day long, had a heart attack. The director gave her tray for a whole week for a romantic extramarital under the eyes of his wife incorporated the technical team. Time and on budget were so happily overwhelmed to the point that the production company of Coppola, Zoetrope, went bankrupt and the theatrical release was compromised until his selection at Cannes with a montage done in an emergency. This adventure film is told in the documentary Heart of Darkness dedicated to filming. Palme d'or at Cannes' festival in 1979, Oscar for best photography.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    more of an anti-war movie than a pro-war one
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    scottj471
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I can't argue with anyone who says this movie is good all around. The cast is great, the scenes change well from one to the next, the special effects are good for 1979, and the plot is solid. For some one looking for a movie that is more pro-war this isn't really your trade. With the exception of Robert Duvall's, one of the great cast members, Air Mobile unit and the scenes they performed so nicely. Other than that it's your, unfortunately, typical Vietnam war movie that presents our soldiers as rapists, murderers, drug addicts, and uncommitted freaks who can't be controlled or commanded. Once you get over all that BS you can enjoy this movie to the full. If not, check out We Were Soldiers with Mel Gibson for a realistic war movie.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    a tale of a world teetering on the edge of Darkness
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    silva-w-pius
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    In film it's a very rare occurrence  thus highly sort after, that a film can possess the holy trinity of a combination of a; great script, a legendary director and an almost god like actor. But such is the elusive nature of this endeavour, it never has quite has been attained in the history of film  well that's before a certain masterpiece going by the name of Apocalypse now graced our screens with this almost mythical alliance of this magnitude. The director: Francis Ford Coppola (Godfather trilogy). The story: a tale of a world teetering on the edge of Darkness almost ready to descent into primal madness, as Capt. Willard (Martin Sheen) has to navigate his way through hell on earth to find and kill AWOL Col. Kurtz (The actor:) Marlon Brando (On the Waterfront and Godfather 1) - whose very name is translated into greatness in almost every language known to man. The epic tale of this coming together will probably never happen again or would even have another three components assembled that will ever parallel it. So it something to be marvelled at, as you sits down in your comfortable chair to watch such a spectacle. It has been widely reported from a variety of different sources about the hardship endured by the production team. Such as shooting in a country notorious for typhoons, even at one time the place they were story the film burnt down, but luckily it remained safe, and the little fact that the main character Martin sheen was a supposed alcoholic, and would turn up on set with hangovers. All this helps to perpetuate the legend that is apocalypse now, and the irony that they were facing their own war, just at the same time they were filming it. But what I love most in film, is when bold story and director hold up a mirror to society, penetrating through the shards and illusions of morality and believing that we are able to distinguish between good vs. Evil as if it was between black and white, that we like to delude ourselves with every day, but then when we enter the battlefield it seems our civilised selves gets left behind as lines get blurred. And that is what Apocalypse now does best, it blurs the line. And with lines blurred it not a surprised that the main characters go insane, pretty much anyone would, in the face of a world that turns the world you lived and knew upside down. But my only criticism of film, is the focus of the film, I feel it waved far too much into the obsession of Martin Sheen's character as he tries to find Marlon Brando, when I feel that they could have taken time aside to explore the war from the perspective of the other men accompanying him on his journey, particularly Laurence Fishbuornes character who was just 17, so it would have been interesting to hear things from a black boy fighting in a white man's war. It obvious my stance on the film, that I believe is must see for all, but if the first paragraph wasn't enough to persuade you into watching Apocalypse now, here is another, I would go as far as to say that Vittorio Storaro cinematography was as if watching a walking and talking Picasso piece, such was the extent of the visual art mastery he conjured up in Apocalypse Now, as if he were the offspring of Gandalf and Dumbledore. The final few scenes with Marlon Brando were simply captivating, short but sweet. Vittorio Storaro's blending of darkness and shimmers of light streaking across Brando's face was simply breathtaking, giving Brando an almost god like aura. The scene itself probably belongs hanged up on a wall in the Tate Modern as much as it deserves to be on a film screen. The benchmark for all to follow.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Apocalypse Now - The Best War film ever made?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Daniel Metcalf
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    After I had watched "Psycho" I decided to watch "Apocalypse Now" for similar reasons. Both were two of the highest films on my watch list and recent posts by a member on here persuaded me not to delay my viewings and finally watch them. The work of Hitchcock made me want to see Psycho after immediately falling in love with some of his films, the same can be said of Coppola although I had only seen "The Godfather" it was a film that afterwards I knew I had just watched a masterpiece. "Apocalypse Now" is a film of three thirds (I decided to watch the Redux version, perhaps two halves is more applicable to the original) As the Americans lead by Kiglore approach a Vietnamese village we witness one of the great battle scenes in film history and it's no surprise that Quentin Tarantino rates this film as one of his favourites of all time with the first third something you'd expect to see from the director himself. In the first third, Coppola manages to create one of (if not) the greatest battle scenes in film history. We see the Americans lead by Capt. Kilgore destroy an entire Vietnamese village. Although some may see this seen as maleficent and uneasy due to the sheer amount of bloodshed, the superb performance of Kilgore turns it in to an extremely enjoyable, bizarre and fun scene. We see him turn on music and joking around before killing hundreds of people, then once the men land on ground we see him getting ready to search the waves amidst all the chaos as he produces one of the film's most memorable lines, "I love the spell of napalm in the morning". Robert Duvall creates one of the most memorable and fun characters in film history, someone who flourishes in the setting of war and someone whose insane behaviour will stay in our minds long after viewing. In the middle the film tends to drag more than the other thirds, some of the scenes are justified as we learn more about Captain Kurtz, an ex soldier who has gone insane and set himself up as a God among the local people. At first it seems that we can attempt to justify some of Kurtz actions and can understand why he may have gone crazy, it is not until the finally scenes that the full extent of his command is revealed. Martin Sheen portrays the film's main character, Captain Willard, the narrator of the story and the man sent on the mission to assassinate Kurtz. His morals and attitude towards the various situations are important to the film, at first he feels reluctant to murder a US soldier, where as in the final scenes we see a much more different side to his character upon finally meeting Kurtz. At first we begin to understand why the war would turn someone crazy, after all surely Kilgore himself could be classified as such? Watching the Redux version I can certainly understand the criticisms that people have for the film with two scenes, the second meeting with the playmates and the dinner conversation with the French family seeming odd and out of place as well as lengthening the film without little contribution however it certainly does not make the film worse in anyway and allows use to have a perhaps much needed retrieve from the action filled scenes that come both before and after it. Slight Spoilers in paragraph - I won't say much about the final third in case you have not seen the film (despite the spoiler warning), but once we finally get to the Kurtz compound the scenes that follow are brilliant and horrifying at the same time. Dead bodies dangling around everywhere and decapitated heads provide us with a horrifying setting and the scale of the size, the amount of men under Kurtz command is horrifying in itself. The final scene that involves the sacrifice of a buffalo (which was very much real, adding a shocking and brutal feel to amplify an already dark scene), the final scene in which we see Willard stand facing the entire tribe is brilliant and his pause for a split second is brilliantly captured as he reacts to the perhaps unexpected and once again sees the extent of command Kurtz has set up. The film's sound is also like no other for which it deservedly won an Oscar for, going back to the battle scene the music played helps great a grand joyous feel to the whole situation despite hundreds of deaths, the sound throughout is superb, from the opening sequences to the final scene. Marlon Brando, the film's main star has little time on screen and when he does we barely get to see his face, a deliberate and brave decision that helps build up the mystery and scary character that he is. "Apocalypse Now" is a war film like no other and immediately finds itself as one of my favourites of all time. You may have recently seen by thoughts on "Kramer vs. Kramer" a film produced in the same year and even though I enjoyed it I immediately thought to myself 'surely this wasn't a better film than Apocalypse Now?', like I expected it is in my opinion an injustice how such a film that although good could beat a masterpiece to win the Best Picture award for 1979.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Watched on release in Sheffield 1979
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    intrepid-s-t-88
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It was just an ordinary Saturday afternoon. 15 lads having a few beers and talking about the same stuff we talked about the year before. I suggested going to see this movie. I think most of us knew some of terrible stuff that went on over there. The thing I remember most, is the films ability to keep 15 likely lads quite for the duration, the subdued and thoughtful demeanor of the lads when we emerged from the last panoramic screen venue in Sheffield.The opening scene with the chopper to "The Doors" recombined with the slow-mo swoosh of the copter blades. Awesome....and a prelude to the madness that was Vietnam....and "The Horror....The Horror".I even, maybe,smelled the napalm next morning, and loved it!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One Of My Favorite Films
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Alex Krajci
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    1979's Apocalypse Now Is One Of My Favorite Films, I Like It Because Of Francis Ford Coppola's Direction, John Milius And Francis Ford Coppola's Screenplay, The Editing And Vittorio Storaro's Cinematography, This Movie Came Out From The Year Angela And Heath Ledger Were, The Wonder Woman TV Series With Lynda Carter Ended In 1979, 1963 Was 16 Years Old In 1979, This Movie Came Out 34 Years Ago Back In August Of 1979, My Favorite War Film Is 1998's Saving Private Ryan With Tom Hanks, 1972's The Godfather Is My Fourth Favorite Film Of All Time, This Movie Will Be 40 Years Old In 2019, This Movie Was 25 Years Old In 2004.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Fanastic movie, but enjoyment may require your undivided attention...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Kane Yoder (soggybreeches@gmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Let me start by saying I only made this account so I could write a review of Apocalypse Now. I'm out of college now, but I remember watching this movie when I was in high school and I remember boredom and confusion and, truthfully, a lack of interest. I didn't "get" the movie. It was too slow. What was the point? What was the mission? Why weren't they getting on with it at a breakneck speed like in Bond or Bourne or ... you know what I mean. Fast forward to college (I majored in English for the plentiful job prospects ha ha) and studied Heart of Darkness, completely forgetting about Apocalypse Now. Just as many people hate this movie or love it, many people hate the novel by Joseph Conrad or love it. It's slow going and easy to miss the point. I've learned that sometimes we just have to slow our thoughts down to match the pace of the storyteller, instead of trying to outdo him or her. If you enjoy Heart of Darkness then you will enjoy this movie. Even though the era and location is completely different, this movie is almost an expansion on Heart of Darkness. You get more juicy bits of dialogue, you get to fall a little bit deeper into the crevasses of Kurtz's cracked mind. And if you're any bit a sane human being, you'll find yourself strangely comfortable with the violence and cruelty and language of the movie. You don't get the feeling that the screen is hiding anything from you and at the same time there're no morals getting stuffed down your throat. The characters on screen deal with the gruesome details of war in their own ways. Pick whom you agree with. Some you will pity, some you will find hilarious. One question the movie begs: what, in war, is right? The music for this movie serves the setting excellently, at one point the bass thumping two beats like a heartbeat. Some rock and roll from the era prevails (like The Doors's "The End"). All of it to make Martin Sheen's journey utterly foreign, exotic, yet familiar. The visuals in this movie are fantastic. So vibrant and colorful, sometimes it's like a good acid trip. You don't see colors like these in movies nowadays. Watch it and you'll know what I mean. I don't want to say anything about the plot, but here... This movie, even though it is slow, wastes no time with dialogue. A lot of it is voice-over! If you don't pay attention, you'll miss a new development either on the mission, or on the character. (If you fail to understand the characters in this movie, then you will probably not like the movie.) Watch This Movie!! Slow your mind down, try to enjoy it. Give it your undivided attention. Amid all the carnage, callousness, and ruthlessness, you may find a story that is very human, and very close to your soul.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The horrors of war...the horrors of humanity...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    endrit qarolli
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    To summarize this film in one sentence: The best film of all time.This movie does not get enough credit.It is original, dark, meaningful Cappolas best work. After watching this movie for the first time i thought it was bad but it got me wondering so i decided to give it another shot and i was amazed the two hours and a half passed like a second it was truly an experience worth remembering a movie worth watching.Every time the movie starts and Jim Morrison starts singing it gives me goosebumps it just drives me crazy.The speech of Marlon Brando is outstanding, and when Robert Duvall say "I love the smell of napalms in the morning it smells like victory" to me that smells like something wonderfully dark and amazing its about to happen, and this movie is that.A truly astonishing piece of art. The horror...The horror This is the end...
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Flawless Film With Great Buildup and Pacing
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    chrisborg1999
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    To say that Apocalypse Now is good is a major understatement. Even to say it is great is an understatement too. But, a milestone for film making and one of Ford Coppala's best (he has so many though) A very interesting fact is that over 200 hours of film were shot and it too 3 years to edit which you can see very clearly considering that the cinematography and transitions are perfect and nothing is out of place. The musical score fits the tone perfectly and the characters are very well developed I can't give anything away because I can't tell you for everyone interprets this movie differently. But please, I urge you to watch this masterpiece for you to experience how Vietnam War life was like
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    This Is The End...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    AaronCapenBanner
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Francis Ford Coppola directs this fascinating but very strange, unique film about Army Captain Willard(Martin Sheen, fine shell-shocked performance) who is sent "Up River" on a secret mission to assassinate renegade Col. Kurtz(Marlon Brando, bizarre but unforgettable performance) who has apparently gone insane, abandoned his command, and now rules over a primitive people in the remote jungles of Vietnam. Story is far more involved than that though, especially in the expanded directors cut that is much longer, but also fascinating. Willard encounters many strange sights and people(even among his own crew) as he tries to make sense out of the enveloping madness of this war, and his own inner demons. Film is a visual marvel, and holds your attention as it unfolds its increasingly philosophical, even existentialist narrative. May take multiple viewings to fully comprehend, but is worth it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Amazing and great!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bernard-layer
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Strange, fascinating, grandiose, paranoid, overwhelming, epic, disgusting, gigantic! These are the many adjectives that can be used to describe the monument of cinema. The Redux version extended by about 45 minutes, was fully supervised by Francis Coppola for the 20th anniversary of the film and to its operation on DVD. Sequences reintegrated not distort the original about the film. We have the right to more playmates, more madness and especially more Brando, for the benefit of the character Kurtz. Only the sequence of the French plantation (30 minutes alone) is questionable digression because it has the French so naive and causes a break from the narrative. The film, supported by a director prey to megalomania, was brought forth in pain. The sets were ravaged by a storm. Helicopters lent by the army of the country where the shooting took place, were requisitioned to fight against a coup when turning the aerial sequences. Lead actor Martin Sheen, drunk all day long, had a heart attack. The director gave her tray for a whole week for a romantic extramarital under the eyes of his wife incorporated the technical team. Time and on budget were so happily overwhelmed to the point that the production company of Coppola, Zoetrope, went bankrupt and the theatrical release was compromised until his selection at Cannes with a montage done in an emergency. This adventure film is told in the documentary Heart of Darkness dedicated to filming. Palme d'or at Cannes' festival in 1979, Oscar for best photography.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    more of an anti-war movie than a pro-war one
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    scottj471
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I can't argue with anyone who says this movie is good all around. The cast is great, the scenes change well from one to the next, the special effects are good for 1979, and the plot is solid. For some one looking for a movie that is more pro-war this isn't really your trade. With the exception of Robert Duvall's, one of the great cast members, Air Mobile unit and the scenes they performed so nicely. Other than that it's your, unfortunately, typical Vietnam war movie that presents our soldiers as rapists, murderers, drug addicts, and uncommitted freaks who can't be controlled or commanded. Once you get over all that BS you can enjoy this movie to the full. If not, check out We Were Soldiers with Mel Gibson for a realistic war movie.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    a tale of a world teetering on the edge of Darkness
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    silva-w-pius
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    In film it's a very rare occurrence  thus highly sort after, that a film can possess the holy trinity of a combination of a; great script, a legendary director and an almost god like actor. But such is the elusive nature of this endeavour, it never has quite has been attained in the history of film  well that's before a certain masterpiece going by the name of Apocalypse now graced our screens with this almost mythical alliance of this magnitude. The director: Francis Ford Coppola (Godfather trilogy). The story: a tale of a world teetering on the edge of Darkness almost ready to descent into primal madness, as Capt. Willard (Martin Sheen) has to navigate his way through hell on earth to find and kill AWOL Col. Kurtz (The actor:) Marlon Brando (On the Waterfront and Godfather 1) - whose very name is translated into greatness in almost every language known to man. The epic tale of this coming together will probably never happen again or would even have another three components assembled that will ever parallel it. So it something to be marvelled at, as you sits down in your comfortable chair to watch such a spectacle. It has been widely reported from a variety of different sources about the hardship endured by the production team. Such as shooting in a country notorious for typhoons, even at one time the place they were story the film burnt down, but luckily it remained safe, and the little fact that the main character Martin sheen was a supposed alcoholic, and would turn up on set with hangovers. All this helps to perpetuate the legend that is apocalypse now, and the irony that they were facing their own war, just at the same time they were filming it. But what I love most in film, is when bold story and director hold up a mirror to society, penetrating through the shards and illusions of morality and believing that we are able to distinguish between good vs. Evil as if it was between black and white, that we like to delude ourselves with every day, but then when we enter the battlefield it seems our civilised selves gets left behind as lines get blurred. And that is what Apocalypse now does best, it blurs the line. And with lines blurred it not a surprised that the main characters go insane, pretty much anyone would, in the face of a world that turns the world you lived and knew upside down. But my only criticism of film, is the focus of the film, I feel it waved far too much into the obsession of Martin Sheen's character as he tries to find Marlon Brando, when I feel that they could have taken time aside to explore the war from the perspective of the other men accompanying him on his journey, particularly Laurence Fishbuornes character who was just 17, so it would have been interesting to hear things from a black boy fighting in a white man's war. It obvious my stance on the film, that I believe is must see for all, but if the first paragraph wasn't enough to persuade you into watching Apocalypse now, here is another, I would go as far as to say that Vittorio Storaro cinematography was as if watching a walking and talking Picasso piece, such was the extent of the visual art mastery he conjured up in Apocalypse Now, as if he were the offspring of Gandalf and Dumbledore. The final few scenes with Marlon Brando were simply captivating, short but sweet. Vittorio Storaro's blending of darkness and shimmers of light streaking across Brando's face was simply breathtaking, giving Brando an almost god like aura. The scene itself probably belongs hanged up on a wall in the Tate Modern as much as it deserves to be on a film screen. The benchmark for all to follow.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Apocalypse Now - The Best War film ever made?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Daniel Metcalf
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    After I had watched "Psycho" I decided to watch "Apocalypse Now" for similar reasons. Both were two of the highest films on my watch list and recent posts by a member on here persuaded me not to delay my viewings and finally watch them. The work of Hitchcock made me want to see Psycho after immediately falling in love with some of his films, the same can be said of Coppola although I had only seen "The Godfather" it was a film that afterwards I knew I had just watched a masterpiece. "Apocalypse Now" is a film of three thirds (I decided to watch the Redux version, perhaps two halves is more applicable to the original) As the Americans lead by Kiglore approach a Vietnamese village we witness one of the great battle scenes in film history and it's no surprise that Quentin Tarantino rates this film as one of his favourites of all time with the first third something you'd expect to see from the director himself. In the first third, Coppola manages to create one of (if not) the greatest battle scenes in film history. We see the Americans lead by Capt. Kilgore destroy an entire Vietnamese village. Although some may see this seen as maleficent and uneasy due to the sheer amount of bloodshed, the superb performance of Kilgore turns it in to an extremely enjoyable, bizarre and fun scene. We see him turn on music and joking around before killing hundreds of people, then once the men land on ground we see him getting ready to search the waves amidst all the chaos as he produces one of the film's most memorable lines, "I love the spell of napalm in the morning". Robert Duvall creates one of the most memorable and fun characters in film history, someone who flourishes in the setting of war and someone whose insane behaviour will stay in our minds long after viewing. In the middle the film tends to drag more than the other thirds, some of the scenes are justified as we learn more about Captain Kurtz, an ex soldier who has gone insane and set himself up as a God among the local people. At first it seems that we can attempt to justify some of Kurtz actions and can understand why he may have gone crazy, it is not until the finally scenes that the full extent of his command is revealed. Martin Sheen portrays the film's main character, Captain Willard, the narrator of the story and the man sent on the mission to assassinate Kurtz. His morals and attitude towards the various situations are important to the film, at first he feels reluctant to murder a US soldier, where as in the final scenes we see a much more different side to his character upon finally meeting Kurtz. At first we begin to understand why the war would turn someone crazy, after all surely Kilgore himself could be classified as such? Watching the Redux version I can certainly understand the criticisms that people have for the film with two scenes, the second meeting with the playmates and the dinner conversation with the French family seeming odd and out of place as well as lengthening the film without little contribution however it certainly does not make the film worse in anyway and allows use to have a perhaps much needed retrieve from the action filled scenes that come both before and after it. Slight Spoilers in paragraph - I won't say much about the final third in case you have not seen the film (despite the spoiler warning), but once we finally get to the Kurtz compound the scenes that follow are brilliant and horrifying at the same time. Dead bodies dangling around everywhere and decapitated heads provide us with a horrifying setting and the scale of the size, the amount of men under Kurtz command is horrifying in itself. The final scene that involves the sacrifice of a buffalo (which was very much real, adding a shocking and brutal feel to amplify an already dark scene), the final scene in which we see Willard stand facing the entire tribe is brilliant and his pause for a split second is brilliantly captured as he reacts to the perhaps unexpected and once again sees the extent of command Kurtz has set up. The film's sound is also like no other for which it deservedly won an Oscar for, going back to the battle scene the music played helps great a grand joyous feel to the whole situation despite hundreds of deaths, the sound throughout is superb, from the opening sequences to the final scene. Marlon Brando, the film's main star has little time on screen and when he does we barely get to see his face, a deliberate and brave decision that helps build up the mystery and scary character that he is. "Apocalypse Now" is a war film like no other and immediately finds itself as one of my favourites of all time. You may have recently seen by thoughts on "Kramer vs. Kramer" a film produced in the same year and even though I enjoyed it I immediately thought to myself 'surely this wasn't a better film than Apocalypse Now?', like I expected it is in my opinion an injustice how such a film that although good could beat a masterpiece to win the Best Picture award for 1979.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Watched on release in Sheffield 1979
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    intrepid-s-t-88
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It was just an ordinary Saturday afternoon. 15 lads having a few beers and talking about the same stuff we talked about the year before. I suggested going to see this movie. I think most of us knew some of terrible stuff that went on over there. The thing I remember most, is the films ability to keep 15 likely lads quite for the duration, the subdued and thoughtful demeanor of the lads when we emerged from the last panoramic screen venue in Sheffield.The opening scene with the chopper to "The Doors" recombined with the slow-mo swoosh of the copter blades. Awesome....and a prelude to the madness that was Vietnam....and "The Horror....The Horror".I even, maybe,smelled the napalm next morning, and loved it!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One Of My Favorite Films
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Alex Krajci
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    1979's Apocalypse Now Is One Of My Favorite Films, I Like It Because Of Francis Ford Coppola's Direction, John Milius And Francis Ford Coppola's Screenplay, The Editing And Vittorio Storaro's Cinematography, This Movie Came Out From The Year Angela And Heath Ledger Were, The Wonder Woman TV Series With Lynda Carter Ended In 1979, 1963 Was 16 Years Old In 1979, This Movie Came Out 34 Years Ago Back In August Of 1979, My Favorite War Film Is 1998's Saving Private Ryan With Tom Hanks, 1972's The Godfather Is My Fourth Favorite Film Of All Time, This Movie Will Be 40 Years Old In 2019, This Movie Was 25 Years Old In 2004.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Fanastic movie, but enjoyment may require your undivided attention...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Kane Yoder (soggybreeches@gmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Let me start by saying I only made this account so I could write a review of Apocalypse Now. I'm out of college now, but I remember watching this movie when I was in high school and I remember boredom and confusion and, truthfully, a lack of interest. I didn't "get" the movie. It was too slow. What was the point? What was the mission? Why weren't they getting on with it at a breakneck speed like in Bond or Bourne or ... you know what I mean. Fast forward to college (I majored in English for the plentiful job prospects ha ha) and studied Heart of Darkness, completely forgetting about Apocalypse Now. Just as many people hate this movie or love it, many people hate the novel by Joseph Conrad or love it. It's slow going and easy to miss the point. I've learned that sometimes we just have to slow our thoughts down to match the pace of the storyteller, instead of trying to outdo him or her. If you enjoy Heart of Darkness then you will enjoy this movie. Even though the era and location is completely different, this movie is almost an expansion on Heart of Darkness. You get more juicy bits of dialogue, you get to fall a little bit deeper into the crevasses of Kurtz's cracked mind. And if you're any bit a sane human being, you'll find yourself strangely comfortable with the violence and cruelty and language of the movie. You don't get the feeling that the screen is hiding anything from you and at the same time there're no morals getting stuffed down your throat. The characters on screen deal with the gruesome details of war in their own ways. Pick whom you agree with. Some you will pity, some you will find hilarious. One question the movie begs: what, in war, is right? The music for this movie serves the setting excellently, at one point the bass thumping two beats like a heartbeat. Some rock and roll from the era prevails (like The Doors's "The End"). All of it to make Martin Sheen's journey utterly foreign, exotic, yet familiar. The visuals in this movie are fantastic. So vibrant and colorful, sometimes it's like a good acid trip. You don't see colors like these in movies nowadays. Watch it and you'll know what I mean. I don't want to say anything about the plot, but here... This movie, even though it is slow, wastes no time with dialogue. A lot of it is voice-over! If you don't pay attention, you'll miss a new development either on the mission, or on the character. (If you fail to understand the characters in this movie, then you will probably not like the movie.) Watch This Movie!! Slow your mind down, try to enjoy it. Give it your undivided attention. Amid all the carnage, callousness, and ruthlessness, you may find a story that is very human, and very close to your soul.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The horrors of war...the horrors of humanity...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    endrit qarolli
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    To summarize this film in one sentence: The best film of all time.This movie does not get enough credit.It is original, dark, meaningful Cappolas best work. After watching this movie for the first time i thought it was bad but it got me wondering so i decided to give it another shot and i was amazed the two hours and a half passed like a second it was truly an experience worth remembering a movie worth watching.Every time the movie starts and Jim Morrison starts singing it gives me goosebumps it just drives me crazy.The speech of Marlon Brando is outstanding, and when Robert Duvall say "I love the smell of napalms in the morning it smells like victory" to me that smells like something wonderfully dark and amazing its about to happen, and this movie is that.A truly astonishing piece of art. The horror...The horror This is the end...
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Flawless Film With Great Buildup and Pacing
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    chrisborg1999
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    To say that Apocalypse Now is good is a major understatement. Even to say it is great is an understatement too. But, a milestone for film making and one of Ford Coppala's best (he has so many though) A very interesting fact is that over 200 hours of film were shot and it too 3 years to edit which you can see very clearly considering that the cinematography and transitions are perfect and nothing is out of place. The musical score fits the tone perfectly and the characters are very well developed I can't give anything away because I can't tell you for everyone interprets this movie differently. But please, I urge you to watch this masterpiece for you to experience how Vietnam War life was like
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    This Is The End...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    AaronCapenBanner
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Francis Ford Coppola directs this fascinating but very strange, unique film about Army Captain Willard(Martin Sheen, fine shell-shocked performance) who is sent "Up River" on a secret mission to assassinate renegade Col. Kurtz(Marlon Brando, bizarre but unforgettable performance) who has apparently gone insane, abandoned his command, and now rules over a primitive people in the remote jungles of Vietnam. Story is far more involved than that though, especially in the expanded directors cut that is much longer, but also fascinating. Willard encounters many strange sights and people(even among his own crew) as he tries to make sense out of the enveloping madness of this war, and his own inner demons. Film is a visual marvel, and holds your attention as it unfolds its increasingly philosophical, even existentialist narrative. May take multiple viewings to fully comprehend, but is worth it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Amazing and great!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bernard-layer
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Strange, fascinating, grandiose, paranoid, overwhelming, epic, disgusting, gigantic! These are the many adjectives that can be used to describe the monument of cinema. The Redux version extended by about 45 minutes, was fully supervised by Francis Coppola for the 20th anniversary of the film and to its operation on DVD. Sequences reintegrated not distort the original about the film. We have the right to more playmates, more madness and especially more Brando, for the benefit of the character Kurtz. Only the sequence of the French plantation (30 minutes alone) is questionable digression because it has the French so naive and causes a break from the narrative. The film, supported by a director prey to megalomania, was brought forth in pain. The sets were ravaged by a storm. Helicopters lent by the army of the country where the shooting took place, were requisitioned to fight against a coup when turning the aerial sequences. Lead actor Martin Sheen, drunk all day long, had a heart attack. The director gave her tray for a whole week for a romantic extramarital under the eyes of his wife incorporated the technical team. Time and on budget were so happily overwhelmed to the point that the production company of Coppola, Zoetrope, went bankrupt and the theatrical release was compromised until his selection at Cannes with a montage done in an emergency. This adventure film is told in the documentary Heart of Darkness dedicated to filming. Palme d'or at Cannes' festival in 1979, Oscar for best photography.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    more of an anti-war movie than a pro-war one
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    scottj471
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I can't argue with anyone who says this movie is good all around. The cast is great, the scenes change well from one to the next, the special effects are good for 1979, and the plot is solid. For some one looking for a movie that is more pro-war this isn't really your trade. With the exception of Robert Duvall's, one of the great cast members, Air Mobile unit and the scenes they performed so nicely. Other than that it's your, unfortunately, typical Vietnam war movie that presents our soldiers as rapists, murderers, drug addicts, and uncommitted freaks who can't be controlled or commanded. Once you get over all that BS you can enjoy this movie to the full. If not, check out We Were Soldiers with Mel Gibson for a realistic war movie.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    a tale of a world teetering on the edge of Darkness
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    silva-w-pius
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    In film it's a very rare occurrence  thus highly sort after, that a film can possess the holy trinity of a combination of a; great script, a legendary director and an almost god like actor. But such is the elusive nature of this endeavour, it never has quite has been attained in the history of film  well that's before a certain masterpiece going by the name of Apocalypse now graced our screens with this almost mythical alliance of this magnitude. The director: Francis Ford Coppola (Godfather trilogy). The story: a tale of a world teetering on the edge of Darkness almost ready to descent into primal madness, as Capt. Willard (Martin Sheen) has to navigate his way through hell on earth to find and kill AWOL Col. Kurtz (The actor:) Marlon Brando (On the Waterfront and Godfather 1) - whose very name is translated into greatness in almost every language known to man. The epic tale of this coming together will probably never happen again or would even have another three components assembled that will ever parallel it. So it something to be marvelled at, as you sits down in your comfortable chair to watch such a spectacle. It has been widely reported from a variety of different sources about the hardship endured by the production team. Such as shooting in a country notorious for typhoons, even at one time the place they were story the film burnt down, but luckily it remained safe, and the little fact that the main character Martin sheen was a supposed alcoholic, and would turn up on set with hangovers. All this helps to perpetuate the legend that is apocalypse now, and the irony that they were facing their own war, just at the same time they were filming it. But what I love most in film, is when bold story and director hold up a mirror to society, penetrating through the shards and illusions of morality and believing that we are able to distinguish between good vs. Evil as if it was between black and white, that we like to delude ourselves with every day, but then when we enter the battlefield it seems our civilised selves gets left behind as lines get blurred. And that is what Apocalypse now does best, it blurs the line. And with lines blurred it not a surprised that the main characters go insane, pretty much anyone would, in the face of a world that turns the world you lived and knew upside down. But my only criticism of film, is the focus of the film, I feel it waved far too much into the obsession of Martin Sheen's character as he tries to find Marlon Brando, when I feel that they could have taken time aside to explore the war from the perspective of the other men accompanying him on his journey, particularly Laurence Fishbuornes character who was just 17, so it would have been interesting to hear things from a black boy fighting in a white man's war. It obvious my stance on the film, that I believe is must see for all, but if the first paragraph wasn't enough to persuade you into watching Apocalypse now, here is another, I would go as far as to say that Vittorio Storaro cinematography was as if watching a walking and talking Picasso piece, such was the extent of the visual art mastery he conjured up in Apocalypse Now, as if he were the offspring of Gandalf and Dumbledore. The final few scenes with Marlon Brando were simply captivating, short but sweet. Vittorio Storaro's blending of darkness and shimmers of light streaking across Brando's face was simply breathtaking, giving Brando an almost god like aura. The scene itself probably belongs hanged up on a wall in the Tate Modern as much as it deserves to be on a film screen. The benchmark for all to follow.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Apocalypse Now - The Best War film ever made?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Daniel Metcalf
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    After I had watched "Psycho" I decided to watch "Apocalypse Now" for similar reasons. Both were two of the highest films on my watch list and recent posts by a member on here persuaded me not to delay my viewings and finally watch them. The work of Hitchcock made me want to see Psycho after immediately falling in love with some of his films, the same can be said of Coppola although I had only seen "The Godfather" it was a film that afterwards I knew I had just watched a masterpiece. "Apocalypse Now" is a film of three thirds (I decided to watch the Redux version, perhaps two halves is more applicable to the original) As the Americans lead by Kiglore approach a Vietnamese village we witness one of the great battle scenes in film history and it's no surprise that Quentin Tarantino rates this film as one of his favourites of all time with the first third something you'd expect to see from the director himself. In the first third, Coppola manages to create one of (if not) the greatest battle scenes in film history. We see the Americans lead by Capt. Kilgore destroy an entire Vietnamese village. Although some may see this seen as maleficent and uneasy due to the sheer amount of bloodshed, the superb performance of Kilgore turns it in to an extremely enjoyable, bizarre and fun scene. We see him turn on music and joking around before killing hundreds of people, then once the men land on ground we see him getting ready to search the waves amidst all the chaos as he produces one of the film's most memorable lines, "I love the spell of napalm in the morning". Robert Duvall creates one of the most memorable and fun characters in film history, someone who flourishes in the setting of war and someone whose insane behaviour will stay in our minds long after viewing. In the middle the film tends to drag more than the other thirds, some of the scenes are justified as we learn more about Captain Kurtz, an ex soldier who has gone insane and set himself up as a God among the local people. At first it seems that we can attempt to justify some of Kurtz actions and can understand why he may have gone crazy, it is not until the finally scenes that the full extent of his command is revealed. Martin Sheen portrays the film's main character, Captain Willard, the narrator of the story and the man sent on the mission to assassinate Kurtz. His morals and attitude towards the various situations are important to the film, at first he feels reluctant to murder a US soldier, where as in the final scenes we see a much more different side to his character upon finally meeting Kurtz. At first we begin to understand why the war would turn someone crazy, after all surely Kilgore himself could be classified as such? Watching the Redux version I can certainly understand the criticisms that people have for the film with two scenes, the second meeting with the playmates and the dinner conversation with the French family seeming odd and out of place as well as lengthening the film without little contribution however it certainly does not make the film worse in anyway and allows use to have a perhaps much needed retrieve from the action filled scenes that come both before and after it. Slight Spoilers in paragraph - I won't say much about the final third in case you have not seen the film (despite the spoiler warning), but once we finally get to the Kurtz compound the scenes that follow are brilliant and horrifying at the same time. Dead bodies dangling around everywhere and decapitated heads provide us with a horrifying setting and the scale of the size, the amount of men under Kurtz command is horrifying in itself. The final scene that involves the sacrifice of a buffalo (which was very much real, adding a shocking and brutal feel to amplify an already dark scene), the final scene in which we see Willard stand facing the entire tribe is brilliant and his pause for a split second is brilliantly captured as he reacts to the perhaps unexpected and once again sees the extent of command Kurtz has set up. The film's sound is also like no other for which it deservedly won an Oscar for, going back to the battle scene the music played helps great a grand joyous feel to the whole situation despite hundreds of deaths, the sound throughout is superb, from the opening sequences to the final scene. Marlon Brando, the film's main star has little time on screen and when he does we barely get to see his face, a deliberate and brave decision that helps build up the mystery and scary character that he is. "Apocalypse Now" is a war film like no other and immediately finds itself as one of my favourites of all time. You may have recently seen by thoughts on "Kramer vs. Kramer" a film produced in the same year and even though I enjoyed it I immediately thought to myself 'surely this wasn't a better film than Apocalypse Now?', like I expected it is in my opinion an injustice how such a film that although good could beat a masterpiece to win the Best Picture award for 1979.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Watched on release in Sheffield 1979
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    intrepid-s-t-88
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It was just an ordinary Saturday afternoon. 15 lads having a few beers and talking about the same stuff we talked about the year before. I suggested going to see this movie. I think most of us knew some of terrible stuff that went on over there. The thing I remember most, is the films ability to keep 15 likely lads quite for the duration, the subdued and thoughtful demeanor of the lads when we emerged from the last panoramic screen venue in Sheffield.The opening scene with the chopper to "The Doors" recombined with the slow-mo swoosh of the copter blades. Awesome....and a prelude to the madness that was Vietnam....and "The Horror....The Horror".I even, maybe,smelled the napalm next morning, and loved it!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One Of My Favorite Films
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Alex Krajci
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    1979's Apocalypse Now Is One Of My Favorite Films, I Like It Because Of Francis Ford Coppola's Direction, John Milius And Francis Ford Coppola's Screenplay, The Editing And Vittorio Storaro's Cinematography, This Movie Came Out From The Year Angela And Heath Ledger Were, The Wonder Woman TV Series With Lynda Carter Ended In 1979, 1963 Was 16 Years Old In 1979, This Movie Came Out 34 Years Ago Back In August Of 1979, My Favorite War Film Is 1998's Saving Private Ryan With Tom Hanks, 1972's The Godfather Is My Fourth Favorite Film Of All Time, This Movie Will Be 40 Years Old In 2019, This Movie Was 25 Years Old In 2004.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Fanastic movie, but enjoyment may require your undivided attention...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Kane Yoder (soggybreeches@gmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Let me start by saying I only made this account so I could write a review of Apocalypse Now. I'm out of college now, but I remember watching this movie when I was in high school and I remember boredom and confusion and, truthfully, a lack of interest. I didn't "get" the movie. It was too slow. What was the point? What was the mission? Why weren't they getting on with it at a breakneck speed like in Bond or Bourne or ... you know what I mean. Fast forward to college (I majored in English for the plentiful job prospects ha ha) and studied Heart of Darkness, completely forgetting about Apocalypse Now. Just as many people hate this movie or love it, many people hate the novel by Joseph Conrad or love it. It's slow going and easy to miss the point. I've learned that sometimes we just have to slow our thoughts down to match the pace of the storyteller, instead of trying to outdo him or her. If you enjoy Heart of Darkness then you will enjoy this movie. Even though the era and location is completely different, this movie is almost an expansion on Heart of Darkness. You get more juicy bits of dialogue, you get to fall a little bit deeper into the crevasses of Kurtz's cracked mind. And if you're any bit a sane human being, you'll find yourself strangely comfortable with the violence and cruelty and language of the movie. You don't get the feeling that the screen is hiding anything from you and at the same time there're no morals getting stuffed down your throat. The characters on screen deal with the gruesome details of war in their own ways. Pick whom you agree with. Some you will pity, some you will find hilarious. One question the movie begs: what, in war, is right? The music for this movie serves the setting excellently, at one point the bass thumping two beats like a heartbeat. Some rock and roll from the era prevails (like The Doors's "The End"). All of it to make Martin Sheen's journey utterly foreign, exotic, yet familiar. The visuals in this movie are fantastic. So vibrant and colorful, sometimes it's like a good acid trip. You don't see colors like these in movies nowadays. Watch it and you'll know what I mean. I don't want to say anything about the plot, but here... This movie, even though it is slow, wastes no time with dialogue. A lot of it is voice-over! If you don't pay attention, you'll miss a new development either on the mission, or on the character. (If you fail to understand the characters in this movie, then you will probably not like the movie.) Watch This Movie!! Slow your mind down, try to enjoy it. Give it your undivided attention. Amid all the carnage, callousness, and ruthlessness, you may find a story that is very human, and very close to your soul.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The horrors of war...the horrors of humanity...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    endrit qarolli
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    To summarize this film in one sentence: The best film of all time.This movie does not get enough credit.It is original, dark, meaningful Cappolas best work. After watching this movie for the first time i thought it was bad but it got me wondering so i decided to give it another shot and i was amazed the two hours and a half passed like a second it was truly an experience worth remembering a movie worth watching.Every time the movie starts and Jim Morrison starts singing it gives me goosebumps it just drives me crazy.The speech of Marlon Brando is outstanding, and when Robert Duvall say "I love the smell of napalms in the morning it smells like victory" to me that smells like something wonderfully dark and amazing its about to happen, and this movie is that.A truly astonishing piece of art. The horror...The horror This is the end...
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Flawless Film With Great Buildup and Pacing
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    chrisborg1999
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    To say that Apocalypse Now is good is a major understatement. Even to say it is great is an understatement too. But, a milestone for film making and one of Ford Coppala's best (he has so many though) A very interesting fact is that over 200 hours of film were shot and it too 3 years to edit which you can see very clearly considering that the cinematography and transitions are perfect and nothing is out of place. The musical score fits the tone perfectly and the characters are very well developed I can't give anything away because I can't tell you for everyone interprets this movie differently. But please, I urge you to watch this masterpiece for you to experience how Vietnam War life was like
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    This Is The End...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    AaronCapenBanner
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Francis Ford Coppola directs this fascinating but very strange, unique film about Army Captain Willard(Martin Sheen, fine shell-shocked performance) who is sent "Up River" on a secret mission to assassinate renegade Col. Kurtz(Marlon Brando, bizarre but unforgettable performance) who has apparently gone insane, abandoned his command, and now rules over a primitive people in the remote jungles of Vietnam. Story is far more involved than that though, especially in the expanded directors cut that is much longer, but also fascinating. Willard encounters many strange sights and people(even among his own crew) as he tries to make sense out of the enveloping madness of this war, and his own inner demons. Film is a visual marvel, and holds your attention as it unfolds its increasingly philosophical, even existentialist narrative. May take multiple viewings to fully comprehend, but is worth it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Amazing and great!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bernard-layer
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Strange, fascinating, grandiose, paranoid, overwhelming, epic, disgusting, gigantic! These are the many adjectives that can be used to describe the monument of cinema. The Redux version extended by about 45 minutes, was fully supervised by Francis Coppola for the 20th anniversary of the film and to its operation on DVD. Sequences reintegrated not distort the original about the film. We have the right to more playmates, more madness and especially more Brando, for the benefit of the character Kurtz. Only the sequence of the French plantation (30 minutes alone) is questionable digression because it has the French so naive and causes a break from the narrative. The film, supported by a director prey to megalomania, was brought forth in pain. The sets were ravaged by a storm. Helicopters lent by the army of the country where the shooting took place, were requisitioned to fight against a coup when turning the aerial sequences. Lead actor Martin Sheen, drunk all day long, had a heart attack. The director gave her tray for a whole week for a romantic extramarital under the eyes of his wife incorporated the technical team. Time and on budget were so happily overwhelmed to the point that the production company of Coppola, Zoetrope, went bankrupt and the theatrical release was compromised until his selection at Cannes with a montage done in an emergency. This adventure film is told in the documentary Heart of Darkness dedicated to filming. Palme d'or at Cannes' festival in 1979, Oscar for best photography.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    more of an anti-war movie than a pro-war one
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    scottj471
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I can't argue with anyone who says this movie is good all around. The cast is great, the scenes change well from one to the next, the special effects are good for 1979, and the plot is solid. For some one looking for a movie that is more pro-war this isn't really your trade. With the exception of Robert Duvall's, one of the great cast members, Air Mobile unit and the scenes they performed so nicely. Other than that it's your, unfortunately, typical Vietnam war movie that presents our soldiers as rapists, murderers, drug addicts, and uncommitted freaks who can't be controlled or commanded. Once you get over all that BS you can enjoy this movie to the full. If not, check out We Were Soldiers with Mel Gibson for a realistic war movie.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    a tale of a world teetering on the edge of Darkness
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    silva-w-pius
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    In film it's a very rare occurrence  thus highly sort after, that a film can possess the holy trinity of a combination of a; great script, a legendary director and an almost god like actor. But such is the elusive nature of this endeavour, it never has quite has been attained in the history of film  well that's before a certain masterpiece going by the name of Apocalypse now graced our screens with this almost mythical alliance of this magnitude. The director: Francis Ford Coppola (Godfather trilogy). The story: a tale of a world teetering on the edge of Darkness almost ready to descent into primal madness, as Capt. Willard (Martin Sheen) has to navigate his way through hell on earth to find and kill AWOL Col. Kurtz (The actor:) Marlon Brando (On the Waterfront and Godfather 1) - whose very name is translated into greatness in almost every language known to man. The epic tale of this coming together will probably never happen again or would even have another three components assembled that will ever parallel it. So it something to be marvelled at, as you sits down in your comfortable chair to watch such a spectacle. It has been widely reported from a variety of different sources about the hardship endured by the production team. Such as shooting in a country notorious for typhoons, even at one time the place they were story the film burnt down, but luckily it remained safe, and the little fact that the main character Martin sheen was a supposed alcoholic, and would turn up on set with hangovers. All this helps to perpetuate the legend that is apocalypse now, and the irony that they were facing their own war, just at the same time they were filming it. But what I love most in film, is when bold story and director hold up a mirror to society, penetrating through the shards and illusions of morality and believing that we are able to distinguish between good vs. Evil as if it was between black and white, that we like to delude ourselves with every day, but then when we enter the battlefield it seems our civilised selves gets left behind as lines get blurred. And that is what Apocalypse now does best, it blurs the line. And with lines blurred it not a surprised that the main characters go insane, pretty much anyone would, in the face of a world that turns the world you lived and knew upside down. But my only criticism of film, is the focus of the film, I feel it waved far too much into the obsession of Martin Sheen's character as he tries to find Marlon Brando, when I feel that they could have taken time aside to explore the war from the perspective of the other men accompanying him on his journey, particularly Laurence Fishbuornes character who was just 17, so it would have been interesting to hear things from a black boy fighting in a white man's war. It obvious my stance on the film, that I believe is must see for all, but if the first paragraph wasn't enough to persuade you into watching Apocalypse now, here is another, I would go as far as to say that Vittorio Storaro cinematography was as if watching a walking and talking Picasso piece, such was the extent of the visual art mastery he conjured up in Apocalypse Now, as if he were the offspring of Gandalf and Dumbledore. The final few scenes with Marlon Brando were simply captivating, short but sweet. Vittorio Storaro's blending of darkness and shimmers of light streaking across Brando's face was simply breathtaking, giving Brando an almost god like aura. The scene itself probably belongs hanged up on a wall in the Tate Modern as much as it deserves to be on a film screen. The benchmark for all to follow.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Apocalypse Now - The Best War film ever made?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Daniel Metcalf
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    After I had watched "Psycho" I decided to watch "Apocalypse Now" for similar reasons. Both were two of the highest films on my watch list and recent posts by a member on here persuaded me not to delay my viewings and finally watch them. The work of Hitchcock made me want to see Psycho after immediately falling in love with some of his films, the same can be said of Coppola although I had only seen "The Godfather" it was a film that afterwards I knew I had just watched a masterpiece. "Apocalypse Now" is a film of three thirds (I decided to watch the Redux version, perhaps two halves is more applicable to the original) As the Americans lead by Kiglore approach a Vietnamese village we witness one of the great battle scenes in film history and it's no surprise that Quentin Tarantino rates this film as one of his favourites of all time with the first third something you'd expect to see from the director himself. In the first third, Coppola manages to create one of (if not) the greatest battle scenes in film history. We see the Americans lead by Capt. Kilgore destroy an entire Vietnamese village. Although some may see this seen as maleficent and uneasy due to the sheer amount of bloodshed, the superb performance of Kilgore turns it in to an extremely enjoyable, bizarre and fun scene. We see him turn on music and joking around before killing hundreds of people, then once the men land on ground we see him getting ready to search the waves amidst all the chaos as he produces one of the film's most memorable lines, "I love the spell of napalm in the morning". Robert Duvall creates one of the most memorable and fun characters in film history, someone who flourishes in the setting of war and someone whose insane behaviour will stay in our minds long after viewing. In the middle the film tends to drag more than the other thirds, some of the scenes are justified as we learn more about Captain Kurtz, an ex soldier who has gone insane and set himself up as a God among the local people. At first it seems that we can attempt to justify some of Kurtz actions and can understand why he may have gone crazy, it is not until the finally scenes that the full extent of his command is revealed. Martin Sheen portrays the film's main character, Captain Willard, the narrator of the story and the man sent on the mission to assassinate Kurtz. His morals and attitude towards the various situations are important to the film, at first he feels reluctant to murder a US soldier, where as in the final scenes we see a much more different side to his character upon finally meeting Kurtz. At first we begin to understand why the war would turn someone crazy, after all surely Kilgore himself could be classified as such? Watching the Redux version I can certainly understand the criticisms that people have for the film with two scenes, the second meeting with the playmates and the dinner conversation with the French family seeming odd and out of place as well as lengthening the film without little contribution however it certainly does not make the film worse in anyway and allows use to have a perhaps much needed retrieve from the action filled scenes that come both before and after it. Slight Spoilers in paragraph - I won't say much about the final third in case you have not seen the film (despite the spoiler warning), but once we finally get to the Kurtz compound the scenes that follow are brilliant and horrifying at the same time. Dead bodies dangling around everywhere and decapitated heads provide us with a horrifying setting and the scale of the size, the amount of men under Kurtz command is horrifying in itself. The final scene that involves the sacrifice of a buffalo (which was very much real, adding a shocking and brutal feel to amplify an already dark scene), the final scene in which we see Willard stand facing the entire tribe is brilliant and his pause for a split second is brilliantly captured as he reacts to the perhaps unexpected and once again sees the extent of command Kurtz has set up. The film's sound is also like no other for which it deservedly won an Oscar for, going back to the battle scene the music played helps great a grand joyous feel to the whole situation despite hundreds of deaths, the sound throughout is superb, from the opening sequences to the final scene. Marlon Brando, the film's main star has little time on screen and when he does we barely get to see his face, a deliberate and brave decision that helps build up the mystery and scary character that he is. "Apocalypse Now" is a war film like no other and immediately finds itself as one of my favourites of all time. You may have recently seen by thoughts on "Kramer vs. Kramer" a film produced in the same year and even though I enjoyed it I immediately thought to myself 'surely this wasn't a better film than Apocalypse Now?', like I expected it is in my opinion an injustice how such a film that although good could beat a masterpiece to win the Best Picture award for 1979.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Watched on release in Sheffield 1979
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    intrepid-s-t-88
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It was just an ordinary Saturday afternoon. 15 lads having a few beers and talking about the same stuff we talked about the year before. I suggested going to see this movie. I think most of us knew some of terrible stuff that went on over there. The thing I remember most, is the films ability to keep 15 likely lads quite for the duration, the subdued and thoughtful demeanor of the lads when we emerged from the last panoramic screen venue in Sheffield.The opening scene with the chopper to "The Doors" recombined with the slow-mo swoosh of the copter blades. Awesome....and a prelude to the madness that was Vietnam....and "The Horror....The Horror".I even, maybe,smelled the napalm next morning, and loved it!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One Of My Favorite Films
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Alex Krajci
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    1979's Apocalypse Now Is One Of My Favorite Films, I Like It Because Of Francis Ford Coppola's Direction, John Milius And Francis Ford Coppola's Screenplay, The Editing And Vittorio Storaro's Cinematography, This Movie Came Out From The Year Angela And Heath Ledger Were, The Wonder Woman TV Series With Lynda Carter Ended In 1979, 1963 Was 16 Years Old In 1979, This Movie Came Out 34 Years Ago Back In August Of 1979, My Favorite War Film Is 1998's Saving Private Ryan With Tom Hanks, 1972's The Godfather Is My Fourth Favorite Film Of All Time, This Movie Will Be 40 Years Old In 2019, This Movie Was 25 Years Old In 2004.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Fanastic movie, but enjoyment may require your undivided attention...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Kane Yoder (soggybreeches@gmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Let me start by saying I only made this account so I could write a review of Apocalypse Now. I'm out of college now, but I remember watching this movie when I was in high school and I remember boredom and confusion and, truthfully, a lack of interest. I didn't "get" the movie. It was too slow. What was the point? What was the mission? Why weren't they getting on with it at a breakneck speed like in Bond or Bourne or ... you know what I mean. Fast forward to college (I majored in English for the plentiful job prospects ha ha) and studied Heart of Darkness, completely forgetting about Apocalypse Now. Just as many people hate this movie or love it, many people hate the novel by Joseph Conrad or love it. It's slow going and easy to miss the point. I've learned that sometimes we just have to slow our thoughts down to match the pace of the storyteller, instead of trying to outdo him or her. If you enjoy Heart of Darkness then you will enjoy this movie. Even though the era and location is completely different, this movie is almost an expansion on Heart of Darkness. You get more juicy bits of dialogue, you get to fall a little bit deeper into the crevasses of Kurtz's cracked mind. And if you're any bit a sane human being, you'll find yourself strangely comfortable with the violence and cruelty and language of the movie. You don't get the feeling that the screen is hiding anything from you and at the same time there're no morals getting stuffed down your throat. The characters on screen deal with the gruesome details of war in their own ways. Pick whom you agree with. Some you will pity, some you will find hilarious. One question the movie begs: what, in war, is right? The music for this movie serves the setting excellently, at one point the bass thumping two beats like a heartbeat. Some rock and roll from the era prevails (like The Doors's "The End"). All of it to make Martin Sheen's journey utterly foreign, exotic, yet familiar. The visuals in this movie are fantastic. So vibrant and colorful, sometimes it's like a good acid trip. You don't see colors like these in movies nowadays. Watch it and you'll know what I mean. I don't want to say anything about the plot, but here... This movie, even though it is slow, wastes no time with dialogue. A lot of it is voice-over! If you don't pay attention, you'll miss a new development either on the mission, or on the character. (If you fail to understand the characters in this movie, then you will probably not like the movie.) Watch This Movie!! Slow your mind down, try to enjoy it. Give it your undivided attention. Amid all the carnage, callousness, and ruthlessness, you may find a story that is very human, and very close to your soul.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The horrors of war...the horrors of humanity...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    endrit qarolli
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    To summarize this film in one sentence: The best film of all time.This movie does not get enough credit.It is original, dark, meaningful Cappolas best work. After watching this movie for the first time i thought it was bad but it got me wondering so i decided to give it another shot and i was amazed the two hours and a half passed like a second it was truly an experience worth remembering a movie worth watching.Every time the movie starts and Jim Morrison starts singing it gives me goosebumps it just drives me crazy.The speech of Marlon Brando is outstanding, and when Robert Duvall say "I love the smell of napalms in the morning it smells like victory" to me that smells like something wonderfully dark and amazing its about to happen, and this movie is that.A truly astonishing piece of art. The horror...The horror This is the end...
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Flawless Film With Great Buildup and Pacing
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    chrisborg1999
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    To say that Apocalypse Now is good is a major understatement. Even to say it is great is an understatement too. But, a milestone for film making and one of Ford Coppala's best (he has so many though) A very interesting fact is that over 200 hours of film were shot and it too 3 years to edit which you can see very clearly considering that the cinematography and transitions are perfect and nothing is out of place. The musical score fits the tone perfectly and the characters are very well developed I can't give anything away because I can't tell you for everyone interprets this movie differently. But please, I urge you to watch this masterpiece for you to experience how Vietnam War life was like
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    This Is The End...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    AaronCapenBanner
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Francis Ford Coppola directs this fascinating but very strange, unique film about Army Captain Willard(Martin Sheen, fine shell-shocked performance) who is sent "Up River" on a secret mission to assassinate renegade Col. Kurtz(Marlon Brando, bizarre but unforgettable performance) who has apparently gone insane, abandoned his command, and now rules over a primitive people in the remote jungles of Vietnam. Story is far more involved than that though, especially in the expanded directors cut that is much longer, but also fascinating. Willard encounters many strange sights and people(even among his own crew) as he tries to make sense out of the enveloping madness of this war, and his own inner demons. Film is a visual marvel, and holds your attention as it unfolds its increasingly philosophical, even existentialist narrative. May take multiple viewings to fully comprehend, but is worth it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Amazing and great!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bernard-layer
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Strange, fascinating, grandiose, paranoid, overwhelming, epic, disgusting, gigantic! These are the many adjectives that can be used to describe the monument of cinema. The Redux version extended by about 45 minutes, was fully supervised by Francis Coppola for the 20th anniversary of the film and to its operation on DVD. Sequences reintegrated not distort the original about the film. We have the right to more playmates, more madness and especially more Brando, for the benefit of the character Kurtz. Only the sequence of the French plantation (30 minutes alone) is questionable digression because it has the French so naive and causes a break from the narrative. The film, supported by a director prey to megalomania, was brought forth in pain. The sets were ravaged by a storm. Helicopters lent by the army of the country where the shooting took place, were requisitioned to fight against a coup when turning the aerial sequences. Lead actor Martin Sheen, drunk all day long, had a heart attack. The director gave her tray for a whole week for a romantic extramarital under the eyes of his wife incorporated the technical team. Time and on budget were so happily overwhelmed to the point that the production company of Coppola, Zoetrope, went bankrupt and the theatrical release was compromised until his selection at Cannes with a montage done in an emergency. This adventure film is told in the documentary Heart of Darkness dedicated to filming. Palme d'or at Cannes' festival in 1979, Oscar for best photography.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    more of an anti-war movie than a pro-war one
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    scottj471
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I can't argue with anyone who says this movie is good all around. The cast is great, the scenes change well from one to the next, the special effects are good for 1979, and the plot is solid. For some one looking for a movie that is more pro-war this isn't really your trade. With the exception of Robert Duvall's, one of the great cast members, Air Mobile unit and the scenes they performed so nicely. Other than that it's your, unfortunately, typical Vietnam war movie that presents our soldiers as rapists, murderers, drug addicts, and uncommitted freaks who can't be controlled or commanded. Once you get over all that BS you can enjoy this movie to the full. If not, check out We Were Soldiers with Mel Gibson for a realistic war movie.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    a tale of a world teetering on the edge of Darkness
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    silva-w-pius
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    In film it's a very rare occurrence  thus highly sort after, that a film can possess the holy trinity of a combination of a; great script, a legendary director and an almost god like actor. But such is the elusive nature of this endeavour, it never has quite has been attained in the history of film  well that's before a certain masterpiece going by the name of Apocalypse now graced our screens with this almost mythical alliance of this magnitude. The director: Francis Ford Coppola (Godfather trilogy). The story: a tale of a world teetering on the edge of Darkness almost ready to descent into primal madness, as Capt. Willard (Martin Sheen) has to navigate his way through hell on earth to find and kill AWOL Col. Kurtz (The actor:) Marlon Brando (On the Waterfront and Godfather 1) - whose very name is translated into greatness in almost every language known to man. The epic tale of this coming together will probably never happen again or would even have another three components assembled that will ever parallel it. So it something to be marvelled at, as you sits down in your comfortable chair to watch such a spectacle. It has been widely reported from a variety of different sources about the hardship endured by the production team. Such as shooting in a country notorious for typhoons, even at one time the place they were story the film burnt down, but luckily it remained safe, and the little fact that the main character Martin sheen was a supposed alcoholic, and would turn up on set with hangovers. All this helps to perpetuate the legend that is apocalypse now, and the irony that they were facing their own war, just at the same time they were filming it. But what I love most in film, is when bold story and director hold up a mirror to society, penetrating through the shards and illusions of morality and believing that we are able to distinguish between good vs. Evil as if it was between black and white, that we like to delude ourselves with every day, but then when we enter the battlefield it seems our civilised selves gets left behind as lines get blurred. And that is what Apocalypse now does best, it blurs the line. And with lines blurred it not a surprised that the main characters go insane, pretty much anyone would, in the face of a world that turns the world you lived and knew upside down. But my only criticism of film, is the focus of the film, I feel it waved far too much into the obsession of Martin Sheen's character as he tries to find Marlon Brando, when I feel that they could have taken time aside to explore the war from the perspective of the other men accompanying him on his journey, particularly Laurence Fishbuornes character who was just 17, so it would have been interesting to hear things from a black boy fighting in a white man's war. It obvious my stance on the film, that I believe is must see for all, but if the first paragraph wasn't enough to persuade you into watching Apocalypse now, here is another, I would go as far as to say that Vittorio Storaro cinematography was as if watching a walking and talking Picasso piece, such was the extent of the visual art mastery he conjured up in Apocalypse Now, as if he were the offspring of Gandalf and Dumbledore. The final few scenes with Marlon Brando were simply captivating, short but sweet. Vittorio Storaro's blending of darkness and shimmers of light streaking across Brando's face was simply breathtaking, giving Brando an almost god like aura. The scene itself probably belongs hanged up on a wall in the Tate Modern as much as it deserves to be on a film screen. The benchmark for all to follow.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Apocalypse Now - The Best War film ever made?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Daniel Metcalf
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    After I had watched "Psycho" I decided to watch "Apocalypse Now" for similar reasons. Both were two of the highest films on my watch list and recent posts by a member on here persuaded me not to delay my viewings and finally watch them. The work of Hitchcock made me want to see Psycho after immediately falling in love with some of his films, the same can be said of Coppola although I had only seen "The Godfather" it was a film that afterwards I knew I had just watched a masterpiece. "Apocalypse Now" is a film of three thirds (I decided to watch the Redux version, perhaps two halves is more applicable to the original) As the Americans lead by Kiglore approach a Vietnamese village we witness one of the great battle scenes in film history and it's no surprise that Quentin Tarantino rates this film as one of his favourites of all time with the first third something you'd expect to see from the director himself. In the first third, Coppola manages to create one of (if not) the greatest battle scenes in film history. We see the Americans lead by Capt. Kilgore destroy an entire Vietnamese village. Although some may see this seen as maleficent and uneasy due to the sheer amount of bloodshed, the superb performance of Kilgore turns it in to an extremely enjoyable, bizarre and fun scene. We see him turn on music and joking around before killing hundreds of people, then once the men land on ground we see him getting ready to search the waves amidst all the chaos as he produces one of the film's most memorable lines, "I love the spell of napalm in the morning". Robert Duvall creates one of the most memorable and fun characters in film history, someone who flourishes in the setting of war and someone whose insane behaviour will stay in our minds long after viewing. In the middle the film tends to drag more than the other thirds, some of the scenes are justified as we learn more about Captain Kurtz, an ex soldier who has gone insane and set himself up as a God among the local people. At first it seems that we can attempt to justify some of Kurtz actions and can understand why he may have gone crazy, it is not until the finally scenes that the full extent of his command is revealed. Martin Sheen portrays the film's main character, Captain Willard, the narrator of the story and the man sent on the mission to assassinate Kurtz. His morals and attitude towards the various situations are important to the film, at first he feels reluctant to murder a US soldier, where as in the final scenes we see a much more different side to his character upon finally meeting Kurtz. At first we begin to understand why the war would turn someone crazy, after all surely Kilgore himself could be classified as such? Watching the Redux version I can certainly understand the criticisms that people have for the film with two scenes, the second meeting with the playmates and the dinner conversation with the French family seeming odd and out of place as well as lengthening the film without little contribution however it certainly does not make the film worse in anyway and allows use to have a perhaps much needed retrieve from the action filled scenes that come both before and after it. Slight Spoilers in paragraph - I won't say much about the final third in case you have not seen the film (despite the spoiler warning), but once we finally get to the Kurtz compound the scenes that follow are brilliant and horrifying at the same time. Dead bodies dangling around everywhere and decapitated heads provide us with a horrifying setting and the scale of the size, the amount of men under Kurtz command is horrifying in itself. The final scene that involves the sacrifice of a buffalo (which was very much real, adding a shocking and brutal feel to amplify an already dark scene), the final scene in which we see Willard stand facing the entire tribe is brilliant and his pause for a split second is brilliantly captured as he reacts to the perhaps unexpected and once again sees the extent of command Kurtz has set up. The film's sound is also like no other for which it deservedly won an Oscar for, going back to the battle scene the music played helps great a grand joyous feel to the whole situation despite hundreds of deaths, the sound throughout is superb, from the opening sequences to the final scene. Marlon Brando, the film's main star has little time on screen and when he does we barely get to see his face, a deliberate and brave decision that helps build up the mystery and scary character that he is. "Apocalypse Now" is a war film like no other and immediately finds itself as one of my favourites of all time. You may have recently seen by thoughts on "Kramer vs. Kramer" a film produced in the same year and even though I enjoyed it I immediately thought to myself 'surely this wasn't a better film than Apocalypse Now?', like I expected it is in my opinion an injustice how such a film that although good could beat a masterpiece to win the Best Picture award for 1979.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Watched on release in Sheffield 1979
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    intrepid-s-t-88
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It was just an ordinary Saturday afternoon. 15 lads having a few beers and talking about the same stuff we talked about the year before. I suggested going to see this movie. I think most of us knew some of terrible stuff that went on over there. The thing I remember most, is the films ability to keep 15 likely lads quite for the duration, the subdued and thoughtful demeanor of the lads when we emerged from the last panoramic screen venue in Sheffield.The opening scene with the chopper to "The Doors" recombined with the slow-mo swoosh of the copter blades. Awesome....and a prelude to the madness that was Vietnam....and "The Horror....The Horror".I even, maybe,smelled the napalm next morning, and loved it!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One Of My Favorite Films
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Alex Krajci
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    1979's Apocalypse Now Is One Of My Favorite Films, I Like It Because Of Francis Ford Coppola's Direction, John Milius And Francis Ford Coppola's Screenplay, The Editing And Vittorio Storaro's Cinematography, This Movie Came Out From The Year Angela And Heath Ledger Were, The Wonder Woman TV Series With Lynda Carter Ended In 1979, 1963 Was 16 Years Old In 1979, This Movie Came Out 34 Years Ago Back In August Of 1979, My Favorite War Film Is 1998's Saving Private Ryan With Tom Hanks, 1972's The Godfather Is My Fourth Favorite Film Of All Time, This Movie Will Be 40 Years Old In 2019, This Movie Was 25 Years Old In 2004.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Fanastic movie, but enjoyment may require your undivided attention...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Kane Yoder (soggybreeches@gmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Let me start by saying I only made this account so I could write a review of Apocalypse Now. I'm out of college now, but I remember watching this movie when I was in high school and I remember boredom and confusion and, truthfully, a lack of interest. I didn't "get" the movie. It was too slow. What was the point? What was the mission? Why weren't they getting on with it at a breakneck speed like in Bond or Bourne or ... you know what I mean. Fast forward to college (I majored in English for the plentiful job prospects ha ha) and studied Heart of Darkness, completely forgetting about Apocalypse Now. Just as many people hate this movie or love it, many people hate the novel by Joseph Conrad or love it. It's slow going and easy to miss the point. I've learned that sometimes we just have to slow our thoughts down to match the pace of the storyteller, instead of trying to outdo him or her. If you enjoy Heart of Darkness then you will enjoy this movie. Even though the era and location is completely different, this movie is almost an expansion on Heart of Darkness. You get more juicy bits of dialogue, you get to fall a little bit deeper into the crevasses of Kurtz's cracked mind. And if you're any bit a sane human being, you'll find yourself strangely comfortable with the violence and cruelty and language of the movie. You don't get the feeling that the screen is hiding anything from you and at the same time there're no morals getting stuffed down your throat. The characters on screen deal with the gruesome details of war in their own ways. Pick whom you agree with. Some you will pity, some you will find hilarious. One question the movie begs: what, in war, is right? The music for this movie serves the setting excellently, at one point the bass thumping two beats like a heartbeat. Some rock and roll from the era prevails (like The Doors's "The End"). All of it to make Martin Sheen's journey utterly foreign, exotic, yet familiar. The visuals in this movie are fantastic. So vibrant and colorful, sometimes it's like a good acid trip. You don't see colors like these in movies nowadays. Watch it and you'll know what I mean. I don't want to say anything about the plot, but here... This movie, even though it is slow, wastes no time with dialogue. A lot of it is voice-over! If you don't pay attention, you'll miss a new development either on the mission, or on the character. (If you fail to understand the characters in this movie, then you will probably not like the movie.) Watch This Movie!! Slow your mind down, try to enjoy it. Give it your undivided attention. Amid all the carnage, callousness, and ruthlessness, you may find a story that is very human, and very close to your soul.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The horrors of war...the horrors of humanity...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    endrit qarolli
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    To summarize this film in one sentence: The best film of all time.This movie does not get enough credit.It is original, dark, meaningful Cappolas best work. After watching this movie for the first time i thought it was bad but it got me wondering so i decided to give it another shot and i was amazed the two hours and a half passed like a second it was truly an experience worth remembering a movie worth watching.Every time the movie starts and Jim Morrison starts singing it gives me goosebumps it just drives me crazy.The speech of Marlon Brando is outstanding, and when Robert Duvall say "I love the smell of napalms in the morning it smells like victory" to me that smells like something wonderfully dark and amazing its about to happen, and this movie is that.A truly astonishing piece of art. The horror...The horror This is the end...
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Flawless Film With Great Buildup and Pacing
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    chrisborg1999
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    To say that Apocalypse Now is good is a major understatement. Even to say it is great is an understatement too. But, a milestone for film making and one of Ford Coppala's best (he has so many though) A very interesting fact is that over 200 hours of film were shot and it too 3 years to edit which you can see very clearly considering that the cinematography and transitions are perfect and nothing is out of place. The musical score fits the tone perfectly and the characters are very well developed I can't give anything away because I can't tell you for everyone interprets this movie differently. But please, I urge you to watch this masterpiece for you to experience how Vietnam War life was like
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    This Is The End...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    AaronCapenBanner
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Francis Ford Coppola directs this fascinating but very strange, unique film about Army Captain Willard(Martin Sheen, fine shell-shocked performance) who is sent "Up River" on a secret mission to assassinate renegade Col. Kurtz(Marlon Brando, bizarre but unforgettable performance) who has apparently gone insane, abandoned his command, and now rules over a primitive people in the remote jungles of Vietnam. Story is far more involved than that though, especially in the expanded directors cut that is much longer, but also fascinating. Willard encounters many strange sights and people(even among his own crew) as he tries to make sense out of the enveloping madness of this war, and his own inner demons. Film is a visual marvel, and holds your attention as it unfolds its increasingly philosophical, even existentialist narrative. May take multiple viewings to fully comprehend, but is worth it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Amazing and great!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bernard-layer
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Strange, fascinating, grandiose, paranoid, overwhelming, epic, disgusting, gigantic! These are the many adjectives that can be used to describe the monument of cinema. The Redux version extended by about 45 minutes, was fully supervised by Francis Coppola for the 20th anniversary of the film and to its operation on DVD. Sequences reintegrated not distort the original about the film. We have the right to more playmates, more madness and especially more Brando, for the benefit of the character Kurtz. Only the sequence of the French plantation (30 minutes alone) is questionable digression because it has the French so naive and causes a break from the narrative. The film, supported by a director prey to megalomania, was brought forth in pain. The sets were ravaged by a storm. Helicopters lent by the army of the country where the shooting took place, were requisitioned to fight against a coup when turning the aerial sequences. Lead actor Martin Sheen, drunk all day long, had a heart attack. The director gave her tray for a whole week for a romantic extramarital under the eyes of his wife incorporated the technical team. Time and on budget were so happily overwhelmed to the point that the production company of Coppola, Zoetrope, went bankrupt and the theatrical release was compromised until his selection at Cannes with a montage done in an emergency. This adventure film is told in the documentary Heart of Darkness dedicated to filming. Palme d'or at Cannes' festival in 1979, Oscar for best photography.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    more of an anti-war movie than a pro-war one
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    scottj471
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I can't argue with anyone who says this movie is good all around. The cast is great, the scenes change well from one to the next, the special effects are good for 1979, and the plot is solid. For some one looking for a movie that is more pro-war this isn't really your trade. With the exception of Robert Duvall's, one of the great cast members, Air Mobile unit and the scenes they performed so nicely. Other than that it's your, unfortunately, typical Vietnam war movie that presents our soldiers as rapists, murderers, drug addicts, and uncommitted freaks who can't be controlled or commanded. Once you get over all that BS you can enjoy this movie to the full. If not, check out We Were Soldiers with Mel Gibson for a realistic war movie.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    a tale of a world teetering on the edge of Darkness
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    silva-w-pius
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    In film it's a very rare occurrence  thus highly sort after, that a film can possess the holy trinity of a combination of a; great script, a legendary director and an almost god like actor. But such is the elusive nature of this endeavour, it never has quite has been attained in the history of film  well that's before a certain masterpiece going by the name of Apocalypse now graced our screens with this almost mythical alliance of this magnitude. The director: Francis Ford Coppola (Godfather trilogy). The story: a tale of a world teetering on the edge of Darkness almost ready to descent into primal madness, as Capt. Willard (Martin Sheen) has to navigate his way through hell on earth to find and kill AWOL Col. Kurtz (The actor:) Marlon Brando (On the Waterfront and Godfather 1) - whose very name is translated into greatness in almost every language known to man. The epic tale of this coming together will probably never happen again or would even have another three components assembled that will ever parallel it. So it something to be marvelled at, as you sits down in your comfortable chair to watch such a spectacle. It has been widely reported from a variety of different sources about the hardship endured by the production team. Such as shooting in a country notorious for typhoons, even at one time the place they were story the film burnt down, but luckily it remained safe, and the little fact that the main character Martin sheen was a supposed alcoholic, and would turn up on set with hangovers. All this helps to perpetuate the legend that is apocalypse now, and the irony that they were facing their own war, just at the same time they were filming it. But what I love most in film, is when bold story and director hold up a mirror to society, penetrating through the shards and illusions of morality and believing that we are able to distinguish between good vs. Evil as if it was between black and white, that we like to delude ourselves with every day, but then when we enter the battlefield it seems our civilised selves gets left behind as lines get blurred. And that is what Apocalypse now does best, it blurs the line. And with lines blurred it not a surprised that the main characters go insane, pretty much anyone would, in the face of a world that turns the world you lived and knew upside down. But my only criticism of film, is the focus of the film, I feel it waved far too much into the obsession of Martin Sheen's character as he tries to find Marlon Brando, when I feel that they could have taken time aside to explore the war from the perspective of the other men accompanying him on his journey, particularly Laurence Fishbuornes character who was just 17, so it would have been interesting to hear things from a black boy fighting in a white man's war. It obvious my stance on the film, that I believe is must see for all, but if the first paragraph wasn't enough to persuade you into watching Apocalypse now, here is another, I would go as far as to say that Vittorio Storaro cinematography was as if watching a walking and talking Picasso piece, such was the extent of the visual art mastery he conjured up in Apocalypse Now, as if he were the offspring of Gandalf and Dumbledore. The final few scenes with Marlon Brando were simply captivating, short but sweet. Vittorio Storaro's blending of darkness and shimmers of light streaking across Brando's face was simply breathtaking, giving Brando an almost god like aura. The scene itself probably belongs hanged up on a wall in the Tate Modern as much as it deserves to be on a film screen. The benchmark for all to follow.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Apocalypse Now - The Best War film ever made?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Daniel Metcalf
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    After I had watched "Psycho" I decided to watch "Apocalypse Now" for similar reasons. Both were two of the highest films on my watch list and recent posts by a member on here persuaded me not to delay my viewings and finally watch them. The work of Hitchcock made me want to see Psycho after immediately falling in love with some of his films, the same can be said of Coppola although I had only seen "The Godfather" it was a film that afterwards I knew I had just watched a masterpiece. "Apocalypse Now" is a film of three thirds (I decided to watch the Redux version, perhaps two halves is more applicable to the original) As the Americans lead by Kiglore approach a Vietnamese village we witness one of the great battle scenes in film history and it's no surprise that Quentin Tarantino rates this film as one of his favourites of all time with the first third something you'd expect to see from the director himself. In the first third, Coppola manages to create one of (if not) the greatest battle scenes in film history. We see the Americans lead by Capt. Kilgore destroy an entire Vietnamese village. Although some may see this seen as maleficent and uneasy due to the sheer amount of bloodshed, the superb performance of Kilgore turns it in to an extremely enjoyable, bizarre and fun scene. We see him turn on music and joking around before killing hundreds of people, then once the men land on ground we see him getting ready to search the waves amidst all the chaos as he produces one of the film's most memorable lines, "I love the spell of napalm in the morning". Robert Duvall creates one of the most memorable and fun characters in film history, someone who flourishes in the setting of war and someone whose insane behaviour will stay in our minds long after viewing. In the middle the film tends to drag more than the other thirds, some of the scenes are justified as we learn more about Captain Kurtz, an ex soldier who has gone insane and set himself up as a God among the local people. At first it seems that we can attempt to justify some of Kurtz actions and can understand why he may have gone crazy, it is not until the finally scenes that the full extent of his command is revealed. Martin Sheen portrays the film's main character, Captain Willard, the narrator of the story and the man sent on the mission to assassinate Kurtz. His morals and attitude towards the various situations are important to the film, at first he feels reluctant to murder a US soldier, where as in the final scenes we see a much more different side to his character upon finally meeting Kurtz. At first we begin to understand why the war would turn someone crazy, after all surely Kilgore himself could be classified as such? Watching the Redux version I can certainly understand the criticisms that people have for the film with two scenes, the second meeting with the playmates and the dinner conversation with the French family seeming odd and out of place as well as lengthening the film without little contribution however it certainly does not make the film worse in anyway and allows use to have a perhaps much needed retrieve from the action filled scenes that come both before and after it. Slight Spoilers in paragraph - I won't say much about the final third in case you have not seen the film (despite the spoiler warning), but once we finally get to the Kurtz compound the scenes that follow are brilliant and horrifying at the same time. Dead bodies dangling around everywhere and decapitated heads provide us with a horrifying setting and the scale of the size, the amount of men under Kurtz command is horrifying in itself. The final scene that involves the sacrifice of a buffalo (which was very much real, adding a shocking and brutal feel to amplify an already dark scene), the final scene in which we see Willard stand facing the entire tribe is brilliant and his pause for a split second is brilliantly captured as he reacts to the perhaps unexpected and once again sees the extent of command Kurtz has set up. The film's sound is also like no other for which it deservedly won an Oscar for, going back to the battle scene the music played helps great a grand joyous feel to the whole situation despite hundreds of deaths, the sound throughout is superb, from the opening sequences to the final scene. Marlon Brando, the film's main star has little time on screen and when he does we barely get to see his face, a deliberate and brave decision that helps build up the mystery and scary character that he is. "Apocalypse Now" is a war film like no other and immediately finds itself as one of my favourites of all time. You may have recently seen by thoughts on "Kramer vs. Kramer" a film produced in the same year and even though I enjoyed it I immediately thought to myself 'surely this wasn't a better film than Apocalypse Now?', like I expected it is in my opinion an injustice how such a film that although good could beat a masterpiece to win the Best Picture award for 1979.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Watched on release in Sheffield 1979
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    intrepid-s-t-88
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It was just an ordinary Saturday afternoon. 15 lads having a few beers and talking about the same stuff we talked about the year before. I suggested going to see this movie. I think most of us knew some of terrible stuff that went on over there. The thing I remember most, is the films ability to keep 15 likely lads quite for the duration, the subdued and thoughtful demeanor of the lads when we emerged from the last panoramic screen venue in Sheffield.The opening scene with the chopper to "The Doors" recombined with the slow-mo swoosh of the copter blades. Awesome....and a prelude to the madness that was Vietnam....and "The Horror....The Horror".I even, maybe,smelled the napalm next morning, and loved it!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One Of My Favorite Films
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Alex Krajci
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    1979's Apocalypse Now Is One Of My Favorite Films, I Like It Because Of Francis Ford Coppola's Direction, John Milius And Francis Ford Coppola's Screenplay, The Editing And Vittorio Storaro's Cinematography, This Movie Came Out From The Year Angela And Heath Ledger Were, The Wonder Woman TV Series With Lynda Carter Ended In 1979, 1963 Was 16 Years Old In 1979, This Movie Came Out 34 Years Ago Back In August Of 1979, My Favorite War Film Is 1998's Saving Private Ryan With Tom Hanks, 1972's The Godfather Is My Fourth Favorite Film Of All Time, This Movie Will Be 40 Years Old In 2019, This Movie Was 25 Years Old In 2004.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Fanastic movie, but enjoyment may require your undivided attention...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Kane Yoder (soggybreeches@gmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Let me start by saying I only made this account so I could write a review of Apocalypse Now. I'm out of college now, but I remember watching this movie when I was in high school and I remember boredom and confusion and, truthfully, a lack of interest. I didn't "get" the movie. It was too slow. What was the point? What was the mission? Why weren't they getting on with it at a breakneck speed like in Bond or Bourne or ... you know what I mean. Fast forward to college (I majored in English for the plentiful job prospects ha ha) and studied Heart of Darkness, completely forgetting about Apocalypse Now. Just as many people hate this movie or love it, many people hate the novel by Joseph Conrad or love it. It's slow going and easy to miss the point. I've learned that sometimes we just have to slow our thoughts down to match the pace of the storyteller, instead of trying to outdo him or her. If you enjoy Heart of Darkness then you will enjoy this movie. Even though the era and location is completely different, this movie is almost an expansion on Heart of Darkness. You get more juicy bits of dialogue, you get to fall a little bit deeper into the crevasses of Kurtz's cracked mind. And if you're any bit a sane human being, you'll find yourself strangely comfortable with the violence and cruelty and language of the movie. You don't get the feeling that the screen is hiding anything from you and at the same time there're no morals getting stuffed down your throat. The characters on screen deal with the gruesome details of war in their own ways. Pick whom you agree with. Some you will pity, some you will find hilarious. One question the movie begs: what, in war, is right? The music for this movie serves the setting excellently, at one point the bass thumping two beats like a heartbeat. Some rock and roll from the era prevails (like The Doors's "The End"). All of it to make Martin Sheen's journey utterly foreign, exotic, yet familiar. The visuals in this movie are fantastic. So vibrant and colorful, sometimes it's like a good acid trip. You don't see colors like these in movies nowadays. Watch it and you'll know what I mean. I don't want to say anything about the plot, but here... This movie, even though it is slow, wastes no time with dialogue. A lot of it is voice-over! If you don't pay attention, you'll miss a new development either on the mission, or on the character. (If you fail to understand the characters in this movie, then you will probably not like the movie.) Watch This Movie!! Slow your mind down, try to enjoy it. Give it your undivided attention. Amid all the carnage, callousness, and ruthlessness, you may find a story that is very human, and very close to your soul.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The horrors of war...the horrors of humanity...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    endrit qarolli
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    To summarize this film in one sentence: The best film of all time.This movie does not get enough credit.It is original, dark, meaningful Cappolas best work. After watching this movie for the first time i thought it was bad but it got me wondering so i decided to give it another shot and i was amazed the two hours and a half passed like a second it was truly an experience worth remembering a movie worth watching.Every time the movie starts and Jim Morrison starts singing it gives me goosebumps it just drives me crazy.The speech of Marlon Brando is outstanding, and when Robert Duvall say "I love the smell of napalms in the morning it smells like victory" to me that smells like something wonderfully dark and amazing its about to happen, and this movie is that.A truly astonishing piece of art. The horror...The horror This is the end...
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Flawless Film With Great Buildup and Pacing
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    chrisborg1999
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    To say that Apocalypse Now is good is a major understatement. Even to say it is great is an understatement too. But, a milestone for film making and one of Ford Coppala's best (he has so many though) A very interesting fact is that over 200 hours of film were shot and it too 3 years to edit which you can see very clearly considering that the cinematography and transitions are perfect and nothing is out of place. The musical score fits the tone perfectly and the characters are very well developed I can't give anything away because I can't tell you for everyone interprets this movie differently. But please, I urge you to watch this masterpiece for you to experience how Vietnam War life was like
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    This Is The End...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    AaronCapenBanner
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Francis Ford Coppola directs this fascinating but very strange, unique film about Army Captain Willard(Martin Sheen, fine shell-shocked performance) who is sent "Up River" on a secret mission to assassinate renegade Col. Kurtz(Marlon Brando, bizarre but unforgettable performance) who has apparently gone insane, abandoned his command, and now rules over a primitive people in the remote jungles of Vietnam. Story is far more involved than that though, especially in the expanded directors cut that is much longer, but also fascinating. Willard encounters many strange sights and people(even among his own crew) as he tries to make sense out of the enveloping madness of this war, and his own inner demons. Film is a visual marvel, and holds your attention as it unfolds its increasingly philosophical, even existentialist narrative. May take multiple viewings to fully comprehend, but is worth it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Amazing and great!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bernard-layer
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Strange, fascinating, grandiose, paranoid, overwhelming, epic, disgusting, gigantic! These are the many adjectives that can be used to describe the monument of cinema. The Redux version extended by about 45 minutes, was fully supervised by Francis Coppola for the 20th anniversary of the film and to its operation on DVD. Sequences reintegrated not distort the original about the film. We have the right to more playmates, more madness and especially more Brando, for the benefit of the character Kurtz. Only the sequence of the French plantation (30 minutes alone) is questionable digression because it has the French so naive and causes a break from the narrative. The film, supported by a director prey to megalomania, was brought forth in pain. The sets were ravaged by a storm. Helicopters lent by the army of the country where the shooting took place, were requisitioned to fight against a coup when turning the aerial sequences. Lead actor Martin Sheen, drunk all day long, had a heart attack. The director gave her tray for a whole week for a romantic extramarital under the eyes of his wife incorporated the technical team. Time and on budget were so happily overwhelmed to the point that the production company of Coppola, Zoetrope, went bankrupt and the theatrical release was compromised until his selection at Cannes with a montage done in an emergency. This adventure film is told in the documentary Heart of Darkness dedicated to filming. Palme d'or at Cannes' festival in 1979, Oscar for best photography.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    more of an anti-war movie than a pro-war one
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    scottj471
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I can't argue with anyone who says this movie is good all around. The cast is great, the scenes change well from one to the next, the special effects are good for 1979, and the plot is solid. For some one looking for a movie that is more pro-war this isn't really your trade. With the exception of Robert Duvall's, one of the great cast members, Air Mobile unit and the scenes they performed so nicely. Other than that it's your, unfortunately, typical Vietnam war movie that presents our soldiers as rapists, murderers, drug addicts, and uncommitted freaks who can't be controlled or commanded. Once you get over all that BS you can enjoy this movie to the full. If not, check out We Were Soldiers with Mel Gibson for a realistic war movie.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    a tale of a world teetering on the edge of Darkness
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    silva-w-pius
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    In film it's a very rare occurrence  thus highly sort after, that a film can possess the holy trinity of a combination of a; great script, a legendary director and an almost god like actor. But such is the elusive nature of this endeavour, it never has quite has been attained in the history of film  well that's before a certain masterpiece going by the name of Apocalypse now graced our screens with this almost mythical alliance of this magnitude. The director: Francis Ford Coppola (Godfather trilogy). The story: a tale of a world teetering on the edge of Darkness almost ready to descent into primal madness, as Capt. Willard (Martin Sheen) has to navigate his way through hell on earth to find and kill AWOL Col. Kurtz (The actor:) Marlon Brando (On the Waterfront and Godfather 1) - whose very name is translated into greatness in almost every language known to man. The epic tale of this coming together will probably never happen again or would even have another three components assembled that will ever parallel it. So it something to be marvelled at, as you sits down in your comfortable chair to watch such a spectacle. It has been widely reported from a variety of different sources about the hardship endured by the production team. Such as shooting in a country notorious for typhoons, even at one time the place they were story the film burnt down, but luckily it remained safe, and the little fact that the main character Martin sheen was a supposed alcoholic, and would turn up on set with hangovers. All this helps to perpetuate the legend that is apocalypse now, and the irony that they were facing their own war, just at the same time they were filming it. But what I love most in film, is when bold story and director hold up a mirror to society, penetrating through the shards and illusions of morality and believing that we are able to distinguish between good vs. Evil as if it was between black and white, that we like to delude ourselves with every day, but then when we enter the battlefield it seems our civilised selves gets left behind as lines get blurred. And that is what Apocalypse now does best, it blurs the line. And with lines blurred it not a surprised that the main characters go insane, pretty much anyone would, in the face of a world that turns the world you lived and knew upside down. But my only criticism of film, is the focus of the film, I feel it waved far too much into the obsession of Martin Sheen's character as he tries to find Marlon Brando, when I feel that they could have taken time aside to explore the war from the perspective of the other men accompanying him on his journey, particularly Laurence Fishbuornes character who was just 17, so it would have been interesting to hear things from a black boy fighting in a white man's war. It obvious my stance on the film, that I believe is must see for all, but if the first paragraph wasn't enough to persuade you into watching Apocalypse now, here is another, I would go as far as to say that Vittorio Storaro cinematography was as if watching a walking and talking Picasso piece, such was the extent of the visual art mastery he conjured up in Apocalypse Now, as if he were the offspring of Gandalf and Dumbledore. The final few scenes with Marlon Brando were simply captivating, short but sweet. Vittorio Storaro's blending of darkness and shimmers of light streaking across Brando's face was simply breathtaking, giving Brando an almost god like aura. The scene itself probably belongs hanged up on a wall in the Tate Modern as much as it deserves to be on a film screen. The benchmark for all to follow.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Apocalypse Now - The Best War film ever made?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Daniel Metcalf
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    After I had watched "Psycho" I decided to watch "Apocalypse Now" for similar reasons. Both were two of the highest films on my watch list and recent posts by a member on here persuaded me not to delay my viewings and finally watch them. The work of Hitchcock made me want to see Psycho after immediately falling in love with some of his films, the same can be said of Coppola although I had only seen "The Godfather" it was a film that afterwards I knew I had just watched a masterpiece. "Apocalypse Now" is a film of three thirds (I decided to watch the Redux version, perhaps two halves is more applicable to the original) As the Americans lead by Kiglore approach a Vietnamese village we witness one of the great battle scenes in film history and it's no surprise that Quentin Tarantino rates this film as one of his favourites of all time with the first third something you'd expect to see from the director himself. In the first third, Coppola manages to create one of (if not) the greatest battle scenes in film history. We see the Americans lead by Capt. Kilgore destroy an entire Vietnamese village. Although some may see this seen as maleficent and uneasy due to the sheer amount of bloodshed, the superb performance of Kilgore turns it in to an extremely enjoyable, bizarre and fun scene. We see him turn on music and joking around before killing hundreds of people, then once the men land on ground we see him getting ready to search the waves amidst all the chaos as he produces one of the film's most memorable lines, "I love the spell of napalm in the morning". Robert Duvall creates one of the most memorable and fun characters in film history, someone who flourishes in the setting of war and someone whose insane behaviour will stay in our minds long after viewing. In the middle the film tends to drag more than the other thirds, some of the scenes are justified as we learn more about Captain Kurtz, an ex soldier who has gone insane and set himself up as a God among the local people. At first it seems that we can attempt to justify some of Kurtz actions and can understand why he may have gone crazy, it is not until the finally scenes that the full extent of his command is revealed. Martin Sheen portrays the film's main character, Captain Willard, the narrator of the story and the man sent on the mission to assassinate Kurtz. His morals and attitude towards the various situations are important to the film, at first he feels reluctant to murder a US soldier, where as in the final scenes we see a much more different side to his character upon finally meeting Kurtz. At first we begin to understand why the war would turn someone crazy, after all surely Kilgore himself could be classified as such? Watching the Redux version I can certainly understand the criticisms that people have for the film with two scenes, the second meeting with the playmates and the dinner conversation with the French family seeming odd and out of place as well as lengthening the film without little contribution however it certainly does not make the film worse in anyway and allows use to have a perhaps much needed retrieve from the action filled scenes that come both before and after it. Slight Spoilers in paragraph - I won't say much about the final third in case you have not seen the film (despite the spoiler warning), but once we finally get to the Kurtz compound the scenes that follow are brilliant and horrifying at the same time. Dead bodies dangling around everywhere and decapitated heads provide us with a horrifying setting and the scale of the size, the amount of men under Kurtz command is horrifying in itself. The final scene that involves the sacrifice of a buffalo (which was very much real, adding a shocking and brutal feel to amplify an already dark scene), the final scene in which we see Willard stand facing the entire tribe is brilliant and his pause for a split second is brilliantly captured as he reacts to the perhaps unexpected and once again sees the extent of command Kurtz has set up. The film's sound is also like no other for which it deservedly won an Oscar for, going back to the battle scene the music played helps great a grand joyous feel to the whole situation despite hundreds of deaths, the sound throughout is superb, from the opening sequences to the final scene. Marlon Brando, the film's main star has little time on screen and when he does we barely get to see his face, a deliberate and brave decision that helps build up the mystery and scary character that he is. "Apocalypse Now" is a war film like no other and immediately finds itself as one of my favourites of all time. You may have recently seen by thoughts on "Kramer vs. Kramer" a film produced in the same year and even though I enjoyed it I immediately thought to myself 'surely this wasn't a better film than Apocalypse Now?', like I expected it is in my opinion an injustice how such a film that although good could beat a masterpiece to win the Best Picture award for 1979.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Watched on release in Sheffield 1979
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    intrepid-s-t-88
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It was just an ordinary Saturday afternoon. 15 lads having a few beers and talking about the same stuff we talked about the year before. I suggested going to see this movie. I think most of us knew some of terrible stuff that went on over there. The thing I remember most, is the films ability to keep 15 likely lads quite for the duration, the subdued and thoughtful demeanor of the lads when we emerged from the last panoramic screen venue in Sheffield.The opening scene with the chopper to "The Doors" recombined with the slow-mo swoosh of the copter blades. Awesome....and a prelude to the madness that was Vietnam....and "The Horror....The Horror".I even, maybe,smelled the napalm next morning, and loved it!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One Of My Favorite Films
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Alex Krajci
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    1979's Apocalypse Now Is One Of My Favorite Films, I Like It Because Of Francis Ford Coppola's Direction, John Milius And Francis Ford Coppola's Screenplay, The Editing And Vittorio Storaro's Cinematography, This Movie Came Out From The Year Angela And Heath Ledger Were, The Wonder Woman TV Series With Lynda Carter Ended In 1979, 1963 Was 16 Years Old In 1979, This Movie Came Out 34 Years Ago Back In August Of 1979, My Favorite War Film Is 1998's Saving Private Ryan With Tom Hanks, 1972's The Godfather Is My Fourth Favorite Film Of All Time, This Movie Will Be 40 Years Old In 2019, This Movie Was 25 Years Old In 2004.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Fanastic movie, but enjoyment may require your undivided attention...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Kane Yoder (soggybreeches@gmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Let me start by saying I only made this account so I could write a review of Apocalypse Now. I'm out of college now, but I remember watching this movie when I was in high school and I remember boredom and confusion and, truthfully, a lack of interest. I didn't "get" the movie. It was too slow. What was the point? What was the mission? Why weren't they getting on with it at a breakneck speed like in Bond or Bourne or ... you know what I mean. Fast forward to college (I majored in English for the plentiful job prospects ha ha) and studied Heart of Darkness, completely forgetting about Apocalypse Now. Just as many people hate this movie or love it, many people hate the novel by Joseph Conrad or love it. It's slow going and easy to miss the point. I've learned that sometimes we just have to slow our thoughts down to match the pace of the storyteller, instead of trying to outdo him or her. If you enjoy Heart of Darkness then you will enjoy this movie. Even though the era and location is completely different, this movie is almost an expansion on Heart of Darkness. You get more juicy bits of dialogue, you get to fall a little bit deeper into the crevasses of Kurtz's cracked mind. And if you're any bit a sane human being, you'll find yourself strangely comfortable with the violence and cruelty and language of the movie. You don't get the feeling that the screen is hiding anything from you and at the same time there're no morals getting stuffed down your throat. The characters on screen deal with the gruesome details of war in their own ways. Pick whom you agree with. Some you will pity, some you will find hilarious. One question the movie begs: what, in war, is right? The music for this movie serves the setting excellently, at one point the bass thumping two beats like a heartbeat. Some rock and roll from the era prevails (like The Doors's "The End"). All of it to make Martin Sheen's journey utterly foreign, exotic, yet familiar. The visuals in this movie are fantastic. So vibrant and colorful, sometimes it's like a good acid trip. You don't see colors like these in movies nowadays. Watch it and you'll know what I mean. I don't want to say anything about the plot, but here... This movie, even though it is slow, wastes no time with dialogue. A lot of it is voice-over! If you don't pay attention, you'll miss a new development either on the mission, or on the character. (If you fail to understand the characters in this movie, then you will probably not like the movie.) Watch This Movie!! Slow your mind down, try to enjoy it. Give it your undivided attention. Amid all the carnage, callousness, and ruthlessness, you may find a story that is very human, and very close to your soul.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The horrors of war...the horrors of humanity...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    endrit qarolli
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    To summarize this film in one sentence: The best film of all time.This movie does not get enough credit.It is original, dark, meaningful Cappolas best work. After watching this movie for the first time i thought it was bad but it got me wondering so i decided to give it another shot and i was amazed the two hours and a half passed like a second it was truly an experience worth remembering a movie worth watching.Every time the movie starts and Jim Morrison starts singing it gives me goosebumps it just drives me crazy.The speech of Marlon Brando is outstanding, and when Robert Duvall say "I love the smell of napalms in the morning it smells like victory" to me that smells like something wonderfully dark and amazing its about to happen, and this movie is that.A truly astonishing piece of art. The horror...The horror This is the end...
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Flawless Film With Great Buildup and Pacing
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    chrisborg1999
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    To say that Apocalypse Now is good is a major understatement. Even to say it is great is an understatement too. But, a milestone for film making and one of Ford Coppala's best (he has so many though) A very interesting fact is that over 200 hours of film were shot and it too 3 years to edit which you can see very clearly considering that the cinematography and transitions are perfect and nothing is out of place. The musical score fits the tone perfectly and the characters are very well developed I can't give anything away because I can't tell you for everyone interprets this movie differently. But please, I urge you to watch this masterpiece for you to experience how Vietnam War life was like
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    This Is The End...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    AaronCapenBanner
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Francis Ford Coppola directs this fascinating but very strange, unique film about Army Captain Willard(Martin Sheen, fine shell-shocked performance) who is sent "Up River" on a secret mission to assassinate renegade Col. Kurtz(Marlon Brando, bizarre but unforgettable performance) who has apparently gone insane, abandoned his command, and now rules over a primitive people in the remote jungles of Vietnam. Story is far more involved than that though, especially in the expanded directors cut that is much longer, but also fascinating. Willard encounters many strange sights and people(even among his own crew) as he tries to make sense out of the enveloping madness of this war, and his own inner demons. Film is a visual marvel, and holds your attention as it unfolds its increasingly philosophical, even existentialist narrative. May take multiple viewings to fully comprehend, but is worth it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Amazing and great!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bernard-layer
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Strange, fascinating, grandiose, paranoid, overwhelming, epic, disgusting, gigantic! These are the many adjectives that can be used to describe the monument of cinema. The Redux version extended by about 45 minutes, was fully supervised by Francis Coppola for the 20th anniversary of the film and to its operation on DVD. Sequences reintegrated not distort the original about the film. We have the right to more playmates, more madness and especially more Brando, for the benefit of the character Kurtz. Only the sequence of the French plantation (30 minutes alone) is questionable digression because it has the French so naive and causes a break from the narrative. The film, supported by a director prey to megalomania, was brought forth in pain. The sets were ravaged by a storm. Helicopters lent by the army of the country where the shooting took place, were requisitioned to fight against a coup when turning the aerial sequences. Lead actor Martin Sheen, drunk all day long, had a heart attack. The director gave her tray for a whole week for a romantic extramarital under the eyes of his wife incorporated the technical team. Time and on budget were so happily overwhelmed to the point that the production company of Coppola, Zoetrope, went bankrupt and the theatrical release was compromised until his selection at Cannes with a montage done in an emergency. This adventure film is told in the documentary Heart of Darkness dedicated to filming. Palme d'or at Cannes' festival in 1979, Oscar for best photography.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    more of an anti-war movie than a pro-war one
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    scottj471
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I can't argue with anyone who says this movie is good all around. The cast is great, the scenes change well from one to the next, the special effects are good for 1979, and the plot is solid. For some one looking for a movie that is more pro-war this isn't really your trade. With the exception of Robert Duvall's, one of the great cast members, Air Mobile unit and the scenes they performed so nicely. Other than that it's your, unfortunately, typical Vietnam war movie that presents our soldiers as rapists, murderers, drug addicts, and uncommitted freaks who can't be controlled or commanded. Once you get over all that BS you can enjoy this movie to the full. If not, check out We Were Soldiers with Mel Gibson for a realistic war movie.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    a tale of a world teetering on the edge of Darkness
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    silva-w-pius
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    In film it's a very rare occurrence  thus highly sort after, that a film can possess the holy trinity of a combination of a; great script, a legendary director and an almost god like actor. But such is the elusive nature of this endeavour, it never has quite has been attained in the history of film  well that's before a certain masterpiece going by the name of Apocalypse now graced our screens with this almost mythical alliance of this magnitude. The director: Francis Ford Coppola (Godfather trilogy). The story: a tale of a world teetering on the edge of Darkness almost ready to descent into primal madness, as Capt. Willard (Martin Sheen) has to navigate his way through hell on earth to find and kill AWOL Col. Kurtz (The actor:) Marlon Brando (On the Waterfront and Godfather 1) - whose very name is translated into greatness in almost every language known to man. The epic tale of this coming together will probably never happen again or would even have another three components assembled that will ever parallel it. So it something to be marvelled at, as you sits down in your comfortable chair to watch such a spectacle. It has been widely reported from a variety of different sources about the hardship endured by the production team. Such as shooting in a country notorious for typhoons, even at one time the place they were story the film burnt down, but luckily it remained safe, and the little fact that the main character Martin sheen was a supposed alcoholic, and would turn up on set with hangovers. All this helps to perpetuate the legend that is apocalypse now, and the irony that they were facing their own war, just at the same time they were filming it. But what I love most in film, is when bold story and director hold up a mirror to society, penetrating through the shards and illusions of morality and believing that we are able to distinguish between good vs. Evil as if it was between black and white, that we like to delude ourselves with every day, but then when we enter the battlefield it seems our civilised selves gets left behind as lines get blurred. And that is what Apocalypse now does best, it blurs the line. And with lines blurred it not a surprised that the main characters go insane, pretty much anyone would, in the face of a world that turns the world you lived and knew upside down. But my only criticism of film, is the focus of the film, I feel it waved far too much into the obsession of Martin Sheen's character as he tries to find Marlon Brando, when I feel that they could have taken time aside to explore the war from the perspective of the other men accompanying him on his journey, particularly Laurence Fishbuornes character who was just 17, so it would have been interesting to hear things from a black boy fighting in a white man's war. It obvious my stance on the film, that I believe is must see for all, but if the first paragraph wasn't enough to persuade you into watching Apocalypse now, here is another, I would go as far as to say that Vittorio Storaro cinematography was as if watching a walking and talking Picasso piece, such was the extent of the visual art mastery he conjured up in Apocalypse Now, as if he were the offspring of Gandalf and Dumbledore. The final few scenes with Marlon Brando were simply captivating, short but sweet. Vittorio Storaro's blending of darkness and shimmers of light streaking across Brando's face was simply breathtaking, giving Brando an almost god like aura. The scene itself probably belongs hanged up on a wall in the Tate Modern as much as it deserves to be on a film screen. The benchmark for all to follow.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Apocalypse Now - The Best War film ever made?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Daniel Metcalf
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    After I had watched "Psycho" I decided to watch "Apocalypse Now" for similar reasons. Both were two of the highest films on my watch list and recent posts by a member on here persuaded me not to delay my viewings and finally watch them. The work of Hitchcock made me want to see Psycho after immediately falling in love with some of his films, the same can be said of Coppola although I had only seen "The Godfather" it was a film that afterwards I knew I had just watched a masterpiece. "Apocalypse Now" is a film of three thirds (I decided to watch the Redux version, perhaps two halves is more applicable to the original) As the Americans lead by Kiglore approach a Vietnamese village we witness one of the great battle scenes in film history and it's no surprise that Quentin Tarantino rates this film as one of his favourites of all time with the first third something you'd expect to see from the director himself. In the first third, Coppola manages to create one of (if not) the greatest battle scenes in film history. We see the Americans lead by Capt. Kilgore destroy an entire Vietnamese village. Although some may see this seen as maleficent and uneasy due to the sheer amount of bloodshed, the superb performance of Kilgore turns it in to an extremely enjoyable, bizarre and fun scene. We see him turn on music and joking around before killing hundreds of people, then once the men land on ground we see him getting ready to search the waves amidst all the chaos as he produces one of the film's most memorable lines, "I love the spell of napalm in the morning". Robert Duvall creates one of the most memorable and fun characters in film history, someone who flourishes in the setting of war and someone whose insane behaviour will stay in our minds long after viewing. In the middle the film tends to drag more than the other thirds, some of the scenes are justified as we learn more about Captain Kurtz, an ex soldier who has gone insane and set himself up as a God among the local people. At first it seems that we can attempt to justify some of Kurtz actions and can understand why he may have gone crazy, it is not until the finally scenes that the full extent of his command is revealed. Martin Sheen portrays the film's main character, Captain Willard, the narrator of the story and the man sent on the mission to assassinate Kurtz. His morals and attitude towards the various situations are important to the film, at first he feels reluctant to murder a US soldier, where as in the final scenes we see a much more different side to his character upon finally meeting Kurtz. At first we begin to understand why the war would turn someone crazy, after all surely Kilgore himself could be classified as such? Watching the Redux version I can certainly understand the criticisms that people have for the film with two scenes, the second meeting with the playmates and the dinner conversation with the French family seeming odd and out of place as well as lengthening the film without little contribution however it certainly does not make the film worse in anyway and allows use to have a perhaps much needed retrieve from the action filled scenes that come both before and after it. Slight Spoilers in paragraph - I won't say much about the final third in case you have not seen the film (despite the spoiler warning), but once we finally get to the Kurtz compound the scenes that follow are brilliant and horrifying at the same time. Dead bodies dangling around everywhere and decapitated heads provide us with a horrifying setting and the scale of the size, the amount of men under Kurtz command is horrifying in itself. The final scene that involves the sacrifice of a buffalo (which was very much real, adding a shocking and brutal feel to amplify an already dark scene), the final scene in which we see Willard stand facing the entire tribe is brilliant and his pause for a split second is brilliantly captured as he reacts to the perhaps unexpected and once again sees the extent of command Kurtz has set up. The film's sound is also like no other for which it deservedly won an Oscar for, going back to the battle scene the music played helps great a grand joyous feel to the whole situation despite hundreds of deaths, the sound throughout is superb, from the opening sequences to the final scene. Marlon Brando, the film's main star has little time on screen and when he does we barely get to see his face, a deliberate and brave decision that helps build up the mystery and scary character that he is. "Apocalypse Now" is a war film like no other and immediately finds itself as one of my favourites of all time. You may have recently seen by thoughts on "Kramer vs. Kramer" a film produced in the same year and even though I enjoyed it I immediately thought to myself 'surely this wasn't a better film than Apocalypse Now?', like I expected it is in my opinion an injustice how such a film that although good could beat a masterpiece to win the Best Picture award for 1979.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Watched on release in Sheffield 1979
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    intrepid-s-t-88
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It was just an ordinary Saturday afternoon. 15 lads having a few beers and talking about the same stuff we talked about the year before. I suggested going to see this movie. I think most of us knew some of terrible stuff that went on over there. The thing I remember most, is the films ability to keep 15 likely lads quite for the duration, the subdued and thoughtful demeanor of the lads when we emerged from the last panoramic screen venue in Sheffield.The opening scene with the chopper to "The Doors" recombined with the slow-mo swoosh of the copter blades. Awesome....and a prelude to the madness that was Vietnam....and "The Horror....The Horror".I even, maybe,smelled the napalm next morning, and loved it!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One Of My Favorite Films
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Alex Krajci
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    1979's Apocalypse Now Is One Of My Favorite Films, I Like It Because Of Francis Ford Coppola's Direction, John Milius And Francis Ford Coppola's Screenplay, The Editing And Vittorio Storaro's Cinematography, This Movie Came Out From The Year Angela And Heath Ledger Were, The Wonder Woman TV Series With Lynda Carter Ended In 1979, 1963 Was 16 Years Old In 1979, This Movie Came Out 34 Years Ago Back In August Of 1979, My Favorite War Film Is 1998's Saving Private Ryan With Tom Hanks, 1972's The Godfather Is My Fourth Favorite Film Of All Time, This Movie Will Be 40 Years Old In 2019, This Movie Was 25 Years Old In 2004.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Fanastic movie, but enjoyment may require your undivided attention...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Kane Yoder (soggybreeches@gmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Let me start by saying I only made this account so I could write a review of Apocalypse Now. I'm out of college now, but I remember watching this movie when I was in high school and I remember boredom and confusion and, truthfully, a lack of interest. I didn't "get" the movie. It was too slow. What was the point? What was the mission? Why weren't they getting on with it at a breakneck speed like in Bond or Bourne or ... you know what I mean. Fast forward to college (I majored in English for the plentiful job prospects ha ha) and studied Heart of Darkness, completely forgetting about Apocalypse Now. Just as many people hate this movie or love it, many people hate the novel by Joseph Conrad or love it. It's slow going and easy to miss the point. I've learned that sometimes we just have to slow our thoughts down to match the pace of the storyteller, instead of trying to outdo him or her. If you enjoy Heart of Darkness then you will enjoy this movie. Even though the era and location is completely different, this movie is almost an expansion on Heart of Darkness. You get more juicy bits of dialogue, you get to fall a little bit deeper into the crevasses of Kurtz's cracked mind. And if you're any bit a sane human being, you'll find yourself strangely comfortable with the violence and cruelty and language of the movie. You don't get the feeling that the screen is hiding anything from you and at the same time there're no morals getting stuffed down your throat. The characters on screen deal with the gruesome details of war in their own ways. Pick whom you agree with. Some you will pity, some you will find hilarious. One question the movie begs: what, in war, is right? The music for this movie serves the setting excellently, at one point the bass thumping two beats like a heartbeat. Some rock and roll from the era prevails (like The Doors's "The End"). All of it to make Martin Sheen's journey utterly foreign, exotic, yet familiar. The visuals in this movie are fantastic. So vibrant and colorful, sometimes it's like a good acid trip. You don't see colors like these in movies nowadays. Watch it and you'll know what I mean. I don't want to say anything about the plot, but here... This movie, even though it is slow, wastes no time with dialogue. A lot of it is voice-over! If you don't pay attention, you'll miss a new development either on the mission, or on the character. (If you fail to understand the characters in this movie, then you will probably not like the movie.) Watch This Movie!! Slow your mind down, try to enjoy it. Give it your undivided attention. Amid all the carnage, callousness, and ruthlessness, you may find a story that is very human, and very close to your soul.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The horrors of war...the horrors of humanity...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    endrit qarolli
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    To summarize this film in one sentence: The best film of all time.This movie does not get enough credit.It is original, dark, meaningful Cappolas best work. After watching this movie for the first time i thought it was bad but it got me wondering so i decided to give it another shot and i was amazed the two hours and a half passed like a second it was truly an experience worth remembering a movie worth watching.Every time the movie starts and Jim Morrison starts singing it gives me goosebumps it just drives me crazy.The speech of Marlon Brando is outstanding, and when Robert Duvall say "I love the smell of napalms in the morning it smells like victory" to me that smells like something wonderfully dark and amazing its about to happen, and this movie is that.A truly astonishing piece of art. The horror...The horror This is the end...
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Flawless Film With Great Buildup and Pacing
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    chrisborg1999
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    To say that Apocalypse Now is good is a major understatement. Even to say it is great is an understatement too. But, a milestone for film making and one of Ford Coppala's best (he has so many though) A very interesting fact is that over 200 hours of film were shot and it too 3 years to edit which you can see very clearly considering that the cinematography and transitions are perfect and nothing is out of place. The musical score fits the tone perfectly and the characters are very well developed I can't give anything away because I can't tell you for everyone interprets this movie differently. But please, I urge you to watch this masterpiece for you to experience how Vietnam War life was like
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    This Is The End...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    AaronCapenBanner
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Francis Ford Coppola directs this fascinating but very strange, unique film about Army Captain Willard(Martin Sheen, fine shell-shocked performance) who is sent "Up River" on a secret mission to assassinate renegade Col. Kurtz(Marlon Brando, bizarre but unforgettable performance) who has apparently gone insane, abandoned his command, and now rules over a primitive people in the remote jungles of Vietnam. Story is far more involved than that though, especially in the expanded directors cut that is much longer, but also fascinating. Willard encounters many strange sights and people(even among his own crew) as he tries to make sense out of the enveloping madness of this war, and his own inner demons. Film is a visual marvel, and holds your attention as it unfolds its increasingly philosophical, even existentialist narrative. May take multiple viewings to fully comprehend, but is worth it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Amazing and great!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bernard-layer
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Strange, fascinating, grandiose, paranoid, overwhelming, epic, disgusting, gigantic! These are the many adjectives that can be used to describe the monument of cinema. The Redux version extended by about 45 minutes, was fully supervised by Francis Coppola for the 20th anniversary of the film and to its operation on DVD. Sequences reintegrated not distort the original about the film. We have the right to more playmates, more madness and especially more Brando, for the benefit of the character Kurtz. Only the sequence of the French plantation (30 minutes alone) is questionable digression because it has the French so naive and causes a break from the narrative. The film, supported by a director prey to megalomania, was brought forth in pain. The sets were ravaged by a storm. Helicopters lent by the army of the country where the shooting took place, were requisitioned to fight against a coup when turning the aerial sequences. Lead actor Martin Sheen, drunk all day long, had a heart attack. The director gave her tray for a whole week for a romantic extramarital under the eyes of his wife incorporated the technical team. Time and on budget were so happily overwhelmed to the point that the production company of Coppola, Zoetrope, went bankrupt and the theatrical release was compromised until his selection at Cannes with a montage done in an emergency. This adventure film is told in the documentary Heart of Darkness dedicated to filming. Palme d'or at Cannes' festival in 1979, Oscar for best photography.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    more of an anti-war movie than a pro-war one
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    scottj471
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I can't argue with anyone who says this movie is good all around. The cast is great, the scenes change well from one to the next, the special effects are good for 1979, and the plot is solid. For some one looking for a movie that is more pro-war this isn't really your trade. With the exception of Robert Duvall's, one of the great cast members, Air Mobile unit and the scenes they performed so nicely. Other than that it's your, unfortunately, typical Vietnam war movie that presents our soldiers as rapists, murderers, drug addicts, and uncommitted freaks who can't be controlled or commanded. Once you get over all that BS you can enjoy this movie to the full. If not, check out We Were Soldiers with Mel Gibson for a realistic war movie.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    a tale of a world teetering on the edge of Darkness
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    silva-w-pius
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    In film it's a very rare occurrence  thus highly sort after, that a film can possess the holy trinity of a combination of a; great script, a legendary director and an almost god like actor. But such is the elusive nature of this endeavour, it never has quite has been attained in the history of film  well that's before a certain masterpiece going by the name of Apocalypse now graced our screens with this almost mythical alliance of this magnitude. The director: Francis Ford Coppola (Godfather trilogy). The story: a tale of a world teetering on the edge of Darkness almost ready to descent into primal madness, as Capt. Willard (Martin Sheen) has to navigate his way through hell on earth to find and kill AWOL Col. Kurtz (The actor:) Marlon Brando (On the Waterfront and Godfather 1) - whose very name is translated into greatness in almost every language known to man. The epic tale of this coming together will probably never happen again or would even have another three components assembled that will ever parallel it. So it something to be marvelled at, as you sits down in your comfortable chair to watch such a spectacle. It has been widely reported from a variety of different sources about the hardship endured by the production team. Such as shooting in a country notorious for typhoons, even at one time the place they were story the film burnt down, but luckily it remained safe, and the little fact that the main character Martin sheen was a supposed alcoholic, and would turn up on set with hangovers. All this helps to perpetuate the legend that is apocalypse now, and the irony that they were facing their own war, just at the same time they were filming it. But what I love most in film, is when bold story and director hold up a mirror to society, penetrating through the shards and illusions of morality and believing that we are able to distinguish between good vs. Evil as if it was between black and white, that we like to delude ourselves with every day, but then when we enter the battlefield it seems our civilised selves gets left behind as lines get blurred. And that is what Apocalypse now does best, it blurs the line. And with lines blurred it not a surprised that the main characters go insane, pretty much anyone would, in the face of a world that turns the world you lived and knew upside down. But my only criticism of film, is the focus of the film, I feel it waved far too much into the obsession of Martin Sheen's character as he tries to find Marlon Brando, when I feel that they could have taken time aside to explore the war from the perspective of the other men accompanying him on his journey, particularly Laurence Fishbuornes character who was just 17, so it would have been interesting to hear things from a black boy fighting in a white man's war. It obvious my stance on the film, that I believe is must see for all, but if the first paragraph wasn't enough to persuade you into watching Apocalypse now, here is another, I would go as far as to say that Vittorio Storaro cinematography was as if watching a walking and talking Picasso piece, such was the extent of the visual art mastery he conjured up in Apocalypse Now, as if he were the offspring of Gandalf and Dumbledore. The final few scenes with Marlon Brando were simply captivating, short but sweet. Vittorio Storaro's blending of darkness and shimmers of light streaking across Brando's face was simply breathtaking, giving Brando an almost god like aura. The scene itself probably belongs hanged up on a wall in the Tate Modern as much as it deserves to be on a film screen. The benchmark for all to follow.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Apocalypse Now - The Best War film ever made?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Daniel Metcalf
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    After I had watched "Psycho" I decided to watch "Apocalypse Now" for similar reasons. Both were two of the highest films on my watch list and recent posts by a member on here persuaded me not to delay my viewings and finally watch them. The work of Hitchcock made me want to see Psycho after immediately falling in love with some of his films, the same can be said of Coppola although I had only seen "The Godfather" it was a film that afterwards I knew I had just watched a masterpiece. "Apocalypse Now" is a film of three thirds (I decided to watch the Redux version, perhaps two halves is more applicable to the original) As the Americans lead by Kiglore approach a Vietnamese village we witness one of the great battle scenes in film history and it's no surprise that Quentin Tarantino rates this film as one of his favourites of all time with the first third something you'd expect to see from the director himself. In the first third, Coppola manages to create one of (if not) the greatest battle scenes in film history. We see the Americans lead by Capt. Kilgore destroy an entire Vietnamese village. Although some may see this seen as maleficent and uneasy due to the sheer amount of bloodshed, the superb performance of Kilgore turns it in to an extremely enjoyable, bizarre and fun scene. We see him turn on music and joking around before killing hundreds of people, then once the men land on ground we see him getting ready to search the waves amidst all the chaos as he produces one of the film's most memorable lines, "I love the spell of napalm in the morning". Robert Duvall creates one of the most memorable and fun characters in film history, someone who flourishes in the setting of war and someone whose insane behaviour will stay in our minds long after viewing. In the middle the film tends to drag more than the other thirds, some of the scenes are justified as we learn more about Captain Kurtz, an ex soldier who has gone insane and set himself up as a God among the local people. At first it seems that we can attempt to justify some of Kurtz actions and can understand why he may have gone crazy, it is not until the finally scenes that the full extent of his command is revealed. Martin Sheen portrays the film's main character, Captain Willard, the narrator of the story and the man sent on the mission to assassinate Kurtz. His morals and attitude towards the various situations are important to the film, at first he feels reluctant to murder a US soldier, where as in the final scenes we see a much more different side to his character upon finally meeting Kurtz. At first we begin to understand why the war would turn someone crazy, after all surely Kilgore himself could be classified as such? Watching the Redux version I can certainly understand the criticisms that people have for the film with two scenes, the second meeting with the playmates and the dinner conversation with the French family seeming odd and out of place as well as lengthening the film without little contribution however it certainly does not make the film worse in anyway and allows use to have a perhaps much needed retrieve from the action filled scenes that come both before and after it. Slight Spoilers in paragraph - I won't say much about the final third in case you have not seen the film (despite the spoiler warning), but once we finally get to the Kurtz compound the scenes that follow are brilliant and horrifying at the same time. Dead bodies dangling around everywhere and decapitated heads provide us with a horrifying setting and the scale of the size, the amount of men under Kurtz command is horrifying in itself. The final scene that involves the sacrifice of a buffalo (which was very much real, adding a shocking and brutal feel to amplify an already dark scene), the final scene in which we see Willard stand facing the entire tribe is brilliant and his pause for a split second is brilliantly captured as he reacts to the perhaps unexpected and once again sees the extent of command Kurtz has set up. The film's sound is also like no other for which it deservedly won an Oscar for, going back to the battle scene the music played helps great a grand joyous feel to the whole situation despite hundreds of deaths, the sound throughout is superb, from the opening sequences to the final scene. Marlon Brando, the film's main star has little time on screen and when he does we barely get to see his face, a deliberate and brave decision that helps build up the mystery and scary character that he is. "Apocalypse Now" is a war film like no other and immediately finds itself as one of my favourites of all time. You may have recently seen by thoughts on "Kramer vs. Kramer" a film produced in the same year and even though I enjoyed it I immediately thought to myself 'surely this wasn't a better film than Apocalypse Now?', like I expected it is in my opinion an injustice how such a film that although good could beat a masterpiece to win the Best Picture award for 1979.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Watched on release in Sheffield 1979
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    intrepid-s-t-88
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It was just an ordinary Saturday afternoon. 15 lads having a few beers and talking about the same stuff we talked about the year before. I suggested going to see this movie. I think most of us knew some of terrible stuff that went on over there. The thing I remember most, is the films ability to keep 15 likely lads quite for the duration, the subdued and thoughtful demeanor of the lads when we emerged from the last panoramic screen venue in Sheffield.The opening scene with the chopper to "The Doors" recombined with the slow-mo swoosh of the copter blades. Awesome....and a prelude to the madness that was Vietnam....and "The Horror....The Horror".I even, maybe,smelled the napalm next morning, and loved it!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
 </reviews>
</filme>
