<filme>
 <id>
  186
 </id>
 <imdburl>
  http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0080455
 </imdburl>
 <ano>
  1980
 </ano>
 <titulo>
  Os Irm&atilde;os Cara de Pau
 </titulo>
 <rating>
  7.9
 </rating>
 <sinopse>
  Jake Blues, just out from prison, puts together his old band to save the Catholic home where he and brother Elwood were raised.
 </sinopse>
 <storyline>
  After the release of Jake Blues from prison, he and brother Elwood go to visit "The Penguin", the last of the nuns who raised them in a boarding school. They learn the Archdiocese will stop supporting the school and will sell the place to the Education Authority. The only way to keep the place open is if the $5000 tax on the property is paid within 11 days. The Blues Brothers want to help, and decide to put their blues band back together and raise the the money by staging a big gig. As they set off on their "mission from God" they seem to make more enemies along the way. Will they manage to come up with the money in time?
 </storyline>
 <generos>
  <genero>
   Action
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Comedy
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Crime
  </genero>
 </generos>
 <keywords>
  <keyword>
   band
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   money
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   prison
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   catholic
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   police
  </keyword>
 </keywords>
 <diretores>
  <diretor>
   John Landis
  </diretor>
 </diretores>
 <escritores>
  <escritor>
   Dan Aykroyd
  </escritor>
  <escritor>
   John Landis
  </escritor>
 </escritores>
 <atores>
  <ator>
   John Belushi
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Dan Aykroyd
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Cab Calloway
  </ator>
 </atores>
 <reviews>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Even the Vatican recommends it!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Suzanne Sellers
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Just saw this film again for the 20th or so time. Love every scene, but I think my favorite is where they go to visit "The Penguin" (nun) and they mange to offend her with their profanity. She tears them a new one as they fall down the stairs in their little kiddie desks. Its hilarious physical comedy. This film takes me back to a great time in my life which, by comparison, seems so much better entertainment-wise. Things were so much simpler then. As everyone has mentioned, the music is great. So many greats who have passed on now - the great blues and R&B groups, John Lee Hooker, James Brown, Ray Charles, Belushi, John Candy and so many others. Belushi and Akroyd are hilarious in different ways, but play off each other beautifully. I can't believe this movie isn't a 10/10. Its a cult film and will live forever.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Some Flaws but Overall Entertaining
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Michael_Elliott
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Blues Brothers (1980) *** (out of 4) Madhouse from John Landis has Jake and Elwood Blues (John Belushi, Dan Aykroyd) getting their band back together so that they can raise $5,000 to save their orphanage where they were raised. At first it seems like raising the cash will be easy but the brothers soon have Nazies, cops, angry cowboys and others chasing them through Chicago. THE BLUES BROTHERS is one of the most entertaining bad movies I've ever seen. There's so many great things in this movie but at the same time there are so many things that bothered me and kept me from enjoying the picture even more. We'll start with the bad and I'd say it's obvious that there's no story here. Instead of an actual story we just get non-stop music scenes as well as car crashes, two things that actually work in the movie but the extended running time is just way too long and I was constantly looking at the watch to see how much longer there was. The lack of any real story and the extended running time are certainly the two things that keep this from being better because outside of this there's quite a bit to enjoy here. The best thing is the fact that Landis pretty much throws everything out the window and right at the viewer. This includes some of the craziest, most over-the-top chase/wreck scenes that you're ever going to witness. There are many throughout the picture but for me the highlight would have to be the one inside the mall where everything in sight gets destroyed at least twice. Another good thing the film has going for it are some of the musical performances especially the ones dealing with Ray Charles, Cab Calloway, Aretha Franklin and John Lee Hooker. Then, of course, you've got Belushi and Aykroyd turning in great performances as the Blue Brothers. You can't help but feel like you're watching real brothers doing real blues. THE BLUES BROTHERS is far from perfect but there's still enough here that makes it worth viewing.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of the greatest comedy's
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Sean Rajnert (Newsgeek13@gmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Blues Brohers, what can i say... it's a comedy. an action movie maybe even a parody. The plot is (NO Spoilers) Jake Blues, a man released from a correctional center, meets up with his brother Elwood. The blues brothers are a band and they have to get the band back together to raise $5,000 for their catholic home. What makes this movie so great is the humor, there's things people do for no reason, their chased by everyone, and by the middle of the movie. You believe this is a normal day for the two. I only have one problem with the movie, it does tend to feel a little longer than it is, but the comedy and the music make up for it. I give this movie a 3 & 1/2 stars out of four. A great movie everybody should check out. (Well, at least wait for your kid to be 14 years of age)
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A great musical for people who don't like musicals!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Tweekums
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    As the film opens we see Jake Blues being released from prison and picked up by his brother Elwood; they head to the orphanage where they were raised and learn that the place will me closed down of somebody doesn't pay the $5000 tax demand in the next few days. Soon The Blues Brothers are on a mission from God to save the orphanage. To do this Jake wants to get their old band back together but it won't be easy as the members have all got on with their lives while he was in jail. Even once they have got the band back together it will be hard to earn that sort of money at short notice and that isn't mentioning the fact that they are wanted by the police, the local Nazis and a mysterious woman who is determined to kill Jake! It is safe to say that by the time they pay the $5000 considerably more damage will have been none! The opening scene might make one think this was going to be a fairly slow movie but once Jake is out of prison it isn't long before the laughter and mayhem begin and there is a lot of both. The action is over the top and utterly hilarious with countless cop cars, shop windows and even entire buildings being destroyed. This mayhem is regularly interrupted by musical interludes by the likes of James Brown, Aretha Franklin, Ray Charles and Cab Callaway. These songs are frequently accompanied by entertaining dance routines. As well as lots of well known singers there are also quite a few other well known people in cameo roles; the best being Carrie Fisher who plays the woman trying to kill Jake; I loved how it isn't explained why she is doing it till nearly the end. John Belushi and Dan Aykroyd are great as Jake and Elwood; two characters who almost never remove their sunglasses; even at night. I'd heartily recommend this to anybody wanting a good laugh; don't worry if you don't usually like musicals; this one is great!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Over Produced and Overrated
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    leonlouisricci
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Way over produced and exaggerated, this overrated Movie has a number or funny bits and some bouncy Music, some of it by real Soul and R&B greats, but it is also filled with so many car crashes that it wrecks the momentum. There could easily be 45 minutes cut in the form of unnecessary big budget, obligatory scenes and this would be a more enjoyable Musical/Comedy. As it is, there is so much that is disjointed and destructive that it literally collapses onto itself with over indulgence and unrestrained tomfoolery. Worth a view for the better parts, but be prepared to endure endless repetition, mostly of the vehicular nature. Aykroyd and Belushi were naturals on SNL and other projects, but this big production didn't do them any favors in the creative department because they were buried in so much rubble.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Overblown
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bigverybadtom
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie is a landmark-it was responsible for Chicago becoming the setting for a number of future movies. On its own, it is based on a Saturday Night Live sketch about two white characters with pretensions of being blues musicians. Add a number of major real-life blues musicians and an even larger number of car crashes, and that's the recipe for the movie. The premise is about two brothers, one just out of Joliet prison, who try to raise money to save an orphanage from closing down, and to do so, bring together the members of their old band. Of course, their efforts to do so end up causing trouble with the law, as well as other people (such as a country and western-themed bar and the band that was supposed to play there). In the end, dozens of police cars chase after them, and even the National Guard, before they fulfill their quest. There are some genuinely funny parts, but overall the whole movie depends on exaggeration-twenty police cars crashing into twenty police cars, as critic Roger Ebert had put it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Hilarious Musical Comedy! Belushi And Aykroyd Are Great!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Humphrey Fish
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Jake Blues, just out from prison, puts together his old band to save the Catholic home where he and brother Elwood were raised. The Blues Brothers is arguably the funniest movie of 1980, it is a comedy masterpiece, it's a hilarious musical comedy film! This movie provides a ton of things that help make it great, for one thing, it gives the viewers a lot of hilarious performances from the cast, it gives the viewers a lot of very hysterical scenes and gags, and lastly, it gives the viewers a lot of enjoyment with a lot of very great music! I saw this movie, and I certainly had a great time watching it, it is like an amusement park there are a lot of huge laughs everywhere, such as the car chase through the mall, and the scene where The Blues Brothers are getting hit by the nun repeatedly with a yardstick, not to mention the part where they pose as the Good Ol' Boys. The movie has a lot more hysterical scenes, but I won't name them, as it would most likely spoil the movie, and I don't want to do that. But anyway, as far as comedy movies go, The Blues Brothers is a movie that's as hysterical as they come! Dan Aykroyd and John Belushi are great together, they were perfect for the roles of Elwood And Jake Blues respectively. While Aykroyd would later go on to achieve further greatness, Belushi's career was cut short, as he died from an accidental drug overdose at the young age of 33, sad. If Belushi and Aykroyd don't do the trick, then perhaps the supporting cast will. We've got a lot of real life blues musicians in this movie, such as Cab Calloway, Aretha Franklin, Ray Charles, and James Brown, and what a great lineup that is! The movie has tons to recommend, for one thing, the fact that it's a hilarious movie, another thing is the acting in the movie, as well as the all-star cast of actors. But the two best people in this movie are (and you might have guessed it) Dan Aykroyd and John Belushi, they were outstanding together, not only where they great with their acting, but they were also superb at singing and dancing! The Blues Brothers is a comedy movie that will last, it's will forever remain one of the funniest movies ever made for years and years to come. Here is something that I have to tell you, you're on a mission from God, and that mission is to watch this movie. Really, you've got to watch it, you won't regret it, it really is as hysterical as everyone says it is, and when you watch it, you will perfectly see what I mean. Before I continue, let me say this. I know that I may sound like I'm repeating myself, but sorry if I am, because what I am saying is true, this movie is a comic gem! So if you want to see a great movie with a lot of great acting, music, excitement, and dancing, then don't worry about that, because The Blues Brothers is a movie that contains all of these things! So step into the Bluesmobile with Jake and Elwood Blues and get ready for an awesome musical comedy adventure that you will absolutely love, that's the 1980 masterpiece, The Blues Brothers! 10/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    R.I.P John Belushi
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    omar wasief
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/9/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Blues Brothers' is a bit of both, lending exposure to rhythm and blues legends who might otherwise have faded into silence while at the same time treating black culture as a colorful pantomime backdrop for the antics of two white comedians. That Dan Aykroyd and John Belushi adore this music is not in question  it's lovingly chosen and brilliantly performed  but the film sometimes feels like a work of cultural tourism, particularly in scenes set in a gospel church and a Chicago street market. These lively musical sequences also sit awkwardly with director John Landis's bizarre predilection for wholesale destruction: sure, smashing up cop cars can be fun, but Landis takes things to a tiresome extreme. Still, the film retains a huge nostalgic kick, thanks in large part to Aykroyd and Belushi's easy rapport, a smattering of daft, shaggy humor and some truly iconic musical sequences.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Film That Gets Better And Better, The More You Watch It!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    SebMModernsII
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    What more can I say about a movie that has outstanding car chases and jazzy blues music being fantastic?! It is! Some strong language is present, don't show it to your children (Even if they can't help but love it!) Two brothers (Played By John Belushi And Dan Aykroyd) are reunited after one brother "Jake Blues" is released from prison. They are on the run from The Police! (There are a lot of police in this film!) and on the way, they try to make money with their music to help keep The Church open. There is a lot of great music in this film, there is even a singing of Robert Johnson's "Sweet Home Chicago!" The film ends with The Blues Brothers entertaining the prisoners with their hit Rock'N Roll dance song "Let's Rock!" and The End Credits involves a reprise of their best songs! A must see, if you haven't yet watched it! Overall Rating: 10/10!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Pretty damn funny
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Terrell Howell (KnightsofNi11)
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Back in the 70's John Belushi and Dan Akroyd introduced the characters of Jake and Elwood Blues on the ever popular Saturday Night Live. In 1980 legendary director John Landis gave the characters their own feature length film. The Blues Brothers stars Belushi and Akroyd as Jake and Elwood, respectively, and it follows them as they attempt to put their old band back together in order to raise money to save the Catholic orphanage home where they were raised. Dubbing this quest a mission from God the two set out on a wacky and action packed adventure full of screwball situations and nut job characters. What ensues is a lot of fun. The Blues Brothers is one of those essential 80's comedies. It's worked its way to earning the status of a classic and so these days, no matter how you feel about comedies, it's just one of those that you have to see. It's also one of the very few successful films to be made out of SNL characters, and that's always a treat to watch, especially if you know the characters from the TV show. Seeing them come to life in a whole new way through the big screen is something really exciting to witness. And with characters as classic as Jake and Elwood Blues, played by their original actors, the ingenious Dan Akroyd and John Belushi, it had to have been a nostalgic experience for 1980 audiences. I didn't get as much of this, however. I know the characters for how iconic they are today and I've seen some of the Blues Brothers SNL skits, but I can't say this movie had the same effect for me as it would have had for audiences back in the day excited to see their favorite SNL characters put on the big screen. As far as this just being a good movie, it's funny and that's about it. I definitely enjoyed watching this flick, but it's not much more than just a silly over-the-top comedy. The only thing that makes it better than a lot of the other screwball comedies like it would be it's great actors and the legendary status behind the characters. All in all, The Blues Brothers is just a lot of hilarious wackiness with some crazy song and dance numbers thrown in throughout. It's a lot of fun in a weird, explosive, irreverent way.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Even the Vatican recommends it!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Suzanne Sellers
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Just saw this film again for the 20th or so time. Love every scene, but I think my favorite is where they go to visit "The Penguin" (nun) and they mange to offend her with their profanity. She tears them a new one as they fall down the stairs in their little kiddie desks. Its hilarious physical comedy. This film takes me back to a great time in my life which, by comparison, seems so much better entertainment-wise. Things were so much simpler then. As everyone has mentioned, the music is great. So many greats who have passed on now - the great blues and R&B groups, John Lee Hooker, James Brown, Ray Charles, Belushi, John Candy and so many others. Belushi and Akroyd are hilarious in different ways, but play off each other beautifully. I can't believe this movie isn't a 10/10. Its a cult film and will live forever.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Some Flaws but Overall Entertaining
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Michael_Elliott
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Blues Brothers (1980) *** (out of 4) Madhouse from John Landis has Jake and Elwood Blues (John Belushi, Dan Aykroyd) getting their band back together so that they can raise $5,000 to save their orphanage where they were raised. At first it seems like raising the cash will be easy but the brothers soon have Nazies, cops, angry cowboys and others chasing them through Chicago. THE BLUES BROTHERS is one of the most entertaining bad movies I've ever seen. There's so many great things in this movie but at the same time there are so many things that bothered me and kept me from enjoying the picture even more. We'll start with the bad and I'd say it's obvious that there's no story here. Instead of an actual story we just get non-stop music scenes as well as car crashes, two things that actually work in the movie but the extended running time is just way too long and I was constantly looking at the watch to see how much longer there was. The lack of any real story and the extended running time are certainly the two things that keep this from being better because outside of this there's quite a bit to enjoy here. The best thing is the fact that Landis pretty much throws everything out the window and right at the viewer. This includes some of the craziest, most over-the-top chase/wreck scenes that you're ever going to witness. There are many throughout the picture but for me the highlight would have to be the one inside the mall where everything in sight gets destroyed at least twice. Another good thing the film has going for it are some of the musical performances especially the ones dealing with Ray Charles, Cab Calloway, Aretha Franklin and John Lee Hooker. Then, of course, you've got Belushi and Aykroyd turning in great performances as the Blue Brothers. You can't help but feel like you're watching real brothers doing real blues. THE BLUES BROTHERS is far from perfect but there's still enough here that makes it worth viewing.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of the greatest comedy's
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Sean Rajnert (Newsgeek13@gmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Blues Brohers, what can i say... it's a comedy. an action movie maybe even a parody. The plot is (NO Spoilers) Jake Blues, a man released from a correctional center, meets up with his brother Elwood. The blues brothers are a band and they have to get the band back together to raise $5,000 for their catholic home. What makes this movie so great is the humor, there's things people do for no reason, their chased by everyone, and by the middle of the movie. You believe this is a normal day for the two. I only have one problem with the movie, it does tend to feel a little longer than it is, but the comedy and the music make up for it. I give this movie a 3 & 1/2 stars out of four. A great movie everybody should check out. (Well, at least wait for your kid to be 14 years of age)
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A great musical for people who don't like musicals!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Tweekums
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    As the film opens we see Jake Blues being released from prison and picked up by his brother Elwood; they head to the orphanage where they were raised and learn that the place will me closed down of somebody doesn't pay the $5000 tax demand in the next few days. Soon The Blues Brothers are on a mission from God to save the orphanage. To do this Jake wants to get their old band back together but it won't be easy as the members have all got on with their lives while he was in jail. Even once they have got the band back together it will be hard to earn that sort of money at short notice and that isn't mentioning the fact that they are wanted by the police, the local Nazis and a mysterious woman who is determined to kill Jake! It is safe to say that by the time they pay the $5000 considerably more damage will have been none! The opening scene might make one think this was going to be a fairly slow movie but once Jake is out of prison it isn't long before the laughter and mayhem begin and there is a lot of both. The action is over the top and utterly hilarious with countless cop cars, shop windows and even entire buildings being destroyed. This mayhem is regularly interrupted by musical interludes by the likes of James Brown, Aretha Franklin, Ray Charles and Cab Callaway. These songs are frequently accompanied by entertaining dance routines. As well as lots of well known singers there are also quite a few other well known people in cameo roles; the best being Carrie Fisher who plays the woman trying to kill Jake; I loved how it isn't explained why she is doing it till nearly the end. John Belushi and Dan Aykroyd are great as Jake and Elwood; two characters who almost never remove their sunglasses; even at night. I'd heartily recommend this to anybody wanting a good laugh; don't worry if you don't usually like musicals; this one is great!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Over Produced and Overrated
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    leonlouisricci
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Way over produced and exaggerated, this overrated Movie has a number or funny bits and some bouncy Music, some of it by real Soul and R&B greats, but it is also filled with so many car crashes that it wrecks the momentum. There could easily be 45 minutes cut in the form of unnecessary big budget, obligatory scenes and this would be a more enjoyable Musical/Comedy. As it is, there is so much that is disjointed and destructive that it literally collapses onto itself with over indulgence and unrestrained tomfoolery. Worth a view for the better parts, but be prepared to endure endless repetition, mostly of the vehicular nature. Aykroyd and Belushi were naturals on SNL and other projects, but this big production didn't do them any favors in the creative department because they were buried in so much rubble.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Overblown
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bigverybadtom
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie is a landmark-it was responsible for Chicago becoming the setting for a number of future movies. On its own, it is based on a Saturday Night Live sketch about two white characters with pretensions of being blues musicians. Add a number of major real-life blues musicians and an even larger number of car crashes, and that's the recipe for the movie. The premise is about two brothers, one just out of Joliet prison, who try to raise money to save an orphanage from closing down, and to do so, bring together the members of their old band. Of course, their efforts to do so end up causing trouble with the law, as well as other people (such as a country and western-themed bar and the band that was supposed to play there). In the end, dozens of police cars chase after them, and even the National Guard, before they fulfill their quest. There are some genuinely funny parts, but overall the whole movie depends on exaggeration-twenty police cars crashing into twenty police cars, as critic Roger Ebert had put it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Hilarious Musical Comedy! Belushi And Aykroyd Are Great!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Humphrey Fish
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Jake Blues, just out from prison, puts together his old band to save the Catholic home where he and brother Elwood were raised. The Blues Brothers is arguably the funniest movie of 1980, it is a comedy masterpiece, it's a hilarious musical comedy film! This movie provides a ton of things that help make it great, for one thing, it gives the viewers a lot of hilarious performances from the cast, it gives the viewers a lot of very hysterical scenes and gags, and lastly, it gives the viewers a lot of enjoyment with a lot of very great music! I saw this movie, and I certainly had a great time watching it, it is like an amusement park there are a lot of huge laughs everywhere, such as the car chase through the mall, and the scene where The Blues Brothers are getting hit by the nun repeatedly with a yardstick, not to mention the part where they pose as the Good Ol' Boys. The movie has a lot more hysterical scenes, but I won't name them, as it would most likely spoil the movie, and I don't want to do that. But anyway, as far as comedy movies go, The Blues Brothers is a movie that's as hysterical as they come! Dan Aykroyd and John Belushi are great together, they were perfect for the roles of Elwood And Jake Blues respectively. While Aykroyd would later go on to achieve further greatness, Belushi's career was cut short, as he died from an accidental drug overdose at the young age of 33, sad. If Belushi and Aykroyd don't do the trick, then perhaps the supporting cast will. We've got a lot of real life blues musicians in this movie, such as Cab Calloway, Aretha Franklin, Ray Charles, and James Brown, and what a great lineup that is! The movie has tons to recommend, for one thing, the fact that it's a hilarious movie, another thing is the acting in the movie, as well as the all-star cast of actors. But the two best people in this movie are (and you might have guessed it) Dan Aykroyd and John Belushi, they were outstanding together, not only where they great with their acting, but they were also superb at singing and dancing! The Blues Brothers is a comedy movie that will last, it's will forever remain one of the funniest movies ever made for years and years to come. Here is something that I have to tell you, you're on a mission from God, and that mission is to watch this movie. Really, you've got to watch it, you won't regret it, it really is as hysterical as everyone says it is, and when you watch it, you will perfectly see what I mean. Before I continue, let me say this. I know that I may sound like I'm repeating myself, but sorry if I am, because what I am saying is true, this movie is a comic gem! So if you want to see a great movie with a lot of great acting, music, excitement, and dancing, then don't worry about that, because The Blues Brothers is a movie that contains all of these things! So step into the Bluesmobile with Jake and Elwood Blues and get ready for an awesome musical comedy adventure that you will absolutely love, that's the 1980 masterpiece, The Blues Brothers! 10/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    R.I.P John Belushi
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    omar wasief
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/9/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Blues Brothers' is a bit of both, lending exposure to rhythm and blues legends who might otherwise have faded into silence while at the same time treating black culture as a colorful pantomime backdrop for the antics of two white comedians. That Dan Aykroyd and John Belushi adore this music is not in question  it's lovingly chosen and brilliantly performed  but the film sometimes feels like a work of cultural tourism, particularly in scenes set in a gospel church and a Chicago street market. These lively musical sequences also sit awkwardly with director John Landis's bizarre predilection for wholesale destruction: sure, smashing up cop cars can be fun, but Landis takes things to a tiresome extreme. Still, the film retains a huge nostalgic kick, thanks in large part to Aykroyd and Belushi's easy rapport, a smattering of daft, shaggy humor and some truly iconic musical sequences.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Film That Gets Better And Better, The More You Watch It!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    SebMModernsII
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    What more can I say about a movie that has outstanding car chases and jazzy blues music being fantastic?! It is! Some strong language is present, don't show it to your children (Even if they can't help but love it!) Two brothers (Played By John Belushi And Dan Aykroyd) are reunited after one brother "Jake Blues" is released from prison. They are on the run from The Police! (There are a lot of police in this film!) and on the way, they try to make money with their music to help keep The Church open. There is a lot of great music in this film, there is even a singing of Robert Johnson's "Sweet Home Chicago!" The film ends with The Blues Brothers entertaining the prisoners with their hit Rock'N Roll dance song "Let's Rock!" and The End Credits involves a reprise of their best songs! A must see, if you haven't yet watched it! Overall Rating: 10/10!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Pretty damn funny
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Terrell Howell (KnightsofNi11)
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Back in the 70's John Belushi and Dan Akroyd introduced the characters of Jake and Elwood Blues on the ever popular Saturday Night Live. In 1980 legendary director John Landis gave the characters their own feature length film. The Blues Brothers stars Belushi and Akroyd as Jake and Elwood, respectively, and it follows them as they attempt to put their old band back together in order to raise money to save the Catholic orphanage home where they were raised. Dubbing this quest a mission from God the two set out on a wacky and action packed adventure full of screwball situations and nut job characters. What ensues is a lot of fun. The Blues Brothers is one of those essential 80's comedies. It's worked its way to earning the status of a classic and so these days, no matter how you feel about comedies, it's just one of those that you have to see. It's also one of the very few successful films to be made out of SNL characters, and that's always a treat to watch, especially if you know the characters from the TV show. Seeing them come to life in a whole new way through the big screen is something really exciting to witness. And with characters as classic as Jake and Elwood Blues, played by their original actors, the ingenious Dan Akroyd and John Belushi, it had to have been a nostalgic experience for 1980 audiences. I didn't get as much of this, however. I know the characters for how iconic they are today and I've seen some of the Blues Brothers SNL skits, but I can't say this movie had the same effect for me as it would have had for audiences back in the day excited to see their favorite SNL characters put on the big screen. As far as this just being a good movie, it's funny and that's about it. I definitely enjoyed watching this flick, but it's not much more than just a silly over-the-top comedy. The only thing that makes it better than a lot of the other screwball comedies like it would be it's great actors and the legendary status behind the characters. All in all, The Blues Brothers is just a lot of hilarious wackiness with some crazy song and dance numbers thrown in throughout. It's a lot of fun in a weird, explosive, irreverent way.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Even the Vatican recommends it!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Suzanne Sellers
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Just saw this film again for the 20th or so time. Love every scene, but I think my favorite is where they go to visit "The Penguin" (nun) and they mange to offend her with their profanity. She tears them a new one as they fall down the stairs in their little kiddie desks. Its hilarious physical comedy. This film takes me back to a great time in my life which, by comparison, seems so much better entertainment-wise. Things were so much simpler then. As everyone has mentioned, the music is great. So many greats who have passed on now - the great blues and R&B groups, John Lee Hooker, James Brown, Ray Charles, Belushi, John Candy and so many others. Belushi and Akroyd are hilarious in different ways, but play off each other beautifully. I can't believe this movie isn't a 10/10. Its a cult film and will live forever.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Some Flaws but Overall Entertaining
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Michael_Elliott
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Blues Brothers (1980) *** (out of 4) Madhouse from John Landis has Jake and Elwood Blues (John Belushi, Dan Aykroyd) getting their band back together so that they can raise $5,000 to save their orphanage where they were raised. At first it seems like raising the cash will be easy but the brothers soon have Nazies, cops, angry cowboys and others chasing them through Chicago. THE BLUES BROTHERS is one of the most entertaining bad movies I've ever seen. There's so many great things in this movie but at the same time there are so many things that bothered me and kept me from enjoying the picture even more. We'll start with the bad and I'd say it's obvious that there's no story here. Instead of an actual story we just get non-stop music scenes as well as car crashes, two things that actually work in the movie but the extended running time is just way too long and I was constantly looking at the watch to see how much longer there was. The lack of any real story and the extended running time are certainly the two things that keep this from being better because outside of this there's quite a bit to enjoy here. The best thing is the fact that Landis pretty much throws everything out the window and right at the viewer. This includes some of the craziest, most over-the-top chase/wreck scenes that you're ever going to witness. There are many throughout the picture but for me the highlight would have to be the one inside the mall where everything in sight gets destroyed at least twice. Another good thing the film has going for it are some of the musical performances especially the ones dealing with Ray Charles, Cab Calloway, Aretha Franklin and John Lee Hooker. Then, of course, you've got Belushi and Aykroyd turning in great performances as the Blue Brothers. You can't help but feel like you're watching real brothers doing real blues. THE BLUES BROTHERS is far from perfect but there's still enough here that makes it worth viewing.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of the greatest comedy's
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Sean Rajnert (Newsgeek13@gmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Blues Brohers, what can i say... it's a comedy. an action movie maybe even a parody. The plot is (NO Spoilers) Jake Blues, a man released from a correctional center, meets up with his brother Elwood. The blues brothers are a band and they have to get the band back together to raise $5,000 for their catholic home. What makes this movie so great is the humor, there's things people do for no reason, their chased by everyone, and by the middle of the movie. You believe this is a normal day for the two. I only have one problem with the movie, it does tend to feel a little longer than it is, but the comedy and the music make up for it. I give this movie a 3 & 1/2 stars out of four. A great movie everybody should check out. (Well, at least wait for your kid to be 14 years of age)
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A great musical for people who don't like musicals!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Tweekums
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    As the film opens we see Jake Blues being released from prison and picked up by his brother Elwood; they head to the orphanage where they were raised and learn that the place will me closed down of somebody doesn't pay the $5000 tax demand in the next few days. Soon The Blues Brothers are on a mission from God to save the orphanage. To do this Jake wants to get their old band back together but it won't be easy as the members have all got on with their lives while he was in jail. Even once they have got the band back together it will be hard to earn that sort of money at short notice and that isn't mentioning the fact that they are wanted by the police, the local Nazis and a mysterious woman who is determined to kill Jake! It is safe to say that by the time they pay the $5000 considerably more damage will have been none! The opening scene might make one think this was going to be a fairly slow movie but once Jake is out of prison it isn't long before the laughter and mayhem begin and there is a lot of both. The action is over the top and utterly hilarious with countless cop cars, shop windows and even entire buildings being destroyed. This mayhem is regularly interrupted by musical interludes by the likes of James Brown, Aretha Franklin, Ray Charles and Cab Callaway. These songs are frequently accompanied by entertaining dance routines. As well as lots of well known singers there are also quite a few other well known people in cameo roles; the best being Carrie Fisher who plays the woman trying to kill Jake; I loved how it isn't explained why she is doing it till nearly the end. John Belushi and Dan Aykroyd are great as Jake and Elwood; two characters who almost never remove their sunglasses; even at night. I'd heartily recommend this to anybody wanting a good laugh; don't worry if you don't usually like musicals; this one is great!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Over Produced and Overrated
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    leonlouisricci
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Way over produced and exaggerated, this overrated Movie has a number or funny bits and some bouncy Music, some of it by real Soul and R&B greats, but it is also filled with so many car crashes that it wrecks the momentum. There could easily be 45 minutes cut in the form of unnecessary big budget, obligatory scenes and this would be a more enjoyable Musical/Comedy. As it is, there is so much that is disjointed and destructive that it literally collapses onto itself with over indulgence and unrestrained tomfoolery. Worth a view for the better parts, but be prepared to endure endless repetition, mostly of the vehicular nature. Aykroyd and Belushi were naturals on SNL and other projects, but this big production didn't do them any favors in the creative department because they were buried in so much rubble.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Overblown
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bigverybadtom
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie is a landmark-it was responsible for Chicago becoming the setting for a number of future movies. On its own, it is based on a Saturday Night Live sketch about two white characters with pretensions of being blues musicians. Add a number of major real-life blues musicians and an even larger number of car crashes, and that's the recipe for the movie. The premise is about two brothers, one just out of Joliet prison, who try to raise money to save an orphanage from closing down, and to do so, bring together the members of their old band. Of course, their efforts to do so end up causing trouble with the law, as well as other people (such as a country and western-themed bar and the band that was supposed to play there). In the end, dozens of police cars chase after them, and even the National Guard, before they fulfill their quest. There are some genuinely funny parts, but overall the whole movie depends on exaggeration-twenty police cars crashing into twenty police cars, as critic Roger Ebert had put it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Hilarious Musical Comedy! Belushi And Aykroyd Are Great!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Humphrey Fish
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Jake Blues, just out from prison, puts together his old band to save the Catholic home where he and brother Elwood were raised. The Blues Brothers is arguably the funniest movie of 1980, it is a comedy masterpiece, it's a hilarious musical comedy film! This movie provides a ton of things that help make it great, for one thing, it gives the viewers a lot of hilarious performances from the cast, it gives the viewers a lot of very hysterical scenes and gags, and lastly, it gives the viewers a lot of enjoyment with a lot of very great music! I saw this movie, and I certainly had a great time watching it, it is like an amusement park there are a lot of huge laughs everywhere, such as the car chase through the mall, and the scene where The Blues Brothers are getting hit by the nun repeatedly with a yardstick, not to mention the part where they pose as the Good Ol' Boys. The movie has a lot more hysterical scenes, but I won't name them, as it would most likely spoil the movie, and I don't want to do that. But anyway, as far as comedy movies go, The Blues Brothers is a movie that's as hysterical as they come! Dan Aykroyd and John Belushi are great together, they were perfect for the roles of Elwood And Jake Blues respectively. While Aykroyd would later go on to achieve further greatness, Belushi's career was cut short, as he died from an accidental drug overdose at the young age of 33, sad. If Belushi and Aykroyd don't do the trick, then perhaps the supporting cast will. We've got a lot of real life blues musicians in this movie, such as Cab Calloway, Aretha Franklin, Ray Charles, and James Brown, and what a great lineup that is! The movie has tons to recommend, for one thing, the fact that it's a hilarious movie, another thing is the acting in the movie, as well as the all-star cast of actors. But the two best people in this movie are (and you might have guessed it) Dan Aykroyd and John Belushi, they were outstanding together, not only where they great with their acting, but they were also superb at singing and dancing! The Blues Brothers is a comedy movie that will last, it's will forever remain one of the funniest movies ever made for years and years to come. Here is something that I have to tell you, you're on a mission from God, and that mission is to watch this movie. Really, you've got to watch it, you won't regret it, it really is as hysterical as everyone says it is, and when you watch it, you will perfectly see what I mean. Before I continue, let me say this. I know that I may sound like I'm repeating myself, but sorry if I am, because what I am saying is true, this movie is a comic gem! So if you want to see a great movie with a lot of great acting, music, excitement, and dancing, then don't worry about that, because The Blues Brothers is a movie that contains all of these things! So step into the Bluesmobile with Jake and Elwood Blues and get ready for an awesome musical comedy adventure that you will absolutely love, that's the 1980 masterpiece, The Blues Brothers! 10/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    R.I.P John Belushi
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    omar wasief
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/9/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Blues Brothers' is a bit of both, lending exposure to rhythm and blues legends who might otherwise have faded into silence while at the same time treating black culture as a colorful pantomime backdrop for the antics of two white comedians. That Dan Aykroyd and John Belushi adore this music is not in question  it's lovingly chosen and brilliantly performed  but the film sometimes feels like a work of cultural tourism, particularly in scenes set in a gospel church and a Chicago street market. These lively musical sequences also sit awkwardly with director John Landis's bizarre predilection for wholesale destruction: sure, smashing up cop cars can be fun, but Landis takes things to a tiresome extreme. Still, the film retains a huge nostalgic kick, thanks in large part to Aykroyd and Belushi's easy rapport, a smattering of daft, shaggy humor and some truly iconic musical sequences.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Film That Gets Better And Better, The More You Watch It!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    SebMModernsII
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    What more can I say about a movie that has outstanding car chases and jazzy blues music being fantastic?! It is! Some strong language is present, don't show it to your children (Even if they can't help but love it!) Two brothers (Played By John Belushi And Dan Aykroyd) are reunited after one brother "Jake Blues" is released from prison. They are on the run from The Police! (There are a lot of police in this film!) and on the way, they try to make money with their music to help keep The Church open. There is a lot of great music in this film, there is even a singing of Robert Johnson's "Sweet Home Chicago!" The film ends with The Blues Brothers entertaining the prisoners with their hit Rock'N Roll dance song "Let's Rock!" and The End Credits involves a reprise of their best songs! A must see, if you haven't yet watched it! Overall Rating: 10/10!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Pretty damn funny
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Terrell Howell (KnightsofNi11)
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Back in the 70's John Belushi and Dan Akroyd introduced the characters of Jake and Elwood Blues on the ever popular Saturday Night Live. In 1980 legendary director John Landis gave the characters their own feature length film. The Blues Brothers stars Belushi and Akroyd as Jake and Elwood, respectively, and it follows them as they attempt to put their old band back together in order to raise money to save the Catholic orphanage home where they were raised. Dubbing this quest a mission from God the two set out on a wacky and action packed adventure full of screwball situations and nut job characters. What ensues is a lot of fun. The Blues Brothers is one of those essential 80's comedies. It's worked its way to earning the status of a classic and so these days, no matter how you feel about comedies, it's just one of those that you have to see. It's also one of the very few successful films to be made out of SNL characters, and that's always a treat to watch, especially if you know the characters from the TV show. Seeing them come to life in a whole new way through the big screen is something really exciting to witness. And with characters as classic as Jake and Elwood Blues, played by their original actors, the ingenious Dan Akroyd and John Belushi, it had to have been a nostalgic experience for 1980 audiences. I didn't get as much of this, however. I know the characters for how iconic they are today and I've seen some of the Blues Brothers SNL skits, but I can't say this movie had the same effect for me as it would have had for audiences back in the day excited to see their favorite SNL characters put on the big screen. As far as this just being a good movie, it's funny and that's about it. I definitely enjoyed watching this flick, but it's not much more than just a silly over-the-top comedy. The only thing that makes it better than a lot of the other screwball comedies like it would be it's great actors and the legendary status behind the characters. All in all, The Blues Brothers is just a lot of hilarious wackiness with some crazy song and dance numbers thrown in throughout. It's a lot of fun in a weird, explosive, irreverent way.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Even the Vatican recommends it!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Suzanne Sellers
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Just saw this film again for the 20th or so time. Love every scene, but I think my favorite is where they go to visit "The Penguin" (nun) and they mange to offend her with their profanity. She tears them a new one as they fall down the stairs in their little kiddie desks. Its hilarious physical comedy. This film takes me back to a great time in my life which, by comparison, seems so much better entertainment-wise. Things were so much simpler then. As everyone has mentioned, the music is great. So many greats who have passed on now - the great blues and R&B groups, John Lee Hooker, James Brown, Ray Charles, Belushi, John Candy and so many others. Belushi and Akroyd are hilarious in different ways, but play off each other beautifully. I can't believe this movie isn't a 10/10. Its a cult film and will live forever.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Some Flaws but Overall Entertaining
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Michael_Elliott
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Blues Brothers (1980) *** (out of 4) Madhouse from John Landis has Jake and Elwood Blues (John Belushi, Dan Aykroyd) getting their band back together so that they can raise $5,000 to save their orphanage where they were raised. At first it seems like raising the cash will be easy but the brothers soon have Nazies, cops, angry cowboys and others chasing them through Chicago. THE BLUES BROTHERS is one of the most entertaining bad movies I've ever seen. There's so many great things in this movie but at the same time there are so many things that bothered me and kept me from enjoying the picture even more. We'll start with the bad and I'd say it's obvious that there's no story here. Instead of an actual story we just get non-stop music scenes as well as car crashes, two things that actually work in the movie but the extended running time is just way too long and I was constantly looking at the watch to see how much longer there was. The lack of any real story and the extended running time are certainly the two things that keep this from being better because outside of this there's quite a bit to enjoy here. The best thing is the fact that Landis pretty much throws everything out the window and right at the viewer. This includes some of the craziest, most over-the-top chase/wreck scenes that you're ever going to witness. There are many throughout the picture but for me the highlight would have to be the one inside the mall where everything in sight gets destroyed at least twice. Another good thing the film has going for it are some of the musical performances especially the ones dealing with Ray Charles, Cab Calloway, Aretha Franklin and John Lee Hooker. Then, of course, you've got Belushi and Aykroyd turning in great performances as the Blue Brothers. You can't help but feel like you're watching real brothers doing real blues. THE BLUES BROTHERS is far from perfect but there's still enough here that makes it worth viewing.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of the greatest comedy's
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Sean Rajnert (Newsgeek13@gmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Blues Brohers, what can i say... it's a comedy. an action movie maybe even a parody. The plot is (NO Spoilers) Jake Blues, a man released from a correctional center, meets up with his brother Elwood. The blues brothers are a band and they have to get the band back together to raise $5,000 for their catholic home. What makes this movie so great is the humor, there's things people do for no reason, their chased by everyone, and by the middle of the movie. You believe this is a normal day for the two. I only have one problem with the movie, it does tend to feel a little longer than it is, but the comedy and the music make up for it. I give this movie a 3 & 1/2 stars out of four. A great movie everybody should check out. (Well, at least wait for your kid to be 14 years of age)
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A great musical for people who don't like musicals!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Tweekums
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    As the film opens we see Jake Blues being released from prison and picked up by his brother Elwood; they head to the orphanage where they were raised and learn that the place will me closed down of somebody doesn't pay the $5000 tax demand in the next few days. Soon The Blues Brothers are on a mission from God to save the orphanage. To do this Jake wants to get their old band back together but it won't be easy as the members have all got on with their lives while he was in jail. Even once they have got the band back together it will be hard to earn that sort of money at short notice and that isn't mentioning the fact that they are wanted by the police, the local Nazis and a mysterious woman who is determined to kill Jake! It is safe to say that by the time they pay the $5000 considerably more damage will have been none! The opening scene might make one think this was going to be a fairly slow movie but once Jake is out of prison it isn't long before the laughter and mayhem begin and there is a lot of both. The action is over the top and utterly hilarious with countless cop cars, shop windows and even entire buildings being destroyed. This mayhem is regularly interrupted by musical interludes by the likes of James Brown, Aretha Franklin, Ray Charles and Cab Callaway. These songs are frequently accompanied by entertaining dance routines. As well as lots of well known singers there are also quite a few other well known people in cameo roles; the best being Carrie Fisher who plays the woman trying to kill Jake; I loved how it isn't explained why she is doing it till nearly the end. John Belushi and Dan Aykroyd are great as Jake and Elwood; two characters who almost never remove their sunglasses; even at night. I'd heartily recommend this to anybody wanting a good laugh; don't worry if you don't usually like musicals; this one is great!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Over Produced and Overrated
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    leonlouisricci
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Way over produced and exaggerated, this overrated Movie has a number or funny bits and some bouncy Music, some of it by real Soul and R&B greats, but it is also filled with so many car crashes that it wrecks the momentum. There could easily be 45 minutes cut in the form of unnecessary big budget, obligatory scenes and this would be a more enjoyable Musical/Comedy. As it is, there is so much that is disjointed and destructive that it literally collapses onto itself with over indulgence and unrestrained tomfoolery. Worth a view for the better parts, but be prepared to endure endless repetition, mostly of the vehicular nature. Aykroyd and Belushi were naturals on SNL and other projects, but this big production didn't do them any favors in the creative department because they were buried in so much rubble.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Overblown
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bigverybadtom
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie is a landmark-it was responsible for Chicago becoming the setting for a number of future movies. On its own, it is based on a Saturday Night Live sketch about two white characters with pretensions of being blues musicians. Add a number of major real-life blues musicians and an even larger number of car crashes, and that's the recipe for the movie. The premise is about two brothers, one just out of Joliet prison, who try to raise money to save an orphanage from closing down, and to do so, bring together the members of their old band. Of course, their efforts to do so end up causing trouble with the law, as well as other people (such as a country and western-themed bar and the band that was supposed to play there). In the end, dozens of police cars chase after them, and even the National Guard, before they fulfill their quest. There are some genuinely funny parts, but overall the whole movie depends on exaggeration-twenty police cars crashing into twenty police cars, as critic Roger Ebert had put it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Hilarious Musical Comedy! Belushi And Aykroyd Are Great!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Humphrey Fish
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Jake Blues, just out from prison, puts together his old band to save the Catholic home where he and brother Elwood were raised. The Blues Brothers is arguably the funniest movie of 1980, it is a comedy masterpiece, it's a hilarious musical comedy film! This movie provides a ton of things that help make it great, for one thing, it gives the viewers a lot of hilarious performances from the cast, it gives the viewers a lot of very hysterical scenes and gags, and lastly, it gives the viewers a lot of enjoyment with a lot of very great music! I saw this movie, and I certainly had a great time watching it, it is like an amusement park there are a lot of huge laughs everywhere, such as the car chase through the mall, and the scene where The Blues Brothers are getting hit by the nun repeatedly with a yardstick, not to mention the part where they pose as the Good Ol' Boys. The movie has a lot more hysterical scenes, but I won't name them, as it would most likely spoil the movie, and I don't want to do that. But anyway, as far as comedy movies go, The Blues Brothers is a movie that's as hysterical as they come! Dan Aykroyd and John Belushi are great together, they were perfect for the roles of Elwood And Jake Blues respectively. While Aykroyd would later go on to achieve further greatness, Belushi's career was cut short, as he died from an accidental drug overdose at the young age of 33, sad. If Belushi and Aykroyd don't do the trick, then perhaps the supporting cast will. We've got a lot of real life blues musicians in this movie, such as Cab Calloway, Aretha Franklin, Ray Charles, and James Brown, and what a great lineup that is! The movie has tons to recommend, for one thing, the fact that it's a hilarious movie, another thing is the acting in the movie, as well as the all-star cast of actors. But the two best people in this movie are (and you might have guessed it) Dan Aykroyd and John Belushi, they were outstanding together, not only where they great with their acting, but they were also superb at singing and dancing! The Blues Brothers is a comedy movie that will last, it's will forever remain one of the funniest movies ever made for years and years to come. Here is something that I have to tell you, you're on a mission from God, and that mission is to watch this movie. Really, you've got to watch it, you won't regret it, it really is as hysterical as everyone says it is, and when you watch it, you will perfectly see what I mean. Before I continue, let me say this. I know that I may sound like I'm repeating myself, but sorry if I am, because what I am saying is true, this movie is a comic gem! So if you want to see a great movie with a lot of great acting, music, excitement, and dancing, then don't worry about that, because The Blues Brothers is a movie that contains all of these things! So step into the Bluesmobile with Jake and Elwood Blues and get ready for an awesome musical comedy adventure that you will absolutely love, that's the 1980 masterpiece, The Blues Brothers! 10/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    R.I.P John Belushi
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    omar wasief
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/9/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Blues Brothers' is a bit of both, lending exposure to rhythm and blues legends who might otherwise have faded into silence while at the same time treating black culture as a colorful pantomime backdrop for the antics of two white comedians. That Dan Aykroyd and John Belushi adore this music is not in question  it's lovingly chosen and brilliantly performed  but the film sometimes feels like a work of cultural tourism, particularly in scenes set in a gospel church and a Chicago street market. These lively musical sequences also sit awkwardly with director John Landis's bizarre predilection for wholesale destruction: sure, smashing up cop cars can be fun, but Landis takes things to a tiresome extreme. Still, the film retains a huge nostalgic kick, thanks in large part to Aykroyd and Belushi's easy rapport, a smattering of daft, shaggy humor and some truly iconic musical sequences.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Film That Gets Better And Better, The More You Watch It!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    SebMModernsII
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    What more can I say about a movie that has outstanding car chases and jazzy blues music being fantastic?! It is! Some strong language is present, don't show it to your children (Even if they can't help but love it!) Two brothers (Played By John Belushi And Dan Aykroyd) are reunited after one brother "Jake Blues" is released from prison. They are on the run from The Police! (There are a lot of police in this film!) and on the way, they try to make money with their music to help keep The Church open. There is a lot of great music in this film, there is even a singing of Robert Johnson's "Sweet Home Chicago!" The film ends with The Blues Brothers entertaining the prisoners with their hit Rock'N Roll dance song "Let's Rock!" and The End Credits involves a reprise of their best songs! A must see, if you haven't yet watched it! Overall Rating: 10/10!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Pretty damn funny
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Terrell Howell (KnightsofNi11)
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Back in the 70's John Belushi and Dan Akroyd introduced the characters of Jake and Elwood Blues on the ever popular Saturday Night Live. In 1980 legendary director John Landis gave the characters their own feature length film. The Blues Brothers stars Belushi and Akroyd as Jake and Elwood, respectively, and it follows them as they attempt to put their old band back together in order to raise money to save the Catholic orphanage home where they were raised. Dubbing this quest a mission from God the two set out on a wacky and action packed adventure full of screwball situations and nut job characters. What ensues is a lot of fun. The Blues Brothers is one of those essential 80's comedies. It's worked its way to earning the status of a classic and so these days, no matter how you feel about comedies, it's just one of those that you have to see. It's also one of the very few successful films to be made out of SNL characters, and that's always a treat to watch, especially if you know the characters from the TV show. Seeing them come to life in a whole new way through the big screen is something really exciting to witness. And with characters as classic as Jake and Elwood Blues, played by their original actors, the ingenious Dan Akroyd and John Belushi, it had to have been a nostalgic experience for 1980 audiences. I didn't get as much of this, however. I know the characters for how iconic they are today and I've seen some of the Blues Brothers SNL skits, but I can't say this movie had the same effect for me as it would have had for audiences back in the day excited to see their favorite SNL characters put on the big screen. As far as this just being a good movie, it's funny and that's about it. I definitely enjoyed watching this flick, but it's not much more than just a silly over-the-top comedy. The only thing that makes it better than a lot of the other screwball comedies like it would be it's great actors and the legendary status behind the characters. All in all, The Blues Brothers is just a lot of hilarious wackiness with some crazy song and dance numbers thrown in throughout. It's a lot of fun in a weird, explosive, irreverent way.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Even the Vatican recommends it!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Suzanne Sellers
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Just saw this film again for the 20th or so time. Love every scene, but I think my favorite is where they go to visit "The Penguin" (nun) and they mange to offend her with their profanity. She tears them a new one as they fall down the stairs in their little kiddie desks. Its hilarious physical comedy. This film takes me back to a great time in my life which, by comparison, seems so much better entertainment-wise. Things were so much simpler then. As everyone has mentioned, the music is great. So many greats who have passed on now - the great blues and R&B groups, John Lee Hooker, James Brown, Ray Charles, Belushi, John Candy and so many others. Belushi and Akroyd are hilarious in different ways, but play off each other beautifully. I can't believe this movie isn't a 10/10. Its a cult film and will live forever.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Some Flaws but Overall Entertaining
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Michael_Elliott
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Blues Brothers (1980) *** (out of 4) Madhouse from John Landis has Jake and Elwood Blues (John Belushi, Dan Aykroyd) getting their band back together so that they can raise $5,000 to save their orphanage where they were raised. At first it seems like raising the cash will be easy but the brothers soon have Nazies, cops, angry cowboys and others chasing them through Chicago. THE BLUES BROTHERS is one of the most entertaining bad movies I've ever seen. There's so many great things in this movie but at the same time there are so many things that bothered me and kept me from enjoying the picture even more. We'll start with the bad and I'd say it's obvious that there's no story here. Instead of an actual story we just get non-stop music scenes as well as car crashes, two things that actually work in the movie but the extended running time is just way too long and I was constantly looking at the watch to see how much longer there was. The lack of any real story and the extended running time are certainly the two things that keep this from being better because outside of this there's quite a bit to enjoy here. The best thing is the fact that Landis pretty much throws everything out the window and right at the viewer. This includes some of the craziest, most over-the-top chase/wreck scenes that you're ever going to witness. There are many throughout the picture but for me the highlight would have to be the one inside the mall where everything in sight gets destroyed at least twice. Another good thing the film has going for it are some of the musical performances especially the ones dealing with Ray Charles, Cab Calloway, Aretha Franklin and John Lee Hooker. Then, of course, you've got Belushi and Aykroyd turning in great performances as the Blue Brothers. You can't help but feel like you're watching real brothers doing real blues. THE BLUES BROTHERS is far from perfect but there's still enough here that makes it worth viewing.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of the greatest comedy's
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Sean Rajnert (Newsgeek13@gmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Blues Brohers, what can i say... it's a comedy. an action movie maybe even a parody. The plot is (NO Spoilers) Jake Blues, a man released from a correctional center, meets up with his brother Elwood. The blues brothers are a band and they have to get the band back together to raise $5,000 for their catholic home. What makes this movie so great is the humor, there's things people do for no reason, their chased by everyone, and by the middle of the movie. You believe this is a normal day for the two. I only have one problem with the movie, it does tend to feel a little longer than it is, but the comedy and the music make up for it. I give this movie a 3 & 1/2 stars out of four. A great movie everybody should check out. (Well, at least wait for your kid to be 14 years of age)
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A great musical for people who don't like musicals!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Tweekums
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    As the film opens we see Jake Blues being released from prison and picked up by his brother Elwood; they head to the orphanage where they were raised and learn that the place will me closed down of somebody doesn't pay the $5000 tax demand in the next few days. Soon The Blues Brothers are on a mission from God to save the orphanage. To do this Jake wants to get their old band back together but it won't be easy as the members have all got on with their lives while he was in jail. Even once they have got the band back together it will be hard to earn that sort of money at short notice and that isn't mentioning the fact that they are wanted by the police, the local Nazis and a mysterious woman who is determined to kill Jake! It is safe to say that by the time they pay the $5000 considerably more damage will have been none! The opening scene might make one think this was going to be a fairly slow movie but once Jake is out of prison it isn't long before the laughter and mayhem begin and there is a lot of both. The action is over the top and utterly hilarious with countless cop cars, shop windows and even entire buildings being destroyed. This mayhem is regularly interrupted by musical interludes by the likes of James Brown, Aretha Franklin, Ray Charles and Cab Callaway. These songs are frequently accompanied by entertaining dance routines. As well as lots of well known singers there are also quite a few other well known people in cameo roles; the best being Carrie Fisher who plays the woman trying to kill Jake; I loved how it isn't explained why she is doing it till nearly the end. John Belushi and Dan Aykroyd are great as Jake and Elwood; two characters who almost never remove their sunglasses; even at night. I'd heartily recommend this to anybody wanting a good laugh; don't worry if you don't usually like musicals; this one is great!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Over Produced and Overrated
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    leonlouisricci
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Way over produced and exaggerated, this overrated Movie has a number or funny bits and some bouncy Music, some of it by real Soul and R&B greats, but it is also filled with so many car crashes that it wrecks the momentum. There could easily be 45 minutes cut in the form of unnecessary big budget, obligatory scenes and this would be a more enjoyable Musical/Comedy. As it is, there is so much that is disjointed and destructive that it literally collapses onto itself with over indulgence and unrestrained tomfoolery. Worth a view for the better parts, but be prepared to endure endless repetition, mostly of the vehicular nature. Aykroyd and Belushi were naturals on SNL and other projects, but this big production didn't do them any favors in the creative department because they were buried in so much rubble.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Overblown
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bigverybadtom
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie is a landmark-it was responsible for Chicago becoming the setting for a number of future movies. On its own, it is based on a Saturday Night Live sketch about two white characters with pretensions of being blues musicians. Add a number of major real-life blues musicians and an even larger number of car crashes, and that's the recipe for the movie. The premise is about two brothers, one just out of Joliet prison, who try to raise money to save an orphanage from closing down, and to do so, bring together the members of their old band. Of course, their efforts to do so end up causing trouble with the law, as well as other people (such as a country and western-themed bar and the band that was supposed to play there). In the end, dozens of police cars chase after them, and even the National Guard, before they fulfill their quest. There are some genuinely funny parts, but overall the whole movie depends on exaggeration-twenty police cars crashing into twenty police cars, as critic Roger Ebert had put it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Hilarious Musical Comedy! Belushi And Aykroyd Are Great!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Humphrey Fish
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Jake Blues, just out from prison, puts together his old band to save the Catholic home where he and brother Elwood were raised. The Blues Brothers is arguably the funniest movie of 1980, it is a comedy masterpiece, it's a hilarious musical comedy film! This movie provides a ton of things that help make it great, for one thing, it gives the viewers a lot of hilarious performances from the cast, it gives the viewers a lot of very hysterical scenes and gags, and lastly, it gives the viewers a lot of enjoyment with a lot of very great music! I saw this movie, and I certainly had a great time watching it, it is like an amusement park there are a lot of huge laughs everywhere, such as the car chase through the mall, and the scene where The Blues Brothers are getting hit by the nun repeatedly with a yardstick, not to mention the part where they pose as the Good Ol' Boys. The movie has a lot more hysterical scenes, but I won't name them, as it would most likely spoil the movie, and I don't want to do that. But anyway, as far as comedy movies go, The Blues Brothers is a movie that's as hysterical as they come! Dan Aykroyd and John Belushi are great together, they were perfect for the roles of Elwood And Jake Blues respectively. While Aykroyd would later go on to achieve further greatness, Belushi's career was cut short, as he died from an accidental drug overdose at the young age of 33, sad. If Belushi and Aykroyd don't do the trick, then perhaps the supporting cast will. We've got a lot of real life blues musicians in this movie, such as Cab Calloway, Aretha Franklin, Ray Charles, and James Brown, and what a great lineup that is! The movie has tons to recommend, for one thing, the fact that it's a hilarious movie, another thing is the acting in the movie, as well as the all-star cast of actors. But the two best people in this movie are (and you might have guessed it) Dan Aykroyd and John Belushi, they were outstanding together, not only where they great with their acting, but they were also superb at singing and dancing! The Blues Brothers is a comedy movie that will last, it's will forever remain one of the funniest movies ever made for years and years to come. Here is something that I have to tell you, you're on a mission from God, and that mission is to watch this movie. Really, you've got to watch it, you won't regret it, it really is as hysterical as everyone says it is, and when you watch it, you will perfectly see what I mean. Before I continue, let me say this. I know that I may sound like I'm repeating myself, but sorry if I am, because what I am saying is true, this movie is a comic gem! So if you want to see a great movie with a lot of great acting, music, excitement, and dancing, then don't worry about that, because The Blues Brothers is a movie that contains all of these things! So step into the Bluesmobile with Jake and Elwood Blues and get ready for an awesome musical comedy adventure that you will absolutely love, that's the 1980 masterpiece, The Blues Brothers! 10/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    R.I.P John Belushi
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    omar wasief
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/9/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Blues Brothers' is a bit of both, lending exposure to rhythm and blues legends who might otherwise have faded into silence while at the same time treating black culture as a colorful pantomime backdrop for the antics of two white comedians. That Dan Aykroyd and John Belushi adore this music is not in question  it's lovingly chosen and brilliantly performed  but the film sometimes feels like a work of cultural tourism, particularly in scenes set in a gospel church and a Chicago street market. These lively musical sequences also sit awkwardly with director John Landis's bizarre predilection for wholesale destruction: sure, smashing up cop cars can be fun, but Landis takes things to a tiresome extreme. Still, the film retains a huge nostalgic kick, thanks in large part to Aykroyd and Belushi's easy rapport, a smattering of daft, shaggy humor and some truly iconic musical sequences.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Film That Gets Better And Better, The More You Watch It!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    SebMModernsII
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    What more can I say about a movie that has outstanding car chases and jazzy blues music being fantastic?! It is! Some strong language is present, don't show it to your children (Even if they can't help but love it!) Two brothers (Played By John Belushi And Dan Aykroyd) are reunited after one brother "Jake Blues" is released from prison. They are on the run from The Police! (There are a lot of police in this film!) and on the way, they try to make money with their music to help keep The Church open. There is a lot of great music in this film, there is even a singing of Robert Johnson's "Sweet Home Chicago!" The film ends with The Blues Brothers entertaining the prisoners with their hit Rock'N Roll dance song "Let's Rock!" and The End Credits involves a reprise of their best songs! A must see, if you haven't yet watched it! Overall Rating: 10/10!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Pretty damn funny
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Terrell Howell (KnightsofNi11)
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Back in the 70's John Belushi and Dan Akroyd introduced the characters of Jake and Elwood Blues on the ever popular Saturday Night Live. In 1980 legendary director John Landis gave the characters their own feature length film. The Blues Brothers stars Belushi and Akroyd as Jake and Elwood, respectively, and it follows them as they attempt to put their old band back together in order to raise money to save the Catholic orphanage home where they were raised. Dubbing this quest a mission from God the two set out on a wacky and action packed adventure full of screwball situations and nut job characters. What ensues is a lot of fun. The Blues Brothers is one of those essential 80's comedies. It's worked its way to earning the status of a classic and so these days, no matter how you feel about comedies, it's just one of those that you have to see. It's also one of the very few successful films to be made out of SNL characters, and that's always a treat to watch, especially if you know the characters from the TV show. Seeing them come to life in a whole new way through the big screen is something really exciting to witness. And with characters as classic as Jake and Elwood Blues, played by their original actors, the ingenious Dan Akroyd and John Belushi, it had to have been a nostalgic experience for 1980 audiences. I didn't get as much of this, however. I know the characters for how iconic they are today and I've seen some of the Blues Brothers SNL skits, but I can't say this movie had the same effect for me as it would have had for audiences back in the day excited to see their favorite SNL characters put on the big screen. As far as this just being a good movie, it's funny and that's about it. I definitely enjoyed watching this flick, but it's not much more than just a silly over-the-top comedy. The only thing that makes it better than a lot of the other screwball comedies like it would be it's great actors and the legendary status behind the characters. All in all, The Blues Brothers is just a lot of hilarious wackiness with some crazy song and dance numbers thrown in throughout. It's a lot of fun in a weird, explosive, irreverent way.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Even the Vatican recommends it!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Suzanne Sellers
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Just saw this film again for the 20th or so time. Love every scene, but I think my favorite is where they go to visit "The Penguin" (nun) and they mange to offend her with their profanity. She tears them a new one as they fall down the stairs in their little kiddie desks. Its hilarious physical comedy. This film takes me back to a great time in my life which, by comparison, seems so much better entertainment-wise. Things were so much simpler then. As everyone has mentioned, the music is great. So many greats who have passed on now - the great blues and R&B groups, John Lee Hooker, James Brown, Ray Charles, Belushi, John Candy and so many others. Belushi and Akroyd are hilarious in different ways, but play off each other beautifully. I can't believe this movie isn't a 10/10. Its a cult film and will live forever.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Some Flaws but Overall Entertaining
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Michael_Elliott
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Blues Brothers (1980) *** (out of 4) Madhouse from John Landis has Jake and Elwood Blues (John Belushi, Dan Aykroyd) getting their band back together so that they can raise $5,000 to save their orphanage where they were raised. At first it seems like raising the cash will be easy but the brothers soon have Nazies, cops, angry cowboys and others chasing them through Chicago. THE BLUES BROTHERS is one of the most entertaining bad movies I've ever seen. There's so many great things in this movie but at the same time there are so many things that bothered me and kept me from enjoying the picture even more. We'll start with the bad and I'd say it's obvious that there's no story here. Instead of an actual story we just get non-stop music scenes as well as car crashes, two things that actually work in the movie but the extended running time is just way too long and I was constantly looking at the watch to see how much longer there was. The lack of any real story and the extended running time are certainly the two things that keep this from being better because outside of this there's quite a bit to enjoy here. The best thing is the fact that Landis pretty much throws everything out the window and right at the viewer. This includes some of the craziest, most over-the-top chase/wreck scenes that you're ever going to witness. There are many throughout the picture but for me the highlight would have to be the one inside the mall where everything in sight gets destroyed at least twice. Another good thing the film has going for it are some of the musical performances especially the ones dealing with Ray Charles, Cab Calloway, Aretha Franklin and John Lee Hooker. Then, of course, you've got Belushi and Aykroyd turning in great performances as the Blue Brothers. You can't help but feel like you're watching real brothers doing real blues. THE BLUES BROTHERS is far from perfect but there's still enough here that makes it worth viewing.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of the greatest comedy's
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Sean Rajnert (Newsgeek13@gmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Blues Brohers, what can i say... it's a comedy. an action movie maybe even a parody. The plot is (NO Spoilers) Jake Blues, a man released from a correctional center, meets up with his brother Elwood. The blues brothers are a band and they have to get the band back together to raise $5,000 for their catholic home. What makes this movie so great is the humor, there's things people do for no reason, their chased by everyone, and by the middle of the movie. You believe this is a normal day for the two. I only have one problem with the movie, it does tend to feel a little longer than it is, but the comedy and the music make up for it. I give this movie a 3 & 1/2 stars out of four. A great movie everybody should check out. (Well, at least wait for your kid to be 14 years of age)
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A great musical for people who don't like musicals!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Tweekums
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    As the film opens we see Jake Blues being released from prison and picked up by his brother Elwood; they head to the orphanage where they were raised and learn that the place will me closed down of somebody doesn't pay the $5000 tax demand in the next few days. Soon The Blues Brothers are on a mission from God to save the orphanage. To do this Jake wants to get their old band back together but it won't be easy as the members have all got on with their lives while he was in jail. Even once they have got the band back together it will be hard to earn that sort of money at short notice and that isn't mentioning the fact that they are wanted by the police, the local Nazis and a mysterious woman who is determined to kill Jake! It is safe to say that by the time they pay the $5000 considerably more damage will have been none! The opening scene might make one think this was going to be a fairly slow movie but once Jake is out of prison it isn't long before the laughter and mayhem begin and there is a lot of both. The action is over the top and utterly hilarious with countless cop cars, shop windows and even entire buildings being destroyed. This mayhem is regularly interrupted by musical interludes by the likes of James Brown, Aretha Franklin, Ray Charles and Cab Callaway. These songs are frequently accompanied by entertaining dance routines. As well as lots of well known singers there are also quite a few other well known people in cameo roles; the best being Carrie Fisher who plays the woman trying to kill Jake; I loved how it isn't explained why she is doing it till nearly the end. John Belushi and Dan Aykroyd are great as Jake and Elwood; two characters who almost never remove their sunglasses; even at night. I'd heartily recommend this to anybody wanting a good laugh; don't worry if you don't usually like musicals; this one is great!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Over Produced and Overrated
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    leonlouisricci
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Way over produced and exaggerated, this overrated Movie has a number or funny bits and some bouncy Music, some of it by real Soul and R&B greats, but it is also filled with so many car crashes that it wrecks the momentum. There could easily be 45 minutes cut in the form of unnecessary big budget, obligatory scenes and this would be a more enjoyable Musical/Comedy. As it is, there is so much that is disjointed and destructive that it literally collapses onto itself with over indulgence and unrestrained tomfoolery. Worth a view for the better parts, but be prepared to endure endless repetition, mostly of the vehicular nature. Aykroyd and Belushi were naturals on SNL and other projects, but this big production didn't do them any favors in the creative department because they were buried in so much rubble.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Overblown
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bigverybadtom
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie is a landmark-it was responsible for Chicago becoming the setting for a number of future movies. On its own, it is based on a Saturday Night Live sketch about two white characters with pretensions of being blues musicians. Add a number of major real-life blues musicians and an even larger number of car crashes, and that's the recipe for the movie. The premise is about two brothers, one just out of Joliet prison, who try to raise money to save an orphanage from closing down, and to do so, bring together the members of their old band. Of course, their efforts to do so end up causing trouble with the law, as well as other people (such as a country and western-themed bar and the band that was supposed to play there). In the end, dozens of police cars chase after them, and even the National Guard, before they fulfill their quest. There are some genuinely funny parts, but overall the whole movie depends on exaggeration-twenty police cars crashing into twenty police cars, as critic Roger Ebert had put it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Hilarious Musical Comedy! Belushi And Aykroyd Are Great!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Humphrey Fish
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Jake Blues, just out from prison, puts together his old band to save the Catholic home where he and brother Elwood were raised. The Blues Brothers is arguably the funniest movie of 1980, it is a comedy masterpiece, it's a hilarious musical comedy film! This movie provides a ton of things that help make it great, for one thing, it gives the viewers a lot of hilarious performances from the cast, it gives the viewers a lot of very hysterical scenes and gags, and lastly, it gives the viewers a lot of enjoyment with a lot of very great music! I saw this movie, and I certainly had a great time watching it, it is like an amusement park there are a lot of huge laughs everywhere, such as the car chase through the mall, and the scene where The Blues Brothers are getting hit by the nun repeatedly with a yardstick, not to mention the part where they pose as the Good Ol' Boys. The movie has a lot more hysterical scenes, but I won't name them, as it would most likely spoil the movie, and I don't want to do that. But anyway, as far as comedy movies go, The Blues Brothers is a movie that's as hysterical as they come! Dan Aykroyd and John Belushi are great together, they were perfect for the roles of Elwood And Jake Blues respectively. While Aykroyd would later go on to achieve further greatness, Belushi's career was cut short, as he died from an accidental drug overdose at the young age of 33, sad. If Belushi and Aykroyd don't do the trick, then perhaps the supporting cast will. We've got a lot of real life blues musicians in this movie, such as Cab Calloway, Aretha Franklin, Ray Charles, and James Brown, and what a great lineup that is! The movie has tons to recommend, for one thing, the fact that it's a hilarious movie, another thing is the acting in the movie, as well as the all-star cast of actors. But the two best people in this movie are (and you might have guessed it) Dan Aykroyd and John Belushi, they were outstanding together, not only where they great with their acting, but they were also superb at singing and dancing! The Blues Brothers is a comedy movie that will last, it's will forever remain one of the funniest movies ever made for years and years to come. Here is something that I have to tell you, you're on a mission from God, and that mission is to watch this movie. Really, you've got to watch it, you won't regret it, it really is as hysterical as everyone says it is, and when you watch it, you will perfectly see what I mean. Before I continue, let me say this. I know that I may sound like I'm repeating myself, but sorry if I am, because what I am saying is true, this movie is a comic gem! So if you want to see a great movie with a lot of great acting, music, excitement, and dancing, then don't worry about that, because The Blues Brothers is a movie that contains all of these things! So step into the Bluesmobile with Jake and Elwood Blues and get ready for an awesome musical comedy adventure that you will absolutely love, that's the 1980 masterpiece, The Blues Brothers! 10/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    R.I.P John Belushi
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    omar wasief
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/9/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Blues Brothers' is a bit of both, lending exposure to rhythm and blues legends who might otherwise have faded into silence while at the same time treating black culture as a colorful pantomime backdrop for the antics of two white comedians. That Dan Aykroyd and John Belushi adore this music is not in question  it's lovingly chosen and brilliantly performed  but the film sometimes feels like a work of cultural tourism, particularly in scenes set in a gospel church and a Chicago street market. These lively musical sequences also sit awkwardly with director John Landis's bizarre predilection for wholesale destruction: sure, smashing up cop cars can be fun, but Landis takes things to a tiresome extreme. Still, the film retains a huge nostalgic kick, thanks in large part to Aykroyd and Belushi's easy rapport, a smattering of daft, shaggy humor and some truly iconic musical sequences.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Film That Gets Better And Better, The More You Watch It!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    SebMModernsII
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    What more can I say about a movie that has outstanding car chases and jazzy blues music being fantastic?! It is! Some strong language is present, don't show it to your children (Even if they can't help but love it!) Two brothers (Played By John Belushi And Dan Aykroyd) are reunited after one brother "Jake Blues" is released from prison. They are on the run from The Police! (There are a lot of police in this film!) and on the way, they try to make money with their music to help keep The Church open. There is a lot of great music in this film, there is even a singing of Robert Johnson's "Sweet Home Chicago!" The film ends with The Blues Brothers entertaining the prisoners with their hit Rock'N Roll dance song "Let's Rock!" and The End Credits involves a reprise of their best songs! A must see, if you haven't yet watched it! Overall Rating: 10/10!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Pretty damn funny
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Terrell Howell (KnightsofNi11)
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Back in the 70's John Belushi and Dan Akroyd introduced the characters of Jake and Elwood Blues on the ever popular Saturday Night Live. In 1980 legendary director John Landis gave the characters their own feature length film. The Blues Brothers stars Belushi and Akroyd as Jake and Elwood, respectively, and it follows them as they attempt to put their old band back together in order to raise money to save the Catholic orphanage home where they were raised. Dubbing this quest a mission from God the two set out on a wacky and action packed adventure full of screwball situations and nut job characters. What ensues is a lot of fun. The Blues Brothers is one of those essential 80's comedies. It's worked its way to earning the status of a classic and so these days, no matter how you feel about comedies, it's just one of those that you have to see. It's also one of the very few successful films to be made out of SNL characters, and that's always a treat to watch, especially if you know the characters from the TV show. Seeing them come to life in a whole new way through the big screen is something really exciting to witness. And with characters as classic as Jake and Elwood Blues, played by their original actors, the ingenious Dan Akroyd and John Belushi, it had to have been a nostalgic experience for 1980 audiences. I didn't get as much of this, however. I know the characters for how iconic they are today and I've seen some of the Blues Brothers SNL skits, but I can't say this movie had the same effect for me as it would have had for audiences back in the day excited to see their favorite SNL characters put on the big screen. As far as this just being a good movie, it's funny and that's about it. I definitely enjoyed watching this flick, but it's not much more than just a silly over-the-top comedy. The only thing that makes it better than a lot of the other screwball comedies like it would be it's great actors and the legendary status behind the characters. All in all, The Blues Brothers is just a lot of hilarious wackiness with some crazy song and dance numbers thrown in throughout. It's a lot of fun in a weird, explosive, irreverent way.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Even the Vatican recommends it!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Suzanne Sellers
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Just saw this film again for the 20th or so time. Love every scene, but I think my favorite is where they go to visit "The Penguin" (nun) and they mange to offend her with their profanity. She tears them a new one as they fall down the stairs in their little kiddie desks. Its hilarious physical comedy. This film takes me back to a great time in my life which, by comparison, seems so much better entertainment-wise. Things were so much simpler then. As everyone has mentioned, the music is great. So many greats who have passed on now - the great blues and R&B groups, John Lee Hooker, James Brown, Ray Charles, Belushi, John Candy and so many others. Belushi and Akroyd are hilarious in different ways, but play off each other beautifully. I can't believe this movie isn't a 10/10. Its a cult film and will live forever.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Some Flaws but Overall Entertaining
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Michael_Elliott
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Blues Brothers (1980) *** (out of 4) Madhouse from John Landis has Jake and Elwood Blues (John Belushi, Dan Aykroyd) getting their band back together so that they can raise $5,000 to save their orphanage where they were raised. At first it seems like raising the cash will be easy but the brothers soon have Nazies, cops, angry cowboys and others chasing them through Chicago. THE BLUES BROTHERS is one of the most entertaining bad movies I've ever seen. There's so many great things in this movie but at the same time there are so many things that bothered me and kept me from enjoying the picture even more. We'll start with the bad and I'd say it's obvious that there's no story here. Instead of an actual story we just get non-stop music scenes as well as car crashes, two things that actually work in the movie but the extended running time is just way too long and I was constantly looking at the watch to see how much longer there was. The lack of any real story and the extended running time are certainly the two things that keep this from being better because outside of this there's quite a bit to enjoy here. The best thing is the fact that Landis pretty much throws everything out the window and right at the viewer. This includes some of the craziest, most over-the-top chase/wreck scenes that you're ever going to witness. There are many throughout the picture but for me the highlight would have to be the one inside the mall where everything in sight gets destroyed at least twice. Another good thing the film has going for it are some of the musical performances especially the ones dealing with Ray Charles, Cab Calloway, Aretha Franklin and John Lee Hooker. Then, of course, you've got Belushi and Aykroyd turning in great performances as the Blue Brothers. You can't help but feel like you're watching real brothers doing real blues. THE BLUES BROTHERS is far from perfect but there's still enough here that makes it worth viewing.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of the greatest comedy's
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Sean Rajnert (Newsgeek13@gmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Blues Brohers, what can i say... it's a comedy. an action movie maybe even a parody. The plot is (NO Spoilers) Jake Blues, a man released from a correctional center, meets up with his brother Elwood. The blues brothers are a band and they have to get the band back together to raise $5,000 for their catholic home. What makes this movie so great is the humor, there's things people do for no reason, their chased by everyone, and by the middle of the movie. You believe this is a normal day for the two. I only have one problem with the movie, it does tend to feel a little longer than it is, but the comedy and the music make up for it. I give this movie a 3 & 1/2 stars out of four. A great movie everybody should check out. (Well, at least wait for your kid to be 14 years of age)
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A great musical for people who don't like musicals!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Tweekums
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    As the film opens we see Jake Blues being released from prison and picked up by his brother Elwood; they head to the orphanage where they were raised and learn that the place will me closed down of somebody doesn't pay the $5000 tax demand in the next few days. Soon The Blues Brothers are on a mission from God to save the orphanage. To do this Jake wants to get their old band back together but it won't be easy as the members have all got on with their lives while he was in jail. Even once they have got the band back together it will be hard to earn that sort of money at short notice and that isn't mentioning the fact that they are wanted by the police, the local Nazis and a mysterious woman who is determined to kill Jake! It is safe to say that by the time they pay the $5000 considerably more damage will have been none! The opening scene might make one think this was going to be a fairly slow movie but once Jake is out of prison it isn't long before the laughter and mayhem begin and there is a lot of both. The action is over the top and utterly hilarious with countless cop cars, shop windows and even entire buildings being destroyed. This mayhem is regularly interrupted by musical interludes by the likes of James Brown, Aretha Franklin, Ray Charles and Cab Callaway. These songs are frequently accompanied by entertaining dance routines. As well as lots of well known singers there are also quite a few other well known people in cameo roles; the best being Carrie Fisher who plays the woman trying to kill Jake; I loved how it isn't explained why she is doing it till nearly the end. John Belushi and Dan Aykroyd are great as Jake and Elwood; two characters who almost never remove their sunglasses; even at night. I'd heartily recommend this to anybody wanting a good laugh; don't worry if you don't usually like musicals; this one is great!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Over Produced and Overrated
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    leonlouisricci
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Way over produced and exaggerated, this overrated Movie has a number or funny bits and some bouncy Music, some of it by real Soul and R&B greats, but it is also filled with so many car crashes that it wrecks the momentum. There could easily be 45 minutes cut in the form of unnecessary big budget, obligatory scenes and this would be a more enjoyable Musical/Comedy. As it is, there is so much that is disjointed and destructive that it literally collapses onto itself with over indulgence and unrestrained tomfoolery. Worth a view for the better parts, but be prepared to endure endless repetition, mostly of the vehicular nature. Aykroyd and Belushi were naturals on SNL and other projects, but this big production didn't do them any favors in the creative department because they were buried in so much rubble.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Overblown
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bigverybadtom
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie is a landmark-it was responsible for Chicago becoming the setting for a number of future movies. On its own, it is based on a Saturday Night Live sketch about two white characters with pretensions of being blues musicians. Add a number of major real-life blues musicians and an even larger number of car crashes, and that's the recipe for the movie. The premise is about two brothers, one just out of Joliet prison, who try to raise money to save an orphanage from closing down, and to do so, bring together the members of their old band. Of course, their efforts to do so end up causing trouble with the law, as well as other people (such as a country and western-themed bar and the band that was supposed to play there). In the end, dozens of police cars chase after them, and even the National Guard, before they fulfill their quest. There are some genuinely funny parts, but overall the whole movie depends on exaggeration-twenty police cars crashing into twenty police cars, as critic Roger Ebert had put it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Hilarious Musical Comedy! Belushi And Aykroyd Are Great!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Humphrey Fish
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Jake Blues, just out from prison, puts together his old band to save the Catholic home where he and brother Elwood were raised. The Blues Brothers is arguably the funniest movie of 1980, it is a comedy masterpiece, it's a hilarious musical comedy film! This movie provides a ton of things that help make it great, for one thing, it gives the viewers a lot of hilarious performances from the cast, it gives the viewers a lot of very hysterical scenes and gags, and lastly, it gives the viewers a lot of enjoyment with a lot of very great music! I saw this movie, and I certainly had a great time watching it, it is like an amusement park there are a lot of huge laughs everywhere, such as the car chase through the mall, and the scene where The Blues Brothers are getting hit by the nun repeatedly with a yardstick, not to mention the part where they pose as the Good Ol' Boys. The movie has a lot more hysterical scenes, but I won't name them, as it would most likely spoil the movie, and I don't want to do that. But anyway, as far as comedy movies go, The Blues Brothers is a movie that's as hysterical as they come! Dan Aykroyd and John Belushi are great together, they were perfect for the roles of Elwood And Jake Blues respectively. While Aykroyd would later go on to achieve further greatness, Belushi's career was cut short, as he died from an accidental drug overdose at the young age of 33, sad. If Belushi and Aykroyd don't do the trick, then perhaps the supporting cast will. We've got a lot of real life blues musicians in this movie, such as Cab Calloway, Aretha Franklin, Ray Charles, and James Brown, and what a great lineup that is! The movie has tons to recommend, for one thing, the fact that it's a hilarious movie, another thing is the acting in the movie, as well as the all-star cast of actors. But the two best people in this movie are (and you might have guessed it) Dan Aykroyd and John Belushi, they were outstanding together, not only where they great with their acting, but they were also superb at singing and dancing! The Blues Brothers is a comedy movie that will last, it's will forever remain one of the funniest movies ever made for years and years to come. Here is something that I have to tell you, you're on a mission from God, and that mission is to watch this movie. Really, you've got to watch it, you won't regret it, it really is as hysterical as everyone says it is, and when you watch it, you will perfectly see what I mean. Before I continue, let me say this. I know that I may sound like I'm repeating myself, but sorry if I am, because what I am saying is true, this movie is a comic gem! So if you want to see a great movie with a lot of great acting, music, excitement, and dancing, then don't worry about that, because The Blues Brothers is a movie that contains all of these things! So step into the Bluesmobile with Jake and Elwood Blues and get ready for an awesome musical comedy adventure that you will absolutely love, that's the 1980 masterpiece, The Blues Brothers! 10/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    R.I.P John Belushi
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    omar wasief
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/9/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Blues Brothers' is a bit of both, lending exposure to rhythm and blues legends who might otherwise have faded into silence while at the same time treating black culture as a colorful pantomime backdrop for the antics of two white comedians. That Dan Aykroyd and John Belushi adore this music is not in question  it's lovingly chosen and brilliantly performed  but the film sometimes feels like a work of cultural tourism, particularly in scenes set in a gospel church and a Chicago street market. These lively musical sequences also sit awkwardly with director John Landis's bizarre predilection for wholesale destruction: sure, smashing up cop cars can be fun, but Landis takes things to a tiresome extreme. Still, the film retains a huge nostalgic kick, thanks in large part to Aykroyd and Belushi's easy rapport, a smattering of daft, shaggy humor and some truly iconic musical sequences.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Film That Gets Better And Better, The More You Watch It!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    SebMModernsII
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    What more can I say about a movie that has outstanding car chases and jazzy blues music being fantastic?! It is! Some strong language is present, don't show it to your children (Even if they can't help but love it!) Two brothers (Played By John Belushi And Dan Aykroyd) are reunited after one brother "Jake Blues" is released from prison. They are on the run from The Police! (There are a lot of police in this film!) and on the way, they try to make money with their music to help keep The Church open. There is a lot of great music in this film, there is even a singing of Robert Johnson's "Sweet Home Chicago!" The film ends with The Blues Brothers entertaining the prisoners with their hit Rock'N Roll dance song "Let's Rock!" and The End Credits involves a reprise of their best songs! A must see, if you haven't yet watched it! Overall Rating: 10/10!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Pretty damn funny
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Terrell Howell (KnightsofNi11)
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Back in the 70's John Belushi and Dan Akroyd introduced the characters of Jake and Elwood Blues on the ever popular Saturday Night Live. In 1980 legendary director John Landis gave the characters their own feature length film. The Blues Brothers stars Belushi and Akroyd as Jake and Elwood, respectively, and it follows them as they attempt to put their old band back together in order to raise money to save the Catholic orphanage home where they were raised. Dubbing this quest a mission from God the two set out on a wacky and action packed adventure full of screwball situations and nut job characters. What ensues is a lot of fun. The Blues Brothers is one of those essential 80's comedies. It's worked its way to earning the status of a classic and so these days, no matter how you feel about comedies, it's just one of those that you have to see. It's also one of the very few successful films to be made out of SNL characters, and that's always a treat to watch, especially if you know the characters from the TV show. Seeing them come to life in a whole new way through the big screen is something really exciting to witness. And with characters as classic as Jake and Elwood Blues, played by their original actors, the ingenious Dan Akroyd and John Belushi, it had to have been a nostalgic experience for 1980 audiences. I didn't get as much of this, however. I know the characters for how iconic they are today and I've seen some of the Blues Brothers SNL skits, but I can't say this movie had the same effect for me as it would have had for audiences back in the day excited to see their favorite SNL characters put on the big screen. As far as this just being a good movie, it's funny and that's about it. I definitely enjoyed watching this flick, but it's not much more than just a silly over-the-top comedy. The only thing that makes it better than a lot of the other screwball comedies like it would be it's great actors and the legendary status behind the characters. All in all, The Blues Brothers is just a lot of hilarious wackiness with some crazy song and dance numbers thrown in throughout. It's a lot of fun in a weird, explosive, irreverent way.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Even the Vatican recommends it!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Suzanne Sellers
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Just saw this film again for the 20th or so time. Love every scene, but I think my favorite is where they go to visit "The Penguin" (nun) and they mange to offend her with their profanity. She tears them a new one as they fall down the stairs in their little kiddie desks. Its hilarious physical comedy. This film takes me back to a great time in my life which, by comparison, seems so much better entertainment-wise. Things were so much simpler then. As everyone has mentioned, the music is great. So many greats who have passed on now - the great blues and R&B groups, John Lee Hooker, James Brown, Ray Charles, Belushi, John Candy and so many others. Belushi and Akroyd are hilarious in different ways, but play off each other beautifully. I can't believe this movie isn't a 10/10. Its a cult film and will live forever.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Some Flaws but Overall Entertaining
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Michael_Elliott
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Blues Brothers (1980) *** (out of 4) Madhouse from John Landis has Jake and Elwood Blues (John Belushi, Dan Aykroyd) getting their band back together so that they can raise $5,000 to save their orphanage where they were raised. At first it seems like raising the cash will be easy but the brothers soon have Nazies, cops, angry cowboys and others chasing them through Chicago. THE BLUES BROTHERS is one of the most entertaining bad movies I've ever seen. There's so many great things in this movie but at the same time there are so many things that bothered me and kept me from enjoying the picture even more. We'll start with the bad and I'd say it's obvious that there's no story here. Instead of an actual story we just get non-stop music scenes as well as car crashes, two things that actually work in the movie but the extended running time is just way too long and I was constantly looking at the watch to see how much longer there was. The lack of any real story and the extended running time are certainly the two things that keep this from being better because outside of this there's quite a bit to enjoy here. The best thing is the fact that Landis pretty much throws everything out the window and right at the viewer. This includes some of the craziest, most over-the-top chase/wreck scenes that you're ever going to witness. There are many throughout the picture but for me the highlight would have to be the one inside the mall where everything in sight gets destroyed at least twice. Another good thing the film has going for it are some of the musical performances especially the ones dealing with Ray Charles, Cab Calloway, Aretha Franklin and John Lee Hooker. Then, of course, you've got Belushi and Aykroyd turning in great performances as the Blue Brothers. You can't help but feel like you're watching real brothers doing real blues. THE BLUES BROTHERS is far from perfect but there's still enough here that makes it worth viewing.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of the greatest comedy's
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Sean Rajnert (Newsgeek13@gmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Blues Brohers, what can i say... it's a comedy. an action movie maybe even a parody. The plot is (NO Spoilers) Jake Blues, a man released from a correctional center, meets up with his brother Elwood. The blues brothers are a band and they have to get the band back together to raise $5,000 for their catholic home. What makes this movie so great is the humor, there's things people do for no reason, their chased by everyone, and by the middle of the movie. You believe this is a normal day for the two. I only have one problem with the movie, it does tend to feel a little longer than it is, but the comedy and the music make up for it. I give this movie a 3 & 1/2 stars out of four. A great movie everybody should check out. (Well, at least wait for your kid to be 14 years of age)
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A great musical for people who don't like musicals!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Tweekums
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    As the film opens we see Jake Blues being released from prison and picked up by his brother Elwood; they head to the orphanage where they were raised and learn that the place will me closed down of somebody doesn't pay the $5000 tax demand in the next few days. Soon The Blues Brothers are on a mission from God to save the orphanage. To do this Jake wants to get their old band back together but it won't be easy as the members have all got on with their lives while he was in jail. Even once they have got the band back together it will be hard to earn that sort of money at short notice and that isn't mentioning the fact that they are wanted by the police, the local Nazis and a mysterious woman who is determined to kill Jake! It is safe to say that by the time they pay the $5000 considerably more damage will have been none! The opening scene might make one think this was going to be a fairly slow movie but once Jake is out of prison it isn't long before the laughter and mayhem begin and there is a lot of both. The action is over the top and utterly hilarious with countless cop cars, shop windows and even entire buildings being destroyed. This mayhem is regularly interrupted by musical interludes by the likes of James Brown, Aretha Franklin, Ray Charles and Cab Callaway. These songs are frequently accompanied by entertaining dance routines. As well as lots of well known singers there are also quite a few other well known people in cameo roles; the best being Carrie Fisher who plays the woman trying to kill Jake; I loved how it isn't explained why she is doing it till nearly the end. John Belushi and Dan Aykroyd are great as Jake and Elwood; two characters who almost never remove their sunglasses; even at night. I'd heartily recommend this to anybody wanting a good laugh; don't worry if you don't usually like musicals; this one is great!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Over Produced and Overrated
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    leonlouisricci
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Way over produced and exaggerated, this overrated Movie has a number or funny bits and some bouncy Music, some of it by real Soul and R&B greats, but it is also filled with so many car crashes that it wrecks the momentum. There could easily be 45 minutes cut in the form of unnecessary big budget, obligatory scenes and this would be a more enjoyable Musical/Comedy. As it is, there is so much that is disjointed and destructive that it literally collapses onto itself with over indulgence and unrestrained tomfoolery. Worth a view for the better parts, but be prepared to endure endless repetition, mostly of the vehicular nature. Aykroyd and Belushi were naturals on SNL and other projects, but this big production didn't do them any favors in the creative department because they were buried in so much rubble.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Overblown
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bigverybadtom
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie is a landmark-it was responsible for Chicago becoming the setting for a number of future movies. On its own, it is based on a Saturday Night Live sketch about two white characters with pretensions of being blues musicians. Add a number of major real-life blues musicians and an even larger number of car crashes, and that's the recipe for the movie. The premise is about two brothers, one just out of Joliet prison, who try to raise money to save an orphanage from closing down, and to do so, bring together the members of their old band. Of course, their efforts to do so end up causing trouble with the law, as well as other people (such as a country and western-themed bar and the band that was supposed to play there). In the end, dozens of police cars chase after them, and even the National Guard, before they fulfill their quest. There are some genuinely funny parts, but overall the whole movie depends on exaggeration-twenty police cars crashing into twenty police cars, as critic Roger Ebert had put it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Hilarious Musical Comedy! Belushi And Aykroyd Are Great!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Humphrey Fish
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Jake Blues, just out from prison, puts together his old band to save the Catholic home where he and brother Elwood were raised. The Blues Brothers is arguably the funniest movie of 1980, it is a comedy masterpiece, it's a hilarious musical comedy film! This movie provides a ton of things that help make it great, for one thing, it gives the viewers a lot of hilarious performances from the cast, it gives the viewers a lot of very hysterical scenes and gags, and lastly, it gives the viewers a lot of enjoyment with a lot of very great music! I saw this movie, and I certainly had a great time watching it, it is like an amusement park there are a lot of huge laughs everywhere, such as the car chase through the mall, and the scene where The Blues Brothers are getting hit by the nun repeatedly with a yardstick, not to mention the part where they pose as the Good Ol' Boys. The movie has a lot more hysterical scenes, but I won't name them, as it would most likely spoil the movie, and I don't want to do that. But anyway, as far as comedy movies go, The Blues Brothers is a movie that's as hysterical as they come! Dan Aykroyd and John Belushi are great together, they were perfect for the roles of Elwood And Jake Blues respectively. While Aykroyd would later go on to achieve further greatness, Belushi's career was cut short, as he died from an accidental drug overdose at the young age of 33, sad. If Belushi and Aykroyd don't do the trick, then perhaps the supporting cast will. We've got a lot of real life blues musicians in this movie, such as Cab Calloway, Aretha Franklin, Ray Charles, and James Brown, and what a great lineup that is! The movie has tons to recommend, for one thing, the fact that it's a hilarious movie, another thing is the acting in the movie, as well as the all-star cast of actors. But the two best people in this movie are (and you might have guessed it) Dan Aykroyd and John Belushi, they were outstanding together, not only where they great with their acting, but they were also superb at singing and dancing! The Blues Brothers is a comedy movie that will last, it's will forever remain one of the funniest movies ever made for years and years to come. Here is something that I have to tell you, you're on a mission from God, and that mission is to watch this movie. Really, you've got to watch it, you won't regret it, it really is as hysterical as everyone says it is, and when you watch it, you will perfectly see what I mean. Before I continue, let me say this. I know that I may sound like I'm repeating myself, but sorry if I am, because what I am saying is true, this movie is a comic gem! So if you want to see a great movie with a lot of great acting, music, excitement, and dancing, then don't worry about that, because The Blues Brothers is a movie that contains all of these things! So step into the Bluesmobile with Jake and Elwood Blues and get ready for an awesome musical comedy adventure that you will absolutely love, that's the 1980 masterpiece, The Blues Brothers! 10/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    R.I.P John Belushi
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    omar wasief
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/9/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Blues Brothers' is a bit of both, lending exposure to rhythm and blues legends who might otherwise have faded into silence while at the same time treating black culture as a colorful pantomime backdrop for the antics of two white comedians. That Dan Aykroyd and John Belushi adore this music is not in question  it's lovingly chosen and brilliantly performed  but the film sometimes feels like a work of cultural tourism, particularly in scenes set in a gospel church and a Chicago street market. These lively musical sequences also sit awkwardly with director John Landis's bizarre predilection for wholesale destruction: sure, smashing up cop cars can be fun, but Landis takes things to a tiresome extreme. Still, the film retains a huge nostalgic kick, thanks in large part to Aykroyd and Belushi's easy rapport, a smattering of daft, shaggy humor and some truly iconic musical sequences.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Film That Gets Better And Better, The More You Watch It!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    SebMModernsII
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    What more can I say about a movie that has outstanding car chases and jazzy blues music being fantastic?! It is! Some strong language is present, don't show it to your children (Even if they can't help but love it!) Two brothers (Played By John Belushi And Dan Aykroyd) are reunited after one brother "Jake Blues" is released from prison. They are on the run from The Police! (There are a lot of police in this film!) and on the way, they try to make money with their music to help keep The Church open. There is a lot of great music in this film, there is even a singing of Robert Johnson's "Sweet Home Chicago!" The film ends with The Blues Brothers entertaining the prisoners with their hit Rock'N Roll dance song "Let's Rock!" and The End Credits involves a reprise of their best songs! A must see, if you haven't yet watched it! Overall Rating: 10/10!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Pretty damn funny
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Terrell Howell (KnightsofNi11)
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Back in the 70's John Belushi and Dan Akroyd introduced the characters of Jake and Elwood Blues on the ever popular Saturday Night Live. In 1980 legendary director John Landis gave the characters their own feature length film. The Blues Brothers stars Belushi and Akroyd as Jake and Elwood, respectively, and it follows them as they attempt to put their old band back together in order to raise money to save the Catholic orphanage home where they were raised. Dubbing this quest a mission from God the two set out on a wacky and action packed adventure full of screwball situations and nut job characters. What ensues is a lot of fun. The Blues Brothers is one of those essential 80's comedies. It's worked its way to earning the status of a classic and so these days, no matter how you feel about comedies, it's just one of those that you have to see. It's also one of the very few successful films to be made out of SNL characters, and that's always a treat to watch, especially if you know the characters from the TV show. Seeing them come to life in a whole new way through the big screen is something really exciting to witness. And with characters as classic as Jake and Elwood Blues, played by their original actors, the ingenious Dan Akroyd and John Belushi, it had to have been a nostalgic experience for 1980 audiences. I didn't get as much of this, however. I know the characters for how iconic they are today and I've seen some of the Blues Brothers SNL skits, but I can't say this movie had the same effect for me as it would have had for audiences back in the day excited to see their favorite SNL characters put on the big screen. As far as this just being a good movie, it's funny and that's about it. I definitely enjoyed watching this flick, but it's not much more than just a silly over-the-top comedy. The only thing that makes it better than a lot of the other screwball comedies like it would be it's great actors and the legendary status behind the characters. All in all, The Blues Brothers is just a lot of hilarious wackiness with some crazy song and dance numbers thrown in throughout. It's a lot of fun in a weird, explosive, irreverent way.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Even the Vatican recommends it!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Suzanne Sellers
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Just saw this film again for the 20th or so time. Love every scene, but I think my favorite is where they go to visit "The Penguin" (nun) and they mange to offend her with their profanity. She tears them a new one as they fall down the stairs in their little kiddie desks. Its hilarious physical comedy. This film takes me back to a great time in my life which, by comparison, seems so much better entertainment-wise. Things were so much simpler then. As everyone has mentioned, the music is great. So many greats who have passed on now - the great blues and R&B groups, John Lee Hooker, James Brown, Ray Charles, Belushi, John Candy and so many others. Belushi and Akroyd are hilarious in different ways, but play off each other beautifully. I can't believe this movie isn't a 10/10. Its a cult film and will live forever.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Some Flaws but Overall Entertaining
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Michael_Elliott
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Blues Brothers (1980) *** (out of 4) Madhouse from John Landis has Jake and Elwood Blues (John Belushi, Dan Aykroyd) getting their band back together so that they can raise $5,000 to save their orphanage where they were raised. At first it seems like raising the cash will be easy but the brothers soon have Nazies, cops, angry cowboys and others chasing them through Chicago. THE BLUES BROTHERS is one of the most entertaining bad movies I've ever seen. There's so many great things in this movie but at the same time there are so many things that bothered me and kept me from enjoying the picture even more. We'll start with the bad and I'd say it's obvious that there's no story here. Instead of an actual story we just get non-stop music scenes as well as car crashes, two things that actually work in the movie but the extended running time is just way too long and I was constantly looking at the watch to see how much longer there was. The lack of any real story and the extended running time are certainly the two things that keep this from being better because outside of this there's quite a bit to enjoy here. The best thing is the fact that Landis pretty much throws everything out the window and right at the viewer. This includes some of the craziest, most over-the-top chase/wreck scenes that you're ever going to witness. There are many throughout the picture but for me the highlight would have to be the one inside the mall where everything in sight gets destroyed at least twice. Another good thing the film has going for it are some of the musical performances especially the ones dealing with Ray Charles, Cab Calloway, Aretha Franklin and John Lee Hooker. Then, of course, you've got Belushi and Aykroyd turning in great performances as the Blue Brothers. You can't help but feel like you're watching real brothers doing real blues. THE BLUES BROTHERS is far from perfect but there's still enough here that makes it worth viewing.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of the greatest comedy's
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Sean Rajnert (Newsgeek13@gmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Blues Brohers, what can i say... it's a comedy. an action movie maybe even a parody. The plot is (NO Spoilers) Jake Blues, a man released from a correctional center, meets up with his brother Elwood. The blues brothers are a band and they have to get the band back together to raise $5,000 for their catholic home. What makes this movie so great is the humor, there's things people do for no reason, their chased by everyone, and by the middle of the movie. You believe this is a normal day for the two. I only have one problem with the movie, it does tend to feel a little longer than it is, but the comedy and the music make up for it. I give this movie a 3 & 1/2 stars out of four. A great movie everybody should check out. (Well, at least wait for your kid to be 14 years of age)
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A great musical for people who don't like musicals!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Tweekums
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    As the film opens we see Jake Blues being released from prison and picked up by his brother Elwood; they head to the orphanage where they were raised and learn that the place will me closed down of somebody doesn't pay the $5000 tax demand in the next few days. Soon The Blues Brothers are on a mission from God to save the orphanage. To do this Jake wants to get their old band back together but it won't be easy as the members have all got on with their lives while he was in jail. Even once they have got the band back together it will be hard to earn that sort of money at short notice and that isn't mentioning the fact that they are wanted by the police, the local Nazis and a mysterious woman who is determined to kill Jake! It is safe to say that by the time they pay the $5000 considerably more damage will have been none! The opening scene might make one think this was going to be a fairly slow movie but once Jake is out of prison it isn't long before the laughter and mayhem begin and there is a lot of both. The action is over the top and utterly hilarious with countless cop cars, shop windows and even entire buildings being destroyed. This mayhem is regularly interrupted by musical interludes by the likes of James Brown, Aretha Franklin, Ray Charles and Cab Callaway. These songs are frequently accompanied by entertaining dance routines. As well as lots of well known singers there are also quite a few other well known people in cameo roles; the best being Carrie Fisher who plays the woman trying to kill Jake; I loved how it isn't explained why she is doing it till nearly the end. John Belushi and Dan Aykroyd are great as Jake and Elwood; two characters who almost never remove their sunglasses; even at night. I'd heartily recommend this to anybody wanting a good laugh; don't worry if you don't usually like musicals; this one is great!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Over Produced and Overrated
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    leonlouisricci
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Way over produced and exaggerated, this overrated Movie has a number or funny bits and some bouncy Music, some of it by real Soul and R&B greats, but it is also filled with so many car crashes that it wrecks the momentum. There could easily be 45 minutes cut in the form of unnecessary big budget, obligatory scenes and this would be a more enjoyable Musical/Comedy. As it is, there is so much that is disjointed and destructive that it literally collapses onto itself with over indulgence and unrestrained tomfoolery. Worth a view for the better parts, but be prepared to endure endless repetition, mostly of the vehicular nature. Aykroyd and Belushi were naturals on SNL and other projects, but this big production didn't do them any favors in the creative department because they were buried in so much rubble.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Overblown
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bigverybadtom
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie is a landmark-it was responsible for Chicago becoming the setting for a number of future movies. On its own, it is based on a Saturday Night Live sketch about two white characters with pretensions of being blues musicians. Add a number of major real-life blues musicians and an even larger number of car crashes, and that's the recipe for the movie. The premise is about two brothers, one just out of Joliet prison, who try to raise money to save an orphanage from closing down, and to do so, bring together the members of their old band. Of course, their efforts to do so end up causing trouble with the law, as well as other people (such as a country and western-themed bar and the band that was supposed to play there). In the end, dozens of police cars chase after them, and even the National Guard, before they fulfill their quest. There are some genuinely funny parts, but overall the whole movie depends on exaggeration-twenty police cars crashing into twenty police cars, as critic Roger Ebert had put it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Hilarious Musical Comedy! Belushi And Aykroyd Are Great!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Humphrey Fish
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Jake Blues, just out from prison, puts together his old band to save the Catholic home where he and brother Elwood were raised. The Blues Brothers is arguably the funniest movie of 1980, it is a comedy masterpiece, it's a hilarious musical comedy film! This movie provides a ton of things that help make it great, for one thing, it gives the viewers a lot of hilarious performances from the cast, it gives the viewers a lot of very hysterical scenes and gags, and lastly, it gives the viewers a lot of enjoyment with a lot of very great music! I saw this movie, and I certainly had a great time watching it, it is like an amusement park there are a lot of huge laughs everywhere, such as the car chase through the mall, and the scene where The Blues Brothers are getting hit by the nun repeatedly with a yardstick, not to mention the part where they pose as the Good Ol' Boys. The movie has a lot more hysterical scenes, but I won't name them, as it would most likely spoil the movie, and I don't want to do that. But anyway, as far as comedy movies go, The Blues Brothers is a movie that's as hysterical as they come! Dan Aykroyd and John Belushi are great together, they were perfect for the roles of Elwood And Jake Blues respectively. While Aykroyd would later go on to achieve further greatness, Belushi's career was cut short, as he died from an accidental drug overdose at the young age of 33, sad. If Belushi and Aykroyd don't do the trick, then perhaps the supporting cast will. We've got a lot of real life blues musicians in this movie, such as Cab Calloway, Aretha Franklin, Ray Charles, and James Brown, and what a great lineup that is! The movie has tons to recommend, for one thing, the fact that it's a hilarious movie, another thing is the acting in the movie, as well as the all-star cast of actors. But the two best people in this movie are (and you might have guessed it) Dan Aykroyd and John Belushi, they were outstanding together, not only where they great with their acting, but they were also superb at singing and dancing! The Blues Brothers is a comedy movie that will last, it's will forever remain one of the funniest movies ever made for years and years to come. Here is something that I have to tell you, you're on a mission from God, and that mission is to watch this movie. Really, you've got to watch it, you won't regret it, it really is as hysterical as everyone says it is, and when you watch it, you will perfectly see what I mean. Before I continue, let me say this. I know that I may sound like I'm repeating myself, but sorry if I am, because what I am saying is true, this movie is a comic gem! So if you want to see a great movie with a lot of great acting, music, excitement, and dancing, then don't worry about that, because The Blues Brothers is a movie that contains all of these things! So step into the Bluesmobile with Jake and Elwood Blues and get ready for an awesome musical comedy adventure that you will absolutely love, that's the 1980 masterpiece, The Blues Brothers! 10/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    R.I.P John Belushi
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    omar wasief
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/9/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Blues Brothers' is a bit of both, lending exposure to rhythm and blues legends who might otherwise have faded into silence while at the same time treating black culture as a colorful pantomime backdrop for the antics of two white comedians. That Dan Aykroyd and John Belushi adore this music is not in question  it's lovingly chosen and brilliantly performed  but the film sometimes feels like a work of cultural tourism, particularly in scenes set in a gospel church and a Chicago street market. These lively musical sequences also sit awkwardly with director John Landis's bizarre predilection for wholesale destruction: sure, smashing up cop cars can be fun, but Landis takes things to a tiresome extreme. Still, the film retains a huge nostalgic kick, thanks in large part to Aykroyd and Belushi's easy rapport, a smattering of daft, shaggy humor and some truly iconic musical sequences.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Film That Gets Better And Better, The More You Watch It!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    SebMModernsII
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    What more can I say about a movie that has outstanding car chases and jazzy blues music being fantastic?! It is! Some strong language is present, don't show it to your children (Even if they can't help but love it!) Two brothers (Played By John Belushi And Dan Aykroyd) are reunited after one brother "Jake Blues" is released from prison. They are on the run from The Police! (There are a lot of police in this film!) and on the way, they try to make money with their music to help keep The Church open. There is a lot of great music in this film, there is even a singing of Robert Johnson's "Sweet Home Chicago!" The film ends with The Blues Brothers entertaining the prisoners with their hit Rock'N Roll dance song "Let's Rock!" and The End Credits involves a reprise of their best songs! A must see, if you haven't yet watched it! Overall Rating: 10/10!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Pretty damn funny
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Terrell Howell (KnightsofNi11)
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Back in the 70's John Belushi and Dan Akroyd introduced the characters of Jake and Elwood Blues on the ever popular Saturday Night Live. In 1980 legendary director John Landis gave the characters their own feature length film. The Blues Brothers stars Belushi and Akroyd as Jake and Elwood, respectively, and it follows them as they attempt to put their old band back together in order to raise money to save the Catholic orphanage home where they were raised. Dubbing this quest a mission from God the two set out on a wacky and action packed adventure full of screwball situations and nut job characters. What ensues is a lot of fun. The Blues Brothers is one of those essential 80's comedies. It's worked its way to earning the status of a classic and so these days, no matter how you feel about comedies, it's just one of those that you have to see. It's also one of the very few successful films to be made out of SNL characters, and that's always a treat to watch, especially if you know the characters from the TV show. Seeing them come to life in a whole new way through the big screen is something really exciting to witness. And with characters as classic as Jake and Elwood Blues, played by their original actors, the ingenious Dan Akroyd and John Belushi, it had to have been a nostalgic experience for 1980 audiences. I didn't get as much of this, however. I know the characters for how iconic they are today and I've seen some of the Blues Brothers SNL skits, but I can't say this movie had the same effect for me as it would have had for audiences back in the day excited to see their favorite SNL characters put on the big screen. As far as this just being a good movie, it's funny and that's about it. I definitely enjoyed watching this flick, but it's not much more than just a silly over-the-top comedy. The only thing that makes it better than a lot of the other screwball comedies like it would be it's great actors and the legendary status behind the characters. All in all, The Blues Brothers is just a lot of hilarious wackiness with some crazy song and dance numbers thrown in throughout. It's a lot of fun in a weird, explosive, irreverent way.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Even the Vatican recommends it!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Suzanne Sellers
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Just saw this film again for the 20th or so time. Love every scene, but I think my favorite is where they go to visit "The Penguin" (nun) and they mange to offend her with their profanity. She tears them a new one as they fall down the stairs in their little kiddie desks. Its hilarious physical comedy. This film takes me back to a great time in my life which, by comparison, seems so much better entertainment-wise. Things were so much simpler then. As everyone has mentioned, the music is great. So many greats who have passed on now - the great blues and R&B groups, John Lee Hooker, James Brown, Ray Charles, Belushi, John Candy and so many others. Belushi and Akroyd are hilarious in different ways, but play off each other beautifully. I can't believe this movie isn't a 10/10. Its a cult film and will live forever.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Some Flaws but Overall Entertaining
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Michael_Elliott
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Blues Brothers (1980) *** (out of 4) Madhouse from John Landis has Jake and Elwood Blues (John Belushi, Dan Aykroyd) getting their band back together so that they can raise $5,000 to save their orphanage where they were raised. At first it seems like raising the cash will be easy but the brothers soon have Nazies, cops, angry cowboys and others chasing them through Chicago. THE BLUES BROTHERS is one of the most entertaining bad movies I've ever seen. There's so many great things in this movie but at the same time there are so many things that bothered me and kept me from enjoying the picture even more. We'll start with the bad and I'd say it's obvious that there's no story here. Instead of an actual story we just get non-stop music scenes as well as car crashes, two things that actually work in the movie but the extended running time is just way too long and I was constantly looking at the watch to see how much longer there was. The lack of any real story and the extended running time are certainly the two things that keep this from being better because outside of this there's quite a bit to enjoy here. The best thing is the fact that Landis pretty much throws everything out the window and right at the viewer. This includes some of the craziest, most over-the-top chase/wreck scenes that you're ever going to witness. There are many throughout the picture but for me the highlight would have to be the one inside the mall where everything in sight gets destroyed at least twice. Another good thing the film has going for it are some of the musical performances especially the ones dealing with Ray Charles, Cab Calloway, Aretha Franklin and John Lee Hooker. Then, of course, you've got Belushi and Aykroyd turning in great performances as the Blue Brothers. You can't help but feel like you're watching real brothers doing real blues. THE BLUES BROTHERS is far from perfect but there's still enough here that makes it worth viewing.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of the greatest comedy's
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Sean Rajnert (Newsgeek13@gmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Blues Brohers, what can i say... it's a comedy. an action movie maybe even a parody. The plot is (NO Spoilers) Jake Blues, a man released from a correctional center, meets up with his brother Elwood. The blues brothers are a band and they have to get the band back together to raise $5,000 for their catholic home. What makes this movie so great is the humor, there's things people do for no reason, their chased by everyone, and by the middle of the movie. You believe this is a normal day for the two. I only have one problem with the movie, it does tend to feel a little longer than it is, but the comedy and the music make up for it. I give this movie a 3 & 1/2 stars out of four. A great movie everybody should check out. (Well, at least wait for your kid to be 14 years of age)
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A great musical for people who don't like musicals!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Tweekums
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    As the film opens we see Jake Blues being released from prison and picked up by his brother Elwood; they head to the orphanage where they were raised and learn that the place will me closed down of somebody doesn't pay the $5000 tax demand in the next few days. Soon The Blues Brothers are on a mission from God to save the orphanage. To do this Jake wants to get their old band back together but it won't be easy as the members have all got on with their lives while he was in jail. Even once they have got the band back together it will be hard to earn that sort of money at short notice and that isn't mentioning the fact that they are wanted by the police, the local Nazis and a mysterious woman who is determined to kill Jake! It is safe to say that by the time they pay the $5000 considerably more damage will have been none! The opening scene might make one think this was going to be a fairly slow movie but once Jake is out of prison it isn't long before the laughter and mayhem begin and there is a lot of both. The action is over the top and utterly hilarious with countless cop cars, shop windows and even entire buildings being destroyed. This mayhem is regularly interrupted by musical interludes by the likes of James Brown, Aretha Franklin, Ray Charles and Cab Callaway. These songs are frequently accompanied by entertaining dance routines. As well as lots of well known singers there are also quite a few other well known people in cameo roles; the best being Carrie Fisher who plays the woman trying to kill Jake; I loved how it isn't explained why she is doing it till nearly the end. John Belushi and Dan Aykroyd are great as Jake and Elwood; two characters who almost never remove their sunglasses; even at night. I'd heartily recommend this to anybody wanting a good laugh; don't worry if you don't usually like musicals; this one is great!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Over Produced and Overrated
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    leonlouisricci
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Way over produced and exaggerated, this overrated Movie has a number or funny bits and some bouncy Music, some of it by real Soul and R&B greats, but it is also filled with so many car crashes that it wrecks the momentum. There could easily be 45 minutes cut in the form of unnecessary big budget, obligatory scenes and this would be a more enjoyable Musical/Comedy. As it is, there is so much that is disjointed and destructive that it literally collapses onto itself with over indulgence and unrestrained tomfoolery. Worth a view for the better parts, but be prepared to endure endless repetition, mostly of the vehicular nature. Aykroyd and Belushi were naturals on SNL and other projects, but this big production didn't do them any favors in the creative department because they were buried in so much rubble.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Overblown
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bigverybadtom
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie is a landmark-it was responsible for Chicago becoming the setting for a number of future movies. On its own, it is based on a Saturday Night Live sketch about two white characters with pretensions of being blues musicians. Add a number of major real-life blues musicians and an even larger number of car crashes, and that's the recipe for the movie. The premise is about two brothers, one just out of Joliet prison, who try to raise money to save an orphanage from closing down, and to do so, bring together the members of their old band. Of course, their efforts to do so end up causing trouble with the law, as well as other people (such as a country and western-themed bar and the band that was supposed to play there). In the end, dozens of police cars chase after them, and even the National Guard, before they fulfill their quest. There are some genuinely funny parts, but overall the whole movie depends on exaggeration-twenty police cars crashing into twenty police cars, as critic Roger Ebert had put it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Hilarious Musical Comedy! Belushi And Aykroyd Are Great!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Humphrey Fish
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Jake Blues, just out from prison, puts together his old band to save the Catholic home where he and brother Elwood were raised. The Blues Brothers is arguably the funniest movie of 1980, it is a comedy masterpiece, it's a hilarious musical comedy film! This movie provides a ton of things that help make it great, for one thing, it gives the viewers a lot of hilarious performances from the cast, it gives the viewers a lot of very hysterical scenes and gags, and lastly, it gives the viewers a lot of enjoyment with a lot of very great music! I saw this movie, and I certainly had a great time watching it, it is like an amusement park there are a lot of huge laughs everywhere, such as the car chase through the mall, and the scene where The Blues Brothers are getting hit by the nun repeatedly with a yardstick, not to mention the part where they pose as the Good Ol' Boys. The movie has a lot more hysterical scenes, but I won't name them, as it would most likely spoil the movie, and I don't want to do that. But anyway, as far as comedy movies go, The Blues Brothers is a movie that's as hysterical as they come! Dan Aykroyd and John Belushi are great together, they were perfect for the roles of Elwood And Jake Blues respectively. While Aykroyd would later go on to achieve further greatness, Belushi's career was cut short, as he died from an accidental drug overdose at the young age of 33, sad. If Belushi and Aykroyd don't do the trick, then perhaps the supporting cast will. We've got a lot of real life blues musicians in this movie, such as Cab Calloway, Aretha Franklin, Ray Charles, and James Brown, and what a great lineup that is! The movie has tons to recommend, for one thing, the fact that it's a hilarious movie, another thing is the acting in the movie, as well as the all-star cast of actors. But the two best people in this movie are (and you might have guessed it) Dan Aykroyd and John Belushi, they were outstanding together, not only where they great with their acting, but they were also superb at singing and dancing! The Blues Brothers is a comedy movie that will last, it's will forever remain one of the funniest movies ever made for years and years to come. Here is something that I have to tell you, you're on a mission from God, and that mission is to watch this movie. Really, you've got to watch it, you won't regret it, it really is as hysterical as everyone says it is, and when you watch it, you will perfectly see what I mean. Before I continue, let me say this. I know that I may sound like I'm repeating myself, but sorry if I am, because what I am saying is true, this movie is a comic gem! So if you want to see a great movie with a lot of great acting, music, excitement, and dancing, then don't worry about that, because The Blues Brothers is a movie that contains all of these things! So step into the Bluesmobile with Jake and Elwood Blues and get ready for an awesome musical comedy adventure that you will absolutely love, that's the 1980 masterpiece, The Blues Brothers! 10/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    R.I.P John Belushi
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    omar wasief
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/9/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Blues Brothers' is a bit of both, lending exposure to rhythm and blues legends who might otherwise have faded into silence while at the same time treating black culture as a colorful pantomime backdrop for the antics of two white comedians. That Dan Aykroyd and John Belushi adore this music is not in question  it's lovingly chosen and brilliantly performed  but the film sometimes feels like a work of cultural tourism, particularly in scenes set in a gospel church and a Chicago street market. These lively musical sequences also sit awkwardly with director John Landis's bizarre predilection for wholesale destruction: sure, smashing up cop cars can be fun, but Landis takes things to a tiresome extreme. Still, the film retains a huge nostalgic kick, thanks in large part to Aykroyd and Belushi's easy rapport, a smattering of daft, shaggy humor and some truly iconic musical sequences.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Film That Gets Better And Better, The More You Watch It!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    SebMModernsII
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    What more can I say about a movie that has outstanding car chases and jazzy blues music being fantastic?! It is! Some strong language is present, don't show it to your children (Even if they can't help but love it!) Two brothers (Played By John Belushi And Dan Aykroyd) are reunited after one brother "Jake Blues" is released from prison. They are on the run from The Police! (There are a lot of police in this film!) and on the way, they try to make money with their music to help keep The Church open. There is a lot of great music in this film, there is even a singing of Robert Johnson's "Sweet Home Chicago!" The film ends with The Blues Brothers entertaining the prisoners with their hit Rock'N Roll dance song "Let's Rock!" and The End Credits involves a reprise of their best songs! A must see, if you haven't yet watched it! Overall Rating: 10/10!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Pretty damn funny
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Terrell Howell (KnightsofNi11)
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Back in the 70's John Belushi and Dan Akroyd introduced the characters of Jake and Elwood Blues on the ever popular Saturday Night Live. In 1980 legendary director John Landis gave the characters their own feature length film. The Blues Brothers stars Belushi and Akroyd as Jake and Elwood, respectively, and it follows them as they attempt to put their old band back together in order to raise money to save the Catholic orphanage home where they were raised. Dubbing this quest a mission from God the two set out on a wacky and action packed adventure full of screwball situations and nut job characters. What ensues is a lot of fun. The Blues Brothers is one of those essential 80's comedies. It's worked its way to earning the status of a classic and so these days, no matter how you feel about comedies, it's just one of those that you have to see. It's also one of the very few successful films to be made out of SNL characters, and that's always a treat to watch, especially if you know the characters from the TV show. Seeing them come to life in a whole new way through the big screen is something really exciting to witness. And with characters as classic as Jake and Elwood Blues, played by their original actors, the ingenious Dan Akroyd and John Belushi, it had to have been a nostalgic experience for 1980 audiences. I didn't get as much of this, however. I know the characters for how iconic they are today and I've seen some of the Blues Brothers SNL skits, but I can't say this movie had the same effect for me as it would have had for audiences back in the day excited to see their favorite SNL characters put on the big screen. As far as this just being a good movie, it's funny and that's about it. I definitely enjoyed watching this flick, but it's not much more than just a silly over-the-top comedy. The only thing that makes it better than a lot of the other screwball comedies like it would be it's great actors and the legendary status behind the characters. All in all, The Blues Brothers is just a lot of hilarious wackiness with some crazy song and dance numbers thrown in throughout. It's a lot of fun in a weird, explosive, irreverent way.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
 </reviews>
</filme>
