<filme>
 <id>
  188
 </id>
 <imdburl>
  http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0093058
 </imdburl>
 <ano>
  1987
 </ano>
 <titulo>
  Nascido Para Matar
 </titulo>
 <rating>
  8.4
 </rating>
 <sinopse>
  A pragmatic U.S. Marine observes the dehumanizing effects the Vietnam War has on his fellow Marine recruits from their brutal boot camp training to the bloody street fighting set in 1968 in Hue, Vietnam.
 </sinopse>
 <storyline>
  A two-segment look at the effect of the military mindset and war itself on Vietnam era Marines. The first half follows a group of recruits in boot camp under the command of the punishing Gunnery Sergeant Hartman. The second half shows one of those recruits, Joker, covering the war as a correspondent for Stars and Stripes, focusing on the Tet offensive.
 </storyline>
 <generos>
  <genero>
   Drama
  </genero>
  <genero>
   War
  </genero>
 </generos>
 <keywords>
  <keyword>
   vietnam
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   recruit
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   sergeant
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   training
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   tet offensive
  </keyword>
 </keywords>
 <diretores>
  <diretor>
   Stanley Kubrick
  </diretor>
 </diretores>
 <escritores>
  <escritor>
   Gustav Hasford
  </escritor>
  <escritor>
   Stanley Kubrick
  </escritor>
 </escritores>
 <atores>
  <ator>
   Matthew Modine
  </ator>
  <ator>
   R. Lee Ermey
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Vincent D'Onofrio
  </ator>
 </atores>
 <reviews>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    R. Lee Ermey.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    AaronCapenBanner
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    R. Lee Ermey dominates this Stanley Kubrick directed Vietnam War drama, as he plays profane, no-nonsense, ultra tough Gunnery Sergeant Hartman, who belittles, browbeats, and insults the marine recruits in brutal boot camp training. Vincent D'Onofrio plays a slow-witted recruit who gets it the worst from Hartman, until he finds out that he is quite good at shooting... Mathew Modine plays "Joker", since he has an overt sense of humor that also captures the attention of Hartman, whose relentless, unmerciful verbal attacks take their toll in ways he didn't imagine... Film then picks up later, as Joker is a war correspondent for Stars & Stripes, who witnesses first hand the insanity of Vietnam... R. Lee Ermey so dominates the first half of the film(in an unforgettable, searing portrayal of dehumanization) that, when his part is over, it leaves a looming shadow over the rest of the film that is never lifted, though it is still a well-presented look at the war, though nothing exceptional. Worth watching for Ermey, who should have received an Academy Award!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A film of two halves
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tcr1991
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    'Full Metal Jacket' was a film that I had been meaning to watch for a while after all the good stuff I had heard about it. It really is a film of two halves, unfortunately I didn't like the 2nd half. The 1st half at boot camp was excellent, we saw a lot of character development and emotion as well as a lot of humour and really serious issues. R. Lee Ermey and Vincent D'Onofrio were just brilliant. The 2nd half I didn't enjoy as much, it looked great and there was a lot of action but it was just a bit boring and felt really dragged out, whereas the 1st part just had everything that you wanted. Glad I got round to seeing it but wouldn't watch it again, slightly disappointed after a really good start to the film. 6/10.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Bootcamp can be fun....Sometimes
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    A Stoners Review
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Really good movie. It's plot is mainly following a youngster through boot camp into the Vietnam war. The truth is throughout boot camp this movie is a gem. But once they go to war it kinda slows down a bit, and its not all that great towards the end, but don't get me wrong, it's still really good. I know I gave it an 8 but it's more like a 7.8 or something. All in all it's a hell of a movie. I say smoke a few bowls, relax and let this movie take you through the life a youngster during the days when boot camp really put you through some snit. If you haven't seen it, it is a must my friend. Peace out my fellow stoner's and may the weed take you away.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of my top ten
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    sraloff
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie is great. Great story, great acting and a lot of memorable scenes. You know a movie is good if you here quotes from it on a regular basis from people who probably don't even know where the saying came from (ie the younger generations). I love how it takes you from boot camp to the war and lets the viewer experience every aspect of the Vietnam war. It was a gritty time and the movie pulls no punches: if you are creating killing machines you have to be tough. Unlike todays army that is volunteer, most were there not by choice and the basic training scenes show the deconstruction of a boy and the construction of a soldier. The war scenes show these newly minted soldiers struggling to maintain their human element. We watch as the try and find balance between taking lives and knowing they will have to live theirs upon return. Many of these actors went on to play other great roles and I can't help but think it was due to their involvement with Full Metal Jacket.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    From boys to men to boys
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Marc Israel
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Events of dehumanization as learned scene by scene as coldly dictated by director Stanley Kubrick. Our Marines are always rallying around something white trying to hold onto their own values, themselves and, overall, their sanity. Much like "The Deer Hunter", this anti-war film is broken down into two parts, one prior to war, and then into the beast itself. While one movie shone an extra light on those stateside, Full Metal Jacket stayed with our boys and to what was left of themselves; their boyhood instincts (to defend each other) and their Mickey Mouse marches which drove the point home. This cold film doesn't bring you into each character as others might, but war is not about one person, is it? It is full of dogma (first to go, last to know), direction (our marines got lost) and dehumanization (see the first hour alone to hear the non-stop rant of Gunnery Seargent Hartman (Lee Ermey). Brutal and darkly funny, this is what I held onto as our narrator, Joker (Mathew Modine) is simply trying to fend off the brainwash, while it bounced off of Private Pyle (Vincent D'Onofrio) whose story tells us all Kubrick needed to say. That is why the second half of the film in Viet Nam seemed only to serve the audience a follow up and adventure as to what happened to some of our original boot camp marines. I still found the film both detached and personal, as if I was trying to fend off the disgracing of my viewers' soul. I like this film due to that internal struggle of whether or not to view war as acceptable.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not quite the full picture
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Prism10
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Stanley Kubrick, the eccentric director is lionised by Hollywood. A man who spent the latter part of his life living in London and shooting his films in England despite them being set elsewhere whether it was outer space, some hotel in the mountains of America or in this case a Vietnam war film. Full Metal Jacket arrived with plaudits from the critics. Its a film of two halves, the more interesting part being the first half set at boot camp with a sadistic drill instructor. The second half which is the more action based Vietnam set element is less interesting. Why? Because a year earlier we all watched 'Platoon' which swept the big prizes at the Oscars and directed by someone who served in Vietnam and fully conveyed the anti war message and politics of it all now that some years have passed by since the war ended. We saw Nam films before and better in Platoon and Apocalypse Now. Also these films although did not got to Vietnam, at least filmed in location whether it would be the Philippines or Thailand that is standing in. Full Metal Jacket was filmed in various parts of London dressed up as Vietnam. It shows, the sets do not look authentic, you do not get the feeling you are in the far east and it shows up the limitations of the second half of the story. It was too little and too late.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    War is not worth wasting our youth
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    StoryCharts
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Full Metal Jacket is about the idea that war is not worth wasting our youth. It tries to prove this with two stories: the first is the marines training for deployment, the second is the marines in action in Vietnam. The first story, the marines training for deployment, is told with two external plots: that of the not so bright marine Pyle trying to finish boot camp and the second is the entire class of marines trying to graduate. The class of marines succeed in graduating, but Pyle does not. He goes crazy after the harsh treatment meant to harden him to become a killer and commits suicide. So this story gets to the point that preparing for war is inhumane and not worth wasting our youth. The second story is about the marines fighting to win the war in Vietnam. This is told with two plots: that of winning the war and the second of the declining morality of the marines. The war is not won, it ends ambiguously as the marines win a small insignificant battle and return to camp while the morality of the marines shows a constant decline and ends with our hero committing murder. The movie is a great testament to the anti-war movement and a visual essay on the meaninglessness of war. But it is not a very engaging story. The first half of the movie makes a tight dramatic point that training marines to be killer has some inhumane consequences and proves it with Pyle's suicide. But the second half doesn't have an overall story arc to hang its hat on. The status of the main external plot of winning the war is left ambiguous. So the moral decline of our hero who has to commit murder at the end doesn't create as much meaning since the murder doesn't get us any further in winning the war. One can argue that that's the point of the movie, is that these atrocities are senseless and meaningless. And that is true. But in terms of a dramatic story, the meaning of the action is lost because the filmmakers abhorred making winning the war into any resemblance of a real plot. In the first half of the movie, Pyle's suicide is juxtaposed with the success of class of marines all graduating. Thus it makes the point that his suicide is not worth it for us to successfully train marines. But in the second half of the movie, Joker commits murder but this action is not juxtaposed with progression of any other plot. So the action loses the chance to create meaning through a consequence for his actions. It feels like the movie was cut off without any real resolution, like another 15 minutes were missing. My Story Chart of the movie is at storycharts.ca
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An outstanding and unique war movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    axel-koch
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    In 1987, 30 years after he'd firstly dealt with the subject of war in Paths of Glory, legendary American auteur Stanley Kubrick returned to the award-promising genre and released Full Metal Jacket. While it neither got the praise nor the awards it deserved when it came out, it has since then become a fan favorite and one of Kubrick's most beloved movies. Full Metal Jacket is split in two cohesive parts: the first and shorter one setting place at a military boot camp in South Carolina and the second one depicting the actual war events in Vietnam. The audience's relationship to the characters is supposed to be very distant and Kubrick lets us know very little about them. The narrator, nicknamed Joker, is a spectacled young man that believes to see through the military indoctrination. He tries to resist the system and, as he says himself, is only here to be the first kid on his block to get a confirmed kill. This is, of course, highly unconventional for a war movie protagonist and Matthew Modine plays him in a realistic, yet not particularly likable manner. Vincent D'Onofrio portrays the burly and universally untalented Private "Gomer Pyle", who gets permanently insulted and degraded by the vulgar and loud Drill Sergeant Hartman, who is played extraordinarily well by R. Lee Ermey, who was a real-life Drill Sergeant some time before. His eloquent and absolutely R-rated speeches are hilarious and simply the best part of the movie. It's sad somewhat, that his character doesn't accompany the recruits in the Vietnam War that follows; at some parts, I really wished for awesome one-liners like " I bet you're the kind of guy that would f*** a person in the a** and not even have the goddamn common courtesy to give him a reach-around!" But let's not be too harsh: the second part, if remarkably more serious, is again entertaining and because of the excellently crafted war scenes utterly gripping. Typically for a Kubrick film, Full Metal Jacket has a lot of ongoing themes and motifs in it that you may not even recognize when watching it for the first time. He's dealing with sexuality and not only in the two scenes in which Vietnamese hookers appear. The recruits have an absurd relationship with their rifle - especially D'Onofrio's character - and in the film's second part the killing scenes seem to bring an orgasmic feeling to the soldiers. Furthermore, you can probably correctly interpret religious imagery as well as father-mother-child themes into the movie - the minute director Stanley Kubrick is likely to have intended all of them. But you don't even need to think about the film in such a 'sophisticated' way, Mr. K shows a great game with the war scenes already. There may not be as many as in genre classics Apocalypse Now or Platoon and, admittedly, they don't have the aesthetic greatness that the ones in the aforementioned Coppola flick had. However, what Full Metal Jacket has is an authenticity that is even more impressive if you are aware that the Vietnam scenes where in fact shot in a disused gas work in the vicinity of London. Kubrick made the most out of it and also did terrific work with the sound and the editing which is impeccable. Because Kubrick wanted to make the recruits as one multi-persona character, there isn't as much to find out about the individual characters as some people may have wished for. Yet still, there is a very interesting and often only subliminal character study on the protagonist, Private Joker. Most of all, while Full Metal Jacket has the same view on war as the majority of other war films (even though the movie's protagonist is a war advocate, Kubrick himself is, of course, against war - I hope you noticed that), it shows us something new. A partly documentary and partly alarming new take that could have been boring. Thanks to Kubrick, it's not. At least not at the first time watching it - the prolonged war scenes lose their thrill once you know what's going to happen.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Let's talk about the source material
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jackhammer111
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The movie is well reviewed by others and most people find it very compelling. I like it to but am bothered by some shifts in tone in the final third although I think Kubrick deserves credit for not dodging the issue of atrocities. I prefer war movies that don't glorify war more as in "Platoon" or the great German U-Boat film "Das Boot" (see it in German with English subtitles, when they overdubbed it in English they wrecked a great background soundtrack). All in all there's a bit too much flag waving in this for me but it's a great movie but I can help remembering that part of the promotion for "Full Metal Jacket" including displaying the novel that served as source material for it in supermarket checkout lanes. Seeing Kubrick's name on it I picked it up. The novel was called "the Short Timers" written by Marine Gustav Hasford who was in theater during 1968-69. The great prolific essayist, columnist, novelist, screen writer (including my favorite sci fi movie, "a Boy and his Dog") Harlan Ellison said of Short timers "It is one of the most amazing stretches of writing I've ever encountered." Even though I know this is a movie review, not a book review, I have to tell you the source for most of the movie was written largely in a different kind of English called jarhead lingo. It was very cool to read inspired sections that are prose written with those word. Unfortunately, way more people were interested in watching Kubrick's movie than reading the real deal, the book didn't sell well, his deal with Kubrick wasn't very good and Hasford died alone almost broke in a motel room in Greece of heart related diabetic problems. I don't know which is more heartbreaking. Hasford's early death or the fact that "the Short Timers" is out of print while people still buy Kubrick's movie and somebody gets paid. The book has now become a rather expensive collector's item selling online for between $15 and upwards of $400. If you Google the title and his name you'll find a link to a scribd page that will load the whole book like a pdf. But you can't save or download it without paying. But you can read it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The best Marine Corps Bootcamp movie ever!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    sftd1973
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is a great movie that really depicts the life of a recruit going through Marine Corps Recruit Training. It is so real and straight to the point. Even with the additional Hollywood input in the movie, it still displays that reality that recruits go through to become United States Marines. Skip to the Viet Nam half of the movie. The Tet Offensive was a great part of the history of the Viet Nam war and this movie captures that history in great detail. The scenes of the fighting in the city is unique because most Viet Nam movies only show the fighting in the jungles and the rice patties and villages. Stanley Kubrick outdid himself with this movie and R. Lee Ermey immortalized himself as the Senior Drill Instructor and as the Gunnery Sergeant that everyone will always think of when anyone mentions the Marine Corps. Mathew Modine was outside himself in this movie and played a character that is totally outside of his normal range of characters. I give him a 10 along with R. Lee Ermey a 10 as well.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    R. Lee Ermey.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    AaronCapenBanner
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    R. Lee Ermey dominates this Stanley Kubrick directed Vietnam War drama, as he plays profane, no-nonsense, ultra tough Gunnery Sergeant Hartman, who belittles, browbeats, and insults the marine recruits in brutal boot camp training. Vincent D'Onofrio plays a slow-witted recruit who gets it the worst from Hartman, until he finds out that he is quite good at shooting... Mathew Modine plays "Joker", since he has an overt sense of humor that also captures the attention of Hartman, whose relentless, unmerciful verbal attacks take their toll in ways he didn't imagine... Film then picks up later, as Joker is a war correspondent for Stars & Stripes, who witnesses first hand the insanity of Vietnam... R. Lee Ermey so dominates the first half of the film(in an unforgettable, searing portrayal of dehumanization) that, when his part is over, it leaves a looming shadow over the rest of the film that is never lifted, though it is still a well-presented look at the war, though nothing exceptional. Worth watching for Ermey, who should have received an Academy Award!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A film of two halves
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tcr1991
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    'Full Metal Jacket' was a film that I had been meaning to watch for a while after all the good stuff I had heard about it. It really is a film of two halves, unfortunately I didn't like the 2nd half. The 1st half at boot camp was excellent, we saw a lot of character development and emotion as well as a lot of humour and really serious issues. R. Lee Ermey and Vincent D'Onofrio were just brilliant. The 2nd half I didn't enjoy as much, it looked great and there was a lot of action but it was just a bit boring and felt really dragged out, whereas the 1st part just had everything that you wanted. Glad I got round to seeing it but wouldn't watch it again, slightly disappointed after a really good start to the film. 6/10.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Bootcamp can be fun....Sometimes
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    A Stoners Review
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Really good movie. It's plot is mainly following a youngster through boot camp into the Vietnam war. The truth is throughout boot camp this movie is a gem. But once they go to war it kinda slows down a bit, and its not all that great towards the end, but don't get me wrong, it's still really good. I know I gave it an 8 but it's more like a 7.8 or something. All in all it's a hell of a movie. I say smoke a few bowls, relax and let this movie take you through the life a youngster during the days when boot camp really put you through some snit. If you haven't seen it, it is a must my friend. Peace out my fellow stoner's and may the weed take you away.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of my top ten
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    sraloff
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie is great. Great story, great acting and a lot of memorable scenes. You know a movie is good if you here quotes from it on a regular basis from people who probably don't even know where the saying came from (ie the younger generations). I love how it takes you from boot camp to the war and lets the viewer experience every aspect of the Vietnam war. It was a gritty time and the movie pulls no punches: if you are creating killing machines you have to be tough. Unlike todays army that is volunteer, most were there not by choice and the basic training scenes show the deconstruction of a boy and the construction of a soldier. The war scenes show these newly minted soldiers struggling to maintain their human element. We watch as the try and find balance between taking lives and knowing they will have to live theirs upon return. Many of these actors went on to play other great roles and I can't help but think it was due to their involvement with Full Metal Jacket.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    From boys to men to boys
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Marc Israel
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Events of dehumanization as learned scene by scene as coldly dictated by director Stanley Kubrick. Our Marines are always rallying around something white trying to hold onto their own values, themselves and, overall, their sanity. Much like "The Deer Hunter", this anti-war film is broken down into two parts, one prior to war, and then into the beast itself. While one movie shone an extra light on those stateside, Full Metal Jacket stayed with our boys and to what was left of themselves; their boyhood instincts (to defend each other) and their Mickey Mouse marches which drove the point home. This cold film doesn't bring you into each character as others might, but war is not about one person, is it? It is full of dogma (first to go, last to know), direction (our marines got lost) and dehumanization (see the first hour alone to hear the non-stop rant of Gunnery Seargent Hartman (Lee Ermey). Brutal and darkly funny, this is what I held onto as our narrator, Joker (Mathew Modine) is simply trying to fend off the brainwash, while it bounced off of Private Pyle (Vincent D'Onofrio) whose story tells us all Kubrick needed to say. That is why the second half of the film in Viet Nam seemed only to serve the audience a follow up and adventure as to what happened to some of our original boot camp marines. I still found the film both detached and personal, as if I was trying to fend off the disgracing of my viewers' soul. I like this film due to that internal struggle of whether or not to view war as acceptable.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not quite the full picture
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Prism10
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Stanley Kubrick, the eccentric director is lionised by Hollywood. A man who spent the latter part of his life living in London and shooting his films in England despite them being set elsewhere whether it was outer space, some hotel in the mountains of America or in this case a Vietnam war film. Full Metal Jacket arrived with plaudits from the critics. Its a film of two halves, the more interesting part being the first half set at boot camp with a sadistic drill instructor. The second half which is the more action based Vietnam set element is less interesting. Why? Because a year earlier we all watched 'Platoon' which swept the big prizes at the Oscars and directed by someone who served in Vietnam and fully conveyed the anti war message and politics of it all now that some years have passed by since the war ended. We saw Nam films before and better in Platoon and Apocalypse Now. Also these films although did not got to Vietnam, at least filmed in location whether it would be the Philippines or Thailand that is standing in. Full Metal Jacket was filmed in various parts of London dressed up as Vietnam. It shows, the sets do not look authentic, you do not get the feeling you are in the far east and it shows up the limitations of the second half of the story. It was too little and too late.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    War is not worth wasting our youth
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    StoryCharts
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Full Metal Jacket is about the idea that war is not worth wasting our youth. It tries to prove this with two stories: the first is the marines training for deployment, the second is the marines in action in Vietnam. The first story, the marines training for deployment, is told with two external plots: that of the not so bright marine Pyle trying to finish boot camp and the second is the entire class of marines trying to graduate. The class of marines succeed in graduating, but Pyle does not. He goes crazy after the harsh treatment meant to harden him to become a killer and commits suicide. So this story gets to the point that preparing for war is inhumane and not worth wasting our youth. The second story is about the marines fighting to win the war in Vietnam. This is told with two plots: that of winning the war and the second of the declining morality of the marines. The war is not won, it ends ambiguously as the marines win a small insignificant battle and return to camp while the morality of the marines shows a constant decline and ends with our hero committing murder. The movie is a great testament to the anti-war movement and a visual essay on the meaninglessness of war. But it is not a very engaging story. The first half of the movie makes a tight dramatic point that training marines to be killer has some inhumane consequences and proves it with Pyle's suicide. But the second half doesn't have an overall story arc to hang its hat on. The status of the main external plot of winning the war is left ambiguous. So the moral decline of our hero who has to commit murder at the end doesn't create as much meaning since the murder doesn't get us any further in winning the war. One can argue that that's the point of the movie, is that these atrocities are senseless and meaningless. And that is true. But in terms of a dramatic story, the meaning of the action is lost because the filmmakers abhorred making winning the war into any resemblance of a real plot. In the first half of the movie, Pyle's suicide is juxtaposed with the success of class of marines all graduating. Thus it makes the point that his suicide is not worth it for us to successfully train marines. But in the second half of the movie, Joker commits murder but this action is not juxtaposed with progression of any other plot. So the action loses the chance to create meaning through a consequence for his actions. It feels like the movie was cut off without any real resolution, like another 15 minutes were missing. My Story Chart of the movie is at storycharts.ca
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An outstanding and unique war movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    axel-koch
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    In 1987, 30 years after he'd firstly dealt with the subject of war in Paths of Glory, legendary American auteur Stanley Kubrick returned to the award-promising genre and released Full Metal Jacket. While it neither got the praise nor the awards it deserved when it came out, it has since then become a fan favorite and one of Kubrick's most beloved movies. Full Metal Jacket is split in two cohesive parts: the first and shorter one setting place at a military boot camp in South Carolina and the second one depicting the actual war events in Vietnam. The audience's relationship to the characters is supposed to be very distant and Kubrick lets us know very little about them. The narrator, nicknamed Joker, is a spectacled young man that believes to see through the military indoctrination. He tries to resist the system and, as he says himself, is only here to be the first kid on his block to get a confirmed kill. This is, of course, highly unconventional for a war movie protagonist and Matthew Modine plays him in a realistic, yet not particularly likable manner. Vincent D'Onofrio portrays the burly and universally untalented Private "Gomer Pyle", who gets permanently insulted and degraded by the vulgar and loud Drill Sergeant Hartman, who is played extraordinarily well by R. Lee Ermey, who was a real-life Drill Sergeant some time before. His eloquent and absolutely R-rated speeches are hilarious and simply the best part of the movie. It's sad somewhat, that his character doesn't accompany the recruits in the Vietnam War that follows; at some parts, I really wished for awesome one-liners like " I bet you're the kind of guy that would f*** a person in the a** and not even have the goddamn common courtesy to give him a reach-around!" But let's not be too harsh: the second part, if remarkably more serious, is again entertaining and because of the excellently crafted war scenes utterly gripping. Typically for a Kubrick film, Full Metal Jacket has a lot of ongoing themes and motifs in it that you may not even recognize when watching it for the first time. He's dealing with sexuality and not only in the two scenes in which Vietnamese hookers appear. The recruits have an absurd relationship with their rifle - especially D'Onofrio's character - and in the film's second part the killing scenes seem to bring an orgasmic feeling to the soldiers. Furthermore, you can probably correctly interpret religious imagery as well as father-mother-child themes into the movie - the minute director Stanley Kubrick is likely to have intended all of them. But you don't even need to think about the film in such a 'sophisticated' way, Mr. K shows a great game with the war scenes already. There may not be as many as in genre classics Apocalypse Now or Platoon and, admittedly, they don't have the aesthetic greatness that the ones in the aforementioned Coppola flick had. However, what Full Metal Jacket has is an authenticity that is even more impressive if you are aware that the Vietnam scenes where in fact shot in a disused gas work in the vicinity of London. Kubrick made the most out of it and also did terrific work with the sound and the editing which is impeccable. Because Kubrick wanted to make the recruits as one multi-persona character, there isn't as much to find out about the individual characters as some people may have wished for. Yet still, there is a very interesting and often only subliminal character study on the protagonist, Private Joker. Most of all, while Full Metal Jacket has the same view on war as the majority of other war films (even though the movie's protagonist is a war advocate, Kubrick himself is, of course, against war - I hope you noticed that), it shows us something new. A partly documentary and partly alarming new take that could have been boring. Thanks to Kubrick, it's not. At least not at the first time watching it - the prolonged war scenes lose their thrill once you know what's going to happen.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Let's talk about the source material
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jackhammer111
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The movie is well reviewed by others and most people find it very compelling. I like it to but am bothered by some shifts in tone in the final third although I think Kubrick deserves credit for not dodging the issue of atrocities. I prefer war movies that don't glorify war more as in "Platoon" or the great German U-Boat film "Das Boot" (see it in German with English subtitles, when they overdubbed it in English they wrecked a great background soundtrack). All in all there's a bit too much flag waving in this for me but it's a great movie but I can help remembering that part of the promotion for "Full Metal Jacket" including displaying the novel that served as source material for it in supermarket checkout lanes. Seeing Kubrick's name on it I picked it up. The novel was called "the Short Timers" written by Marine Gustav Hasford who was in theater during 1968-69. The great prolific essayist, columnist, novelist, screen writer (including my favorite sci fi movie, "a Boy and his Dog") Harlan Ellison said of Short timers "It is one of the most amazing stretches of writing I've ever encountered." Even though I know this is a movie review, not a book review, I have to tell you the source for most of the movie was written largely in a different kind of English called jarhead lingo. It was very cool to read inspired sections that are prose written with those word. Unfortunately, way more people were interested in watching Kubrick's movie than reading the real deal, the book didn't sell well, his deal with Kubrick wasn't very good and Hasford died alone almost broke in a motel room in Greece of heart related diabetic problems. I don't know which is more heartbreaking. Hasford's early death or the fact that "the Short Timers" is out of print while people still buy Kubrick's movie and somebody gets paid. The book has now become a rather expensive collector's item selling online for between $15 and upwards of $400. If you Google the title and his name you'll find a link to a scribd page that will load the whole book like a pdf. But you can't save or download it without paying. But you can read it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The best Marine Corps Bootcamp movie ever!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    sftd1973
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is a great movie that really depicts the life of a recruit going through Marine Corps Recruit Training. It is so real and straight to the point. Even with the additional Hollywood input in the movie, it still displays that reality that recruits go through to become United States Marines. Skip to the Viet Nam half of the movie. The Tet Offensive was a great part of the history of the Viet Nam war and this movie captures that history in great detail. The scenes of the fighting in the city is unique because most Viet Nam movies only show the fighting in the jungles and the rice patties and villages. Stanley Kubrick outdid himself with this movie and R. Lee Ermey immortalized himself as the Senior Drill Instructor and as the Gunnery Sergeant that everyone will always think of when anyone mentions the Marine Corps. Mathew Modine was outside himself in this movie and played a character that is totally outside of his normal range of characters. I give him a 10 along with R. Lee Ermey a 10 as well.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    R. Lee Ermey.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    AaronCapenBanner
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    R. Lee Ermey dominates this Stanley Kubrick directed Vietnam War drama, as he plays profane, no-nonsense, ultra tough Gunnery Sergeant Hartman, who belittles, browbeats, and insults the marine recruits in brutal boot camp training. Vincent D'Onofrio plays a slow-witted recruit who gets it the worst from Hartman, until he finds out that he is quite good at shooting... Mathew Modine plays "Joker", since he has an overt sense of humor that also captures the attention of Hartman, whose relentless, unmerciful verbal attacks take their toll in ways he didn't imagine... Film then picks up later, as Joker is a war correspondent for Stars & Stripes, who witnesses first hand the insanity of Vietnam... R. Lee Ermey so dominates the first half of the film(in an unforgettable, searing portrayal of dehumanization) that, when his part is over, it leaves a looming shadow over the rest of the film that is never lifted, though it is still a well-presented look at the war, though nothing exceptional. Worth watching for Ermey, who should have received an Academy Award!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A film of two halves
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tcr1991
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    'Full Metal Jacket' was a film that I had been meaning to watch for a while after all the good stuff I had heard about it. It really is a film of two halves, unfortunately I didn't like the 2nd half. The 1st half at boot camp was excellent, we saw a lot of character development and emotion as well as a lot of humour and really serious issues. R. Lee Ermey and Vincent D'Onofrio were just brilliant. The 2nd half I didn't enjoy as much, it looked great and there was a lot of action but it was just a bit boring and felt really dragged out, whereas the 1st part just had everything that you wanted. Glad I got round to seeing it but wouldn't watch it again, slightly disappointed after a really good start to the film. 6/10.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Bootcamp can be fun....Sometimes
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    A Stoners Review
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Really good movie. It's plot is mainly following a youngster through boot camp into the Vietnam war. The truth is throughout boot camp this movie is a gem. But once they go to war it kinda slows down a bit, and its not all that great towards the end, but don't get me wrong, it's still really good. I know I gave it an 8 but it's more like a 7.8 or something. All in all it's a hell of a movie. I say smoke a few bowls, relax and let this movie take you through the life a youngster during the days when boot camp really put you through some snit. If you haven't seen it, it is a must my friend. Peace out my fellow stoner's and may the weed take you away.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of my top ten
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    sraloff
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie is great. Great story, great acting and a lot of memorable scenes. You know a movie is good if you here quotes from it on a regular basis from people who probably don't even know where the saying came from (ie the younger generations). I love how it takes you from boot camp to the war and lets the viewer experience every aspect of the Vietnam war. It was a gritty time and the movie pulls no punches: if you are creating killing machines you have to be tough. Unlike todays army that is volunteer, most were there not by choice and the basic training scenes show the deconstruction of a boy and the construction of a soldier. The war scenes show these newly minted soldiers struggling to maintain their human element. We watch as the try and find balance between taking lives and knowing they will have to live theirs upon return. Many of these actors went on to play other great roles and I can't help but think it was due to their involvement with Full Metal Jacket.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    From boys to men to boys
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Marc Israel
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Events of dehumanization as learned scene by scene as coldly dictated by director Stanley Kubrick. Our Marines are always rallying around something white trying to hold onto their own values, themselves and, overall, their sanity. Much like "The Deer Hunter", this anti-war film is broken down into two parts, one prior to war, and then into the beast itself. While one movie shone an extra light on those stateside, Full Metal Jacket stayed with our boys and to what was left of themselves; their boyhood instincts (to defend each other) and their Mickey Mouse marches which drove the point home. This cold film doesn't bring you into each character as others might, but war is not about one person, is it? It is full of dogma (first to go, last to know), direction (our marines got lost) and dehumanization (see the first hour alone to hear the non-stop rant of Gunnery Seargent Hartman (Lee Ermey). Brutal and darkly funny, this is what I held onto as our narrator, Joker (Mathew Modine) is simply trying to fend off the brainwash, while it bounced off of Private Pyle (Vincent D'Onofrio) whose story tells us all Kubrick needed to say. That is why the second half of the film in Viet Nam seemed only to serve the audience a follow up and adventure as to what happened to some of our original boot camp marines. I still found the film both detached and personal, as if I was trying to fend off the disgracing of my viewers' soul. I like this film due to that internal struggle of whether or not to view war as acceptable.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not quite the full picture
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Prism10
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Stanley Kubrick, the eccentric director is lionised by Hollywood. A man who spent the latter part of his life living in London and shooting his films in England despite them being set elsewhere whether it was outer space, some hotel in the mountains of America or in this case a Vietnam war film. Full Metal Jacket arrived with plaudits from the critics. Its a film of two halves, the more interesting part being the first half set at boot camp with a sadistic drill instructor. The second half which is the more action based Vietnam set element is less interesting. Why? Because a year earlier we all watched 'Platoon' which swept the big prizes at the Oscars and directed by someone who served in Vietnam and fully conveyed the anti war message and politics of it all now that some years have passed by since the war ended. We saw Nam films before and better in Platoon and Apocalypse Now. Also these films although did not got to Vietnam, at least filmed in location whether it would be the Philippines or Thailand that is standing in. Full Metal Jacket was filmed in various parts of London dressed up as Vietnam. It shows, the sets do not look authentic, you do not get the feeling you are in the far east and it shows up the limitations of the second half of the story. It was too little and too late.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    War is not worth wasting our youth
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    StoryCharts
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Full Metal Jacket is about the idea that war is not worth wasting our youth. It tries to prove this with two stories: the first is the marines training for deployment, the second is the marines in action in Vietnam. The first story, the marines training for deployment, is told with two external plots: that of the not so bright marine Pyle trying to finish boot camp and the second is the entire class of marines trying to graduate. The class of marines succeed in graduating, but Pyle does not. He goes crazy after the harsh treatment meant to harden him to become a killer and commits suicide. So this story gets to the point that preparing for war is inhumane and not worth wasting our youth. The second story is about the marines fighting to win the war in Vietnam. This is told with two plots: that of winning the war and the second of the declining morality of the marines. The war is not won, it ends ambiguously as the marines win a small insignificant battle and return to camp while the morality of the marines shows a constant decline and ends with our hero committing murder. The movie is a great testament to the anti-war movement and a visual essay on the meaninglessness of war. But it is not a very engaging story. The first half of the movie makes a tight dramatic point that training marines to be killer has some inhumane consequences and proves it with Pyle's suicide. But the second half doesn't have an overall story arc to hang its hat on. The status of the main external plot of winning the war is left ambiguous. So the moral decline of our hero who has to commit murder at the end doesn't create as much meaning since the murder doesn't get us any further in winning the war. One can argue that that's the point of the movie, is that these atrocities are senseless and meaningless. And that is true. But in terms of a dramatic story, the meaning of the action is lost because the filmmakers abhorred making winning the war into any resemblance of a real plot. In the first half of the movie, Pyle's suicide is juxtaposed with the success of class of marines all graduating. Thus it makes the point that his suicide is not worth it for us to successfully train marines. But in the second half of the movie, Joker commits murder but this action is not juxtaposed with progression of any other plot. So the action loses the chance to create meaning through a consequence for his actions. It feels like the movie was cut off without any real resolution, like another 15 minutes were missing. My Story Chart of the movie is at storycharts.ca
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An outstanding and unique war movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    axel-koch
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    In 1987, 30 years after he'd firstly dealt with the subject of war in Paths of Glory, legendary American auteur Stanley Kubrick returned to the award-promising genre and released Full Metal Jacket. While it neither got the praise nor the awards it deserved when it came out, it has since then become a fan favorite and one of Kubrick's most beloved movies. Full Metal Jacket is split in two cohesive parts: the first and shorter one setting place at a military boot camp in South Carolina and the second one depicting the actual war events in Vietnam. The audience's relationship to the characters is supposed to be very distant and Kubrick lets us know very little about them. The narrator, nicknamed Joker, is a spectacled young man that believes to see through the military indoctrination. He tries to resist the system and, as he says himself, is only here to be the first kid on his block to get a confirmed kill. This is, of course, highly unconventional for a war movie protagonist and Matthew Modine plays him in a realistic, yet not particularly likable manner. Vincent D'Onofrio portrays the burly and universally untalented Private "Gomer Pyle", who gets permanently insulted and degraded by the vulgar and loud Drill Sergeant Hartman, who is played extraordinarily well by R. Lee Ermey, who was a real-life Drill Sergeant some time before. His eloquent and absolutely R-rated speeches are hilarious and simply the best part of the movie. It's sad somewhat, that his character doesn't accompany the recruits in the Vietnam War that follows; at some parts, I really wished for awesome one-liners like " I bet you're the kind of guy that would f*** a person in the a** and not even have the goddamn common courtesy to give him a reach-around!" But let's not be too harsh: the second part, if remarkably more serious, is again entertaining and because of the excellently crafted war scenes utterly gripping. Typically for a Kubrick film, Full Metal Jacket has a lot of ongoing themes and motifs in it that you may not even recognize when watching it for the first time. He's dealing with sexuality and not only in the two scenes in which Vietnamese hookers appear. The recruits have an absurd relationship with their rifle - especially D'Onofrio's character - and in the film's second part the killing scenes seem to bring an orgasmic feeling to the soldiers. Furthermore, you can probably correctly interpret religious imagery as well as father-mother-child themes into the movie - the minute director Stanley Kubrick is likely to have intended all of them. But you don't even need to think about the film in such a 'sophisticated' way, Mr. K shows a great game with the war scenes already. There may not be as many as in genre classics Apocalypse Now or Platoon and, admittedly, they don't have the aesthetic greatness that the ones in the aforementioned Coppola flick had. However, what Full Metal Jacket has is an authenticity that is even more impressive if you are aware that the Vietnam scenes where in fact shot in a disused gas work in the vicinity of London. Kubrick made the most out of it and also did terrific work with the sound and the editing which is impeccable. Because Kubrick wanted to make the recruits as one multi-persona character, there isn't as much to find out about the individual characters as some people may have wished for. Yet still, there is a very interesting and often only subliminal character study on the protagonist, Private Joker. Most of all, while Full Metal Jacket has the same view on war as the majority of other war films (even though the movie's protagonist is a war advocate, Kubrick himself is, of course, against war - I hope you noticed that), it shows us something new. A partly documentary and partly alarming new take that could have been boring. Thanks to Kubrick, it's not. At least not at the first time watching it - the prolonged war scenes lose their thrill once you know what's going to happen.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Let's talk about the source material
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jackhammer111
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The movie is well reviewed by others and most people find it very compelling. I like it to but am bothered by some shifts in tone in the final third although I think Kubrick deserves credit for not dodging the issue of atrocities. I prefer war movies that don't glorify war more as in "Platoon" or the great German U-Boat film "Das Boot" (see it in German with English subtitles, when they overdubbed it in English they wrecked a great background soundtrack). All in all there's a bit too much flag waving in this for me but it's a great movie but I can help remembering that part of the promotion for "Full Metal Jacket" including displaying the novel that served as source material for it in supermarket checkout lanes. Seeing Kubrick's name on it I picked it up. The novel was called "the Short Timers" written by Marine Gustav Hasford who was in theater during 1968-69. The great prolific essayist, columnist, novelist, screen writer (including my favorite sci fi movie, "a Boy and his Dog") Harlan Ellison said of Short timers "It is one of the most amazing stretches of writing I've ever encountered." Even though I know this is a movie review, not a book review, I have to tell you the source for most of the movie was written largely in a different kind of English called jarhead lingo. It was very cool to read inspired sections that are prose written with those word. Unfortunately, way more people were interested in watching Kubrick's movie than reading the real deal, the book didn't sell well, his deal with Kubrick wasn't very good and Hasford died alone almost broke in a motel room in Greece of heart related diabetic problems. I don't know which is more heartbreaking. Hasford's early death or the fact that "the Short Timers" is out of print while people still buy Kubrick's movie and somebody gets paid. The book has now become a rather expensive collector's item selling online for between $15 and upwards of $400. If you Google the title and his name you'll find a link to a scribd page that will load the whole book like a pdf. But you can't save or download it without paying. But you can read it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The best Marine Corps Bootcamp movie ever!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    sftd1973
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is a great movie that really depicts the life of a recruit going through Marine Corps Recruit Training. It is so real and straight to the point. Even with the additional Hollywood input in the movie, it still displays that reality that recruits go through to become United States Marines. Skip to the Viet Nam half of the movie. The Tet Offensive was a great part of the history of the Viet Nam war and this movie captures that history in great detail. The scenes of the fighting in the city is unique because most Viet Nam movies only show the fighting in the jungles and the rice patties and villages. Stanley Kubrick outdid himself with this movie and R. Lee Ermey immortalized himself as the Senior Drill Instructor and as the Gunnery Sergeant that everyone will always think of when anyone mentions the Marine Corps. Mathew Modine was outside himself in this movie and played a character that is totally outside of his normal range of characters. I give him a 10 along with R. Lee Ermey a 10 as well.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    R. Lee Ermey.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    AaronCapenBanner
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    R. Lee Ermey dominates this Stanley Kubrick directed Vietnam War drama, as he plays profane, no-nonsense, ultra tough Gunnery Sergeant Hartman, who belittles, browbeats, and insults the marine recruits in brutal boot camp training. Vincent D'Onofrio plays a slow-witted recruit who gets it the worst from Hartman, until he finds out that he is quite good at shooting... Mathew Modine plays "Joker", since he has an overt sense of humor that also captures the attention of Hartman, whose relentless, unmerciful verbal attacks take their toll in ways he didn't imagine... Film then picks up later, as Joker is a war correspondent for Stars & Stripes, who witnesses first hand the insanity of Vietnam... R. Lee Ermey so dominates the first half of the film(in an unforgettable, searing portrayal of dehumanization) that, when his part is over, it leaves a looming shadow over the rest of the film that is never lifted, though it is still a well-presented look at the war, though nothing exceptional. Worth watching for Ermey, who should have received an Academy Award!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A film of two halves
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tcr1991
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    'Full Metal Jacket' was a film that I had been meaning to watch for a while after all the good stuff I had heard about it. It really is a film of two halves, unfortunately I didn't like the 2nd half. The 1st half at boot camp was excellent, we saw a lot of character development and emotion as well as a lot of humour and really serious issues. R. Lee Ermey and Vincent D'Onofrio were just brilliant. The 2nd half I didn't enjoy as much, it looked great and there was a lot of action but it was just a bit boring and felt really dragged out, whereas the 1st part just had everything that you wanted. Glad I got round to seeing it but wouldn't watch it again, slightly disappointed after a really good start to the film. 6/10.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Bootcamp can be fun....Sometimes
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    A Stoners Review
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Really good movie. It's plot is mainly following a youngster through boot camp into the Vietnam war. The truth is throughout boot camp this movie is a gem. But once they go to war it kinda slows down a bit, and its not all that great towards the end, but don't get me wrong, it's still really good. I know I gave it an 8 but it's more like a 7.8 or something. All in all it's a hell of a movie. I say smoke a few bowls, relax and let this movie take you through the life a youngster during the days when boot camp really put you through some snit. If you haven't seen it, it is a must my friend. Peace out my fellow stoner's and may the weed take you away.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of my top ten
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    sraloff
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie is great. Great story, great acting and a lot of memorable scenes. You know a movie is good if you here quotes from it on a regular basis from people who probably don't even know where the saying came from (ie the younger generations). I love how it takes you from boot camp to the war and lets the viewer experience every aspect of the Vietnam war. It was a gritty time and the movie pulls no punches: if you are creating killing machines you have to be tough. Unlike todays army that is volunteer, most were there not by choice and the basic training scenes show the deconstruction of a boy and the construction of a soldier. The war scenes show these newly minted soldiers struggling to maintain their human element. We watch as the try and find balance between taking lives and knowing they will have to live theirs upon return. Many of these actors went on to play other great roles and I can't help but think it was due to their involvement with Full Metal Jacket.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    From boys to men to boys
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Marc Israel
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Events of dehumanization as learned scene by scene as coldly dictated by director Stanley Kubrick. Our Marines are always rallying around something white trying to hold onto their own values, themselves and, overall, their sanity. Much like "The Deer Hunter", this anti-war film is broken down into two parts, one prior to war, and then into the beast itself. While one movie shone an extra light on those stateside, Full Metal Jacket stayed with our boys and to what was left of themselves; their boyhood instincts (to defend each other) and their Mickey Mouse marches which drove the point home. This cold film doesn't bring you into each character as others might, but war is not about one person, is it? It is full of dogma (first to go, last to know), direction (our marines got lost) and dehumanization (see the first hour alone to hear the non-stop rant of Gunnery Seargent Hartman (Lee Ermey). Brutal and darkly funny, this is what I held onto as our narrator, Joker (Mathew Modine) is simply trying to fend off the brainwash, while it bounced off of Private Pyle (Vincent D'Onofrio) whose story tells us all Kubrick needed to say. That is why the second half of the film in Viet Nam seemed only to serve the audience a follow up and adventure as to what happened to some of our original boot camp marines. I still found the film both detached and personal, as if I was trying to fend off the disgracing of my viewers' soul. I like this film due to that internal struggle of whether or not to view war as acceptable.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not quite the full picture
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Prism10
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Stanley Kubrick, the eccentric director is lionised by Hollywood. A man who spent the latter part of his life living in London and shooting his films in England despite them being set elsewhere whether it was outer space, some hotel in the mountains of America or in this case a Vietnam war film. Full Metal Jacket arrived with plaudits from the critics. Its a film of two halves, the more interesting part being the first half set at boot camp with a sadistic drill instructor. The second half which is the more action based Vietnam set element is less interesting. Why? Because a year earlier we all watched 'Platoon' which swept the big prizes at the Oscars and directed by someone who served in Vietnam and fully conveyed the anti war message and politics of it all now that some years have passed by since the war ended. We saw Nam films before and better in Platoon and Apocalypse Now. Also these films although did not got to Vietnam, at least filmed in location whether it would be the Philippines or Thailand that is standing in. Full Metal Jacket was filmed in various parts of London dressed up as Vietnam. It shows, the sets do not look authentic, you do not get the feeling you are in the far east and it shows up the limitations of the second half of the story. It was too little and too late.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    War is not worth wasting our youth
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    StoryCharts
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Full Metal Jacket is about the idea that war is not worth wasting our youth. It tries to prove this with two stories: the first is the marines training for deployment, the second is the marines in action in Vietnam. The first story, the marines training for deployment, is told with two external plots: that of the not so bright marine Pyle trying to finish boot camp and the second is the entire class of marines trying to graduate. The class of marines succeed in graduating, but Pyle does not. He goes crazy after the harsh treatment meant to harden him to become a killer and commits suicide. So this story gets to the point that preparing for war is inhumane and not worth wasting our youth. The second story is about the marines fighting to win the war in Vietnam. This is told with two plots: that of winning the war and the second of the declining morality of the marines. The war is not won, it ends ambiguously as the marines win a small insignificant battle and return to camp while the morality of the marines shows a constant decline and ends with our hero committing murder. The movie is a great testament to the anti-war movement and a visual essay on the meaninglessness of war. But it is not a very engaging story. The first half of the movie makes a tight dramatic point that training marines to be killer has some inhumane consequences and proves it with Pyle's suicide. But the second half doesn't have an overall story arc to hang its hat on. The status of the main external plot of winning the war is left ambiguous. So the moral decline of our hero who has to commit murder at the end doesn't create as much meaning since the murder doesn't get us any further in winning the war. One can argue that that's the point of the movie, is that these atrocities are senseless and meaningless. And that is true. But in terms of a dramatic story, the meaning of the action is lost because the filmmakers abhorred making winning the war into any resemblance of a real plot. In the first half of the movie, Pyle's suicide is juxtaposed with the success of class of marines all graduating. Thus it makes the point that his suicide is not worth it for us to successfully train marines. But in the second half of the movie, Joker commits murder but this action is not juxtaposed with progression of any other plot. So the action loses the chance to create meaning through a consequence for his actions. It feels like the movie was cut off without any real resolution, like another 15 minutes were missing. My Story Chart of the movie is at storycharts.ca
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An outstanding and unique war movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    axel-koch
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    In 1987, 30 years after he'd firstly dealt with the subject of war in Paths of Glory, legendary American auteur Stanley Kubrick returned to the award-promising genre and released Full Metal Jacket. While it neither got the praise nor the awards it deserved when it came out, it has since then become a fan favorite and one of Kubrick's most beloved movies. Full Metal Jacket is split in two cohesive parts: the first and shorter one setting place at a military boot camp in South Carolina and the second one depicting the actual war events in Vietnam. The audience's relationship to the characters is supposed to be very distant and Kubrick lets us know very little about them. The narrator, nicknamed Joker, is a spectacled young man that believes to see through the military indoctrination. He tries to resist the system and, as he says himself, is only here to be the first kid on his block to get a confirmed kill. This is, of course, highly unconventional for a war movie protagonist and Matthew Modine plays him in a realistic, yet not particularly likable manner. Vincent D'Onofrio portrays the burly and universally untalented Private "Gomer Pyle", who gets permanently insulted and degraded by the vulgar and loud Drill Sergeant Hartman, who is played extraordinarily well by R. Lee Ermey, who was a real-life Drill Sergeant some time before. His eloquent and absolutely R-rated speeches are hilarious and simply the best part of the movie. It's sad somewhat, that his character doesn't accompany the recruits in the Vietnam War that follows; at some parts, I really wished for awesome one-liners like " I bet you're the kind of guy that would f*** a person in the a** and not even have the goddamn common courtesy to give him a reach-around!" But let's not be too harsh: the second part, if remarkably more serious, is again entertaining and because of the excellently crafted war scenes utterly gripping. Typically for a Kubrick film, Full Metal Jacket has a lot of ongoing themes and motifs in it that you may not even recognize when watching it for the first time. He's dealing with sexuality and not only in the two scenes in which Vietnamese hookers appear. The recruits have an absurd relationship with their rifle - especially D'Onofrio's character - and in the film's second part the killing scenes seem to bring an orgasmic feeling to the soldiers. Furthermore, you can probably correctly interpret religious imagery as well as father-mother-child themes into the movie - the minute director Stanley Kubrick is likely to have intended all of them. But you don't even need to think about the film in such a 'sophisticated' way, Mr. K shows a great game with the war scenes already. There may not be as many as in genre classics Apocalypse Now or Platoon and, admittedly, they don't have the aesthetic greatness that the ones in the aforementioned Coppola flick had. However, what Full Metal Jacket has is an authenticity that is even more impressive if you are aware that the Vietnam scenes where in fact shot in a disused gas work in the vicinity of London. Kubrick made the most out of it and also did terrific work with the sound and the editing which is impeccable. Because Kubrick wanted to make the recruits as one multi-persona character, there isn't as much to find out about the individual characters as some people may have wished for. Yet still, there is a very interesting and often only subliminal character study on the protagonist, Private Joker. Most of all, while Full Metal Jacket has the same view on war as the majority of other war films (even though the movie's protagonist is a war advocate, Kubrick himself is, of course, against war - I hope you noticed that), it shows us something new. A partly documentary and partly alarming new take that could have been boring. Thanks to Kubrick, it's not. At least not at the first time watching it - the prolonged war scenes lose their thrill once you know what's going to happen.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Let's talk about the source material
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jackhammer111
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The movie is well reviewed by others and most people find it very compelling. I like it to but am bothered by some shifts in tone in the final third although I think Kubrick deserves credit for not dodging the issue of atrocities. I prefer war movies that don't glorify war more as in "Platoon" or the great German U-Boat film "Das Boot" (see it in German with English subtitles, when they overdubbed it in English they wrecked a great background soundtrack). All in all there's a bit too much flag waving in this for me but it's a great movie but I can help remembering that part of the promotion for "Full Metal Jacket" including displaying the novel that served as source material for it in supermarket checkout lanes. Seeing Kubrick's name on it I picked it up. The novel was called "the Short Timers" written by Marine Gustav Hasford who was in theater during 1968-69. The great prolific essayist, columnist, novelist, screen writer (including my favorite sci fi movie, "a Boy and his Dog") Harlan Ellison said of Short timers "It is one of the most amazing stretches of writing I've ever encountered." Even though I know this is a movie review, not a book review, I have to tell you the source for most of the movie was written largely in a different kind of English called jarhead lingo. It was very cool to read inspired sections that are prose written with those word. Unfortunately, way more people were interested in watching Kubrick's movie than reading the real deal, the book didn't sell well, his deal with Kubrick wasn't very good and Hasford died alone almost broke in a motel room in Greece of heart related diabetic problems. I don't know which is more heartbreaking. Hasford's early death or the fact that "the Short Timers" is out of print while people still buy Kubrick's movie and somebody gets paid. The book has now become a rather expensive collector's item selling online for between $15 and upwards of $400. If you Google the title and his name you'll find a link to a scribd page that will load the whole book like a pdf. But you can't save or download it without paying. But you can read it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The best Marine Corps Bootcamp movie ever!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    sftd1973
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is a great movie that really depicts the life of a recruit going through Marine Corps Recruit Training. It is so real and straight to the point. Even with the additional Hollywood input in the movie, it still displays that reality that recruits go through to become United States Marines. Skip to the Viet Nam half of the movie. The Tet Offensive was a great part of the history of the Viet Nam war and this movie captures that history in great detail. The scenes of the fighting in the city is unique because most Viet Nam movies only show the fighting in the jungles and the rice patties and villages. Stanley Kubrick outdid himself with this movie and R. Lee Ermey immortalized himself as the Senior Drill Instructor and as the Gunnery Sergeant that everyone will always think of when anyone mentions the Marine Corps. Mathew Modine was outside himself in this movie and played a character that is totally outside of his normal range of characters. I give him a 10 along with R. Lee Ermey a 10 as well.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    R. Lee Ermey.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    AaronCapenBanner
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    R. Lee Ermey dominates this Stanley Kubrick directed Vietnam War drama, as he plays profane, no-nonsense, ultra tough Gunnery Sergeant Hartman, who belittles, browbeats, and insults the marine recruits in brutal boot camp training. Vincent D'Onofrio plays a slow-witted recruit who gets it the worst from Hartman, until he finds out that he is quite good at shooting... Mathew Modine plays "Joker", since he has an overt sense of humor that also captures the attention of Hartman, whose relentless, unmerciful verbal attacks take their toll in ways he didn't imagine... Film then picks up later, as Joker is a war correspondent for Stars & Stripes, who witnesses first hand the insanity of Vietnam... R. Lee Ermey so dominates the first half of the film(in an unforgettable, searing portrayal of dehumanization) that, when his part is over, it leaves a looming shadow over the rest of the film that is never lifted, though it is still a well-presented look at the war, though nothing exceptional. Worth watching for Ermey, who should have received an Academy Award!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A film of two halves
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tcr1991
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    'Full Metal Jacket' was a film that I had been meaning to watch for a while after all the good stuff I had heard about it. It really is a film of two halves, unfortunately I didn't like the 2nd half. The 1st half at boot camp was excellent, we saw a lot of character development and emotion as well as a lot of humour and really serious issues. R. Lee Ermey and Vincent D'Onofrio were just brilliant. The 2nd half I didn't enjoy as much, it looked great and there was a lot of action but it was just a bit boring and felt really dragged out, whereas the 1st part just had everything that you wanted. Glad I got round to seeing it but wouldn't watch it again, slightly disappointed after a really good start to the film. 6/10.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Bootcamp can be fun....Sometimes
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    A Stoners Review
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Really good movie. It's plot is mainly following a youngster through boot camp into the Vietnam war. The truth is throughout boot camp this movie is a gem. But once they go to war it kinda slows down a bit, and its not all that great towards the end, but don't get me wrong, it's still really good. I know I gave it an 8 but it's more like a 7.8 or something. All in all it's a hell of a movie. I say smoke a few bowls, relax and let this movie take you through the life a youngster during the days when boot camp really put you through some snit. If you haven't seen it, it is a must my friend. Peace out my fellow stoner's and may the weed take you away.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of my top ten
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    sraloff
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie is great. Great story, great acting and a lot of memorable scenes. You know a movie is good if you here quotes from it on a regular basis from people who probably don't even know where the saying came from (ie the younger generations). I love how it takes you from boot camp to the war and lets the viewer experience every aspect of the Vietnam war. It was a gritty time and the movie pulls no punches: if you are creating killing machines you have to be tough. Unlike todays army that is volunteer, most were there not by choice and the basic training scenes show the deconstruction of a boy and the construction of a soldier. The war scenes show these newly minted soldiers struggling to maintain their human element. We watch as the try and find balance between taking lives and knowing they will have to live theirs upon return. Many of these actors went on to play other great roles and I can't help but think it was due to their involvement with Full Metal Jacket.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    From boys to men to boys
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Marc Israel
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Events of dehumanization as learned scene by scene as coldly dictated by director Stanley Kubrick. Our Marines are always rallying around something white trying to hold onto their own values, themselves and, overall, their sanity. Much like "The Deer Hunter", this anti-war film is broken down into two parts, one prior to war, and then into the beast itself. While one movie shone an extra light on those stateside, Full Metal Jacket stayed with our boys and to what was left of themselves; their boyhood instincts (to defend each other) and their Mickey Mouse marches which drove the point home. This cold film doesn't bring you into each character as others might, but war is not about one person, is it? It is full of dogma (first to go, last to know), direction (our marines got lost) and dehumanization (see the first hour alone to hear the non-stop rant of Gunnery Seargent Hartman (Lee Ermey). Brutal and darkly funny, this is what I held onto as our narrator, Joker (Mathew Modine) is simply trying to fend off the brainwash, while it bounced off of Private Pyle (Vincent D'Onofrio) whose story tells us all Kubrick needed to say. That is why the second half of the film in Viet Nam seemed only to serve the audience a follow up and adventure as to what happened to some of our original boot camp marines. I still found the film both detached and personal, as if I was trying to fend off the disgracing of my viewers' soul. I like this film due to that internal struggle of whether or not to view war as acceptable.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not quite the full picture
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Prism10
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Stanley Kubrick, the eccentric director is lionised by Hollywood. A man who spent the latter part of his life living in London and shooting his films in England despite them being set elsewhere whether it was outer space, some hotel in the mountains of America or in this case a Vietnam war film. Full Metal Jacket arrived with plaudits from the critics. Its a film of two halves, the more interesting part being the first half set at boot camp with a sadistic drill instructor. The second half which is the more action based Vietnam set element is less interesting. Why? Because a year earlier we all watched 'Platoon' which swept the big prizes at the Oscars and directed by someone who served in Vietnam and fully conveyed the anti war message and politics of it all now that some years have passed by since the war ended. We saw Nam films before and better in Platoon and Apocalypse Now. Also these films although did not got to Vietnam, at least filmed in location whether it would be the Philippines or Thailand that is standing in. Full Metal Jacket was filmed in various parts of London dressed up as Vietnam. It shows, the sets do not look authentic, you do not get the feeling you are in the far east and it shows up the limitations of the second half of the story. It was too little and too late.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    War is not worth wasting our youth
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    StoryCharts
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Full Metal Jacket is about the idea that war is not worth wasting our youth. It tries to prove this with two stories: the first is the marines training for deployment, the second is the marines in action in Vietnam. The first story, the marines training for deployment, is told with two external plots: that of the not so bright marine Pyle trying to finish boot camp and the second is the entire class of marines trying to graduate. The class of marines succeed in graduating, but Pyle does not. He goes crazy after the harsh treatment meant to harden him to become a killer and commits suicide. So this story gets to the point that preparing for war is inhumane and not worth wasting our youth. The second story is about the marines fighting to win the war in Vietnam. This is told with two plots: that of winning the war and the second of the declining morality of the marines. The war is not won, it ends ambiguously as the marines win a small insignificant battle and return to camp while the morality of the marines shows a constant decline and ends with our hero committing murder. The movie is a great testament to the anti-war movement and a visual essay on the meaninglessness of war. But it is not a very engaging story. The first half of the movie makes a tight dramatic point that training marines to be killer has some inhumane consequences and proves it with Pyle's suicide. But the second half doesn't have an overall story arc to hang its hat on. The status of the main external plot of winning the war is left ambiguous. So the moral decline of our hero who has to commit murder at the end doesn't create as much meaning since the murder doesn't get us any further in winning the war. One can argue that that's the point of the movie, is that these atrocities are senseless and meaningless. And that is true. But in terms of a dramatic story, the meaning of the action is lost because the filmmakers abhorred making winning the war into any resemblance of a real plot. In the first half of the movie, Pyle's suicide is juxtaposed with the success of class of marines all graduating. Thus it makes the point that his suicide is not worth it for us to successfully train marines. But in the second half of the movie, Joker commits murder but this action is not juxtaposed with progression of any other plot. So the action loses the chance to create meaning through a consequence for his actions. It feels like the movie was cut off without any real resolution, like another 15 minutes were missing. My Story Chart of the movie is at storycharts.ca
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An outstanding and unique war movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    axel-koch
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    In 1987, 30 years after he'd firstly dealt with the subject of war in Paths of Glory, legendary American auteur Stanley Kubrick returned to the award-promising genre and released Full Metal Jacket. While it neither got the praise nor the awards it deserved when it came out, it has since then become a fan favorite and one of Kubrick's most beloved movies. Full Metal Jacket is split in two cohesive parts: the first and shorter one setting place at a military boot camp in South Carolina and the second one depicting the actual war events in Vietnam. The audience's relationship to the characters is supposed to be very distant and Kubrick lets us know very little about them. The narrator, nicknamed Joker, is a spectacled young man that believes to see through the military indoctrination. He tries to resist the system and, as he says himself, is only here to be the first kid on his block to get a confirmed kill. This is, of course, highly unconventional for a war movie protagonist and Matthew Modine plays him in a realistic, yet not particularly likable manner. Vincent D'Onofrio portrays the burly and universally untalented Private "Gomer Pyle", who gets permanently insulted and degraded by the vulgar and loud Drill Sergeant Hartman, who is played extraordinarily well by R. Lee Ermey, who was a real-life Drill Sergeant some time before. His eloquent and absolutely R-rated speeches are hilarious and simply the best part of the movie. It's sad somewhat, that his character doesn't accompany the recruits in the Vietnam War that follows; at some parts, I really wished for awesome one-liners like " I bet you're the kind of guy that would f*** a person in the a** and not even have the goddamn common courtesy to give him a reach-around!" But let's not be too harsh: the second part, if remarkably more serious, is again entertaining and because of the excellently crafted war scenes utterly gripping. Typically for a Kubrick film, Full Metal Jacket has a lot of ongoing themes and motifs in it that you may not even recognize when watching it for the first time. He's dealing with sexuality and not only in the two scenes in which Vietnamese hookers appear. The recruits have an absurd relationship with their rifle - especially D'Onofrio's character - and in the film's second part the killing scenes seem to bring an orgasmic feeling to the soldiers. Furthermore, you can probably correctly interpret religious imagery as well as father-mother-child themes into the movie - the minute director Stanley Kubrick is likely to have intended all of them. But you don't even need to think about the film in such a 'sophisticated' way, Mr. K shows a great game with the war scenes already. There may not be as many as in genre classics Apocalypse Now or Platoon and, admittedly, they don't have the aesthetic greatness that the ones in the aforementioned Coppola flick had. However, what Full Metal Jacket has is an authenticity that is even more impressive if you are aware that the Vietnam scenes where in fact shot in a disused gas work in the vicinity of London. Kubrick made the most out of it and also did terrific work with the sound and the editing which is impeccable. Because Kubrick wanted to make the recruits as one multi-persona character, there isn't as much to find out about the individual characters as some people may have wished for. Yet still, there is a very interesting and often only subliminal character study on the protagonist, Private Joker. Most of all, while Full Metal Jacket has the same view on war as the majority of other war films (even though the movie's protagonist is a war advocate, Kubrick himself is, of course, against war - I hope you noticed that), it shows us something new. A partly documentary and partly alarming new take that could have been boring. Thanks to Kubrick, it's not. At least not at the first time watching it - the prolonged war scenes lose their thrill once you know what's going to happen.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Let's talk about the source material
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jackhammer111
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The movie is well reviewed by others and most people find it very compelling. I like it to but am bothered by some shifts in tone in the final third although I think Kubrick deserves credit for not dodging the issue of atrocities. I prefer war movies that don't glorify war more as in "Platoon" or the great German U-Boat film "Das Boot" (see it in German with English subtitles, when they overdubbed it in English they wrecked a great background soundtrack). All in all there's a bit too much flag waving in this for me but it's a great movie but I can help remembering that part of the promotion for "Full Metal Jacket" including displaying the novel that served as source material for it in supermarket checkout lanes. Seeing Kubrick's name on it I picked it up. The novel was called "the Short Timers" written by Marine Gustav Hasford who was in theater during 1968-69. The great prolific essayist, columnist, novelist, screen writer (including my favorite sci fi movie, "a Boy and his Dog") Harlan Ellison said of Short timers "It is one of the most amazing stretches of writing I've ever encountered." Even though I know this is a movie review, not a book review, I have to tell you the source for most of the movie was written largely in a different kind of English called jarhead lingo. It was very cool to read inspired sections that are prose written with those word. Unfortunately, way more people were interested in watching Kubrick's movie than reading the real deal, the book didn't sell well, his deal with Kubrick wasn't very good and Hasford died alone almost broke in a motel room in Greece of heart related diabetic problems. I don't know which is more heartbreaking. Hasford's early death or the fact that "the Short Timers" is out of print while people still buy Kubrick's movie and somebody gets paid. The book has now become a rather expensive collector's item selling online for between $15 and upwards of $400. If you Google the title and his name you'll find a link to a scribd page that will load the whole book like a pdf. But you can't save or download it without paying. But you can read it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The best Marine Corps Bootcamp movie ever!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    sftd1973
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is a great movie that really depicts the life of a recruit going through Marine Corps Recruit Training. It is so real and straight to the point. Even with the additional Hollywood input in the movie, it still displays that reality that recruits go through to become United States Marines. Skip to the Viet Nam half of the movie. The Tet Offensive was a great part of the history of the Viet Nam war and this movie captures that history in great detail. The scenes of the fighting in the city is unique because most Viet Nam movies only show the fighting in the jungles and the rice patties and villages. Stanley Kubrick outdid himself with this movie and R. Lee Ermey immortalized himself as the Senior Drill Instructor and as the Gunnery Sergeant that everyone will always think of when anyone mentions the Marine Corps. Mathew Modine was outside himself in this movie and played a character that is totally outside of his normal range of characters. I give him a 10 along with R. Lee Ermey a 10 as well.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    R. Lee Ermey.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    AaronCapenBanner
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    R. Lee Ermey dominates this Stanley Kubrick directed Vietnam War drama, as he plays profane, no-nonsense, ultra tough Gunnery Sergeant Hartman, who belittles, browbeats, and insults the marine recruits in brutal boot camp training. Vincent D'Onofrio plays a slow-witted recruit who gets it the worst from Hartman, until he finds out that he is quite good at shooting... Mathew Modine plays "Joker", since he has an overt sense of humor that also captures the attention of Hartman, whose relentless, unmerciful verbal attacks take their toll in ways he didn't imagine... Film then picks up later, as Joker is a war correspondent for Stars & Stripes, who witnesses first hand the insanity of Vietnam... R. Lee Ermey so dominates the first half of the film(in an unforgettable, searing portrayal of dehumanization) that, when his part is over, it leaves a looming shadow over the rest of the film that is never lifted, though it is still a well-presented look at the war, though nothing exceptional. Worth watching for Ermey, who should have received an Academy Award!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A film of two halves
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tcr1991
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    'Full Metal Jacket' was a film that I had been meaning to watch for a while after all the good stuff I had heard about it. It really is a film of two halves, unfortunately I didn't like the 2nd half. The 1st half at boot camp was excellent, we saw a lot of character development and emotion as well as a lot of humour and really serious issues. R. Lee Ermey and Vincent D'Onofrio were just brilliant. The 2nd half I didn't enjoy as much, it looked great and there was a lot of action but it was just a bit boring and felt really dragged out, whereas the 1st part just had everything that you wanted. Glad I got round to seeing it but wouldn't watch it again, slightly disappointed after a really good start to the film. 6/10.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Bootcamp can be fun....Sometimes
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    A Stoners Review
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Really good movie. It's plot is mainly following a youngster through boot camp into the Vietnam war. The truth is throughout boot camp this movie is a gem. But once they go to war it kinda slows down a bit, and its not all that great towards the end, but don't get me wrong, it's still really good. I know I gave it an 8 but it's more like a 7.8 or something. All in all it's a hell of a movie. I say smoke a few bowls, relax and let this movie take you through the life a youngster during the days when boot camp really put you through some snit. If you haven't seen it, it is a must my friend. Peace out my fellow stoner's and may the weed take you away.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of my top ten
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    sraloff
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie is great. Great story, great acting and a lot of memorable scenes. You know a movie is good if you here quotes from it on a regular basis from people who probably don't even know where the saying came from (ie the younger generations). I love how it takes you from boot camp to the war and lets the viewer experience every aspect of the Vietnam war. It was a gritty time and the movie pulls no punches: if you are creating killing machines you have to be tough. Unlike todays army that is volunteer, most were there not by choice and the basic training scenes show the deconstruction of a boy and the construction of a soldier. The war scenes show these newly minted soldiers struggling to maintain their human element. We watch as the try and find balance between taking lives and knowing they will have to live theirs upon return. Many of these actors went on to play other great roles and I can't help but think it was due to their involvement with Full Metal Jacket.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    From boys to men to boys
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Marc Israel
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Events of dehumanization as learned scene by scene as coldly dictated by director Stanley Kubrick. Our Marines are always rallying around something white trying to hold onto their own values, themselves and, overall, their sanity. Much like "The Deer Hunter", this anti-war film is broken down into two parts, one prior to war, and then into the beast itself. While one movie shone an extra light on those stateside, Full Metal Jacket stayed with our boys and to what was left of themselves; their boyhood instincts (to defend each other) and their Mickey Mouse marches which drove the point home. This cold film doesn't bring you into each character as others might, but war is not about one person, is it? It is full of dogma (first to go, last to know), direction (our marines got lost) and dehumanization (see the first hour alone to hear the non-stop rant of Gunnery Seargent Hartman (Lee Ermey). Brutal and darkly funny, this is what I held onto as our narrator, Joker (Mathew Modine) is simply trying to fend off the brainwash, while it bounced off of Private Pyle (Vincent D'Onofrio) whose story tells us all Kubrick needed to say. That is why the second half of the film in Viet Nam seemed only to serve the audience a follow up and adventure as to what happened to some of our original boot camp marines. I still found the film both detached and personal, as if I was trying to fend off the disgracing of my viewers' soul. I like this film due to that internal struggle of whether or not to view war as acceptable.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not quite the full picture
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Prism10
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Stanley Kubrick, the eccentric director is lionised by Hollywood. A man who spent the latter part of his life living in London and shooting his films in England despite them being set elsewhere whether it was outer space, some hotel in the mountains of America or in this case a Vietnam war film. Full Metal Jacket arrived with plaudits from the critics. Its a film of two halves, the more interesting part being the first half set at boot camp with a sadistic drill instructor. The second half which is the more action based Vietnam set element is less interesting. Why? Because a year earlier we all watched 'Platoon' which swept the big prizes at the Oscars and directed by someone who served in Vietnam and fully conveyed the anti war message and politics of it all now that some years have passed by since the war ended. We saw Nam films before and better in Platoon and Apocalypse Now. Also these films although did not got to Vietnam, at least filmed in location whether it would be the Philippines or Thailand that is standing in. Full Metal Jacket was filmed in various parts of London dressed up as Vietnam. It shows, the sets do not look authentic, you do not get the feeling you are in the far east and it shows up the limitations of the second half of the story. It was too little and too late.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    War is not worth wasting our youth
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    StoryCharts
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Full Metal Jacket is about the idea that war is not worth wasting our youth. It tries to prove this with two stories: the first is the marines training for deployment, the second is the marines in action in Vietnam. The first story, the marines training for deployment, is told with two external plots: that of the not so bright marine Pyle trying to finish boot camp and the second is the entire class of marines trying to graduate. The class of marines succeed in graduating, but Pyle does not. He goes crazy after the harsh treatment meant to harden him to become a killer and commits suicide. So this story gets to the point that preparing for war is inhumane and not worth wasting our youth. The second story is about the marines fighting to win the war in Vietnam. This is told with two plots: that of winning the war and the second of the declining morality of the marines. The war is not won, it ends ambiguously as the marines win a small insignificant battle and return to camp while the morality of the marines shows a constant decline and ends with our hero committing murder. The movie is a great testament to the anti-war movement and a visual essay on the meaninglessness of war. But it is not a very engaging story. The first half of the movie makes a tight dramatic point that training marines to be killer has some inhumane consequences and proves it with Pyle's suicide. But the second half doesn't have an overall story arc to hang its hat on. The status of the main external plot of winning the war is left ambiguous. So the moral decline of our hero who has to commit murder at the end doesn't create as much meaning since the murder doesn't get us any further in winning the war. One can argue that that's the point of the movie, is that these atrocities are senseless and meaningless. And that is true. But in terms of a dramatic story, the meaning of the action is lost because the filmmakers abhorred making winning the war into any resemblance of a real plot. In the first half of the movie, Pyle's suicide is juxtaposed with the success of class of marines all graduating. Thus it makes the point that his suicide is not worth it for us to successfully train marines. But in the second half of the movie, Joker commits murder but this action is not juxtaposed with progression of any other plot. So the action loses the chance to create meaning through a consequence for his actions. It feels like the movie was cut off without any real resolution, like another 15 minutes were missing. My Story Chart of the movie is at storycharts.ca
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An outstanding and unique war movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    axel-koch
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    In 1987, 30 years after he'd firstly dealt with the subject of war in Paths of Glory, legendary American auteur Stanley Kubrick returned to the award-promising genre and released Full Metal Jacket. While it neither got the praise nor the awards it deserved when it came out, it has since then become a fan favorite and one of Kubrick's most beloved movies. Full Metal Jacket is split in two cohesive parts: the first and shorter one setting place at a military boot camp in South Carolina and the second one depicting the actual war events in Vietnam. The audience's relationship to the characters is supposed to be very distant and Kubrick lets us know very little about them. The narrator, nicknamed Joker, is a spectacled young man that believes to see through the military indoctrination. He tries to resist the system and, as he says himself, is only here to be the first kid on his block to get a confirmed kill. This is, of course, highly unconventional for a war movie protagonist and Matthew Modine plays him in a realistic, yet not particularly likable manner. Vincent D'Onofrio portrays the burly and universally untalented Private "Gomer Pyle", who gets permanently insulted and degraded by the vulgar and loud Drill Sergeant Hartman, who is played extraordinarily well by R. Lee Ermey, who was a real-life Drill Sergeant some time before. His eloquent and absolutely R-rated speeches are hilarious and simply the best part of the movie. It's sad somewhat, that his character doesn't accompany the recruits in the Vietnam War that follows; at some parts, I really wished for awesome one-liners like " I bet you're the kind of guy that would f*** a person in the a** and not even have the goddamn common courtesy to give him a reach-around!" But let's not be too harsh: the second part, if remarkably more serious, is again entertaining and because of the excellently crafted war scenes utterly gripping. Typically for a Kubrick film, Full Metal Jacket has a lot of ongoing themes and motifs in it that you may not even recognize when watching it for the first time. He's dealing with sexuality and not only in the two scenes in which Vietnamese hookers appear. The recruits have an absurd relationship with their rifle - especially D'Onofrio's character - and in the film's second part the killing scenes seem to bring an orgasmic feeling to the soldiers. Furthermore, you can probably correctly interpret religious imagery as well as father-mother-child themes into the movie - the minute director Stanley Kubrick is likely to have intended all of them. But you don't even need to think about the film in such a 'sophisticated' way, Mr. K shows a great game with the war scenes already. There may not be as many as in genre classics Apocalypse Now or Platoon and, admittedly, they don't have the aesthetic greatness that the ones in the aforementioned Coppola flick had. However, what Full Metal Jacket has is an authenticity that is even more impressive if you are aware that the Vietnam scenes where in fact shot in a disused gas work in the vicinity of London. Kubrick made the most out of it and also did terrific work with the sound and the editing which is impeccable. Because Kubrick wanted to make the recruits as one multi-persona character, there isn't as much to find out about the individual characters as some people may have wished for. Yet still, there is a very interesting and often only subliminal character study on the protagonist, Private Joker. Most of all, while Full Metal Jacket has the same view on war as the majority of other war films (even though the movie's protagonist is a war advocate, Kubrick himself is, of course, against war - I hope you noticed that), it shows us something new. A partly documentary and partly alarming new take that could have been boring. Thanks to Kubrick, it's not. At least not at the first time watching it - the prolonged war scenes lose their thrill once you know what's going to happen.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Let's talk about the source material
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jackhammer111
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The movie is well reviewed by others and most people find it very compelling. I like it to but am bothered by some shifts in tone in the final third although I think Kubrick deserves credit for not dodging the issue of atrocities. I prefer war movies that don't glorify war more as in "Platoon" or the great German U-Boat film "Das Boot" (see it in German with English subtitles, when they overdubbed it in English they wrecked a great background soundtrack). All in all there's a bit too much flag waving in this for me but it's a great movie but I can help remembering that part of the promotion for "Full Metal Jacket" including displaying the novel that served as source material for it in supermarket checkout lanes. Seeing Kubrick's name on it I picked it up. The novel was called "the Short Timers" written by Marine Gustav Hasford who was in theater during 1968-69. The great prolific essayist, columnist, novelist, screen writer (including my favorite sci fi movie, "a Boy and his Dog") Harlan Ellison said of Short timers "It is one of the most amazing stretches of writing I've ever encountered." Even though I know this is a movie review, not a book review, I have to tell you the source for most of the movie was written largely in a different kind of English called jarhead lingo. It was very cool to read inspired sections that are prose written with those word. Unfortunately, way more people were interested in watching Kubrick's movie than reading the real deal, the book didn't sell well, his deal with Kubrick wasn't very good and Hasford died alone almost broke in a motel room in Greece of heart related diabetic problems. I don't know which is more heartbreaking. Hasford's early death or the fact that "the Short Timers" is out of print while people still buy Kubrick's movie and somebody gets paid. The book has now become a rather expensive collector's item selling online for between $15 and upwards of $400. If you Google the title and his name you'll find a link to a scribd page that will load the whole book like a pdf. But you can't save or download it without paying. But you can read it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The best Marine Corps Bootcamp movie ever!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    sftd1973
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is a great movie that really depicts the life of a recruit going through Marine Corps Recruit Training. It is so real and straight to the point. Even with the additional Hollywood input in the movie, it still displays that reality that recruits go through to become United States Marines. Skip to the Viet Nam half of the movie. The Tet Offensive was a great part of the history of the Viet Nam war and this movie captures that history in great detail. The scenes of the fighting in the city is unique because most Viet Nam movies only show the fighting in the jungles and the rice patties and villages. Stanley Kubrick outdid himself with this movie and R. Lee Ermey immortalized himself as the Senior Drill Instructor and as the Gunnery Sergeant that everyone will always think of when anyone mentions the Marine Corps. Mathew Modine was outside himself in this movie and played a character that is totally outside of his normal range of characters. I give him a 10 along with R. Lee Ermey a 10 as well.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    R. Lee Ermey.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    AaronCapenBanner
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    R. Lee Ermey dominates this Stanley Kubrick directed Vietnam War drama, as he plays profane, no-nonsense, ultra tough Gunnery Sergeant Hartman, who belittles, browbeats, and insults the marine recruits in brutal boot camp training. Vincent D'Onofrio plays a slow-witted recruit who gets it the worst from Hartman, until he finds out that he is quite good at shooting... Mathew Modine plays "Joker", since he has an overt sense of humor that also captures the attention of Hartman, whose relentless, unmerciful verbal attacks take their toll in ways he didn't imagine... Film then picks up later, as Joker is a war correspondent for Stars & Stripes, who witnesses first hand the insanity of Vietnam... R. Lee Ermey so dominates the first half of the film(in an unforgettable, searing portrayal of dehumanization) that, when his part is over, it leaves a looming shadow over the rest of the film that is never lifted, though it is still a well-presented look at the war, though nothing exceptional. Worth watching for Ermey, who should have received an Academy Award!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A film of two halves
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tcr1991
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    'Full Metal Jacket' was a film that I had been meaning to watch for a while after all the good stuff I had heard about it. It really is a film of two halves, unfortunately I didn't like the 2nd half. The 1st half at boot camp was excellent, we saw a lot of character development and emotion as well as a lot of humour and really serious issues. R. Lee Ermey and Vincent D'Onofrio were just brilliant. The 2nd half I didn't enjoy as much, it looked great and there was a lot of action but it was just a bit boring and felt really dragged out, whereas the 1st part just had everything that you wanted. Glad I got round to seeing it but wouldn't watch it again, slightly disappointed after a really good start to the film. 6/10.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Bootcamp can be fun....Sometimes
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    A Stoners Review
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Really good movie. It's plot is mainly following a youngster through boot camp into the Vietnam war. The truth is throughout boot camp this movie is a gem. But once they go to war it kinda slows down a bit, and its not all that great towards the end, but don't get me wrong, it's still really good. I know I gave it an 8 but it's more like a 7.8 or something. All in all it's a hell of a movie. I say smoke a few bowls, relax and let this movie take you through the life a youngster during the days when boot camp really put you through some snit. If you haven't seen it, it is a must my friend. Peace out my fellow stoner's and may the weed take you away.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of my top ten
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    sraloff
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie is great. Great story, great acting and a lot of memorable scenes. You know a movie is good if you here quotes from it on a regular basis from people who probably don't even know where the saying came from (ie the younger generations). I love how it takes you from boot camp to the war and lets the viewer experience every aspect of the Vietnam war. It was a gritty time and the movie pulls no punches: if you are creating killing machines you have to be tough. Unlike todays army that is volunteer, most were there not by choice and the basic training scenes show the deconstruction of a boy and the construction of a soldier. The war scenes show these newly minted soldiers struggling to maintain their human element. We watch as the try and find balance between taking lives and knowing they will have to live theirs upon return. Many of these actors went on to play other great roles and I can't help but think it was due to their involvement with Full Metal Jacket.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    From boys to men to boys
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Marc Israel
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Events of dehumanization as learned scene by scene as coldly dictated by director Stanley Kubrick. Our Marines are always rallying around something white trying to hold onto their own values, themselves and, overall, their sanity. Much like "The Deer Hunter", this anti-war film is broken down into two parts, one prior to war, and then into the beast itself. While one movie shone an extra light on those stateside, Full Metal Jacket stayed with our boys and to what was left of themselves; their boyhood instincts (to defend each other) and their Mickey Mouse marches which drove the point home. This cold film doesn't bring you into each character as others might, but war is not about one person, is it? It is full of dogma (first to go, last to know), direction (our marines got lost) and dehumanization (see the first hour alone to hear the non-stop rant of Gunnery Seargent Hartman (Lee Ermey). Brutal and darkly funny, this is what I held onto as our narrator, Joker (Mathew Modine) is simply trying to fend off the brainwash, while it bounced off of Private Pyle (Vincent D'Onofrio) whose story tells us all Kubrick needed to say. That is why the second half of the film in Viet Nam seemed only to serve the audience a follow up and adventure as to what happened to some of our original boot camp marines. I still found the film both detached and personal, as if I was trying to fend off the disgracing of my viewers' soul. I like this film due to that internal struggle of whether or not to view war as acceptable.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not quite the full picture
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Prism10
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Stanley Kubrick, the eccentric director is lionised by Hollywood. A man who spent the latter part of his life living in London and shooting his films in England despite them being set elsewhere whether it was outer space, some hotel in the mountains of America or in this case a Vietnam war film. Full Metal Jacket arrived with plaudits from the critics. Its a film of two halves, the more interesting part being the first half set at boot camp with a sadistic drill instructor. The second half which is the more action based Vietnam set element is less interesting. Why? Because a year earlier we all watched 'Platoon' which swept the big prizes at the Oscars and directed by someone who served in Vietnam and fully conveyed the anti war message and politics of it all now that some years have passed by since the war ended. We saw Nam films before and better in Platoon and Apocalypse Now. Also these films although did not got to Vietnam, at least filmed in location whether it would be the Philippines or Thailand that is standing in. Full Metal Jacket was filmed in various parts of London dressed up as Vietnam. It shows, the sets do not look authentic, you do not get the feeling you are in the far east and it shows up the limitations of the second half of the story. It was too little and too late.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    War is not worth wasting our youth
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    StoryCharts
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Full Metal Jacket is about the idea that war is not worth wasting our youth. It tries to prove this with two stories: the first is the marines training for deployment, the second is the marines in action in Vietnam. The first story, the marines training for deployment, is told with two external plots: that of the not so bright marine Pyle trying to finish boot camp and the second is the entire class of marines trying to graduate. The class of marines succeed in graduating, but Pyle does not. He goes crazy after the harsh treatment meant to harden him to become a killer and commits suicide. So this story gets to the point that preparing for war is inhumane and not worth wasting our youth. The second story is about the marines fighting to win the war in Vietnam. This is told with two plots: that of winning the war and the second of the declining morality of the marines. The war is not won, it ends ambiguously as the marines win a small insignificant battle and return to camp while the morality of the marines shows a constant decline and ends with our hero committing murder. The movie is a great testament to the anti-war movement and a visual essay on the meaninglessness of war. But it is not a very engaging story. The first half of the movie makes a tight dramatic point that training marines to be killer has some inhumane consequences and proves it with Pyle's suicide. But the second half doesn't have an overall story arc to hang its hat on. The status of the main external plot of winning the war is left ambiguous. So the moral decline of our hero who has to commit murder at the end doesn't create as much meaning since the murder doesn't get us any further in winning the war. One can argue that that's the point of the movie, is that these atrocities are senseless and meaningless. And that is true. But in terms of a dramatic story, the meaning of the action is lost because the filmmakers abhorred making winning the war into any resemblance of a real plot. In the first half of the movie, Pyle's suicide is juxtaposed with the success of class of marines all graduating. Thus it makes the point that his suicide is not worth it for us to successfully train marines. But in the second half of the movie, Joker commits murder but this action is not juxtaposed with progression of any other plot. So the action loses the chance to create meaning through a consequence for his actions. It feels like the movie was cut off without any real resolution, like another 15 minutes were missing. My Story Chart of the movie is at storycharts.ca
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An outstanding and unique war movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    axel-koch
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    In 1987, 30 years after he'd firstly dealt with the subject of war in Paths of Glory, legendary American auteur Stanley Kubrick returned to the award-promising genre and released Full Metal Jacket. While it neither got the praise nor the awards it deserved when it came out, it has since then become a fan favorite and one of Kubrick's most beloved movies. Full Metal Jacket is split in two cohesive parts: the first and shorter one setting place at a military boot camp in South Carolina and the second one depicting the actual war events in Vietnam. The audience's relationship to the characters is supposed to be very distant and Kubrick lets us know very little about them. The narrator, nicknamed Joker, is a spectacled young man that believes to see through the military indoctrination. He tries to resist the system and, as he says himself, is only here to be the first kid on his block to get a confirmed kill. This is, of course, highly unconventional for a war movie protagonist and Matthew Modine plays him in a realistic, yet not particularly likable manner. Vincent D'Onofrio portrays the burly and universally untalented Private "Gomer Pyle", who gets permanently insulted and degraded by the vulgar and loud Drill Sergeant Hartman, who is played extraordinarily well by R. Lee Ermey, who was a real-life Drill Sergeant some time before. His eloquent and absolutely R-rated speeches are hilarious and simply the best part of the movie. It's sad somewhat, that his character doesn't accompany the recruits in the Vietnam War that follows; at some parts, I really wished for awesome one-liners like " I bet you're the kind of guy that would f*** a person in the a** and not even have the goddamn common courtesy to give him a reach-around!" But let's not be too harsh: the second part, if remarkably more serious, is again entertaining and because of the excellently crafted war scenes utterly gripping. Typically for a Kubrick film, Full Metal Jacket has a lot of ongoing themes and motifs in it that you may not even recognize when watching it for the first time. He's dealing with sexuality and not only in the two scenes in which Vietnamese hookers appear. The recruits have an absurd relationship with their rifle - especially D'Onofrio's character - and in the film's second part the killing scenes seem to bring an orgasmic feeling to the soldiers. Furthermore, you can probably correctly interpret religious imagery as well as father-mother-child themes into the movie - the minute director Stanley Kubrick is likely to have intended all of them. But you don't even need to think about the film in such a 'sophisticated' way, Mr. K shows a great game with the war scenes already. There may not be as many as in genre classics Apocalypse Now or Platoon and, admittedly, they don't have the aesthetic greatness that the ones in the aforementioned Coppola flick had. However, what Full Metal Jacket has is an authenticity that is even more impressive if you are aware that the Vietnam scenes where in fact shot in a disused gas work in the vicinity of London. Kubrick made the most out of it and also did terrific work with the sound and the editing which is impeccable. Because Kubrick wanted to make the recruits as one multi-persona character, there isn't as much to find out about the individual characters as some people may have wished for. Yet still, there is a very interesting and often only subliminal character study on the protagonist, Private Joker. Most of all, while Full Metal Jacket has the same view on war as the majority of other war films (even though the movie's protagonist is a war advocate, Kubrick himself is, of course, against war - I hope you noticed that), it shows us something new. A partly documentary and partly alarming new take that could have been boring. Thanks to Kubrick, it's not. At least not at the first time watching it - the prolonged war scenes lose their thrill once you know what's going to happen.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Let's talk about the source material
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jackhammer111
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The movie is well reviewed by others and most people find it very compelling. I like it to but am bothered by some shifts in tone in the final third although I think Kubrick deserves credit for not dodging the issue of atrocities. I prefer war movies that don't glorify war more as in "Platoon" or the great German U-Boat film "Das Boot" (see it in German with English subtitles, when they overdubbed it in English they wrecked a great background soundtrack). All in all there's a bit too much flag waving in this for me but it's a great movie but I can help remembering that part of the promotion for "Full Metal Jacket" including displaying the novel that served as source material for it in supermarket checkout lanes. Seeing Kubrick's name on it I picked it up. The novel was called "the Short Timers" written by Marine Gustav Hasford who was in theater during 1968-69. The great prolific essayist, columnist, novelist, screen writer (including my favorite sci fi movie, "a Boy and his Dog") Harlan Ellison said of Short timers "It is one of the most amazing stretches of writing I've ever encountered." Even though I know this is a movie review, not a book review, I have to tell you the source for most of the movie was written largely in a different kind of English called jarhead lingo. It was very cool to read inspired sections that are prose written with those word. Unfortunately, way more people were interested in watching Kubrick's movie than reading the real deal, the book didn't sell well, his deal with Kubrick wasn't very good and Hasford died alone almost broke in a motel room in Greece of heart related diabetic problems. I don't know which is more heartbreaking. Hasford's early death or the fact that "the Short Timers" is out of print while people still buy Kubrick's movie and somebody gets paid. The book has now become a rather expensive collector's item selling online for between $15 and upwards of $400. If you Google the title and his name you'll find a link to a scribd page that will load the whole book like a pdf. But you can't save or download it without paying. But you can read it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The best Marine Corps Bootcamp movie ever!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    sftd1973
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is a great movie that really depicts the life of a recruit going through Marine Corps Recruit Training. It is so real and straight to the point. Even with the additional Hollywood input in the movie, it still displays that reality that recruits go through to become United States Marines. Skip to the Viet Nam half of the movie. The Tet Offensive was a great part of the history of the Viet Nam war and this movie captures that history in great detail. The scenes of the fighting in the city is unique because most Viet Nam movies only show the fighting in the jungles and the rice patties and villages. Stanley Kubrick outdid himself with this movie and R. Lee Ermey immortalized himself as the Senior Drill Instructor and as the Gunnery Sergeant that everyone will always think of when anyone mentions the Marine Corps. Mathew Modine was outside himself in this movie and played a character that is totally outside of his normal range of characters. I give him a 10 along with R. Lee Ermey a 10 as well.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    R. Lee Ermey.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    AaronCapenBanner
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    R. Lee Ermey dominates this Stanley Kubrick directed Vietnam War drama, as he plays profane, no-nonsense, ultra tough Gunnery Sergeant Hartman, who belittles, browbeats, and insults the marine recruits in brutal boot camp training. Vincent D'Onofrio plays a slow-witted recruit who gets it the worst from Hartman, until he finds out that he is quite good at shooting... Mathew Modine plays "Joker", since he has an overt sense of humor that also captures the attention of Hartman, whose relentless, unmerciful verbal attacks take their toll in ways he didn't imagine... Film then picks up later, as Joker is a war correspondent for Stars & Stripes, who witnesses first hand the insanity of Vietnam... R. Lee Ermey so dominates the first half of the film(in an unforgettable, searing portrayal of dehumanization) that, when his part is over, it leaves a looming shadow over the rest of the film that is never lifted, though it is still a well-presented look at the war, though nothing exceptional. Worth watching for Ermey, who should have received an Academy Award!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A film of two halves
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tcr1991
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    'Full Metal Jacket' was a film that I had been meaning to watch for a while after all the good stuff I had heard about it. It really is a film of two halves, unfortunately I didn't like the 2nd half. The 1st half at boot camp was excellent, we saw a lot of character development and emotion as well as a lot of humour and really serious issues. R. Lee Ermey and Vincent D'Onofrio were just brilliant. The 2nd half I didn't enjoy as much, it looked great and there was a lot of action but it was just a bit boring and felt really dragged out, whereas the 1st part just had everything that you wanted. Glad I got round to seeing it but wouldn't watch it again, slightly disappointed after a really good start to the film. 6/10.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Bootcamp can be fun....Sometimes
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    A Stoners Review
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Really good movie. It's plot is mainly following a youngster through boot camp into the Vietnam war. The truth is throughout boot camp this movie is a gem. But once they go to war it kinda slows down a bit, and its not all that great towards the end, but don't get me wrong, it's still really good. I know I gave it an 8 but it's more like a 7.8 or something. All in all it's a hell of a movie. I say smoke a few bowls, relax and let this movie take you through the life a youngster during the days when boot camp really put you through some snit. If you haven't seen it, it is a must my friend. Peace out my fellow stoner's and may the weed take you away.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of my top ten
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    sraloff
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie is great. Great story, great acting and a lot of memorable scenes. You know a movie is good if you here quotes from it on a regular basis from people who probably don't even know where the saying came from (ie the younger generations). I love how it takes you from boot camp to the war and lets the viewer experience every aspect of the Vietnam war. It was a gritty time and the movie pulls no punches: if you are creating killing machines you have to be tough. Unlike todays army that is volunteer, most were there not by choice and the basic training scenes show the deconstruction of a boy and the construction of a soldier. The war scenes show these newly minted soldiers struggling to maintain their human element. We watch as the try and find balance between taking lives and knowing they will have to live theirs upon return. Many of these actors went on to play other great roles and I can't help but think it was due to their involvement with Full Metal Jacket.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    From boys to men to boys
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Marc Israel
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Events of dehumanization as learned scene by scene as coldly dictated by director Stanley Kubrick. Our Marines are always rallying around something white trying to hold onto their own values, themselves and, overall, their sanity. Much like "The Deer Hunter", this anti-war film is broken down into two parts, one prior to war, and then into the beast itself. While one movie shone an extra light on those stateside, Full Metal Jacket stayed with our boys and to what was left of themselves; their boyhood instincts (to defend each other) and their Mickey Mouse marches which drove the point home. This cold film doesn't bring you into each character as others might, but war is not about one person, is it? It is full of dogma (first to go, last to know), direction (our marines got lost) and dehumanization (see the first hour alone to hear the non-stop rant of Gunnery Seargent Hartman (Lee Ermey). Brutal and darkly funny, this is what I held onto as our narrator, Joker (Mathew Modine) is simply trying to fend off the brainwash, while it bounced off of Private Pyle (Vincent D'Onofrio) whose story tells us all Kubrick needed to say. That is why the second half of the film in Viet Nam seemed only to serve the audience a follow up and adventure as to what happened to some of our original boot camp marines. I still found the film both detached and personal, as if I was trying to fend off the disgracing of my viewers' soul. I like this film due to that internal struggle of whether or not to view war as acceptable.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not quite the full picture
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Prism10
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Stanley Kubrick, the eccentric director is lionised by Hollywood. A man who spent the latter part of his life living in London and shooting his films in England despite them being set elsewhere whether it was outer space, some hotel in the mountains of America or in this case a Vietnam war film. Full Metal Jacket arrived with plaudits from the critics. Its a film of two halves, the more interesting part being the first half set at boot camp with a sadistic drill instructor. The second half which is the more action based Vietnam set element is less interesting. Why? Because a year earlier we all watched 'Platoon' which swept the big prizes at the Oscars and directed by someone who served in Vietnam and fully conveyed the anti war message and politics of it all now that some years have passed by since the war ended. We saw Nam films before and better in Platoon and Apocalypse Now. Also these films although did not got to Vietnam, at least filmed in location whether it would be the Philippines or Thailand that is standing in. Full Metal Jacket was filmed in various parts of London dressed up as Vietnam. It shows, the sets do not look authentic, you do not get the feeling you are in the far east and it shows up the limitations of the second half of the story. It was too little and too late.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    War is not worth wasting our youth
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    StoryCharts
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Full Metal Jacket is about the idea that war is not worth wasting our youth. It tries to prove this with two stories: the first is the marines training for deployment, the second is the marines in action in Vietnam. The first story, the marines training for deployment, is told with two external plots: that of the not so bright marine Pyle trying to finish boot camp and the second is the entire class of marines trying to graduate. The class of marines succeed in graduating, but Pyle does not. He goes crazy after the harsh treatment meant to harden him to become a killer and commits suicide. So this story gets to the point that preparing for war is inhumane and not worth wasting our youth. The second story is about the marines fighting to win the war in Vietnam. This is told with two plots: that of winning the war and the second of the declining morality of the marines. The war is not won, it ends ambiguously as the marines win a small insignificant battle and return to camp while the morality of the marines shows a constant decline and ends with our hero committing murder. The movie is a great testament to the anti-war movement and a visual essay on the meaninglessness of war. But it is not a very engaging story. The first half of the movie makes a tight dramatic point that training marines to be killer has some inhumane consequences and proves it with Pyle's suicide. But the second half doesn't have an overall story arc to hang its hat on. The status of the main external plot of winning the war is left ambiguous. So the moral decline of our hero who has to commit murder at the end doesn't create as much meaning since the murder doesn't get us any further in winning the war. One can argue that that's the point of the movie, is that these atrocities are senseless and meaningless. And that is true. But in terms of a dramatic story, the meaning of the action is lost because the filmmakers abhorred making winning the war into any resemblance of a real plot. In the first half of the movie, Pyle's suicide is juxtaposed with the success of class of marines all graduating. Thus it makes the point that his suicide is not worth it for us to successfully train marines. But in the second half of the movie, Joker commits murder but this action is not juxtaposed with progression of any other plot. So the action loses the chance to create meaning through a consequence for his actions. It feels like the movie was cut off without any real resolution, like another 15 minutes were missing. My Story Chart of the movie is at storycharts.ca
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An outstanding and unique war movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    axel-koch
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    In 1987, 30 years after he'd firstly dealt with the subject of war in Paths of Glory, legendary American auteur Stanley Kubrick returned to the award-promising genre and released Full Metal Jacket. While it neither got the praise nor the awards it deserved when it came out, it has since then become a fan favorite and one of Kubrick's most beloved movies. Full Metal Jacket is split in two cohesive parts: the first and shorter one setting place at a military boot camp in South Carolina and the second one depicting the actual war events in Vietnam. The audience's relationship to the characters is supposed to be very distant and Kubrick lets us know very little about them. The narrator, nicknamed Joker, is a spectacled young man that believes to see through the military indoctrination. He tries to resist the system and, as he says himself, is only here to be the first kid on his block to get a confirmed kill. This is, of course, highly unconventional for a war movie protagonist and Matthew Modine plays him in a realistic, yet not particularly likable manner. Vincent D'Onofrio portrays the burly and universally untalented Private "Gomer Pyle", who gets permanently insulted and degraded by the vulgar and loud Drill Sergeant Hartman, who is played extraordinarily well by R. Lee Ermey, who was a real-life Drill Sergeant some time before. His eloquent and absolutely R-rated speeches are hilarious and simply the best part of the movie. It's sad somewhat, that his character doesn't accompany the recruits in the Vietnam War that follows; at some parts, I really wished for awesome one-liners like " I bet you're the kind of guy that would f*** a person in the a** and not even have the goddamn common courtesy to give him a reach-around!" But let's not be too harsh: the second part, if remarkably more serious, is again entertaining and because of the excellently crafted war scenes utterly gripping. Typically for a Kubrick film, Full Metal Jacket has a lot of ongoing themes and motifs in it that you may not even recognize when watching it for the first time. He's dealing with sexuality and not only in the two scenes in which Vietnamese hookers appear. The recruits have an absurd relationship with their rifle - especially D'Onofrio's character - and in the film's second part the killing scenes seem to bring an orgasmic feeling to the soldiers. Furthermore, you can probably correctly interpret religious imagery as well as father-mother-child themes into the movie - the minute director Stanley Kubrick is likely to have intended all of them. But you don't even need to think about the film in such a 'sophisticated' way, Mr. K shows a great game with the war scenes already. There may not be as many as in genre classics Apocalypse Now or Platoon and, admittedly, they don't have the aesthetic greatness that the ones in the aforementioned Coppola flick had. However, what Full Metal Jacket has is an authenticity that is even more impressive if you are aware that the Vietnam scenes where in fact shot in a disused gas work in the vicinity of London. Kubrick made the most out of it and also did terrific work with the sound and the editing which is impeccable. Because Kubrick wanted to make the recruits as one multi-persona character, there isn't as much to find out about the individual characters as some people may have wished for. Yet still, there is a very interesting and often only subliminal character study on the protagonist, Private Joker. Most of all, while Full Metal Jacket has the same view on war as the majority of other war films (even though the movie's protagonist is a war advocate, Kubrick himself is, of course, against war - I hope you noticed that), it shows us something new. A partly documentary and partly alarming new take that could have been boring. Thanks to Kubrick, it's not. At least not at the first time watching it - the prolonged war scenes lose their thrill once you know what's going to happen.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Let's talk about the source material
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jackhammer111
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The movie is well reviewed by others and most people find it very compelling. I like it to but am bothered by some shifts in tone in the final third although I think Kubrick deserves credit for not dodging the issue of atrocities. I prefer war movies that don't glorify war more as in "Platoon" or the great German U-Boat film "Das Boot" (see it in German with English subtitles, when they overdubbed it in English they wrecked a great background soundtrack). All in all there's a bit too much flag waving in this for me but it's a great movie but I can help remembering that part of the promotion for "Full Metal Jacket" including displaying the novel that served as source material for it in supermarket checkout lanes. Seeing Kubrick's name on it I picked it up. The novel was called "the Short Timers" written by Marine Gustav Hasford who was in theater during 1968-69. The great prolific essayist, columnist, novelist, screen writer (including my favorite sci fi movie, "a Boy and his Dog") Harlan Ellison said of Short timers "It is one of the most amazing stretches of writing I've ever encountered." Even though I know this is a movie review, not a book review, I have to tell you the source for most of the movie was written largely in a different kind of English called jarhead lingo. It was very cool to read inspired sections that are prose written with those word. Unfortunately, way more people were interested in watching Kubrick's movie than reading the real deal, the book didn't sell well, his deal with Kubrick wasn't very good and Hasford died alone almost broke in a motel room in Greece of heart related diabetic problems. I don't know which is more heartbreaking. Hasford's early death or the fact that "the Short Timers" is out of print while people still buy Kubrick's movie and somebody gets paid. The book has now become a rather expensive collector's item selling online for between $15 and upwards of $400. If you Google the title and his name you'll find a link to a scribd page that will load the whole book like a pdf. But you can't save or download it without paying. But you can read it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The best Marine Corps Bootcamp movie ever!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    sftd1973
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is a great movie that really depicts the life of a recruit going through Marine Corps Recruit Training. It is so real and straight to the point. Even with the additional Hollywood input in the movie, it still displays that reality that recruits go through to become United States Marines. Skip to the Viet Nam half of the movie. The Tet Offensive was a great part of the history of the Viet Nam war and this movie captures that history in great detail. The scenes of the fighting in the city is unique because most Viet Nam movies only show the fighting in the jungles and the rice patties and villages. Stanley Kubrick outdid himself with this movie and R. Lee Ermey immortalized himself as the Senior Drill Instructor and as the Gunnery Sergeant that everyone will always think of when anyone mentions the Marine Corps. Mathew Modine was outside himself in this movie and played a character that is totally outside of his normal range of characters. I give him a 10 along with R. Lee Ermey a 10 as well.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    R. Lee Ermey.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    AaronCapenBanner
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    R. Lee Ermey dominates this Stanley Kubrick directed Vietnam War drama, as he plays profane, no-nonsense, ultra tough Gunnery Sergeant Hartman, who belittles, browbeats, and insults the marine recruits in brutal boot camp training. Vincent D'Onofrio plays a slow-witted recruit who gets it the worst from Hartman, until he finds out that he is quite good at shooting... Mathew Modine plays "Joker", since he has an overt sense of humor that also captures the attention of Hartman, whose relentless, unmerciful verbal attacks take their toll in ways he didn't imagine... Film then picks up later, as Joker is a war correspondent for Stars & Stripes, who witnesses first hand the insanity of Vietnam... R. Lee Ermey so dominates the first half of the film(in an unforgettable, searing portrayal of dehumanization) that, when his part is over, it leaves a looming shadow over the rest of the film that is never lifted, though it is still a well-presented look at the war, though nothing exceptional. Worth watching for Ermey, who should have received an Academy Award!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A film of two halves
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tcr1991
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    'Full Metal Jacket' was a film that I had been meaning to watch for a while after all the good stuff I had heard about it. It really is a film of two halves, unfortunately I didn't like the 2nd half. The 1st half at boot camp was excellent, we saw a lot of character development and emotion as well as a lot of humour and really serious issues. R. Lee Ermey and Vincent D'Onofrio were just brilliant. The 2nd half I didn't enjoy as much, it looked great and there was a lot of action but it was just a bit boring and felt really dragged out, whereas the 1st part just had everything that you wanted. Glad I got round to seeing it but wouldn't watch it again, slightly disappointed after a really good start to the film. 6/10.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Bootcamp can be fun....Sometimes
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    A Stoners Review
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Really good movie. It's plot is mainly following a youngster through boot camp into the Vietnam war. The truth is throughout boot camp this movie is a gem. But once they go to war it kinda slows down a bit, and its not all that great towards the end, but don't get me wrong, it's still really good. I know I gave it an 8 but it's more like a 7.8 or something. All in all it's a hell of a movie. I say smoke a few bowls, relax and let this movie take you through the life a youngster during the days when boot camp really put you through some snit. If you haven't seen it, it is a must my friend. Peace out my fellow stoner's and may the weed take you away.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of my top ten
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    sraloff
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie is great. Great story, great acting and a lot of memorable scenes. You know a movie is good if you here quotes from it on a regular basis from people who probably don't even know where the saying came from (ie the younger generations). I love how it takes you from boot camp to the war and lets the viewer experience every aspect of the Vietnam war. It was a gritty time and the movie pulls no punches: if you are creating killing machines you have to be tough. Unlike todays army that is volunteer, most were there not by choice and the basic training scenes show the deconstruction of a boy and the construction of a soldier. The war scenes show these newly minted soldiers struggling to maintain their human element. We watch as the try and find balance between taking lives and knowing they will have to live theirs upon return. Many of these actors went on to play other great roles and I can't help but think it was due to their involvement with Full Metal Jacket.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    From boys to men to boys
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Marc Israel
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Events of dehumanization as learned scene by scene as coldly dictated by director Stanley Kubrick. Our Marines are always rallying around something white trying to hold onto their own values, themselves and, overall, their sanity. Much like "The Deer Hunter", this anti-war film is broken down into two parts, one prior to war, and then into the beast itself. While one movie shone an extra light on those stateside, Full Metal Jacket stayed with our boys and to what was left of themselves; their boyhood instincts (to defend each other) and their Mickey Mouse marches which drove the point home. This cold film doesn't bring you into each character as others might, but war is not about one person, is it? It is full of dogma (first to go, last to know), direction (our marines got lost) and dehumanization (see the first hour alone to hear the non-stop rant of Gunnery Seargent Hartman (Lee Ermey). Brutal and darkly funny, this is what I held onto as our narrator, Joker (Mathew Modine) is simply trying to fend off the brainwash, while it bounced off of Private Pyle (Vincent D'Onofrio) whose story tells us all Kubrick needed to say. That is why the second half of the film in Viet Nam seemed only to serve the audience a follow up and adventure as to what happened to some of our original boot camp marines. I still found the film both detached and personal, as if I was trying to fend off the disgracing of my viewers' soul. I like this film due to that internal struggle of whether or not to view war as acceptable.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not quite the full picture
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Prism10
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Stanley Kubrick, the eccentric director is lionised by Hollywood. A man who spent the latter part of his life living in London and shooting his films in England despite them being set elsewhere whether it was outer space, some hotel in the mountains of America or in this case a Vietnam war film. Full Metal Jacket arrived with plaudits from the critics. Its a film of two halves, the more interesting part being the first half set at boot camp with a sadistic drill instructor. The second half which is the more action based Vietnam set element is less interesting. Why? Because a year earlier we all watched 'Platoon' which swept the big prizes at the Oscars and directed by someone who served in Vietnam and fully conveyed the anti war message and politics of it all now that some years have passed by since the war ended. We saw Nam films before and better in Platoon and Apocalypse Now. Also these films although did not got to Vietnam, at least filmed in location whether it would be the Philippines or Thailand that is standing in. Full Metal Jacket was filmed in various parts of London dressed up as Vietnam. It shows, the sets do not look authentic, you do not get the feeling you are in the far east and it shows up the limitations of the second half of the story. It was too little and too late.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    War is not worth wasting our youth
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    StoryCharts
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Full Metal Jacket is about the idea that war is not worth wasting our youth. It tries to prove this with two stories: the first is the marines training for deployment, the second is the marines in action in Vietnam. The first story, the marines training for deployment, is told with two external plots: that of the not so bright marine Pyle trying to finish boot camp and the second is the entire class of marines trying to graduate. The class of marines succeed in graduating, but Pyle does not. He goes crazy after the harsh treatment meant to harden him to become a killer and commits suicide. So this story gets to the point that preparing for war is inhumane and not worth wasting our youth. The second story is about the marines fighting to win the war in Vietnam. This is told with two plots: that of winning the war and the second of the declining morality of the marines. The war is not won, it ends ambiguously as the marines win a small insignificant battle and return to camp while the morality of the marines shows a constant decline and ends with our hero committing murder. The movie is a great testament to the anti-war movement and a visual essay on the meaninglessness of war. But it is not a very engaging story. The first half of the movie makes a tight dramatic point that training marines to be killer has some inhumane consequences and proves it with Pyle's suicide. But the second half doesn't have an overall story arc to hang its hat on. The status of the main external plot of winning the war is left ambiguous. So the moral decline of our hero who has to commit murder at the end doesn't create as much meaning since the murder doesn't get us any further in winning the war. One can argue that that's the point of the movie, is that these atrocities are senseless and meaningless. And that is true. But in terms of a dramatic story, the meaning of the action is lost because the filmmakers abhorred making winning the war into any resemblance of a real plot. In the first half of the movie, Pyle's suicide is juxtaposed with the success of class of marines all graduating. Thus it makes the point that his suicide is not worth it for us to successfully train marines. But in the second half of the movie, Joker commits murder but this action is not juxtaposed with progression of any other plot. So the action loses the chance to create meaning through a consequence for his actions. It feels like the movie was cut off without any real resolution, like another 15 minutes were missing. My Story Chart of the movie is at storycharts.ca
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An outstanding and unique war movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    axel-koch
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    In 1987, 30 years after he'd firstly dealt with the subject of war in Paths of Glory, legendary American auteur Stanley Kubrick returned to the award-promising genre and released Full Metal Jacket. While it neither got the praise nor the awards it deserved when it came out, it has since then become a fan favorite and one of Kubrick's most beloved movies. Full Metal Jacket is split in two cohesive parts: the first and shorter one setting place at a military boot camp in South Carolina and the second one depicting the actual war events in Vietnam. The audience's relationship to the characters is supposed to be very distant and Kubrick lets us know very little about them. The narrator, nicknamed Joker, is a spectacled young man that believes to see through the military indoctrination. He tries to resist the system and, as he says himself, is only here to be the first kid on his block to get a confirmed kill. This is, of course, highly unconventional for a war movie protagonist and Matthew Modine plays him in a realistic, yet not particularly likable manner. Vincent D'Onofrio portrays the burly and universally untalented Private "Gomer Pyle", who gets permanently insulted and degraded by the vulgar and loud Drill Sergeant Hartman, who is played extraordinarily well by R. Lee Ermey, who was a real-life Drill Sergeant some time before. His eloquent and absolutely R-rated speeches are hilarious and simply the best part of the movie. It's sad somewhat, that his character doesn't accompany the recruits in the Vietnam War that follows; at some parts, I really wished for awesome one-liners like " I bet you're the kind of guy that would f*** a person in the a** and not even have the goddamn common courtesy to give him a reach-around!" But let's not be too harsh: the second part, if remarkably more serious, is again entertaining and because of the excellently crafted war scenes utterly gripping. Typically for a Kubrick film, Full Metal Jacket has a lot of ongoing themes and motifs in it that you may not even recognize when watching it for the first time. He's dealing with sexuality and not only in the two scenes in which Vietnamese hookers appear. The recruits have an absurd relationship with their rifle - especially D'Onofrio's character - and in the film's second part the killing scenes seem to bring an orgasmic feeling to the soldiers. Furthermore, you can probably correctly interpret religious imagery as well as father-mother-child themes into the movie - the minute director Stanley Kubrick is likely to have intended all of them. But you don't even need to think about the film in such a 'sophisticated' way, Mr. K shows a great game with the war scenes already. There may not be as many as in genre classics Apocalypse Now or Platoon and, admittedly, they don't have the aesthetic greatness that the ones in the aforementioned Coppola flick had. However, what Full Metal Jacket has is an authenticity that is even more impressive if you are aware that the Vietnam scenes where in fact shot in a disused gas work in the vicinity of London. Kubrick made the most out of it and also did terrific work with the sound and the editing which is impeccable. Because Kubrick wanted to make the recruits as one multi-persona character, there isn't as much to find out about the individual characters as some people may have wished for. Yet still, there is a very interesting and often only subliminal character study on the protagonist, Private Joker. Most of all, while Full Metal Jacket has the same view on war as the majority of other war films (even though the movie's protagonist is a war advocate, Kubrick himself is, of course, against war - I hope you noticed that), it shows us something new. A partly documentary and partly alarming new take that could have been boring. Thanks to Kubrick, it's not. At least not at the first time watching it - the prolonged war scenes lose their thrill once you know what's going to happen.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Let's talk about the source material
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jackhammer111
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The movie is well reviewed by others and most people find it very compelling. I like it to but am bothered by some shifts in tone in the final third although I think Kubrick deserves credit for not dodging the issue of atrocities. I prefer war movies that don't glorify war more as in "Platoon" or the great German U-Boat film "Das Boot" (see it in German with English subtitles, when they overdubbed it in English they wrecked a great background soundtrack). All in all there's a bit too much flag waving in this for me but it's a great movie but I can help remembering that part of the promotion for "Full Metal Jacket" including displaying the novel that served as source material for it in supermarket checkout lanes. Seeing Kubrick's name on it I picked it up. The novel was called "the Short Timers" written by Marine Gustav Hasford who was in theater during 1968-69. The great prolific essayist, columnist, novelist, screen writer (including my favorite sci fi movie, "a Boy and his Dog") Harlan Ellison said of Short timers "It is one of the most amazing stretches of writing I've ever encountered." Even though I know this is a movie review, not a book review, I have to tell you the source for most of the movie was written largely in a different kind of English called jarhead lingo. It was very cool to read inspired sections that are prose written with those word. Unfortunately, way more people were interested in watching Kubrick's movie than reading the real deal, the book didn't sell well, his deal with Kubrick wasn't very good and Hasford died alone almost broke in a motel room in Greece of heart related diabetic problems. I don't know which is more heartbreaking. Hasford's early death or the fact that "the Short Timers" is out of print while people still buy Kubrick's movie and somebody gets paid. The book has now become a rather expensive collector's item selling online for between $15 and upwards of $400. If you Google the title and his name you'll find a link to a scribd page that will load the whole book like a pdf. But you can't save or download it without paying. But you can read it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The best Marine Corps Bootcamp movie ever!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    sftd1973
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is a great movie that really depicts the life of a recruit going through Marine Corps Recruit Training. It is so real and straight to the point. Even with the additional Hollywood input in the movie, it still displays that reality that recruits go through to become United States Marines. Skip to the Viet Nam half of the movie. The Tet Offensive was a great part of the history of the Viet Nam war and this movie captures that history in great detail. The scenes of the fighting in the city is unique because most Viet Nam movies only show the fighting in the jungles and the rice patties and villages. Stanley Kubrick outdid himself with this movie and R. Lee Ermey immortalized himself as the Senior Drill Instructor and as the Gunnery Sergeant that everyone will always think of when anyone mentions the Marine Corps. Mathew Modine was outside himself in this movie and played a character that is totally outside of his normal range of characters. I give him a 10 along with R. Lee Ermey a 10 as well.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    R. Lee Ermey.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    AaronCapenBanner
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    R. Lee Ermey dominates this Stanley Kubrick directed Vietnam War drama, as he plays profane, no-nonsense, ultra tough Gunnery Sergeant Hartman, who belittles, browbeats, and insults the marine recruits in brutal boot camp training. Vincent D'Onofrio plays a slow-witted recruit who gets it the worst from Hartman, until he finds out that he is quite good at shooting... Mathew Modine plays "Joker", since he has an overt sense of humor that also captures the attention of Hartman, whose relentless, unmerciful verbal attacks take their toll in ways he didn't imagine... Film then picks up later, as Joker is a war correspondent for Stars & Stripes, who witnesses first hand the insanity of Vietnam... R. Lee Ermey so dominates the first half of the film(in an unforgettable, searing portrayal of dehumanization) that, when his part is over, it leaves a looming shadow over the rest of the film that is never lifted, though it is still a well-presented look at the war, though nothing exceptional. Worth watching for Ermey, who should have received an Academy Award!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A film of two halves
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tcr1991
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    'Full Metal Jacket' was a film that I had been meaning to watch for a while after all the good stuff I had heard about it. It really is a film of two halves, unfortunately I didn't like the 2nd half. The 1st half at boot camp was excellent, we saw a lot of character development and emotion as well as a lot of humour and really serious issues. R. Lee Ermey and Vincent D'Onofrio were just brilliant. The 2nd half I didn't enjoy as much, it looked great and there was a lot of action but it was just a bit boring and felt really dragged out, whereas the 1st part just had everything that you wanted. Glad I got round to seeing it but wouldn't watch it again, slightly disappointed after a really good start to the film. 6/10.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Bootcamp can be fun....Sometimes
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    A Stoners Review
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Really good movie. It's plot is mainly following a youngster through boot camp into the Vietnam war. The truth is throughout boot camp this movie is a gem. But once they go to war it kinda slows down a bit, and its not all that great towards the end, but don't get me wrong, it's still really good. I know I gave it an 8 but it's more like a 7.8 or something. All in all it's a hell of a movie. I say smoke a few bowls, relax and let this movie take you through the life a youngster during the days when boot camp really put you through some snit. If you haven't seen it, it is a must my friend. Peace out my fellow stoner's and may the weed take you away.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of my top ten
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    sraloff
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie is great. Great story, great acting and a lot of memorable scenes. You know a movie is good if you here quotes from it on a regular basis from people who probably don't even know where the saying came from (ie the younger generations). I love how it takes you from boot camp to the war and lets the viewer experience every aspect of the Vietnam war. It was a gritty time and the movie pulls no punches: if you are creating killing machines you have to be tough. Unlike todays army that is volunteer, most were there not by choice and the basic training scenes show the deconstruction of a boy and the construction of a soldier. The war scenes show these newly minted soldiers struggling to maintain their human element. We watch as the try and find balance between taking lives and knowing they will have to live theirs upon return. Many of these actors went on to play other great roles and I can't help but think it was due to their involvement with Full Metal Jacket.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    From boys to men to boys
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Marc Israel
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Events of dehumanization as learned scene by scene as coldly dictated by director Stanley Kubrick. Our Marines are always rallying around something white trying to hold onto their own values, themselves and, overall, their sanity. Much like "The Deer Hunter", this anti-war film is broken down into two parts, one prior to war, and then into the beast itself. While one movie shone an extra light on those stateside, Full Metal Jacket stayed with our boys and to what was left of themselves; their boyhood instincts (to defend each other) and their Mickey Mouse marches which drove the point home. This cold film doesn't bring you into each character as others might, but war is not about one person, is it? It is full of dogma (first to go, last to know), direction (our marines got lost) and dehumanization (see the first hour alone to hear the non-stop rant of Gunnery Seargent Hartman (Lee Ermey). Brutal and darkly funny, this is what I held onto as our narrator, Joker (Mathew Modine) is simply trying to fend off the brainwash, while it bounced off of Private Pyle (Vincent D'Onofrio) whose story tells us all Kubrick needed to say. That is why the second half of the film in Viet Nam seemed only to serve the audience a follow up and adventure as to what happened to some of our original boot camp marines. I still found the film both detached and personal, as if I was trying to fend off the disgracing of my viewers' soul. I like this film due to that internal struggle of whether or not to view war as acceptable.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not quite the full picture
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Prism10
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Stanley Kubrick, the eccentric director is lionised by Hollywood. A man who spent the latter part of his life living in London and shooting his films in England despite them being set elsewhere whether it was outer space, some hotel in the mountains of America or in this case a Vietnam war film. Full Metal Jacket arrived with plaudits from the critics. Its a film of two halves, the more interesting part being the first half set at boot camp with a sadistic drill instructor. The second half which is the more action based Vietnam set element is less interesting. Why? Because a year earlier we all watched 'Platoon' which swept the big prizes at the Oscars and directed by someone who served in Vietnam and fully conveyed the anti war message and politics of it all now that some years have passed by since the war ended. We saw Nam films before and better in Platoon and Apocalypse Now. Also these films although did not got to Vietnam, at least filmed in location whether it would be the Philippines or Thailand that is standing in. Full Metal Jacket was filmed in various parts of London dressed up as Vietnam. It shows, the sets do not look authentic, you do not get the feeling you are in the far east and it shows up the limitations of the second half of the story. It was too little and too late.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    War is not worth wasting our youth
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    StoryCharts
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Full Metal Jacket is about the idea that war is not worth wasting our youth. It tries to prove this with two stories: the first is the marines training for deployment, the second is the marines in action in Vietnam. The first story, the marines training for deployment, is told with two external plots: that of the not so bright marine Pyle trying to finish boot camp and the second is the entire class of marines trying to graduate. The class of marines succeed in graduating, but Pyle does not. He goes crazy after the harsh treatment meant to harden him to become a killer and commits suicide. So this story gets to the point that preparing for war is inhumane and not worth wasting our youth. The second story is about the marines fighting to win the war in Vietnam. This is told with two plots: that of winning the war and the second of the declining morality of the marines. The war is not won, it ends ambiguously as the marines win a small insignificant battle and return to camp while the morality of the marines shows a constant decline and ends with our hero committing murder. The movie is a great testament to the anti-war movement and a visual essay on the meaninglessness of war. But it is not a very engaging story. The first half of the movie makes a tight dramatic point that training marines to be killer has some inhumane consequences and proves it with Pyle's suicide. But the second half doesn't have an overall story arc to hang its hat on. The status of the main external plot of winning the war is left ambiguous. So the moral decline of our hero who has to commit murder at the end doesn't create as much meaning since the murder doesn't get us any further in winning the war. One can argue that that's the point of the movie, is that these atrocities are senseless and meaningless. And that is true. But in terms of a dramatic story, the meaning of the action is lost because the filmmakers abhorred making winning the war into any resemblance of a real plot. In the first half of the movie, Pyle's suicide is juxtaposed with the success of class of marines all graduating. Thus it makes the point that his suicide is not worth it for us to successfully train marines. But in the second half of the movie, Joker commits murder but this action is not juxtaposed with progression of any other plot. So the action loses the chance to create meaning through a consequence for his actions. It feels like the movie was cut off without any real resolution, like another 15 minutes were missing. My Story Chart of the movie is at storycharts.ca
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An outstanding and unique war movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    axel-koch
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    In 1987, 30 years after he'd firstly dealt with the subject of war in Paths of Glory, legendary American auteur Stanley Kubrick returned to the award-promising genre and released Full Metal Jacket. While it neither got the praise nor the awards it deserved when it came out, it has since then become a fan favorite and one of Kubrick's most beloved movies. Full Metal Jacket is split in two cohesive parts: the first and shorter one setting place at a military boot camp in South Carolina and the second one depicting the actual war events in Vietnam. The audience's relationship to the characters is supposed to be very distant and Kubrick lets us know very little about them. The narrator, nicknamed Joker, is a spectacled young man that believes to see through the military indoctrination. He tries to resist the system and, as he says himself, is only here to be the first kid on his block to get a confirmed kill. This is, of course, highly unconventional for a war movie protagonist and Matthew Modine plays him in a realistic, yet not particularly likable manner. Vincent D'Onofrio portrays the burly and universally untalented Private "Gomer Pyle", who gets permanently insulted and degraded by the vulgar and loud Drill Sergeant Hartman, who is played extraordinarily well by R. Lee Ermey, who was a real-life Drill Sergeant some time before. His eloquent and absolutely R-rated speeches are hilarious and simply the best part of the movie. It's sad somewhat, that his character doesn't accompany the recruits in the Vietnam War that follows; at some parts, I really wished for awesome one-liners like " I bet you're the kind of guy that would f*** a person in the a** and not even have the goddamn common courtesy to give him a reach-around!" But let's not be too harsh: the second part, if remarkably more serious, is again entertaining and because of the excellently crafted war scenes utterly gripping. Typically for a Kubrick film, Full Metal Jacket has a lot of ongoing themes and motifs in it that you may not even recognize when watching it for the first time. He's dealing with sexuality and not only in the two scenes in which Vietnamese hookers appear. The recruits have an absurd relationship with their rifle - especially D'Onofrio's character - and in the film's second part the killing scenes seem to bring an orgasmic feeling to the soldiers. Furthermore, you can probably correctly interpret religious imagery as well as father-mother-child themes into the movie - the minute director Stanley Kubrick is likely to have intended all of them. But you don't even need to think about the film in such a 'sophisticated' way, Mr. K shows a great game with the war scenes already. There may not be as many as in genre classics Apocalypse Now or Platoon and, admittedly, they don't have the aesthetic greatness that the ones in the aforementioned Coppola flick had. However, what Full Metal Jacket has is an authenticity that is even more impressive if you are aware that the Vietnam scenes where in fact shot in a disused gas work in the vicinity of London. Kubrick made the most out of it and also did terrific work with the sound and the editing which is impeccable. Because Kubrick wanted to make the recruits as one multi-persona character, there isn't as much to find out about the individual characters as some people may have wished for. Yet still, there is a very interesting and often only subliminal character study on the protagonist, Private Joker. Most of all, while Full Metal Jacket has the same view on war as the majority of other war films (even though the movie's protagonist is a war advocate, Kubrick himself is, of course, against war - I hope you noticed that), it shows us something new. A partly documentary and partly alarming new take that could have been boring. Thanks to Kubrick, it's not. At least not at the first time watching it - the prolonged war scenes lose their thrill once you know what's going to happen.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Let's talk about the source material
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jackhammer111
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The movie is well reviewed by others and most people find it very compelling. I like it to but am bothered by some shifts in tone in the final third although I think Kubrick deserves credit for not dodging the issue of atrocities. I prefer war movies that don't glorify war more as in "Platoon" or the great German U-Boat film "Das Boot" (see it in German with English subtitles, when they overdubbed it in English they wrecked a great background soundtrack). All in all there's a bit too much flag waving in this for me but it's a great movie but I can help remembering that part of the promotion for "Full Metal Jacket" including displaying the novel that served as source material for it in supermarket checkout lanes. Seeing Kubrick's name on it I picked it up. The novel was called "the Short Timers" written by Marine Gustav Hasford who was in theater during 1968-69. The great prolific essayist, columnist, novelist, screen writer (including my favorite sci fi movie, "a Boy and his Dog") Harlan Ellison said of Short timers "It is one of the most amazing stretches of writing I've ever encountered." Even though I know this is a movie review, not a book review, I have to tell you the source for most of the movie was written largely in a different kind of English called jarhead lingo. It was very cool to read inspired sections that are prose written with those word. Unfortunately, way more people were interested in watching Kubrick's movie than reading the real deal, the book didn't sell well, his deal with Kubrick wasn't very good and Hasford died alone almost broke in a motel room in Greece of heart related diabetic problems. I don't know which is more heartbreaking. Hasford's early death or the fact that "the Short Timers" is out of print while people still buy Kubrick's movie and somebody gets paid. The book has now become a rather expensive collector's item selling online for between $15 and upwards of $400. If you Google the title and his name you'll find a link to a scribd page that will load the whole book like a pdf. But you can't save or download it without paying. But you can read it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The best Marine Corps Bootcamp movie ever!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    sftd1973
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is a great movie that really depicts the life of a recruit going through Marine Corps Recruit Training. It is so real and straight to the point. Even with the additional Hollywood input in the movie, it still displays that reality that recruits go through to become United States Marines. Skip to the Viet Nam half of the movie. The Tet Offensive was a great part of the history of the Viet Nam war and this movie captures that history in great detail. The scenes of the fighting in the city is unique because most Viet Nam movies only show the fighting in the jungles and the rice patties and villages. Stanley Kubrick outdid himself with this movie and R. Lee Ermey immortalized himself as the Senior Drill Instructor and as the Gunnery Sergeant that everyone will always think of when anyone mentions the Marine Corps. Mathew Modine was outside himself in this movie and played a character that is totally outside of his normal range of characters. I give him a 10 along with R. Lee Ermey a 10 as well.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
 </reviews>
</filme>
