<filme>
 <id>
  19
 </id>
 <imdburl>
  http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0112379
 </imdburl>
 <ano>
  1995
 </ano>
 <titulo>
  A Exc&ecirc;ntrica Fam&iacute;lia de Antonia
 </titulo>
 <rating>
  7.2
 </rating>
 <sinopse>
  A Dutch matron establishes and, for several generations, oversees a close-knit, matriarchal community where feminism and liberalism thrive.
 </sinopse>
 <storyline>
  In an anonymous Dutch village, a sturdy, strong-willed matriarch looks back upon her life, the generations of family and friends gathered around her table, and ponders the cyclical nature of time.
 </storyline>
 <generos>
  <genero>
   Comedy
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Drama
  </genero>
 </generos>
 <keywords>
  <keyword>
   dutch
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   village
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   ex priest
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   full moon
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   death
  </keyword>
 </keywords>
 <diretores>
  <diretor>
   Marleen Gorris
  </diretor>
 </diretores>
 <escritores>
  <escritor>
   Marleen Gorris
  </escritor>
 </escritores>
 <atores>
  <ator>
   Willeke van Ammelrooy
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Jan Decleir
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Veerle van Overloop
  </ator>
 </atores>
 <reviews>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Nothing to fear
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gizmomogwai
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The winner of the 1995 Oscar for a foreign language film has, I think, been unfairly derided on political grounds. Antonia, called Antonia's Line in English, is a Dutch feminist film and has drawn criticism just for that. Sexists love to paint feminists with one brush based on a lunatic fringe, but as a male film watcher I can testify that there's nothing about the film that should be offensive to men. A villain rapist is a man, but rapists exist in life and there are plenty of men in the film who are decent. The women in the family never marry, but many of them still love men and keep them close in their lives. What really scares closet sexists is that the women in this movie are strong characters- even if it's in a positive way, that just won't sit will with those still wishing for a male-run society. The real objective of feminism is for men and women to share power, not make females the sole power. Antonia's Line (a title that makes more sense than the original title of Antonia, because it better captures the focus of the movie), is a fine film that includes colourful, interesting characters, some funny moments and some compelling drama. For example, Th&eacute;r&egrave;se is an interesting character because of her abnormal intelligence, and when the narrator announces she's been raped it's a shocking, disheartening moment (even though we don't actually see that rape). There's also some humour in Danielle announcing she wants a baby but also having a lack of interest in a husband, and in how her own mother arranges for her to get laid. There are lots of characters for a fairly short film, but most of even the minor characters have some appeal. This movie deserved its Oscar and it deserves to be seen.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Virtues and Flaws
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    palmiro
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    One of those films that falls in the category of "a celebration of life" (films falling into this category are a sure bet for serious Oscar consideration for Best Foreign Film). This film annoyed me a bit because it seemed to suggest that happiness is to be found simply by cultivating our relationships to one another and keeping connected. But there's also a big wide world out there, beyond our little Dutch village, and it plays a huge role in our chances of finding some measure of happiness--and it's something we ignore at our peril. Best feature of this feminist fable was its immanentism: an absolute refusal to accept the notion that there is any reality beyond the sentient existence we experience as we pass through life--so that all we can know and enjoy and hope for is contained in the endless cycle of Birth, Love, and Death.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Interesting and mildly amusing
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    billcr12
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/5/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A feminist tale which in some ways reminded me of The World According to Garp, with Glenn Close as an independent woman who decides to have a baby without the active participation of a father figure. The difference is that rather than an American perspective, it is a Dutch one. Antonia tells everyone that this is the last day of her life and she tells her story in flashbacks, starting with her arrival at the family farm with her daughter Danielle, and her intention of raising her as a single mother. Following in her mother's footsteps, Danielle announces that she would like to have a child and so Antonia searches for the proper donor. The line continues when Danielle gives birth to Therese who then begets Sarah; got it? This is not a mainstream work, by any means. The acting is solid and the viewpoint an interesting one. I was mildly amused.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I'm a Married Guy With Kids, and I Loved This Film. The World Needs More Films Like This.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    madcardinal
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/4/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Antonia's Line" is a beautiful, poignant film which skillfully manages to celebrate life in all its fertile richness while it simultaneously throws a richly deserved counter-punch into the face of 2,000 years of arrogant, church-sponsored misogyny. When a modern film such as this one cleverly turns the tables on real historical injustice, I do not find it offensive at all. I'm a man and I found this film admirable for giving a hoot about redressing a justified, legitimate grievance. Until very recently, women were not regarded as significant beings in their own right; they were deemed valuable only as helpmates to be utilized and governed by men - significant only to the extent that they were subordinate to a father and later a husband, and they were supposed to accept this secondary status without complaint, protest or challenge. Such traditional subjugation of women is rubbish and this movie plainly says so. That's a good thing. I see no reason to be offended by such truthfulness. These are not matters of conjecture but of historical fact. This movie features wonderful, strong female characters who are people in their own right - they are not compliant appendages of domineering male characters. Strong, independent women are found in cinema with extreme rarity, and this film has five of them! There are at least three male characters who are good human beings in this film: Farmer Bas; Crooked Finger; and Simon; so you can forget the reviews falsely complaining that all the male characters are creeps. Refreshingly, this movie also celebrates sexual joy without censorship or hand-wringing. It's even quite amusing, bringing a life-affirming smile to the viewer's face despite some of the violent and somber events which occur in other parts of the film. I found Dennis Littrell's review on this web site to be excellent, because it cites the ancient mythological underpinnings of this film. The soundtrack is beautiful. I suggest paying especially careful attention to the conversations between older and younger female characters, because they contain a complex interplay of emotion, intelligence, belief and intuition - and so, just when you think you have a character pigeonholed (for example, Antonia is completely atheist), you notice a nuance pointing in another direction. Sarah's final pronouncement in the film also alludes to new possibilities, if you're listening carefully. A fabulous, unique film, "Antonia's Line" gets my highest recommendation.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Yep....this movie was awful
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    TheCritic2009
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/4/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I have seen way to many movies in my life it is beyond official. I have sat through entire trilogies without having to stretch, take a break etc. But this one basically I wish I had just taken a bathroom break for the duration. I am a man I'm sure your aware by the way I am typing this out but don't give me some line about being a sexist. I want you to get paid the same amount blah blah blah, but this movie was just awful. Basically from minute one we skip bout 10 years every five minutes. This would be OK if we fully developed the characters or made you in anyway care about any of them but the director didn't. The plot is about a family of women who decide that they should keep men as a non important part of their lives which would of been great if there would have been a reason for it but there wasn't.(besides the lesbian I get that)They basically just seemed to make men look as objects so if the shoe was on the other foot all you ladies would hate this flick too. What else to say pretty pointless just seemed like the director decided to make a movie that forced feminism on everyone. And this movies sex scenes were gross and just trying to prove some pointless point about women in control. I don't know I'm rambling. Terrible movie. Check out departures if you wanna see a foreign film that was actually worth your time.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Sensitive, Surreal, Humorous, and Indomitable
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gradyharp
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/7/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    ANTONIA'S LINE continues as fresh today as when it was released and awarded Oscars in 1995. This very fine little Dutch film mocks the old adage of 'You can't go back home again' by introducing Antonia and her daughter returning to a village she had abandoned and setting up changes among the odd assortment of townsfolk that initiate a heritage of both wonderful and tragic events, each of which is a parable about family and community. The women rule here, even to the point of deciding to conceive by barter, by compulsion, and by taking arms against the macho power symbols of rape. All manner of variations of normal (spiritually possessed, moon howlers, disillusioned priests, mentally retarded, social outcasts) come under the influence of Antonia's strongly world-wise persona. The results are like a fairy tale for adults, both in content and in the wonderful visual effects. The cast is extraordinary as is the pacing of the direction. The message of this film endures - it pleads to be viewed regularly. Grady Harp
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Life-Affirming
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Magic Lamp
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/7/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is an epic movie. The movie plays out intensely, gripping attention right from the first frame. It affirms life in its story of death. Its complex in its simplicity, its comic in its seriousness, its subtle in its gravity. It depicts a life lived well and fully. It questions norms and it glorifies personal values. It gives the heart the mandate to lead the way. It may jerk people to take a fresh new look at their way of living their life. It may seem feminist or iconoclastic, but at the same time its very traditional and conservative in its message of family togetherness and social interdependence. I loved it!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Dutch touch on feminism
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Lee Eisenberg (eisenberg.lee@gmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/6/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The 1995 winner of Best Foreign Language Film tells the story of a woman, her daughter and granddaughter over several years in the Netherlands. The women do everything to show their strength. One of the best parts is what happens after a hypocrite makes fun of the granddaughter; I would hate to be in his place! Overall, "Antonia" (called "Antonia's Line" in English) is definitely one that I recommend. This and "The Assault" are Holland's two supreme masterpieces. In other words, ik reken erop (Dutch for "I count on it") because it is truly iets zoets (Dutch for "something sweet"). A veritable part of De Geschiedenis Des Nederlandsen Films (history of Dutch cinema).
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Well made but also at the same time ineffective.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Boba_Fett1138
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/9/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Funny thing with this movie is that it's an highly appreciated one (it even received an Oscar for best foreign language movie) all over the world but in its own native country the Netherlands it wasn't received that well. At least not as an Oscar worthy movie and everyone within the Netherlands at the time also was quite surprised it took home the Oscar. What I can say about this movie is that it feels like a waste opportunity. The movie feels like one with hugely potential and if it worked out better this could had really been an 'epic' strong feminist family drama but instead the movie jumps all over the place also with its different styles and it's mostly an ineffective one. There is not much interesting within the movie, although you certainly have the feeling that the story itself had plenty of interesting elements to offer but yet it somehow doesn't always translate well to the big screen. Perhaps if the movie would had been an hour longer it would had worked out better and also as a more effective one. The movie covers basically the entire lifespan of a strong-woman of the Dutch countryside and the future generations of women, her daughter her grand-daughter and right up till her great-grand daughter, while she herself is of course aging. This becomes an interesting aspect of the movie. It begins right after the end of WW II and it ends somewhere in the '90's or so I would guess. So the world around her is constantly changing but yet it also stays the same because she keeps all the people she care for close to her. This means that parts of the movie are set in different time-era's, which gives the movie something unique. It's obvious that this movie was intended as a strong feminist picture, with all strong female leads in it but with this I mostly feel that the movie isn't as effective as it should had been. It just doesn't feature enough strong or original moments within the movie. It's still a really well made and good looking movie though. It doesn't look at all like the movie got shot in the Netherlands, the countryside and all within this movie is far too beautiful looking for that. But I always have that with Dutch movies and I guess I just don't know how beautiful my country actually is. Perhaps I just need to stop watching so many movies and get out more... Female director Marleen Gorris is obviously capable of making a beautiful and professional looking movie. She actually now has a quite successful career in America as a movie director, which is quite an accomplishment not only because she is Dutch but also foremost because she is a female. She actually was the first woman to direct a movie that won an Oscar for best foreign film. Guess she is a strong woman just like Antonia in this movie and that's why she directed this movie with so much obvious passion and devotion. I wasn't too happy about the acting within this movie though. Willeke van Ammelrooy has always been praised for her role but in all honesty her performance is quite a mixed bag. As the younger Antonia she isn't always too great but as the older Antonia she's much better and more convincing. Can't say that the make-up always looks convincing though. Jan Decleir is normally always a real great actor but his role in this movie isn't anything too memorable but this is mostly due to the far too limited screen time he gets in this movie and he also has far too little lines to speak. He however still does a good job with his sequences and it's actually nice to notice that he took on a Dutch accent and for once dropped his native Belgian one. Still it's weird to hear many other actors within this movie still speak with a Belgian accent, while the movie is obviously set in the Netherlands but this of course has everything to do with the fact that this is a Belgium co-production and a certain part of the cast & crew just HAD to be Belgian. I wish I could say that it was a brilliant Dutch movie, worthy of its Oscar... 6/10 http://bobafett1138.blogspot.com/
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    This is the only dance we dance.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    lastliberal
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/5/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It takes courage to grow up and turn out to be who you truly are. I can't think of any other platitude that better describes this amazing film by writer/director Marleen Gorris. The Motion Picture Academy felt as strongly as I do, as they awarded it an Oscar; a well-deserved Oscar, I might add. It is about the progeny of Antonia (Willeke van Ammelrooy), a woman who returns to her village after WWII and begins life with her daughter Danielle (Els Dottermans). There is never any mention of a father. This is a feminist film in the purest sense. Men are not bashed, but there is a sense that they are not very useful, except for producing more daughters. Danielle seeks a male to impregnate her and bears a child prodigy, Th&eacute;r&egrave;se (Carolien Spoor, Esther Vriesendorp, and Veerle van Overloop), Th&eacute;r&egrave;se becomes a pupil of the town intellectual Crooked Finger (Mil Seghers) and cannot find a man who can satisfy her intellectually and physically, so she settles for the physical and has a daughter of her own. Men in this movie serve as seed bearers, or teachers, or comfort bearers, or, in one case, messengers of evil, as one manages to rape two women. But the film is not just about feminism, it is also about acceptance. Antonia never hesitates to give comfort and shelter to anyone in need, whether it bee someone with an intellectual disability, the raped sister, the woman who loves having babies, or the priest who finds that celebrating life is better than celebrating death. Her own daughter finds love in the arms of Th&eacute;r&egrave;se's tutor, and this is not judged, only accepted as another part of life. Everyone seems to find love in Antonia's circle, and her real progeny is exceeded by those she touches with love and acceptance. It is a beautiful story with a wealth of interesting characters. Gorris is an amazing writer and one can only be thrilled at her talent.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Nothing to fear
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gizmomogwai
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The winner of the 1995 Oscar for a foreign language film has, I think, been unfairly derided on political grounds. Antonia, called Antonia's Line in English, is a Dutch feminist film and has drawn criticism just for that. Sexists love to paint feminists with one brush based on a lunatic fringe, but as a male film watcher I can testify that there's nothing about the film that should be offensive to men. A villain rapist is a man, but rapists exist in life and there are plenty of men in the film who are decent. The women in the family never marry, but many of them still love men and keep them close in their lives. What really scares closet sexists is that the women in this movie are strong characters- even if it's in a positive way, that just won't sit will with those still wishing for a male-run society. The real objective of feminism is for men and women to share power, not make females the sole power. Antonia's Line (a title that makes more sense than the original title of Antonia, because it better captures the focus of the movie), is a fine film that includes colourful, interesting characters, some funny moments and some compelling drama. For example, Th&eacute;r&egrave;se is an interesting character because of her abnormal intelligence, and when the narrator announces she's been raped it's a shocking, disheartening moment (even though we don't actually see that rape). There's also some humour in Danielle announcing she wants a baby but also having a lack of interest in a husband, and in how her own mother arranges for her to get laid. There are lots of characters for a fairly short film, but most of even the minor characters have some appeal. This movie deserved its Oscar and it deserves to be seen.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Virtues and Flaws
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    palmiro
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    One of those films that falls in the category of "a celebration of life" (films falling into this category are a sure bet for serious Oscar consideration for Best Foreign Film). This film annoyed me a bit because it seemed to suggest that happiness is to be found simply by cultivating our relationships to one another and keeping connected. But there's also a big wide world out there, beyond our little Dutch village, and it plays a huge role in our chances of finding some measure of happiness--and it's something we ignore at our peril. Best feature of this feminist fable was its immanentism: an absolute refusal to accept the notion that there is any reality beyond the sentient existence we experience as we pass through life--so that all we can know and enjoy and hope for is contained in the endless cycle of Birth, Love, and Death.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Interesting and mildly amusing
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    billcr12
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/5/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A feminist tale which in some ways reminded me of The World According to Garp, with Glenn Close as an independent woman who decides to have a baby without the active participation of a father figure. The difference is that rather than an American perspective, it is a Dutch one. Antonia tells everyone that this is the last day of her life and she tells her story in flashbacks, starting with her arrival at the family farm with her daughter Danielle, and her intention of raising her as a single mother. Following in her mother's footsteps, Danielle announces that she would like to have a child and so Antonia searches for the proper donor. The line continues when Danielle gives birth to Therese who then begets Sarah; got it? This is not a mainstream work, by any means. The acting is solid and the viewpoint an interesting one. I was mildly amused.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I'm a Married Guy With Kids, and I Loved This Film. The World Needs More Films Like This.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    madcardinal
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/4/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Antonia's Line" is a beautiful, poignant film which skillfully manages to celebrate life in all its fertile richness while it simultaneously throws a richly deserved counter-punch into the face of 2,000 years of arrogant, church-sponsored misogyny. When a modern film such as this one cleverly turns the tables on real historical injustice, I do not find it offensive at all. I'm a man and I found this film admirable for giving a hoot about redressing a justified, legitimate grievance. Until very recently, women were not regarded as significant beings in their own right; they were deemed valuable only as helpmates to be utilized and governed by men - significant only to the extent that they were subordinate to a father and later a husband, and they were supposed to accept this secondary status without complaint, protest or challenge. Such traditional subjugation of women is rubbish and this movie plainly says so. That's a good thing. I see no reason to be offended by such truthfulness. These are not matters of conjecture but of historical fact. This movie features wonderful, strong female characters who are people in their own right - they are not compliant appendages of domineering male characters. Strong, independent women are found in cinema with extreme rarity, and this film has five of them! There are at least three male characters who are good human beings in this film: Farmer Bas; Crooked Finger; and Simon; so you can forget the reviews falsely complaining that all the male characters are creeps. Refreshingly, this movie also celebrates sexual joy without censorship or hand-wringing. It's even quite amusing, bringing a life-affirming smile to the viewer's face despite some of the violent and somber events which occur in other parts of the film. I found Dennis Littrell's review on this web site to be excellent, because it cites the ancient mythological underpinnings of this film. The soundtrack is beautiful. I suggest paying especially careful attention to the conversations between older and younger female characters, because they contain a complex interplay of emotion, intelligence, belief and intuition - and so, just when you think you have a character pigeonholed (for example, Antonia is completely atheist), you notice a nuance pointing in another direction. Sarah's final pronouncement in the film also alludes to new possibilities, if you're listening carefully. A fabulous, unique film, "Antonia's Line" gets my highest recommendation.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Yep....this movie was awful
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    TheCritic2009
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/4/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I have seen way to many movies in my life it is beyond official. I have sat through entire trilogies without having to stretch, take a break etc. But this one basically I wish I had just taken a bathroom break for the duration. I am a man I'm sure your aware by the way I am typing this out but don't give me some line about being a sexist. I want you to get paid the same amount blah blah blah, but this movie was just awful. Basically from minute one we skip bout 10 years every five minutes. This would be OK if we fully developed the characters or made you in anyway care about any of them but the director didn't. The plot is about a family of women who decide that they should keep men as a non important part of their lives which would of been great if there would have been a reason for it but there wasn't.(besides the lesbian I get that)They basically just seemed to make men look as objects so if the shoe was on the other foot all you ladies would hate this flick too. What else to say pretty pointless just seemed like the director decided to make a movie that forced feminism on everyone. And this movies sex scenes were gross and just trying to prove some pointless point about women in control. I don't know I'm rambling. Terrible movie. Check out departures if you wanna see a foreign film that was actually worth your time.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Sensitive, Surreal, Humorous, and Indomitable
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gradyharp
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/7/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    ANTONIA'S LINE continues as fresh today as when it was released and awarded Oscars in 1995. This very fine little Dutch film mocks the old adage of 'You can't go back home again' by introducing Antonia and her daughter returning to a village she had abandoned and setting up changes among the odd assortment of townsfolk that initiate a heritage of both wonderful and tragic events, each of which is a parable about family and community. The women rule here, even to the point of deciding to conceive by barter, by compulsion, and by taking arms against the macho power symbols of rape. All manner of variations of normal (spiritually possessed, moon howlers, disillusioned priests, mentally retarded, social outcasts) come under the influence of Antonia's strongly world-wise persona. The results are like a fairy tale for adults, both in content and in the wonderful visual effects. The cast is extraordinary as is the pacing of the direction. The message of this film endures - it pleads to be viewed regularly. Grady Harp
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Life-Affirming
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Magic Lamp
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/7/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is an epic movie. The movie plays out intensely, gripping attention right from the first frame. It affirms life in its story of death. Its complex in its simplicity, its comic in its seriousness, its subtle in its gravity. It depicts a life lived well and fully. It questions norms and it glorifies personal values. It gives the heart the mandate to lead the way. It may jerk people to take a fresh new look at their way of living their life. It may seem feminist or iconoclastic, but at the same time its very traditional and conservative in its message of family togetherness and social interdependence. I loved it!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Dutch touch on feminism
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Lee Eisenberg (eisenberg.lee@gmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/6/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The 1995 winner of Best Foreign Language Film tells the story of a woman, her daughter and granddaughter over several years in the Netherlands. The women do everything to show their strength. One of the best parts is what happens after a hypocrite makes fun of the granddaughter; I would hate to be in his place! Overall, "Antonia" (called "Antonia's Line" in English) is definitely one that I recommend. This and "The Assault" are Holland's two supreme masterpieces. In other words, ik reken erop (Dutch for "I count on it") because it is truly iets zoets (Dutch for "something sweet"). A veritable part of De Geschiedenis Des Nederlandsen Films (history of Dutch cinema).
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Well made but also at the same time ineffective.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Boba_Fett1138
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/9/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Funny thing with this movie is that it's an highly appreciated one (it even received an Oscar for best foreign language movie) all over the world but in its own native country the Netherlands it wasn't received that well. At least not as an Oscar worthy movie and everyone within the Netherlands at the time also was quite surprised it took home the Oscar. What I can say about this movie is that it feels like a waste opportunity. The movie feels like one with hugely potential and if it worked out better this could had really been an 'epic' strong feminist family drama but instead the movie jumps all over the place also with its different styles and it's mostly an ineffective one. There is not much interesting within the movie, although you certainly have the feeling that the story itself had plenty of interesting elements to offer but yet it somehow doesn't always translate well to the big screen. Perhaps if the movie would had been an hour longer it would had worked out better and also as a more effective one. The movie covers basically the entire lifespan of a strong-woman of the Dutch countryside and the future generations of women, her daughter her grand-daughter and right up till her great-grand daughter, while she herself is of course aging. This becomes an interesting aspect of the movie. It begins right after the end of WW II and it ends somewhere in the '90's or so I would guess. So the world around her is constantly changing but yet it also stays the same because she keeps all the people she care for close to her. This means that parts of the movie are set in different time-era's, which gives the movie something unique. It's obvious that this movie was intended as a strong feminist picture, with all strong female leads in it but with this I mostly feel that the movie isn't as effective as it should had been. It just doesn't feature enough strong or original moments within the movie. It's still a really well made and good looking movie though. It doesn't look at all like the movie got shot in the Netherlands, the countryside and all within this movie is far too beautiful looking for that. But I always have that with Dutch movies and I guess I just don't know how beautiful my country actually is. Perhaps I just need to stop watching so many movies and get out more... Female director Marleen Gorris is obviously capable of making a beautiful and professional looking movie. She actually now has a quite successful career in America as a movie director, which is quite an accomplishment not only because she is Dutch but also foremost because she is a female. She actually was the first woman to direct a movie that won an Oscar for best foreign film. Guess she is a strong woman just like Antonia in this movie and that's why she directed this movie with so much obvious passion and devotion. I wasn't too happy about the acting within this movie though. Willeke van Ammelrooy has always been praised for her role but in all honesty her performance is quite a mixed bag. As the younger Antonia she isn't always too great but as the older Antonia she's much better and more convincing. Can't say that the make-up always looks convincing though. Jan Decleir is normally always a real great actor but his role in this movie isn't anything too memorable but this is mostly due to the far too limited screen time he gets in this movie and he also has far too little lines to speak. He however still does a good job with his sequences and it's actually nice to notice that he took on a Dutch accent and for once dropped his native Belgian one. Still it's weird to hear many other actors within this movie still speak with a Belgian accent, while the movie is obviously set in the Netherlands but this of course has everything to do with the fact that this is a Belgium co-production and a certain part of the cast & crew just HAD to be Belgian. I wish I could say that it was a brilliant Dutch movie, worthy of its Oscar... 6/10 http://bobafett1138.blogspot.com/
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    This is the only dance we dance.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    lastliberal
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/5/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It takes courage to grow up and turn out to be who you truly are. I can't think of any other platitude that better describes this amazing film by writer/director Marleen Gorris. The Motion Picture Academy felt as strongly as I do, as they awarded it an Oscar; a well-deserved Oscar, I might add. It is about the progeny of Antonia (Willeke van Ammelrooy), a woman who returns to her village after WWII and begins life with her daughter Danielle (Els Dottermans). There is never any mention of a father. This is a feminist film in the purest sense. Men are not bashed, but there is a sense that they are not very useful, except for producing more daughters. Danielle seeks a male to impregnate her and bears a child prodigy, Th&eacute;r&egrave;se (Carolien Spoor, Esther Vriesendorp, and Veerle van Overloop), Th&eacute;r&egrave;se becomes a pupil of the town intellectual Crooked Finger (Mil Seghers) and cannot find a man who can satisfy her intellectually and physically, so she settles for the physical and has a daughter of her own. Men in this movie serve as seed bearers, or teachers, or comfort bearers, or, in one case, messengers of evil, as one manages to rape two women. But the film is not just about feminism, it is also about acceptance. Antonia never hesitates to give comfort and shelter to anyone in need, whether it bee someone with an intellectual disability, the raped sister, the woman who loves having babies, or the priest who finds that celebrating life is better than celebrating death. Her own daughter finds love in the arms of Th&eacute;r&egrave;se's tutor, and this is not judged, only accepted as another part of life. Everyone seems to find love in Antonia's circle, and her real progeny is exceeded by those she touches with love and acceptance. It is a beautiful story with a wealth of interesting characters. Gorris is an amazing writer and one can only be thrilled at her talent.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Nothing to fear
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gizmomogwai
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The winner of the 1995 Oscar for a foreign language film has, I think, been unfairly derided on political grounds. Antonia, called Antonia's Line in English, is a Dutch feminist film and has drawn criticism just for that. Sexists love to paint feminists with one brush based on a lunatic fringe, but as a male film watcher I can testify that there's nothing about the film that should be offensive to men. A villain rapist is a man, but rapists exist in life and there are plenty of men in the film who are decent. The women in the family never marry, but many of them still love men and keep them close in their lives. What really scares closet sexists is that the women in this movie are strong characters- even if it's in a positive way, that just won't sit will with those still wishing for a male-run society. The real objective of feminism is for men and women to share power, not make females the sole power. Antonia's Line (a title that makes more sense than the original title of Antonia, because it better captures the focus of the movie), is a fine film that includes colourful, interesting characters, some funny moments and some compelling drama. For example, Th&eacute;r&egrave;se is an interesting character because of her abnormal intelligence, and when the narrator announces she's been raped it's a shocking, disheartening moment (even though we don't actually see that rape). There's also some humour in Danielle announcing she wants a baby but also having a lack of interest in a husband, and in how her own mother arranges for her to get laid. There are lots of characters for a fairly short film, but most of even the minor characters have some appeal. This movie deserved its Oscar and it deserves to be seen.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Virtues and Flaws
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    palmiro
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    One of those films that falls in the category of "a celebration of life" (films falling into this category are a sure bet for serious Oscar consideration for Best Foreign Film). This film annoyed me a bit because it seemed to suggest that happiness is to be found simply by cultivating our relationships to one another and keeping connected. But there's also a big wide world out there, beyond our little Dutch village, and it plays a huge role in our chances of finding some measure of happiness--and it's something we ignore at our peril. Best feature of this feminist fable was its immanentism: an absolute refusal to accept the notion that there is any reality beyond the sentient existence we experience as we pass through life--so that all we can know and enjoy and hope for is contained in the endless cycle of Birth, Love, and Death.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Interesting and mildly amusing
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    billcr12
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/5/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A feminist tale which in some ways reminded me of The World According to Garp, with Glenn Close as an independent woman who decides to have a baby without the active participation of a father figure. The difference is that rather than an American perspective, it is a Dutch one. Antonia tells everyone that this is the last day of her life and she tells her story in flashbacks, starting with her arrival at the family farm with her daughter Danielle, and her intention of raising her as a single mother. Following in her mother's footsteps, Danielle announces that she would like to have a child and so Antonia searches for the proper donor. The line continues when Danielle gives birth to Therese who then begets Sarah; got it? This is not a mainstream work, by any means. The acting is solid and the viewpoint an interesting one. I was mildly amused.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I'm a Married Guy With Kids, and I Loved This Film. The World Needs More Films Like This.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    madcardinal
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/4/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Antonia's Line" is a beautiful, poignant film which skillfully manages to celebrate life in all its fertile richness while it simultaneously throws a richly deserved counter-punch into the face of 2,000 years of arrogant, church-sponsored misogyny. When a modern film such as this one cleverly turns the tables on real historical injustice, I do not find it offensive at all. I'm a man and I found this film admirable for giving a hoot about redressing a justified, legitimate grievance. Until very recently, women were not regarded as significant beings in their own right; they were deemed valuable only as helpmates to be utilized and governed by men - significant only to the extent that they were subordinate to a father and later a husband, and they were supposed to accept this secondary status without complaint, protest or challenge. Such traditional subjugation of women is rubbish and this movie plainly says so. That's a good thing. I see no reason to be offended by such truthfulness. These are not matters of conjecture but of historical fact. This movie features wonderful, strong female characters who are people in their own right - they are not compliant appendages of domineering male characters. Strong, independent women are found in cinema with extreme rarity, and this film has five of them! There are at least three male characters who are good human beings in this film: Farmer Bas; Crooked Finger; and Simon; so you can forget the reviews falsely complaining that all the male characters are creeps. Refreshingly, this movie also celebrates sexual joy without censorship or hand-wringing. It's even quite amusing, bringing a life-affirming smile to the viewer's face despite some of the violent and somber events which occur in other parts of the film. I found Dennis Littrell's review on this web site to be excellent, because it cites the ancient mythological underpinnings of this film. The soundtrack is beautiful. I suggest paying especially careful attention to the conversations between older and younger female characters, because they contain a complex interplay of emotion, intelligence, belief and intuition - and so, just when you think you have a character pigeonholed (for example, Antonia is completely atheist), you notice a nuance pointing in another direction. Sarah's final pronouncement in the film also alludes to new possibilities, if you're listening carefully. A fabulous, unique film, "Antonia's Line" gets my highest recommendation.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Yep....this movie was awful
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    TheCritic2009
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/4/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I have seen way to many movies in my life it is beyond official. I have sat through entire trilogies without having to stretch, take a break etc. But this one basically I wish I had just taken a bathroom break for the duration. I am a man I'm sure your aware by the way I am typing this out but don't give me some line about being a sexist. I want you to get paid the same amount blah blah blah, but this movie was just awful. Basically from minute one we skip bout 10 years every five minutes. This would be OK if we fully developed the characters or made you in anyway care about any of them but the director didn't. The plot is about a family of women who decide that they should keep men as a non important part of their lives which would of been great if there would have been a reason for it but there wasn't.(besides the lesbian I get that)They basically just seemed to make men look as objects so if the shoe was on the other foot all you ladies would hate this flick too. What else to say pretty pointless just seemed like the director decided to make a movie that forced feminism on everyone. And this movies sex scenes were gross and just trying to prove some pointless point about women in control. I don't know I'm rambling. Terrible movie. Check out departures if you wanna see a foreign film that was actually worth your time.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Sensitive, Surreal, Humorous, and Indomitable
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gradyharp
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/7/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    ANTONIA'S LINE continues as fresh today as when it was released and awarded Oscars in 1995. This very fine little Dutch film mocks the old adage of 'You can't go back home again' by introducing Antonia and her daughter returning to a village she had abandoned and setting up changes among the odd assortment of townsfolk that initiate a heritage of both wonderful and tragic events, each of which is a parable about family and community. The women rule here, even to the point of deciding to conceive by barter, by compulsion, and by taking arms against the macho power symbols of rape. All manner of variations of normal (spiritually possessed, moon howlers, disillusioned priests, mentally retarded, social outcasts) come under the influence of Antonia's strongly world-wise persona. The results are like a fairy tale for adults, both in content and in the wonderful visual effects. The cast is extraordinary as is the pacing of the direction. The message of this film endures - it pleads to be viewed regularly. Grady Harp
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Life-Affirming
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Magic Lamp
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/7/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is an epic movie. The movie plays out intensely, gripping attention right from the first frame. It affirms life in its story of death. Its complex in its simplicity, its comic in its seriousness, its subtle in its gravity. It depicts a life lived well and fully. It questions norms and it glorifies personal values. It gives the heart the mandate to lead the way. It may jerk people to take a fresh new look at their way of living their life. It may seem feminist or iconoclastic, but at the same time its very traditional and conservative in its message of family togetherness and social interdependence. I loved it!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Dutch touch on feminism
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Lee Eisenberg (eisenberg.lee@gmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/6/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The 1995 winner of Best Foreign Language Film tells the story of a woman, her daughter and granddaughter over several years in the Netherlands. The women do everything to show their strength. One of the best parts is what happens after a hypocrite makes fun of the granddaughter; I would hate to be in his place! Overall, "Antonia" (called "Antonia's Line" in English) is definitely one that I recommend. This and "The Assault" are Holland's two supreme masterpieces. In other words, ik reken erop (Dutch for "I count on it") because it is truly iets zoets (Dutch for "something sweet"). A veritable part of De Geschiedenis Des Nederlandsen Films (history of Dutch cinema).
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Well made but also at the same time ineffective.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Boba_Fett1138
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/9/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Funny thing with this movie is that it's an highly appreciated one (it even received an Oscar for best foreign language movie) all over the world but in its own native country the Netherlands it wasn't received that well. At least not as an Oscar worthy movie and everyone within the Netherlands at the time also was quite surprised it took home the Oscar. What I can say about this movie is that it feels like a waste opportunity. The movie feels like one with hugely potential and if it worked out better this could had really been an 'epic' strong feminist family drama but instead the movie jumps all over the place also with its different styles and it's mostly an ineffective one. There is not much interesting within the movie, although you certainly have the feeling that the story itself had plenty of interesting elements to offer but yet it somehow doesn't always translate well to the big screen. Perhaps if the movie would had been an hour longer it would had worked out better and also as a more effective one. The movie covers basically the entire lifespan of a strong-woman of the Dutch countryside and the future generations of women, her daughter her grand-daughter and right up till her great-grand daughter, while she herself is of course aging. This becomes an interesting aspect of the movie. It begins right after the end of WW II and it ends somewhere in the '90's or so I would guess. So the world around her is constantly changing but yet it also stays the same because she keeps all the people she care for close to her. This means that parts of the movie are set in different time-era's, which gives the movie something unique. It's obvious that this movie was intended as a strong feminist picture, with all strong female leads in it but with this I mostly feel that the movie isn't as effective as it should had been. It just doesn't feature enough strong or original moments within the movie. It's still a really well made and good looking movie though. It doesn't look at all like the movie got shot in the Netherlands, the countryside and all within this movie is far too beautiful looking for that. But I always have that with Dutch movies and I guess I just don't know how beautiful my country actually is. Perhaps I just need to stop watching so many movies and get out more... Female director Marleen Gorris is obviously capable of making a beautiful and professional looking movie. She actually now has a quite successful career in America as a movie director, which is quite an accomplishment not only because she is Dutch but also foremost because she is a female. She actually was the first woman to direct a movie that won an Oscar for best foreign film. Guess she is a strong woman just like Antonia in this movie and that's why she directed this movie with so much obvious passion and devotion. I wasn't too happy about the acting within this movie though. Willeke van Ammelrooy has always been praised for her role but in all honesty her performance is quite a mixed bag. As the younger Antonia she isn't always too great but as the older Antonia she's much better and more convincing. Can't say that the make-up always looks convincing though. Jan Decleir is normally always a real great actor but his role in this movie isn't anything too memorable but this is mostly due to the far too limited screen time he gets in this movie and he also has far too little lines to speak. He however still does a good job with his sequences and it's actually nice to notice that he took on a Dutch accent and for once dropped his native Belgian one. Still it's weird to hear many other actors within this movie still speak with a Belgian accent, while the movie is obviously set in the Netherlands but this of course has everything to do with the fact that this is a Belgium co-production and a certain part of the cast & crew just HAD to be Belgian. I wish I could say that it was a brilliant Dutch movie, worthy of its Oscar... 6/10 http://bobafett1138.blogspot.com/
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    This is the only dance we dance.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    lastliberal
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/5/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It takes courage to grow up and turn out to be who you truly are. I can't think of any other platitude that better describes this amazing film by writer/director Marleen Gorris. The Motion Picture Academy felt as strongly as I do, as they awarded it an Oscar; a well-deserved Oscar, I might add. It is about the progeny of Antonia (Willeke van Ammelrooy), a woman who returns to her village after WWII and begins life with her daughter Danielle (Els Dottermans). There is never any mention of a father. This is a feminist film in the purest sense. Men are not bashed, but there is a sense that they are not very useful, except for producing more daughters. Danielle seeks a male to impregnate her and bears a child prodigy, Th&eacute;r&egrave;se (Carolien Spoor, Esther Vriesendorp, and Veerle van Overloop), Th&eacute;r&egrave;se becomes a pupil of the town intellectual Crooked Finger (Mil Seghers) and cannot find a man who can satisfy her intellectually and physically, so she settles for the physical and has a daughter of her own. Men in this movie serve as seed bearers, or teachers, or comfort bearers, or, in one case, messengers of evil, as one manages to rape two women. But the film is not just about feminism, it is also about acceptance. Antonia never hesitates to give comfort and shelter to anyone in need, whether it bee someone with an intellectual disability, the raped sister, the woman who loves having babies, or the priest who finds that celebrating life is better than celebrating death. Her own daughter finds love in the arms of Th&eacute;r&egrave;se's tutor, and this is not judged, only accepted as another part of life. Everyone seems to find love in Antonia's circle, and her real progeny is exceeded by those she touches with love and acceptance. It is a beautiful story with a wealth of interesting characters. Gorris is an amazing writer and one can only be thrilled at her talent.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Nothing to fear
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gizmomogwai
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The winner of the 1995 Oscar for a foreign language film has, I think, been unfairly derided on political grounds. Antonia, called Antonia's Line in English, is a Dutch feminist film and has drawn criticism just for that. Sexists love to paint feminists with one brush based on a lunatic fringe, but as a male film watcher I can testify that there's nothing about the film that should be offensive to men. A villain rapist is a man, but rapists exist in life and there are plenty of men in the film who are decent. The women in the family never marry, but many of them still love men and keep them close in their lives. What really scares closet sexists is that the women in this movie are strong characters- even if it's in a positive way, that just won't sit will with those still wishing for a male-run society. The real objective of feminism is for men and women to share power, not make females the sole power. Antonia's Line (a title that makes more sense than the original title of Antonia, because it better captures the focus of the movie), is a fine film that includes colourful, interesting characters, some funny moments and some compelling drama. For example, Th&eacute;r&egrave;se is an interesting character because of her abnormal intelligence, and when the narrator announces she's been raped it's a shocking, disheartening moment (even though we don't actually see that rape). There's also some humour in Danielle announcing she wants a baby but also having a lack of interest in a husband, and in how her own mother arranges for her to get laid. There are lots of characters for a fairly short film, but most of even the minor characters have some appeal. This movie deserved its Oscar and it deserves to be seen.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Virtues and Flaws
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    palmiro
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    One of those films that falls in the category of "a celebration of life" (films falling into this category are a sure bet for serious Oscar consideration for Best Foreign Film). This film annoyed me a bit because it seemed to suggest that happiness is to be found simply by cultivating our relationships to one another and keeping connected. But there's also a big wide world out there, beyond our little Dutch village, and it plays a huge role in our chances of finding some measure of happiness--and it's something we ignore at our peril. Best feature of this feminist fable was its immanentism: an absolute refusal to accept the notion that there is any reality beyond the sentient existence we experience as we pass through life--so that all we can know and enjoy and hope for is contained in the endless cycle of Birth, Love, and Death.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Interesting and mildly amusing
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    billcr12
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/5/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A feminist tale which in some ways reminded me of The World According to Garp, with Glenn Close as an independent woman who decides to have a baby without the active participation of a father figure. The difference is that rather than an American perspective, it is a Dutch one. Antonia tells everyone that this is the last day of her life and she tells her story in flashbacks, starting with her arrival at the family farm with her daughter Danielle, and her intention of raising her as a single mother. Following in her mother's footsteps, Danielle announces that she would like to have a child and so Antonia searches for the proper donor. The line continues when Danielle gives birth to Therese who then begets Sarah; got it? This is not a mainstream work, by any means. The acting is solid and the viewpoint an interesting one. I was mildly amused.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I'm a Married Guy With Kids, and I Loved This Film. The World Needs More Films Like This.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    madcardinal
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/4/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Antonia's Line" is a beautiful, poignant film which skillfully manages to celebrate life in all its fertile richness while it simultaneously throws a richly deserved counter-punch into the face of 2,000 years of arrogant, church-sponsored misogyny. When a modern film such as this one cleverly turns the tables on real historical injustice, I do not find it offensive at all. I'm a man and I found this film admirable for giving a hoot about redressing a justified, legitimate grievance. Until very recently, women were not regarded as significant beings in their own right; they were deemed valuable only as helpmates to be utilized and governed by men - significant only to the extent that they were subordinate to a father and later a husband, and they were supposed to accept this secondary status without complaint, protest or challenge. Such traditional subjugation of women is rubbish and this movie plainly says so. That's a good thing. I see no reason to be offended by such truthfulness. These are not matters of conjecture but of historical fact. This movie features wonderful, strong female characters who are people in their own right - they are not compliant appendages of domineering male characters. Strong, independent women are found in cinema with extreme rarity, and this film has five of them! There are at least three male characters who are good human beings in this film: Farmer Bas; Crooked Finger; and Simon; so you can forget the reviews falsely complaining that all the male characters are creeps. Refreshingly, this movie also celebrates sexual joy without censorship or hand-wringing. It's even quite amusing, bringing a life-affirming smile to the viewer's face despite some of the violent and somber events which occur in other parts of the film. I found Dennis Littrell's review on this web site to be excellent, because it cites the ancient mythological underpinnings of this film. The soundtrack is beautiful. I suggest paying especially careful attention to the conversations between older and younger female characters, because they contain a complex interplay of emotion, intelligence, belief and intuition - and so, just when you think you have a character pigeonholed (for example, Antonia is completely atheist), you notice a nuance pointing in another direction. Sarah's final pronouncement in the film also alludes to new possibilities, if you're listening carefully. A fabulous, unique film, "Antonia's Line" gets my highest recommendation.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Yep....this movie was awful
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    TheCritic2009
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/4/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I have seen way to many movies in my life it is beyond official. I have sat through entire trilogies without having to stretch, take a break etc. But this one basically I wish I had just taken a bathroom break for the duration. I am a man I'm sure your aware by the way I am typing this out but don't give me some line about being a sexist. I want you to get paid the same amount blah blah blah, but this movie was just awful. Basically from minute one we skip bout 10 years every five minutes. This would be OK if we fully developed the characters or made you in anyway care about any of them but the director didn't. The plot is about a family of women who decide that they should keep men as a non important part of their lives which would of been great if there would have been a reason for it but there wasn't.(besides the lesbian I get that)They basically just seemed to make men look as objects so if the shoe was on the other foot all you ladies would hate this flick too. What else to say pretty pointless just seemed like the director decided to make a movie that forced feminism on everyone. And this movies sex scenes were gross and just trying to prove some pointless point about women in control. I don't know I'm rambling. Terrible movie. Check out departures if you wanna see a foreign film that was actually worth your time.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Sensitive, Surreal, Humorous, and Indomitable
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gradyharp
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/7/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    ANTONIA'S LINE continues as fresh today as when it was released and awarded Oscars in 1995. This very fine little Dutch film mocks the old adage of 'You can't go back home again' by introducing Antonia and her daughter returning to a village she had abandoned and setting up changes among the odd assortment of townsfolk that initiate a heritage of both wonderful and tragic events, each of which is a parable about family and community. The women rule here, even to the point of deciding to conceive by barter, by compulsion, and by taking arms against the macho power symbols of rape. All manner of variations of normal (spiritually possessed, moon howlers, disillusioned priests, mentally retarded, social outcasts) come under the influence of Antonia's strongly world-wise persona. The results are like a fairy tale for adults, both in content and in the wonderful visual effects. The cast is extraordinary as is the pacing of the direction. The message of this film endures - it pleads to be viewed regularly. Grady Harp
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Life-Affirming
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Magic Lamp
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/7/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is an epic movie. The movie plays out intensely, gripping attention right from the first frame. It affirms life in its story of death. Its complex in its simplicity, its comic in its seriousness, its subtle in its gravity. It depicts a life lived well and fully. It questions norms and it glorifies personal values. It gives the heart the mandate to lead the way. It may jerk people to take a fresh new look at their way of living their life. It may seem feminist or iconoclastic, but at the same time its very traditional and conservative in its message of family togetherness and social interdependence. I loved it!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Dutch touch on feminism
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Lee Eisenberg (eisenberg.lee@gmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/6/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The 1995 winner of Best Foreign Language Film tells the story of a woman, her daughter and granddaughter over several years in the Netherlands. The women do everything to show their strength. One of the best parts is what happens after a hypocrite makes fun of the granddaughter; I would hate to be in his place! Overall, "Antonia" (called "Antonia's Line" in English) is definitely one that I recommend. This and "The Assault" are Holland's two supreme masterpieces. In other words, ik reken erop (Dutch for "I count on it") because it is truly iets zoets (Dutch for "something sweet"). A veritable part of De Geschiedenis Des Nederlandsen Films (history of Dutch cinema).
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Well made but also at the same time ineffective.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Boba_Fett1138
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/9/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Funny thing with this movie is that it's an highly appreciated one (it even received an Oscar for best foreign language movie) all over the world but in its own native country the Netherlands it wasn't received that well. At least not as an Oscar worthy movie and everyone within the Netherlands at the time also was quite surprised it took home the Oscar. What I can say about this movie is that it feels like a waste opportunity. The movie feels like one with hugely potential and if it worked out better this could had really been an 'epic' strong feminist family drama but instead the movie jumps all over the place also with its different styles and it's mostly an ineffective one. There is not much interesting within the movie, although you certainly have the feeling that the story itself had plenty of interesting elements to offer but yet it somehow doesn't always translate well to the big screen. Perhaps if the movie would had been an hour longer it would had worked out better and also as a more effective one. The movie covers basically the entire lifespan of a strong-woman of the Dutch countryside and the future generations of women, her daughter her grand-daughter and right up till her great-grand daughter, while she herself is of course aging. This becomes an interesting aspect of the movie. It begins right after the end of WW II and it ends somewhere in the '90's or so I would guess. So the world around her is constantly changing but yet it also stays the same because she keeps all the people she care for close to her. This means that parts of the movie are set in different time-era's, which gives the movie something unique. It's obvious that this movie was intended as a strong feminist picture, with all strong female leads in it but with this I mostly feel that the movie isn't as effective as it should had been. It just doesn't feature enough strong or original moments within the movie. It's still a really well made and good looking movie though. It doesn't look at all like the movie got shot in the Netherlands, the countryside and all within this movie is far too beautiful looking for that. But I always have that with Dutch movies and I guess I just don't know how beautiful my country actually is. Perhaps I just need to stop watching so many movies and get out more... Female director Marleen Gorris is obviously capable of making a beautiful and professional looking movie. She actually now has a quite successful career in America as a movie director, which is quite an accomplishment not only because she is Dutch but also foremost because she is a female. She actually was the first woman to direct a movie that won an Oscar for best foreign film. Guess she is a strong woman just like Antonia in this movie and that's why she directed this movie with so much obvious passion and devotion. I wasn't too happy about the acting within this movie though. Willeke van Ammelrooy has always been praised for her role but in all honesty her performance is quite a mixed bag. As the younger Antonia she isn't always too great but as the older Antonia she's much better and more convincing. Can't say that the make-up always looks convincing though. Jan Decleir is normally always a real great actor but his role in this movie isn't anything too memorable but this is mostly due to the far too limited screen time he gets in this movie and he also has far too little lines to speak. He however still does a good job with his sequences and it's actually nice to notice that he took on a Dutch accent and for once dropped his native Belgian one. Still it's weird to hear many other actors within this movie still speak with a Belgian accent, while the movie is obviously set in the Netherlands but this of course has everything to do with the fact that this is a Belgium co-production and a certain part of the cast & crew just HAD to be Belgian. I wish I could say that it was a brilliant Dutch movie, worthy of its Oscar... 6/10 http://bobafett1138.blogspot.com/
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    This is the only dance we dance.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    lastliberal
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/5/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It takes courage to grow up and turn out to be who you truly are. I can't think of any other platitude that better describes this amazing film by writer/director Marleen Gorris. The Motion Picture Academy felt as strongly as I do, as they awarded it an Oscar; a well-deserved Oscar, I might add. It is about the progeny of Antonia (Willeke van Ammelrooy), a woman who returns to her village after WWII and begins life with her daughter Danielle (Els Dottermans). There is never any mention of a father. This is a feminist film in the purest sense. Men are not bashed, but there is a sense that they are not very useful, except for producing more daughters. Danielle seeks a male to impregnate her and bears a child prodigy, Th&eacute;r&egrave;se (Carolien Spoor, Esther Vriesendorp, and Veerle van Overloop), Th&eacute;r&egrave;se becomes a pupil of the town intellectual Crooked Finger (Mil Seghers) and cannot find a man who can satisfy her intellectually and physically, so she settles for the physical and has a daughter of her own. Men in this movie serve as seed bearers, or teachers, or comfort bearers, or, in one case, messengers of evil, as one manages to rape two women. But the film is not just about feminism, it is also about acceptance. Antonia never hesitates to give comfort and shelter to anyone in need, whether it bee someone with an intellectual disability, the raped sister, the woman who loves having babies, or the priest who finds that celebrating life is better than celebrating death. Her own daughter finds love in the arms of Th&eacute;r&egrave;se's tutor, and this is not judged, only accepted as another part of life. Everyone seems to find love in Antonia's circle, and her real progeny is exceeded by those she touches with love and acceptance. It is a beautiful story with a wealth of interesting characters. Gorris is an amazing writer and one can only be thrilled at her talent.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Nothing to fear
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gizmomogwai
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The winner of the 1995 Oscar for a foreign language film has, I think, been unfairly derided on political grounds. Antonia, called Antonia's Line in English, is a Dutch feminist film and has drawn criticism just for that. Sexists love to paint feminists with one brush based on a lunatic fringe, but as a male film watcher I can testify that there's nothing about the film that should be offensive to men. A villain rapist is a man, but rapists exist in life and there are plenty of men in the film who are decent. The women in the family never marry, but many of them still love men and keep them close in their lives. What really scares closet sexists is that the women in this movie are strong characters- even if it's in a positive way, that just won't sit will with those still wishing for a male-run society. The real objective of feminism is for men and women to share power, not make females the sole power. Antonia's Line (a title that makes more sense than the original title of Antonia, because it better captures the focus of the movie), is a fine film that includes colourful, interesting characters, some funny moments and some compelling drama. For example, Th&eacute;r&egrave;se is an interesting character because of her abnormal intelligence, and when the narrator announces she's been raped it's a shocking, disheartening moment (even though we don't actually see that rape). There's also some humour in Danielle announcing she wants a baby but also having a lack of interest in a husband, and in how her own mother arranges for her to get laid. There are lots of characters for a fairly short film, but most of even the minor characters have some appeal. This movie deserved its Oscar and it deserves to be seen.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Virtues and Flaws
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    palmiro
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    One of those films that falls in the category of "a celebration of life" (films falling into this category are a sure bet for serious Oscar consideration for Best Foreign Film). This film annoyed me a bit because it seemed to suggest that happiness is to be found simply by cultivating our relationships to one another and keeping connected. But there's also a big wide world out there, beyond our little Dutch village, and it plays a huge role in our chances of finding some measure of happiness--and it's something we ignore at our peril. Best feature of this feminist fable was its immanentism: an absolute refusal to accept the notion that there is any reality beyond the sentient existence we experience as we pass through life--so that all we can know and enjoy and hope for is contained in the endless cycle of Birth, Love, and Death.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Interesting and mildly amusing
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    billcr12
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/5/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A feminist tale which in some ways reminded me of The World According to Garp, with Glenn Close as an independent woman who decides to have a baby without the active participation of a father figure. The difference is that rather than an American perspective, it is a Dutch one. Antonia tells everyone that this is the last day of her life and she tells her story in flashbacks, starting with her arrival at the family farm with her daughter Danielle, and her intention of raising her as a single mother. Following in her mother's footsteps, Danielle announces that she would like to have a child and so Antonia searches for the proper donor. The line continues when Danielle gives birth to Therese who then begets Sarah; got it? This is not a mainstream work, by any means. The acting is solid and the viewpoint an interesting one. I was mildly amused.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I'm a Married Guy With Kids, and I Loved This Film. The World Needs More Films Like This.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    madcardinal
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/4/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Antonia's Line" is a beautiful, poignant film which skillfully manages to celebrate life in all its fertile richness while it simultaneously throws a richly deserved counter-punch into the face of 2,000 years of arrogant, church-sponsored misogyny. When a modern film such as this one cleverly turns the tables on real historical injustice, I do not find it offensive at all. I'm a man and I found this film admirable for giving a hoot about redressing a justified, legitimate grievance. Until very recently, women were not regarded as significant beings in their own right; they were deemed valuable only as helpmates to be utilized and governed by men - significant only to the extent that they were subordinate to a father and later a husband, and they were supposed to accept this secondary status without complaint, protest or challenge. Such traditional subjugation of women is rubbish and this movie plainly says so. That's a good thing. I see no reason to be offended by such truthfulness. These are not matters of conjecture but of historical fact. This movie features wonderful, strong female characters who are people in their own right - they are not compliant appendages of domineering male characters. Strong, independent women are found in cinema with extreme rarity, and this film has five of them! There are at least three male characters who are good human beings in this film: Farmer Bas; Crooked Finger; and Simon; so you can forget the reviews falsely complaining that all the male characters are creeps. Refreshingly, this movie also celebrates sexual joy without censorship or hand-wringing. It's even quite amusing, bringing a life-affirming smile to the viewer's face despite some of the violent and somber events which occur in other parts of the film. I found Dennis Littrell's review on this web site to be excellent, because it cites the ancient mythological underpinnings of this film. The soundtrack is beautiful. I suggest paying especially careful attention to the conversations between older and younger female characters, because they contain a complex interplay of emotion, intelligence, belief and intuition - and so, just when you think you have a character pigeonholed (for example, Antonia is completely atheist), you notice a nuance pointing in another direction. Sarah's final pronouncement in the film also alludes to new possibilities, if you're listening carefully. A fabulous, unique film, "Antonia's Line" gets my highest recommendation.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Yep....this movie was awful
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    TheCritic2009
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/4/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I have seen way to many movies in my life it is beyond official. I have sat through entire trilogies without having to stretch, take a break etc. But this one basically I wish I had just taken a bathroom break for the duration. I am a man I'm sure your aware by the way I am typing this out but don't give me some line about being a sexist. I want you to get paid the same amount blah blah blah, but this movie was just awful. Basically from minute one we skip bout 10 years every five minutes. This would be OK if we fully developed the characters or made you in anyway care about any of them but the director didn't. The plot is about a family of women who decide that they should keep men as a non important part of their lives which would of been great if there would have been a reason for it but there wasn't.(besides the lesbian I get that)They basically just seemed to make men look as objects so if the shoe was on the other foot all you ladies would hate this flick too. What else to say pretty pointless just seemed like the director decided to make a movie that forced feminism on everyone. And this movies sex scenes were gross and just trying to prove some pointless point about women in control. I don't know I'm rambling. Terrible movie. Check out departures if you wanna see a foreign film that was actually worth your time.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Sensitive, Surreal, Humorous, and Indomitable
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gradyharp
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/7/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    ANTONIA'S LINE continues as fresh today as when it was released and awarded Oscars in 1995. This very fine little Dutch film mocks the old adage of 'You can't go back home again' by introducing Antonia and her daughter returning to a village she had abandoned and setting up changes among the odd assortment of townsfolk that initiate a heritage of both wonderful and tragic events, each of which is a parable about family and community. The women rule here, even to the point of deciding to conceive by barter, by compulsion, and by taking arms against the macho power symbols of rape. All manner of variations of normal (spiritually possessed, moon howlers, disillusioned priests, mentally retarded, social outcasts) come under the influence of Antonia's strongly world-wise persona. The results are like a fairy tale for adults, both in content and in the wonderful visual effects. The cast is extraordinary as is the pacing of the direction. The message of this film endures - it pleads to be viewed regularly. Grady Harp
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Life-Affirming
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Magic Lamp
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/7/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is an epic movie. The movie plays out intensely, gripping attention right from the first frame. It affirms life in its story of death. Its complex in its simplicity, its comic in its seriousness, its subtle in its gravity. It depicts a life lived well and fully. It questions norms and it glorifies personal values. It gives the heart the mandate to lead the way. It may jerk people to take a fresh new look at their way of living their life. It may seem feminist or iconoclastic, but at the same time its very traditional and conservative in its message of family togetherness and social interdependence. I loved it!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Dutch touch on feminism
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Lee Eisenberg (eisenberg.lee@gmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/6/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The 1995 winner of Best Foreign Language Film tells the story of a woman, her daughter and granddaughter over several years in the Netherlands. The women do everything to show their strength. One of the best parts is what happens after a hypocrite makes fun of the granddaughter; I would hate to be in his place! Overall, "Antonia" (called "Antonia's Line" in English) is definitely one that I recommend. This and "The Assault" are Holland's two supreme masterpieces. In other words, ik reken erop (Dutch for "I count on it") because it is truly iets zoets (Dutch for "something sweet"). A veritable part of De Geschiedenis Des Nederlandsen Films (history of Dutch cinema).
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Well made but also at the same time ineffective.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Boba_Fett1138
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/9/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Funny thing with this movie is that it's an highly appreciated one (it even received an Oscar for best foreign language movie) all over the world but in its own native country the Netherlands it wasn't received that well. At least not as an Oscar worthy movie and everyone within the Netherlands at the time also was quite surprised it took home the Oscar. What I can say about this movie is that it feels like a waste opportunity. The movie feels like one with hugely potential and if it worked out better this could had really been an 'epic' strong feminist family drama but instead the movie jumps all over the place also with its different styles and it's mostly an ineffective one. There is not much interesting within the movie, although you certainly have the feeling that the story itself had plenty of interesting elements to offer but yet it somehow doesn't always translate well to the big screen. Perhaps if the movie would had been an hour longer it would had worked out better and also as a more effective one. The movie covers basically the entire lifespan of a strong-woman of the Dutch countryside and the future generations of women, her daughter her grand-daughter and right up till her great-grand daughter, while she herself is of course aging. This becomes an interesting aspect of the movie. It begins right after the end of WW II and it ends somewhere in the '90's or so I would guess. So the world around her is constantly changing but yet it also stays the same because she keeps all the people she care for close to her. This means that parts of the movie are set in different time-era's, which gives the movie something unique. It's obvious that this movie was intended as a strong feminist picture, with all strong female leads in it but with this I mostly feel that the movie isn't as effective as it should had been. It just doesn't feature enough strong or original moments within the movie. It's still a really well made and good looking movie though. It doesn't look at all like the movie got shot in the Netherlands, the countryside and all within this movie is far too beautiful looking for that. But I always have that with Dutch movies and I guess I just don't know how beautiful my country actually is. Perhaps I just need to stop watching so many movies and get out more... Female director Marleen Gorris is obviously capable of making a beautiful and professional looking movie. She actually now has a quite successful career in America as a movie director, which is quite an accomplishment not only because she is Dutch but also foremost because she is a female. She actually was the first woman to direct a movie that won an Oscar for best foreign film. Guess she is a strong woman just like Antonia in this movie and that's why she directed this movie with so much obvious passion and devotion. I wasn't too happy about the acting within this movie though. Willeke van Ammelrooy has always been praised for her role but in all honesty her performance is quite a mixed bag. As the younger Antonia she isn't always too great but as the older Antonia she's much better and more convincing. Can't say that the make-up always looks convincing though. Jan Decleir is normally always a real great actor but his role in this movie isn't anything too memorable but this is mostly due to the far too limited screen time he gets in this movie and he also has far too little lines to speak. He however still does a good job with his sequences and it's actually nice to notice that he took on a Dutch accent and for once dropped his native Belgian one. Still it's weird to hear many other actors within this movie still speak with a Belgian accent, while the movie is obviously set in the Netherlands but this of course has everything to do with the fact that this is a Belgium co-production and a certain part of the cast & crew just HAD to be Belgian. I wish I could say that it was a brilliant Dutch movie, worthy of its Oscar... 6/10 http://bobafett1138.blogspot.com/
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    This is the only dance we dance.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    lastliberal
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/5/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It takes courage to grow up and turn out to be who you truly are. I can't think of any other platitude that better describes this amazing film by writer/director Marleen Gorris. The Motion Picture Academy felt as strongly as I do, as they awarded it an Oscar; a well-deserved Oscar, I might add. It is about the progeny of Antonia (Willeke van Ammelrooy), a woman who returns to her village after WWII and begins life with her daughter Danielle (Els Dottermans). There is never any mention of a father. This is a feminist film in the purest sense. Men are not bashed, but there is a sense that they are not very useful, except for producing more daughters. Danielle seeks a male to impregnate her and bears a child prodigy, Th&eacute;r&egrave;se (Carolien Spoor, Esther Vriesendorp, and Veerle van Overloop), Th&eacute;r&egrave;se becomes a pupil of the town intellectual Crooked Finger (Mil Seghers) and cannot find a man who can satisfy her intellectually and physically, so she settles for the physical and has a daughter of her own. Men in this movie serve as seed bearers, or teachers, or comfort bearers, or, in one case, messengers of evil, as one manages to rape two women. But the film is not just about feminism, it is also about acceptance. Antonia never hesitates to give comfort and shelter to anyone in need, whether it bee someone with an intellectual disability, the raped sister, the woman who loves having babies, or the priest who finds that celebrating life is better than celebrating death. Her own daughter finds love in the arms of Th&eacute;r&egrave;se's tutor, and this is not judged, only accepted as another part of life. Everyone seems to find love in Antonia's circle, and her real progeny is exceeded by those she touches with love and acceptance. It is a beautiful story with a wealth of interesting characters. Gorris is an amazing writer and one can only be thrilled at her talent.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Nothing to fear
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gizmomogwai
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The winner of the 1995 Oscar for a foreign language film has, I think, been unfairly derided on political grounds. Antonia, called Antonia's Line in English, is a Dutch feminist film and has drawn criticism just for that. Sexists love to paint feminists with one brush based on a lunatic fringe, but as a male film watcher I can testify that there's nothing about the film that should be offensive to men. A villain rapist is a man, but rapists exist in life and there are plenty of men in the film who are decent. The women in the family never marry, but many of them still love men and keep them close in their lives. What really scares closet sexists is that the women in this movie are strong characters- even if it's in a positive way, that just won't sit will with those still wishing for a male-run society. The real objective of feminism is for men and women to share power, not make females the sole power. Antonia's Line (a title that makes more sense than the original title of Antonia, because it better captures the focus of the movie), is a fine film that includes colourful, interesting characters, some funny moments and some compelling drama. For example, Th&eacute;r&egrave;se is an interesting character because of her abnormal intelligence, and when the narrator announces she's been raped it's a shocking, disheartening moment (even though we don't actually see that rape). There's also some humour in Danielle announcing she wants a baby but also having a lack of interest in a husband, and in how her own mother arranges for her to get laid. There are lots of characters for a fairly short film, but most of even the minor characters have some appeal. This movie deserved its Oscar and it deserves to be seen.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Virtues and Flaws
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    palmiro
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    One of those films that falls in the category of "a celebration of life" (films falling into this category are a sure bet for serious Oscar consideration for Best Foreign Film). This film annoyed me a bit because it seemed to suggest that happiness is to be found simply by cultivating our relationships to one another and keeping connected. But there's also a big wide world out there, beyond our little Dutch village, and it plays a huge role in our chances of finding some measure of happiness--and it's something we ignore at our peril. Best feature of this feminist fable was its immanentism: an absolute refusal to accept the notion that there is any reality beyond the sentient existence we experience as we pass through life--so that all we can know and enjoy and hope for is contained in the endless cycle of Birth, Love, and Death.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Interesting and mildly amusing
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    billcr12
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/5/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A feminist tale which in some ways reminded me of The World According to Garp, with Glenn Close as an independent woman who decides to have a baby without the active participation of a father figure. The difference is that rather than an American perspective, it is a Dutch one. Antonia tells everyone that this is the last day of her life and she tells her story in flashbacks, starting with her arrival at the family farm with her daughter Danielle, and her intention of raising her as a single mother. Following in her mother's footsteps, Danielle announces that she would like to have a child and so Antonia searches for the proper donor. The line continues when Danielle gives birth to Therese who then begets Sarah; got it? This is not a mainstream work, by any means. The acting is solid and the viewpoint an interesting one. I was mildly amused.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I'm a Married Guy With Kids, and I Loved This Film. The World Needs More Films Like This.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    madcardinal
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/4/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Antonia's Line" is a beautiful, poignant film which skillfully manages to celebrate life in all its fertile richness while it simultaneously throws a richly deserved counter-punch into the face of 2,000 years of arrogant, church-sponsored misogyny. When a modern film such as this one cleverly turns the tables on real historical injustice, I do not find it offensive at all. I'm a man and I found this film admirable for giving a hoot about redressing a justified, legitimate grievance. Until very recently, women were not regarded as significant beings in their own right; they were deemed valuable only as helpmates to be utilized and governed by men - significant only to the extent that they were subordinate to a father and later a husband, and they were supposed to accept this secondary status without complaint, protest or challenge. Such traditional subjugation of women is rubbish and this movie plainly says so. That's a good thing. I see no reason to be offended by such truthfulness. These are not matters of conjecture but of historical fact. This movie features wonderful, strong female characters who are people in their own right - they are not compliant appendages of domineering male characters. Strong, independent women are found in cinema with extreme rarity, and this film has five of them! There are at least three male characters who are good human beings in this film: Farmer Bas; Crooked Finger; and Simon; so you can forget the reviews falsely complaining that all the male characters are creeps. Refreshingly, this movie also celebrates sexual joy without censorship or hand-wringing. It's even quite amusing, bringing a life-affirming smile to the viewer's face despite some of the violent and somber events which occur in other parts of the film. I found Dennis Littrell's review on this web site to be excellent, because it cites the ancient mythological underpinnings of this film. The soundtrack is beautiful. I suggest paying especially careful attention to the conversations between older and younger female characters, because they contain a complex interplay of emotion, intelligence, belief and intuition - and so, just when you think you have a character pigeonholed (for example, Antonia is completely atheist), you notice a nuance pointing in another direction. Sarah's final pronouncement in the film also alludes to new possibilities, if you're listening carefully. A fabulous, unique film, "Antonia's Line" gets my highest recommendation.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Yep....this movie was awful
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    TheCritic2009
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/4/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I have seen way to many movies in my life it is beyond official. I have sat through entire trilogies without having to stretch, take a break etc. But this one basically I wish I had just taken a bathroom break for the duration. I am a man I'm sure your aware by the way I am typing this out but don't give me some line about being a sexist. I want you to get paid the same amount blah blah blah, but this movie was just awful. Basically from minute one we skip bout 10 years every five minutes. This would be OK if we fully developed the characters or made you in anyway care about any of them but the director didn't. The plot is about a family of women who decide that they should keep men as a non important part of their lives which would of been great if there would have been a reason for it but there wasn't.(besides the lesbian I get that)They basically just seemed to make men look as objects so if the shoe was on the other foot all you ladies would hate this flick too. What else to say pretty pointless just seemed like the director decided to make a movie that forced feminism on everyone. And this movies sex scenes were gross and just trying to prove some pointless point about women in control. I don't know I'm rambling. Terrible movie. Check out departures if you wanna see a foreign film that was actually worth your time.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Sensitive, Surreal, Humorous, and Indomitable
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gradyharp
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/7/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    ANTONIA'S LINE continues as fresh today as when it was released and awarded Oscars in 1995. This very fine little Dutch film mocks the old adage of 'You can't go back home again' by introducing Antonia and her daughter returning to a village she had abandoned and setting up changes among the odd assortment of townsfolk that initiate a heritage of both wonderful and tragic events, each of which is a parable about family and community. The women rule here, even to the point of deciding to conceive by barter, by compulsion, and by taking arms against the macho power symbols of rape. All manner of variations of normal (spiritually possessed, moon howlers, disillusioned priests, mentally retarded, social outcasts) come under the influence of Antonia's strongly world-wise persona. The results are like a fairy tale for adults, both in content and in the wonderful visual effects. The cast is extraordinary as is the pacing of the direction. The message of this film endures - it pleads to be viewed regularly. Grady Harp
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Life-Affirming
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Magic Lamp
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/7/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is an epic movie. The movie plays out intensely, gripping attention right from the first frame. It affirms life in its story of death. Its complex in its simplicity, its comic in its seriousness, its subtle in its gravity. It depicts a life lived well and fully. It questions norms and it glorifies personal values. It gives the heart the mandate to lead the way. It may jerk people to take a fresh new look at their way of living their life. It may seem feminist or iconoclastic, but at the same time its very traditional and conservative in its message of family togetherness and social interdependence. I loved it!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Dutch touch on feminism
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Lee Eisenberg (eisenberg.lee@gmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/6/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The 1995 winner of Best Foreign Language Film tells the story of a woman, her daughter and granddaughter over several years in the Netherlands. The women do everything to show their strength. One of the best parts is what happens after a hypocrite makes fun of the granddaughter; I would hate to be in his place! Overall, "Antonia" (called "Antonia's Line" in English) is definitely one that I recommend. This and "The Assault" are Holland's two supreme masterpieces. In other words, ik reken erop (Dutch for "I count on it") because it is truly iets zoets (Dutch for "something sweet"). A veritable part of De Geschiedenis Des Nederlandsen Films (history of Dutch cinema).
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Well made but also at the same time ineffective.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Boba_Fett1138
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/9/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Funny thing with this movie is that it's an highly appreciated one (it even received an Oscar for best foreign language movie) all over the world but in its own native country the Netherlands it wasn't received that well. At least not as an Oscar worthy movie and everyone within the Netherlands at the time also was quite surprised it took home the Oscar. What I can say about this movie is that it feels like a waste opportunity. The movie feels like one with hugely potential and if it worked out better this could had really been an 'epic' strong feminist family drama but instead the movie jumps all over the place also with its different styles and it's mostly an ineffective one. There is not much interesting within the movie, although you certainly have the feeling that the story itself had plenty of interesting elements to offer but yet it somehow doesn't always translate well to the big screen. Perhaps if the movie would had been an hour longer it would had worked out better and also as a more effective one. The movie covers basically the entire lifespan of a strong-woman of the Dutch countryside and the future generations of women, her daughter her grand-daughter and right up till her great-grand daughter, while she herself is of course aging. This becomes an interesting aspect of the movie. It begins right after the end of WW II and it ends somewhere in the '90's or so I would guess. So the world around her is constantly changing but yet it also stays the same because she keeps all the people she care for close to her. This means that parts of the movie are set in different time-era's, which gives the movie something unique. It's obvious that this movie was intended as a strong feminist picture, with all strong female leads in it but with this I mostly feel that the movie isn't as effective as it should had been. It just doesn't feature enough strong or original moments within the movie. It's still a really well made and good looking movie though. It doesn't look at all like the movie got shot in the Netherlands, the countryside and all within this movie is far too beautiful looking for that. But I always have that with Dutch movies and I guess I just don't know how beautiful my country actually is. Perhaps I just need to stop watching so many movies and get out more... Female director Marleen Gorris is obviously capable of making a beautiful and professional looking movie. She actually now has a quite successful career in America as a movie director, which is quite an accomplishment not only because she is Dutch but also foremost because she is a female. She actually was the first woman to direct a movie that won an Oscar for best foreign film. Guess she is a strong woman just like Antonia in this movie and that's why she directed this movie with so much obvious passion and devotion. I wasn't too happy about the acting within this movie though. Willeke van Ammelrooy has always been praised for her role but in all honesty her performance is quite a mixed bag. As the younger Antonia she isn't always too great but as the older Antonia she's much better and more convincing. Can't say that the make-up always looks convincing though. Jan Decleir is normally always a real great actor but his role in this movie isn't anything too memorable but this is mostly due to the far too limited screen time he gets in this movie and he also has far too little lines to speak. He however still does a good job with his sequences and it's actually nice to notice that he took on a Dutch accent and for once dropped his native Belgian one. Still it's weird to hear many other actors within this movie still speak with a Belgian accent, while the movie is obviously set in the Netherlands but this of course has everything to do with the fact that this is a Belgium co-production and a certain part of the cast & crew just HAD to be Belgian. I wish I could say that it was a brilliant Dutch movie, worthy of its Oscar... 6/10 http://bobafett1138.blogspot.com/
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    This is the only dance we dance.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    lastliberal
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/5/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It takes courage to grow up and turn out to be who you truly are. I can't think of any other platitude that better describes this amazing film by writer/director Marleen Gorris. The Motion Picture Academy felt as strongly as I do, as they awarded it an Oscar; a well-deserved Oscar, I might add. It is about the progeny of Antonia (Willeke van Ammelrooy), a woman who returns to her village after WWII and begins life with her daughter Danielle (Els Dottermans). There is never any mention of a father. This is a feminist film in the purest sense. Men are not bashed, but there is a sense that they are not very useful, except for producing more daughters. Danielle seeks a male to impregnate her and bears a child prodigy, Th&eacute;r&egrave;se (Carolien Spoor, Esther Vriesendorp, and Veerle van Overloop), Th&eacute;r&egrave;se becomes a pupil of the town intellectual Crooked Finger (Mil Seghers) and cannot find a man who can satisfy her intellectually and physically, so she settles for the physical and has a daughter of her own. Men in this movie serve as seed bearers, or teachers, or comfort bearers, or, in one case, messengers of evil, as one manages to rape two women. But the film is not just about feminism, it is also about acceptance. Antonia never hesitates to give comfort and shelter to anyone in need, whether it bee someone with an intellectual disability, the raped sister, the woman who loves having babies, or the priest who finds that celebrating life is better than celebrating death. Her own daughter finds love in the arms of Th&eacute;r&egrave;se's tutor, and this is not judged, only accepted as another part of life. Everyone seems to find love in Antonia's circle, and her real progeny is exceeded by those she touches with love and acceptance. It is a beautiful story with a wealth of interesting characters. Gorris is an amazing writer and one can only be thrilled at her talent.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Nothing to fear
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gizmomogwai
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The winner of the 1995 Oscar for a foreign language film has, I think, been unfairly derided on political grounds. Antonia, called Antonia's Line in English, is a Dutch feminist film and has drawn criticism just for that. Sexists love to paint feminists with one brush based on a lunatic fringe, but as a male film watcher I can testify that there's nothing about the film that should be offensive to men. A villain rapist is a man, but rapists exist in life and there are plenty of men in the film who are decent. The women in the family never marry, but many of them still love men and keep them close in their lives. What really scares closet sexists is that the women in this movie are strong characters- even if it's in a positive way, that just won't sit will with those still wishing for a male-run society. The real objective of feminism is for men and women to share power, not make females the sole power. Antonia's Line (a title that makes more sense than the original title of Antonia, because it better captures the focus of the movie), is a fine film that includes colourful, interesting characters, some funny moments and some compelling drama. For example, Th&eacute;r&egrave;se is an interesting character because of her abnormal intelligence, and when the narrator announces she's been raped it's a shocking, disheartening moment (even though we don't actually see that rape). There's also some humour in Danielle announcing she wants a baby but also having a lack of interest in a husband, and in how her own mother arranges for her to get laid. There are lots of characters for a fairly short film, but most of even the minor characters have some appeal. This movie deserved its Oscar and it deserves to be seen.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Virtues and Flaws
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    palmiro
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    One of those films that falls in the category of "a celebration of life" (films falling into this category are a sure bet for serious Oscar consideration for Best Foreign Film). This film annoyed me a bit because it seemed to suggest that happiness is to be found simply by cultivating our relationships to one another and keeping connected. But there's also a big wide world out there, beyond our little Dutch village, and it plays a huge role in our chances of finding some measure of happiness--and it's something we ignore at our peril. Best feature of this feminist fable was its immanentism: an absolute refusal to accept the notion that there is any reality beyond the sentient existence we experience as we pass through life--so that all we can know and enjoy and hope for is contained in the endless cycle of Birth, Love, and Death.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Interesting and mildly amusing
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    billcr12
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/5/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A feminist tale which in some ways reminded me of The World According to Garp, with Glenn Close as an independent woman who decides to have a baby without the active participation of a father figure. The difference is that rather than an American perspective, it is a Dutch one. Antonia tells everyone that this is the last day of her life and she tells her story in flashbacks, starting with her arrival at the family farm with her daughter Danielle, and her intention of raising her as a single mother. Following in her mother's footsteps, Danielle announces that she would like to have a child and so Antonia searches for the proper donor. The line continues when Danielle gives birth to Therese who then begets Sarah; got it? This is not a mainstream work, by any means. The acting is solid and the viewpoint an interesting one. I was mildly amused.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I'm a Married Guy With Kids, and I Loved This Film. The World Needs More Films Like This.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    madcardinal
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/4/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Antonia's Line" is a beautiful, poignant film which skillfully manages to celebrate life in all its fertile richness while it simultaneously throws a richly deserved counter-punch into the face of 2,000 years of arrogant, church-sponsored misogyny. When a modern film such as this one cleverly turns the tables on real historical injustice, I do not find it offensive at all. I'm a man and I found this film admirable for giving a hoot about redressing a justified, legitimate grievance. Until very recently, women were not regarded as significant beings in their own right; they were deemed valuable only as helpmates to be utilized and governed by men - significant only to the extent that they were subordinate to a father and later a husband, and they were supposed to accept this secondary status without complaint, protest or challenge. Such traditional subjugation of women is rubbish and this movie plainly says so. That's a good thing. I see no reason to be offended by such truthfulness. These are not matters of conjecture but of historical fact. This movie features wonderful, strong female characters who are people in their own right - they are not compliant appendages of domineering male characters. Strong, independent women are found in cinema with extreme rarity, and this film has five of them! There are at least three male characters who are good human beings in this film: Farmer Bas; Crooked Finger; and Simon; so you can forget the reviews falsely complaining that all the male characters are creeps. Refreshingly, this movie also celebrates sexual joy without censorship or hand-wringing. It's even quite amusing, bringing a life-affirming smile to the viewer's face despite some of the violent and somber events which occur in other parts of the film. I found Dennis Littrell's review on this web site to be excellent, because it cites the ancient mythological underpinnings of this film. The soundtrack is beautiful. I suggest paying especially careful attention to the conversations between older and younger female characters, because they contain a complex interplay of emotion, intelligence, belief and intuition - and so, just when you think you have a character pigeonholed (for example, Antonia is completely atheist), you notice a nuance pointing in another direction. Sarah's final pronouncement in the film also alludes to new possibilities, if you're listening carefully. A fabulous, unique film, "Antonia's Line" gets my highest recommendation.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Yep....this movie was awful
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    TheCritic2009
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/4/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I have seen way to many movies in my life it is beyond official. I have sat through entire trilogies without having to stretch, take a break etc. But this one basically I wish I had just taken a bathroom break for the duration. I am a man I'm sure your aware by the way I am typing this out but don't give me some line about being a sexist. I want you to get paid the same amount blah blah blah, but this movie was just awful. Basically from minute one we skip bout 10 years every five minutes. This would be OK if we fully developed the characters or made you in anyway care about any of them but the director didn't. The plot is about a family of women who decide that they should keep men as a non important part of their lives which would of been great if there would have been a reason for it but there wasn't.(besides the lesbian I get that)They basically just seemed to make men look as objects so if the shoe was on the other foot all you ladies would hate this flick too. What else to say pretty pointless just seemed like the director decided to make a movie that forced feminism on everyone. And this movies sex scenes were gross and just trying to prove some pointless point about women in control. I don't know I'm rambling. Terrible movie. Check out departures if you wanna see a foreign film that was actually worth your time.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Sensitive, Surreal, Humorous, and Indomitable
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gradyharp
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/7/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    ANTONIA'S LINE continues as fresh today as when it was released and awarded Oscars in 1995. This very fine little Dutch film mocks the old adage of 'You can't go back home again' by introducing Antonia and her daughter returning to a village she had abandoned and setting up changes among the odd assortment of townsfolk that initiate a heritage of both wonderful and tragic events, each of which is a parable about family and community. The women rule here, even to the point of deciding to conceive by barter, by compulsion, and by taking arms against the macho power symbols of rape. All manner of variations of normal (spiritually possessed, moon howlers, disillusioned priests, mentally retarded, social outcasts) come under the influence of Antonia's strongly world-wise persona. The results are like a fairy tale for adults, both in content and in the wonderful visual effects. The cast is extraordinary as is the pacing of the direction. The message of this film endures - it pleads to be viewed regularly. Grady Harp
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Life-Affirming
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Magic Lamp
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/7/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is an epic movie. The movie plays out intensely, gripping attention right from the first frame. It affirms life in its story of death. Its complex in its simplicity, its comic in its seriousness, its subtle in its gravity. It depicts a life lived well and fully. It questions norms and it glorifies personal values. It gives the heart the mandate to lead the way. It may jerk people to take a fresh new look at their way of living their life. It may seem feminist or iconoclastic, but at the same time its very traditional and conservative in its message of family togetherness and social interdependence. I loved it!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Dutch touch on feminism
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Lee Eisenberg (eisenberg.lee@gmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/6/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The 1995 winner of Best Foreign Language Film tells the story of a woman, her daughter and granddaughter over several years in the Netherlands. The women do everything to show their strength. One of the best parts is what happens after a hypocrite makes fun of the granddaughter; I would hate to be in his place! Overall, "Antonia" (called "Antonia's Line" in English) is definitely one that I recommend. This and "The Assault" are Holland's two supreme masterpieces. In other words, ik reken erop (Dutch for "I count on it") because it is truly iets zoets (Dutch for "something sweet"). A veritable part of De Geschiedenis Des Nederlandsen Films (history of Dutch cinema).
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Well made but also at the same time ineffective.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Boba_Fett1138
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/9/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Funny thing with this movie is that it's an highly appreciated one (it even received an Oscar for best foreign language movie) all over the world but in its own native country the Netherlands it wasn't received that well. At least not as an Oscar worthy movie and everyone within the Netherlands at the time also was quite surprised it took home the Oscar. What I can say about this movie is that it feels like a waste opportunity. The movie feels like one with hugely potential and if it worked out better this could had really been an 'epic' strong feminist family drama but instead the movie jumps all over the place also with its different styles and it's mostly an ineffective one. There is not much interesting within the movie, although you certainly have the feeling that the story itself had plenty of interesting elements to offer but yet it somehow doesn't always translate well to the big screen. Perhaps if the movie would had been an hour longer it would had worked out better and also as a more effective one. The movie covers basically the entire lifespan of a strong-woman of the Dutch countryside and the future generations of women, her daughter her grand-daughter and right up till her great-grand daughter, while she herself is of course aging. This becomes an interesting aspect of the movie. It begins right after the end of WW II and it ends somewhere in the '90's or so I would guess. So the world around her is constantly changing but yet it also stays the same because she keeps all the people she care for close to her. This means that parts of the movie are set in different time-era's, which gives the movie something unique. It's obvious that this movie was intended as a strong feminist picture, with all strong female leads in it but with this I mostly feel that the movie isn't as effective as it should had been. It just doesn't feature enough strong or original moments within the movie. It's still a really well made and good looking movie though. It doesn't look at all like the movie got shot in the Netherlands, the countryside and all within this movie is far too beautiful looking for that. But I always have that with Dutch movies and I guess I just don't know how beautiful my country actually is. Perhaps I just need to stop watching so many movies and get out more... Female director Marleen Gorris is obviously capable of making a beautiful and professional looking movie. She actually now has a quite successful career in America as a movie director, which is quite an accomplishment not only because she is Dutch but also foremost because she is a female. She actually was the first woman to direct a movie that won an Oscar for best foreign film. Guess she is a strong woman just like Antonia in this movie and that's why she directed this movie with so much obvious passion and devotion. I wasn't too happy about the acting within this movie though. Willeke van Ammelrooy has always been praised for her role but in all honesty her performance is quite a mixed bag. As the younger Antonia she isn't always too great but as the older Antonia she's much better and more convincing. Can't say that the make-up always looks convincing though. Jan Decleir is normally always a real great actor but his role in this movie isn't anything too memorable but this is mostly due to the far too limited screen time he gets in this movie and he also has far too little lines to speak. He however still does a good job with his sequences and it's actually nice to notice that he took on a Dutch accent and for once dropped his native Belgian one. Still it's weird to hear many other actors within this movie still speak with a Belgian accent, while the movie is obviously set in the Netherlands but this of course has everything to do with the fact that this is a Belgium co-production and a certain part of the cast & crew just HAD to be Belgian. I wish I could say that it was a brilliant Dutch movie, worthy of its Oscar... 6/10 http://bobafett1138.blogspot.com/
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    This is the only dance we dance.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    lastliberal
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/5/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It takes courage to grow up and turn out to be who you truly are. I can't think of any other platitude that better describes this amazing film by writer/director Marleen Gorris. The Motion Picture Academy felt as strongly as I do, as they awarded it an Oscar; a well-deserved Oscar, I might add. It is about the progeny of Antonia (Willeke van Ammelrooy), a woman who returns to her village after WWII and begins life with her daughter Danielle (Els Dottermans). There is never any mention of a father. This is a feminist film in the purest sense. Men are not bashed, but there is a sense that they are not very useful, except for producing more daughters. Danielle seeks a male to impregnate her and bears a child prodigy, Th&eacute;r&egrave;se (Carolien Spoor, Esther Vriesendorp, and Veerle van Overloop), Th&eacute;r&egrave;se becomes a pupil of the town intellectual Crooked Finger (Mil Seghers) and cannot find a man who can satisfy her intellectually and physically, so she settles for the physical and has a daughter of her own. Men in this movie serve as seed bearers, or teachers, or comfort bearers, or, in one case, messengers of evil, as one manages to rape two women. But the film is not just about feminism, it is also about acceptance. Antonia never hesitates to give comfort and shelter to anyone in need, whether it bee someone with an intellectual disability, the raped sister, the woman who loves having babies, or the priest who finds that celebrating life is better than celebrating death. Her own daughter finds love in the arms of Th&eacute;r&egrave;se's tutor, and this is not judged, only accepted as another part of life. Everyone seems to find love in Antonia's circle, and her real progeny is exceeded by those she touches with love and acceptance. It is a beautiful story with a wealth of interesting characters. Gorris is an amazing writer and one can only be thrilled at her talent.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
 </reviews>
</filme>
