<filme>
 <id>
  190
 </id>
 <imdburl>
  http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0097499
 </imdburl>
 <ano>
  1989
 </ano>
 <titulo>
  Henrique V
 </titulo>
 <rating>
  7.7
 </rating>
 <sinopse>
  The gritty adaption of William Shakespeare's play about the English King's bloody conquest of France.
 </sinopse>
 <storyline>
  King Henry V of England is insulted by the King of France. As a result, he leads his army into battle against France. Along the way, the young king must struggle with the sinking morale of his troops and his own inner doubts. The war culminates at the bloody Battle of Agincourt.
 </storyline>
 <generos>
  <genero>
   Action
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Biography
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Drama
  </genero>
 </generos>
 <keywords>
  <keyword>
   king
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   france
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   england
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   battle
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   king of france
  </keyword>
 </keywords>
 <diretores>
  <diretor>
   Kenneth Branagh
  </diretor>
 </diretores>
 <escritores>
  <escritor>
   William Shakespeare
  </escritor>
  <escritor>
   Kenneth Branagh
  </escritor>
 </escritores>
 <atores>
  <ator>
   Kenneth Branagh
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Derek Jacobi
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Simon Shepherd
  </ator>
 </atores>
 <reviews>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Powerful and Gritty Adaptation...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Janis Livens
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I'm one of those illiterate hacks who hasn't read a single Shakespeare play till the end. It's because in my country we have our own "bard" and Shakespeare's plays were glanced at best. The film itself was brilliant at times and dull at others. It works as individuals scenes perfectly but fails at being compelling narrative due many scenes that felt pointless to me. The reason why enjoyed the most of Henry V was Kenneth Branagh. His brilliant performance carried the film for me and any scene with him was a joy to watch. It's really hard to comment on the acting. The cast is brilliant from top to bottom, my favorite being Brian "Gordon's Alive!" Blessed and Ian Holm. The direction by Kenneth Branagh is worth mentioning. He clearly made Henry V as an anti-war film and it works perfectly. The aftermath of the battle is very powerful, thanks to the direction and magnificent score. But sadly, it's not without problems. The most glaring problem to me, was the pacing. Nearly every single flashback scene stopped the film to a screeching halt. And then there is the silly ending. While I did enjoy the chemistry between Emma Thompson and Kenneth Branagh, it slightly ruined the dark tone the aftermath of the battle had set. In other words, they should have cut some of the scenes out for a better flow of the narrative. Henry V is a good Shakespeare adaptation. I loved the performances by the cast and some of the brilliant set pieces of the film. But as a whole it's just watchable. If you like Shakespeare's plays this is a must see but for anyone else it's hard to recommend. Especially if your English isn't very good.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Henry V
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ShibanPD
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The greatest adaptation of a Shakespearean play to the screen, Henry V, adapted by, directed by, and starring Kenneth Branagh, bridges the gap between faithful reproduction and innovative representation in an extremely exciting, most cinematic way. Branagh has certainly done his homework, and we are the benefactors of his erudition. For the most part, he has reduced Shakespeare's text to those elements which are not only screen-worthy, but the meanings of which ride easily on tone, gesture, and action, so that Shakespeare's poetic, though metaphorically dense language presents little obstacle to the understanding of the modern ear. Remainingand out of place for such a successful transition between mediumsare unnecessary lines delivered by the Chorus (played by a fiery Derek Jacobi), which beg us to pardon the meagerness of the presentation and beseech us to use our imaginations to fill in the resulting holes. Famous lines to those familiar with the stage, but strangely redundant from within the context of a film of such high production value, grandness, and beautywith a visual and aural realization that rises to match the quality of the bard's text. On the side of embellishment, Branagh interweaves lines, characters, and scenes from parts of Henry IV, through clever flashbacks. The purpose of this device is to summon Hal's past relationships with old friends who are now his subjects, and to elucidate the duality of Hal/Henry; for Hal was not always king, and in his younger days, he caroused with commoners, drunkards, liars, and even thieves. The effectiveness of this device varies: the hanging of Bardolph draws additional emotional impact from it, but, in spite of it and several fine, heartfelt performances, the reminiscing after Falstaff's death falls flat, since we, unlike the audience of Shakespeare's time, have not come to know and love this Sir John Falstaff through Parts 1 and 2 of Henry IV and other works. Now the betrayal of Falstaff by Hal, though moderately effective in the use of this same device, is one of the most interesting scenes in the film, as it employs a flash forward within a flashback, in which we hear Hal think what he will eventually say to Falstaff, and Falstaff responds to his disavowal. Hal's transformation into Henry V is really the heart of Shakespeare's story, as it requires him to sever connections to his "wilder days" in order to lead his countrymen in worldly pursuits. Branagh's handling of it is quite remarkable. Branagh's own acting performance as the title character is smart and passionate, commanding and stirring. It does suffer slightly from that same ailment that afflicts other zealous students of Shakespeare: he knows his lines so well that they, at times, lose their spontaneity and/or authenticity. That penetrating knowledge, which detracts slightly from his performance, overcompensates as an asset to his bold, definitive adaptation and assured direction. Additional assets are an unforgettably powerful score by Patrick Doyle and a solid surrounding cast, which includes Paul Scofield (as King Charles VI of France), Brian Blessed, Ian Holm, Judi Dench, Emma Thompson, and a young Christian Bale. Most notable among the supporting players are Robert Stephens as Auncient Pistol and Christopher Ravenscroft, who, as Montjoy, turns a messenger part into a key role through his earnest, telling reactions to both Henry and the French Dauphin.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Here is all the glory, power, drama, suspense, and intrigue the Bard intended in this rousing play.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Frederick Smith
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/3/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    There may be one hundred or so men who are capable of bringing Shakespeare to the screen, but none so talented and capable as Kenneth Branaugh. Here is all the glory, power, drama, suspense, and intrigue the Bard intended in this rousing play. Jacobi is incredible as the Chorus, a device we would call narrator, and builds his role with eloquence and tempered techniques of voice seldom seen in film. Branaugh displays a rare and insightful look at the character of the now wizened king who was so foolish as a boy. The cast, in all, is superb in their understanding of their roles and carry them off with a passion that perhaps only an Englishman can understand. I have seen this film several times, having a copy along with other versions of Shakespearean plays, and by far this is the most exciting, the most accurate, and the most palatable film of its genre. Combine a timeless tale of war and conquest with a cast already world renown and you have this film, a modern testament to the power of Shakespeare. Rated PG-13 for a violent and bloody battle, this film is fit for the high school crowd and, in my humble opinion, should be shown to every English student about to study Shakespeare.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Touch Of The Tyrant
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bkoganbing
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Some years ago I read a history of the 100 Years War and it was by a British author named Desmond Siward who advanced the notion that Henry V was one of the great tyrants in making of English history. Had it not been for his early death that's how he would have gone down in history. Thinking on it, imagine if you will how history might have regarded him had he lived another decade and had been in power for the British occupation of over half of France and had been the man in charge when Joan Of Arc was burned at the stake? When Winston Churchill gave all aid and assistance he could to Laurence Olivier;s Henry V during World War II it was to show the glory of English arms at a high point in their history. Even if it was at the expense of France whom the British were now allies with. Olivier played Henry V in true heroic mold, but in this production of Henry V, Kenneth Branagh gives Henry V a touch of the tyrant as in current historiography. This Henry V was not guided by wartime necessity, but could be closer to the truth. I did like the inclusions of those flashback scenes from Henry IV where we see merry Prince Hal cavorting with his low companions like Sir John Falstaff. Those might have been some invention of Shakespeare, but certainly the man who was Henry V was all business when he was on the throne. This newer Henry V received several Oscar nominations including one for Kenneth Branagh to match the one that Laurence Olivier got over 40 years earlier for Best Actor. It's certainly a different Henry that Branagh gives us. You can hardly see a Prince Hal in this king.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Wonderful Adaptation Of Shakespeare's Play
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    SiliconDesertMan40
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/11/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Henry V is a film based on William Shakespeare's play The Life of Henry the Fifth about the famous English king.Kenneth Branagh stars in the title role,wrote the screenplay and directed the movie.It also features Paul Scofield,Ian Holm,Emma Thompson,Alec McCowen,Judi Dench and Christian Bale. It is frequently compared with the 1944 film of the play directed by and starring Laurence Olivier. The visual style of former is grittier and more realistic than that of the latter. The movie has a narrator with the name Chrous.After the he introduces the play, young king of England Henry V begins an angry dialogue with King Charles of France. The king's son, Dauphin,insults Henry and the argument escalates into war. In flashback, Henry is seen as a young man drinking in a tavern with Falstaff, Bardolph,Nym,Pistol, and Mistress Quickly. Meanwhile, Henry and his captain, Fluellen, assemble an army and invade France. The French greatly outnumber the British troops, yet Henry leads them to victory in the Battle of Agincourt after delivering his famous St. Crispin's Day Speech. Throughout this struggle, Henry also courts Katherine and eventually wins her over. Henry V is definitely an absorbing and entertaining film for it was updated for modern viewers.It was also an energetic,passionate,and wonderfully acted as well.Apart from that,it was a triumphant adaptation of Shakespeare's play and it brought about the playwright's timeless talent and appeal.Overall,it is a wonderful film not only for the fans of Shakespeare but anyone who loves great film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Coach Henry
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    drystyx
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/8/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Henry V, according to Shakesspeare's version of History, is well directed. And well acted. Well done all around. And since Shakespeare is best read instead of seen, it works very well in closed captioning. A liar is a person who says he/she understands the words as they are quickly sent out in these plays. In truth, they cannot be deciphered by the brain at such a pace, unless they are read. Personally, I didn't care for all the dim lighting, but it made for realistic dreary castle settings, if not for distinguishing what is going on. And it works for effect, because like black and white, dim lighting helps to focus on the story and not on all the distractions. What sets this Shakespeare play apart from nearly all other dramas and films is that most films show the warrior soldier as a father figure already, finished with his battle days. Here, we have the soldier hero as a young man, before he becomes the old hero. And it is very engaging. This Henry is a very likable character, and very three dimensional. It's refreshing to see a director treat a heroine as a "trophy", the beauty to be won, and of course it was written that way. Henry becomes like the coach giving the famous gung ho half time speech. However, there is more to him than just talk. We wonder what his battle strategy will be, and we're sure he has one. Indeed, though vastly outnumbered against the French, he does use his archers in a cunning way, with a troops of swords dashing out to the foray to hold the enemy at bay and in artillery range. With their swords at about 100 yards, the archers send their artillery barrage over their heads at about 150 yards, making the French between a rock and a hard place in three ways: 1. The French in front have no healthy reinforcements 2. The French in back must work their way over bodies, or be forced back 3. The French in front get into the artillery barrage if they retreat, so they have only one direction This is the play in which the king goes out among his men incognito, by the way. We really only get a good look at Henry and a couple of others. Many of the characters are well drawn, but fleeting in their appearance.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Where's a muse of fire when you need one?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Xander Seavy (RiffRaffMcKinley)
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/4/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Derek Jacobi's wonderfully proud, winking Chorus and Patrick Doyle's interesting (but barely) score are the sole redeeming features of this early Kenneth Branagh misfire. A gritty (in a BBC sense of the word) take on Shakespeare's mostly tedious historical play, "Henry V" gives far too much power to one man in the worst way that Branagh repeated so often to such bewildering acclaim. He not only directs and, rather pretentiously, "adapts for the screen" the words of the Bard, but also plays the title character. And sadly, he is by far no Olivier. The man has talent, to be sure, but it either wasn't here yet or it had fled temporarily when he took up this triple task. The only "flat, unraised spirit" here is Branagh himself, who essays a monotonous monarch with all the emotional depth of Keanu Reeves after an all-nighter. He even fumbles his one good instinct as a filmmaker: flashing back to "Henry IV" is an excellent way to provide backstory for people who aren't too familiar with the soap opera nature of some of Shakespeare's histories (which is primarily important here for the character of Falstaff), but the technique doesn't mesh with the rest of the picture. And why keep the Chorus? He's a purely theatrical device. He's there to tell us we have to imagine that we're in France or Southampton-- a necessity of the theater, in which all you can see is a stage and what's on it, but somewhat disconcerting in a film because the entire point of a film is to show us someplace we normally wouldn't see. Did he keep the Chorus to make his job, as a director, of sustaining our illusion that much easier? Whatever the motives (and no disrespect to the vibrant Jacobi), it was not the right decision. It's a boring, slow-to-evolve adaptation of a terrible, impossible-to-read play. (I am a fan of ol' Will, but his history plays are some of the most tedious dramas ever to plague the page.) If you're a fan of the kind of epic battle scenes of films as diverse as "Platoon" and "Gladiator," you'll definitely enjoy that aspect of the movie. Action-wise, it has its moments. But after a while, you just want Branagh to stick to doing one thing. Unfortunately, he's too self-indulgent to get that idea into his head.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Definitely one of the greater adaptations off of a Shakespearean play
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jdkraus
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/4/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Kenneth Brannagh's 1989 release of Henry V is definitely one of the greater adaptations off of a Shakespearean play. What really makes this film such a success is the big production that Brannagh had when he filmed this picture. Even though the Chorus reminds the viewer that the movie is just a mere imitation, I felt like I was looking at what it was like during the early 1400s. The costumes look very real, in fact, at the 1990 Academy Awards, the film won an Oscar for Best Costume Design. The production design and sets also add a sense of authenticity to the time period. The lighting in this film is unique, for it is generally low-key, giving both a literal and a figurative sense of darkness. This no doubt helped make the movie feel all the more dramatic and intense. The actors are perfect in their roles, whether it be the insignificant or the larger-than-life characters. One actor worth noting is Brian Blessed as Exeter. His encounter with the French king and the Dauphin is thoroughly amusing to watch. He not only carries the brutish demeanor of man ready to take on the whole French army, but he speaks coolly, delivering his lines carefully and fluently, all the while staring at the French king with terrifying eyes that makes him recoil. Simply brilliant! The real master of this film though is the main star and director Kenneth Brannagh. He does not merely act as King Henry V; he becomes the man. There are many great scenes where he displays his fierceness and determination as King Henry. One that comes to mind is when Henry is given the gift of tennis balls from Francean insult of calling him immature. As he speaks, threatening invasion of France to the Dauphin, there is an enraged confidence, yet restraint in his voice. It is obvious that he is dead serious about his threat, particularly when he refers to the French prince, "his balls have turned to gun-stones". Brannagh did not shout during this scene to strike fear in the Dauphin, for he did not have to. All it takes for Brannagh is one glance to scare a ferocious bear. Brannagh also reveals sheds of brutality and violence within Henry. When he finds out that three of his close associates had betrayed him, in a fit of rage, he grabs one of them and throws him on table. Henry then grabs the man's face, as he demands why he turned traitor. Once again, this explicitly shows that Henry is not a person to be feared or to be messed with. In short, Brannagh does not merely act as King Henry V; he becomes the man. As director, he proves in knowing how to suck a viewer into a film. The choice of shots throughout the film are excellent, whether it be the close ups during the heated debates or the three-minute long tracking shot that follows Brannagh as he carries a dead boy through the aftermath of Agincourt. I consider this shot to be one of the best scenes I have ever seen in cinema. Though Brannagh's film is a Shakespearean adaptation, it stands up as its own. It is perfectly acted and directed. If Shakespeare were alive to see this, he would be thoroughly impressed.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Very well crafted
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    TheLittleSongbird
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/3/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I like Kenneth Branagh's Shakespeare films, and Henry V is one of his better ones. The play is a very good one, and this film does it justice. Visually, it is very beautiful to look at, with interesting camera angles and great scenery and costumes. The music fits each scene very well and doesn't fall into the trap of being too melodramatic. The film like the play has a fine, compelling story that makes you feel all sorts of emotions, and the dialogue is wonderful. Branagh's directorial flair has a lot of vigour to it, and the Battle of Agincourt especially is very evocatively staged. The performances are uniformly good, Branagh is particularly impressive in the title role and the supporting cast are all fine Derek Jacobi coming off best in yet another one of his great performances. Overall, very well crafted. 9/10 Bethany Cox
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    In the script it is written, and on the screen it's pictures - F. Lang
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    clwydjones
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/2/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A Good "Televised" Play (i.e. a British film) For a master class on adapting Shakespeare to cinema you need to watch Akira Kurosawa's seminal "Throne of blood". This film is entertaining, but it's not cinema it's a very long TV drama (if you liked the BBC's Robin Hood series you'll love this). For anyone who's coming to Shakespeare for the first time I'd recommend Olivier's version. It's not a 'complete' version of the play, but it has the wit, subtlety and invention missing in Branagh. Olivier is much truer to the spirit of Shakespeare - it's playful and funny in parts (for example the lovely scene where Catherine is learning English). Most importantly Olivier brings out the beauty of Shakespears words (the spine tingling soliloquy in Henry's nighttime tour of the camp?). Branagh's version is neither a film or a play. It unfortunately the throttling of language for dramatic effect. Drowned in muzak and delivered with holly-pine-wood whispers or "You slag!" shouting. And kicks the crap out of the language with odd action film stresses and punctuations. Making the whole play difficult to listen to and understand. There's nothing playful or subtle about it - it's wall to wall drama - which inevitably gets a bit tedious after a while. The lines seem to be there more for pulling faces than for pleasure. A bit like being server a steak you really wanted to tuck into, but cant as someone's covered it in tomato sauce and half a pound of salt. Although there are some funny bits e.g. Derek Jacobi doing Marty DiBergi "introduction to Spinal Tap" at the start. It's also very 80's (e.g. Branagh's hair cut) - When he's asked if he's Cornishman I half expected him to answer, "No I am from Hampstead" Derek Jacobi (with thespian scarf) on the White Cliff of Dover doing Michael Palin's Ripping Yarns "You know, I think it was G.K. Chesterton, who once said..." (Tomkinson's schooldays) Required watching I imagine for all those poor high school students who are forced to learn Shakespeare... (I award it 1 only to try and introduce some sanity to the overall rating. As an adaptation of Shakespeare - 6.5/10. As a general film - 6/10. as a serious cinematic film - 1/10)
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Powerful and Gritty Adaptation...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Janis Livens
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I'm one of those illiterate hacks who hasn't read a single Shakespeare play till the end. It's because in my country we have our own "bard" and Shakespeare's plays were glanced at best. The film itself was brilliant at times and dull at others. It works as individuals scenes perfectly but fails at being compelling narrative due many scenes that felt pointless to me. The reason why enjoyed the most of Henry V was Kenneth Branagh. His brilliant performance carried the film for me and any scene with him was a joy to watch. It's really hard to comment on the acting. The cast is brilliant from top to bottom, my favorite being Brian "Gordon's Alive!" Blessed and Ian Holm. The direction by Kenneth Branagh is worth mentioning. He clearly made Henry V as an anti-war film and it works perfectly. The aftermath of the battle is very powerful, thanks to the direction and magnificent score. But sadly, it's not without problems. The most glaring problem to me, was the pacing. Nearly every single flashback scene stopped the film to a screeching halt. And then there is the silly ending. While I did enjoy the chemistry between Emma Thompson and Kenneth Branagh, it slightly ruined the dark tone the aftermath of the battle had set. In other words, they should have cut some of the scenes out for a better flow of the narrative. Henry V is a good Shakespeare adaptation. I loved the performances by the cast and some of the brilliant set pieces of the film. But as a whole it's just watchable. If you like Shakespeare's plays this is a must see but for anyone else it's hard to recommend. Especially if your English isn't very good.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Henry V
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ShibanPD
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The greatest adaptation of a Shakespearean play to the screen, Henry V, adapted by, directed by, and starring Kenneth Branagh, bridges the gap between faithful reproduction and innovative representation in an extremely exciting, most cinematic way. Branagh has certainly done his homework, and we are the benefactors of his erudition. For the most part, he has reduced Shakespeare's text to those elements which are not only screen-worthy, but the meanings of which ride easily on tone, gesture, and action, so that Shakespeare's poetic, though metaphorically dense language presents little obstacle to the understanding of the modern ear. Remainingand out of place for such a successful transition between mediumsare unnecessary lines delivered by the Chorus (played by a fiery Derek Jacobi), which beg us to pardon the meagerness of the presentation and beseech us to use our imaginations to fill in the resulting holes. Famous lines to those familiar with the stage, but strangely redundant from within the context of a film of such high production value, grandness, and beautywith a visual and aural realization that rises to match the quality of the bard's text. On the side of embellishment, Branagh interweaves lines, characters, and scenes from parts of Henry IV, through clever flashbacks. The purpose of this device is to summon Hal's past relationships with old friends who are now his subjects, and to elucidate the duality of Hal/Henry; for Hal was not always king, and in his younger days, he caroused with commoners, drunkards, liars, and even thieves. The effectiveness of this device varies: the hanging of Bardolph draws additional emotional impact from it, but, in spite of it and several fine, heartfelt performances, the reminiscing after Falstaff's death falls flat, since we, unlike the audience of Shakespeare's time, have not come to know and love this Sir John Falstaff through Parts 1 and 2 of Henry IV and other works. Now the betrayal of Falstaff by Hal, though moderately effective in the use of this same device, is one of the most interesting scenes in the film, as it employs a flash forward within a flashback, in which we hear Hal think what he will eventually say to Falstaff, and Falstaff responds to his disavowal. Hal's transformation into Henry V is really the heart of Shakespeare's story, as it requires him to sever connections to his "wilder days" in order to lead his countrymen in worldly pursuits. Branagh's handling of it is quite remarkable. Branagh's own acting performance as the title character is smart and passionate, commanding and stirring. It does suffer slightly from that same ailment that afflicts other zealous students of Shakespeare: he knows his lines so well that they, at times, lose their spontaneity and/or authenticity. That penetrating knowledge, which detracts slightly from his performance, overcompensates as an asset to his bold, definitive adaptation and assured direction. Additional assets are an unforgettably powerful score by Patrick Doyle and a solid surrounding cast, which includes Paul Scofield (as King Charles VI of France), Brian Blessed, Ian Holm, Judi Dench, Emma Thompson, and a young Christian Bale. Most notable among the supporting players are Robert Stephens as Auncient Pistol and Christopher Ravenscroft, who, as Montjoy, turns a messenger part into a key role through his earnest, telling reactions to both Henry and the French Dauphin.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Here is all the glory, power, drama, suspense, and intrigue the Bard intended in this rousing play.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Frederick Smith
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/3/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    There may be one hundred or so men who are capable of bringing Shakespeare to the screen, but none so talented and capable as Kenneth Branaugh. Here is all the glory, power, drama, suspense, and intrigue the Bard intended in this rousing play. Jacobi is incredible as the Chorus, a device we would call narrator, and builds his role with eloquence and tempered techniques of voice seldom seen in film. Branaugh displays a rare and insightful look at the character of the now wizened king who was so foolish as a boy. The cast, in all, is superb in their understanding of their roles and carry them off with a passion that perhaps only an Englishman can understand. I have seen this film several times, having a copy along with other versions of Shakespearean plays, and by far this is the most exciting, the most accurate, and the most palatable film of its genre. Combine a timeless tale of war and conquest with a cast already world renown and you have this film, a modern testament to the power of Shakespeare. Rated PG-13 for a violent and bloody battle, this film is fit for the high school crowd and, in my humble opinion, should be shown to every English student about to study Shakespeare.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Touch Of The Tyrant
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bkoganbing
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Some years ago I read a history of the 100 Years War and it was by a British author named Desmond Siward who advanced the notion that Henry V was one of the great tyrants in making of English history. Had it not been for his early death that's how he would have gone down in history. Thinking on it, imagine if you will how history might have regarded him had he lived another decade and had been in power for the British occupation of over half of France and had been the man in charge when Joan Of Arc was burned at the stake? When Winston Churchill gave all aid and assistance he could to Laurence Olivier;s Henry V during World War II it was to show the glory of English arms at a high point in their history. Even if it was at the expense of France whom the British were now allies with. Olivier played Henry V in true heroic mold, but in this production of Henry V, Kenneth Branagh gives Henry V a touch of the tyrant as in current historiography. This Henry V was not guided by wartime necessity, but could be closer to the truth. I did like the inclusions of those flashback scenes from Henry IV where we see merry Prince Hal cavorting with his low companions like Sir John Falstaff. Those might have been some invention of Shakespeare, but certainly the man who was Henry V was all business when he was on the throne. This newer Henry V received several Oscar nominations including one for Kenneth Branagh to match the one that Laurence Olivier got over 40 years earlier for Best Actor. It's certainly a different Henry that Branagh gives us. You can hardly see a Prince Hal in this king.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Wonderful Adaptation Of Shakespeare's Play
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    SiliconDesertMan40
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/11/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Henry V is a film based on William Shakespeare's play The Life of Henry the Fifth about the famous English king.Kenneth Branagh stars in the title role,wrote the screenplay and directed the movie.It also features Paul Scofield,Ian Holm,Emma Thompson,Alec McCowen,Judi Dench and Christian Bale. It is frequently compared with the 1944 film of the play directed by and starring Laurence Olivier. The visual style of former is grittier and more realistic than that of the latter. The movie has a narrator with the name Chrous.After the he introduces the play, young king of England Henry V begins an angry dialogue with King Charles of France. The king's son, Dauphin,insults Henry and the argument escalates into war. In flashback, Henry is seen as a young man drinking in a tavern with Falstaff, Bardolph,Nym,Pistol, and Mistress Quickly. Meanwhile, Henry and his captain, Fluellen, assemble an army and invade France. The French greatly outnumber the British troops, yet Henry leads them to victory in the Battle of Agincourt after delivering his famous St. Crispin's Day Speech. Throughout this struggle, Henry also courts Katherine and eventually wins her over. Henry V is definitely an absorbing and entertaining film for it was updated for modern viewers.It was also an energetic,passionate,and wonderfully acted as well.Apart from that,it was a triumphant adaptation of Shakespeare's play and it brought about the playwright's timeless talent and appeal.Overall,it is a wonderful film not only for the fans of Shakespeare but anyone who loves great film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Coach Henry
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    drystyx
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/8/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Henry V, according to Shakesspeare's version of History, is well directed. And well acted. Well done all around. And since Shakespeare is best read instead of seen, it works very well in closed captioning. A liar is a person who says he/she understands the words as they are quickly sent out in these plays. In truth, they cannot be deciphered by the brain at such a pace, unless they are read. Personally, I didn't care for all the dim lighting, but it made for realistic dreary castle settings, if not for distinguishing what is going on. And it works for effect, because like black and white, dim lighting helps to focus on the story and not on all the distractions. What sets this Shakespeare play apart from nearly all other dramas and films is that most films show the warrior soldier as a father figure already, finished with his battle days. Here, we have the soldier hero as a young man, before he becomes the old hero. And it is very engaging. This Henry is a very likable character, and very three dimensional. It's refreshing to see a director treat a heroine as a "trophy", the beauty to be won, and of course it was written that way. Henry becomes like the coach giving the famous gung ho half time speech. However, there is more to him than just talk. We wonder what his battle strategy will be, and we're sure he has one. Indeed, though vastly outnumbered against the French, he does use his archers in a cunning way, with a troops of swords dashing out to the foray to hold the enemy at bay and in artillery range. With their swords at about 100 yards, the archers send their artillery barrage over their heads at about 150 yards, making the French between a rock and a hard place in three ways: 1. The French in front have no healthy reinforcements 2. The French in back must work their way over bodies, or be forced back 3. The French in front get into the artillery barrage if they retreat, so they have only one direction This is the play in which the king goes out among his men incognito, by the way. We really only get a good look at Henry and a couple of others. Many of the characters are well drawn, but fleeting in their appearance.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Where's a muse of fire when you need one?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Xander Seavy (RiffRaffMcKinley)
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/4/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Derek Jacobi's wonderfully proud, winking Chorus and Patrick Doyle's interesting (but barely) score are the sole redeeming features of this early Kenneth Branagh misfire. A gritty (in a BBC sense of the word) take on Shakespeare's mostly tedious historical play, "Henry V" gives far too much power to one man in the worst way that Branagh repeated so often to such bewildering acclaim. He not only directs and, rather pretentiously, "adapts for the screen" the words of the Bard, but also plays the title character. And sadly, he is by far no Olivier. The man has talent, to be sure, but it either wasn't here yet or it had fled temporarily when he took up this triple task. The only "flat, unraised spirit" here is Branagh himself, who essays a monotonous monarch with all the emotional depth of Keanu Reeves after an all-nighter. He even fumbles his one good instinct as a filmmaker: flashing back to "Henry IV" is an excellent way to provide backstory for people who aren't too familiar with the soap opera nature of some of Shakespeare's histories (which is primarily important here for the character of Falstaff), but the technique doesn't mesh with the rest of the picture. And why keep the Chorus? He's a purely theatrical device. He's there to tell us we have to imagine that we're in France or Southampton-- a necessity of the theater, in which all you can see is a stage and what's on it, but somewhat disconcerting in a film because the entire point of a film is to show us someplace we normally wouldn't see. Did he keep the Chorus to make his job, as a director, of sustaining our illusion that much easier? Whatever the motives (and no disrespect to the vibrant Jacobi), it was not the right decision. It's a boring, slow-to-evolve adaptation of a terrible, impossible-to-read play. (I am a fan of ol' Will, but his history plays are some of the most tedious dramas ever to plague the page.) If you're a fan of the kind of epic battle scenes of films as diverse as "Platoon" and "Gladiator," you'll definitely enjoy that aspect of the movie. Action-wise, it has its moments. But after a while, you just want Branagh to stick to doing one thing. Unfortunately, he's too self-indulgent to get that idea into his head.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Definitely one of the greater adaptations off of a Shakespearean play
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jdkraus
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/4/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Kenneth Brannagh's 1989 release of Henry V is definitely one of the greater adaptations off of a Shakespearean play. What really makes this film such a success is the big production that Brannagh had when he filmed this picture. Even though the Chorus reminds the viewer that the movie is just a mere imitation, I felt like I was looking at what it was like during the early 1400s. The costumes look very real, in fact, at the 1990 Academy Awards, the film won an Oscar for Best Costume Design. The production design and sets also add a sense of authenticity to the time period. The lighting in this film is unique, for it is generally low-key, giving both a literal and a figurative sense of darkness. This no doubt helped make the movie feel all the more dramatic and intense. The actors are perfect in their roles, whether it be the insignificant or the larger-than-life characters. One actor worth noting is Brian Blessed as Exeter. His encounter with the French king and the Dauphin is thoroughly amusing to watch. He not only carries the brutish demeanor of man ready to take on the whole French army, but he speaks coolly, delivering his lines carefully and fluently, all the while staring at the French king with terrifying eyes that makes him recoil. Simply brilliant! The real master of this film though is the main star and director Kenneth Brannagh. He does not merely act as King Henry V; he becomes the man. There are many great scenes where he displays his fierceness and determination as King Henry. One that comes to mind is when Henry is given the gift of tennis balls from Francean insult of calling him immature. As he speaks, threatening invasion of France to the Dauphin, there is an enraged confidence, yet restraint in his voice. It is obvious that he is dead serious about his threat, particularly when he refers to the French prince, "his balls have turned to gun-stones". Brannagh did not shout during this scene to strike fear in the Dauphin, for he did not have to. All it takes for Brannagh is one glance to scare a ferocious bear. Brannagh also reveals sheds of brutality and violence within Henry. When he finds out that three of his close associates had betrayed him, in a fit of rage, he grabs one of them and throws him on table. Henry then grabs the man's face, as he demands why he turned traitor. Once again, this explicitly shows that Henry is not a person to be feared or to be messed with. In short, Brannagh does not merely act as King Henry V; he becomes the man. As director, he proves in knowing how to suck a viewer into a film. The choice of shots throughout the film are excellent, whether it be the close ups during the heated debates or the three-minute long tracking shot that follows Brannagh as he carries a dead boy through the aftermath of Agincourt. I consider this shot to be one of the best scenes I have ever seen in cinema. Though Brannagh's film is a Shakespearean adaptation, it stands up as its own. It is perfectly acted and directed. If Shakespeare were alive to see this, he would be thoroughly impressed.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Very well crafted
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    TheLittleSongbird
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/3/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I like Kenneth Branagh's Shakespeare films, and Henry V is one of his better ones. The play is a very good one, and this film does it justice. Visually, it is very beautiful to look at, with interesting camera angles and great scenery and costumes. The music fits each scene very well and doesn't fall into the trap of being too melodramatic. The film like the play has a fine, compelling story that makes you feel all sorts of emotions, and the dialogue is wonderful. Branagh's directorial flair has a lot of vigour to it, and the Battle of Agincourt especially is very evocatively staged. The performances are uniformly good, Branagh is particularly impressive in the title role and the supporting cast are all fine Derek Jacobi coming off best in yet another one of his great performances. Overall, very well crafted. 9/10 Bethany Cox
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    In the script it is written, and on the screen it's pictures - F. Lang
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    clwydjones
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/2/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A Good "Televised" Play (i.e. a British film) For a master class on adapting Shakespeare to cinema you need to watch Akira Kurosawa's seminal "Throne of blood". This film is entertaining, but it's not cinema it's a very long TV drama (if you liked the BBC's Robin Hood series you'll love this). For anyone who's coming to Shakespeare for the first time I'd recommend Olivier's version. It's not a 'complete' version of the play, but it has the wit, subtlety and invention missing in Branagh. Olivier is much truer to the spirit of Shakespeare - it's playful and funny in parts (for example the lovely scene where Catherine is learning English). Most importantly Olivier brings out the beauty of Shakespears words (the spine tingling soliloquy in Henry's nighttime tour of the camp?). Branagh's version is neither a film or a play. It unfortunately the throttling of language for dramatic effect. Drowned in muzak and delivered with holly-pine-wood whispers or "You slag!" shouting. And kicks the crap out of the language with odd action film stresses and punctuations. Making the whole play difficult to listen to and understand. There's nothing playful or subtle about it - it's wall to wall drama - which inevitably gets a bit tedious after a while. The lines seem to be there more for pulling faces than for pleasure. A bit like being server a steak you really wanted to tuck into, but cant as someone's covered it in tomato sauce and half a pound of salt. Although there are some funny bits e.g. Derek Jacobi doing Marty DiBergi "introduction to Spinal Tap" at the start. It's also very 80's (e.g. Branagh's hair cut) - When he's asked if he's Cornishman I half expected him to answer, "No I am from Hampstead" Derek Jacobi (with thespian scarf) on the White Cliff of Dover doing Michael Palin's Ripping Yarns "You know, I think it was G.K. Chesterton, who once said..." (Tomkinson's schooldays) Required watching I imagine for all those poor high school students who are forced to learn Shakespeare... (I award it 1 only to try and introduce some sanity to the overall rating. As an adaptation of Shakespeare - 6.5/10. As a general film - 6/10. as a serious cinematic film - 1/10)
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Powerful and Gritty Adaptation...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Janis Livens
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I'm one of those illiterate hacks who hasn't read a single Shakespeare play till the end. It's because in my country we have our own "bard" and Shakespeare's plays were glanced at best. The film itself was brilliant at times and dull at others. It works as individuals scenes perfectly but fails at being compelling narrative due many scenes that felt pointless to me. The reason why enjoyed the most of Henry V was Kenneth Branagh. His brilliant performance carried the film for me and any scene with him was a joy to watch. It's really hard to comment on the acting. The cast is brilliant from top to bottom, my favorite being Brian "Gordon's Alive!" Blessed and Ian Holm. The direction by Kenneth Branagh is worth mentioning. He clearly made Henry V as an anti-war film and it works perfectly. The aftermath of the battle is very powerful, thanks to the direction and magnificent score. But sadly, it's not without problems. The most glaring problem to me, was the pacing. Nearly every single flashback scene stopped the film to a screeching halt. And then there is the silly ending. While I did enjoy the chemistry between Emma Thompson and Kenneth Branagh, it slightly ruined the dark tone the aftermath of the battle had set. In other words, they should have cut some of the scenes out for a better flow of the narrative. Henry V is a good Shakespeare adaptation. I loved the performances by the cast and some of the brilliant set pieces of the film. But as a whole it's just watchable. If you like Shakespeare's plays this is a must see but for anyone else it's hard to recommend. Especially if your English isn't very good.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Henry V
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ShibanPD
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The greatest adaptation of a Shakespearean play to the screen, Henry V, adapted by, directed by, and starring Kenneth Branagh, bridges the gap between faithful reproduction and innovative representation in an extremely exciting, most cinematic way. Branagh has certainly done his homework, and we are the benefactors of his erudition. For the most part, he has reduced Shakespeare's text to those elements which are not only screen-worthy, but the meanings of which ride easily on tone, gesture, and action, so that Shakespeare's poetic, though metaphorically dense language presents little obstacle to the understanding of the modern ear. Remainingand out of place for such a successful transition between mediumsare unnecessary lines delivered by the Chorus (played by a fiery Derek Jacobi), which beg us to pardon the meagerness of the presentation and beseech us to use our imaginations to fill in the resulting holes. Famous lines to those familiar with the stage, but strangely redundant from within the context of a film of such high production value, grandness, and beautywith a visual and aural realization that rises to match the quality of the bard's text. On the side of embellishment, Branagh interweaves lines, characters, and scenes from parts of Henry IV, through clever flashbacks. The purpose of this device is to summon Hal's past relationships with old friends who are now his subjects, and to elucidate the duality of Hal/Henry; for Hal was not always king, and in his younger days, he caroused with commoners, drunkards, liars, and even thieves. The effectiveness of this device varies: the hanging of Bardolph draws additional emotional impact from it, but, in spite of it and several fine, heartfelt performances, the reminiscing after Falstaff's death falls flat, since we, unlike the audience of Shakespeare's time, have not come to know and love this Sir John Falstaff through Parts 1 and 2 of Henry IV and other works. Now the betrayal of Falstaff by Hal, though moderately effective in the use of this same device, is one of the most interesting scenes in the film, as it employs a flash forward within a flashback, in which we hear Hal think what he will eventually say to Falstaff, and Falstaff responds to his disavowal. Hal's transformation into Henry V is really the heart of Shakespeare's story, as it requires him to sever connections to his "wilder days" in order to lead his countrymen in worldly pursuits. Branagh's handling of it is quite remarkable. Branagh's own acting performance as the title character is smart and passionate, commanding and stirring. It does suffer slightly from that same ailment that afflicts other zealous students of Shakespeare: he knows his lines so well that they, at times, lose their spontaneity and/or authenticity. That penetrating knowledge, which detracts slightly from his performance, overcompensates as an asset to his bold, definitive adaptation and assured direction. Additional assets are an unforgettably powerful score by Patrick Doyle and a solid surrounding cast, which includes Paul Scofield (as King Charles VI of France), Brian Blessed, Ian Holm, Judi Dench, Emma Thompson, and a young Christian Bale. Most notable among the supporting players are Robert Stephens as Auncient Pistol and Christopher Ravenscroft, who, as Montjoy, turns a messenger part into a key role through his earnest, telling reactions to both Henry and the French Dauphin.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Here is all the glory, power, drama, suspense, and intrigue the Bard intended in this rousing play.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Frederick Smith
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/3/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    There may be one hundred or so men who are capable of bringing Shakespeare to the screen, but none so talented and capable as Kenneth Branaugh. Here is all the glory, power, drama, suspense, and intrigue the Bard intended in this rousing play. Jacobi is incredible as the Chorus, a device we would call narrator, and builds his role with eloquence and tempered techniques of voice seldom seen in film. Branaugh displays a rare and insightful look at the character of the now wizened king who was so foolish as a boy. The cast, in all, is superb in their understanding of their roles and carry them off with a passion that perhaps only an Englishman can understand. I have seen this film several times, having a copy along with other versions of Shakespearean plays, and by far this is the most exciting, the most accurate, and the most palatable film of its genre. Combine a timeless tale of war and conquest with a cast already world renown and you have this film, a modern testament to the power of Shakespeare. Rated PG-13 for a violent and bloody battle, this film is fit for the high school crowd and, in my humble opinion, should be shown to every English student about to study Shakespeare.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Touch Of The Tyrant
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bkoganbing
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Some years ago I read a history of the 100 Years War and it was by a British author named Desmond Siward who advanced the notion that Henry V was one of the great tyrants in making of English history. Had it not been for his early death that's how he would have gone down in history. Thinking on it, imagine if you will how history might have regarded him had he lived another decade and had been in power for the British occupation of over half of France and had been the man in charge when Joan Of Arc was burned at the stake? When Winston Churchill gave all aid and assistance he could to Laurence Olivier;s Henry V during World War II it was to show the glory of English arms at a high point in their history. Even if it was at the expense of France whom the British were now allies with. Olivier played Henry V in true heroic mold, but in this production of Henry V, Kenneth Branagh gives Henry V a touch of the tyrant as in current historiography. This Henry V was not guided by wartime necessity, but could be closer to the truth. I did like the inclusions of those flashback scenes from Henry IV where we see merry Prince Hal cavorting with his low companions like Sir John Falstaff. Those might have been some invention of Shakespeare, but certainly the man who was Henry V was all business when he was on the throne. This newer Henry V received several Oscar nominations including one for Kenneth Branagh to match the one that Laurence Olivier got over 40 years earlier for Best Actor. It's certainly a different Henry that Branagh gives us. You can hardly see a Prince Hal in this king.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Wonderful Adaptation Of Shakespeare's Play
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    SiliconDesertMan40
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/11/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Henry V is a film based on William Shakespeare's play The Life of Henry the Fifth about the famous English king.Kenneth Branagh stars in the title role,wrote the screenplay and directed the movie.It also features Paul Scofield,Ian Holm,Emma Thompson,Alec McCowen,Judi Dench and Christian Bale. It is frequently compared with the 1944 film of the play directed by and starring Laurence Olivier. The visual style of former is grittier and more realistic than that of the latter. The movie has a narrator with the name Chrous.After the he introduces the play, young king of England Henry V begins an angry dialogue with King Charles of France. The king's son, Dauphin,insults Henry and the argument escalates into war. In flashback, Henry is seen as a young man drinking in a tavern with Falstaff, Bardolph,Nym,Pistol, and Mistress Quickly. Meanwhile, Henry and his captain, Fluellen, assemble an army and invade France. The French greatly outnumber the British troops, yet Henry leads them to victory in the Battle of Agincourt after delivering his famous St. Crispin's Day Speech. Throughout this struggle, Henry also courts Katherine and eventually wins her over. Henry V is definitely an absorbing and entertaining film for it was updated for modern viewers.It was also an energetic,passionate,and wonderfully acted as well.Apart from that,it was a triumphant adaptation of Shakespeare's play and it brought about the playwright's timeless talent and appeal.Overall,it is a wonderful film not only for the fans of Shakespeare but anyone who loves great film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Coach Henry
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    drystyx
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/8/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Henry V, according to Shakesspeare's version of History, is well directed. And well acted. Well done all around. And since Shakespeare is best read instead of seen, it works very well in closed captioning. A liar is a person who says he/she understands the words as they are quickly sent out in these plays. In truth, they cannot be deciphered by the brain at such a pace, unless they are read. Personally, I didn't care for all the dim lighting, but it made for realistic dreary castle settings, if not for distinguishing what is going on. And it works for effect, because like black and white, dim lighting helps to focus on the story and not on all the distractions. What sets this Shakespeare play apart from nearly all other dramas and films is that most films show the warrior soldier as a father figure already, finished with his battle days. Here, we have the soldier hero as a young man, before he becomes the old hero. And it is very engaging. This Henry is a very likable character, and very three dimensional. It's refreshing to see a director treat a heroine as a "trophy", the beauty to be won, and of course it was written that way. Henry becomes like the coach giving the famous gung ho half time speech. However, there is more to him than just talk. We wonder what his battle strategy will be, and we're sure he has one. Indeed, though vastly outnumbered against the French, he does use his archers in a cunning way, with a troops of swords dashing out to the foray to hold the enemy at bay and in artillery range. With their swords at about 100 yards, the archers send their artillery barrage over their heads at about 150 yards, making the French between a rock and a hard place in three ways: 1. The French in front have no healthy reinforcements 2. The French in back must work their way over bodies, or be forced back 3. The French in front get into the artillery barrage if they retreat, so they have only one direction This is the play in which the king goes out among his men incognito, by the way. We really only get a good look at Henry and a couple of others. Many of the characters are well drawn, but fleeting in their appearance.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Where's a muse of fire when you need one?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Xander Seavy (RiffRaffMcKinley)
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/4/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Derek Jacobi's wonderfully proud, winking Chorus and Patrick Doyle's interesting (but barely) score are the sole redeeming features of this early Kenneth Branagh misfire. A gritty (in a BBC sense of the word) take on Shakespeare's mostly tedious historical play, "Henry V" gives far too much power to one man in the worst way that Branagh repeated so often to such bewildering acclaim. He not only directs and, rather pretentiously, "adapts for the screen" the words of the Bard, but also plays the title character. And sadly, he is by far no Olivier. The man has talent, to be sure, but it either wasn't here yet or it had fled temporarily when he took up this triple task. The only "flat, unraised spirit" here is Branagh himself, who essays a monotonous monarch with all the emotional depth of Keanu Reeves after an all-nighter. He even fumbles his one good instinct as a filmmaker: flashing back to "Henry IV" is an excellent way to provide backstory for people who aren't too familiar with the soap opera nature of some of Shakespeare's histories (which is primarily important here for the character of Falstaff), but the technique doesn't mesh with the rest of the picture. And why keep the Chorus? He's a purely theatrical device. He's there to tell us we have to imagine that we're in France or Southampton-- a necessity of the theater, in which all you can see is a stage and what's on it, but somewhat disconcerting in a film because the entire point of a film is to show us someplace we normally wouldn't see. Did he keep the Chorus to make his job, as a director, of sustaining our illusion that much easier? Whatever the motives (and no disrespect to the vibrant Jacobi), it was not the right decision. It's a boring, slow-to-evolve adaptation of a terrible, impossible-to-read play. (I am a fan of ol' Will, but his history plays are some of the most tedious dramas ever to plague the page.) If you're a fan of the kind of epic battle scenes of films as diverse as "Platoon" and "Gladiator," you'll definitely enjoy that aspect of the movie. Action-wise, it has its moments. But after a while, you just want Branagh to stick to doing one thing. Unfortunately, he's too self-indulgent to get that idea into his head.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Definitely one of the greater adaptations off of a Shakespearean play
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jdkraus
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/4/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Kenneth Brannagh's 1989 release of Henry V is definitely one of the greater adaptations off of a Shakespearean play. What really makes this film such a success is the big production that Brannagh had when he filmed this picture. Even though the Chorus reminds the viewer that the movie is just a mere imitation, I felt like I was looking at what it was like during the early 1400s. The costumes look very real, in fact, at the 1990 Academy Awards, the film won an Oscar for Best Costume Design. The production design and sets also add a sense of authenticity to the time period. The lighting in this film is unique, for it is generally low-key, giving both a literal and a figurative sense of darkness. This no doubt helped make the movie feel all the more dramatic and intense. The actors are perfect in their roles, whether it be the insignificant or the larger-than-life characters. One actor worth noting is Brian Blessed as Exeter. His encounter with the French king and the Dauphin is thoroughly amusing to watch. He not only carries the brutish demeanor of man ready to take on the whole French army, but he speaks coolly, delivering his lines carefully and fluently, all the while staring at the French king with terrifying eyes that makes him recoil. Simply brilliant! The real master of this film though is the main star and director Kenneth Brannagh. He does not merely act as King Henry V; he becomes the man. There are many great scenes where he displays his fierceness and determination as King Henry. One that comes to mind is when Henry is given the gift of tennis balls from Francean insult of calling him immature. As he speaks, threatening invasion of France to the Dauphin, there is an enraged confidence, yet restraint in his voice. It is obvious that he is dead serious about his threat, particularly when he refers to the French prince, "his balls have turned to gun-stones". Brannagh did not shout during this scene to strike fear in the Dauphin, for he did not have to. All it takes for Brannagh is one glance to scare a ferocious bear. Brannagh also reveals sheds of brutality and violence within Henry. When he finds out that three of his close associates had betrayed him, in a fit of rage, he grabs one of them and throws him on table. Henry then grabs the man's face, as he demands why he turned traitor. Once again, this explicitly shows that Henry is not a person to be feared or to be messed with. In short, Brannagh does not merely act as King Henry V; he becomes the man. As director, he proves in knowing how to suck a viewer into a film. The choice of shots throughout the film are excellent, whether it be the close ups during the heated debates or the three-minute long tracking shot that follows Brannagh as he carries a dead boy through the aftermath of Agincourt. I consider this shot to be one of the best scenes I have ever seen in cinema. Though Brannagh's film is a Shakespearean adaptation, it stands up as its own. It is perfectly acted and directed. If Shakespeare were alive to see this, he would be thoroughly impressed.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Very well crafted
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    TheLittleSongbird
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/3/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I like Kenneth Branagh's Shakespeare films, and Henry V is one of his better ones. The play is a very good one, and this film does it justice. Visually, it is very beautiful to look at, with interesting camera angles and great scenery and costumes. The music fits each scene very well and doesn't fall into the trap of being too melodramatic. The film like the play has a fine, compelling story that makes you feel all sorts of emotions, and the dialogue is wonderful. Branagh's directorial flair has a lot of vigour to it, and the Battle of Agincourt especially is very evocatively staged. The performances are uniformly good, Branagh is particularly impressive in the title role and the supporting cast are all fine Derek Jacobi coming off best in yet another one of his great performances. Overall, very well crafted. 9/10 Bethany Cox
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    In the script it is written, and on the screen it's pictures - F. Lang
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    clwydjones
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/2/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A Good "Televised" Play (i.e. a British film) For a master class on adapting Shakespeare to cinema you need to watch Akira Kurosawa's seminal "Throne of blood". This film is entertaining, but it's not cinema it's a very long TV drama (if you liked the BBC's Robin Hood series you'll love this). For anyone who's coming to Shakespeare for the first time I'd recommend Olivier's version. It's not a 'complete' version of the play, but it has the wit, subtlety and invention missing in Branagh. Olivier is much truer to the spirit of Shakespeare - it's playful and funny in parts (for example the lovely scene where Catherine is learning English). Most importantly Olivier brings out the beauty of Shakespears words (the spine tingling soliloquy in Henry's nighttime tour of the camp?). Branagh's version is neither a film or a play. It unfortunately the throttling of language for dramatic effect. Drowned in muzak and delivered with holly-pine-wood whispers or "You slag!" shouting. And kicks the crap out of the language with odd action film stresses and punctuations. Making the whole play difficult to listen to and understand. There's nothing playful or subtle about it - it's wall to wall drama - which inevitably gets a bit tedious after a while. The lines seem to be there more for pulling faces than for pleasure. A bit like being server a steak you really wanted to tuck into, but cant as someone's covered it in tomato sauce and half a pound of salt. Although there are some funny bits e.g. Derek Jacobi doing Marty DiBergi "introduction to Spinal Tap" at the start. It's also very 80's (e.g. Branagh's hair cut) - When he's asked if he's Cornishman I half expected him to answer, "No I am from Hampstead" Derek Jacobi (with thespian scarf) on the White Cliff of Dover doing Michael Palin's Ripping Yarns "You know, I think it was G.K. Chesterton, who once said..." (Tomkinson's schooldays) Required watching I imagine for all those poor high school students who are forced to learn Shakespeare... (I award it 1 only to try and introduce some sanity to the overall rating. As an adaptation of Shakespeare - 6.5/10. As a general film - 6/10. as a serious cinematic film - 1/10)
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Powerful and Gritty Adaptation...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Janis Livens
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I'm one of those illiterate hacks who hasn't read a single Shakespeare play till the end. It's because in my country we have our own "bard" and Shakespeare's plays were glanced at best. The film itself was brilliant at times and dull at others. It works as individuals scenes perfectly but fails at being compelling narrative due many scenes that felt pointless to me. The reason why enjoyed the most of Henry V was Kenneth Branagh. His brilliant performance carried the film for me and any scene with him was a joy to watch. It's really hard to comment on the acting. The cast is brilliant from top to bottom, my favorite being Brian "Gordon's Alive!" Blessed and Ian Holm. The direction by Kenneth Branagh is worth mentioning. He clearly made Henry V as an anti-war film and it works perfectly. The aftermath of the battle is very powerful, thanks to the direction and magnificent score. But sadly, it's not without problems. The most glaring problem to me, was the pacing. Nearly every single flashback scene stopped the film to a screeching halt. And then there is the silly ending. While I did enjoy the chemistry between Emma Thompson and Kenneth Branagh, it slightly ruined the dark tone the aftermath of the battle had set. In other words, they should have cut some of the scenes out for a better flow of the narrative. Henry V is a good Shakespeare adaptation. I loved the performances by the cast and some of the brilliant set pieces of the film. But as a whole it's just watchable. If you like Shakespeare's plays this is a must see but for anyone else it's hard to recommend. Especially if your English isn't very good.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Henry V
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ShibanPD
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The greatest adaptation of a Shakespearean play to the screen, Henry V, adapted by, directed by, and starring Kenneth Branagh, bridges the gap between faithful reproduction and innovative representation in an extremely exciting, most cinematic way. Branagh has certainly done his homework, and we are the benefactors of his erudition. For the most part, he has reduced Shakespeare's text to those elements which are not only screen-worthy, but the meanings of which ride easily on tone, gesture, and action, so that Shakespeare's poetic, though metaphorically dense language presents little obstacle to the understanding of the modern ear. Remainingand out of place for such a successful transition between mediumsare unnecessary lines delivered by the Chorus (played by a fiery Derek Jacobi), which beg us to pardon the meagerness of the presentation and beseech us to use our imaginations to fill in the resulting holes. Famous lines to those familiar with the stage, but strangely redundant from within the context of a film of such high production value, grandness, and beautywith a visual and aural realization that rises to match the quality of the bard's text. On the side of embellishment, Branagh interweaves lines, characters, and scenes from parts of Henry IV, through clever flashbacks. The purpose of this device is to summon Hal's past relationships with old friends who are now his subjects, and to elucidate the duality of Hal/Henry; for Hal was not always king, and in his younger days, he caroused with commoners, drunkards, liars, and even thieves. The effectiveness of this device varies: the hanging of Bardolph draws additional emotional impact from it, but, in spite of it and several fine, heartfelt performances, the reminiscing after Falstaff's death falls flat, since we, unlike the audience of Shakespeare's time, have not come to know and love this Sir John Falstaff through Parts 1 and 2 of Henry IV and other works. Now the betrayal of Falstaff by Hal, though moderately effective in the use of this same device, is one of the most interesting scenes in the film, as it employs a flash forward within a flashback, in which we hear Hal think what he will eventually say to Falstaff, and Falstaff responds to his disavowal. Hal's transformation into Henry V is really the heart of Shakespeare's story, as it requires him to sever connections to his "wilder days" in order to lead his countrymen in worldly pursuits. Branagh's handling of it is quite remarkable. Branagh's own acting performance as the title character is smart and passionate, commanding and stirring. It does suffer slightly from that same ailment that afflicts other zealous students of Shakespeare: he knows his lines so well that they, at times, lose their spontaneity and/or authenticity. That penetrating knowledge, which detracts slightly from his performance, overcompensates as an asset to his bold, definitive adaptation and assured direction. Additional assets are an unforgettably powerful score by Patrick Doyle and a solid surrounding cast, which includes Paul Scofield (as King Charles VI of France), Brian Blessed, Ian Holm, Judi Dench, Emma Thompson, and a young Christian Bale. Most notable among the supporting players are Robert Stephens as Auncient Pistol and Christopher Ravenscroft, who, as Montjoy, turns a messenger part into a key role through his earnest, telling reactions to both Henry and the French Dauphin.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Here is all the glory, power, drama, suspense, and intrigue the Bard intended in this rousing play.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Frederick Smith
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/3/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    There may be one hundred or so men who are capable of bringing Shakespeare to the screen, but none so talented and capable as Kenneth Branaugh. Here is all the glory, power, drama, suspense, and intrigue the Bard intended in this rousing play. Jacobi is incredible as the Chorus, a device we would call narrator, and builds his role with eloquence and tempered techniques of voice seldom seen in film. Branaugh displays a rare and insightful look at the character of the now wizened king who was so foolish as a boy. The cast, in all, is superb in their understanding of their roles and carry them off with a passion that perhaps only an Englishman can understand. I have seen this film several times, having a copy along with other versions of Shakespearean plays, and by far this is the most exciting, the most accurate, and the most palatable film of its genre. Combine a timeless tale of war and conquest with a cast already world renown and you have this film, a modern testament to the power of Shakespeare. Rated PG-13 for a violent and bloody battle, this film is fit for the high school crowd and, in my humble opinion, should be shown to every English student about to study Shakespeare.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Touch Of The Tyrant
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bkoganbing
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Some years ago I read a history of the 100 Years War and it was by a British author named Desmond Siward who advanced the notion that Henry V was one of the great tyrants in making of English history. Had it not been for his early death that's how he would have gone down in history. Thinking on it, imagine if you will how history might have regarded him had he lived another decade and had been in power for the British occupation of over half of France and had been the man in charge when Joan Of Arc was burned at the stake? When Winston Churchill gave all aid and assistance he could to Laurence Olivier;s Henry V during World War II it was to show the glory of English arms at a high point in their history. Even if it was at the expense of France whom the British were now allies with. Olivier played Henry V in true heroic mold, but in this production of Henry V, Kenneth Branagh gives Henry V a touch of the tyrant as in current historiography. This Henry V was not guided by wartime necessity, but could be closer to the truth. I did like the inclusions of those flashback scenes from Henry IV where we see merry Prince Hal cavorting with his low companions like Sir John Falstaff. Those might have been some invention of Shakespeare, but certainly the man who was Henry V was all business when he was on the throne. This newer Henry V received several Oscar nominations including one for Kenneth Branagh to match the one that Laurence Olivier got over 40 years earlier for Best Actor. It's certainly a different Henry that Branagh gives us. You can hardly see a Prince Hal in this king.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Wonderful Adaptation Of Shakespeare's Play
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    SiliconDesertMan40
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/11/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Henry V is a film based on William Shakespeare's play The Life of Henry the Fifth about the famous English king.Kenneth Branagh stars in the title role,wrote the screenplay and directed the movie.It also features Paul Scofield,Ian Holm,Emma Thompson,Alec McCowen,Judi Dench and Christian Bale. It is frequently compared with the 1944 film of the play directed by and starring Laurence Olivier. The visual style of former is grittier and more realistic than that of the latter. The movie has a narrator with the name Chrous.After the he introduces the play, young king of England Henry V begins an angry dialogue with King Charles of France. The king's son, Dauphin,insults Henry and the argument escalates into war. In flashback, Henry is seen as a young man drinking in a tavern with Falstaff, Bardolph,Nym,Pistol, and Mistress Quickly. Meanwhile, Henry and his captain, Fluellen, assemble an army and invade France. The French greatly outnumber the British troops, yet Henry leads them to victory in the Battle of Agincourt after delivering his famous St. Crispin's Day Speech. Throughout this struggle, Henry also courts Katherine and eventually wins her over. Henry V is definitely an absorbing and entertaining film for it was updated for modern viewers.It was also an energetic,passionate,and wonderfully acted as well.Apart from that,it was a triumphant adaptation of Shakespeare's play and it brought about the playwright's timeless talent and appeal.Overall,it is a wonderful film not only for the fans of Shakespeare but anyone who loves great film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Coach Henry
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    drystyx
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/8/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Henry V, according to Shakesspeare's version of History, is well directed. And well acted. Well done all around. And since Shakespeare is best read instead of seen, it works very well in closed captioning. A liar is a person who says he/she understands the words as they are quickly sent out in these plays. In truth, they cannot be deciphered by the brain at such a pace, unless they are read. Personally, I didn't care for all the dim lighting, but it made for realistic dreary castle settings, if not for distinguishing what is going on. And it works for effect, because like black and white, dim lighting helps to focus on the story and not on all the distractions. What sets this Shakespeare play apart from nearly all other dramas and films is that most films show the warrior soldier as a father figure already, finished with his battle days. Here, we have the soldier hero as a young man, before he becomes the old hero. And it is very engaging. This Henry is a very likable character, and very three dimensional. It's refreshing to see a director treat a heroine as a "trophy", the beauty to be won, and of course it was written that way. Henry becomes like the coach giving the famous gung ho half time speech. However, there is more to him than just talk. We wonder what his battle strategy will be, and we're sure he has one. Indeed, though vastly outnumbered against the French, he does use his archers in a cunning way, with a troops of swords dashing out to the foray to hold the enemy at bay and in artillery range. With their swords at about 100 yards, the archers send their artillery barrage over their heads at about 150 yards, making the French between a rock and a hard place in three ways: 1. The French in front have no healthy reinforcements 2. The French in back must work their way over bodies, or be forced back 3. The French in front get into the artillery barrage if they retreat, so they have only one direction This is the play in which the king goes out among his men incognito, by the way. We really only get a good look at Henry and a couple of others. Many of the characters are well drawn, but fleeting in their appearance.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Where's a muse of fire when you need one?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Xander Seavy (RiffRaffMcKinley)
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/4/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Derek Jacobi's wonderfully proud, winking Chorus and Patrick Doyle's interesting (but barely) score are the sole redeeming features of this early Kenneth Branagh misfire. A gritty (in a BBC sense of the word) take on Shakespeare's mostly tedious historical play, "Henry V" gives far too much power to one man in the worst way that Branagh repeated so often to such bewildering acclaim. He not only directs and, rather pretentiously, "adapts for the screen" the words of the Bard, but also plays the title character. And sadly, he is by far no Olivier. The man has talent, to be sure, but it either wasn't here yet or it had fled temporarily when he took up this triple task. The only "flat, unraised spirit" here is Branagh himself, who essays a monotonous monarch with all the emotional depth of Keanu Reeves after an all-nighter. He even fumbles his one good instinct as a filmmaker: flashing back to "Henry IV" is an excellent way to provide backstory for people who aren't too familiar with the soap opera nature of some of Shakespeare's histories (which is primarily important here for the character of Falstaff), but the technique doesn't mesh with the rest of the picture. And why keep the Chorus? He's a purely theatrical device. He's there to tell us we have to imagine that we're in France or Southampton-- a necessity of the theater, in which all you can see is a stage and what's on it, but somewhat disconcerting in a film because the entire point of a film is to show us someplace we normally wouldn't see. Did he keep the Chorus to make his job, as a director, of sustaining our illusion that much easier? Whatever the motives (and no disrespect to the vibrant Jacobi), it was not the right decision. It's a boring, slow-to-evolve adaptation of a terrible, impossible-to-read play. (I am a fan of ol' Will, but his history plays are some of the most tedious dramas ever to plague the page.) If you're a fan of the kind of epic battle scenes of films as diverse as "Platoon" and "Gladiator," you'll definitely enjoy that aspect of the movie. Action-wise, it has its moments. But after a while, you just want Branagh to stick to doing one thing. Unfortunately, he's too self-indulgent to get that idea into his head.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Definitely one of the greater adaptations off of a Shakespearean play
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jdkraus
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/4/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Kenneth Brannagh's 1989 release of Henry V is definitely one of the greater adaptations off of a Shakespearean play. What really makes this film such a success is the big production that Brannagh had when he filmed this picture. Even though the Chorus reminds the viewer that the movie is just a mere imitation, I felt like I was looking at what it was like during the early 1400s. The costumes look very real, in fact, at the 1990 Academy Awards, the film won an Oscar for Best Costume Design. The production design and sets also add a sense of authenticity to the time period. The lighting in this film is unique, for it is generally low-key, giving both a literal and a figurative sense of darkness. This no doubt helped make the movie feel all the more dramatic and intense. The actors are perfect in their roles, whether it be the insignificant or the larger-than-life characters. One actor worth noting is Brian Blessed as Exeter. His encounter with the French king and the Dauphin is thoroughly amusing to watch. He not only carries the brutish demeanor of man ready to take on the whole French army, but he speaks coolly, delivering his lines carefully and fluently, all the while staring at the French king with terrifying eyes that makes him recoil. Simply brilliant! The real master of this film though is the main star and director Kenneth Brannagh. He does not merely act as King Henry V; he becomes the man. There are many great scenes where he displays his fierceness and determination as King Henry. One that comes to mind is when Henry is given the gift of tennis balls from Francean insult of calling him immature. As he speaks, threatening invasion of France to the Dauphin, there is an enraged confidence, yet restraint in his voice. It is obvious that he is dead serious about his threat, particularly when he refers to the French prince, "his balls have turned to gun-stones". Brannagh did not shout during this scene to strike fear in the Dauphin, for he did not have to. All it takes for Brannagh is one glance to scare a ferocious bear. Brannagh also reveals sheds of brutality and violence within Henry. When he finds out that three of his close associates had betrayed him, in a fit of rage, he grabs one of them and throws him on table. Henry then grabs the man's face, as he demands why he turned traitor. Once again, this explicitly shows that Henry is not a person to be feared or to be messed with. In short, Brannagh does not merely act as King Henry V; he becomes the man. As director, he proves in knowing how to suck a viewer into a film. The choice of shots throughout the film are excellent, whether it be the close ups during the heated debates or the three-minute long tracking shot that follows Brannagh as he carries a dead boy through the aftermath of Agincourt. I consider this shot to be one of the best scenes I have ever seen in cinema. Though Brannagh's film is a Shakespearean adaptation, it stands up as its own. It is perfectly acted and directed. If Shakespeare were alive to see this, he would be thoroughly impressed.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Very well crafted
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    TheLittleSongbird
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/3/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I like Kenneth Branagh's Shakespeare films, and Henry V is one of his better ones. The play is a very good one, and this film does it justice. Visually, it is very beautiful to look at, with interesting camera angles and great scenery and costumes. The music fits each scene very well and doesn't fall into the trap of being too melodramatic. The film like the play has a fine, compelling story that makes you feel all sorts of emotions, and the dialogue is wonderful. Branagh's directorial flair has a lot of vigour to it, and the Battle of Agincourt especially is very evocatively staged. The performances are uniformly good, Branagh is particularly impressive in the title role and the supporting cast are all fine Derek Jacobi coming off best in yet another one of his great performances. Overall, very well crafted. 9/10 Bethany Cox
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    In the script it is written, and on the screen it's pictures - F. Lang
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    clwydjones
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/2/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A Good "Televised" Play (i.e. a British film) For a master class on adapting Shakespeare to cinema you need to watch Akira Kurosawa's seminal "Throne of blood". This film is entertaining, but it's not cinema it's a very long TV drama (if you liked the BBC's Robin Hood series you'll love this). For anyone who's coming to Shakespeare for the first time I'd recommend Olivier's version. It's not a 'complete' version of the play, but it has the wit, subtlety and invention missing in Branagh. Olivier is much truer to the spirit of Shakespeare - it's playful and funny in parts (for example the lovely scene where Catherine is learning English). Most importantly Olivier brings out the beauty of Shakespears words (the spine tingling soliloquy in Henry's nighttime tour of the camp?). Branagh's version is neither a film or a play. It unfortunately the throttling of language for dramatic effect. Drowned in muzak and delivered with holly-pine-wood whispers or "You slag!" shouting. And kicks the crap out of the language with odd action film stresses and punctuations. Making the whole play difficult to listen to and understand. There's nothing playful or subtle about it - it's wall to wall drama - which inevitably gets a bit tedious after a while. The lines seem to be there more for pulling faces than for pleasure. A bit like being server a steak you really wanted to tuck into, but cant as someone's covered it in tomato sauce and half a pound of salt. Although there are some funny bits e.g. Derek Jacobi doing Marty DiBergi "introduction to Spinal Tap" at the start. It's also very 80's (e.g. Branagh's hair cut) - When he's asked if he's Cornishman I half expected him to answer, "No I am from Hampstead" Derek Jacobi (with thespian scarf) on the White Cliff of Dover doing Michael Palin's Ripping Yarns "You know, I think it was G.K. Chesterton, who once said..." (Tomkinson's schooldays) Required watching I imagine for all those poor high school students who are forced to learn Shakespeare... (I award it 1 only to try and introduce some sanity to the overall rating. As an adaptation of Shakespeare - 6.5/10. As a general film - 6/10. as a serious cinematic film - 1/10)
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Powerful and Gritty Adaptation...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Janis Livens
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I'm one of those illiterate hacks who hasn't read a single Shakespeare play till the end. It's because in my country we have our own "bard" and Shakespeare's plays were glanced at best. The film itself was brilliant at times and dull at others. It works as individuals scenes perfectly but fails at being compelling narrative due many scenes that felt pointless to me. The reason why enjoyed the most of Henry V was Kenneth Branagh. His brilliant performance carried the film for me and any scene with him was a joy to watch. It's really hard to comment on the acting. The cast is brilliant from top to bottom, my favorite being Brian "Gordon's Alive!" Blessed and Ian Holm. The direction by Kenneth Branagh is worth mentioning. He clearly made Henry V as an anti-war film and it works perfectly. The aftermath of the battle is very powerful, thanks to the direction and magnificent score. But sadly, it's not without problems. The most glaring problem to me, was the pacing. Nearly every single flashback scene stopped the film to a screeching halt. And then there is the silly ending. While I did enjoy the chemistry between Emma Thompson and Kenneth Branagh, it slightly ruined the dark tone the aftermath of the battle had set. In other words, they should have cut some of the scenes out for a better flow of the narrative. Henry V is a good Shakespeare adaptation. I loved the performances by the cast and some of the brilliant set pieces of the film. But as a whole it's just watchable. If you like Shakespeare's plays this is a must see but for anyone else it's hard to recommend. Especially if your English isn't very good.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Henry V
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ShibanPD
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The greatest adaptation of a Shakespearean play to the screen, Henry V, adapted by, directed by, and starring Kenneth Branagh, bridges the gap between faithful reproduction and innovative representation in an extremely exciting, most cinematic way. Branagh has certainly done his homework, and we are the benefactors of his erudition. For the most part, he has reduced Shakespeare's text to those elements which are not only screen-worthy, but the meanings of which ride easily on tone, gesture, and action, so that Shakespeare's poetic, though metaphorically dense language presents little obstacle to the understanding of the modern ear. Remainingand out of place for such a successful transition between mediumsare unnecessary lines delivered by the Chorus (played by a fiery Derek Jacobi), which beg us to pardon the meagerness of the presentation and beseech us to use our imaginations to fill in the resulting holes. Famous lines to those familiar with the stage, but strangely redundant from within the context of a film of such high production value, grandness, and beautywith a visual and aural realization that rises to match the quality of the bard's text. On the side of embellishment, Branagh interweaves lines, characters, and scenes from parts of Henry IV, through clever flashbacks. The purpose of this device is to summon Hal's past relationships with old friends who are now his subjects, and to elucidate the duality of Hal/Henry; for Hal was not always king, and in his younger days, he caroused with commoners, drunkards, liars, and even thieves. The effectiveness of this device varies: the hanging of Bardolph draws additional emotional impact from it, but, in spite of it and several fine, heartfelt performances, the reminiscing after Falstaff's death falls flat, since we, unlike the audience of Shakespeare's time, have not come to know and love this Sir John Falstaff through Parts 1 and 2 of Henry IV and other works. Now the betrayal of Falstaff by Hal, though moderately effective in the use of this same device, is one of the most interesting scenes in the film, as it employs a flash forward within a flashback, in which we hear Hal think what he will eventually say to Falstaff, and Falstaff responds to his disavowal. Hal's transformation into Henry V is really the heart of Shakespeare's story, as it requires him to sever connections to his "wilder days" in order to lead his countrymen in worldly pursuits. Branagh's handling of it is quite remarkable. Branagh's own acting performance as the title character is smart and passionate, commanding and stirring. It does suffer slightly from that same ailment that afflicts other zealous students of Shakespeare: he knows his lines so well that they, at times, lose their spontaneity and/or authenticity. That penetrating knowledge, which detracts slightly from his performance, overcompensates as an asset to his bold, definitive adaptation and assured direction. Additional assets are an unforgettably powerful score by Patrick Doyle and a solid surrounding cast, which includes Paul Scofield (as King Charles VI of France), Brian Blessed, Ian Holm, Judi Dench, Emma Thompson, and a young Christian Bale. Most notable among the supporting players are Robert Stephens as Auncient Pistol and Christopher Ravenscroft, who, as Montjoy, turns a messenger part into a key role through his earnest, telling reactions to both Henry and the French Dauphin.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Here is all the glory, power, drama, suspense, and intrigue the Bard intended in this rousing play.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Frederick Smith
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/3/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    There may be one hundred or so men who are capable of bringing Shakespeare to the screen, but none so talented and capable as Kenneth Branaugh. Here is all the glory, power, drama, suspense, and intrigue the Bard intended in this rousing play. Jacobi is incredible as the Chorus, a device we would call narrator, and builds his role with eloquence and tempered techniques of voice seldom seen in film. Branaugh displays a rare and insightful look at the character of the now wizened king who was so foolish as a boy. The cast, in all, is superb in their understanding of their roles and carry them off with a passion that perhaps only an Englishman can understand. I have seen this film several times, having a copy along with other versions of Shakespearean plays, and by far this is the most exciting, the most accurate, and the most palatable film of its genre. Combine a timeless tale of war and conquest with a cast already world renown and you have this film, a modern testament to the power of Shakespeare. Rated PG-13 for a violent and bloody battle, this film is fit for the high school crowd and, in my humble opinion, should be shown to every English student about to study Shakespeare.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Touch Of The Tyrant
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bkoganbing
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Some years ago I read a history of the 100 Years War and it was by a British author named Desmond Siward who advanced the notion that Henry V was one of the great tyrants in making of English history. Had it not been for his early death that's how he would have gone down in history. Thinking on it, imagine if you will how history might have regarded him had he lived another decade and had been in power for the British occupation of over half of France and had been the man in charge when Joan Of Arc was burned at the stake? When Winston Churchill gave all aid and assistance he could to Laurence Olivier;s Henry V during World War II it was to show the glory of English arms at a high point in their history. Even if it was at the expense of France whom the British were now allies with. Olivier played Henry V in true heroic mold, but in this production of Henry V, Kenneth Branagh gives Henry V a touch of the tyrant as in current historiography. This Henry V was not guided by wartime necessity, but could be closer to the truth. I did like the inclusions of those flashback scenes from Henry IV where we see merry Prince Hal cavorting with his low companions like Sir John Falstaff. Those might have been some invention of Shakespeare, but certainly the man who was Henry V was all business when he was on the throne. This newer Henry V received several Oscar nominations including one for Kenneth Branagh to match the one that Laurence Olivier got over 40 years earlier for Best Actor. It's certainly a different Henry that Branagh gives us. You can hardly see a Prince Hal in this king.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Wonderful Adaptation Of Shakespeare's Play
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    SiliconDesertMan40
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/11/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Henry V is a film based on William Shakespeare's play The Life of Henry the Fifth about the famous English king.Kenneth Branagh stars in the title role,wrote the screenplay and directed the movie.It also features Paul Scofield,Ian Holm,Emma Thompson,Alec McCowen,Judi Dench and Christian Bale. It is frequently compared with the 1944 film of the play directed by and starring Laurence Olivier. The visual style of former is grittier and more realistic than that of the latter. The movie has a narrator with the name Chrous.After the he introduces the play, young king of England Henry V begins an angry dialogue with King Charles of France. The king's son, Dauphin,insults Henry and the argument escalates into war. In flashback, Henry is seen as a young man drinking in a tavern with Falstaff, Bardolph,Nym,Pistol, and Mistress Quickly. Meanwhile, Henry and his captain, Fluellen, assemble an army and invade France. The French greatly outnumber the British troops, yet Henry leads them to victory in the Battle of Agincourt after delivering his famous St. Crispin's Day Speech. Throughout this struggle, Henry also courts Katherine and eventually wins her over. Henry V is definitely an absorbing and entertaining film for it was updated for modern viewers.It was also an energetic,passionate,and wonderfully acted as well.Apart from that,it was a triumphant adaptation of Shakespeare's play and it brought about the playwright's timeless talent and appeal.Overall,it is a wonderful film not only for the fans of Shakespeare but anyone who loves great film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Coach Henry
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    drystyx
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/8/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Henry V, according to Shakesspeare's version of History, is well directed. And well acted. Well done all around. And since Shakespeare is best read instead of seen, it works very well in closed captioning. A liar is a person who says he/she understands the words as they are quickly sent out in these plays. In truth, they cannot be deciphered by the brain at such a pace, unless they are read. Personally, I didn't care for all the dim lighting, but it made for realistic dreary castle settings, if not for distinguishing what is going on. And it works for effect, because like black and white, dim lighting helps to focus on the story and not on all the distractions. What sets this Shakespeare play apart from nearly all other dramas and films is that most films show the warrior soldier as a father figure already, finished with his battle days. Here, we have the soldier hero as a young man, before he becomes the old hero. And it is very engaging. This Henry is a very likable character, and very three dimensional. It's refreshing to see a director treat a heroine as a "trophy", the beauty to be won, and of course it was written that way. Henry becomes like the coach giving the famous gung ho half time speech. However, there is more to him than just talk. We wonder what his battle strategy will be, and we're sure he has one. Indeed, though vastly outnumbered against the French, he does use his archers in a cunning way, with a troops of swords dashing out to the foray to hold the enemy at bay and in artillery range. With their swords at about 100 yards, the archers send their artillery barrage over their heads at about 150 yards, making the French between a rock and a hard place in three ways: 1. The French in front have no healthy reinforcements 2. The French in back must work their way over bodies, or be forced back 3. The French in front get into the artillery barrage if they retreat, so they have only one direction This is the play in which the king goes out among his men incognito, by the way. We really only get a good look at Henry and a couple of others. Many of the characters are well drawn, but fleeting in their appearance.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Where's a muse of fire when you need one?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Xander Seavy (RiffRaffMcKinley)
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/4/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Derek Jacobi's wonderfully proud, winking Chorus and Patrick Doyle's interesting (but barely) score are the sole redeeming features of this early Kenneth Branagh misfire. A gritty (in a BBC sense of the word) take on Shakespeare's mostly tedious historical play, "Henry V" gives far too much power to one man in the worst way that Branagh repeated so often to such bewildering acclaim. He not only directs and, rather pretentiously, "adapts for the screen" the words of the Bard, but also plays the title character. And sadly, he is by far no Olivier. The man has talent, to be sure, but it either wasn't here yet or it had fled temporarily when he took up this triple task. The only "flat, unraised spirit" here is Branagh himself, who essays a monotonous monarch with all the emotional depth of Keanu Reeves after an all-nighter. He even fumbles his one good instinct as a filmmaker: flashing back to "Henry IV" is an excellent way to provide backstory for people who aren't too familiar with the soap opera nature of some of Shakespeare's histories (which is primarily important here for the character of Falstaff), but the technique doesn't mesh with the rest of the picture. And why keep the Chorus? He's a purely theatrical device. He's there to tell us we have to imagine that we're in France or Southampton-- a necessity of the theater, in which all you can see is a stage and what's on it, but somewhat disconcerting in a film because the entire point of a film is to show us someplace we normally wouldn't see. Did he keep the Chorus to make his job, as a director, of sustaining our illusion that much easier? Whatever the motives (and no disrespect to the vibrant Jacobi), it was not the right decision. It's a boring, slow-to-evolve adaptation of a terrible, impossible-to-read play. (I am a fan of ol' Will, but his history plays are some of the most tedious dramas ever to plague the page.) If you're a fan of the kind of epic battle scenes of films as diverse as "Platoon" and "Gladiator," you'll definitely enjoy that aspect of the movie. Action-wise, it has its moments. But after a while, you just want Branagh to stick to doing one thing. Unfortunately, he's too self-indulgent to get that idea into his head.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Definitely one of the greater adaptations off of a Shakespearean play
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jdkraus
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/4/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Kenneth Brannagh's 1989 release of Henry V is definitely one of the greater adaptations off of a Shakespearean play. What really makes this film such a success is the big production that Brannagh had when he filmed this picture. Even though the Chorus reminds the viewer that the movie is just a mere imitation, I felt like I was looking at what it was like during the early 1400s. The costumes look very real, in fact, at the 1990 Academy Awards, the film won an Oscar for Best Costume Design. The production design and sets also add a sense of authenticity to the time period. The lighting in this film is unique, for it is generally low-key, giving both a literal and a figurative sense of darkness. This no doubt helped make the movie feel all the more dramatic and intense. The actors are perfect in their roles, whether it be the insignificant or the larger-than-life characters. One actor worth noting is Brian Blessed as Exeter. His encounter with the French king and the Dauphin is thoroughly amusing to watch. He not only carries the brutish demeanor of man ready to take on the whole French army, but he speaks coolly, delivering his lines carefully and fluently, all the while staring at the French king with terrifying eyes that makes him recoil. Simply brilliant! The real master of this film though is the main star and director Kenneth Brannagh. He does not merely act as King Henry V; he becomes the man. There are many great scenes where he displays his fierceness and determination as King Henry. One that comes to mind is when Henry is given the gift of tennis balls from Francean insult of calling him immature. As he speaks, threatening invasion of France to the Dauphin, there is an enraged confidence, yet restraint in his voice. It is obvious that he is dead serious about his threat, particularly when he refers to the French prince, "his balls have turned to gun-stones". Brannagh did not shout during this scene to strike fear in the Dauphin, for he did not have to. All it takes for Brannagh is one glance to scare a ferocious bear. Brannagh also reveals sheds of brutality and violence within Henry. When he finds out that three of his close associates had betrayed him, in a fit of rage, he grabs one of them and throws him on table. Henry then grabs the man's face, as he demands why he turned traitor. Once again, this explicitly shows that Henry is not a person to be feared or to be messed with. In short, Brannagh does not merely act as King Henry V; he becomes the man. As director, he proves in knowing how to suck a viewer into a film. The choice of shots throughout the film are excellent, whether it be the close ups during the heated debates or the three-minute long tracking shot that follows Brannagh as he carries a dead boy through the aftermath of Agincourt. I consider this shot to be one of the best scenes I have ever seen in cinema. Though Brannagh's film is a Shakespearean adaptation, it stands up as its own. It is perfectly acted and directed. If Shakespeare were alive to see this, he would be thoroughly impressed.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Very well crafted
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    TheLittleSongbird
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/3/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I like Kenneth Branagh's Shakespeare films, and Henry V is one of his better ones. The play is a very good one, and this film does it justice. Visually, it is very beautiful to look at, with interesting camera angles and great scenery and costumes. The music fits each scene very well and doesn't fall into the trap of being too melodramatic. The film like the play has a fine, compelling story that makes you feel all sorts of emotions, and the dialogue is wonderful. Branagh's directorial flair has a lot of vigour to it, and the Battle of Agincourt especially is very evocatively staged. The performances are uniformly good, Branagh is particularly impressive in the title role and the supporting cast are all fine Derek Jacobi coming off best in yet another one of his great performances. Overall, very well crafted. 9/10 Bethany Cox
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    In the script it is written, and on the screen it's pictures - F. Lang
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    clwydjones
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/2/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A Good "Televised" Play (i.e. a British film) For a master class on adapting Shakespeare to cinema you need to watch Akira Kurosawa's seminal "Throne of blood". This film is entertaining, but it's not cinema it's a very long TV drama (if you liked the BBC's Robin Hood series you'll love this). For anyone who's coming to Shakespeare for the first time I'd recommend Olivier's version. It's not a 'complete' version of the play, but it has the wit, subtlety and invention missing in Branagh. Olivier is much truer to the spirit of Shakespeare - it's playful and funny in parts (for example the lovely scene where Catherine is learning English). Most importantly Olivier brings out the beauty of Shakespears words (the spine tingling soliloquy in Henry's nighttime tour of the camp?). Branagh's version is neither a film or a play. It unfortunately the throttling of language for dramatic effect. Drowned in muzak and delivered with holly-pine-wood whispers or "You slag!" shouting. And kicks the crap out of the language with odd action film stresses and punctuations. Making the whole play difficult to listen to and understand. There's nothing playful or subtle about it - it's wall to wall drama - which inevitably gets a bit tedious after a while. The lines seem to be there more for pulling faces than for pleasure. A bit like being server a steak you really wanted to tuck into, but cant as someone's covered it in tomato sauce and half a pound of salt. Although there are some funny bits e.g. Derek Jacobi doing Marty DiBergi "introduction to Spinal Tap" at the start. It's also very 80's (e.g. Branagh's hair cut) - When he's asked if he's Cornishman I half expected him to answer, "No I am from Hampstead" Derek Jacobi (with thespian scarf) on the White Cliff of Dover doing Michael Palin's Ripping Yarns "You know, I think it was G.K. Chesterton, who once said..." (Tomkinson's schooldays) Required watching I imagine for all those poor high school students who are forced to learn Shakespeare... (I award it 1 only to try and introduce some sanity to the overall rating. As an adaptation of Shakespeare - 6.5/10. As a general film - 6/10. as a serious cinematic film - 1/10)
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Powerful and Gritty Adaptation...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Janis Livens
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I'm one of those illiterate hacks who hasn't read a single Shakespeare play till the end. It's because in my country we have our own "bard" and Shakespeare's plays were glanced at best. The film itself was brilliant at times and dull at others. It works as individuals scenes perfectly but fails at being compelling narrative due many scenes that felt pointless to me. The reason why enjoyed the most of Henry V was Kenneth Branagh. His brilliant performance carried the film for me and any scene with him was a joy to watch. It's really hard to comment on the acting. The cast is brilliant from top to bottom, my favorite being Brian "Gordon's Alive!" Blessed and Ian Holm. The direction by Kenneth Branagh is worth mentioning. He clearly made Henry V as an anti-war film and it works perfectly. The aftermath of the battle is very powerful, thanks to the direction and magnificent score. But sadly, it's not without problems. The most glaring problem to me, was the pacing. Nearly every single flashback scene stopped the film to a screeching halt. And then there is the silly ending. While I did enjoy the chemistry between Emma Thompson and Kenneth Branagh, it slightly ruined the dark tone the aftermath of the battle had set. In other words, they should have cut some of the scenes out for a better flow of the narrative. Henry V is a good Shakespeare adaptation. I loved the performances by the cast and some of the brilliant set pieces of the film. But as a whole it's just watchable. If you like Shakespeare's plays this is a must see but for anyone else it's hard to recommend. Especially if your English isn't very good.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Henry V
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ShibanPD
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The greatest adaptation of a Shakespearean play to the screen, Henry V, adapted by, directed by, and starring Kenneth Branagh, bridges the gap between faithful reproduction and innovative representation in an extremely exciting, most cinematic way. Branagh has certainly done his homework, and we are the benefactors of his erudition. For the most part, he has reduced Shakespeare's text to those elements which are not only screen-worthy, but the meanings of which ride easily on tone, gesture, and action, so that Shakespeare's poetic, though metaphorically dense language presents little obstacle to the understanding of the modern ear. Remainingand out of place for such a successful transition between mediumsare unnecessary lines delivered by the Chorus (played by a fiery Derek Jacobi), which beg us to pardon the meagerness of the presentation and beseech us to use our imaginations to fill in the resulting holes. Famous lines to those familiar with the stage, but strangely redundant from within the context of a film of such high production value, grandness, and beautywith a visual and aural realization that rises to match the quality of the bard's text. On the side of embellishment, Branagh interweaves lines, characters, and scenes from parts of Henry IV, through clever flashbacks. The purpose of this device is to summon Hal's past relationships with old friends who are now his subjects, and to elucidate the duality of Hal/Henry; for Hal was not always king, and in his younger days, he caroused with commoners, drunkards, liars, and even thieves. The effectiveness of this device varies: the hanging of Bardolph draws additional emotional impact from it, but, in spite of it and several fine, heartfelt performances, the reminiscing after Falstaff's death falls flat, since we, unlike the audience of Shakespeare's time, have not come to know and love this Sir John Falstaff through Parts 1 and 2 of Henry IV and other works. Now the betrayal of Falstaff by Hal, though moderately effective in the use of this same device, is one of the most interesting scenes in the film, as it employs a flash forward within a flashback, in which we hear Hal think what he will eventually say to Falstaff, and Falstaff responds to his disavowal. Hal's transformation into Henry V is really the heart of Shakespeare's story, as it requires him to sever connections to his "wilder days" in order to lead his countrymen in worldly pursuits. Branagh's handling of it is quite remarkable. Branagh's own acting performance as the title character is smart and passionate, commanding and stirring. It does suffer slightly from that same ailment that afflicts other zealous students of Shakespeare: he knows his lines so well that they, at times, lose their spontaneity and/or authenticity. That penetrating knowledge, which detracts slightly from his performance, overcompensates as an asset to his bold, definitive adaptation and assured direction. Additional assets are an unforgettably powerful score by Patrick Doyle and a solid surrounding cast, which includes Paul Scofield (as King Charles VI of France), Brian Blessed, Ian Holm, Judi Dench, Emma Thompson, and a young Christian Bale. Most notable among the supporting players are Robert Stephens as Auncient Pistol and Christopher Ravenscroft, who, as Montjoy, turns a messenger part into a key role through his earnest, telling reactions to both Henry and the French Dauphin.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Here is all the glory, power, drama, suspense, and intrigue the Bard intended in this rousing play.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Frederick Smith
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/3/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    There may be one hundred or so men who are capable of bringing Shakespeare to the screen, but none so talented and capable as Kenneth Branaugh. Here is all the glory, power, drama, suspense, and intrigue the Bard intended in this rousing play. Jacobi is incredible as the Chorus, a device we would call narrator, and builds his role with eloquence and tempered techniques of voice seldom seen in film. Branaugh displays a rare and insightful look at the character of the now wizened king who was so foolish as a boy. The cast, in all, is superb in their understanding of their roles and carry them off with a passion that perhaps only an Englishman can understand. I have seen this film several times, having a copy along with other versions of Shakespearean plays, and by far this is the most exciting, the most accurate, and the most palatable film of its genre. Combine a timeless tale of war and conquest with a cast already world renown and you have this film, a modern testament to the power of Shakespeare. Rated PG-13 for a violent and bloody battle, this film is fit for the high school crowd and, in my humble opinion, should be shown to every English student about to study Shakespeare.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Touch Of The Tyrant
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bkoganbing
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Some years ago I read a history of the 100 Years War and it was by a British author named Desmond Siward who advanced the notion that Henry V was one of the great tyrants in making of English history. Had it not been for his early death that's how he would have gone down in history. Thinking on it, imagine if you will how history might have regarded him had he lived another decade and had been in power for the British occupation of over half of France and had been the man in charge when Joan Of Arc was burned at the stake? When Winston Churchill gave all aid and assistance he could to Laurence Olivier;s Henry V during World War II it was to show the glory of English arms at a high point in their history. Even if it was at the expense of France whom the British were now allies with. Olivier played Henry V in true heroic mold, but in this production of Henry V, Kenneth Branagh gives Henry V a touch of the tyrant as in current historiography. This Henry V was not guided by wartime necessity, but could be closer to the truth. I did like the inclusions of those flashback scenes from Henry IV where we see merry Prince Hal cavorting with his low companions like Sir John Falstaff. Those might have been some invention of Shakespeare, but certainly the man who was Henry V was all business when he was on the throne. This newer Henry V received several Oscar nominations including one for Kenneth Branagh to match the one that Laurence Olivier got over 40 years earlier for Best Actor. It's certainly a different Henry that Branagh gives us. You can hardly see a Prince Hal in this king.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Wonderful Adaptation Of Shakespeare's Play
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    SiliconDesertMan40
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/11/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Henry V is a film based on William Shakespeare's play The Life of Henry the Fifth about the famous English king.Kenneth Branagh stars in the title role,wrote the screenplay and directed the movie.It also features Paul Scofield,Ian Holm,Emma Thompson,Alec McCowen,Judi Dench and Christian Bale. It is frequently compared with the 1944 film of the play directed by and starring Laurence Olivier. The visual style of former is grittier and more realistic than that of the latter. The movie has a narrator with the name Chrous.After the he introduces the play, young king of England Henry V begins an angry dialogue with King Charles of France. The king's son, Dauphin,insults Henry and the argument escalates into war. In flashback, Henry is seen as a young man drinking in a tavern with Falstaff, Bardolph,Nym,Pistol, and Mistress Quickly. Meanwhile, Henry and his captain, Fluellen, assemble an army and invade France. The French greatly outnumber the British troops, yet Henry leads them to victory in the Battle of Agincourt after delivering his famous St. Crispin's Day Speech. Throughout this struggle, Henry also courts Katherine and eventually wins her over. Henry V is definitely an absorbing and entertaining film for it was updated for modern viewers.It was also an energetic,passionate,and wonderfully acted as well.Apart from that,it was a triumphant adaptation of Shakespeare's play and it brought about the playwright's timeless talent and appeal.Overall,it is a wonderful film not only for the fans of Shakespeare but anyone who loves great film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Coach Henry
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    drystyx
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/8/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Henry V, according to Shakesspeare's version of History, is well directed. And well acted. Well done all around. And since Shakespeare is best read instead of seen, it works very well in closed captioning. A liar is a person who says he/she understands the words as they are quickly sent out in these plays. In truth, they cannot be deciphered by the brain at such a pace, unless they are read. Personally, I didn't care for all the dim lighting, but it made for realistic dreary castle settings, if not for distinguishing what is going on. And it works for effect, because like black and white, dim lighting helps to focus on the story and not on all the distractions. What sets this Shakespeare play apart from nearly all other dramas and films is that most films show the warrior soldier as a father figure already, finished with his battle days. Here, we have the soldier hero as a young man, before he becomes the old hero. And it is very engaging. This Henry is a very likable character, and very three dimensional. It's refreshing to see a director treat a heroine as a "trophy", the beauty to be won, and of course it was written that way. Henry becomes like the coach giving the famous gung ho half time speech. However, there is more to him than just talk. We wonder what his battle strategy will be, and we're sure he has one. Indeed, though vastly outnumbered against the French, he does use his archers in a cunning way, with a troops of swords dashing out to the foray to hold the enemy at bay and in artillery range. With their swords at about 100 yards, the archers send their artillery barrage over their heads at about 150 yards, making the French between a rock and a hard place in three ways: 1. The French in front have no healthy reinforcements 2. The French in back must work their way over bodies, or be forced back 3. The French in front get into the artillery barrage if they retreat, so they have only one direction This is the play in which the king goes out among his men incognito, by the way. We really only get a good look at Henry and a couple of others. Many of the characters are well drawn, but fleeting in their appearance.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Where's a muse of fire when you need one?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Xander Seavy (RiffRaffMcKinley)
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/4/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Derek Jacobi's wonderfully proud, winking Chorus and Patrick Doyle's interesting (but barely) score are the sole redeeming features of this early Kenneth Branagh misfire. A gritty (in a BBC sense of the word) take on Shakespeare's mostly tedious historical play, "Henry V" gives far too much power to one man in the worst way that Branagh repeated so often to such bewildering acclaim. He not only directs and, rather pretentiously, "adapts for the screen" the words of the Bard, but also plays the title character. And sadly, he is by far no Olivier. The man has talent, to be sure, but it either wasn't here yet or it had fled temporarily when he took up this triple task. The only "flat, unraised spirit" here is Branagh himself, who essays a monotonous monarch with all the emotional depth of Keanu Reeves after an all-nighter. He even fumbles his one good instinct as a filmmaker: flashing back to "Henry IV" is an excellent way to provide backstory for people who aren't too familiar with the soap opera nature of some of Shakespeare's histories (which is primarily important here for the character of Falstaff), but the technique doesn't mesh with the rest of the picture. And why keep the Chorus? He's a purely theatrical device. He's there to tell us we have to imagine that we're in France or Southampton-- a necessity of the theater, in which all you can see is a stage and what's on it, but somewhat disconcerting in a film because the entire point of a film is to show us someplace we normally wouldn't see. Did he keep the Chorus to make his job, as a director, of sustaining our illusion that much easier? Whatever the motives (and no disrespect to the vibrant Jacobi), it was not the right decision. It's a boring, slow-to-evolve adaptation of a terrible, impossible-to-read play. (I am a fan of ol' Will, but his history plays are some of the most tedious dramas ever to plague the page.) If you're a fan of the kind of epic battle scenes of films as diverse as "Platoon" and "Gladiator," you'll definitely enjoy that aspect of the movie. Action-wise, it has its moments. But after a while, you just want Branagh to stick to doing one thing. Unfortunately, he's too self-indulgent to get that idea into his head.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Definitely one of the greater adaptations off of a Shakespearean play
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jdkraus
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/4/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Kenneth Brannagh's 1989 release of Henry V is definitely one of the greater adaptations off of a Shakespearean play. What really makes this film such a success is the big production that Brannagh had when he filmed this picture. Even though the Chorus reminds the viewer that the movie is just a mere imitation, I felt like I was looking at what it was like during the early 1400s. The costumes look very real, in fact, at the 1990 Academy Awards, the film won an Oscar for Best Costume Design. The production design and sets also add a sense of authenticity to the time period. The lighting in this film is unique, for it is generally low-key, giving both a literal and a figurative sense of darkness. This no doubt helped make the movie feel all the more dramatic and intense. The actors are perfect in their roles, whether it be the insignificant or the larger-than-life characters. One actor worth noting is Brian Blessed as Exeter. His encounter with the French king and the Dauphin is thoroughly amusing to watch. He not only carries the brutish demeanor of man ready to take on the whole French army, but he speaks coolly, delivering his lines carefully and fluently, all the while staring at the French king with terrifying eyes that makes him recoil. Simply brilliant! The real master of this film though is the main star and director Kenneth Brannagh. He does not merely act as King Henry V; he becomes the man. There are many great scenes where he displays his fierceness and determination as King Henry. One that comes to mind is when Henry is given the gift of tennis balls from Francean insult of calling him immature. As he speaks, threatening invasion of France to the Dauphin, there is an enraged confidence, yet restraint in his voice. It is obvious that he is dead serious about his threat, particularly when he refers to the French prince, "his balls have turned to gun-stones". Brannagh did not shout during this scene to strike fear in the Dauphin, for he did not have to. All it takes for Brannagh is one glance to scare a ferocious bear. Brannagh also reveals sheds of brutality and violence within Henry. When he finds out that three of his close associates had betrayed him, in a fit of rage, he grabs one of them and throws him on table. Henry then grabs the man's face, as he demands why he turned traitor. Once again, this explicitly shows that Henry is not a person to be feared or to be messed with. In short, Brannagh does not merely act as King Henry V; he becomes the man. As director, he proves in knowing how to suck a viewer into a film. The choice of shots throughout the film are excellent, whether it be the close ups during the heated debates or the three-minute long tracking shot that follows Brannagh as he carries a dead boy through the aftermath of Agincourt. I consider this shot to be one of the best scenes I have ever seen in cinema. Though Brannagh's film is a Shakespearean adaptation, it stands up as its own. It is perfectly acted and directed. If Shakespeare were alive to see this, he would be thoroughly impressed.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Very well crafted
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    TheLittleSongbird
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/3/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I like Kenneth Branagh's Shakespeare films, and Henry V is one of his better ones. The play is a very good one, and this film does it justice. Visually, it is very beautiful to look at, with interesting camera angles and great scenery and costumes. The music fits each scene very well and doesn't fall into the trap of being too melodramatic. The film like the play has a fine, compelling story that makes you feel all sorts of emotions, and the dialogue is wonderful. Branagh's directorial flair has a lot of vigour to it, and the Battle of Agincourt especially is very evocatively staged. The performances are uniformly good, Branagh is particularly impressive in the title role and the supporting cast are all fine Derek Jacobi coming off best in yet another one of his great performances. Overall, very well crafted. 9/10 Bethany Cox
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    In the script it is written, and on the screen it's pictures - F. Lang
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    clwydjones
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/2/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A Good "Televised" Play (i.e. a British film) For a master class on adapting Shakespeare to cinema you need to watch Akira Kurosawa's seminal "Throne of blood". This film is entertaining, but it's not cinema it's a very long TV drama (if you liked the BBC's Robin Hood series you'll love this). For anyone who's coming to Shakespeare for the first time I'd recommend Olivier's version. It's not a 'complete' version of the play, but it has the wit, subtlety and invention missing in Branagh. Olivier is much truer to the spirit of Shakespeare - it's playful and funny in parts (for example the lovely scene where Catherine is learning English). Most importantly Olivier brings out the beauty of Shakespears words (the spine tingling soliloquy in Henry's nighttime tour of the camp?). Branagh's version is neither a film or a play. It unfortunately the throttling of language for dramatic effect. Drowned in muzak and delivered with holly-pine-wood whispers or "You slag!" shouting. And kicks the crap out of the language with odd action film stresses and punctuations. Making the whole play difficult to listen to and understand. There's nothing playful or subtle about it - it's wall to wall drama - which inevitably gets a bit tedious after a while. The lines seem to be there more for pulling faces than for pleasure. A bit like being server a steak you really wanted to tuck into, but cant as someone's covered it in tomato sauce and half a pound of salt. Although there are some funny bits e.g. Derek Jacobi doing Marty DiBergi "introduction to Spinal Tap" at the start. It's also very 80's (e.g. Branagh's hair cut) - When he's asked if he's Cornishman I half expected him to answer, "No I am from Hampstead" Derek Jacobi (with thespian scarf) on the White Cliff of Dover doing Michael Palin's Ripping Yarns "You know, I think it was G.K. Chesterton, who once said..." (Tomkinson's schooldays) Required watching I imagine for all those poor high school students who are forced to learn Shakespeare... (I award it 1 only to try and introduce some sanity to the overall rating. As an adaptation of Shakespeare - 6.5/10. As a general film - 6/10. as a serious cinematic film - 1/10)
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Powerful and Gritty Adaptation...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Janis Livens
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I'm one of those illiterate hacks who hasn't read a single Shakespeare play till the end. It's because in my country we have our own "bard" and Shakespeare's plays were glanced at best. The film itself was brilliant at times and dull at others. It works as individuals scenes perfectly but fails at being compelling narrative due many scenes that felt pointless to me. The reason why enjoyed the most of Henry V was Kenneth Branagh. His brilliant performance carried the film for me and any scene with him was a joy to watch. It's really hard to comment on the acting. The cast is brilliant from top to bottom, my favorite being Brian "Gordon's Alive!" Blessed and Ian Holm. The direction by Kenneth Branagh is worth mentioning. He clearly made Henry V as an anti-war film and it works perfectly. The aftermath of the battle is very powerful, thanks to the direction and magnificent score. But sadly, it's not without problems. The most glaring problem to me, was the pacing. Nearly every single flashback scene stopped the film to a screeching halt. And then there is the silly ending. While I did enjoy the chemistry between Emma Thompson and Kenneth Branagh, it slightly ruined the dark tone the aftermath of the battle had set. In other words, they should have cut some of the scenes out for a better flow of the narrative. Henry V is a good Shakespeare adaptation. I loved the performances by the cast and some of the brilliant set pieces of the film. But as a whole it's just watchable. If you like Shakespeare's plays this is a must see but for anyone else it's hard to recommend. Especially if your English isn't very good.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Henry V
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ShibanPD
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The greatest adaptation of a Shakespearean play to the screen, Henry V, adapted by, directed by, and starring Kenneth Branagh, bridges the gap between faithful reproduction and innovative representation in an extremely exciting, most cinematic way. Branagh has certainly done his homework, and we are the benefactors of his erudition. For the most part, he has reduced Shakespeare's text to those elements which are not only screen-worthy, but the meanings of which ride easily on tone, gesture, and action, so that Shakespeare's poetic, though metaphorically dense language presents little obstacle to the understanding of the modern ear. Remainingand out of place for such a successful transition between mediumsare unnecessary lines delivered by the Chorus (played by a fiery Derek Jacobi), which beg us to pardon the meagerness of the presentation and beseech us to use our imaginations to fill in the resulting holes. Famous lines to those familiar with the stage, but strangely redundant from within the context of a film of such high production value, grandness, and beautywith a visual and aural realization that rises to match the quality of the bard's text. On the side of embellishment, Branagh interweaves lines, characters, and scenes from parts of Henry IV, through clever flashbacks. The purpose of this device is to summon Hal's past relationships with old friends who are now his subjects, and to elucidate the duality of Hal/Henry; for Hal was not always king, and in his younger days, he caroused with commoners, drunkards, liars, and even thieves. The effectiveness of this device varies: the hanging of Bardolph draws additional emotional impact from it, but, in spite of it and several fine, heartfelt performances, the reminiscing after Falstaff's death falls flat, since we, unlike the audience of Shakespeare's time, have not come to know and love this Sir John Falstaff through Parts 1 and 2 of Henry IV and other works. Now the betrayal of Falstaff by Hal, though moderately effective in the use of this same device, is one of the most interesting scenes in the film, as it employs a flash forward within a flashback, in which we hear Hal think what he will eventually say to Falstaff, and Falstaff responds to his disavowal. Hal's transformation into Henry V is really the heart of Shakespeare's story, as it requires him to sever connections to his "wilder days" in order to lead his countrymen in worldly pursuits. Branagh's handling of it is quite remarkable. Branagh's own acting performance as the title character is smart and passionate, commanding and stirring. It does suffer slightly from that same ailment that afflicts other zealous students of Shakespeare: he knows his lines so well that they, at times, lose their spontaneity and/or authenticity. That penetrating knowledge, which detracts slightly from his performance, overcompensates as an asset to his bold, definitive adaptation and assured direction. Additional assets are an unforgettably powerful score by Patrick Doyle and a solid surrounding cast, which includes Paul Scofield (as King Charles VI of France), Brian Blessed, Ian Holm, Judi Dench, Emma Thompson, and a young Christian Bale. Most notable among the supporting players are Robert Stephens as Auncient Pistol and Christopher Ravenscroft, who, as Montjoy, turns a messenger part into a key role through his earnest, telling reactions to both Henry and the French Dauphin.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Here is all the glory, power, drama, suspense, and intrigue the Bard intended in this rousing play.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Frederick Smith
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/3/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    There may be one hundred or so men who are capable of bringing Shakespeare to the screen, but none so talented and capable as Kenneth Branaugh. Here is all the glory, power, drama, suspense, and intrigue the Bard intended in this rousing play. Jacobi is incredible as the Chorus, a device we would call narrator, and builds his role with eloquence and tempered techniques of voice seldom seen in film. Branaugh displays a rare and insightful look at the character of the now wizened king who was so foolish as a boy. The cast, in all, is superb in their understanding of their roles and carry them off with a passion that perhaps only an Englishman can understand. I have seen this film several times, having a copy along with other versions of Shakespearean plays, and by far this is the most exciting, the most accurate, and the most palatable film of its genre. Combine a timeless tale of war and conquest with a cast already world renown and you have this film, a modern testament to the power of Shakespeare. Rated PG-13 for a violent and bloody battle, this film is fit for the high school crowd and, in my humble opinion, should be shown to every English student about to study Shakespeare.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Touch Of The Tyrant
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bkoganbing
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Some years ago I read a history of the 100 Years War and it was by a British author named Desmond Siward who advanced the notion that Henry V was one of the great tyrants in making of English history. Had it not been for his early death that's how he would have gone down in history. Thinking on it, imagine if you will how history might have regarded him had he lived another decade and had been in power for the British occupation of over half of France and had been the man in charge when Joan Of Arc was burned at the stake? When Winston Churchill gave all aid and assistance he could to Laurence Olivier;s Henry V during World War II it was to show the glory of English arms at a high point in their history. Even if it was at the expense of France whom the British were now allies with. Olivier played Henry V in true heroic mold, but in this production of Henry V, Kenneth Branagh gives Henry V a touch of the tyrant as in current historiography. This Henry V was not guided by wartime necessity, but could be closer to the truth. I did like the inclusions of those flashback scenes from Henry IV where we see merry Prince Hal cavorting with his low companions like Sir John Falstaff. Those might have been some invention of Shakespeare, but certainly the man who was Henry V was all business when he was on the throne. This newer Henry V received several Oscar nominations including one for Kenneth Branagh to match the one that Laurence Olivier got over 40 years earlier for Best Actor. It's certainly a different Henry that Branagh gives us. You can hardly see a Prince Hal in this king.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Wonderful Adaptation Of Shakespeare's Play
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    SiliconDesertMan40
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/11/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Henry V is a film based on William Shakespeare's play The Life of Henry the Fifth about the famous English king.Kenneth Branagh stars in the title role,wrote the screenplay and directed the movie.It also features Paul Scofield,Ian Holm,Emma Thompson,Alec McCowen,Judi Dench and Christian Bale. It is frequently compared with the 1944 film of the play directed by and starring Laurence Olivier. The visual style of former is grittier and more realistic than that of the latter. The movie has a narrator with the name Chrous.After the he introduces the play, young king of England Henry V begins an angry dialogue with King Charles of France. The king's son, Dauphin,insults Henry and the argument escalates into war. In flashback, Henry is seen as a young man drinking in a tavern with Falstaff, Bardolph,Nym,Pistol, and Mistress Quickly. Meanwhile, Henry and his captain, Fluellen, assemble an army and invade France. The French greatly outnumber the British troops, yet Henry leads them to victory in the Battle of Agincourt after delivering his famous St. Crispin's Day Speech. Throughout this struggle, Henry also courts Katherine and eventually wins her over. Henry V is definitely an absorbing and entertaining film for it was updated for modern viewers.It was also an energetic,passionate,and wonderfully acted as well.Apart from that,it was a triumphant adaptation of Shakespeare's play and it brought about the playwright's timeless talent and appeal.Overall,it is a wonderful film not only for the fans of Shakespeare but anyone who loves great film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Coach Henry
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    drystyx
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/8/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Henry V, according to Shakesspeare's version of History, is well directed. And well acted. Well done all around. And since Shakespeare is best read instead of seen, it works very well in closed captioning. A liar is a person who says he/she understands the words as they are quickly sent out in these plays. In truth, they cannot be deciphered by the brain at such a pace, unless they are read. Personally, I didn't care for all the dim lighting, but it made for realistic dreary castle settings, if not for distinguishing what is going on. And it works for effect, because like black and white, dim lighting helps to focus on the story and not on all the distractions. What sets this Shakespeare play apart from nearly all other dramas and films is that most films show the warrior soldier as a father figure already, finished with his battle days. Here, we have the soldier hero as a young man, before he becomes the old hero. And it is very engaging. This Henry is a very likable character, and very three dimensional. It's refreshing to see a director treat a heroine as a "trophy", the beauty to be won, and of course it was written that way. Henry becomes like the coach giving the famous gung ho half time speech. However, there is more to him than just talk. We wonder what his battle strategy will be, and we're sure he has one. Indeed, though vastly outnumbered against the French, he does use his archers in a cunning way, with a troops of swords dashing out to the foray to hold the enemy at bay and in artillery range. With their swords at about 100 yards, the archers send their artillery barrage over their heads at about 150 yards, making the French between a rock and a hard place in three ways: 1. The French in front have no healthy reinforcements 2. The French in back must work their way over bodies, or be forced back 3. The French in front get into the artillery barrage if they retreat, so they have only one direction This is the play in which the king goes out among his men incognito, by the way. We really only get a good look at Henry and a couple of others. Many of the characters are well drawn, but fleeting in their appearance.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Where's a muse of fire when you need one?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Xander Seavy (RiffRaffMcKinley)
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/4/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Derek Jacobi's wonderfully proud, winking Chorus and Patrick Doyle's interesting (but barely) score are the sole redeeming features of this early Kenneth Branagh misfire. A gritty (in a BBC sense of the word) take on Shakespeare's mostly tedious historical play, "Henry V" gives far too much power to one man in the worst way that Branagh repeated so often to such bewildering acclaim. He not only directs and, rather pretentiously, "adapts for the screen" the words of the Bard, but also plays the title character. And sadly, he is by far no Olivier. The man has talent, to be sure, but it either wasn't here yet or it had fled temporarily when he took up this triple task. The only "flat, unraised spirit" here is Branagh himself, who essays a monotonous monarch with all the emotional depth of Keanu Reeves after an all-nighter. He even fumbles his one good instinct as a filmmaker: flashing back to "Henry IV" is an excellent way to provide backstory for people who aren't too familiar with the soap opera nature of some of Shakespeare's histories (which is primarily important here for the character of Falstaff), but the technique doesn't mesh with the rest of the picture. And why keep the Chorus? He's a purely theatrical device. He's there to tell us we have to imagine that we're in France or Southampton-- a necessity of the theater, in which all you can see is a stage and what's on it, but somewhat disconcerting in a film because the entire point of a film is to show us someplace we normally wouldn't see. Did he keep the Chorus to make his job, as a director, of sustaining our illusion that much easier? Whatever the motives (and no disrespect to the vibrant Jacobi), it was not the right decision. It's a boring, slow-to-evolve adaptation of a terrible, impossible-to-read play. (I am a fan of ol' Will, but his history plays are some of the most tedious dramas ever to plague the page.) If you're a fan of the kind of epic battle scenes of films as diverse as "Platoon" and "Gladiator," you'll definitely enjoy that aspect of the movie. Action-wise, it has its moments. But after a while, you just want Branagh to stick to doing one thing. Unfortunately, he's too self-indulgent to get that idea into his head.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Definitely one of the greater adaptations off of a Shakespearean play
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jdkraus
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/4/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Kenneth Brannagh's 1989 release of Henry V is definitely one of the greater adaptations off of a Shakespearean play. What really makes this film such a success is the big production that Brannagh had when he filmed this picture. Even though the Chorus reminds the viewer that the movie is just a mere imitation, I felt like I was looking at what it was like during the early 1400s. The costumes look very real, in fact, at the 1990 Academy Awards, the film won an Oscar for Best Costume Design. The production design and sets also add a sense of authenticity to the time period. The lighting in this film is unique, for it is generally low-key, giving both a literal and a figurative sense of darkness. This no doubt helped make the movie feel all the more dramatic and intense. The actors are perfect in their roles, whether it be the insignificant or the larger-than-life characters. One actor worth noting is Brian Blessed as Exeter. His encounter with the French king and the Dauphin is thoroughly amusing to watch. He not only carries the brutish demeanor of man ready to take on the whole French army, but he speaks coolly, delivering his lines carefully and fluently, all the while staring at the French king with terrifying eyes that makes him recoil. Simply brilliant! The real master of this film though is the main star and director Kenneth Brannagh. He does not merely act as King Henry V; he becomes the man. There are many great scenes where he displays his fierceness and determination as King Henry. One that comes to mind is when Henry is given the gift of tennis balls from Francean insult of calling him immature. As he speaks, threatening invasion of France to the Dauphin, there is an enraged confidence, yet restraint in his voice. It is obvious that he is dead serious about his threat, particularly when he refers to the French prince, "his balls have turned to gun-stones". Brannagh did not shout during this scene to strike fear in the Dauphin, for he did not have to. All it takes for Brannagh is one glance to scare a ferocious bear. Brannagh also reveals sheds of brutality and violence within Henry. When he finds out that three of his close associates had betrayed him, in a fit of rage, he grabs one of them and throws him on table. Henry then grabs the man's face, as he demands why he turned traitor. Once again, this explicitly shows that Henry is not a person to be feared or to be messed with. In short, Brannagh does not merely act as King Henry V; he becomes the man. As director, he proves in knowing how to suck a viewer into a film. The choice of shots throughout the film are excellent, whether it be the close ups during the heated debates or the three-minute long tracking shot that follows Brannagh as he carries a dead boy through the aftermath of Agincourt. I consider this shot to be one of the best scenes I have ever seen in cinema. Though Brannagh's film is a Shakespearean adaptation, it stands up as its own. It is perfectly acted and directed. If Shakespeare were alive to see this, he would be thoroughly impressed.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Very well crafted
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    TheLittleSongbird
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/3/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I like Kenneth Branagh's Shakespeare films, and Henry V is one of his better ones. The play is a very good one, and this film does it justice. Visually, it is very beautiful to look at, with interesting camera angles and great scenery and costumes. The music fits each scene very well and doesn't fall into the trap of being too melodramatic. The film like the play has a fine, compelling story that makes you feel all sorts of emotions, and the dialogue is wonderful. Branagh's directorial flair has a lot of vigour to it, and the Battle of Agincourt especially is very evocatively staged. The performances are uniformly good, Branagh is particularly impressive in the title role and the supporting cast are all fine Derek Jacobi coming off best in yet another one of his great performances. Overall, very well crafted. 9/10 Bethany Cox
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    In the script it is written, and on the screen it's pictures - F. Lang
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    clwydjones
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/2/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A Good "Televised" Play (i.e. a British film) For a master class on adapting Shakespeare to cinema you need to watch Akira Kurosawa's seminal "Throne of blood". This film is entertaining, but it's not cinema it's a very long TV drama (if you liked the BBC's Robin Hood series you'll love this). For anyone who's coming to Shakespeare for the first time I'd recommend Olivier's version. It's not a 'complete' version of the play, but it has the wit, subtlety and invention missing in Branagh. Olivier is much truer to the spirit of Shakespeare - it's playful and funny in parts (for example the lovely scene where Catherine is learning English). Most importantly Olivier brings out the beauty of Shakespears words (the spine tingling soliloquy in Henry's nighttime tour of the camp?). Branagh's version is neither a film or a play. It unfortunately the throttling of language for dramatic effect. Drowned in muzak and delivered with holly-pine-wood whispers or "You slag!" shouting. And kicks the crap out of the language with odd action film stresses and punctuations. Making the whole play difficult to listen to and understand. There's nothing playful or subtle about it - it's wall to wall drama - which inevitably gets a bit tedious after a while. The lines seem to be there more for pulling faces than for pleasure. A bit like being server a steak you really wanted to tuck into, but cant as someone's covered it in tomato sauce and half a pound of salt. Although there are some funny bits e.g. Derek Jacobi doing Marty DiBergi "introduction to Spinal Tap" at the start. It's also very 80's (e.g. Branagh's hair cut) - When he's asked if he's Cornishman I half expected him to answer, "No I am from Hampstead" Derek Jacobi (with thespian scarf) on the White Cliff of Dover doing Michael Palin's Ripping Yarns "You know, I think it was G.K. Chesterton, who once said..." (Tomkinson's schooldays) Required watching I imagine for all those poor high school students who are forced to learn Shakespeare... (I award it 1 only to try and introduce some sanity to the overall rating. As an adaptation of Shakespeare - 6.5/10. As a general film - 6/10. as a serious cinematic film - 1/10)
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Powerful and Gritty Adaptation...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Janis Livens
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I'm one of those illiterate hacks who hasn't read a single Shakespeare play till the end. It's because in my country we have our own "bard" and Shakespeare's plays were glanced at best. The film itself was brilliant at times and dull at others. It works as individuals scenes perfectly but fails at being compelling narrative due many scenes that felt pointless to me. The reason why enjoyed the most of Henry V was Kenneth Branagh. His brilliant performance carried the film for me and any scene with him was a joy to watch. It's really hard to comment on the acting. The cast is brilliant from top to bottom, my favorite being Brian "Gordon's Alive!" Blessed and Ian Holm. The direction by Kenneth Branagh is worth mentioning. He clearly made Henry V as an anti-war film and it works perfectly. The aftermath of the battle is very powerful, thanks to the direction and magnificent score. But sadly, it's not without problems. The most glaring problem to me, was the pacing. Nearly every single flashback scene stopped the film to a screeching halt. And then there is the silly ending. While I did enjoy the chemistry between Emma Thompson and Kenneth Branagh, it slightly ruined the dark tone the aftermath of the battle had set. In other words, they should have cut some of the scenes out for a better flow of the narrative. Henry V is a good Shakespeare adaptation. I loved the performances by the cast and some of the brilliant set pieces of the film. But as a whole it's just watchable. If you like Shakespeare's plays this is a must see but for anyone else it's hard to recommend. Especially if your English isn't very good.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Henry V
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ShibanPD
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The greatest adaptation of a Shakespearean play to the screen, Henry V, adapted by, directed by, and starring Kenneth Branagh, bridges the gap between faithful reproduction and innovative representation in an extremely exciting, most cinematic way. Branagh has certainly done his homework, and we are the benefactors of his erudition. For the most part, he has reduced Shakespeare's text to those elements which are not only screen-worthy, but the meanings of which ride easily on tone, gesture, and action, so that Shakespeare's poetic, though metaphorically dense language presents little obstacle to the understanding of the modern ear. Remainingand out of place for such a successful transition between mediumsare unnecessary lines delivered by the Chorus (played by a fiery Derek Jacobi), which beg us to pardon the meagerness of the presentation and beseech us to use our imaginations to fill in the resulting holes. Famous lines to those familiar with the stage, but strangely redundant from within the context of a film of such high production value, grandness, and beautywith a visual and aural realization that rises to match the quality of the bard's text. On the side of embellishment, Branagh interweaves lines, characters, and scenes from parts of Henry IV, through clever flashbacks. The purpose of this device is to summon Hal's past relationships with old friends who are now his subjects, and to elucidate the duality of Hal/Henry; for Hal was not always king, and in his younger days, he caroused with commoners, drunkards, liars, and even thieves. The effectiveness of this device varies: the hanging of Bardolph draws additional emotional impact from it, but, in spite of it and several fine, heartfelt performances, the reminiscing after Falstaff's death falls flat, since we, unlike the audience of Shakespeare's time, have not come to know and love this Sir John Falstaff through Parts 1 and 2 of Henry IV and other works. Now the betrayal of Falstaff by Hal, though moderately effective in the use of this same device, is one of the most interesting scenes in the film, as it employs a flash forward within a flashback, in which we hear Hal think what he will eventually say to Falstaff, and Falstaff responds to his disavowal. Hal's transformation into Henry V is really the heart of Shakespeare's story, as it requires him to sever connections to his "wilder days" in order to lead his countrymen in worldly pursuits. Branagh's handling of it is quite remarkable. Branagh's own acting performance as the title character is smart and passionate, commanding and stirring. It does suffer slightly from that same ailment that afflicts other zealous students of Shakespeare: he knows his lines so well that they, at times, lose their spontaneity and/or authenticity. That penetrating knowledge, which detracts slightly from his performance, overcompensates as an asset to his bold, definitive adaptation and assured direction. Additional assets are an unforgettably powerful score by Patrick Doyle and a solid surrounding cast, which includes Paul Scofield (as King Charles VI of France), Brian Blessed, Ian Holm, Judi Dench, Emma Thompson, and a young Christian Bale. Most notable among the supporting players are Robert Stephens as Auncient Pistol and Christopher Ravenscroft, who, as Montjoy, turns a messenger part into a key role through his earnest, telling reactions to both Henry and the French Dauphin.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Here is all the glory, power, drama, suspense, and intrigue the Bard intended in this rousing play.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Frederick Smith
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/3/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    There may be one hundred or so men who are capable of bringing Shakespeare to the screen, but none so talented and capable as Kenneth Branaugh. Here is all the glory, power, drama, suspense, and intrigue the Bard intended in this rousing play. Jacobi is incredible as the Chorus, a device we would call narrator, and builds his role with eloquence and tempered techniques of voice seldom seen in film. Branaugh displays a rare and insightful look at the character of the now wizened king who was so foolish as a boy. The cast, in all, is superb in their understanding of their roles and carry them off with a passion that perhaps only an Englishman can understand. I have seen this film several times, having a copy along with other versions of Shakespearean plays, and by far this is the most exciting, the most accurate, and the most palatable film of its genre. Combine a timeless tale of war and conquest with a cast already world renown and you have this film, a modern testament to the power of Shakespeare. Rated PG-13 for a violent and bloody battle, this film is fit for the high school crowd and, in my humble opinion, should be shown to every English student about to study Shakespeare.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Touch Of The Tyrant
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bkoganbing
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Some years ago I read a history of the 100 Years War and it was by a British author named Desmond Siward who advanced the notion that Henry V was one of the great tyrants in making of English history. Had it not been for his early death that's how he would have gone down in history. Thinking on it, imagine if you will how history might have regarded him had he lived another decade and had been in power for the British occupation of over half of France and had been the man in charge when Joan Of Arc was burned at the stake? When Winston Churchill gave all aid and assistance he could to Laurence Olivier;s Henry V during World War II it was to show the glory of English arms at a high point in their history. Even if it was at the expense of France whom the British were now allies with. Olivier played Henry V in true heroic mold, but in this production of Henry V, Kenneth Branagh gives Henry V a touch of the tyrant as in current historiography. This Henry V was not guided by wartime necessity, but could be closer to the truth. I did like the inclusions of those flashback scenes from Henry IV where we see merry Prince Hal cavorting with his low companions like Sir John Falstaff. Those might have been some invention of Shakespeare, but certainly the man who was Henry V was all business when he was on the throne. This newer Henry V received several Oscar nominations including one for Kenneth Branagh to match the one that Laurence Olivier got over 40 years earlier for Best Actor. It's certainly a different Henry that Branagh gives us. You can hardly see a Prince Hal in this king.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Wonderful Adaptation Of Shakespeare's Play
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    SiliconDesertMan40
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/11/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Henry V is a film based on William Shakespeare's play The Life of Henry the Fifth about the famous English king.Kenneth Branagh stars in the title role,wrote the screenplay and directed the movie.It also features Paul Scofield,Ian Holm,Emma Thompson,Alec McCowen,Judi Dench and Christian Bale. It is frequently compared with the 1944 film of the play directed by and starring Laurence Olivier. The visual style of former is grittier and more realistic than that of the latter. The movie has a narrator with the name Chrous.After the he introduces the play, young king of England Henry V begins an angry dialogue with King Charles of France. The king's son, Dauphin,insults Henry and the argument escalates into war. In flashback, Henry is seen as a young man drinking in a tavern with Falstaff, Bardolph,Nym,Pistol, and Mistress Quickly. Meanwhile, Henry and his captain, Fluellen, assemble an army and invade France. The French greatly outnumber the British troops, yet Henry leads them to victory in the Battle of Agincourt after delivering his famous St. Crispin's Day Speech. Throughout this struggle, Henry also courts Katherine and eventually wins her over. Henry V is definitely an absorbing and entertaining film for it was updated for modern viewers.It was also an energetic,passionate,and wonderfully acted as well.Apart from that,it was a triumphant adaptation of Shakespeare's play and it brought about the playwright's timeless talent and appeal.Overall,it is a wonderful film not only for the fans of Shakespeare but anyone who loves great film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Coach Henry
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    drystyx
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/8/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Henry V, according to Shakesspeare's version of History, is well directed. And well acted. Well done all around. And since Shakespeare is best read instead of seen, it works very well in closed captioning. A liar is a person who says he/she understands the words as they are quickly sent out in these plays. In truth, they cannot be deciphered by the brain at such a pace, unless they are read. Personally, I didn't care for all the dim lighting, but it made for realistic dreary castle settings, if not for distinguishing what is going on. And it works for effect, because like black and white, dim lighting helps to focus on the story and not on all the distractions. What sets this Shakespeare play apart from nearly all other dramas and films is that most films show the warrior soldier as a father figure already, finished with his battle days. Here, we have the soldier hero as a young man, before he becomes the old hero. And it is very engaging. This Henry is a very likable character, and very three dimensional. It's refreshing to see a director treat a heroine as a "trophy", the beauty to be won, and of course it was written that way. Henry becomes like the coach giving the famous gung ho half time speech. However, there is more to him than just talk. We wonder what his battle strategy will be, and we're sure he has one. Indeed, though vastly outnumbered against the French, he does use his archers in a cunning way, with a troops of swords dashing out to the foray to hold the enemy at bay and in artillery range. With their swords at about 100 yards, the archers send their artillery barrage over their heads at about 150 yards, making the French between a rock and a hard place in three ways: 1. The French in front have no healthy reinforcements 2. The French in back must work their way over bodies, or be forced back 3. The French in front get into the artillery barrage if they retreat, so they have only one direction This is the play in which the king goes out among his men incognito, by the way. We really only get a good look at Henry and a couple of others. Many of the characters are well drawn, but fleeting in their appearance.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Where's a muse of fire when you need one?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Xander Seavy (RiffRaffMcKinley)
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/4/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Derek Jacobi's wonderfully proud, winking Chorus and Patrick Doyle's interesting (but barely) score are the sole redeeming features of this early Kenneth Branagh misfire. A gritty (in a BBC sense of the word) take on Shakespeare's mostly tedious historical play, "Henry V" gives far too much power to one man in the worst way that Branagh repeated so often to such bewildering acclaim. He not only directs and, rather pretentiously, "adapts for the screen" the words of the Bard, but also plays the title character. And sadly, he is by far no Olivier. The man has talent, to be sure, but it either wasn't here yet or it had fled temporarily when he took up this triple task. The only "flat, unraised spirit" here is Branagh himself, who essays a monotonous monarch with all the emotional depth of Keanu Reeves after an all-nighter. He even fumbles his one good instinct as a filmmaker: flashing back to "Henry IV" is an excellent way to provide backstory for people who aren't too familiar with the soap opera nature of some of Shakespeare's histories (which is primarily important here for the character of Falstaff), but the technique doesn't mesh with the rest of the picture. And why keep the Chorus? He's a purely theatrical device. He's there to tell us we have to imagine that we're in France or Southampton-- a necessity of the theater, in which all you can see is a stage and what's on it, but somewhat disconcerting in a film because the entire point of a film is to show us someplace we normally wouldn't see. Did he keep the Chorus to make his job, as a director, of sustaining our illusion that much easier? Whatever the motives (and no disrespect to the vibrant Jacobi), it was not the right decision. It's a boring, slow-to-evolve adaptation of a terrible, impossible-to-read play. (I am a fan of ol' Will, but his history plays are some of the most tedious dramas ever to plague the page.) If you're a fan of the kind of epic battle scenes of films as diverse as "Platoon" and "Gladiator," you'll definitely enjoy that aspect of the movie. Action-wise, it has its moments. But after a while, you just want Branagh to stick to doing one thing. Unfortunately, he's too self-indulgent to get that idea into his head.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Definitely one of the greater adaptations off of a Shakespearean play
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jdkraus
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/4/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Kenneth Brannagh's 1989 release of Henry V is definitely one of the greater adaptations off of a Shakespearean play. What really makes this film such a success is the big production that Brannagh had when he filmed this picture. Even though the Chorus reminds the viewer that the movie is just a mere imitation, I felt like I was looking at what it was like during the early 1400s. The costumes look very real, in fact, at the 1990 Academy Awards, the film won an Oscar for Best Costume Design. The production design and sets also add a sense of authenticity to the time period. The lighting in this film is unique, for it is generally low-key, giving both a literal and a figurative sense of darkness. This no doubt helped make the movie feel all the more dramatic and intense. The actors are perfect in their roles, whether it be the insignificant or the larger-than-life characters. One actor worth noting is Brian Blessed as Exeter. His encounter with the French king and the Dauphin is thoroughly amusing to watch. He not only carries the brutish demeanor of man ready to take on the whole French army, but he speaks coolly, delivering his lines carefully and fluently, all the while staring at the French king with terrifying eyes that makes him recoil. Simply brilliant! The real master of this film though is the main star and director Kenneth Brannagh. He does not merely act as King Henry V; he becomes the man. There are many great scenes where he displays his fierceness and determination as King Henry. One that comes to mind is when Henry is given the gift of tennis balls from Francean insult of calling him immature. As he speaks, threatening invasion of France to the Dauphin, there is an enraged confidence, yet restraint in his voice. It is obvious that he is dead serious about his threat, particularly when he refers to the French prince, "his balls have turned to gun-stones". Brannagh did not shout during this scene to strike fear in the Dauphin, for he did not have to. All it takes for Brannagh is one glance to scare a ferocious bear. Brannagh also reveals sheds of brutality and violence within Henry. When he finds out that three of his close associates had betrayed him, in a fit of rage, he grabs one of them and throws him on table. Henry then grabs the man's face, as he demands why he turned traitor. Once again, this explicitly shows that Henry is not a person to be feared or to be messed with. In short, Brannagh does not merely act as King Henry V; he becomes the man. As director, he proves in knowing how to suck a viewer into a film. The choice of shots throughout the film are excellent, whether it be the close ups during the heated debates or the three-minute long tracking shot that follows Brannagh as he carries a dead boy through the aftermath of Agincourt. I consider this shot to be one of the best scenes I have ever seen in cinema. Though Brannagh's film is a Shakespearean adaptation, it stands up as its own. It is perfectly acted and directed. If Shakespeare were alive to see this, he would be thoroughly impressed.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Very well crafted
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    TheLittleSongbird
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/3/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I like Kenneth Branagh's Shakespeare films, and Henry V is one of his better ones. The play is a very good one, and this film does it justice. Visually, it is very beautiful to look at, with interesting camera angles and great scenery and costumes. The music fits each scene very well and doesn't fall into the trap of being too melodramatic. The film like the play has a fine, compelling story that makes you feel all sorts of emotions, and the dialogue is wonderful. Branagh's directorial flair has a lot of vigour to it, and the Battle of Agincourt especially is very evocatively staged. The performances are uniformly good, Branagh is particularly impressive in the title role and the supporting cast are all fine Derek Jacobi coming off best in yet another one of his great performances. Overall, very well crafted. 9/10 Bethany Cox
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    In the script it is written, and on the screen it's pictures - F. Lang
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    clwydjones
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/2/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A Good "Televised" Play (i.e. a British film) For a master class on adapting Shakespeare to cinema you need to watch Akira Kurosawa's seminal "Throne of blood". This film is entertaining, but it's not cinema it's a very long TV drama (if you liked the BBC's Robin Hood series you'll love this). For anyone who's coming to Shakespeare for the first time I'd recommend Olivier's version. It's not a 'complete' version of the play, but it has the wit, subtlety and invention missing in Branagh. Olivier is much truer to the spirit of Shakespeare - it's playful and funny in parts (for example the lovely scene where Catherine is learning English). Most importantly Olivier brings out the beauty of Shakespears words (the spine tingling soliloquy in Henry's nighttime tour of the camp?). Branagh's version is neither a film or a play. It unfortunately the throttling of language for dramatic effect. Drowned in muzak and delivered with holly-pine-wood whispers or "You slag!" shouting. And kicks the crap out of the language with odd action film stresses and punctuations. Making the whole play difficult to listen to and understand. There's nothing playful or subtle about it - it's wall to wall drama - which inevitably gets a bit tedious after a while. The lines seem to be there more for pulling faces than for pleasure. A bit like being server a steak you really wanted to tuck into, but cant as someone's covered it in tomato sauce and half a pound of salt. Although there are some funny bits e.g. Derek Jacobi doing Marty DiBergi "introduction to Spinal Tap" at the start. It's also very 80's (e.g. Branagh's hair cut) - When he's asked if he's Cornishman I half expected him to answer, "No I am from Hampstead" Derek Jacobi (with thespian scarf) on the White Cliff of Dover doing Michael Palin's Ripping Yarns "You know, I think it was G.K. Chesterton, who once said..." (Tomkinson's schooldays) Required watching I imagine for all those poor high school students who are forced to learn Shakespeare... (I award it 1 only to try and introduce some sanity to the overall rating. As an adaptation of Shakespeare - 6.5/10. As a general film - 6/10. as a serious cinematic film - 1/10)
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Powerful and Gritty Adaptation...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Janis Livens
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I'm one of those illiterate hacks who hasn't read a single Shakespeare play till the end. It's because in my country we have our own "bard" and Shakespeare's plays were glanced at best. The film itself was brilliant at times and dull at others. It works as individuals scenes perfectly but fails at being compelling narrative due many scenes that felt pointless to me. The reason why enjoyed the most of Henry V was Kenneth Branagh. His brilliant performance carried the film for me and any scene with him was a joy to watch. It's really hard to comment on the acting. The cast is brilliant from top to bottom, my favorite being Brian "Gordon's Alive!" Blessed and Ian Holm. The direction by Kenneth Branagh is worth mentioning. He clearly made Henry V as an anti-war film and it works perfectly. The aftermath of the battle is very powerful, thanks to the direction and magnificent score. But sadly, it's not without problems. The most glaring problem to me, was the pacing. Nearly every single flashback scene stopped the film to a screeching halt. And then there is the silly ending. While I did enjoy the chemistry between Emma Thompson and Kenneth Branagh, it slightly ruined the dark tone the aftermath of the battle had set. In other words, they should have cut some of the scenes out for a better flow of the narrative. Henry V is a good Shakespeare adaptation. I loved the performances by the cast and some of the brilliant set pieces of the film. But as a whole it's just watchable. If you like Shakespeare's plays this is a must see but for anyone else it's hard to recommend. Especially if your English isn't very good.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Henry V
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ShibanPD
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The greatest adaptation of a Shakespearean play to the screen, Henry V, adapted by, directed by, and starring Kenneth Branagh, bridges the gap between faithful reproduction and innovative representation in an extremely exciting, most cinematic way. Branagh has certainly done his homework, and we are the benefactors of his erudition. For the most part, he has reduced Shakespeare's text to those elements which are not only screen-worthy, but the meanings of which ride easily on tone, gesture, and action, so that Shakespeare's poetic, though metaphorically dense language presents little obstacle to the understanding of the modern ear. Remainingand out of place for such a successful transition between mediumsare unnecessary lines delivered by the Chorus (played by a fiery Derek Jacobi), which beg us to pardon the meagerness of the presentation and beseech us to use our imaginations to fill in the resulting holes. Famous lines to those familiar with the stage, but strangely redundant from within the context of a film of such high production value, grandness, and beautywith a visual and aural realization that rises to match the quality of the bard's text. On the side of embellishment, Branagh interweaves lines, characters, and scenes from parts of Henry IV, through clever flashbacks. The purpose of this device is to summon Hal's past relationships with old friends who are now his subjects, and to elucidate the duality of Hal/Henry; for Hal was not always king, and in his younger days, he caroused with commoners, drunkards, liars, and even thieves. The effectiveness of this device varies: the hanging of Bardolph draws additional emotional impact from it, but, in spite of it and several fine, heartfelt performances, the reminiscing after Falstaff's death falls flat, since we, unlike the audience of Shakespeare's time, have not come to know and love this Sir John Falstaff through Parts 1 and 2 of Henry IV and other works. Now the betrayal of Falstaff by Hal, though moderately effective in the use of this same device, is one of the most interesting scenes in the film, as it employs a flash forward within a flashback, in which we hear Hal think what he will eventually say to Falstaff, and Falstaff responds to his disavowal. Hal's transformation into Henry V is really the heart of Shakespeare's story, as it requires him to sever connections to his "wilder days" in order to lead his countrymen in worldly pursuits. Branagh's handling of it is quite remarkable. Branagh's own acting performance as the title character is smart and passionate, commanding and stirring. It does suffer slightly from that same ailment that afflicts other zealous students of Shakespeare: he knows his lines so well that they, at times, lose their spontaneity and/or authenticity. That penetrating knowledge, which detracts slightly from his performance, overcompensates as an asset to his bold, definitive adaptation and assured direction. Additional assets are an unforgettably powerful score by Patrick Doyle and a solid surrounding cast, which includes Paul Scofield (as King Charles VI of France), Brian Blessed, Ian Holm, Judi Dench, Emma Thompson, and a young Christian Bale. Most notable among the supporting players are Robert Stephens as Auncient Pistol and Christopher Ravenscroft, who, as Montjoy, turns a messenger part into a key role through his earnest, telling reactions to both Henry and the French Dauphin.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Here is all the glory, power, drama, suspense, and intrigue the Bard intended in this rousing play.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Frederick Smith
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/3/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    There may be one hundred or so men who are capable of bringing Shakespeare to the screen, but none so talented and capable as Kenneth Branaugh. Here is all the glory, power, drama, suspense, and intrigue the Bard intended in this rousing play. Jacobi is incredible as the Chorus, a device we would call narrator, and builds his role with eloquence and tempered techniques of voice seldom seen in film. Branaugh displays a rare and insightful look at the character of the now wizened king who was so foolish as a boy. The cast, in all, is superb in their understanding of their roles and carry them off with a passion that perhaps only an Englishman can understand. I have seen this film several times, having a copy along with other versions of Shakespearean plays, and by far this is the most exciting, the most accurate, and the most palatable film of its genre. Combine a timeless tale of war and conquest with a cast already world renown and you have this film, a modern testament to the power of Shakespeare. Rated PG-13 for a violent and bloody battle, this film is fit for the high school crowd and, in my humble opinion, should be shown to every English student about to study Shakespeare.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Touch Of The Tyrant
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bkoganbing
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Some years ago I read a history of the 100 Years War and it was by a British author named Desmond Siward who advanced the notion that Henry V was one of the great tyrants in making of English history. Had it not been for his early death that's how he would have gone down in history. Thinking on it, imagine if you will how history might have regarded him had he lived another decade and had been in power for the British occupation of over half of France and had been the man in charge when Joan Of Arc was burned at the stake? When Winston Churchill gave all aid and assistance he could to Laurence Olivier;s Henry V during World War II it was to show the glory of English arms at a high point in their history. Even if it was at the expense of France whom the British were now allies with. Olivier played Henry V in true heroic mold, but in this production of Henry V, Kenneth Branagh gives Henry V a touch of the tyrant as in current historiography. This Henry V was not guided by wartime necessity, but could be closer to the truth. I did like the inclusions of those flashback scenes from Henry IV where we see merry Prince Hal cavorting with his low companions like Sir John Falstaff. Those might have been some invention of Shakespeare, but certainly the man who was Henry V was all business when he was on the throne. This newer Henry V received several Oscar nominations including one for Kenneth Branagh to match the one that Laurence Olivier got over 40 years earlier for Best Actor. It's certainly a different Henry that Branagh gives us. You can hardly see a Prince Hal in this king.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Wonderful Adaptation Of Shakespeare's Play
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    SiliconDesertMan40
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/11/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Henry V is a film based on William Shakespeare's play The Life of Henry the Fifth about the famous English king.Kenneth Branagh stars in the title role,wrote the screenplay and directed the movie.It also features Paul Scofield,Ian Holm,Emma Thompson,Alec McCowen,Judi Dench and Christian Bale. It is frequently compared with the 1944 film of the play directed by and starring Laurence Olivier. The visual style of former is grittier and more realistic than that of the latter. The movie has a narrator with the name Chrous.After the he introduces the play, young king of England Henry V begins an angry dialogue with King Charles of France. The king's son, Dauphin,insults Henry and the argument escalates into war. In flashback, Henry is seen as a young man drinking in a tavern with Falstaff, Bardolph,Nym,Pistol, and Mistress Quickly. Meanwhile, Henry and his captain, Fluellen, assemble an army and invade France. The French greatly outnumber the British troops, yet Henry leads them to victory in the Battle of Agincourt after delivering his famous St. Crispin's Day Speech. Throughout this struggle, Henry also courts Katherine and eventually wins her over. Henry V is definitely an absorbing and entertaining film for it was updated for modern viewers.It was also an energetic,passionate,and wonderfully acted as well.Apart from that,it was a triumphant adaptation of Shakespeare's play and it brought about the playwright's timeless talent and appeal.Overall,it is a wonderful film not only for the fans of Shakespeare but anyone who loves great film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Coach Henry
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    drystyx
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/8/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Henry V, according to Shakesspeare's version of History, is well directed. And well acted. Well done all around. And since Shakespeare is best read instead of seen, it works very well in closed captioning. A liar is a person who says he/she understands the words as they are quickly sent out in these plays. In truth, they cannot be deciphered by the brain at such a pace, unless they are read. Personally, I didn't care for all the dim lighting, but it made for realistic dreary castle settings, if not for distinguishing what is going on. And it works for effect, because like black and white, dim lighting helps to focus on the story and not on all the distractions. What sets this Shakespeare play apart from nearly all other dramas and films is that most films show the warrior soldier as a father figure already, finished with his battle days. Here, we have the soldier hero as a young man, before he becomes the old hero. And it is very engaging. This Henry is a very likable character, and very three dimensional. It's refreshing to see a director treat a heroine as a "trophy", the beauty to be won, and of course it was written that way. Henry becomes like the coach giving the famous gung ho half time speech. However, there is more to him than just talk. We wonder what his battle strategy will be, and we're sure he has one. Indeed, though vastly outnumbered against the French, he does use his archers in a cunning way, with a troops of swords dashing out to the foray to hold the enemy at bay and in artillery range. With their swords at about 100 yards, the archers send their artillery barrage over their heads at about 150 yards, making the French between a rock and a hard place in three ways: 1. The French in front have no healthy reinforcements 2. The French in back must work their way over bodies, or be forced back 3. The French in front get into the artillery barrage if they retreat, so they have only one direction This is the play in which the king goes out among his men incognito, by the way. We really only get a good look at Henry and a couple of others. Many of the characters are well drawn, but fleeting in their appearance.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Where's a muse of fire when you need one?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Xander Seavy (RiffRaffMcKinley)
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/4/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Derek Jacobi's wonderfully proud, winking Chorus and Patrick Doyle's interesting (but barely) score are the sole redeeming features of this early Kenneth Branagh misfire. A gritty (in a BBC sense of the word) take on Shakespeare's mostly tedious historical play, "Henry V" gives far too much power to one man in the worst way that Branagh repeated so often to such bewildering acclaim. He not only directs and, rather pretentiously, "adapts for the screen" the words of the Bard, but also plays the title character. And sadly, he is by far no Olivier. The man has talent, to be sure, but it either wasn't here yet or it had fled temporarily when he took up this triple task. The only "flat, unraised spirit" here is Branagh himself, who essays a monotonous monarch with all the emotional depth of Keanu Reeves after an all-nighter. He even fumbles his one good instinct as a filmmaker: flashing back to "Henry IV" is an excellent way to provide backstory for people who aren't too familiar with the soap opera nature of some of Shakespeare's histories (which is primarily important here for the character of Falstaff), but the technique doesn't mesh with the rest of the picture. And why keep the Chorus? He's a purely theatrical device. He's there to tell us we have to imagine that we're in France or Southampton-- a necessity of the theater, in which all you can see is a stage and what's on it, but somewhat disconcerting in a film because the entire point of a film is to show us someplace we normally wouldn't see. Did he keep the Chorus to make his job, as a director, of sustaining our illusion that much easier? Whatever the motives (and no disrespect to the vibrant Jacobi), it was not the right decision. It's a boring, slow-to-evolve adaptation of a terrible, impossible-to-read play. (I am a fan of ol' Will, but his history plays are some of the most tedious dramas ever to plague the page.) If you're a fan of the kind of epic battle scenes of films as diverse as "Platoon" and "Gladiator," you'll definitely enjoy that aspect of the movie. Action-wise, it has its moments. But after a while, you just want Branagh to stick to doing one thing. Unfortunately, he's too self-indulgent to get that idea into his head.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Definitely one of the greater adaptations off of a Shakespearean play
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jdkraus
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/4/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Kenneth Brannagh's 1989 release of Henry V is definitely one of the greater adaptations off of a Shakespearean play. What really makes this film such a success is the big production that Brannagh had when he filmed this picture. Even though the Chorus reminds the viewer that the movie is just a mere imitation, I felt like I was looking at what it was like during the early 1400s. The costumes look very real, in fact, at the 1990 Academy Awards, the film won an Oscar for Best Costume Design. The production design and sets also add a sense of authenticity to the time period. The lighting in this film is unique, for it is generally low-key, giving both a literal and a figurative sense of darkness. This no doubt helped make the movie feel all the more dramatic and intense. The actors are perfect in their roles, whether it be the insignificant or the larger-than-life characters. One actor worth noting is Brian Blessed as Exeter. His encounter with the French king and the Dauphin is thoroughly amusing to watch. He not only carries the brutish demeanor of man ready to take on the whole French army, but he speaks coolly, delivering his lines carefully and fluently, all the while staring at the French king with terrifying eyes that makes him recoil. Simply brilliant! The real master of this film though is the main star and director Kenneth Brannagh. He does not merely act as King Henry V; he becomes the man. There are many great scenes where he displays his fierceness and determination as King Henry. One that comes to mind is when Henry is given the gift of tennis balls from Francean insult of calling him immature. As he speaks, threatening invasion of France to the Dauphin, there is an enraged confidence, yet restraint in his voice. It is obvious that he is dead serious about his threat, particularly when he refers to the French prince, "his balls have turned to gun-stones". Brannagh did not shout during this scene to strike fear in the Dauphin, for he did not have to. All it takes for Brannagh is one glance to scare a ferocious bear. Brannagh also reveals sheds of brutality and violence within Henry. When he finds out that three of his close associates had betrayed him, in a fit of rage, he grabs one of them and throws him on table. Henry then grabs the man's face, as he demands why he turned traitor. Once again, this explicitly shows that Henry is not a person to be feared or to be messed with. In short, Brannagh does not merely act as King Henry V; he becomes the man. As director, he proves in knowing how to suck a viewer into a film. The choice of shots throughout the film are excellent, whether it be the close ups during the heated debates or the three-minute long tracking shot that follows Brannagh as he carries a dead boy through the aftermath of Agincourt. I consider this shot to be one of the best scenes I have ever seen in cinema. Though Brannagh's film is a Shakespearean adaptation, it stands up as its own. It is perfectly acted and directed. If Shakespeare were alive to see this, he would be thoroughly impressed.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Very well crafted
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    TheLittleSongbird
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/3/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I like Kenneth Branagh's Shakespeare films, and Henry V is one of his better ones. The play is a very good one, and this film does it justice. Visually, it is very beautiful to look at, with interesting camera angles and great scenery and costumes. The music fits each scene very well and doesn't fall into the trap of being too melodramatic. The film like the play has a fine, compelling story that makes you feel all sorts of emotions, and the dialogue is wonderful. Branagh's directorial flair has a lot of vigour to it, and the Battle of Agincourt especially is very evocatively staged. The performances are uniformly good, Branagh is particularly impressive in the title role and the supporting cast are all fine Derek Jacobi coming off best in yet another one of his great performances. Overall, very well crafted. 9/10 Bethany Cox
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    In the script it is written, and on the screen it's pictures - F. Lang
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    clwydjones
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/2/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A Good "Televised" Play (i.e. a British film) For a master class on adapting Shakespeare to cinema you need to watch Akira Kurosawa's seminal "Throne of blood". This film is entertaining, but it's not cinema it's a very long TV drama (if you liked the BBC's Robin Hood series you'll love this). For anyone who's coming to Shakespeare for the first time I'd recommend Olivier's version. It's not a 'complete' version of the play, but it has the wit, subtlety and invention missing in Branagh. Olivier is much truer to the spirit of Shakespeare - it's playful and funny in parts (for example the lovely scene where Catherine is learning English). Most importantly Olivier brings out the beauty of Shakespears words (the spine tingling soliloquy in Henry's nighttime tour of the camp?). Branagh's version is neither a film or a play. It unfortunately the throttling of language for dramatic effect. Drowned in muzak and delivered with holly-pine-wood whispers or "You slag!" shouting. And kicks the crap out of the language with odd action film stresses and punctuations. Making the whole play difficult to listen to and understand. There's nothing playful or subtle about it - it's wall to wall drama - which inevitably gets a bit tedious after a while. The lines seem to be there more for pulling faces than for pleasure. A bit like being server a steak you really wanted to tuck into, but cant as someone's covered it in tomato sauce and half a pound of salt. Although there are some funny bits e.g. Derek Jacobi doing Marty DiBergi "introduction to Spinal Tap" at the start. It's also very 80's (e.g. Branagh's hair cut) - When he's asked if he's Cornishman I half expected him to answer, "No I am from Hampstead" Derek Jacobi (with thespian scarf) on the White Cliff of Dover doing Michael Palin's Ripping Yarns "You know, I think it was G.K. Chesterton, who once said..." (Tomkinson's schooldays) Required watching I imagine for all those poor high school students who are forced to learn Shakespeare... (I award it 1 only to try and introduce some sanity to the overall rating. As an adaptation of Shakespeare - 6.5/10. As a general film - 6/10. as a serious cinematic film - 1/10)
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Powerful and Gritty Adaptation...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Janis Livens
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I'm one of those illiterate hacks who hasn't read a single Shakespeare play till the end. It's because in my country we have our own "bard" and Shakespeare's plays were glanced at best. The film itself was brilliant at times and dull at others. It works as individuals scenes perfectly but fails at being compelling narrative due many scenes that felt pointless to me. The reason why enjoyed the most of Henry V was Kenneth Branagh. His brilliant performance carried the film for me and any scene with him was a joy to watch. It's really hard to comment on the acting. The cast is brilliant from top to bottom, my favorite being Brian "Gordon's Alive!" Blessed and Ian Holm. The direction by Kenneth Branagh is worth mentioning. He clearly made Henry V as an anti-war film and it works perfectly. The aftermath of the battle is very powerful, thanks to the direction and magnificent score. But sadly, it's not without problems. The most glaring problem to me, was the pacing. Nearly every single flashback scene stopped the film to a screeching halt. And then there is the silly ending. While I did enjoy the chemistry between Emma Thompson and Kenneth Branagh, it slightly ruined the dark tone the aftermath of the battle had set. In other words, they should have cut some of the scenes out for a better flow of the narrative. Henry V is a good Shakespeare adaptation. I loved the performances by the cast and some of the brilliant set pieces of the film. But as a whole it's just watchable. If you like Shakespeare's plays this is a must see but for anyone else it's hard to recommend. Especially if your English isn't very good.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Henry V
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ShibanPD
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The greatest adaptation of a Shakespearean play to the screen, Henry V, adapted by, directed by, and starring Kenneth Branagh, bridges the gap between faithful reproduction and innovative representation in an extremely exciting, most cinematic way. Branagh has certainly done his homework, and we are the benefactors of his erudition. For the most part, he has reduced Shakespeare's text to those elements which are not only screen-worthy, but the meanings of which ride easily on tone, gesture, and action, so that Shakespeare's poetic, though metaphorically dense language presents little obstacle to the understanding of the modern ear. Remainingand out of place for such a successful transition between mediumsare unnecessary lines delivered by the Chorus (played by a fiery Derek Jacobi), which beg us to pardon the meagerness of the presentation and beseech us to use our imaginations to fill in the resulting holes. Famous lines to those familiar with the stage, but strangely redundant from within the context of a film of such high production value, grandness, and beautywith a visual and aural realization that rises to match the quality of the bard's text. On the side of embellishment, Branagh interweaves lines, characters, and scenes from parts of Henry IV, through clever flashbacks. The purpose of this device is to summon Hal's past relationships with old friends who are now his subjects, and to elucidate the duality of Hal/Henry; for Hal was not always king, and in his younger days, he caroused with commoners, drunkards, liars, and even thieves. The effectiveness of this device varies: the hanging of Bardolph draws additional emotional impact from it, but, in spite of it and several fine, heartfelt performances, the reminiscing after Falstaff's death falls flat, since we, unlike the audience of Shakespeare's time, have not come to know and love this Sir John Falstaff through Parts 1 and 2 of Henry IV and other works. Now the betrayal of Falstaff by Hal, though moderately effective in the use of this same device, is one of the most interesting scenes in the film, as it employs a flash forward within a flashback, in which we hear Hal think what he will eventually say to Falstaff, and Falstaff responds to his disavowal. Hal's transformation into Henry V is really the heart of Shakespeare's story, as it requires him to sever connections to his "wilder days" in order to lead his countrymen in worldly pursuits. Branagh's handling of it is quite remarkable. Branagh's own acting performance as the title character is smart and passionate, commanding and stirring. It does suffer slightly from that same ailment that afflicts other zealous students of Shakespeare: he knows his lines so well that they, at times, lose their spontaneity and/or authenticity. That penetrating knowledge, which detracts slightly from his performance, overcompensates as an asset to his bold, definitive adaptation and assured direction. Additional assets are an unforgettably powerful score by Patrick Doyle and a solid surrounding cast, which includes Paul Scofield (as King Charles VI of France), Brian Blessed, Ian Holm, Judi Dench, Emma Thompson, and a young Christian Bale. Most notable among the supporting players are Robert Stephens as Auncient Pistol and Christopher Ravenscroft, who, as Montjoy, turns a messenger part into a key role through his earnest, telling reactions to both Henry and the French Dauphin.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Here is all the glory, power, drama, suspense, and intrigue the Bard intended in this rousing play.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Frederick Smith
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/3/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    There may be one hundred or so men who are capable of bringing Shakespeare to the screen, but none so talented and capable as Kenneth Branaugh. Here is all the glory, power, drama, suspense, and intrigue the Bard intended in this rousing play. Jacobi is incredible as the Chorus, a device we would call narrator, and builds his role with eloquence and tempered techniques of voice seldom seen in film. Branaugh displays a rare and insightful look at the character of the now wizened king who was so foolish as a boy. The cast, in all, is superb in their understanding of their roles and carry them off with a passion that perhaps only an Englishman can understand. I have seen this film several times, having a copy along with other versions of Shakespearean plays, and by far this is the most exciting, the most accurate, and the most palatable film of its genre. Combine a timeless tale of war and conquest with a cast already world renown and you have this film, a modern testament to the power of Shakespeare. Rated PG-13 for a violent and bloody battle, this film is fit for the high school crowd and, in my humble opinion, should be shown to every English student about to study Shakespeare.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Touch Of The Tyrant
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bkoganbing
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Some years ago I read a history of the 100 Years War and it was by a British author named Desmond Siward who advanced the notion that Henry V was one of the great tyrants in making of English history. Had it not been for his early death that's how he would have gone down in history. Thinking on it, imagine if you will how history might have regarded him had he lived another decade and had been in power for the British occupation of over half of France and had been the man in charge when Joan Of Arc was burned at the stake? When Winston Churchill gave all aid and assistance he could to Laurence Olivier;s Henry V during World War II it was to show the glory of English arms at a high point in their history. Even if it was at the expense of France whom the British were now allies with. Olivier played Henry V in true heroic mold, but in this production of Henry V, Kenneth Branagh gives Henry V a touch of the tyrant as in current historiography. This Henry V was not guided by wartime necessity, but could be closer to the truth. I did like the inclusions of those flashback scenes from Henry IV where we see merry Prince Hal cavorting with his low companions like Sir John Falstaff. Those might have been some invention of Shakespeare, but certainly the man who was Henry V was all business when he was on the throne. This newer Henry V received several Oscar nominations including one for Kenneth Branagh to match the one that Laurence Olivier got over 40 years earlier for Best Actor. It's certainly a different Henry that Branagh gives us. You can hardly see a Prince Hal in this king.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Wonderful Adaptation Of Shakespeare's Play
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    SiliconDesertMan40
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/11/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Henry V is a film based on William Shakespeare's play The Life of Henry the Fifth about the famous English king.Kenneth Branagh stars in the title role,wrote the screenplay and directed the movie.It also features Paul Scofield,Ian Holm,Emma Thompson,Alec McCowen,Judi Dench and Christian Bale. It is frequently compared with the 1944 film of the play directed by and starring Laurence Olivier. The visual style of former is grittier and more realistic than that of the latter. The movie has a narrator with the name Chrous.After the he introduces the play, young king of England Henry V begins an angry dialogue with King Charles of France. The king's son, Dauphin,insults Henry and the argument escalates into war. In flashback, Henry is seen as a young man drinking in a tavern with Falstaff, Bardolph,Nym,Pistol, and Mistress Quickly. Meanwhile, Henry and his captain, Fluellen, assemble an army and invade France. The French greatly outnumber the British troops, yet Henry leads them to victory in the Battle of Agincourt after delivering his famous St. Crispin's Day Speech. Throughout this struggle, Henry also courts Katherine and eventually wins her over. Henry V is definitely an absorbing and entertaining film for it was updated for modern viewers.It was also an energetic,passionate,and wonderfully acted as well.Apart from that,it was a triumphant adaptation of Shakespeare's play and it brought about the playwright's timeless talent and appeal.Overall,it is a wonderful film not only for the fans of Shakespeare but anyone who loves great film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Coach Henry
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    drystyx
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/8/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Henry V, according to Shakesspeare's version of History, is well directed. And well acted. Well done all around. And since Shakespeare is best read instead of seen, it works very well in closed captioning. A liar is a person who says he/she understands the words as they are quickly sent out in these plays. In truth, they cannot be deciphered by the brain at such a pace, unless they are read. Personally, I didn't care for all the dim lighting, but it made for realistic dreary castle settings, if not for distinguishing what is going on. And it works for effect, because like black and white, dim lighting helps to focus on the story and not on all the distractions. What sets this Shakespeare play apart from nearly all other dramas and films is that most films show the warrior soldier as a father figure already, finished with his battle days. Here, we have the soldier hero as a young man, before he becomes the old hero. And it is very engaging. This Henry is a very likable character, and very three dimensional. It's refreshing to see a director treat a heroine as a "trophy", the beauty to be won, and of course it was written that way. Henry becomes like the coach giving the famous gung ho half time speech. However, there is more to him than just talk. We wonder what his battle strategy will be, and we're sure he has one. Indeed, though vastly outnumbered against the French, he does use his archers in a cunning way, with a troops of swords dashing out to the foray to hold the enemy at bay and in artillery range. With their swords at about 100 yards, the archers send their artillery barrage over their heads at about 150 yards, making the French between a rock and a hard place in three ways: 1. The French in front have no healthy reinforcements 2. The French in back must work their way over bodies, or be forced back 3. The French in front get into the artillery barrage if they retreat, so they have only one direction This is the play in which the king goes out among his men incognito, by the way. We really only get a good look at Henry and a couple of others. Many of the characters are well drawn, but fleeting in their appearance.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Where's a muse of fire when you need one?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Xander Seavy (RiffRaffMcKinley)
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/4/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Derek Jacobi's wonderfully proud, winking Chorus and Patrick Doyle's interesting (but barely) score are the sole redeeming features of this early Kenneth Branagh misfire. A gritty (in a BBC sense of the word) take on Shakespeare's mostly tedious historical play, "Henry V" gives far too much power to one man in the worst way that Branagh repeated so often to such bewildering acclaim. He not only directs and, rather pretentiously, "adapts for the screen" the words of the Bard, but also plays the title character. And sadly, he is by far no Olivier. The man has talent, to be sure, but it either wasn't here yet or it had fled temporarily when he took up this triple task. The only "flat, unraised spirit" here is Branagh himself, who essays a monotonous monarch with all the emotional depth of Keanu Reeves after an all-nighter. He even fumbles his one good instinct as a filmmaker: flashing back to "Henry IV" is an excellent way to provide backstory for people who aren't too familiar with the soap opera nature of some of Shakespeare's histories (which is primarily important here for the character of Falstaff), but the technique doesn't mesh with the rest of the picture. And why keep the Chorus? He's a purely theatrical device. He's there to tell us we have to imagine that we're in France or Southampton-- a necessity of the theater, in which all you can see is a stage and what's on it, but somewhat disconcerting in a film because the entire point of a film is to show us someplace we normally wouldn't see. Did he keep the Chorus to make his job, as a director, of sustaining our illusion that much easier? Whatever the motives (and no disrespect to the vibrant Jacobi), it was not the right decision. It's a boring, slow-to-evolve adaptation of a terrible, impossible-to-read play. (I am a fan of ol' Will, but his history plays are some of the most tedious dramas ever to plague the page.) If you're a fan of the kind of epic battle scenes of films as diverse as "Platoon" and "Gladiator," you'll definitely enjoy that aspect of the movie. Action-wise, it has its moments. But after a while, you just want Branagh to stick to doing one thing. Unfortunately, he's too self-indulgent to get that idea into his head.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Definitely one of the greater adaptations off of a Shakespearean play
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jdkraus
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/4/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Kenneth Brannagh's 1989 release of Henry V is definitely one of the greater adaptations off of a Shakespearean play. What really makes this film such a success is the big production that Brannagh had when he filmed this picture. Even though the Chorus reminds the viewer that the movie is just a mere imitation, I felt like I was looking at what it was like during the early 1400s. The costumes look very real, in fact, at the 1990 Academy Awards, the film won an Oscar for Best Costume Design. The production design and sets also add a sense of authenticity to the time period. The lighting in this film is unique, for it is generally low-key, giving both a literal and a figurative sense of darkness. This no doubt helped make the movie feel all the more dramatic and intense. The actors are perfect in their roles, whether it be the insignificant or the larger-than-life characters. One actor worth noting is Brian Blessed as Exeter. His encounter with the French king and the Dauphin is thoroughly amusing to watch. He not only carries the brutish demeanor of man ready to take on the whole French army, but he speaks coolly, delivering his lines carefully and fluently, all the while staring at the French king with terrifying eyes that makes him recoil. Simply brilliant! The real master of this film though is the main star and director Kenneth Brannagh. He does not merely act as King Henry V; he becomes the man. There are many great scenes where he displays his fierceness and determination as King Henry. One that comes to mind is when Henry is given the gift of tennis balls from Francean insult of calling him immature. As he speaks, threatening invasion of France to the Dauphin, there is an enraged confidence, yet restraint in his voice. It is obvious that he is dead serious about his threat, particularly when he refers to the French prince, "his balls have turned to gun-stones". Brannagh did not shout during this scene to strike fear in the Dauphin, for he did not have to. All it takes for Brannagh is one glance to scare a ferocious bear. Brannagh also reveals sheds of brutality and violence within Henry. When he finds out that three of his close associates had betrayed him, in a fit of rage, he grabs one of them and throws him on table. Henry then grabs the man's face, as he demands why he turned traitor. Once again, this explicitly shows that Henry is not a person to be feared or to be messed with. In short, Brannagh does not merely act as King Henry V; he becomes the man. As director, he proves in knowing how to suck a viewer into a film. The choice of shots throughout the film are excellent, whether it be the close ups during the heated debates or the three-minute long tracking shot that follows Brannagh as he carries a dead boy through the aftermath of Agincourt. I consider this shot to be one of the best scenes I have ever seen in cinema. Though Brannagh's film is a Shakespearean adaptation, it stands up as its own. It is perfectly acted and directed. If Shakespeare were alive to see this, he would be thoroughly impressed.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Very well crafted
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    TheLittleSongbird
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/3/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I like Kenneth Branagh's Shakespeare films, and Henry V is one of his better ones. The play is a very good one, and this film does it justice. Visually, it is very beautiful to look at, with interesting camera angles and great scenery and costumes. The music fits each scene very well and doesn't fall into the trap of being too melodramatic. The film like the play has a fine, compelling story that makes you feel all sorts of emotions, and the dialogue is wonderful. Branagh's directorial flair has a lot of vigour to it, and the Battle of Agincourt especially is very evocatively staged. The performances are uniformly good, Branagh is particularly impressive in the title role and the supporting cast are all fine Derek Jacobi coming off best in yet another one of his great performances. Overall, very well crafted. 9/10 Bethany Cox
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    In the script it is written, and on the screen it's pictures - F. Lang
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    clwydjones
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/2/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A Good "Televised" Play (i.e. a British film) For a master class on adapting Shakespeare to cinema you need to watch Akira Kurosawa's seminal "Throne of blood". This film is entertaining, but it's not cinema it's a very long TV drama (if you liked the BBC's Robin Hood series you'll love this). For anyone who's coming to Shakespeare for the first time I'd recommend Olivier's version. It's not a 'complete' version of the play, but it has the wit, subtlety and invention missing in Branagh. Olivier is much truer to the spirit of Shakespeare - it's playful and funny in parts (for example the lovely scene where Catherine is learning English). Most importantly Olivier brings out the beauty of Shakespears words (the spine tingling soliloquy in Henry's nighttime tour of the camp?). Branagh's version is neither a film or a play. It unfortunately the throttling of language for dramatic effect. Drowned in muzak and delivered with holly-pine-wood whispers or "You slag!" shouting. And kicks the crap out of the language with odd action film stresses and punctuations. Making the whole play difficult to listen to and understand. There's nothing playful or subtle about it - it's wall to wall drama - which inevitably gets a bit tedious after a while. The lines seem to be there more for pulling faces than for pleasure. A bit like being server a steak you really wanted to tuck into, but cant as someone's covered it in tomato sauce and half a pound of salt. Although there are some funny bits e.g. Derek Jacobi doing Marty DiBergi "introduction to Spinal Tap" at the start. It's also very 80's (e.g. Branagh's hair cut) - When he's asked if he's Cornishman I half expected him to answer, "No I am from Hampstead" Derek Jacobi (with thespian scarf) on the White Cliff of Dover doing Michael Palin's Ripping Yarns "You know, I think it was G.K. Chesterton, who once said..." (Tomkinson's schooldays) Required watching I imagine for all those poor high school students who are forced to learn Shakespeare... (I award it 1 only to try and introduce some sanity to the overall rating. As an adaptation of Shakespeare - 6.5/10. As a general film - 6/10. as a serious cinematic film - 1/10)
   </conteudo>
  </review>
 </reviews>
</filme>
