<filme>
 <id>
  196
 </id>
 <imdburl>
  http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0097165
 </imdburl>
 <ano>
  1989
 </ano>
 <titulo>
  Sociedade dos Poetas Mortos
 </titulo>
 <rating>
  7.9
 </rating>
 <sinopse>
  English teacher John Keating inspires his students to a love of poetry and to seize the day.
 </sinopse>
 <storyline>
  Painfully shy Todd Anderson has been sent to the school where his popular older brother was valedictorian. His room-mate, Neil, although exceedingly bright and popular, is very much under the thumb of his overbearing father. The two, along with their other friends, meet Professor Keating, their new English teacher, who tells them of the Dead Poets Society, and encourages them to go against the status quo. Each, in their own way, does this, and are changed for life.
 </storyline>
 <generos>
  <genero>
   Drama
  </genero>
 </generos>
 <keywords>
  <keyword>
   english teacher
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   teacher
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   poetry
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   student
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   poet
  </keyword>
 </keywords>
 <diretores>
  <diretor>
   Peter Weir
  </diretor>
 </diretores>
 <escritores>
  <escritor>
   Tom Schulman
  </escritor>
 </escritores>
 <atores>
  <ator>
   Robin Williams
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Robert Sean Leonard
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Ethan Hawke
  </ator>
 </atores>
 <reviews>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Ristrictive lives
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Bernardo Rapazote Flores
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    There are certain films that get under your skin, never to come out. They change your life, subtly altering your perceptions of reality, almost always for the better. Dead Poets Society is one of those and it is one of the most emotional movies I've ever seen and gets me every time and it touches everyone, specially people whose dreams are held down by their restrictive parents. This movie touches and thrills us scene after scene -- the "Oh Captain, my captain" scene (Don't you have ANYONE in your life you respect so much that you'd stand up for﻿ them in any situation, stand beside them and support them no matter what? That's what this scene is all about.), Anderson's 'speech' to its classmates, the tragic and touching ending -- crafting one of my favorite movies ever.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Rhyme and Reason
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    leonlouisricci
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It was a different World in 1959 and Teaching Conventions and Learning Institutions were Ultra Conservative, especially by Today's Standards. The Film takes place at an Uppity Prep School with Traditions not easily toppled. Enter Free Thinking Teacher Mr. Keating who is about to "Shake Rattle and Roll". This is a, dare one say it, Poetic Movie with a smooth Patina and an Off-Beat Meter. But, ironically it stays quite standard in its portrayal of Student Rebellion and is nowhere near Kerouac, Ginsberg, or The Beats. Some reference or acknowledgment of "The Movement" might have been a bit closer to the Theme here and would have given it some Street Cred. This is by the Book, pretty much, with its often visited Story and is not without Flaws. Such as the completely out of context Page Ripping Scene that is so badly thought out that it almost makes the Movie Dumb Ass. Did the Writer actually think that Censorship and Book Destruction was an apt way to illustrate Free Thinking. That is unforgivable. An overrated Film, but a Very Good one. Schools were like that, Parents were like that, it is an Inconvenient Truth. In the Decade that followed, for better or worse (mostly better), conventions would collapse, traditions would tumble, and the Lip Service given to Freedom would be challenged. In this Fictional Story, all that was a little ahead of its Time and those involved suffered, like all dissidents.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Walk to the Beat of your Own Drum
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    thedozinglion
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Carpe Diem" is the line often quoted from the 1989 film Dead Poets Society to signify making the most out of life today. However for me the real theme of the movie is better encapsulated in the quotes by Thoreau and Frost on "walking to the beat of your own drum" and "following the path less travelled". A rebellion away from conformity towards individuality. Robin Williams is cast in the role of John Keating, the idealistic new teacher at Welton Academy a conservative prep school during the late 1950s. The school is a milder version of the Bunker Hill Military Academy of TAPS (1981), exacting control through "tradition, honour, discipline and excellence". In essence an expensive factory designed to process boys into men of standing and position at the expense of their uniqueness. Keating's teaching methods allow his students to struggle against not only the school and its lifeless dogma but also family and society's convention. Unlike Kevin Kline's William Hundert in The Emperor's Club (2002), Keating is not interested in shaping the character of the boys he teaches but unlocking their potential. Early in the movie he instructs his class to rip out the antiquated Introduction to Poetry in their textbooks which looks to take the soul out of the verse and replace it with a formula for understanding. This is much like the ethos of the school itself which seeks to remove the identity of the boys to supplant it with a tried and tested docility. The two main leads are played well by the then rising stars Ethan Hawke and Robert Sean Leonard. Their forming of the Dead Poets Society being the central form of rebellion in the film, a midnight meeting group off campus, breaking school regulations while allowing the boys to read the great freethinking poets of the past and their own adolescent compositions to one another. However the true rebel in the movie is not a student but Robin William's quixotic Keating, a free-spirited thinker who challenges the autocratic system in place and give the power of thought to his students. He is the polar opposite of Michael Redgrave's Crocker-Harris in The Browning Version (1951), a man whose passion for teaching has been eroded by years of apathy from his students leading to a teacher of rote rather than reason. Keating forms the midpoint in a trilogy of non-conformist characters played by Williams over a three year period starting with army disc jockey Adrian Cronauer in Good Morning Vietnam (1987) to Dr. Malcolm Sayer in Awakenings (1990). All three fight their prevailing systems (military, academia and medicine) to aid those within it. Williams is well able to embody the radical troublemaker effectively although his schizophrenic personality is toned down in each subsequent film. He is at his best as an actor when he is not playing for laughs but using comedy to flesh out his characters and tell a story. In a memorable scene Keating takes Thoreau's quote from Walden and has the boys acts it out: "If a man loses pace with his companions, perhaps it is because he hears a different drummer. Let him step to the music which he hears, however measured, or far away." Having the self-conscious boys walk around the school courtyard in their own style forces them to have awareness of their individuality much to the disapproval of the watching headmaster. Keating in the scene also quotes Robert Frosts poem The Road Not Taken: "Two roads diverged in a wood, and I I took the one less traveled by, And that has made all the difference." These quotes perfectly represent the concept of not accepting the majority voice as the absolute truth but instead putting yourself and your beliefs at the center. For what good is life if it is half lived without creativity and freedom of choice and action. However the power of freethinking that Keating gives to his student ends in tragedy. To fight against the system and society can be difficult for those unaccustomed to it. Keating is held responsible by the school for the loss due to the fear of the parents and staff of his methods, which have unleashed the raw potential in his students. Alas, there is no Scent of a Women (1992) defiance by the students when the headmaster looks for informers against Keating, all the boys of the Dead Poet Society sign, in effect, his expulsion papers. But the final scene does give hope that these young men will grow up with more than just honour and loyalty that the school demands. They will also have a heart and mind open to their own ideas and beliefs, they will never tamely believe or do what is told them but will seek out the truth as they find it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An instant OBSESSION...Unforgettable!!!!!!!!!!!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    barendbkj
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Never in my life have I ever experienced anything like Dead Poet's Society. This is a fine example how movies should be. It should be touching, it should be funny, it should be something an outsider can be proud of. And I was...I was proud of what they accomplished, that almost decades later it can still be seen as a drama worth beating (and none has beaten it so far). The story is about a group of boys who restart an old Poets club, that was once run by their English teacher, mister John Keating. During the course of the film we are introduced to Keating's majorly uplifting influence in the lives of the boys as he urges them on to follow their dreams and to, seize the day. CARPE DIEM!!! This movie had me hooked from beginning to end. I didn't want it to end. When it was finished I let out a breath of relief as I realized I was not actually part of the fun. But it pulled me in and forced me to feel what the boys were feeling. The acting was phenomenal. The story is timeless and the lessons learned from it, I will always treasure. "Oh captain, my captain. I tip my hat to you sir. WELL DONE."
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Dead poets society
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    audhusenitzad
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie means the world to me!! I watched it for the first time a few weeks ago and I have been moved ever since. I fell in love with every character, especially Charlie Dalton, "Nuwanda". I highly recommend this movie to anyone who wants to see a film to make your feelings go crazy. Through the few scenes located in Mr. Keatings English classroom, the boys become free thinkers and poets, for example, the first scene distinguishes Mr. Keating to be called "Oh Captain My Captain". In a similar setting, Keating encourages the boys to stand up on the desk so they may look at the world in another way.The final scene in which the boys show their support for their English teacher Mr. Keating by standing up on their desks saying "Oh Captain My Captain", closes up the film excellently. This movie changed my life and I hope you're moved by it as much as I was.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Leaves of Class
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    wes-connors
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    In 1959 Delaware (as Vermont), charismatic poetry teacher Robin Williams (as John Keating) arrives to begin work at the "Welton Academy" preparatory school for boys. An alumni of the school, Mr. Williams teaches poetry with uncommon zeal. To gain attention, he demands students tear out the pages of books written by essayists with whom he does not agree. To get participation, he invites students to stand on the teacher's desk. Williams does impersonations of Marlon Brando and John Wayne. His motto is "Seize the Day," a directive made popular by novelist Saul Bellow. Yes, this class is fun... Williams teaches the "dangers of conforming," and encourages students to think for themselves. When they learn Williams belonged to a clandestine club called the "Dead Poets Society" when he was a "Welton" student, the class decides to revive the group. They meet in a cave to read poetry by the masters - but, mainly, they just goof around. Playing the saxophone and sharing "Playboy"-type centerfolds accompany Walt Whitman. Because Williams'' influence extends perilously beyond the classroom, his "unorthodox teaching methods" get the popular teacher in trouble with school administrators... This above average production won good notices and award consideration for director Peter Weir and star Robin Williams. Originally, the teacher held back a secret; "Oscar"-winning writer Tom Schulman was persuaded to drop the idea, so we and the character are left with a gap. Williams' "Keating" is put on the sidelines in favor of the students. Nothing against the actors, who perform exceptionally, but they do look more like handsome young college-aged models than typical high-school aged boys. There is some physical diversity in the extended supporting cast, though. A few of the boys wear glasses... The main stars are sensitive writer Ethan Hawke (as Todd Anderson) and his roommate, aspiring actor Robert Sean Leonard (as Neil Perry). The next tier includes prankster Gale Hansen (as Charlie Dalton) and lovelorn Josh Charles (as Knox Overstreet). Although these players are almost interchangeable, the actors create distinguishable characters. Best of the remaining parts goes to Dylan Kussman (as Richard Cameron), who perversely turns out to be the group's real non-conformist. The film is too self-consciously calculating and manipulative to be fully masterful, but it sure looks nice. ******** Dead Poets Society (6/2/89) Peter Weir ~ Robin Williams, Ethan Hawke, Robert Sean Leonard, Gale Hansen
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Young boys reading poetry during their play-time..... come onnnn.......
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Tracy Winters
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Robin Williams -- you know, I really want to like him, and in this film, I do, though I usually don't like the kinds of films he chooses to participate in ('Good Will Hunting' is by far his best role). Here's a supposedly enigmatic teacher (Williams) motivating his teenage boy students to read poetry in their leisure time. That was unbelievable. I could see them doing this if between poems, they gave each other oral sex or something, but unfortunately, that does not happen in this movie. What does happen is a predictable script by Tom Shulman. We see a plethora of different, but typical characters.... the snitch (Dylan Kussman), the rebellious kid (Gale Hanson), the charming boy (Josh Charles), and even a self-effacing young man (Ethan Hawke) who stutters until the hero of the story (Williams) gives the kid a reason to live, except when Wiliams leaves the school, the kid starts stuttering again (i.e. 'One Flew Over the Cuckoo's Nest'). So much for originality. The final scene is so sappy, you'll want to rinse out your pie-hole with mouthwash.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Much Better Than Expected!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    g-bodyl
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Dead Poets Society is a much better film than I anticipated. Honestly, I thought this would be a film all about poetry and I loathe poetry, so I didn't give this film a chance. I'm glad I did because this is not a film about poetry, but about a group of college kids who have been encouraged to follow their own dreams. This film is a well-made drama that will make you smile, laugh, and cry. It also has one of the most unexpected scenes I have seen in awhile. Peter Weir's film is about a group of college kids who are inspired by their English professor, John Keating. Keating tells his kids who follow their dreams and they do just that. Unfortunately, the dean and the parents have other ideas for their kids. Robin Williams gives a true, inspirational performance as John Keating. He is the teacher that is common nowadays, but someone my parents would yearn to have. Ethan Hawke delivers a stand out performance as one of the kids and so does Robert Sean Leonard. Overall, this is a truly inspirational film that has one simple message for all people, especially younger ones. This message is "Follow our dreams and don't let anyone tell you what you can or can't do." This message should have been used back in the 1950's-1960's. This film is well-acted, has great direction, and should leave a tear or two. I rate this film 9/10.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Inspiring and Life changing
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Melania Chaves
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Carpe Diem": Seize the day. This is the lesson, John Keating, the English schoolteacher wants to convey to his students. This movie is one of the best movies I've ever watched. It helps people to face problems and live life as if there was no tomorrow. It teaches us how to enjoy every aspect of life and let nothing ruin what makes us really happy. It is not only entertaining, but it teaches a great life lesson, which is to think for ourselves and stand up for that in which we believe. It is incomparable with other movies and should definitely be watched by everyone. Dead Poets Society was nominated for four Academy Awards. It is from the genre of drama and although it is a 1989 movie, the picture is great and the movie is so stimulating and outstanding, the picture won't even be a problem. The movie takes place in 1959 in the Welton Academy. In this school education is very strict and students are expected to behave in a highly educated and responsible manner. Several of the students have a different opinion regarding the school's education process. When the new teacher comes, everything changes. John Keating is an unconventional teacher who tells his students to tear out the pages of the books and asks his students to stand on their desks to see the world from a different perspective. He introduces the boys to poetry and teaches them new philosophies about life. He encourages his students to follow their dreams, and to not follow what people expect them to do, but what makes them happy. The characters in this film are so realistic; they create an impact in the audience. I hate movies with flat characters and in this movie the character development is really outstanding. Robin Williams plays an excellent job as the professor and interacts very well with the students. In his early life, Williams studied political science before studying theatre in the Julliard School. He later on performed in nightclubs where he was discovered for the role of Mork on the TV series "Happy Days". Another important character is Robert Leonard who plays the role of Neil Perry. He deserves acknowledgment and fame and is mostly known as Dr. James Wilson on House M.D. Ethan Hawke is another important character in the movie. He plays the role of Todd Anderson in the movie. Ethan was born on 6 November 1970 in Austin Texas. His acting career started as a mix of theatre work and a mix of serious and commercial movies. All of these actors play an excellent role in the movie. They create an exciting plot, and the move builds up perfectly. At first the movie seemed kind of boring, but as I paid more attention and it advanced it was amazing. It tells a story that nobody should miss. I talks about courage, how we should fight for what we want, and to live life to the fullest. One of my favorite scenes was when the English teacher, Mr. Keating, tells the students to tear the pages of a book apart. In every scene he is an excellent teacher, he makes the class entertaining and the students learn more than you could imagine. They do not only learn about English and poetry, but they learn about life. This movie is heartwarming; it has a full meaning, and is contains great poetry that has life lessons. I believe the most important lesson in this movie is to seize the day. This means to make out the most of each day, as if we would die tomorrow. This relates to doing what you like, what you enjoy the most in life. It is getting apart from what society expects from you, and doing what makes you happy. Another important lesson is to be you. We live in a society in which everyone expects something from you, but the most important thing is to be your own self. It will help in mental and spiritual growth. Challenging the status quo is another lesson. Change the way to see life, make a change in the world, in people. One last lesson is to stand up for others. This will not only be beneficial for the people you help but it will help you feel better. I believe everyone who watches the movie should enjoy it. I would recommend it to anyone who wants to watch it but especially for people above 13 years. This is because someone younger than this will maybe not understand well the meaning of the movie and will think it is boring. I would rate the movie PG-13. This movie is as great as the Oscar Winning movie "The Help". Both movies are delightfully different. In "The Help", as well as in "Dead Poets Society", the characters play an excellent role and the plot is entertaining and fun. Along the movie you will not get bored, it catches the audience's attention due to the fact that they treat interesting subjects. They are memorable movies, that once you watch them you will never forget the lesson and it will change your life. Both teach a wonderful lesson that everyone should take into account in their daily lives. Rating 8.7 The criticizer of this movie is Melania Chaves. She is an eleventh grade student at Lincoln School, Costa Rica. She is seventeen years old and will graduate next year from high school. She enjoys watching movies and hanging out with her friends. Her hobbies are playing tennis, running, and playing piano. Carpe Diem!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Dead Poets Society
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    HG Englisch AG
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Dead Poets Society"  A film that makes you think about your dreams and your decisions in life. Good or bad decisions "Carpe Diem  Seize the day." This statement is made by Mr. Keating, the special and unique teacher of "Welton Academy". After he had taught his students the sense of "Carpe Diem" and poetry, the way of thinking of many students changed and some of them started to finish what Mr. Keating had begun when he was at the same age. If you are looking for a film to watch it in class, you should have a look at "Dead Poets Society". It's a 1986 drama film which is directed by Peter Weir and is set at the "Welton Academy" in Vermont. It deals with the teacher Mr Keating who inspires his students with his special view of life and so they build a group called "Dead Poets Society". They meet each other at a cave near the school where they talk about poetry to express themselves. The cave scenes are very amusing and show the boys in funny situations during the meetings. The "new Dead Poets Society" consists of quite different personalities: Neil Perry, the self-confident founder of the group, the shy Todd Anderson, the noisy Richard Cameron, Steven Meeks, the clever one, Charlie Dalton and last but not least Knox Overstreet, a very friendly and polite student. You may find it easy to identify with one of the young boys because of the interesting characters. They can surprise you in different ways and can also make you laugh. If I was asked to rate this film on a scale from 0  10, I would give it 7 points as the film is easy to understand and all elements, which make life worth it like love, friendship or disagreement, are included. It's a classic with a shocking and unexpected ending.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Ristrictive lives
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Bernardo Rapazote Flores
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    There are certain films that get under your skin, never to come out. They change your life, subtly altering your perceptions of reality, almost always for the better. Dead Poets Society is one of those and it is one of the most emotional movies I've ever seen and gets me every time and it touches everyone, specially people whose dreams are held down by their restrictive parents. This movie touches and thrills us scene after scene -- the "Oh Captain, my captain" scene (Don't you have ANYONE in your life you respect so much that you'd stand up for﻿ them in any situation, stand beside them and support them no matter what? That's what this scene is all about.), Anderson's 'speech' to its classmates, the tragic and touching ending -- crafting one of my favorite movies ever.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Rhyme and Reason
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    leonlouisricci
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It was a different World in 1959 and Teaching Conventions and Learning Institutions were Ultra Conservative, especially by Today's Standards. The Film takes place at an Uppity Prep School with Traditions not easily toppled. Enter Free Thinking Teacher Mr. Keating who is about to "Shake Rattle and Roll". This is a, dare one say it, Poetic Movie with a smooth Patina and an Off-Beat Meter. But, ironically it stays quite standard in its portrayal of Student Rebellion and is nowhere near Kerouac, Ginsberg, or The Beats. Some reference or acknowledgment of "The Movement" might have been a bit closer to the Theme here and would have given it some Street Cred. This is by the Book, pretty much, with its often visited Story and is not without Flaws. Such as the completely out of context Page Ripping Scene that is so badly thought out that it almost makes the Movie Dumb Ass. Did the Writer actually think that Censorship and Book Destruction was an apt way to illustrate Free Thinking. That is unforgivable. An overrated Film, but a Very Good one. Schools were like that, Parents were like that, it is an Inconvenient Truth. In the Decade that followed, for better or worse (mostly better), conventions would collapse, traditions would tumble, and the Lip Service given to Freedom would be challenged. In this Fictional Story, all that was a little ahead of its Time and those involved suffered, like all dissidents.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Walk to the Beat of your Own Drum
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    thedozinglion
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Carpe Diem" is the line often quoted from the 1989 film Dead Poets Society to signify making the most out of life today. However for me the real theme of the movie is better encapsulated in the quotes by Thoreau and Frost on "walking to the beat of your own drum" and "following the path less travelled". A rebellion away from conformity towards individuality. Robin Williams is cast in the role of John Keating, the idealistic new teacher at Welton Academy a conservative prep school during the late 1950s. The school is a milder version of the Bunker Hill Military Academy of TAPS (1981), exacting control through "tradition, honour, discipline and excellence". In essence an expensive factory designed to process boys into men of standing and position at the expense of their uniqueness. Keating's teaching methods allow his students to struggle against not only the school and its lifeless dogma but also family and society's convention. Unlike Kevin Kline's William Hundert in The Emperor's Club (2002), Keating is not interested in shaping the character of the boys he teaches but unlocking their potential. Early in the movie he instructs his class to rip out the antiquated Introduction to Poetry in their textbooks which looks to take the soul out of the verse and replace it with a formula for understanding. This is much like the ethos of the school itself which seeks to remove the identity of the boys to supplant it with a tried and tested docility. The two main leads are played well by the then rising stars Ethan Hawke and Robert Sean Leonard. Their forming of the Dead Poets Society being the central form of rebellion in the film, a midnight meeting group off campus, breaking school regulations while allowing the boys to read the great freethinking poets of the past and their own adolescent compositions to one another. However the true rebel in the movie is not a student but Robin William's quixotic Keating, a free-spirited thinker who challenges the autocratic system in place and give the power of thought to his students. He is the polar opposite of Michael Redgrave's Crocker-Harris in The Browning Version (1951), a man whose passion for teaching has been eroded by years of apathy from his students leading to a teacher of rote rather than reason. Keating forms the midpoint in a trilogy of non-conformist characters played by Williams over a three year period starting with army disc jockey Adrian Cronauer in Good Morning Vietnam (1987) to Dr. Malcolm Sayer in Awakenings (1990). All three fight their prevailing systems (military, academia and medicine) to aid those within it. Williams is well able to embody the radical troublemaker effectively although his schizophrenic personality is toned down in each subsequent film. He is at his best as an actor when he is not playing for laughs but using comedy to flesh out his characters and tell a story. In a memorable scene Keating takes Thoreau's quote from Walden and has the boys acts it out: "If a man loses pace with his companions, perhaps it is because he hears a different drummer. Let him step to the music which he hears, however measured, or far away." Having the self-conscious boys walk around the school courtyard in their own style forces them to have awareness of their individuality much to the disapproval of the watching headmaster. Keating in the scene also quotes Robert Frosts poem The Road Not Taken: "Two roads diverged in a wood, and I I took the one less traveled by, And that has made all the difference." These quotes perfectly represent the concept of not accepting the majority voice as the absolute truth but instead putting yourself and your beliefs at the center. For what good is life if it is half lived without creativity and freedom of choice and action. However the power of freethinking that Keating gives to his student ends in tragedy. To fight against the system and society can be difficult for those unaccustomed to it. Keating is held responsible by the school for the loss due to the fear of the parents and staff of his methods, which have unleashed the raw potential in his students. Alas, there is no Scent of a Women (1992) defiance by the students when the headmaster looks for informers against Keating, all the boys of the Dead Poet Society sign, in effect, his expulsion papers. But the final scene does give hope that these young men will grow up with more than just honour and loyalty that the school demands. They will also have a heart and mind open to their own ideas and beliefs, they will never tamely believe or do what is told them but will seek out the truth as they find it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An instant OBSESSION...Unforgettable!!!!!!!!!!!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    barendbkj
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Never in my life have I ever experienced anything like Dead Poet's Society. This is a fine example how movies should be. It should be touching, it should be funny, it should be something an outsider can be proud of. And I was...I was proud of what they accomplished, that almost decades later it can still be seen as a drama worth beating (and none has beaten it so far). The story is about a group of boys who restart an old Poets club, that was once run by their English teacher, mister John Keating. During the course of the film we are introduced to Keating's majorly uplifting influence in the lives of the boys as he urges them on to follow their dreams and to, seize the day. CARPE DIEM!!! This movie had me hooked from beginning to end. I didn't want it to end. When it was finished I let out a breath of relief as I realized I was not actually part of the fun. But it pulled me in and forced me to feel what the boys were feeling. The acting was phenomenal. The story is timeless and the lessons learned from it, I will always treasure. "Oh captain, my captain. I tip my hat to you sir. WELL DONE."
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Dead poets society
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    audhusenitzad
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie means the world to me!! I watched it for the first time a few weeks ago and I have been moved ever since. I fell in love with every character, especially Charlie Dalton, "Nuwanda". I highly recommend this movie to anyone who wants to see a film to make your feelings go crazy. Through the few scenes located in Mr. Keatings English classroom, the boys become free thinkers and poets, for example, the first scene distinguishes Mr. Keating to be called "Oh Captain My Captain". In a similar setting, Keating encourages the boys to stand up on the desk so they may look at the world in another way.The final scene in which the boys show their support for their English teacher Mr. Keating by standing up on their desks saying "Oh Captain My Captain", closes up the film excellently. This movie changed my life and I hope you're moved by it as much as I was.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Leaves of Class
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    wes-connors
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    In 1959 Delaware (as Vermont), charismatic poetry teacher Robin Williams (as John Keating) arrives to begin work at the "Welton Academy" preparatory school for boys. An alumni of the school, Mr. Williams teaches poetry with uncommon zeal. To gain attention, he demands students tear out the pages of books written by essayists with whom he does not agree. To get participation, he invites students to stand on the teacher's desk. Williams does impersonations of Marlon Brando and John Wayne. His motto is "Seize the Day," a directive made popular by novelist Saul Bellow. Yes, this class is fun... Williams teaches the "dangers of conforming," and encourages students to think for themselves. When they learn Williams belonged to a clandestine club called the "Dead Poets Society" when he was a "Welton" student, the class decides to revive the group. They meet in a cave to read poetry by the masters - but, mainly, they just goof around. Playing the saxophone and sharing "Playboy"-type centerfolds accompany Walt Whitman. Because Williams'' influence extends perilously beyond the classroom, his "unorthodox teaching methods" get the popular teacher in trouble with school administrators... This above average production won good notices and award consideration for director Peter Weir and star Robin Williams. Originally, the teacher held back a secret; "Oscar"-winning writer Tom Schulman was persuaded to drop the idea, so we and the character are left with a gap. Williams' "Keating" is put on the sidelines in favor of the students. Nothing against the actors, who perform exceptionally, but they do look more like handsome young college-aged models than typical high-school aged boys. There is some physical diversity in the extended supporting cast, though. A few of the boys wear glasses... The main stars are sensitive writer Ethan Hawke (as Todd Anderson) and his roommate, aspiring actor Robert Sean Leonard (as Neil Perry). The next tier includes prankster Gale Hansen (as Charlie Dalton) and lovelorn Josh Charles (as Knox Overstreet). Although these players are almost interchangeable, the actors create distinguishable characters. Best of the remaining parts goes to Dylan Kussman (as Richard Cameron), who perversely turns out to be the group's real non-conformist. The film is too self-consciously calculating and manipulative to be fully masterful, but it sure looks nice. ******** Dead Poets Society (6/2/89) Peter Weir ~ Robin Williams, Ethan Hawke, Robert Sean Leonard, Gale Hansen
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Young boys reading poetry during their play-time..... come onnnn.......
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Tracy Winters
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Robin Williams -- you know, I really want to like him, and in this film, I do, though I usually don't like the kinds of films he chooses to participate in ('Good Will Hunting' is by far his best role). Here's a supposedly enigmatic teacher (Williams) motivating his teenage boy students to read poetry in their leisure time. That was unbelievable. I could see them doing this if between poems, they gave each other oral sex or something, but unfortunately, that does not happen in this movie. What does happen is a predictable script by Tom Shulman. We see a plethora of different, but typical characters.... the snitch (Dylan Kussman), the rebellious kid (Gale Hanson), the charming boy (Josh Charles), and even a self-effacing young man (Ethan Hawke) who stutters until the hero of the story (Williams) gives the kid a reason to live, except when Wiliams leaves the school, the kid starts stuttering again (i.e. 'One Flew Over the Cuckoo's Nest'). So much for originality. The final scene is so sappy, you'll want to rinse out your pie-hole with mouthwash.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Much Better Than Expected!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    g-bodyl
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Dead Poets Society is a much better film than I anticipated. Honestly, I thought this would be a film all about poetry and I loathe poetry, so I didn't give this film a chance. I'm glad I did because this is not a film about poetry, but about a group of college kids who have been encouraged to follow their own dreams. This film is a well-made drama that will make you smile, laugh, and cry. It also has one of the most unexpected scenes I have seen in awhile. Peter Weir's film is about a group of college kids who are inspired by their English professor, John Keating. Keating tells his kids who follow their dreams and they do just that. Unfortunately, the dean and the parents have other ideas for their kids. Robin Williams gives a true, inspirational performance as John Keating. He is the teacher that is common nowadays, but someone my parents would yearn to have. Ethan Hawke delivers a stand out performance as one of the kids and so does Robert Sean Leonard. Overall, this is a truly inspirational film that has one simple message for all people, especially younger ones. This message is "Follow our dreams and don't let anyone tell you what you can or can't do." This message should have been used back in the 1950's-1960's. This film is well-acted, has great direction, and should leave a tear or two. I rate this film 9/10.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Inspiring and Life changing
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Melania Chaves
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Carpe Diem": Seize the day. This is the lesson, John Keating, the English schoolteacher wants to convey to his students. This movie is one of the best movies I've ever watched. It helps people to face problems and live life as if there was no tomorrow. It teaches us how to enjoy every aspect of life and let nothing ruin what makes us really happy. It is not only entertaining, but it teaches a great life lesson, which is to think for ourselves and stand up for that in which we believe. It is incomparable with other movies and should definitely be watched by everyone. Dead Poets Society was nominated for four Academy Awards. It is from the genre of drama and although it is a 1989 movie, the picture is great and the movie is so stimulating and outstanding, the picture won't even be a problem. The movie takes place in 1959 in the Welton Academy. In this school education is very strict and students are expected to behave in a highly educated and responsible manner. Several of the students have a different opinion regarding the school's education process. When the new teacher comes, everything changes. John Keating is an unconventional teacher who tells his students to tear out the pages of the books and asks his students to stand on their desks to see the world from a different perspective. He introduces the boys to poetry and teaches them new philosophies about life. He encourages his students to follow their dreams, and to not follow what people expect them to do, but what makes them happy. The characters in this film are so realistic; they create an impact in the audience. I hate movies with flat characters and in this movie the character development is really outstanding. Robin Williams plays an excellent job as the professor and interacts very well with the students. In his early life, Williams studied political science before studying theatre in the Julliard School. He later on performed in nightclubs where he was discovered for the role of Mork on the TV series "Happy Days". Another important character is Robert Leonard who plays the role of Neil Perry. He deserves acknowledgment and fame and is mostly known as Dr. James Wilson on House M.D. Ethan Hawke is another important character in the movie. He plays the role of Todd Anderson in the movie. Ethan was born on 6 November 1970 in Austin Texas. His acting career started as a mix of theatre work and a mix of serious and commercial movies. All of these actors play an excellent role in the movie. They create an exciting plot, and the move builds up perfectly. At first the movie seemed kind of boring, but as I paid more attention and it advanced it was amazing. It tells a story that nobody should miss. I talks about courage, how we should fight for what we want, and to live life to the fullest. One of my favorite scenes was when the English teacher, Mr. Keating, tells the students to tear the pages of a book apart. In every scene he is an excellent teacher, he makes the class entertaining and the students learn more than you could imagine. They do not only learn about English and poetry, but they learn about life. This movie is heartwarming; it has a full meaning, and is contains great poetry that has life lessons. I believe the most important lesson in this movie is to seize the day. This means to make out the most of each day, as if we would die tomorrow. This relates to doing what you like, what you enjoy the most in life. It is getting apart from what society expects from you, and doing what makes you happy. Another important lesson is to be you. We live in a society in which everyone expects something from you, but the most important thing is to be your own self. It will help in mental and spiritual growth. Challenging the status quo is another lesson. Change the way to see life, make a change in the world, in people. One last lesson is to stand up for others. This will not only be beneficial for the people you help but it will help you feel better. I believe everyone who watches the movie should enjoy it. I would recommend it to anyone who wants to watch it but especially for people above 13 years. This is because someone younger than this will maybe not understand well the meaning of the movie and will think it is boring. I would rate the movie PG-13. This movie is as great as the Oscar Winning movie "The Help". Both movies are delightfully different. In "The Help", as well as in "Dead Poets Society", the characters play an excellent role and the plot is entertaining and fun. Along the movie you will not get bored, it catches the audience's attention due to the fact that they treat interesting subjects. They are memorable movies, that once you watch them you will never forget the lesson and it will change your life. Both teach a wonderful lesson that everyone should take into account in their daily lives. Rating 8.7 The criticizer of this movie is Melania Chaves. She is an eleventh grade student at Lincoln School, Costa Rica. She is seventeen years old and will graduate next year from high school. She enjoys watching movies and hanging out with her friends. Her hobbies are playing tennis, running, and playing piano. Carpe Diem!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Dead Poets Society
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    HG Englisch AG
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Dead Poets Society"  A film that makes you think about your dreams and your decisions in life. Good or bad decisions "Carpe Diem  Seize the day." This statement is made by Mr. Keating, the special and unique teacher of "Welton Academy". After he had taught his students the sense of "Carpe Diem" and poetry, the way of thinking of many students changed and some of them started to finish what Mr. Keating had begun when he was at the same age. If you are looking for a film to watch it in class, you should have a look at "Dead Poets Society". It's a 1986 drama film which is directed by Peter Weir and is set at the "Welton Academy" in Vermont. It deals with the teacher Mr Keating who inspires his students with his special view of life and so they build a group called "Dead Poets Society". They meet each other at a cave near the school where they talk about poetry to express themselves. The cave scenes are very amusing and show the boys in funny situations during the meetings. The "new Dead Poets Society" consists of quite different personalities: Neil Perry, the self-confident founder of the group, the shy Todd Anderson, the noisy Richard Cameron, Steven Meeks, the clever one, Charlie Dalton and last but not least Knox Overstreet, a very friendly and polite student. You may find it easy to identify with one of the young boys because of the interesting characters. They can surprise you in different ways and can also make you laugh. If I was asked to rate this film on a scale from 0  10, I would give it 7 points as the film is easy to understand and all elements, which make life worth it like love, friendship or disagreement, are included. It's a classic with a shocking and unexpected ending.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Ristrictive lives
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Bernardo Rapazote Flores
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    There are certain films that get under your skin, never to come out. They change your life, subtly altering your perceptions of reality, almost always for the better. Dead Poets Society is one of those and it is one of the most emotional movies I've ever seen and gets me every time and it touches everyone, specially people whose dreams are held down by their restrictive parents. This movie touches and thrills us scene after scene -- the "Oh Captain, my captain" scene (Don't you have ANYONE in your life you respect so much that you'd stand up for﻿ them in any situation, stand beside them and support them no matter what? That's what this scene is all about.), Anderson's 'speech' to its classmates, the tragic and touching ending -- crafting one of my favorite movies ever.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Rhyme and Reason
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    leonlouisricci
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It was a different World in 1959 and Teaching Conventions and Learning Institutions were Ultra Conservative, especially by Today's Standards. The Film takes place at an Uppity Prep School with Traditions not easily toppled. Enter Free Thinking Teacher Mr. Keating who is about to "Shake Rattle and Roll". This is a, dare one say it, Poetic Movie with a smooth Patina and an Off-Beat Meter. But, ironically it stays quite standard in its portrayal of Student Rebellion and is nowhere near Kerouac, Ginsberg, or The Beats. Some reference or acknowledgment of "The Movement" might have been a bit closer to the Theme here and would have given it some Street Cred. This is by the Book, pretty much, with its often visited Story and is not without Flaws. Such as the completely out of context Page Ripping Scene that is so badly thought out that it almost makes the Movie Dumb Ass. Did the Writer actually think that Censorship and Book Destruction was an apt way to illustrate Free Thinking. That is unforgivable. An overrated Film, but a Very Good one. Schools were like that, Parents were like that, it is an Inconvenient Truth. In the Decade that followed, for better or worse (mostly better), conventions would collapse, traditions would tumble, and the Lip Service given to Freedom would be challenged. In this Fictional Story, all that was a little ahead of its Time and those involved suffered, like all dissidents.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Walk to the Beat of your Own Drum
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    thedozinglion
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Carpe Diem" is the line often quoted from the 1989 film Dead Poets Society to signify making the most out of life today. However for me the real theme of the movie is better encapsulated in the quotes by Thoreau and Frost on "walking to the beat of your own drum" and "following the path less travelled". A rebellion away from conformity towards individuality. Robin Williams is cast in the role of John Keating, the idealistic new teacher at Welton Academy a conservative prep school during the late 1950s. The school is a milder version of the Bunker Hill Military Academy of TAPS (1981), exacting control through "tradition, honour, discipline and excellence". In essence an expensive factory designed to process boys into men of standing and position at the expense of their uniqueness. Keating's teaching methods allow his students to struggle against not only the school and its lifeless dogma but also family and society's convention. Unlike Kevin Kline's William Hundert in The Emperor's Club (2002), Keating is not interested in shaping the character of the boys he teaches but unlocking their potential. Early in the movie he instructs his class to rip out the antiquated Introduction to Poetry in their textbooks which looks to take the soul out of the verse and replace it with a formula for understanding. This is much like the ethos of the school itself which seeks to remove the identity of the boys to supplant it with a tried and tested docility. The two main leads are played well by the then rising stars Ethan Hawke and Robert Sean Leonard. Their forming of the Dead Poets Society being the central form of rebellion in the film, a midnight meeting group off campus, breaking school regulations while allowing the boys to read the great freethinking poets of the past and their own adolescent compositions to one another. However the true rebel in the movie is not a student but Robin William's quixotic Keating, a free-spirited thinker who challenges the autocratic system in place and give the power of thought to his students. He is the polar opposite of Michael Redgrave's Crocker-Harris in The Browning Version (1951), a man whose passion for teaching has been eroded by years of apathy from his students leading to a teacher of rote rather than reason. Keating forms the midpoint in a trilogy of non-conformist characters played by Williams over a three year period starting with army disc jockey Adrian Cronauer in Good Morning Vietnam (1987) to Dr. Malcolm Sayer in Awakenings (1990). All three fight their prevailing systems (military, academia and medicine) to aid those within it. Williams is well able to embody the radical troublemaker effectively although his schizophrenic personality is toned down in each subsequent film. He is at his best as an actor when he is not playing for laughs but using comedy to flesh out his characters and tell a story. In a memorable scene Keating takes Thoreau's quote from Walden and has the boys acts it out: "If a man loses pace with his companions, perhaps it is because he hears a different drummer. Let him step to the music which he hears, however measured, or far away." Having the self-conscious boys walk around the school courtyard in their own style forces them to have awareness of their individuality much to the disapproval of the watching headmaster. Keating in the scene also quotes Robert Frosts poem The Road Not Taken: "Two roads diverged in a wood, and I I took the one less traveled by, And that has made all the difference." These quotes perfectly represent the concept of not accepting the majority voice as the absolute truth but instead putting yourself and your beliefs at the center. For what good is life if it is half lived without creativity and freedom of choice and action. However the power of freethinking that Keating gives to his student ends in tragedy. To fight against the system and society can be difficult for those unaccustomed to it. Keating is held responsible by the school for the loss due to the fear of the parents and staff of his methods, which have unleashed the raw potential in his students. Alas, there is no Scent of a Women (1992) defiance by the students when the headmaster looks for informers against Keating, all the boys of the Dead Poet Society sign, in effect, his expulsion papers. But the final scene does give hope that these young men will grow up with more than just honour and loyalty that the school demands. They will also have a heart and mind open to their own ideas and beliefs, they will never tamely believe or do what is told them but will seek out the truth as they find it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An instant OBSESSION...Unforgettable!!!!!!!!!!!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    barendbkj
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Never in my life have I ever experienced anything like Dead Poet's Society. This is a fine example how movies should be. It should be touching, it should be funny, it should be something an outsider can be proud of. And I was...I was proud of what they accomplished, that almost decades later it can still be seen as a drama worth beating (and none has beaten it so far). The story is about a group of boys who restart an old Poets club, that was once run by their English teacher, mister John Keating. During the course of the film we are introduced to Keating's majorly uplifting influence in the lives of the boys as he urges them on to follow their dreams and to, seize the day. CARPE DIEM!!! This movie had me hooked from beginning to end. I didn't want it to end. When it was finished I let out a breath of relief as I realized I was not actually part of the fun. But it pulled me in and forced me to feel what the boys were feeling. The acting was phenomenal. The story is timeless and the lessons learned from it, I will always treasure. "Oh captain, my captain. I tip my hat to you sir. WELL DONE."
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Dead poets society
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    audhusenitzad
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie means the world to me!! I watched it for the first time a few weeks ago and I have been moved ever since. I fell in love with every character, especially Charlie Dalton, "Nuwanda". I highly recommend this movie to anyone who wants to see a film to make your feelings go crazy. Through the few scenes located in Mr. Keatings English classroom, the boys become free thinkers and poets, for example, the first scene distinguishes Mr. Keating to be called "Oh Captain My Captain". In a similar setting, Keating encourages the boys to stand up on the desk so they may look at the world in another way.The final scene in which the boys show their support for their English teacher Mr. Keating by standing up on their desks saying "Oh Captain My Captain", closes up the film excellently. This movie changed my life and I hope you're moved by it as much as I was.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Leaves of Class
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    wes-connors
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    In 1959 Delaware (as Vermont), charismatic poetry teacher Robin Williams (as John Keating) arrives to begin work at the "Welton Academy" preparatory school for boys. An alumni of the school, Mr. Williams teaches poetry with uncommon zeal. To gain attention, he demands students tear out the pages of books written by essayists with whom he does not agree. To get participation, he invites students to stand on the teacher's desk. Williams does impersonations of Marlon Brando and John Wayne. His motto is "Seize the Day," a directive made popular by novelist Saul Bellow. Yes, this class is fun... Williams teaches the "dangers of conforming," and encourages students to think for themselves. When they learn Williams belonged to a clandestine club called the "Dead Poets Society" when he was a "Welton" student, the class decides to revive the group. They meet in a cave to read poetry by the masters - but, mainly, they just goof around. Playing the saxophone and sharing "Playboy"-type centerfolds accompany Walt Whitman. Because Williams'' influence extends perilously beyond the classroom, his "unorthodox teaching methods" get the popular teacher in trouble with school administrators... This above average production won good notices and award consideration for director Peter Weir and star Robin Williams. Originally, the teacher held back a secret; "Oscar"-winning writer Tom Schulman was persuaded to drop the idea, so we and the character are left with a gap. Williams' "Keating" is put on the sidelines in favor of the students. Nothing against the actors, who perform exceptionally, but they do look more like handsome young college-aged models than typical high-school aged boys. There is some physical diversity in the extended supporting cast, though. A few of the boys wear glasses... The main stars are sensitive writer Ethan Hawke (as Todd Anderson) and his roommate, aspiring actor Robert Sean Leonard (as Neil Perry). The next tier includes prankster Gale Hansen (as Charlie Dalton) and lovelorn Josh Charles (as Knox Overstreet). Although these players are almost interchangeable, the actors create distinguishable characters. Best of the remaining parts goes to Dylan Kussman (as Richard Cameron), who perversely turns out to be the group's real non-conformist. The film is too self-consciously calculating and manipulative to be fully masterful, but it sure looks nice. ******** Dead Poets Society (6/2/89) Peter Weir ~ Robin Williams, Ethan Hawke, Robert Sean Leonard, Gale Hansen
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Young boys reading poetry during their play-time..... come onnnn.......
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Tracy Winters
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Robin Williams -- you know, I really want to like him, and in this film, I do, though I usually don't like the kinds of films he chooses to participate in ('Good Will Hunting' is by far his best role). Here's a supposedly enigmatic teacher (Williams) motivating his teenage boy students to read poetry in their leisure time. That was unbelievable. I could see them doing this if between poems, they gave each other oral sex or something, but unfortunately, that does not happen in this movie. What does happen is a predictable script by Tom Shulman. We see a plethora of different, but typical characters.... the snitch (Dylan Kussman), the rebellious kid (Gale Hanson), the charming boy (Josh Charles), and even a self-effacing young man (Ethan Hawke) who stutters until the hero of the story (Williams) gives the kid a reason to live, except when Wiliams leaves the school, the kid starts stuttering again (i.e. 'One Flew Over the Cuckoo's Nest'). So much for originality. The final scene is so sappy, you'll want to rinse out your pie-hole with mouthwash.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Much Better Than Expected!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    g-bodyl
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Dead Poets Society is a much better film than I anticipated. Honestly, I thought this would be a film all about poetry and I loathe poetry, so I didn't give this film a chance. I'm glad I did because this is not a film about poetry, but about a group of college kids who have been encouraged to follow their own dreams. This film is a well-made drama that will make you smile, laugh, and cry. It also has one of the most unexpected scenes I have seen in awhile. Peter Weir's film is about a group of college kids who are inspired by their English professor, John Keating. Keating tells his kids who follow their dreams and they do just that. Unfortunately, the dean and the parents have other ideas for their kids. Robin Williams gives a true, inspirational performance as John Keating. He is the teacher that is common nowadays, but someone my parents would yearn to have. Ethan Hawke delivers a stand out performance as one of the kids and so does Robert Sean Leonard. Overall, this is a truly inspirational film that has one simple message for all people, especially younger ones. This message is "Follow our dreams and don't let anyone tell you what you can or can't do." This message should have been used back in the 1950's-1960's. This film is well-acted, has great direction, and should leave a tear or two. I rate this film 9/10.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Inspiring and Life changing
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Melania Chaves
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Carpe Diem": Seize the day. This is the lesson, John Keating, the English schoolteacher wants to convey to his students. This movie is one of the best movies I've ever watched. It helps people to face problems and live life as if there was no tomorrow. It teaches us how to enjoy every aspect of life and let nothing ruin what makes us really happy. It is not only entertaining, but it teaches a great life lesson, which is to think for ourselves and stand up for that in which we believe. It is incomparable with other movies and should definitely be watched by everyone. Dead Poets Society was nominated for four Academy Awards. It is from the genre of drama and although it is a 1989 movie, the picture is great and the movie is so stimulating and outstanding, the picture won't even be a problem. The movie takes place in 1959 in the Welton Academy. In this school education is very strict and students are expected to behave in a highly educated and responsible manner. Several of the students have a different opinion regarding the school's education process. When the new teacher comes, everything changes. John Keating is an unconventional teacher who tells his students to tear out the pages of the books and asks his students to stand on their desks to see the world from a different perspective. He introduces the boys to poetry and teaches them new philosophies about life. He encourages his students to follow their dreams, and to not follow what people expect them to do, but what makes them happy. The characters in this film are so realistic; they create an impact in the audience. I hate movies with flat characters and in this movie the character development is really outstanding. Robin Williams plays an excellent job as the professor and interacts very well with the students. In his early life, Williams studied political science before studying theatre in the Julliard School. He later on performed in nightclubs where he was discovered for the role of Mork on the TV series "Happy Days". Another important character is Robert Leonard who plays the role of Neil Perry. He deserves acknowledgment and fame and is mostly known as Dr. James Wilson on House M.D. Ethan Hawke is another important character in the movie. He plays the role of Todd Anderson in the movie. Ethan was born on 6 November 1970 in Austin Texas. His acting career started as a mix of theatre work and a mix of serious and commercial movies. All of these actors play an excellent role in the movie. They create an exciting plot, and the move builds up perfectly. At first the movie seemed kind of boring, but as I paid more attention and it advanced it was amazing. It tells a story that nobody should miss. I talks about courage, how we should fight for what we want, and to live life to the fullest. One of my favorite scenes was when the English teacher, Mr. Keating, tells the students to tear the pages of a book apart. In every scene he is an excellent teacher, he makes the class entertaining and the students learn more than you could imagine. They do not only learn about English and poetry, but they learn about life. This movie is heartwarming; it has a full meaning, and is contains great poetry that has life lessons. I believe the most important lesson in this movie is to seize the day. This means to make out the most of each day, as if we would die tomorrow. This relates to doing what you like, what you enjoy the most in life. It is getting apart from what society expects from you, and doing what makes you happy. Another important lesson is to be you. We live in a society in which everyone expects something from you, but the most important thing is to be your own self. It will help in mental and spiritual growth. Challenging the status quo is another lesson. Change the way to see life, make a change in the world, in people. One last lesson is to stand up for others. This will not only be beneficial for the people you help but it will help you feel better. I believe everyone who watches the movie should enjoy it. I would recommend it to anyone who wants to watch it but especially for people above 13 years. This is because someone younger than this will maybe not understand well the meaning of the movie and will think it is boring. I would rate the movie PG-13. This movie is as great as the Oscar Winning movie "The Help". Both movies are delightfully different. In "The Help", as well as in "Dead Poets Society", the characters play an excellent role and the plot is entertaining and fun. Along the movie you will not get bored, it catches the audience's attention due to the fact that they treat interesting subjects. They are memorable movies, that once you watch them you will never forget the lesson and it will change your life. Both teach a wonderful lesson that everyone should take into account in their daily lives. Rating 8.7 The criticizer of this movie is Melania Chaves. She is an eleventh grade student at Lincoln School, Costa Rica. She is seventeen years old and will graduate next year from high school. She enjoys watching movies and hanging out with her friends. Her hobbies are playing tennis, running, and playing piano. Carpe Diem!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Dead Poets Society
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    HG Englisch AG
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Dead Poets Society"  A film that makes you think about your dreams and your decisions in life. Good or bad decisions "Carpe Diem  Seize the day." This statement is made by Mr. Keating, the special and unique teacher of "Welton Academy". After he had taught his students the sense of "Carpe Diem" and poetry, the way of thinking of many students changed and some of them started to finish what Mr. Keating had begun when he was at the same age. If you are looking for a film to watch it in class, you should have a look at "Dead Poets Society". It's a 1986 drama film which is directed by Peter Weir and is set at the "Welton Academy" in Vermont. It deals with the teacher Mr Keating who inspires his students with his special view of life and so they build a group called "Dead Poets Society". They meet each other at a cave near the school where they talk about poetry to express themselves. The cave scenes are very amusing and show the boys in funny situations during the meetings. The "new Dead Poets Society" consists of quite different personalities: Neil Perry, the self-confident founder of the group, the shy Todd Anderson, the noisy Richard Cameron, Steven Meeks, the clever one, Charlie Dalton and last but not least Knox Overstreet, a very friendly and polite student. You may find it easy to identify with one of the young boys because of the interesting characters. They can surprise you in different ways and can also make you laugh. If I was asked to rate this film on a scale from 0  10, I would give it 7 points as the film is easy to understand and all elements, which make life worth it like love, friendship or disagreement, are included. It's a classic with a shocking and unexpected ending.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Ristrictive lives
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Bernardo Rapazote Flores
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    There are certain films that get under your skin, never to come out. They change your life, subtly altering your perceptions of reality, almost always for the better. Dead Poets Society is one of those and it is one of the most emotional movies I've ever seen and gets me every time and it touches everyone, specially people whose dreams are held down by their restrictive parents. This movie touches and thrills us scene after scene -- the "Oh Captain, my captain" scene (Don't you have ANYONE in your life you respect so much that you'd stand up for﻿ them in any situation, stand beside them and support them no matter what? That's what this scene is all about.), Anderson's 'speech' to its classmates, the tragic and touching ending -- crafting one of my favorite movies ever.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Rhyme and Reason
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    leonlouisricci
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It was a different World in 1959 and Teaching Conventions and Learning Institutions were Ultra Conservative, especially by Today's Standards. The Film takes place at an Uppity Prep School with Traditions not easily toppled. Enter Free Thinking Teacher Mr. Keating who is about to "Shake Rattle and Roll". This is a, dare one say it, Poetic Movie with a smooth Patina and an Off-Beat Meter. But, ironically it stays quite standard in its portrayal of Student Rebellion and is nowhere near Kerouac, Ginsberg, or The Beats. Some reference or acknowledgment of "The Movement" might have been a bit closer to the Theme here and would have given it some Street Cred. This is by the Book, pretty much, with its often visited Story and is not without Flaws. Such as the completely out of context Page Ripping Scene that is so badly thought out that it almost makes the Movie Dumb Ass. Did the Writer actually think that Censorship and Book Destruction was an apt way to illustrate Free Thinking. That is unforgivable. An overrated Film, but a Very Good one. Schools were like that, Parents were like that, it is an Inconvenient Truth. In the Decade that followed, for better or worse (mostly better), conventions would collapse, traditions would tumble, and the Lip Service given to Freedom would be challenged. In this Fictional Story, all that was a little ahead of its Time and those involved suffered, like all dissidents.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Walk to the Beat of your Own Drum
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    thedozinglion
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Carpe Diem" is the line often quoted from the 1989 film Dead Poets Society to signify making the most out of life today. However for me the real theme of the movie is better encapsulated in the quotes by Thoreau and Frost on "walking to the beat of your own drum" and "following the path less travelled". A rebellion away from conformity towards individuality. Robin Williams is cast in the role of John Keating, the idealistic new teacher at Welton Academy a conservative prep school during the late 1950s. The school is a milder version of the Bunker Hill Military Academy of TAPS (1981), exacting control through "tradition, honour, discipline and excellence". In essence an expensive factory designed to process boys into men of standing and position at the expense of their uniqueness. Keating's teaching methods allow his students to struggle against not only the school and its lifeless dogma but also family and society's convention. Unlike Kevin Kline's William Hundert in The Emperor's Club (2002), Keating is not interested in shaping the character of the boys he teaches but unlocking their potential. Early in the movie he instructs his class to rip out the antiquated Introduction to Poetry in their textbooks which looks to take the soul out of the verse and replace it with a formula for understanding. This is much like the ethos of the school itself which seeks to remove the identity of the boys to supplant it with a tried and tested docility. The two main leads are played well by the then rising stars Ethan Hawke and Robert Sean Leonard. Their forming of the Dead Poets Society being the central form of rebellion in the film, a midnight meeting group off campus, breaking school regulations while allowing the boys to read the great freethinking poets of the past and their own adolescent compositions to one another. However the true rebel in the movie is not a student but Robin William's quixotic Keating, a free-spirited thinker who challenges the autocratic system in place and give the power of thought to his students. He is the polar opposite of Michael Redgrave's Crocker-Harris in The Browning Version (1951), a man whose passion for teaching has been eroded by years of apathy from his students leading to a teacher of rote rather than reason. Keating forms the midpoint in a trilogy of non-conformist characters played by Williams over a three year period starting with army disc jockey Adrian Cronauer in Good Morning Vietnam (1987) to Dr. Malcolm Sayer in Awakenings (1990). All three fight their prevailing systems (military, academia and medicine) to aid those within it. Williams is well able to embody the radical troublemaker effectively although his schizophrenic personality is toned down in each subsequent film. He is at his best as an actor when he is not playing for laughs but using comedy to flesh out his characters and tell a story. In a memorable scene Keating takes Thoreau's quote from Walden and has the boys acts it out: "If a man loses pace with his companions, perhaps it is because he hears a different drummer. Let him step to the music which he hears, however measured, or far away." Having the self-conscious boys walk around the school courtyard in their own style forces them to have awareness of their individuality much to the disapproval of the watching headmaster. Keating in the scene also quotes Robert Frosts poem The Road Not Taken: "Two roads diverged in a wood, and I I took the one less traveled by, And that has made all the difference." These quotes perfectly represent the concept of not accepting the majority voice as the absolute truth but instead putting yourself and your beliefs at the center. For what good is life if it is half lived without creativity and freedom of choice and action. However the power of freethinking that Keating gives to his student ends in tragedy. To fight against the system and society can be difficult for those unaccustomed to it. Keating is held responsible by the school for the loss due to the fear of the parents and staff of his methods, which have unleashed the raw potential in his students. Alas, there is no Scent of a Women (1992) defiance by the students when the headmaster looks for informers against Keating, all the boys of the Dead Poet Society sign, in effect, his expulsion papers. But the final scene does give hope that these young men will grow up with more than just honour and loyalty that the school demands. They will also have a heart and mind open to their own ideas and beliefs, they will never tamely believe or do what is told them but will seek out the truth as they find it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An instant OBSESSION...Unforgettable!!!!!!!!!!!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    barendbkj
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Never in my life have I ever experienced anything like Dead Poet's Society. This is a fine example how movies should be. It should be touching, it should be funny, it should be something an outsider can be proud of. And I was...I was proud of what they accomplished, that almost decades later it can still be seen as a drama worth beating (and none has beaten it so far). The story is about a group of boys who restart an old Poets club, that was once run by their English teacher, mister John Keating. During the course of the film we are introduced to Keating's majorly uplifting influence in the lives of the boys as he urges them on to follow their dreams and to, seize the day. CARPE DIEM!!! This movie had me hooked from beginning to end. I didn't want it to end. When it was finished I let out a breath of relief as I realized I was not actually part of the fun. But it pulled me in and forced me to feel what the boys were feeling. The acting was phenomenal. The story is timeless and the lessons learned from it, I will always treasure. "Oh captain, my captain. I tip my hat to you sir. WELL DONE."
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Dead poets society
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    audhusenitzad
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie means the world to me!! I watched it for the first time a few weeks ago and I have been moved ever since. I fell in love with every character, especially Charlie Dalton, "Nuwanda". I highly recommend this movie to anyone who wants to see a film to make your feelings go crazy. Through the few scenes located in Mr. Keatings English classroom, the boys become free thinkers and poets, for example, the first scene distinguishes Mr. Keating to be called "Oh Captain My Captain". In a similar setting, Keating encourages the boys to stand up on the desk so they may look at the world in another way.The final scene in which the boys show their support for their English teacher Mr. Keating by standing up on their desks saying "Oh Captain My Captain", closes up the film excellently. This movie changed my life and I hope you're moved by it as much as I was.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Leaves of Class
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    wes-connors
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    In 1959 Delaware (as Vermont), charismatic poetry teacher Robin Williams (as John Keating) arrives to begin work at the "Welton Academy" preparatory school for boys. An alumni of the school, Mr. Williams teaches poetry with uncommon zeal. To gain attention, he demands students tear out the pages of books written by essayists with whom he does not agree. To get participation, he invites students to stand on the teacher's desk. Williams does impersonations of Marlon Brando and John Wayne. His motto is "Seize the Day," a directive made popular by novelist Saul Bellow. Yes, this class is fun... Williams teaches the "dangers of conforming," and encourages students to think for themselves. When they learn Williams belonged to a clandestine club called the "Dead Poets Society" when he was a "Welton" student, the class decides to revive the group. They meet in a cave to read poetry by the masters - but, mainly, they just goof around. Playing the saxophone and sharing "Playboy"-type centerfolds accompany Walt Whitman. Because Williams'' influence extends perilously beyond the classroom, his "unorthodox teaching methods" get the popular teacher in trouble with school administrators... This above average production won good notices and award consideration for director Peter Weir and star Robin Williams. Originally, the teacher held back a secret; "Oscar"-winning writer Tom Schulman was persuaded to drop the idea, so we and the character are left with a gap. Williams' "Keating" is put on the sidelines in favor of the students. Nothing against the actors, who perform exceptionally, but they do look more like handsome young college-aged models than typical high-school aged boys. There is some physical diversity in the extended supporting cast, though. A few of the boys wear glasses... The main stars are sensitive writer Ethan Hawke (as Todd Anderson) and his roommate, aspiring actor Robert Sean Leonard (as Neil Perry). The next tier includes prankster Gale Hansen (as Charlie Dalton) and lovelorn Josh Charles (as Knox Overstreet). Although these players are almost interchangeable, the actors create distinguishable characters. Best of the remaining parts goes to Dylan Kussman (as Richard Cameron), who perversely turns out to be the group's real non-conformist. The film is too self-consciously calculating and manipulative to be fully masterful, but it sure looks nice. ******** Dead Poets Society (6/2/89) Peter Weir ~ Robin Williams, Ethan Hawke, Robert Sean Leonard, Gale Hansen
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Young boys reading poetry during their play-time..... come onnnn.......
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Tracy Winters
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Robin Williams -- you know, I really want to like him, and in this film, I do, though I usually don't like the kinds of films he chooses to participate in ('Good Will Hunting' is by far his best role). Here's a supposedly enigmatic teacher (Williams) motivating his teenage boy students to read poetry in their leisure time. That was unbelievable. I could see them doing this if between poems, they gave each other oral sex or something, but unfortunately, that does not happen in this movie. What does happen is a predictable script by Tom Shulman. We see a plethora of different, but typical characters.... the snitch (Dylan Kussman), the rebellious kid (Gale Hanson), the charming boy (Josh Charles), and even a self-effacing young man (Ethan Hawke) who stutters until the hero of the story (Williams) gives the kid a reason to live, except when Wiliams leaves the school, the kid starts stuttering again (i.e. 'One Flew Over the Cuckoo's Nest'). So much for originality. The final scene is so sappy, you'll want to rinse out your pie-hole with mouthwash.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Much Better Than Expected!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    g-bodyl
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Dead Poets Society is a much better film than I anticipated. Honestly, I thought this would be a film all about poetry and I loathe poetry, so I didn't give this film a chance. I'm glad I did because this is not a film about poetry, but about a group of college kids who have been encouraged to follow their own dreams. This film is a well-made drama that will make you smile, laugh, and cry. It also has one of the most unexpected scenes I have seen in awhile. Peter Weir's film is about a group of college kids who are inspired by their English professor, John Keating. Keating tells his kids who follow their dreams and they do just that. Unfortunately, the dean and the parents have other ideas for their kids. Robin Williams gives a true, inspirational performance as John Keating. He is the teacher that is common nowadays, but someone my parents would yearn to have. Ethan Hawke delivers a stand out performance as one of the kids and so does Robert Sean Leonard. Overall, this is a truly inspirational film that has one simple message for all people, especially younger ones. This message is "Follow our dreams and don't let anyone tell you what you can or can't do." This message should have been used back in the 1950's-1960's. This film is well-acted, has great direction, and should leave a tear or two. I rate this film 9/10.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Inspiring and Life changing
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Melania Chaves
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Carpe Diem": Seize the day. This is the lesson, John Keating, the English schoolteacher wants to convey to his students. This movie is one of the best movies I've ever watched. It helps people to face problems and live life as if there was no tomorrow. It teaches us how to enjoy every aspect of life and let nothing ruin what makes us really happy. It is not only entertaining, but it teaches a great life lesson, which is to think for ourselves and stand up for that in which we believe. It is incomparable with other movies and should definitely be watched by everyone. Dead Poets Society was nominated for four Academy Awards. It is from the genre of drama and although it is a 1989 movie, the picture is great and the movie is so stimulating and outstanding, the picture won't even be a problem. The movie takes place in 1959 in the Welton Academy. In this school education is very strict and students are expected to behave in a highly educated and responsible manner. Several of the students have a different opinion regarding the school's education process. When the new teacher comes, everything changes. John Keating is an unconventional teacher who tells his students to tear out the pages of the books and asks his students to stand on their desks to see the world from a different perspective. He introduces the boys to poetry and teaches them new philosophies about life. He encourages his students to follow their dreams, and to not follow what people expect them to do, but what makes them happy. The characters in this film are so realistic; they create an impact in the audience. I hate movies with flat characters and in this movie the character development is really outstanding. Robin Williams plays an excellent job as the professor and interacts very well with the students. In his early life, Williams studied political science before studying theatre in the Julliard School. He later on performed in nightclubs where he was discovered for the role of Mork on the TV series "Happy Days". Another important character is Robert Leonard who plays the role of Neil Perry. He deserves acknowledgment and fame and is mostly known as Dr. James Wilson on House M.D. Ethan Hawke is another important character in the movie. He plays the role of Todd Anderson in the movie. Ethan was born on 6 November 1970 in Austin Texas. His acting career started as a mix of theatre work and a mix of serious and commercial movies. All of these actors play an excellent role in the movie. They create an exciting plot, and the move builds up perfectly. At first the movie seemed kind of boring, but as I paid more attention and it advanced it was amazing. It tells a story that nobody should miss. I talks about courage, how we should fight for what we want, and to live life to the fullest. One of my favorite scenes was when the English teacher, Mr. Keating, tells the students to tear the pages of a book apart. In every scene he is an excellent teacher, he makes the class entertaining and the students learn more than you could imagine. They do not only learn about English and poetry, but they learn about life. This movie is heartwarming; it has a full meaning, and is contains great poetry that has life lessons. I believe the most important lesson in this movie is to seize the day. This means to make out the most of each day, as if we would die tomorrow. This relates to doing what you like, what you enjoy the most in life. It is getting apart from what society expects from you, and doing what makes you happy. Another important lesson is to be you. We live in a society in which everyone expects something from you, but the most important thing is to be your own self. It will help in mental and spiritual growth. Challenging the status quo is another lesson. Change the way to see life, make a change in the world, in people. One last lesson is to stand up for others. This will not only be beneficial for the people you help but it will help you feel better. I believe everyone who watches the movie should enjoy it. I would recommend it to anyone who wants to watch it but especially for people above 13 years. This is because someone younger than this will maybe not understand well the meaning of the movie and will think it is boring. I would rate the movie PG-13. This movie is as great as the Oscar Winning movie "The Help". Both movies are delightfully different. In "The Help", as well as in "Dead Poets Society", the characters play an excellent role and the plot is entertaining and fun. Along the movie you will not get bored, it catches the audience's attention due to the fact that they treat interesting subjects. They are memorable movies, that once you watch them you will never forget the lesson and it will change your life. Both teach a wonderful lesson that everyone should take into account in their daily lives. Rating 8.7 The criticizer of this movie is Melania Chaves. She is an eleventh grade student at Lincoln School, Costa Rica. She is seventeen years old and will graduate next year from high school. She enjoys watching movies and hanging out with her friends. Her hobbies are playing tennis, running, and playing piano. Carpe Diem!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Dead Poets Society
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    HG Englisch AG
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Dead Poets Society"  A film that makes you think about your dreams and your decisions in life. Good or bad decisions "Carpe Diem  Seize the day." This statement is made by Mr. Keating, the special and unique teacher of "Welton Academy". After he had taught his students the sense of "Carpe Diem" and poetry, the way of thinking of many students changed and some of them started to finish what Mr. Keating had begun when he was at the same age. If you are looking for a film to watch it in class, you should have a look at "Dead Poets Society". It's a 1986 drama film which is directed by Peter Weir and is set at the "Welton Academy" in Vermont. It deals with the teacher Mr Keating who inspires his students with his special view of life and so they build a group called "Dead Poets Society". They meet each other at a cave near the school where they talk about poetry to express themselves. The cave scenes are very amusing and show the boys in funny situations during the meetings. The "new Dead Poets Society" consists of quite different personalities: Neil Perry, the self-confident founder of the group, the shy Todd Anderson, the noisy Richard Cameron, Steven Meeks, the clever one, Charlie Dalton and last but not least Knox Overstreet, a very friendly and polite student. You may find it easy to identify with one of the young boys because of the interesting characters. They can surprise you in different ways and can also make you laugh. If I was asked to rate this film on a scale from 0  10, I would give it 7 points as the film is easy to understand and all elements, which make life worth it like love, friendship or disagreement, are included. It's a classic with a shocking and unexpected ending.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Ristrictive lives
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Bernardo Rapazote Flores
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    There are certain films that get under your skin, never to come out. They change your life, subtly altering your perceptions of reality, almost always for the better. Dead Poets Society is one of those and it is one of the most emotional movies I've ever seen and gets me every time and it touches everyone, specially people whose dreams are held down by their restrictive parents. This movie touches and thrills us scene after scene -- the "Oh Captain, my captain" scene (Don't you have ANYONE in your life you respect so much that you'd stand up for﻿ them in any situation, stand beside them and support them no matter what? That's what this scene is all about.), Anderson's 'speech' to its classmates, the tragic and touching ending -- crafting one of my favorite movies ever.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Rhyme and Reason
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    leonlouisricci
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It was a different World in 1959 and Teaching Conventions and Learning Institutions were Ultra Conservative, especially by Today's Standards. The Film takes place at an Uppity Prep School with Traditions not easily toppled. Enter Free Thinking Teacher Mr. Keating who is about to "Shake Rattle and Roll". This is a, dare one say it, Poetic Movie with a smooth Patina and an Off-Beat Meter. But, ironically it stays quite standard in its portrayal of Student Rebellion and is nowhere near Kerouac, Ginsberg, or The Beats. Some reference or acknowledgment of "The Movement" might have been a bit closer to the Theme here and would have given it some Street Cred. This is by the Book, pretty much, with its often visited Story and is not without Flaws. Such as the completely out of context Page Ripping Scene that is so badly thought out that it almost makes the Movie Dumb Ass. Did the Writer actually think that Censorship and Book Destruction was an apt way to illustrate Free Thinking. That is unforgivable. An overrated Film, but a Very Good one. Schools were like that, Parents were like that, it is an Inconvenient Truth. In the Decade that followed, for better or worse (mostly better), conventions would collapse, traditions would tumble, and the Lip Service given to Freedom would be challenged. In this Fictional Story, all that was a little ahead of its Time and those involved suffered, like all dissidents.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Walk to the Beat of your Own Drum
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    thedozinglion
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Carpe Diem" is the line often quoted from the 1989 film Dead Poets Society to signify making the most out of life today. However for me the real theme of the movie is better encapsulated in the quotes by Thoreau and Frost on "walking to the beat of your own drum" and "following the path less travelled". A rebellion away from conformity towards individuality. Robin Williams is cast in the role of John Keating, the idealistic new teacher at Welton Academy a conservative prep school during the late 1950s. The school is a milder version of the Bunker Hill Military Academy of TAPS (1981), exacting control through "tradition, honour, discipline and excellence". In essence an expensive factory designed to process boys into men of standing and position at the expense of their uniqueness. Keating's teaching methods allow his students to struggle against not only the school and its lifeless dogma but also family and society's convention. Unlike Kevin Kline's William Hundert in The Emperor's Club (2002), Keating is not interested in shaping the character of the boys he teaches but unlocking their potential. Early in the movie he instructs his class to rip out the antiquated Introduction to Poetry in their textbooks which looks to take the soul out of the verse and replace it with a formula for understanding. This is much like the ethos of the school itself which seeks to remove the identity of the boys to supplant it with a tried and tested docility. The two main leads are played well by the then rising stars Ethan Hawke and Robert Sean Leonard. Their forming of the Dead Poets Society being the central form of rebellion in the film, a midnight meeting group off campus, breaking school regulations while allowing the boys to read the great freethinking poets of the past and their own adolescent compositions to one another. However the true rebel in the movie is not a student but Robin William's quixotic Keating, a free-spirited thinker who challenges the autocratic system in place and give the power of thought to his students. He is the polar opposite of Michael Redgrave's Crocker-Harris in The Browning Version (1951), a man whose passion for teaching has been eroded by years of apathy from his students leading to a teacher of rote rather than reason. Keating forms the midpoint in a trilogy of non-conformist characters played by Williams over a three year period starting with army disc jockey Adrian Cronauer in Good Morning Vietnam (1987) to Dr. Malcolm Sayer in Awakenings (1990). All three fight their prevailing systems (military, academia and medicine) to aid those within it. Williams is well able to embody the radical troublemaker effectively although his schizophrenic personality is toned down in each subsequent film. He is at his best as an actor when he is not playing for laughs but using comedy to flesh out his characters and tell a story. In a memorable scene Keating takes Thoreau's quote from Walden and has the boys acts it out: "If a man loses pace with his companions, perhaps it is because he hears a different drummer. Let him step to the music which he hears, however measured, or far away." Having the self-conscious boys walk around the school courtyard in their own style forces them to have awareness of their individuality much to the disapproval of the watching headmaster. Keating in the scene also quotes Robert Frosts poem The Road Not Taken: "Two roads diverged in a wood, and I I took the one less traveled by, And that has made all the difference." These quotes perfectly represent the concept of not accepting the majority voice as the absolute truth but instead putting yourself and your beliefs at the center. For what good is life if it is half lived without creativity and freedom of choice and action. However the power of freethinking that Keating gives to his student ends in tragedy. To fight against the system and society can be difficult for those unaccustomed to it. Keating is held responsible by the school for the loss due to the fear of the parents and staff of his methods, which have unleashed the raw potential in his students. Alas, there is no Scent of a Women (1992) defiance by the students when the headmaster looks for informers against Keating, all the boys of the Dead Poet Society sign, in effect, his expulsion papers. But the final scene does give hope that these young men will grow up with more than just honour and loyalty that the school demands. They will also have a heart and mind open to their own ideas and beliefs, they will never tamely believe or do what is told them but will seek out the truth as they find it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An instant OBSESSION...Unforgettable!!!!!!!!!!!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    barendbkj
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Never in my life have I ever experienced anything like Dead Poet's Society. This is a fine example how movies should be. It should be touching, it should be funny, it should be something an outsider can be proud of. And I was...I was proud of what they accomplished, that almost decades later it can still be seen as a drama worth beating (and none has beaten it so far). The story is about a group of boys who restart an old Poets club, that was once run by their English teacher, mister John Keating. During the course of the film we are introduced to Keating's majorly uplifting influence in the lives of the boys as he urges them on to follow their dreams and to, seize the day. CARPE DIEM!!! This movie had me hooked from beginning to end. I didn't want it to end. When it was finished I let out a breath of relief as I realized I was not actually part of the fun. But it pulled me in and forced me to feel what the boys were feeling. The acting was phenomenal. The story is timeless and the lessons learned from it, I will always treasure. "Oh captain, my captain. I tip my hat to you sir. WELL DONE."
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Dead poets society
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    audhusenitzad
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie means the world to me!! I watched it for the first time a few weeks ago and I have been moved ever since. I fell in love with every character, especially Charlie Dalton, "Nuwanda". I highly recommend this movie to anyone who wants to see a film to make your feelings go crazy. Through the few scenes located in Mr. Keatings English classroom, the boys become free thinkers and poets, for example, the first scene distinguishes Mr. Keating to be called "Oh Captain My Captain". In a similar setting, Keating encourages the boys to stand up on the desk so they may look at the world in another way.The final scene in which the boys show their support for their English teacher Mr. Keating by standing up on their desks saying "Oh Captain My Captain", closes up the film excellently. This movie changed my life and I hope you're moved by it as much as I was.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Leaves of Class
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    wes-connors
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    In 1959 Delaware (as Vermont), charismatic poetry teacher Robin Williams (as John Keating) arrives to begin work at the "Welton Academy" preparatory school for boys. An alumni of the school, Mr. Williams teaches poetry with uncommon zeal. To gain attention, he demands students tear out the pages of books written by essayists with whom he does not agree. To get participation, he invites students to stand on the teacher's desk. Williams does impersonations of Marlon Brando and John Wayne. His motto is "Seize the Day," a directive made popular by novelist Saul Bellow. Yes, this class is fun... Williams teaches the "dangers of conforming," and encourages students to think for themselves. When they learn Williams belonged to a clandestine club called the "Dead Poets Society" when he was a "Welton" student, the class decides to revive the group. They meet in a cave to read poetry by the masters - but, mainly, they just goof around. Playing the saxophone and sharing "Playboy"-type centerfolds accompany Walt Whitman. Because Williams'' influence extends perilously beyond the classroom, his "unorthodox teaching methods" get the popular teacher in trouble with school administrators... This above average production won good notices and award consideration for director Peter Weir and star Robin Williams. Originally, the teacher held back a secret; "Oscar"-winning writer Tom Schulman was persuaded to drop the idea, so we and the character are left with a gap. Williams' "Keating" is put on the sidelines in favor of the students. Nothing against the actors, who perform exceptionally, but they do look more like handsome young college-aged models than typical high-school aged boys. There is some physical diversity in the extended supporting cast, though. A few of the boys wear glasses... The main stars are sensitive writer Ethan Hawke (as Todd Anderson) and his roommate, aspiring actor Robert Sean Leonard (as Neil Perry). The next tier includes prankster Gale Hansen (as Charlie Dalton) and lovelorn Josh Charles (as Knox Overstreet). Although these players are almost interchangeable, the actors create distinguishable characters. Best of the remaining parts goes to Dylan Kussman (as Richard Cameron), who perversely turns out to be the group's real non-conformist. The film is too self-consciously calculating and manipulative to be fully masterful, but it sure looks nice. ******** Dead Poets Society (6/2/89) Peter Weir ~ Robin Williams, Ethan Hawke, Robert Sean Leonard, Gale Hansen
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Young boys reading poetry during their play-time..... come onnnn.......
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Tracy Winters
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Robin Williams -- you know, I really want to like him, and in this film, I do, though I usually don't like the kinds of films he chooses to participate in ('Good Will Hunting' is by far his best role). Here's a supposedly enigmatic teacher (Williams) motivating his teenage boy students to read poetry in their leisure time. That was unbelievable. I could see them doing this if between poems, they gave each other oral sex or something, but unfortunately, that does not happen in this movie. What does happen is a predictable script by Tom Shulman. We see a plethora of different, but typical characters.... the snitch (Dylan Kussman), the rebellious kid (Gale Hanson), the charming boy (Josh Charles), and even a self-effacing young man (Ethan Hawke) who stutters until the hero of the story (Williams) gives the kid a reason to live, except when Wiliams leaves the school, the kid starts stuttering again (i.e. 'One Flew Over the Cuckoo's Nest'). So much for originality. The final scene is so sappy, you'll want to rinse out your pie-hole with mouthwash.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Much Better Than Expected!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    g-bodyl
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Dead Poets Society is a much better film than I anticipated. Honestly, I thought this would be a film all about poetry and I loathe poetry, so I didn't give this film a chance. I'm glad I did because this is not a film about poetry, but about a group of college kids who have been encouraged to follow their own dreams. This film is a well-made drama that will make you smile, laugh, and cry. It also has one of the most unexpected scenes I have seen in awhile. Peter Weir's film is about a group of college kids who are inspired by their English professor, John Keating. Keating tells his kids who follow their dreams and they do just that. Unfortunately, the dean and the parents have other ideas for their kids. Robin Williams gives a true, inspirational performance as John Keating. He is the teacher that is common nowadays, but someone my parents would yearn to have. Ethan Hawke delivers a stand out performance as one of the kids and so does Robert Sean Leonard. Overall, this is a truly inspirational film that has one simple message for all people, especially younger ones. This message is "Follow our dreams and don't let anyone tell you what you can or can't do." This message should have been used back in the 1950's-1960's. This film is well-acted, has great direction, and should leave a tear or two. I rate this film 9/10.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Inspiring and Life changing
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Melania Chaves
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Carpe Diem": Seize the day. This is the lesson, John Keating, the English schoolteacher wants to convey to his students. This movie is one of the best movies I've ever watched. It helps people to face problems and live life as if there was no tomorrow. It teaches us how to enjoy every aspect of life and let nothing ruin what makes us really happy. It is not only entertaining, but it teaches a great life lesson, which is to think for ourselves and stand up for that in which we believe. It is incomparable with other movies and should definitely be watched by everyone. Dead Poets Society was nominated for four Academy Awards. It is from the genre of drama and although it is a 1989 movie, the picture is great and the movie is so stimulating and outstanding, the picture won't even be a problem. The movie takes place in 1959 in the Welton Academy. In this school education is very strict and students are expected to behave in a highly educated and responsible manner. Several of the students have a different opinion regarding the school's education process. When the new teacher comes, everything changes. John Keating is an unconventional teacher who tells his students to tear out the pages of the books and asks his students to stand on their desks to see the world from a different perspective. He introduces the boys to poetry and teaches them new philosophies about life. He encourages his students to follow their dreams, and to not follow what people expect them to do, but what makes them happy. The characters in this film are so realistic; they create an impact in the audience. I hate movies with flat characters and in this movie the character development is really outstanding. Robin Williams plays an excellent job as the professor and interacts very well with the students. In his early life, Williams studied political science before studying theatre in the Julliard School. He later on performed in nightclubs where he was discovered for the role of Mork on the TV series "Happy Days". Another important character is Robert Leonard who plays the role of Neil Perry. He deserves acknowledgment and fame and is mostly known as Dr. James Wilson on House M.D. Ethan Hawke is another important character in the movie. He plays the role of Todd Anderson in the movie. Ethan was born on 6 November 1970 in Austin Texas. His acting career started as a mix of theatre work and a mix of serious and commercial movies. All of these actors play an excellent role in the movie. They create an exciting plot, and the move builds up perfectly. At first the movie seemed kind of boring, but as I paid more attention and it advanced it was amazing. It tells a story that nobody should miss. I talks about courage, how we should fight for what we want, and to live life to the fullest. One of my favorite scenes was when the English teacher, Mr. Keating, tells the students to tear the pages of a book apart. In every scene he is an excellent teacher, he makes the class entertaining and the students learn more than you could imagine. They do not only learn about English and poetry, but they learn about life. This movie is heartwarming; it has a full meaning, and is contains great poetry that has life lessons. I believe the most important lesson in this movie is to seize the day. This means to make out the most of each day, as if we would die tomorrow. This relates to doing what you like, what you enjoy the most in life. It is getting apart from what society expects from you, and doing what makes you happy. Another important lesson is to be you. We live in a society in which everyone expects something from you, but the most important thing is to be your own self. It will help in mental and spiritual growth. Challenging the status quo is another lesson. Change the way to see life, make a change in the world, in people. One last lesson is to stand up for others. This will not only be beneficial for the people you help but it will help you feel better. I believe everyone who watches the movie should enjoy it. I would recommend it to anyone who wants to watch it but especially for people above 13 years. This is because someone younger than this will maybe not understand well the meaning of the movie and will think it is boring. I would rate the movie PG-13. This movie is as great as the Oscar Winning movie "The Help". Both movies are delightfully different. In "The Help", as well as in "Dead Poets Society", the characters play an excellent role and the plot is entertaining and fun. Along the movie you will not get bored, it catches the audience's attention due to the fact that they treat interesting subjects. They are memorable movies, that once you watch them you will never forget the lesson and it will change your life. Both teach a wonderful lesson that everyone should take into account in their daily lives. Rating 8.7 The criticizer of this movie is Melania Chaves. She is an eleventh grade student at Lincoln School, Costa Rica. She is seventeen years old and will graduate next year from high school. She enjoys watching movies and hanging out with her friends. Her hobbies are playing tennis, running, and playing piano. Carpe Diem!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Dead Poets Society
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    HG Englisch AG
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Dead Poets Society"  A film that makes you think about your dreams and your decisions in life. Good or bad decisions "Carpe Diem  Seize the day." This statement is made by Mr. Keating, the special and unique teacher of "Welton Academy". After he had taught his students the sense of "Carpe Diem" and poetry, the way of thinking of many students changed and some of them started to finish what Mr. Keating had begun when he was at the same age. If you are looking for a film to watch it in class, you should have a look at "Dead Poets Society". It's a 1986 drama film which is directed by Peter Weir and is set at the "Welton Academy" in Vermont. It deals with the teacher Mr Keating who inspires his students with his special view of life and so they build a group called "Dead Poets Society". They meet each other at a cave near the school where they talk about poetry to express themselves. The cave scenes are very amusing and show the boys in funny situations during the meetings. The "new Dead Poets Society" consists of quite different personalities: Neil Perry, the self-confident founder of the group, the shy Todd Anderson, the noisy Richard Cameron, Steven Meeks, the clever one, Charlie Dalton and last but not least Knox Overstreet, a very friendly and polite student. You may find it easy to identify with one of the young boys because of the interesting characters. They can surprise you in different ways and can also make you laugh. If I was asked to rate this film on a scale from 0  10, I would give it 7 points as the film is easy to understand and all elements, which make life worth it like love, friendship or disagreement, are included. It's a classic with a shocking and unexpected ending.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Ristrictive lives
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Bernardo Rapazote Flores
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    There are certain films that get under your skin, never to come out. They change your life, subtly altering your perceptions of reality, almost always for the better. Dead Poets Society is one of those and it is one of the most emotional movies I've ever seen and gets me every time and it touches everyone, specially people whose dreams are held down by their restrictive parents. This movie touches and thrills us scene after scene -- the "Oh Captain, my captain" scene (Don't you have ANYONE in your life you respect so much that you'd stand up for﻿ them in any situation, stand beside them and support them no matter what? That's what this scene is all about.), Anderson's 'speech' to its classmates, the tragic and touching ending -- crafting one of my favorite movies ever.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Rhyme and Reason
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    leonlouisricci
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It was a different World in 1959 and Teaching Conventions and Learning Institutions were Ultra Conservative, especially by Today's Standards. The Film takes place at an Uppity Prep School with Traditions not easily toppled. Enter Free Thinking Teacher Mr. Keating who is about to "Shake Rattle and Roll". This is a, dare one say it, Poetic Movie with a smooth Patina and an Off-Beat Meter. But, ironically it stays quite standard in its portrayal of Student Rebellion and is nowhere near Kerouac, Ginsberg, or The Beats. Some reference or acknowledgment of "The Movement" might have been a bit closer to the Theme here and would have given it some Street Cred. This is by the Book, pretty much, with its often visited Story and is not without Flaws. Such as the completely out of context Page Ripping Scene that is so badly thought out that it almost makes the Movie Dumb Ass. Did the Writer actually think that Censorship and Book Destruction was an apt way to illustrate Free Thinking. That is unforgivable. An overrated Film, but a Very Good one. Schools were like that, Parents were like that, it is an Inconvenient Truth. In the Decade that followed, for better or worse (mostly better), conventions would collapse, traditions would tumble, and the Lip Service given to Freedom would be challenged. In this Fictional Story, all that was a little ahead of its Time and those involved suffered, like all dissidents.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Walk to the Beat of your Own Drum
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    thedozinglion
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Carpe Diem" is the line often quoted from the 1989 film Dead Poets Society to signify making the most out of life today. However for me the real theme of the movie is better encapsulated in the quotes by Thoreau and Frost on "walking to the beat of your own drum" and "following the path less travelled". A rebellion away from conformity towards individuality. Robin Williams is cast in the role of John Keating, the idealistic new teacher at Welton Academy a conservative prep school during the late 1950s. The school is a milder version of the Bunker Hill Military Academy of TAPS (1981), exacting control through "tradition, honour, discipline and excellence". In essence an expensive factory designed to process boys into men of standing and position at the expense of their uniqueness. Keating's teaching methods allow his students to struggle against not only the school and its lifeless dogma but also family and society's convention. Unlike Kevin Kline's William Hundert in The Emperor's Club (2002), Keating is not interested in shaping the character of the boys he teaches but unlocking their potential. Early in the movie he instructs his class to rip out the antiquated Introduction to Poetry in their textbooks which looks to take the soul out of the verse and replace it with a formula for understanding. This is much like the ethos of the school itself which seeks to remove the identity of the boys to supplant it with a tried and tested docility. The two main leads are played well by the then rising stars Ethan Hawke and Robert Sean Leonard. Their forming of the Dead Poets Society being the central form of rebellion in the film, a midnight meeting group off campus, breaking school regulations while allowing the boys to read the great freethinking poets of the past and their own adolescent compositions to one another. However the true rebel in the movie is not a student but Robin William's quixotic Keating, a free-spirited thinker who challenges the autocratic system in place and give the power of thought to his students. He is the polar opposite of Michael Redgrave's Crocker-Harris in The Browning Version (1951), a man whose passion for teaching has been eroded by years of apathy from his students leading to a teacher of rote rather than reason. Keating forms the midpoint in a trilogy of non-conformist characters played by Williams over a three year period starting with army disc jockey Adrian Cronauer in Good Morning Vietnam (1987) to Dr. Malcolm Sayer in Awakenings (1990). All three fight their prevailing systems (military, academia and medicine) to aid those within it. Williams is well able to embody the radical troublemaker effectively although his schizophrenic personality is toned down in each subsequent film. He is at his best as an actor when he is not playing for laughs but using comedy to flesh out his characters and tell a story. In a memorable scene Keating takes Thoreau's quote from Walden and has the boys acts it out: "If a man loses pace with his companions, perhaps it is because he hears a different drummer. Let him step to the music which he hears, however measured, or far away." Having the self-conscious boys walk around the school courtyard in their own style forces them to have awareness of their individuality much to the disapproval of the watching headmaster. Keating in the scene also quotes Robert Frosts poem The Road Not Taken: "Two roads diverged in a wood, and I I took the one less traveled by, And that has made all the difference." These quotes perfectly represent the concept of not accepting the majority voice as the absolute truth but instead putting yourself and your beliefs at the center. For what good is life if it is half lived without creativity and freedom of choice and action. However the power of freethinking that Keating gives to his student ends in tragedy. To fight against the system and society can be difficult for those unaccustomed to it. Keating is held responsible by the school for the loss due to the fear of the parents and staff of his methods, which have unleashed the raw potential in his students. Alas, there is no Scent of a Women (1992) defiance by the students when the headmaster looks for informers against Keating, all the boys of the Dead Poet Society sign, in effect, his expulsion papers. But the final scene does give hope that these young men will grow up with more than just honour and loyalty that the school demands. They will also have a heart and mind open to their own ideas and beliefs, they will never tamely believe or do what is told them but will seek out the truth as they find it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An instant OBSESSION...Unforgettable!!!!!!!!!!!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    barendbkj
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Never in my life have I ever experienced anything like Dead Poet's Society. This is a fine example how movies should be. It should be touching, it should be funny, it should be something an outsider can be proud of. And I was...I was proud of what they accomplished, that almost decades later it can still be seen as a drama worth beating (and none has beaten it so far). The story is about a group of boys who restart an old Poets club, that was once run by their English teacher, mister John Keating. During the course of the film we are introduced to Keating's majorly uplifting influence in the lives of the boys as he urges them on to follow their dreams and to, seize the day. CARPE DIEM!!! This movie had me hooked from beginning to end. I didn't want it to end. When it was finished I let out a breath of relief as I realized I was not actually part of the fun. But it pulled me in and forced me to feel what the boys were feeling. The acting was phenomenal. The story is timeless and the lessons learned from it, I will always treasure. "Oh captain, my captain. I tip my hat to you sir. WELL DONE."
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Dead poets society
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    audhusenitzad
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie means the world to me!! I watched it for the first time a few weeks ago and I have been moved ever since. I fell in love with every character, especially Charlie Dalton, "Nuwanda". I highly recommend this movie to anyone who wants to see a film to make your feelings go crazy. Through the few scenes located in Mr. Keatings English classroom, the boys become free thinkers and poets, for example, the first scene distinguishes Mr. Keating to be called "Oh Captain My Captain". In a similar setting, Keating encourages the boys to stand up on the desk so they may look at the world in another way.The final scene in which the boys show their support for their English teacher Mr. Keating by standing up on their desks saying "Oh Captain My Captain", closes up the film excellently. This movie changed my life and I hope you're moved by it as much as I was.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Leaves of Class
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    wes-connors
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    In 1959 Delaware (as Vermont), charismatic poetry teacher Robin Williams (as John Keating) arrives to begin work at the "Welton Academy" preparatory school for boys. An alumni of the school, Mr. Williams teaches poetry with uncommon zeal. To gain attention, he demands students tear out the pages of books written by essayists with whom he does not agree. To get participation, he invites students to stand on the teacher's desk. Williams does impersonations of Marlon Brando and John Wayne. His motto is "Seize the Day," a directive made popular by novelist Saul Bellow. Yes, this class is fun... Williams teaches the "dangers of conforming," and encourages students to think for themselves. When they learn Williams belonged to a clandestine club called the "Dead Poets Society" when he was a "Welton" student, the class decides to revive the group. They meet in a cave to read poetry by the masters - but, mainly, they just goof around. Playing the saxophone and sharing "Playboy"-type centerfolds accompany Walt Whitman. Because Williams'' influence extends perilously beyond the classroom, his "unorthodox teaching methods" get the popular teacher in trouble with school administrators... This above average production won good notices and award consideration for director Peter Weir and star Robin Williams. Originally, the teacher held back a secret; "Oscar"-winning writer Tom Schulman was persuaded to drop the idea, so we and the character are left with a gap. Williams' "Keating" is put on the sidelines in favor of the students. Nothing against the actors, who perform exceptionally, but they do look more like handsome young college-aged models than typical high-school aged boys. There is some physical diversity in the extended supporting cast, though. A few of the boys wear glasses... The main stars are sensitive writer Ethan Hawke (as Todd Anderson) and his roommate, aspiring actor Robert Sean Leonard (as Neil Perry). The next tier includes prankster Gale Hansen (as Charlie Dalton) and lovelorn Josh Charles (as Knox Overstreet). Although these players are almost interchangeable, the actors create distinguishable characters. Best of the remaining parts goes to Dylan Kussman (as Richard Cameron), who perversely turns out to be the group's real non-conformist. The film is too self-consciously calculating and manipulative to be fully masterful, but it sure looks nice. ******** Dead Poets Society (6/2/89) Peter Weir ~ Robin Williams, Ethan Hawke, Robert Sean Leonard, Gale Hansen
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Young boys reading poetry during their play-time..... come onnnn.......
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Tracy Winters
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Robin Williams -- you know, I really want to like him, and in this film, I do, though I usually don't like the kinds of films he chooses to participate in ('Good Will Hunting' is by far his best role). Here's a supposedly enigmatic teacher (Williams) motivating his teenage boy students to read poetry in their leisure time. That was unbelievable. I could see them doing this if between poems, they gave each other oral sex or something, but unfortunately, that does not happen in this movie. What does happen is a predictable script by Tom Shulman. We see a plethora of different, but typical characters.... the snitch (Dylan Kussman), the rebellious kid (Gale Hanson), the charming boy (Josh Charles), and even a self-effacing young man (Ethan Hawke) who stutters until the hero of the story (Williams) gives the kid a reason to live, except when Wiliams leaves the school, the kid starts stuttering again (i.e. 'One Flew Over the Cuckoo's Nest'). So much for originality. The final scene is so sappy, you'll want to rinse out your pie-hole with mouthwash.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Much Better Than Expected!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    g-bodyl
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Dead Poets Society is a much better film than I anticipated. Honestly, I thought this would be a film all about poetry and I loathe poetry, so I didn't give this film a chance. I'm glad I did because this is not a film about poetry, but about a group of college kids who have been encouraged to follow their own dreams. This film is a well-made drama that will make you smile, laugh, and cry. It also has one of the most unexpected scenes I have seen in awhile. Peter Weir's film is about a group of college kids who are inspired by their English professor, John Keating. Keating tells his kids who follow their dreams and they do just that. Unfortunately, the dean and the parents have other ideas for their kids. Robin Williams gives a true, inspirational performance as John Keating. He is the teacher that is common nowadays, but someone my parents would yearn to have. Ethan Hawke delivers a stand out performance as one of the kids and so does Robert Sean Leonard. Overall, this is a truly inspirational film that has one simple message for all people, especially younger ones. This message is "Follow our dreams and don't let anyone tell you what you can or can't do." This message should have been used back in the 1950's-1960's. This film is well-acted, has great direction, and should leave a tear or two. I rate this film 9/10.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Inspiring and Life changing
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Melania Chaves
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Carpe Diem": Seize the day. This is the lesson, John Keating, the English schoolteacher wants to convey to his students. This movie is one of the best movies I've ever watched. It helps people to face problems and live life as if there was no tomorrow. It teaches us how to enjoy every aspect of life and let nothing ruin what makes us really happy. It is not only entertaining, but it teaches a great life lesson, which is to think for ourselves and stand up for that in which we believe. It is incomparable with other movies and should definitely be watched by everyone. Dead Poets Society was nominated for four Academy Awards. It is from the genre of drama and although it is a 1989 movie, the picture is great and the movie is so stimulating and outstanding, the picture won't even be a problem. The movie takes place in 1959 in the Welton Academy. In this school education is very strict and students are expected to behave in a highly educated and responsible manner. Several of the students have a different opinion regarding the school's education process. When the new teacher comes, everything changes. John Keating is an unconventional teacher who tells his students to tear out the pages of the books and asks his students to stand on their desks to see the world from a different perspective. He introduces the boys to poetry and teaches them new philosophies about life. He encourages his students to follow their dreams, and to not follow what people expect them to do, but what makes them happy. The characters in this film are so realistic; they create an impact in the audience. I hate movies with flat characters and in this movie the character development is really outstanding. Robin Williams plays an excellent job as the professor and interacts very well with the students. In his early life, Williams studied political science before studying theatre in the Julliard School. He later on performed in nightclubs where he was discovered for the role of Mork on the TV series "Happy Days". Another important character is Robert Leonard who plays the role of Neil Perry. He deserves acknowledgment and fame and is mostly known as Dr. James Wilson on House M.D. Ethan Hawke is another important character in the movie. He plays the role of Todd Anderson in the movie. Ethan was born on 6 November 1970 in Austin Texas. His acting career started as a mix of theatre work and a mix of serious and commercial movies. All of these actors play an excellent role in the movie. They create an exciting plot, and the move builds up perfectly. At first the movie seemed kind of boring, but as I paid more attention and it advanced it was amazing. It tells a story that nobody should miss. I talks about courage, how we should fight for what we want, and to live life to the fullest. One of my favorite scenes was when the English teacher, Mr. Keating, tells the students to tear the pages of a book apart. In every scene he is an excellent teacher, he makes the class entertaining and the students learn more than you could imagine. They do not only learn about English and poetry, but they learn about life. This movie is heartwarming; it has a full meaning, and is contains great poetry that has life lessons. I believe the most important lesson in this movie is to seize the day. This means to make out the most of each day, as if we would die tomorrow. This relates to doing what you like, what you enjoy the most in life. It is getting apart from what society expects from you, and doing what makes you happy. Another important lesson is to be you. We live in a society in which everyone expects something from you, but the most important thing is to be your own self. It will help in mental and spiritual growth. Challenging the status quo is another lesson. Change the way to see life, make a change in the world, in people. One last lesson is to stand up for others. This will not only be beneficial for the people you help but it will help you feel better. I believe everyone who watches the movie should enjoy it. I would recommend it to anyone who wants to watch it but especially for people above 13 years. This is because someone younger than this will maybe not understand well the meaning of the movie and will think it is boring. I would rate the movie PG-13. This movie is as great as the Oscar Winning movie "The Help". Both movies are delightfully different. In "The Help", as well as in "Dead Poets Society", the characters play an excellent role and the plot is entertaining and fun. Along the movie you will not get bored, it catches the audience's attention due to the fact that they treat interesting subjects. They are memorable movies, that once you watch them you will never forget the lesson and it will change your life. Both teach a wonderful lesson that everyone should take into account in their daily lives. Rating 8.7 The criticizer of this movie is Melania Chaves. She is an eleventh grade student at Lincoln School, Costa Rica. She is seventeen years old and will graduate next year from high school. She enjoys watching movies and hanging out with her friends. Her hobbies are playing tennis, running, and playing piano. Carpe Diem!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Dead Poets Society
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    HG Englisch AG
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Dead Poets Society"  A film that makes you think about your dreams and your decisions in life. Good or bad decisions "Carpe Diem  Seize the day." This statement is made by Mr. Keating, the special and unique teacher of "Welton Academy". After he had taught his students the sense of "Carpe Diem" and poetry, the way of thinking of many students changed and some of them started to finish what Mr. Keating had begun when he was at the same age. If you are looking for a film to watch it in class, you should have a look at "Dead Poets Society". It's a 1986 drama film which is directed by Peter Weir and is set at the "Welton Academy" in Vermont. It deals with the teacher Mr Keating who inspires his students with his special view of life and so they build a group called "Dead Poets Society". They meet each other at a cave near the school where they talk about poetry to express themselves. The cave scenes are very amusing and show the boys in funny situations during the meetings. The "new Dead Poets Society" consists of quite different personalities: Neil Perry, the self-confident founder of the group, the shy Todd Anderson, the noisy Richard Cameron, Steven Meeks, the clever one, Charlie Dalton and last but not least Knox Overstreet, a very friendly and polite student. You may find it easy to identify with one of the young boys because of the interesting characters. They can surprise you in different ways and can also make you laugh. If I was asked to rate this film on a scale from 0  10, I would give it 7 points as the film is easy to understand and all elements, which make life worth it like love, friendship or disagreement, are included. It's a classic with a shocking and unexpected ending.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Ristrictive lives
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Bernardo Rapazote Flores
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    There are certain films that get under your skin, never to come out. They change your life, subtly altering your perceptions of reality, almost always for the better. Dead Poets Society is one of those and it is one of the most emotional movies I've ever seen and gets me every time and it touches everyone, specially people whose dreams are held down by their restrictive parents. This movie touches and thrills us scene after scene -- the "Oh Captain, my captain" scene (Don't you have ANYONE in your life you respect so much that you'd stand up for﻿ them in any situation, stand beside them and support them no matter what? That's what this scene is all about.), Anderson's 'speech' to its classmates, the tragic and touching ending -- crafting one of my favorite movies ever.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Rhyme and Reason
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    leonlouisricci
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It was a different World in 1959 and Teaching Conventions and Learning Institutions were Ultra Conservative, especially by Today's Standards. The Film takes place at an Uppity Prep School with Traditions not easily toppled. Enter Free Thinking Teacher Mr. Keating who is about to "Shake Rattle and Roll". This is a, dare one say it, Poetic Movie with a smooth Patina and an Off-Beat Meter. But, ironically it stays quite standard in its portrayal of Student Rebellion and is nowhere near Kerouac, Ginsberg, or The Beats. Some reference or acknowledgment of "The Movement" might have been a bit closer to the Theme here and would have given it some Street Cred. This is by the Book, pretty much, with its often visited Story and is not without Flaws. Such as the completely out of context Page Ripping Scene that is so badly thought out that it almost makes the Movie Dumb Ass. Did the Writer actually think that Censorship and Book Destruction was an apt way to illustrate Free Thinking. That is unforgivable. An overrated Film, but a Very Good one. Schools were like that, Parents were like that, it is an Inconvenient Truth. In the Decade that followed, for better or worse (mostly better), conventions would collapse, traditions would tumble, and the Lip Service given to Freedom would be challenged. In this Fictional Story, all that was a little ahead of its Time and those involved suffered, like all dissidents.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Walk to the Beat of your Own Drum
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    thedozinglion
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Carpe Diem" is the line often quoted from the 1989 film Dead Poets Society to signify making the most out of life today. However for me the real theme of the movie is better encapsulated in the quotes by Thoreau and Frost on "walking to the beat of your own drum" and "following the path less travelled". A rebellion away from conformity towards individuality. Robin Williams is cast in the role of John Keating, the idealistic new teacher at Welton Academy a conservative prep school during the late 1950s. The school is a milder version of the Bunker Hill Military Academy of TAPS (1981), exacting control through "tradition, honour, discipline and excellence". In essence an expensive factory designed to process boys into men of standing and position at the expense of their uniqueness. Keating's teaching methods allow his students to struggle against not only the school and its lifeless dogma but also family and society's convention. Unlike Kevin Kline's William Hundert in The Emperor's Club (2002), Keating is not interested in shaping the character of the boys he teaches but unlocking their potential. Early in the movie he instructs his class to rip out the antiquated Introduction to Poetry in their textbooks which looks to take the soul out of the verse and replace it with a formula for understanding. This is much like the ethos of the school itself which seeks to remove the identity of the boys to supplant it with a tried and tested docility. The two main leads are played well by the then rising stars Ethan Hawke and Robert Sean Leonard. Their forming of the Dead Poets Society being the central form of rebellion in the film, a midnight meeting group off campus, breaking school regulations while allowing the boys to read the great freethinking poets of the past and their own adolescent compositions to one another. However the true rebel in the movie is not a student but Robin William's quixotic Keating, a free-spirited thinker who challenges the autocratic system in place and give the power of thought to his students. He is the polar opposite of Michael Redgrave's Crocker-Harris in The Browning Version (1951), a man whose passion for teaching has been eroded by years of apathy from his students leading to a teacher of rote rather than reason. Keating forms the midpoint in a trilogy of non-conformist characters played by Williams over a three year period starting with army disc jockey Adrian Cronauer in Good Morning Vietnam (1987) to Dr. Malcolm Sayer in Awakenings (1990). All three fight their prevailing systems (military, academia and medicine) to aid those within it. Williams is well able to embody the radical troublemaker effectively although his schizophrenic personality is toned down in each subsequent film. He is at his best as an actor when he is not playing for laughs but using comedy to flesh out his characters and tell a story. In a memorable scene Keating takes Thoreau's quote from Walden and has the boys acts it out: "If a man loses pace with his companions, perhaps it is because he hears a different drummer. Let him step to the music which he hears, however measured, or far away." Having the self-conscious boys walk around the school courtyard in their own style forces them to have awareness of their individuality much to the disapproval of the watching headmaster. Keating in the scene also quotes Robert Frosts poem The Road Not Taken: "Two roads diverged in a wood, and I I took the one less traveled by, And that has made all the difference." These quotes perfectly represent the concept of not accepting the majority voice as the absolute truth but instead putting yourself and your beliefs at the center. For what good is life if it is half lived without creativity and freedom of choice and action. However the power of freethinking that Keating gives to his student ends in tragedy. To fight against the system and society can be difficult for those unaccustomed to it. Keating is held responsible by the school for the loss due to the fear of the parents and staff of his methods, which have unleashed the raw potential in his students. Alas, there is no Scent of a Women (1992) defiance by the students when the headmaster looks for informers against Keating, all the boys of the Dead Poet Society sign, in effect, his expulsion papers. But the final scene does give hope that these young men will grow up with more than just honour and loyalty that the school demands. They will also have a heart and mind open to their own ideas and beliefs, they will never tamely believe or do what is told them but will seek out the truth as they find it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An instant OBSESSION...Unforgettable!!!!!!!!!!!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    barendbkj
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Never in my life have I ever experienced anything like Dead Poet's Society. This is a fine example how movies should be. It should be touching, it should be funny, it should be something an outsider can be proud of. And I was...I was proud of what they accomplished, that almost decades later it can still be seen as a drama worth beating (and none has beaten it so far). The story is about a group of boys who restart an old Poets club, that was once run by their English teacher, mister John Keating. During the course of the film we are introduced to Keating's majorly uplifting influence in the lives of the boys as he urges them on to follow their dreams and to, seize the day. CARPE DIEM!!! This movie had me hooked from beginning to end. I didn't want it to end. When it was finished I let out a breath of relief as I realized I was not actually part of the fun. But it pulled me in and forced me to feel what the boys were feeling. The acting was phenomenal. The story is timeless and the lessons learned from it, I will always treasure. "Oh captain, my captain. I tip my hat to you sir. WELL DONE."
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Dead poets society
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    audhusenitzad
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie means the world to me!! I watched it for the first time a few weeks ago and I have been moved ever since. I fell in love with every character, especially Charlie Dalton, "Nuwanda". I highly recommend this movie to anyone who wants to see a film to make your feelings go crazy. Through the few scenes located in Mr. Keatings English classroom, the boys become free thinkers and poets, for example, the first scene distinguishes Mr. Keating to be called "Oh Captain My Captain". In a similar setting, Keating encourages the boys to stand up on the desk so they may look at the world in another way.The final scene in which the boys show their support for their English teacher Mr. Keating by standing up on their desks saying "Oh Captain My Captain", closes up the film excellently. This movie changed my life and I hope you're moved by it as much as I was.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Leaves of Class
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    wes-connors
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    In 1959 Delaware (as Vermont), charismatic poetry teacher Robin Williams (as John Keating) arrives to begin work at the "Welton Academy" preparatory school for boys. An alumni of the school, Mr. Williams teaches poetry with uncommon zeal. To gain attention, he demands students tear out the pages of books written by essayists with whom he does not agree. To get participation, he invites students to stand on the teacher's desk. Williams does impersonations of Marlon Brando and John Wayne. His motto is "Seize the Day," a directive made popular by novelist Saul Bellow. Yes, this class is fun... Williams teaches the "dangers of conforming," and encourages students to think for themselves. When they learn Williams belonged to a clandestine club called the "Dead Poets Society" when he was a "Welton" student, the class decides to revive the group. They meet in a cave to read poetry by the masters - but, mainly, they just goof around. Playing the saxophone and sharing "Playboy"-type centerfolds accompany Walt Whitman. Because Williams'' influence extends perilously beyond the classroom, his "unorthodox teaching methods" get the popular teacher in trouble with school administrators... This above average production won good notices and award consideration for director Peter Weir and star Robin Williams. Originally, the teacher held back a secret; "Oscar"-winning writer Tom Schulman was persuaded to drop the idea, so we and the character are left with a gap. Williams' "Keating" is put on the sidelines in favor of the students. Nothing against the actors, who perform exceptionally, but they do look more like handsome young college-aged models than typical high-school aged boys. There is some physical diversity in the extended supporting cast, though. A few of the boys wear glasses... The main stars are sensitive writer Ethan Hawke (as Todd Anderson) and his roommate, aspiring actor Robert Sean Leonard (as Neil Perry). The next tier includes prankster Gale Hansen (as Charlie Dalton) and lovelorn Josh Charles (as Knox Overstreet). Although these players are almost interchangeable, the actors create distinguishable characters. Best of the remaining parts goes to Dylan Kussman (as Richard Cameron), who perversely turns out to be the group's real non-conformist. The film is too self-consciously calculating and manipulative to be fully masterful, but it sure looks nice. ******** Dead Poets Society (6/2/89) Peter Weir ~ Robin Williams, Ethan Hawke, Robert Sean Leonard, Gale Hansen
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Young boys reading poetry during their play-time..... come onnnn.......
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Tracy Winters
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Robin Williams -- you know, I really want to like him, and in this film, I do, though I usually don't like the kinds of films he chooses to participate in ('Good Will Hunting' is by far his best role). Here's a supposedly enigmatic teacher (Williams) motivating his teenage boy students to read poetry in their leisure time. That was unbelievable. I could see them doing this if between poems, they gave each other oral sex or something, but unfortunately, that does not happen in this movie. What does happen is a predictable script by Tom Shulman. We see a plethora of different, but typical characters.... the snitch (Dylan Kussman), the rebellious kid (Gale Hanson), the charming boy (Josh Charles), and even a self-effacing young man (Ethan Hawke) who stutters until the hero of the story (Williams) gives the kid a reason to live, except when Wiliams leaves the school, the kid starts stuttering again (i.e. 'One Flew Over the Cuckoo's Nest'). So much for originality. The final scene is so sappy, you'll want to rinse out your pie-hole with mouthwash.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Much Better Than Expected!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    g-bodyl
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Dead Poets Society is a much better film than I anticipated. Honestly, I thought this would be a film all about poetry and I loathe poetry, so I didn't give this film a chance. I'm glad I did because this is not a film about poetry, but about a group of college kids who have been encouraged to follow their own dreams. This film is a well-made drama that will make you smile, laugh, and cry. It also has one of the most unexpected scenes I have seen in awhile. Peter Weir's film is about a group of college kids who are inspired by their English professor, John Keating. Keating tells his kids who follow their dreams and they do just that. Unfortunately, the dean and the parents have other ideas for their kids. Robin Williams gives a true, inspirational performance as John Keating. He is the teacher that is common nowadays, but someone my parents would yearn to have. Ethan Hawke delivers a stand out performance as one of the kids and so does Robert Sean Leonard. Overall, this is a truly inspirational film that has one simple message for all people, especially younger ones. This message is "Follow our dreams and don't let anyone tell you what you can or can't do." This message should have been used back in the 1950's-1960's. This film is well-acted, has great direction, and should leave a tear or two. I rate this film 9/10.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Inspiring and Life changing
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Melania Chaves
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Carpe Diem": Seize the day. This is the lesson, John Keating, the English schoolteacher wants to convey to his students. This movie is one of the best movies I've ever watched. It helps people to face problems and live life as if there was no tomorrow. It teaches us how to enjoy every aspect of life and let nothing ruin what makes us really happy. It is not only entertaining, but it teaches a great life lesson, which is to think for ourselves and stand up for that in which we believe. It is incomparable with other movies and should definitely be watched by everyone. Dead Poets Society was nominated for four Academy Awards. It is from the genre of drama and although it is a 1989 movie, the picture is great and the movie is so stimulating and outstanding, the picture won't even be a problem. The movie takes place in 1959 in the Welton Academy. In this school education is very strict and students are expected to behave in a highly educated and responsible manner. Several of the students have a different opinion regarding the school's education process. When the new teacher comes, everything changes. John Keating is an unconventional teacher who tells his students to tear out the pages of the books and asks his students to stand on their desks to see the world from a different perspective. He introduces the boys to poetry and teaches them new philosophies about life. He encourages his students to follow their dreams, and to not follow what people expect them to do, but what makes them happy. The characters in this film are so realistic; they create an impact in the audience. I hate movies with flat characters and in this movie the character development is really outstanding. Robin Williams plays an excellent job as the professor and interacts very well with the students. In his early life, Williams studied political science before studying theatre in the Julliard School. He later on performed in nightclubs where he was discovered for the role of Mork on the TV series "Happy Days". Another important character is Robert Leonard who plays the role of Neil Perry. He deserves acknowledgment and fame and is mostly known as Dr. James Wilson on House M.D. Ethan Hawke is another important character in the movie. He plays the role of Todd Anderson in the movie. Ethan was born on 6 November 1970 in Austin Texas. His acting career started as a mix of theatre work and a mix of serious and commercial movies. All of these actors play an excellent role in the movie. They create an exciting plot, and the move builds up perfectly. At first the movie seemed kind of boring, but as I paid more attention and it advanced it was amazing. It tells a story that nobody should miss. I talks about courage, how we should fight for what we want, and to live life to the fullest. One of my favorite scenes was when the English teacher, Mr. Keating, tells the students to tear the pages of a book apart. In every scene he is an excellent teacher, he makes the class entertaining and the students learn more than you could imagine. They do not only learn about English and poetry, but they learn about life. This movie is heartwarming; it has a full meaning, and is contains great poetry that has life lessons. I believe the most important lesson in this movie is to seize the day. This means to make out the most of each day, as if we would die tomorrow. This relates to doing what you like, what you enjoy the most in life. It is getting apart from what society expects from you, and doing what makes you happy. Another important lesson is to be you. We live in a society in which everyone expects something from you, but the most important thing is to be your own self. It will help in mental and spiritual growth. Challenging the status quo is another lesson. Change the way to see life, make a change in the world, in people. One last lesson is to stand up for others. This will not only be beneficial for the people you help but it will help you feel better. I believe everyone who watches the movie should enjoy it. I would recommend it to anyone who wants to watch it but especially for people above 13 years. This is because someone younger than this will maybe not understand well the meaning of the movie and will think it is boring. I would rate the movie PG-13. This movie is as great as the Oscar Winning movie "The Help". Both movies are delightfully different. In "The Help", as well as in "Dead Poets Society", the characters play an excellent role and the plot is entertaining and fun. Along the movie you will not get bored, it catches the audience's attention due to the fact that they treat interesting subjects. They are memorable movies, that once you watch them you will never forget the lesson and it will change your life. Both teach a wonderful lesson that everyone should take into account in their daily lives. Rating 8.7 The criticizer of this movie is Melania Chaves. She is an eleventh grade student at Lincoln School, Costa Rica. She is seventeen years old and will graduate next year from high school. She enjoys watching movies and hanging out with her friends. Her hobbies are playing tennis, running, and playing piano. Carpe Diem!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Dead Poets Society
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    HG Englisch AG
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Dead Poets Society"  A film that makes you think about your dreams and your decisions in life. Good or bad decisions "Carpe Diem  Seize the day." This statement is made by Mr. Keating, the special and unique teacher of "Welton Academy". After he had taught his students the sense of "Carpe Diem" and poetry, the way of thinking of many students changed and some of them started to finish what Mr. Keating had begun when he was at the same age. If you are looking for a film to watch it in class, you should have a look at "Dead Poets Society". It's a 1986 drama film which is directed by Peter Weir and is set at the "Welton Academy" in Vermont. It deals with the teacher Mr Keating who inspires his students with his special view of life and so they build a group called "Dead Poets Society". They meet each other at a cave near the school where they talk about poetry to express themselves. The cave scenes are very amusing and show the boys in funny situations during the meetings. The "new Dead Poets Society" consists of quite different personalities: Neil Perry, the self-confident founder of the group, the shy Todd Anderson, the noisy Richard Cameron, Steven Meeks, the clever one, Charlie Dalton and last but not least Knox Overstreet, a very friendly and polite student. You may find it easy to identify with one of the young boys because of the interesting characters. They can surprise you in different ways and can also make you laugh. If I was asked to rate this film on a scale from 0  10, I would give it 7 points as the film is easy to understand and all elements, which make life worth it like love, friendship or disagreement, are included. It's a classic with a shocking and unexpected ending.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Ristrictive lives
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Bernardo Rapazote Flores
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    There are certain films that get under your skin, never to come out. They change your life, subtly altering your perceptions of reality, almost always for the better. Dead Poets Society is one of those and it is one of the most emotional movies I've ever seen and gets me every time and it touches everyone, specially people whose dreams are held down by their restrictive parents. This movie touches and thrills us scene after scene -- the "Oh Captain, my captain" scene (Don't you have ANYONE in your life you respect so much that you'd stand up for﻿ them in any situation, stand beside them and support them no matter what? That's what this scene is all about.), Anderson's 'speech' to its classmates, the tragic and touching ending -- crafting one of my favorite movies ever.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Rhyme and Reason
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    leonlouisricci
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It was a different World in 1959 and Teaching Conventions and Learning Institutions were Ultra Conservative, especially by Today's Standards. The Film takes place at an Uppity Prep School with Traditions not easily toppled. Enter Free Thinking Teacher Mr. Keating who is about to "Shake Rattle and Roll". This is a, dare one say it, Poetic Movie with a smooth Patina and an Off-Beat Meter. But, ironically it stays quite standard in its portrayal of Student Rebellion and is nowhere near Kerouac, Ginsberg, or The Beats. Some reference or acknowledgment of "The Movement" might have been a bit closer to the Theme here and would have given it some Street Cred. This is by the Book, pretty much, with its often visited Story and is not without Flaws. Such as the completely out of context Page Ripping Scene that is so badly thought out that it almost makes the Movie Dumb Ass. Did the Writer actually think that Censorship and Book Destruction was an apt way to illustrate Free Thinking. That is unforgivable. An overrated Film, but a Very Good one. Schools were like that, Parents were like that, it is an Inconvenient Truth. In the Decade that followed, for better or worse (mostly better), conventions would collapse, traditions would tumble, and the Lip Service given to Freedom would be challenged. In this Fictional Story, all that was a little ahead of its Time and those involved suffered, like all dissidents.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Walk to the Beat of your Own Drum
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    thedozinglion
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Carpe Diem" is the line often quoted from the 1989 film Dead Poets Society to signify making the most out of life today. However for me the real theme of the movie is better encapsulated in the quotes by Thoreau and Frost on "walking to the beat of your own drum" and "following the path less travelled". A rebellion away from conformity towards individuality. Robin Williams is cast in the role of John Keating, the idealistic new teacher at Welton Academy a conservative prep school during the late 1950s. The school is a milder version of the Bunker Hill Military Academy of TAPS (1981), exacting control through "tradition, honour, discipline and excellence". In essence an expensive factory designed to process boys into men of standing and position at the expense of their uniqueness. Keating's teaching methods allow his students to struggle against not only the school and its lifeless dogma but also family and society's convention. Unlike Kevin Kline's William Hundert in The Emperor's Club (2002), Keating is not interested in shaping the character of the boys he teaches but unlocking their potential. Early in the movie he instructs his class to rip out the antiquated Introduction to Poetry in their textbooks which looks to take the soul out of the verse and replace it with a formula for understanding. This is much like the ethos of the school itself which seeks to remove the identity of the boys to supplant it with a tried and tested docility. The two main leads are played well by the then rising stars Ethan Hawke and Robert Sean Leonard. Their forming of the Dead Poets Society being the central form of rebellion in the film, a midnight meeting group off campus, breaking school regulations while allowing the boys to read the great freethinking poets of the past and their own adolescent compositions to one another. However the true rebel in the movie is not a student but Robin William's quixotic Keating, a free-spirited thinker who challenges the autocratic system in place and give the power of thought to his students. He is the polar opposite of Michael Redgrave's Crocker-Harris in The Browning Version (1951), a man whose passion for teaching has been eroded by years of apathy from his students leading to a teacher of rote rather than reason. Keating forms the midpoint in a trilogy of non-conformist characters played by Williams over a three year period starting with army disc jockey Adrian Cronauer in Good Morning Vietnam (1987) to Dr. Malcolm Sayer in Awakenings (1990). All three fight their prevailing systems (military, academia and medicine) to aid those within it. Williams is well able to embody the radical troublemaker effectively although his schizophrenic personality is toned down in each subsequent film. He is at his best as an actor when he is not playing for laughs but using comedy to flesh out his characters and tell a story. In a memorable scene Keating takes Thoreau's quote from Walden and has the boys acts it out: "If a man loses pace with his companions, perhaps it is because he hears a different drummer. Let him step to the music which he hears, however measured, or far away." Having the self-conscious boys walk around the school courtyard in their own style forces them to have awareness of their individuality much to the disapproval of the watching headmaster. Keating in the scene also quotes Robert Frosts poem The Road Not Taken: "Two roads diverged in a wood, and I I took the one less traveled by, And that has made all the difference." These quotes perfectly represent the concept of not accepting the majority voice as the absolute truth but instead putting yourself and your beliefs at the center. For what good is life if it is half lived without creativity and freedom of choice and action. However the power of freethinking that Keating gives to his student ends in tragedy. To fight against the system and society can be difficult for those unaccustomed to it. Keating is held responsible by the school for the loss due to the fear of the parents and staff of his methods, which have unleashed the raw potential in his students. Alas, there is no Scent of a Women (1992) defiance by the students when the headmaster looks for informers against Keating, all the boys of the Dead Poet Society sign, in effect, his expulsion papers. But the final scene does give hope that these young men will grow up with more than just honour and loyalty that the school demands. They will also have a heart and mind open to their own ideas and beliefs, they will never tamely believe or do what is told them but will seek out the truth as they find it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An instant OBSESSION...Unforgettable!!!!!!!!!!!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    barendbkj
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Never in my life have I ever experienced anything like Dead Poet's Society. This is a fine example how movies should be. It should be touching, it should be funny, it should be something an outsider can be proud of. And I was...I was proud of what they accomplished, that almost decades later it can still be seen as a drama worth beating (and none has beaten it so far). The story is about a group of boys who restart an old Poets club, that was once run by their English teacher, mister John Keating. During the course of the film we are introduced to Keating's majorly uplifting influence in the lives of the boys as he urges them on to follow their dreams and to, seize the day. CARPE DIEM!!! This movie had me hooked from beginning to end. I didn't want it to end. When it was finished I let out a breath of relief as I realized I was not actually part of the fun. But it pulled me in and forced me to feel what the boys were feeling. The acting was phenomenal. The story is timeless and the lessons learned from it, I will always treasure. "Oh captain, my captain. I tip my hat to you sir. WELL DONE."
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Dead poets society
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    audhusenitzad
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie means the world to me!! I watched it for the first time a few weeks ago and I have been moved ever since. I fell in love with every character, especially Charlie Dalton, "Nuwanda". I highly recommend this movie to anyone who wants to see a film to make your feelings go crazy. Through the few scenes located in Mr. Keatings English classroom, the boys become free thinkers and poets, for example, the first scene distinguishes Mr. Keating to be called "Oh Captain My Captain". In a similar setting, Keating encourages the boys to stand up on the desk so they may look at the world in another way.The final scene in which the boys show their support for their English teacher Mr. Keating by standing up on their desks saying "Oh Captain My Captain", closes up the film excellently. This movie changed my life and I hope you're moved by it as much as I was.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Leaves of Class
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    wes-connors
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    In 1959 Delaware (as Vermont), charismatic poetry teacher Robin Williams (as John Keating) arrives to begin work at the "Welton Academy" preparatory school for boys. An alumni of the school, Mr. Williams teaches poetry with uncommon zeal. To gain attention, he demands students tear out the pages of books written by essayists with whom he does not agree. To get participation, he invites students to stand on the teacher's desk. Williams does impersonations of Marlon Brando and John Wayne. His motto is "Seize the Day," a directive made popular by novelist Saul Bellow. Yes, this class is fun... Williams teaches the "dangers of conforming," and encourages students to think for themselves. When they learn Williams belonged to a clandestine club called the "Dead Poets Society" when he was a "Welton" student, the class decides to revive the group. They meet in a cave to read poetry by the masters - but, mainly, they just goof around. Playing the saxophone and sharing "Playboy"-type centerfolds accompany Walt Whitman. Because Williams'' influence extends perilously beyond the classroom, his "unorthodox teaching methods" get the popular teacher in trouble with school administrators... This above average production won good notices and award consideration for director Peter Weir and star Robin Williams. Originally, the teacher held back a secret; "Oscar"-winning writer Tom Schulman was persuaded to drop the idea, so we and the character are left with a gap. Williams' "Keating" is put on the sidelines in favor of the students. Nothing against the actors, who perform exceptionally, but they do look more like handsome young college-aged models than typical high-school aged boys. There is some physical diversity in the extended supporting cast, though. A few of the boys wear glasses... The main stars are sensitive writer Ethan Hawke (as Todd Anderson) and his roommate, aspiring actor Robert Sean Leonard (as Neil Perry). The next tier includes prankster Gale Hansen (as Charlie Dalton) and lovelorn Josh Charles (as Knox Overstreet). Although these players are almost interchangeable, the actors create distinguishable characters. Best of the remaining parts goes to Dylan Kussman (as Richard Cameron), who perversely turns out to be the group's real non-conformist. The film is too self-consciously calculating and manipulative to be fully masterful, but it sure looks nice. ******** Dead Poets Society (6/2/89) Peter Weir ~ Robin Williams, Ethan Hawke, Robert Sean Leonard, Gale Hansen
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Young boys reading poetry during their play-time..... come onnnn.......
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Tracy Winters
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Robin Williams -- you know, I really want to like him, and in this film, I do, though I usually don't like the kinds of films he chooses to participate in ('Good Will Hunting' is by far his best role). Here's a supposedly enigmatic teacher (Williams) motivating his teenage boy students to read poetry in their leisure time. That was unbelievable. I could see them doing this if between poems, they gave each other oral sex or something, but unfortunately, that does not happen in this movie. What does happen is a predictable script by Tom Shulman. We see a plethora of different, but typical characters.... the snitch (Dylan Kussman), the rebellious kid (Gale Hanson), the charming boy (Josh Charles), and even a self-effacing young man (Ethan Hawke) who stutters until the hero of the story (Williams) gives the kid a reason to live, except when Wiliams leaves the school, the kid starts stuttering again (i.e. 'One Flew Over the Cuckoo's Nest'). So much for originality. The final scene is so sappy, you'll want to rinse out your pie-hole with mouthwash.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Much Better Than Expected!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    g-bodyl
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Dead Poets Society is a much better film than I anticipated. Honestly, I thought this would be a film all about poetry and I loathe poetry, so I didn't give this film a chance. I'm glad I did because this is not a film about poetry, but about a group of college kids who have been encouraged to follow their own dreams. This film is a well-made drama that will make you smile, laugh, and cry. It also has one of the most unexpected scenes I have seen in awhile. Peter Weir's film is about a group of college kids who are inspired by their English professor, John Keating. Keating tells his kids who follow their dreams and they do just that. Unfortunately, the dean and the parents have other ideas for their kids. Robin Williams gives a true, inspirational performance as John Keating. He is the teacher that is common nowadays, but someone my parents would yearn to have. Ethan Hawke delivers a stand out performance as one of the kids and so does Robert Sean Leonard. Overall, this is a truly inspirational film that has one simple message for all people, especially younger ones. This message is "Follow our dreams and don't let anyone tell you what you can or can't do." This message should have been used back in the 1950's-1960's. This film is well-acted, has great direction, and should leave a tear or two. I rate this film 9/10.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Inspiring and Life changing
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Melania Chaves
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Carpe Diem": Seize the day. This is the lesson, John Keating, the English schoolteacher wants to convey to his students. This movie is one of the best movies I've ever watched. It helps people to face problems and live life as if there was no tomorrow. It teaches us how to enjoy every aspect of life and let nothing ruin what makes us really happy. It is not only entertaining, but it teaches a great life lesson, which is to think for ourselves and stand up for that in which we believe. It is incomparable with other movies and should definitely be watched by everyone. Dead Poets Society was nominated for four Academy Awards. It is from the genre of drama and although it is a 1989 movie, the picture is great and the movie is so stimulating and outstanding, the picture won't even be a problem. The movie takes place in 1959 in the Welton Academy. In this school education is very strict and students are expected to behave in a highly educated and responsible manner. Several of the students have a different opinion regarding the school's education process. When the new teacher comes, everything changes. John Keating is an unconventional teacher who tells his students to tear out the pages of the books and asks his students to stand on their desks to see the world from a different perspective. He introduces the boys to poetry and teaches them new philosophies about life. He encourages his students to follow their dreams, and to not follow what people expect them to do, but what makes them happy. The characters in this film are so realistic; they create an impact in the audience. I hate movies with flat characters and in this movie the character development is really outstanding. Robin Williams plays an excellent job as the professor and interacts very well with the students. In his early life, Williams studied political science before studying theatre in the Julliard School. He later on performed in nightclubs where he was discovered for the role of Mork on the TV series "Happy Days". Another important character is Robert Leonard who plays the role of Neil Perry. He deserves acknowledgment and fame and is mostly known as Dr. James Wilson on House M.D. Ethan Hawke is another important character in the movie. He plays the role of Todd Anderson in the movie. Ethan was born on 6 November 1970 in Austin Texas. His acting career started as a mix of theatre work and a mix of serious and commercial movies. All of these actors play an excellent role in the movie. They create an exciting plot, and the move builds up perfectly. At first the movie seemed kind of boring, but as I paid more attention and it advanced it was amazing. It tells a story that nobody should miss. I talks about courage, how we should fight for what we want, and to live life to the fullest. One of my favorite scenes was when the English teacher, Mr. Keating, tells the students to tear the pages of a book apart. In every scene he is an excellent teacher, he makes the class entertaining and the students learn more than you could imagine. They do not only learn about English and poetry, but they learn about life. This movie is heartwarming; it has a full meaning, and is contains great poetry that has life lessons. I believe the most important lesson in this movie is to seize the day. This means to make out the most of each day, as if we would die tomorrow. This relates to doing what you like, what you enjoy the most in life. It is getting apart from what society expects from you, and doing what makes you happy. Another important lesson is to be you. We live in a society in which everyone expects something from you, but the most important thing is to be your own self. It will help in mental and spiritual growth. Challenging the status quo is another lesson. Change the way to see life, make a change in the world, in people. One last lesson is to stand up for others. This will not only be beneficial for the people you help but it will help you feel better. I believe everyone who watches the movie should enjoy it. I would recommend it to anyone who wants to watch it but especially for people above 13 years. This is because someone younger than this will maybe not understand well the meaning of the movie and will think it is boring. I would rate the movie PG-13. This movie is as great as the Oscar Winning movie "The Help". Both movies are delightfully different. In "The Help", as well as in "Dead Poets Society", the characters play an excellent role and the plot is entertaining and fun. Along the movie you will not get bored, it catches the audience's attention due to the fact that they treat interesting subjects. They are memorable movies, that once you watch them you will never forget the lesson and it will change your life. Both teach a wonderful lesson that everyone should take into account in their daily lives. Rating 8.7 The criticizer of this movie is Melania Chaves. She is an eleventh grade student at Lincoln School, Costa Rica. She is seventeen years old and will graduate next year from high school. She enjoys watching movies and hanging out with her friends. Her hobbies are playing tennis, running, and playing piano. Carpe Diem!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Dead Poets Society
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    HG Englisch AG
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Dead Poets Society"  A film that makes you think about your dreams and your decisions in life. Good or bad decisions "Carpe Diem  Seize the day." This statement is made by Mr. Keating, the special and unique teacher of "Welton Academy". After he had taught his students the sense of "Carpe Diem" and poetry, the way of thinking of many students changed and some of them started to finish what Mr. Keating had begun when he was at the same age. If you are looking for a film to watch it in class, you should have a look at "Dead Poets Society". It's a 1986 drama film which is directed by Peter Weir and is set at the "Welton Academy" in Vermont. It deals with the teacher Mr Keating who inspires his students with his special view of life and so they build a group called "Dead Poets Society". They meet each other at a cave near the school where they talk about poetry to express themselves. The cave scenes are very amusing and show the boys in funny situations during the meetings. The "new Dead Poets Society" consists of quite different personalities: Neil Perry, the self-confident founder of the group, the shy Todd Anderson, the noisy Richard Cameron, Steven Meeks, the clever one, Charlie Dalton and last but not least Knox Overstreet, a very friendly and polite student. You may find it easy to identify with one of the young boys because of the interesting characters. They can surprise you in different ways and can also make you laugh. If I was asked to rate this film on a scale from 0  10, I would give it 7 points as the film is easy to understand and all elements, which make life worth it like love, friendship or disagreement, are included. It's a classic with a shocking and unexpected ending.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Ristrictive lives
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Bernardo Rapazote Flores
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    There are certain films that get under your skin, never to come out. They change your life, subtly altering your perceptions of reality, almost always for the better. Dead Poets Society is one of those and it is one of the most emotional movies I've ever seen and gets me every time and it touches everyone, specially people whose dreams are held down by their restrictive parents. This movie touches and thrills us scene after scene -- the "Oh Captain, my captain" scene (Don't you have ANYONE in your life you respect so much that you'd stand up for﻿ them in any situation, stand beside them and support them no matter what? That's what this scene is all about.), Anderson's 'speech' to its classmates, the tragic and touching ending -- crafting one of my favorite movies ever.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Rhyme and Reason
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    leonlouisricci
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It was a different World in 1959 and Teaching Conventions and Learning Institutions were Ultra Conservative, especially by Today's Standards. The Film takes place at an Uppity Prep School with Traditions not easily toppled. Enter Free Thinking Teacher Mr. Keating who is about to "Shake Rattle and Roll". This is a, dare one say it, Poetic Movie with a smooth Patina and an Off-Beat Meter. But, ironically it stays quite standard in its portrayal of Student Rebellion and is nowhere near Kerouac, Ginsberg, or The Beats. Some reference or acknowledgment of "The Movement" might have been a bit closer to the Theme here and would have given it some Street Cred. This is by the Book, pretty much, with its often visited Story and is not without Flaws. Such as the completely out of context Page Ripping Scene that is so badly thought out that it almost makes the Movie Dumb Ass. Did the Writer actually think that Censorship and Book Destruction was an apt way to illustrate Free Thinking. That is unforgivable. An overrated Film, but a Very Good one. Schools were like that, Parents were like that, it is an Inconvenient Truth. In the Decade that followed, for better or worse (mostly better), conventions would collapse, traditions would tumble, and the Lip Service given to Freedom would be challenged. In this Fictional Story, all that was a little ahead of its Time and those involved suffered, like all dissidents.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Walk to the Beat of your Own Drum
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    thedozinglion
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Carpe Diem" is the line often quoted from the 1989 film Dead Poets Society to signify making the most out of life today. However for me the real theme of the movie is better encapsulated in the quotes by Thoreau and Frost on "walking to the beat of your own drum" and "following the path less travelled". A rebellion away from conformity towards individuality. Robin Williams is cast in the role of John Keating, the idealistic new teacher at Welton Academy a conservative prep school during the late 1950s. The school is a milder version of the Bunker Hill Military Academy of TAPS (1981), exacting control through "tradition, honour, discipline and excellence". In essence an expensive factory designed to process boys into men of standing and position at the expense of their uniqueness. Keating's teaching methods allow his students to struggle against not only the school and its lifeless dogma but also family and society's convention. Unlike Kevin Kline's William Hundert in The Emperor's Club (2002), Keating is not interested in shaping the character of the boys he teaches but unlocking their potential. Early in the movie he instructs his class to rip out the antiquated Introduction to Poetry in their textbooks which looks to take the soul out of the verse and replace it with a formula for understanding. This is much like the ethos of the school itself which seeks to remove the identity of the boys to supplant it with a tried and tested docility. The two main leads are played well by the then rising stars Ethan Hawke and Robert Sean Leonard. Their forming of the Dead Poets Society being the central form of rebellion in the film, a midnight meeting group off campus, breaking school regulations while allowing the boys to read the great freethinking poets of the past and their own adolescent compositions to one another. However the true rebel in the movie is not a student but Robin William's quixotic Keating, a free-spirited thinker who challenges the autocratic system in place and give the power of thought to his students. He is the polar opposite of Michael Redgrave's Crocker-Harris in The Browning Version (1951), a man whose passion for teaching has been eroded by years of apathy from his students leading to a teacher of rote rather than reason. Keating forms the midpoint in a trilogy of non-conformist characters played by Williams over a three year period starting with army disc jockey Adrian Cronauer in Good Morning Vietnam (1987) to Dr. Malcolm Sayer in Awakenings (1990). All three fight their prevailing systems (military, academia and medicine) to aid those within it. Williams is well able to embody the radical troublemaker effectively although his schizophrenic personality is toned down in each subsequent film. He is at his best as an actor when he is not playing for laughs but using comedy to flesh out his characters and tell a story. In a memorable scene Keating takes Thoreau's quote from Walden and has the boys acts it out: "If a man loses pace with his companions, perhaps it is because he hears a different drummer. Let him step to the music which he hears, however measured, or far away." Having the self-conscious boys walk around the school courtyard in their own style forces them to have awareness of their individuality much to the disapproval of the watching headmaster. Keating in the scene also quotes Robert Frosts poem The Road Not Taken: "Two roads diverged in a wood, and I I took the one less traveled by, And that has made all the difference." These quotes perfectly represent the concept of not accepting the majority voice as the absolute truth but instead putting yourself and your beliefs at the center. For what good is life if it is half lived without creativity and freedom of choice and action. However the power of freethinking that Keating gives to his student ends in tragedy. To fight against the system and society can be difficult for those unaccustomed to it. Keating is held responsible by the school for the loss due to the fear of the parents and staff of his methods, which have unleashed the raw potential in his students. Alas, there is no Scent of a Women (1992) defiance by the students when the headmaster looks for informers against Keating, all the boys of the Dead Poet Society sign, in effect, his expulsion papers. But the final scene does give hope that these young men will grow up with more than just honour and loyalty that the school demands. They will also have a heart and mind open to their own ideas and beliefs, they will never tamely believe or do what is told them but will seek out the truth as they find it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An instant OBSESSION...Unforgettable!!!!!!!!!!!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    barendbkj
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Never in my life have I ever experienced anything like Dead Poet's Society. This is a fine example how movies should be. It should be touching, it should be funny, it should be something an outsider can be proud of. And I was...I was proud of what they accomplished, that almost decades later it can still be seen as a drama worth beating (and none has beaten it so far). The story is about a group of boys who restart an old Poets club, that was once run by their English teacher, mister John Keating. During the course of the film we are introduced to Keating's majorly uplifting influence in the lives of the boys as he urges them on to follow their dreams and to, seize the day. CARPE DIEM!!! This movie had me hooked from beginning to end. I didn't want it to end. When it was finished I let out a breath of relief as I realized I was not actually part of the fun. But it pulled me in and forced me to feel what the boys were feeling. The acting was phenomenal. The story is timeless and the lessons learned from it, I will always treasure. "Oh captain, my captain. I tip my hat to you sir. WELL DONE."
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Dead poets society
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    audhusenitzad
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie means the world to me!! I watched it for the first time a few weeks ago and I have been moved ever since. I fell in love with every character, especially Charlie Dalton, "Nuwanda". I highly recommend this movie to anyone who wants to see a film to make your feelings go crazy. Through the few scenes located in Mr. Keatings English classroom, the boys become free thinkers and poets, for example, the first scene distinguishes Mr. Keating to be called "Oh Captain My Captain". In a similar setting, Keating encourages the boys to stand up on the desk so they may look at the world in another way.The final scene in which the boys show their support for their English teacher Mr. Keating by standing up on their desks saying "Oh Captain My Captain", closes up the film excellently. This movie changed my life and I hope you're moved by it as much as I was.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Leaves of Class
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    wes-connors
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    In 1959 Delaware (as Vermont), charismatic poetry teacher Robin Williams (as John Keating) arrives to begin work at the "Welton Academy" preparatory school for boys. An alumni of the school, Mr. Williams teaches poetry with uncommon zeal. To gain attention, he demands students tear out the pages of books written by essayists with whom he does not agree. To get participation, he invites students to stand on the teacher's desk. Williams does impersonations of Marlon Brando and John Wayne. His motto is "Seize the Day," a directive made popular by novelist Saul Bellow. Yes, this class is fun... Williams teaches the "dangers of conforming," and encourages students to think for themselves. When they learn Williams belonged to a clandestine club called the "Dead Poets Society" when he was a "Welton" student, the class decides to revive the group. They meet in a cave to read poetry by the masters - but, mainly, they just goof around. Playing the saxophone and sharing "Playboy"-type centerfolds accompany Walt Whitman. Because Williams'' influence extends perilously beyond the classroom, his "unorthodox teaching methods" get the popular teacher in trouble with school administrators... This above average production won good notices and award consideration for director Peter Weir and star Robin Williams. Originally, the teacher held back a secret; "Oscar"-winning writer Tom Schulman was persuaded to drop the idea, so we and the character are left with a gap. Williams' "Keating" is put on the sidelines in favor of the students. Nothing against the actors, who perform exceptionally, but they do look more like handsome young college-aged models than typical high-school aged boys. There is some physical diversity in the extended supporting cast, though. A few of the boys wear glasses... The main stars are sensitive writer Ethan Hawke (as Todd Anderson) and his roommate, aspiring actor Robert Sean Leonard (as Neil Perry). The next tier includes prankster Gale Hansen (as Charlie Dalton) and lovelorn Josh Charles (as Knox Overstreet). Although these players are almost interchangeable, the actors create distinguishable characters. Best of the remaining parts goes to Dylan Kussman (as Richard Cameron), who perversely turns out to be the group's real non-conformist. The film is too self-consciously calculating and manipulative to be fully masterful, but it sure looks nice. ******** Dead Poets Society (6/2/89) Peter Weir ~ Robin Williams, Ethan Hawke, Robert Sean Leonard, Gale Hansen
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Young boys reading poetry during their play-time..... come onnnn.......
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Tracy Winters
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Robin Williams -- you know, I really want to like him, and in this film, I do, though I usually don't like the kinds of films he chooses to participate in ('Good Will Hunting' is by far his best role). Here's a supposedly enigmatic teacher (Williams) motivating his teenage boy students to read poetry in their leisure time. That was unbelievable. I could see them doing this if between poems, they gave each other oral sex or something, but unfortunately, that does not happen in this movie. What does happen is a predictable script by Tom Shulman. We see a plethora of different, but typical characters.... the snitch (Dylan Kussman), the rebellious kid (Gale Hanson), the charming boy (Josh Charles), and even a self-effacing young man (Ethan Hawke) who stutters until the hero of the story (Williams) gives the kid a reason to live, except when Wiliams leaves the school, the kid starts stuttering again (i.e. 'One Flew Over the Cuckoo's Nest'). So much for originality. The final scene is so sappy, you'll want to rinse out your pie-hole with mouthwash.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Much Better Than Expected!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    g-bodyl
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Dead Poets Society is a much better film than I anticipated. Honestly, I thought this would be a film all about poetry and I loathe poetry, so I didn't give this film a chance. I'm glad I did because this is not a film about poetry, but about a group of college kids who have been encouraged to follow their own dreams. This film is a well-made drama that will make you smile, laugh, and cry. It also has one of the most unexpected scenes I have seen in awhile. Peter Weir's film is about a group of college kids who are inspired by their English professor, John Keating. Keating tells his kids who follow their dreams and they do just that. Unfortunately, the dean and the parents have other ideas for their kids. Robin Williams gives a true, inspirational performance as John Keating. He is the teacher that is common nowadays, but someone my parents would yearn to have. Ethan Hawke delivers a stand out performance as one of the kids and so does Robert Sean Leonard. Overall, this is a truly inspirational film that has one simple message for all people, especially younger ones. This message is "Follow our dreams and don't let anyone tell you what you can or can't do." This message should have been used back in the 1950's-1960's. This film is well-acted, has great direction, and should leave a tear or two. I rate this film 9/10.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Inspiring and Life changing
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Melania Chaves
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Carpe Diem": Seize the day. This is the lesson, John Keating, the English schoolteacher wants to convey to his students. This movie is one of the best movies I've ever watched. It helps people to face problems and live life as if there was no tomorrow. It teaches us how to enjoy every aspect of life and let nothing ruin what makes us really happy. It is not only entertaining, but it teaches a great life lesson, which is to think for ourselves and stand up for that in which we believe. It is incomparable with other movies and should definitely be watched by everyone. Dead Poets Society was nominated for four Academy Awards. It is from the genre of drama and although it is a 1989 movie, the picture is great and the movie is so stimulating and outstanding, the picture won't even be a problem. The movie takes place in 1959 in the Welton Academy. In this school education is very strict and students are expected to behave in a highly educated and responsible manner. Several of the students have a different opinion regarding the school's education process. When the new teacher comes, everything changes. John Keating is an unconventional teacher who tells his students to tear out the pages of the books and asks his students to stand on their desks to see the world from a different perspective. He introduces the boys to poetry and teaches them new philosophies about life. He encourages his students to follow their dreams, and to not follow what people expect them to do, but what makes them happy. The characters in this film are so realistic; they create an impact in the audience. I hate movies with flat characters and in this movie the character development is really outstanding. Robin Williams plays an excellent job as the professor and interacts very well with the students. In his early life, Williams studied political science before studying theatre in the Julliard School. He later on performed in nightclubs where he was discovered for the role of Mork on the TV series "Happy Days". Another important character is Robert Leonard who plays the role of Neil Perry. He deserves acknowledgment and fame and is mostly known as Dr. James Wilson on House M.D. Ethan Hawke is another important character in the movie. He plays the role of Todd Anderson in the movie. Ethan was born on 6 November 1970 in Austin Texas. His acting career started as a mix of theatre work and a mix of serious and commercial movies. All of these actors play an excellent role in the movie. They create an exciting plot, and the move builds up perfectly. At first the movie seemed kind of boring, but as I paid more attention and it advanced it was amazing. It tells a story that nobody should miss. I talks about courage, how we should fight for what we want, and to live life to the fullest. One of my favorite scenes was when the English teacher, Mr. Keating, tells the students to tear the pages of a book apart. In every scene he is an excellent teacher, he makes the class entertaining and the students learn more than you could imagine. They do not only learn about English and poetry, but they learn about life. This movie is heartwarming; it has a full meaning, and is contains great poetry that has life lessons. I believe the most important lesson in this movie is to seize the day. This means to make out the most of each day, as if we would die tomorrow. This relates to doing what you like, what you enjoy the most in life. It is getting apart from what society expects from you, and doing what makes you happy. Another important lesson is to be you. We live in a society in which everyone expects something from you, but the most important thing is to be your own self. It will help in mental and spiritual growth. Challenging the status quo is another lesson. Change the way to see life, make a change in the world, in people. One last lesson is to stand up for others. This will not only be beneficial for the people you help but it will help you feel better. I believe everyone who watches the movie should enjoy it. I would recommend it to anyone who wants to watch it but especially for people above 13 years. This is because someone younger than this will maybe not understand well the meaning of the movie and will think it is boring. I would rate the movie PG-13. This movie is as great as the Oscar Winning movie "The Help". Both movies are delightfully different. In "The Help", as well as in "Dead Poets Society", the characters play an excellent role and the plot is entertaining and fun. Along the movie you will not get bored, it catches the audience's attention due to the fact that they treat interesting subjects. They are memorable movies, that once you watch them you will never forget the lesson and it will change your life. Both teach a wonderful lesson that everyone should take into account in their daily lives. Rating 8.7 The criticizer of this movie is Melania Chaves. She is an eleventh grade student at Lincoln School, Costa Rica. She is seventeen years old and will graduate next year from high school. She enjoys watching movies and hanging out with her friends. Her hobbies are playing tennis, running, and playing piano. Carpe Diem!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Dead Poets Society
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    HG Englisch AG
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Dead Poets Society"  A film that makes you think about your dreams and your decisions in life. Good or bad decisions "Carpe Diem  Seize the day." This statement is made by Mr. Keating, the special and unique teacher of "Welton Academy". After he had taught his students the sense of "Carpe Diem" and poetry, the way of thinking of many students changed and some of them started to finish what Mr. Keating had begun when he was at the same age. If you are looking for a film to watch it in class, you should have a look at "Dead Poets Society". It's a 1986 drama film which is directed by Peter Weir and is set at the "Welton Academy" in Vermont. It deals with the teacher Mr Keating who inspires his students with his special view of life and so they build a group called "Dead Poets Society". They meet each other at a cave near the school where they talk about poetry to express themselves. The cave scenes are very amusing and show the boys in funny situations during the meetings. The "new Dead Poets Society" consists of quite different personalities: Neil Perry, the self-confident founder of the group, the shy Todd Anderson, the noisy Richard Cameron, Steven Meeks, the clever one, Charlie Dalton and last but not least Knox Overstreet, a very friendly and polite student. You may find it easy to identify with one of the young boys because of the interesting characters. They can surprise you in different ways and can also make you laugh. If I was asked to rate this film on a scale from 0  10, I would give it 7 points as the film is easy to understand and all elements, which make life worth it like love, friendship or disagreement, are included. It's a classic with a shocking and unexpected ending.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Ristrictive lives
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Bernardo Rapazote Flores
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    There are certain films that get under your skin, never to come out. They change your life, subtly altering your perceptions of reality, almost always for the better. Dead Poets Society is one of those and it is one of the most emotional movies I've ever seen and gets me every time and it touches everyone, specially people whose dreams are held down by their restrictive parents. This movie touches and thrills us scene after scene -- the "Oh Captain, my captain" scene (Don't you have ANYONE in your life you respect so much that you'd stand up for﻿ them in any situation, stand beside them and support them no matter what? That's what this scene is all about.), Anderson's 'speech' to its classmates, the tragic and touching ending -- crafting one of my favorite movies ever.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Rhyme and Reason
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    leonlouisricci
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It was a different World in 1959 and Teaching Conventions and Learning Institutions were Ultra Conservative, especially by Today's Standards. The Film takes place at an Uppity Prep School with Traditions not easily toppled. Enter Free Thinking Teacher Mr. Keating who is about to "Shake Rattle and Roll". This is a, dare one say it, Poetic Movie with a smooth Patina and an Off-Beat Meter. But, ironically it stays quite standard in its portrayal of Student Rebellion and is nowhere near Kerouac, Ginsberg, or The Beats. Some reference or acknowledgment of "The Movement" might have been a bit closer to the Theme here and would have given it some Street Cred. This is by the Book, pretty much, with its often visited Story and is not without Flaws. Such as the completely out of context Page Ripping Scene that is so badly thought out that it almost makes the Movie Dumb Ass. Did the Writer actually think that Censorship and Book Destruction was an apt way to illustrate Free Thinking. That is unforgivable. An overrated Film, but a Very Good one. Schools were like that, Parents were like that, it is an Inconvenient Truth. In the Decade that followed, for better or worse (mostly better), conventions would collapse, traditions would tumble, and the Lip Service given to Freedom would be challenged. In this Fictional Story, all that was a little ahead of its Time and those involved suffered, like all dissidents.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Walk to the Beat of your Own Drum
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    thedozinglion
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Carpe Diem" is the line often quoted from the 1989 film Dead Poets Society to signify making the most out of life today. However for me the real theme of the movie is better encapsulated in the quotes by Thoreau and Frost on "walking to the beat of your own drum" and "following the path less travelled". A rebellion away from conformity towards individuality. Robin Williams is cast in the role of John Keating, the idealistic new teacher at Welton Academy a conservative prep school during the late 1950s. The school is a milder version of the Bunker Hill Military Academy of TAPS (1981), exacting control through "tradition, honour, discipline and excellence". In essence an expensive factory designed to process boys into men of standing and position at the expense of their uniqueness. Keating's teaching methods allow his students to struggle against not only the school and its lifeless dogma but also family and society's convention. Unlike Kevin Kline's William Hundert in The Emperor's Club (2002), Keating is not interested in shaping the character of the boys he teaches but unlocking their potential. Early in the movie he instructs his class to rip out the antiquated Introduction to Poetry in their textbooks which looks to take the soul out of the verse and replace it with a formula for understanding. This is much like the ethos of the school itself which seeks to remove the identity of the boys to supplant it with a tried and tested docility. The two main leads are played well by the then rising stars Ethan Hawke and Robert Sean Leonard. Their forming of the Dead Poets Society being the central form of rebellion in the film, a midnight meeting group off campus, breaking school regulations while allowing the boys to read the great freethinking poets of the past and their own adolescent compositions to one another. However the true rebel in the movie is not a student but Robin William's quixotic Keating, a free-spirited thinker who challenges the autocratic system in place and give the power of thought to his students. He is the polar opposite of Michael Redgrave's Crocker-Harris in The Browning Version (1951), a man whose passion for teaching has been eroded by years of apathy from his students leading to a teacher of rote rather than reason. Keating forms the midpoint in a trilogy of non-conformist characters played by Williams over a three year period starting with army disc jockey Adrian Cronauer in Good Morning Vietnam (1987) to Dr. Malcolm Sayer in Awakenings (1990). All three fight their prevailing systems (military, academia and medicine) to aid those within it. Williams is well able to embody the radical troublemaker effectively although his schizophrenic personality is toned down in each subsequent film. He is at his best as an actor when he is not playing for laughs but using comedy to flesh out his characters and tell a story. In a memorable scene Keating takes Thoreau's quote from Walden and has the boys acts it out: "If a man loses pace with his companions, perhaps it is because he hears a different drummer. Let him step to the music which he hears, however measured, or far away." Having the self-conscious boys walk around the school courtyard in their own style forces them to have awareness of their individuality much to the disapproval of the watching headmaster. Keating in the scene also quotes Robert Frosts poem The Road Not Taken: "Two roads diverged in a wood, and I I took the one less traveled by, And that has made all the difference." These quotes perfectly represent the concept of not accepting the majority voice as the absolute truth but instead putting yourself and your beliefs at the center. For what good is life if it is half lived without creativity and freedom of choice and action. However the power of freethinking that Keating gives to his student ends in tragedy. To fight against the system and society can be difficult for those unaccustomed to it. Keating is held responsible by the school for the loss due to the fear of the parents and staff of his methods, which have unleashed the raw potential in his students. Alas, there is no Scent of a Women (1992) defiance by the students when the headmaster looks for informers against Keating, all the boys of the Dead Poet Society sign, in effect, his expulsion papers. But the final scene does give hope that these young men will grow up with more than just honour and loyalty that the school demands. They will also have a heart and mind open to their own ideas and beliefs, they will never tamely believe or do what is told them but will seek out the truth as they find it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An instant OBSESSION...Unforgettable!!!!!!!!!!!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    barendbkj
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Never in my life have I ever experienced anything like Dead Poet's Society. This is a fine example how movies should be. It should be touching, it should be funny, it should be something an outsider can be proud of. And I was...I was proud of what they accomplished, that almost decades later it can still be seen as a drama worth beating (and none has beaten it so far). The story is about a group of boys who restart an old Poets club, that was once run by their English teacher, mister John Keating. During the course of the film we are introduced to Keating's majorly uplifting influence in the lives of the boys as he urges them on to follow their dreams and to, seize the day. CARPE DIEM!!! This movie had me hooked from beginning to end. I didn't want it to end. When it was finished I let out a breath of relief as I realized I was not actually part of the fun. But it pulled me in and forced me to feel what the boys were feeling. The acting was phenomenal. The story is timeless and the lessons learned from it, I will always treasure. "Oh captain, my captain. I tip my hat to you sir. WELL DONE."
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Dead poets society
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    audhusenitzad
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie means the world to me!! I watched it for the first time a few weeks ago and I have been moved ever since. I fell in love with every character, especially Charlie Dalton, "Nuwanda". I highly recommend this movie to anyone who wants to see a film to make your feelings go crazy. Through the few scenes located in Mr. Keatings English classroom, the boys become free thinkers and poets, for example, the first scene distinguishes Mr. Keating to be called "Oh Captain My Captain". In a similar setting, Keating encourages the boys to stand up on the desk so they may look at the world in another way.The final scene in which the boys show their support for their English teacher Mr. Keating by standing up on their desks saying "Oh Captain My Captain", closes up the film excellently. This movie changed my life and I hope you're moved by it as much as I was.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Leaves of Class
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    wes-connors
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    In 1959 Delaware (as Vermont), charismatic poetry teacher Robin Williams (as John Keating) arrives to begin work at the "Welton Academy" preparatory school for boys. An alumni of the school, Mr. Williams teaches poetry with uncommon zeal. To gain attention, he demands students tear out the pages of books written by essayists with whom he does not agree. To get participation, he invites students to stand on the teacher's desk. Williams does impersonations of Marlon Brando and John Wayne. His motto is "Seize the Day," a directive made popular by novelist Saul Bellow. Yes, this class is fun... Williams teaches the "dangers of conforming," and encourages students to think for themselves. When they learn Williams belonged to a clandestine club called the "Dead Poets Society" when he was a "Welton" student, the class decides to revive the group. They meet in a cave to read poetry by the masters - but, mainly, they just goof around. Playing the saxophone and sharing "Playboy"-type centerfolds accompany Walt Whitman. Because Williams'' influence extends perilously beyond the classroom, his "unorthodox teaching methods" get the popular teacher in trouble with school administrators... This above average production won good notices and award consideration for director Peter Weir and star Robin Williams. Originally, the teacher held back a secret; "Oscar"-winning writer Tom Schulman was persuaded to drop the idea, so we and the character are left with a gap. Williams' "Keating" is put on the sidelines in favor of the students. Nothing against the actors, who perform exceptionally, but they do look more like handsome young college-aged models than typical high-school aged boys. There is some physical diversity in the extended supporting cast, though. A few of the boys wear glasses... The main stars are sensitive writer Ethan Hawke (as Todd Anderson) and his roommate, aspiring actor Robert Sean Leonard (as Neil Perry). The next tier includes prankster Gale Hansen (as Charlie Dalton) and lovelorn Josh Charles (as Knox Overstreet). Although these players are almost interchangeable, the actors create distinguishable characters. Best of the remaining parts goes to Dylan Kussman (as Richard Cameron), who perversely turns out to be the group's real non-conformist. The film is too self-consciously calculating and manipulative to be fully masterful, but it sure looks nice. ******** Dead Poets Society (6/2/89) Peter Weir ~ Robin Williams, Ethan Hawke, Robert Sean Leonard, Gale Hansen
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Young boys reading poetry during their play-time..... come onnnn.......
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Tracy Winters
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Robin Williams -- you know, I really want to like him, and in this film, I do, though I usually don't like the kinds of films he chooses to participate in ('Good Will Hunting' is by far his best role). Here's a supposedly enigmatic teacher (Williams) motivating his teenage boy students to read poetry in their leisure time. That was unbelievable. I could see them doing this if between poems, they gave each other oral sex or something, but unfortunately, that does not happen in this movie. What does happen is a predictable script by Tom Shulman. We see a plethora of different, but typical characters.... the snitch (Dylan Kussman), the rebellious kid (Gale Hanson), the charming boy (Josh Charles), and even a self-effacing young man (Ethan Hawke) who stutters until the hero of the story (Williams) gives the kid a reason to live, except when Wiliams leaves the school, the kid starts stuttering again (i.e. 'One Flew Over the Cuckoo's Nest'). So much for originality. The final scene is so sappy, you'll want to rinse out your pie-hole with mouthwash.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Much Better Than Expected!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    g-bodyl
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Dead Poets Society is a much better film than I anticipated. Honestly, I thought this would be a film all about poetry and I loathe poetry, so I didn't give this film a chance. I'm glad I did because this is not a film about poetry, but about a group of college kids who have been encouraged to follow their own dreams. This film is a well-made drama that will make you smile, laugh, and cry. It also has one of the most unexpected scenes I have seen in awhile. Peter Weir's film is about a group of college kids who are inspired by their English professor, John Keating. Keating tells his kids who follow their dreams and they do just that. Unfortunately, the dean and the parents have other ideas for their kids. Robin Williams gives a true, inspirational performance as John Keating. He is the teacher that is common nowadays, but someone my parents would yearn to have. Ethan Hawke delivers a stand out performance as one of the kids and so does Robert Sean Leonard. Overall, this is a truly inspirational film that has one simple message for all people, especially younger ones. This message is "Follow our dreams and don't let anyone tell you what you can or can't do." This message should have been used back in the 1950's-1960's. This film is well-acted, has great direction, and should leave a tear or two. I rate this film 9/10.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Inspiring and Life changing
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Melania Chaves
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Carpe Diem": Seize the day. This is the lesson, John Keating, the English schoolteacher wants to convey to his students. This movie is one of the best movies I've ever watched. It helps people to face problems and live life as if there was no tomorrow. It teaches us how to enjoy every aspect of life and let nothing ruin what makes us really happy. It is not only entertaining, but it teaches a great life lesson, which is to think for ourselves and stand up for that in which we believe. It is incomparable with other movies and should definitely be watched by everyone. Dead Poets Society was nominated for four Academy Awards. It is from the genre of drama and although it is a 1989 movie, the picture is great and the movie is so stimulating and outstanding, the picture won't even be a problem. The movie takes place in 1959 in the Welton Academy. In this school education is very strict and students are expected to behave in a highly educated and responsible manner. Several of the students have a different opinion regarding the school's education process. When the new teacher comes, everything changes. John Keating is an unconventional teacher who tells his students to tear out the pages of the books and asks his students to stand on their desks to see the world from a different perspective. He introduces the boys to poetry and teaches them new philosophies about life. He encourages his students to follow their dreams, and to not follow what people expect them to do, but what makes them happy. The characters in this film are so realistic; they create an impact in the audience. I hate movies with flat characters and in this movie the character development is really outstanding. Robin Williams plays an excellent job as the professor and interacts very well with the students. In his early life, Williams studied political science before studying theatre in the Julliard School. He later on performed in nightclubs where he was discovered for the role of Mork on the TV series "Happy Days". Another important character is Robert Leonard who plays the role of Neil Perry. He deserves acknowledgment and fame and is mostly known as Dr. James Wilson on House M.D. Ethan Hawke is another important character in the movie. He plays the role of Todd Anderson in the movie. Ethan was born on 6 November 1970 in Austin Texas. His acting career started as a mix of theatre work and a mix of serious and commercial movies. All of these actors play an excellent role in the movie. They create an exciting plot, and the move builds up perfectly. At first the movie seemed kind of boring, but as I paid more attention and it advanced it was amazing. It tells a story that nobody should miss. I talks about courage, how we should fight for what we want, and to live life to the fullest. One of my favorite scenes was when the English teacher, Mr. Keating, tells the students to tear the pages of a book apart. In every scene he is an excellent teacher, he makes the class entertaining and the students learn more than you could imagine. They do not only learn about English and poetry, but they learn about life. This movie is heartwarming; it has a full meaning, and is contains great poetry that has life lessons. I believe the most important lesson in this movie is to seize the day. This means to make out the most of each day, as if we would die tomorrow. This relates to doing what you like, what you enjoy the most in life. It is getting apart from what society expects from you, and doing what makes you happy. Another important lesson is to be you. We live in a society in which everyone expects something from you, but the most important thing is to be your own self. It will help in mental and spiritual growth. Challenging the status quo is another lesson. Change the way to see life, make a change in the world, in people. One last lesson is to stand up for others. This will not only be beneficial for the people you help but it will help you feel better. I believe everyone who watches the movie should enjoy it. I would recommend it to anyone who wants to watch it but especially for people above 13 years. This is because someone younger than this will maybe not understand well the meaning of the movie and will think it is boring. I would rate the movie PG-13. This movie is as great as the Oscar Winning movie "The Help". Both movies are delightfully different. In "The Help", as well as in "Dead Poets Society", the characters play an excellent role and the plot is entertaining and fun. Along the movie you will not get bored, it catches the audience's attention due to the fact that they treat interesting subjects. They are memorable movies, that once you watch them you will never forget the lesson and it will change your life. Both teach a wonderful lesson that everyone should take into account in their daily lives. Rating 8.7 The criticizer of this movie is Melania Chaves. She is an eleventh grade student at Lincoln School, Costa Rica. She is seventeen years old and will graduate next year from high school. She enjoys watching movies and hanging out with her friends. Her hobbies are playing tennis, running, and playing piano. Carpe Diem!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Dead Poets Society
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    HG Englisch AG
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Dead Poets Society"  A film that makes you think about your dreams and your decisions in life. Good or bad decisions "Carpe Diem  Seize the day." This statement is made by Mr. Keating, the special and unique teacher of "Welton Academy". After he had taught his students the sense of "Carpe Diem" and poetry, the way of thinking of many students changed and some of them started to finish what Mr. Keating had begun when he was at the same age. If you are looking for a film to watch it in class, you should have a look at "Dead Poets Society". It's a 1986 drama film which is directed by Peter Weir and is set at the "Welton Academy" in Vermont. It deals with the teacher Mr Keating who inspires his students with his special view of life and so they build a group called "Dead Poets Society". They meet each other at a cave near the school where they talk about poetry to express themselves. The cave scenes are very amusing and show the boys in funny situations during the meetings. The "new Dead Poets Society" consists of quite different personalities: Neil Perry, the self-confident founder of the group, the shy Todd Anderson, the noisy Richard Cameron, Steven Meeks, the clever one, Charlie Dalton and last but not least Knox Overstreet, a very friendly and polite student. You may find it easy to identify with one of the young boys because of the interesting characters. They can surprise you in different ways and can also make you laugh. If I was asked to rate this film on a scale from 0  10, I would give it 7 points as the film is easy to understand and all elements, which make life worth it like love, friendship or disagreement, are included. It's a classic with a shocking and unexpected ending.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
 </reviews>
</filme>
