<filme>
 <id>
  197
 </id>
 <imdburl>
  http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0061722
 </imdburl>
 <ano>
  1967
 </ano>
 <titulo>
  A Primeira Noite de um Homem
 </titulo>
 <rating>
  8.1
 </rating>
 <sinopse>
  Recent college graduate Benjamin Braddock is trapped into an affair with Mrs. Robinson, who happens to be the wife of his father's business partner and then finds himself falling in love with her daughter, Elaine.
 </sinopse>
 <storyline>
  Ben has recently graduated college, with his parents now expecting great things from him. At his "Homecoming" party, Mrs. Robinson, the wife of his father's business partner, has Ben drive her home, which leads to an affair between the two. The affair eventually ends, but comes back to haunt him when he finds himself falling for Elaine, Mrs. Robinson's daughter.
 </storyline>
 <generos>
  <genero>
   Comedy
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Drama
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Romance
  </genero>
 </generos>
 <keywords>
  <keyword>
   love
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   college graduate
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   hotel
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   graduate
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   hotel room
  </keyword>
 </keywords>
 <diretores>
  <diretor>
   Mike Nichols
  </diretor>
 </diretores>
 <escritores>
  <escritor>
   Calder Willingham
  </escritor>
  <escritor>
   Buck Henry
  </escritor>
 </escritores>
 <atores>
  <ator>
   Dustin Hoffman
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Anne Bancroft
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Katharine Ross
  </ator>
 </atores>
 <reviews>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A treatise on the nature of being a graduate
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    sunshinebeachcinema
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    In following up those cinematic classics that I'm somehow still catching up on, I recently saw The Graduate for the first time. I inevitably went into it with some idea of what was going to happen, but little more than an expectation for Dustin Hoffman to pursue a relationship with an older woman, to the sound of Simon & Garfunkel. Hoffman is Benjamin Braddock, the disaffected young university graduate who returns from his studies to a summer without direction. He is swiftly seduced by Mrs. Robinson, the wife of his father's business partner, and embarks on a lengthy affair, but his affection soon turns to her daughter, Elaine. Yet this is merely the bare bones of the plot: it's more complex than a simple romantic comedy, and the ending, notably, is ambiguous. It's impossible to complain about spoilers for a film that came out over forty years ago; it has seeped into popular culture, and been subjected to merciless parody. The iconic ending sequence is especially strange to watch for someone who grew up repeatedly watching Wayne's World 2 (1993), where it is replicated shot for shot. The critical eye has been on the film for so long, and it has passed through so many generations that its contemporary relevance can be questioned. Though a product of the late 1960s, the counterculture elements we associate with the period, such as free love, psychedelia, or hard rock. Benjamin's sexual experiences are not part of a revolution, and he remains trapped firmly within the rigid framework of upper middle class suburbia. While there's a certain fascination to looking back on a snapshot of the past, many of us no longer have the same relationship with our parents and the older generation. Do we look back at a history of steady liberalisation, but no massive social upheaval, and see further subversion as unnecessary? Do our parents, the children of the past, simply provide us with a system we no longer need to escape? Maybe modern youth have it worse than Benjamin; our coming of age is not so straightforward. We are no longer afforded the opportunity of clear rebellion, and are left to wallow in the established structure. What does hold true is the portrayal of a graduate with no clear future, returning to inhabit the fading skeleton of a life that's somehow no longer his own, and the dull resignation that there's little incentive to do anything about it. As a graduate myself (Though my current social circle suffers an absence of attractive lonely women) I can largely sympathise with Benjamin's predicament. After all, what does the immediate future hold? The prospects of the graduate are numerous and varied. Will it be more of the same on a postgraduate course? Are we heading for the city for a mysterious role as an analyst or consultant (when we're really just brewing tea for executives)? Perhaps it's just going to be a couple more months playing video games in pyjamas before we make a final decision. We still need something. A last hurrah before we're thrown to the world of work and responsibility for good. Could the modern rebellion be merely the fabled gap year abroad? At any rate, it seems coming of age requires something extreme, ditching the world and obligations, the way that Benjamin does at the end of The Graduate. The whole film is an exploration of these questions, symbolically relayed through the central relationships. The choices the characters make in their attachments are reflective of the choices that can be made in all facets of life. This is emphasised stylistically through a number of visually captivating shots and transitions that underline the sense of emptiness and alienation. Water (swimming pools, aquariums, and rain) appears frequently as a tool of separation. The soundtrack contains little youthful euphoria, but is melancholic, featuring repeated motifs that again, accentuate loneliness. These are played during moments that could otherwise be seen as positive steps in Benjamin's life, at the height of his relationship with Mrs. Robinson, and during his final elopement, elevating the drama above mere comedy. His obsession with Elaine is far from romantic destiny, and exists primarily as an escape from his relationship with her mother, and a chance to give his life some purpose outside an unhealthy liaison that makes him feel increasingly trapped. Compared with Mrs. Robinson, Elaine's character is chronically underdeveloped, though she responds positively to Benjamin's pseudo-philosophical ramblings. While she is disgusted to learn of Benjamin's affair with her mother, we learn little else of her thoughts on home, and where she fits in do the loveless dynamic in the Robinson household. We do not know if she as desperate to break free as Benjamin is. She ultimately follows him on impulse, having initially been happy to marry another at her parents' request. The separation from the character of Elaine forces us to experience the relationship purely from the perspective of Benjamin, who has put her on a pedestal and made her the object of his salvation. Despite the vein of sympathy I have as a fellow graduate, Benjamin is at times an insufferable and frustrating character to watch, and ultimately, Mrs. Robinson comes off as more sympathetic. She is the one who is truly lost and trapped. Benjamin still has his whole life ahead of him, once he finally decides what he's going to do with it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An Under-appreciated Classic!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    FilmMuscle
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I find it disappointing that the Graduate isn't one of those constantly-talked-about classics like The Godfather, Kramer vs. Kramer, Apocalypse Now, The Shawshank Redemption, etc. I had mixed expectations for the film since I heard, prior to viewing, some negative opinions and positive ones from individuals who'd recently watched it. Now, let's talk about why this film should be just as remembered of a classic as the others above. First of all and- in my opinion- most importantly, the film carries with it a highly intriguing and interesting story that keeps you entertained the entire way as the clever plot unravels. You're presented with this socially angsty twenty-year-old who's basically helpless, surrounded by intimidating people and frightening situations. He's a character that the audience can't help but love. For me, I could find myself relating to his personality quite a bit. I, too, attempt to stray away from great attention and prefer a much calmer and less crowded environment. The story, itself, keeps your attention because it's just strongly gripping insofar as this character finds himself in extremely awkward and threatening situations. Personally- like with the scene where Benjamin is awkwardly attempting to avoid suspicion while getting a hotel room- I recalled similar instances with myself where I was about to engage in something that could be regrettable and had to deal with suspicious or curious bystanders, family members, or whatnot. While we're still on it, the acting was unbelievably good, especially Dustin Hoffman's break-out performance as Benjamin. The way he portrayed a timid and awkward character surely blew away the moviegoers that night of its release. His timing and speech delivery, overall, creates an absolutely believable story about this fully realistic outcast. The way he would retreat under the pool whenever he felt vulnerable or faced his imposing parents definitely moved me because I could honestly understand him in any given predicament. At times, I feel like finding some peaceful and impenetrable spot to socially leave the world and obtain some time to breathe. The script of this picture is brilliant from the convincing dialogue to the intelligent build-up of relationships and their interconnections. For the moment, let's delve into the more technical side of The Graduate since its cinematography and editing is exceptional- excellent, might I say. The evolution of filmmaking over the decades from when Hollywood first stemmed truly and impressively proved itself in this movie. For example, there's a particular scene where Benjamin is "drifting" on the pool's air mattress, and he's interrupted by his irritating parents and the Robinsons themselves, and as they begin discussing his current uneventful life, the camera perfectly displays these incredibly condescending figures looking down at him with the sun shining so brightly that it seems to be blinding both the viewer and Benjamin as he's forced to look up at them. You sympathize with Benjamin because you feel their aggression and- again- condescending conversation about how he's not doing anything with his life, and I'm sure everyone's been in that sort of position, mentally or physically. Then, another shot shows Elaine as her confused face gets less and less blurry (indicating her progression towards fully understanding the mystery) until she finally realizes what's essentially transpiring between Benjamin and her own mother. In terms of editing, an instance showcases fast cutting to Mrs. Robinson's naked body as Benjamin attempts to ignore it but can't help his lust in a way. The film also smoothly and uniquely transitions to new settings without the audience even noticing at first as Benjamin exits the pool, walks to his room, and is suddenly found entering Mrs. Robinson's bed. Another strength of the camera-work is the noticeably lengthy shots where we witness entire conversations occurring in one single take or the scuba mask scene where a few minutes or so are filmed from a first-person perspective as Benjamin dives into his pool. In sum, the film seemed like a breath of fresh air that was affected by an unquestionably relatable protagonist that you felt for and his escape with the love of his life seemed utterly satisfying as well. Usually, happy endings done the way The Graduate did it come off as corny and clich&eacute;d, but your liking for the characters and their success overshadowed that aspect. So far, I've been loving all the films in class as this is yet another one I can't help but give high praise to.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not A Classic.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    AaronCapenBanner
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Mike Nichols directed this film about Ben Braddock, a confused young man trying to decide on his future in a society he can't understand, but instead becomes involved with the married mother of his reluctant girlfriend, and the various complications that ensue as a result. Dustin Hoffman leads a good cast, it has haunting songs by Simon & Garfunkel, is beloved by many of that generation, and even won Nichols an Academy Award for best director. So what's not to like? For a film that reacts negatively to the word "plastic", that's just how I feel about the characters and setting. Nothing about this film feels particularly real, certainly not the affair of Ben and Mrs. Robinson(Anne Bancroft) which not only isn't believable, it doesn't make sense, feels utterly manufactured and wrong. Katharine Ross as his girlfriend reacts to the news believably, but the ending will leave the viewer up in the air, since it, while dramatically staged, feels forced and unsatisfying. It just doesn't work for me.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    If anyone was born to play an awkward 21 year old...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    cleary-joshua
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    If anyone was born to play an awkward 21 year old deciding what to do with his life, it has to be 30 year old Dustin Hoffman, who steals this movie with his brilliant portrayal of Benjamin Braddock. It's a performance with humour and emotion all rolled into one. For example, Hoffman's performance when he first takes Mrs. Robinson home is hilarious, with his constant nervous stammering and occasional high-pitched squeaks. The final shot of Elaine and Benjamin has so much drama in both of their expressions, and you can tell how great the pair are as actors. They've just run away together, and she's already married. Are they completely happy? Not really, and both of their faces have a sort of "now what?" expression, leaving the audience thinking about whether it was the right decision. As for the story itself, it's comical without becoming too farcical, and has enough drama later on to keep the audience interested. It's also beautifully shot, with a lot of clever cutting and images, such as the fact that Benjamin is always being shot through other objects, like the hotel woodwork, or Mrs. Robinson's leg. The music too is great, and Simon and Garfunkel's songs, though some of them are used almost too much, manage to create just the right atmosphere for the film. The late Roger Ebert originally gave this film 4 stars, but thirty years later, dropped his score down to 3, something I'm not sure I've ever heard of a critic doing. He states in his later review that it's not a film that has stood the test of time, that modern audiences wouldn't find it as funny. I disagree with this, and managed to find humour in a lot of the film. However his main reason for doing so is the character of Benjamin, whom he calls an 'insufferable creep', and now I think about it, Ebert is kind of right. Perhaps the awkwardness does go a bit too far at points, and he is just a bit strange and horrible in taking Elaine to the strip club and stalking her for a long time. This detail aside, I still found it to be a hugely enjoyable film which left a lot to think about afterwards, as well as a lot of laughs, and it's worth watching if only for Hoffman's performance and delivery of that classic line: "Mrs. Robinson, you're trying to seduce me, aren't you."
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    It's Graduation Day! I think this movie is seducing me. You're trying to seduce me. Aren't you?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ironhorse_iv
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The movie has this great 1960's Hollywood New Wave feel to it. This is a coming of age movie that works for me. A lot of coming of age movies seem to try to make their character innocent, but they never actually are. They do a bunch of irresponsible stuff and at the end of the day a lot of people call them "innocent and lost", but it just feels like an excuse to sympathize for being an idiot. However I do sympathize for this character, Benjamin Braddock (Dustin Hoffman). It seemed like he was forced into a pool and not allowed to come back up. The theme of an innocent and confused youth who is exploited, misdirected, seduced and betrayed by a corrupt older generation was well understood by film audiences and captured the spirit of the times. One of the film's posters proclaimed the difficult coming-of-age for college graduate. Directed by Mike Nichols, the film is based on the 1963 novel The Graduate by Charles Webb. The movie opens to one of the best songs of the 1960's, Simon & Garfunkel - The Sound of Silence. This is one of the best songs I've ever listened to. I think the soundtrack pretty much made Simon & Garfunkel from nearly unknown folk singers, to legends of the music industry. You can also hear an earlier version of Mrs. Robinson in the movie. The song as it appears in the film is different from the familiar hit single version, as only the chorus of the song appears late in the film and with slightly different lyrics. It was only later on that Paul Simon and Art Garfunkel re-recorded the song by employing additional lyrics to form the hit single. It's kinda funny that the original song was call 'Mrs. Roosevelt'. It would really be funny to see Eleanor Roosevelt have an affair with a younger man. The Sound of Silence song work for the film as it really fit in with the plot regarding the lack of communication between the controlling parents and the young adults. Anyways, Benjamin Braddock has just arrive back home, after years in College. Dustin Hoffman played the part of the awkward post-graduate student perfectly. I can't see Mike Nichols first choice, Robert Redford in this role. Dustin is kind of awkward that works, he isn't to an abnormal extent creep, he more just describes the entire situation to the woman. Unsure of himself, by being uncomfortable and anxious, and force to hear others decide for him what he will do with his future. Benjamin Braddock soon find himself, seduce by an older woman, Mrs. Robinson (Anne Bancroft) and find himself tempt into an affair. Anne Bancroft is a cougar on the prowl, really to pounce on her prey. She was really pretty in the room. Even though her character is sympathetic, it doesn't change the fact that her character is a vindictive sexual predator. Just the line 'You've known me nearly all your life." Is just disturbing. Mrs. Robinson wanting to bang a kid she watched grow up? That's gross, and just a step below Woody Allen marrying his stepdaughter. She was marry too, so not only is she wanting to date a younger man, she watch when he was kid, but she's also cheating on her husband. It is pure flesh, but she is nice about it. It is just natural, pragmatic and not that romantic-idealistic. She's still the Queen of all Milfs. Her personal life isn't the only thing she's opening. Some people might hate the fact, that the two main characters are two of the most shallow, childish characters. Mrs. Robinson can be especially hateful without any specific motivation, while Benjamin is bit spineless. I do love Dustin Hoffman in the role, but he was way too old for this part. He was playing a 20 year old, and he himself was 30 at the time. Also Anne Bancroft was only 35 during the time of filming. It also kinda funny that the actress Katharine Ross who played Anne Bancroft's daughter Elaine was only 8 years younger than her 35 and 27, miscasting. Katherine Ross looks lovely as Elaine, but she's barely one-dimensional and looks like a girl who would never go for a guy like Dustin Hoffman in a million years. She only went with him, because of her over controlling parents. Anyways, Benjamin soon fall in love with Elaine, and is in a dilemma. Should be continue to live with people telling what to do with his life like Mrs. Robinson or should he set his own future with a girl like Elaine? Find out, by watching it. The ending is up to question, if these two would work out. It leaves a deep interpretation of risky love. This is a classic film: tightly written, intelligent, funny, wonderfully acted, with a great climax with the church, so to speak. You will get seduce into watching the film by how brilliant it is.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of the most overvalued films of all times
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Turin_Horse
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The great and classical soundtrack by Simon & Garfunkel, a group of good actors and one of the most famous scenes in cinema history with Anne Bancroft and Dustin Hoffman as protagonists cannot make up a poor, even lame plot, an incoherent and silly story full of holes and a dull direction and editing. One wonders how such a film could make its way through time to still be considered a "classic" and seemingly appreciated by a high number of people; maybe, for people in the sixties this film meant something, or touched something inside them or whatever, but nowadays The Graduate should long have been put in the bag of dated unworthy-to-watch films. The final scenes with Benjamin trying to prevent the wedding of his sweetheart and taking her with him are just shameful!. There are some very good films from the sixties, try Midnight Cowboy for instance, but skip this over-overvalued film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Creative, compelling & classic
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    stephparsons
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    You've gotta love The Graduate.&nbsp; Even after 44 years, it's still relevant, highly watchable, funny, a titchy bit avant-garde, and boasts a top notch, flawless script.&nbsp; Dustin Hoffman as Ben does a bang up job playing the hapless graduate who desperately wants to escape his boring, careerist fate (as predetermined by&nbsp; his parents and society at large).&nbsp; He exudes 'sullen-youth-ness', boredom-with-life, naivet&eacute;, awkwardness and an (almost) 'aspergers' style of speech which are amusing and poignant.&nbsp; Despite all the drama that unfolds; the seduction followed by the 'coming-of-age' sex with an older woman, the falling in love with a fresh, vibrant young woman, The Graduate is, ultimately, a film about ennui; that dull, thudding, inexorable grind we face upon leaving school and being forced to 'decide what to do' for the rest of our sad, pathetic , predictable lives.&nbsp; Career paths being far more restrictive in the '60s,&nbsp; the sense of doom and pointlessness that Ben feels is exacerbated and he portrays it so very well.&nbsp;&nbsp; The friend of his parents who says, "I have one word for you Ben...plastics", sums up the soulless, futile, and arid future that Ben fears is his destiny. &nbsp;The Graduate experiments successfully with some creative cinematography including unusual camera angles, and interesting switches from one milieu to another e.g. Ben jumping into the swimming pool but ending up on the bed with Mrs Robinson.&nbsp;&nbsp; The swimming pool scene where Ben must walk under water in his birthday present - an old fashioned diving suit- is especially memorable and provides a convincing metaphor for the restrictiveness, loneliness and entrapment that he fears is to be his fate.&nbsp; There is nothing 'awkward' or dated about this classic film, it holds one's attention from start to finish.&nbsp; The ending steers clear of that typical 'happily ever after' Hollywood schmaltz&nbsp; and, in subtle tones presents us with 'ennui in a nutshell' as Ben and Elaine exchange smiles, then worried looks, and then expressions devoid of all emotion.&nbsp; There is nothing I would change about The Graduate, it's a classic and always will be.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Loved it!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    oliviadoerrer17
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Personally thought this particular film was great! I have heard many things about it's wonderful storyline and acting, I definitely had high expectations going into the film and it exceeded those. I always love a movie that is scandalous, and makes you wonder every second if someone is going to get caught. Dustin Hoffman really took on his role and made it believable to his shy nervous personality. He managed to make most scenes awkward which made it very funny. My personal favorite was the scene where Mrs Robinson tried to seduce him, you could tell by his facial expression and sweat he was extremely nervous and uncomfortable. The shots of Mrs Robinson's nude body then to Benjamin's face then back to her body and so on really was comical. The storyline did end up becoming interesting and complicated due to obvious reasons which overall added to the film. I liked the fact that Benjamin never gave up in what he wanted and fought to the end.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Hysterical
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    RoseXGold
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I loved this movie. It was the perfect blend of comedy, drama,love and action. The overall plot was very intriguing. I feel like everyone has been in the main characters shoes before( not knowing exactly what you want to do with your life). The theme was very relate-able. I feel as though everyone had a specific character that they could some how relate to. The music in this film was something that stood out to me. It was a bit more modern. I adored the fact that they not only made this movie a drama. But they also fit a lot of comedy into the film. I feel as though Dustin Hoffman played the role of a personality actor. I felt like I've seen the same persona played in other films he has starred in as well.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Graduate
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    stephypoo912
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I like this film. Even after seeing it three times! Seeing it every time, I have different feelings towards this film. Any way, i still end up liking it and loving the ending. It is a film that is predictable in some ways, but in others it definitely isn't. The whole movie, in itself is great. The editing is a great way to start the break-down. One of my favorite shots is the triple take in the beginning half of the movie. Another editing part that ALWAYS catches my eye is the pool shot then the hotel shot. The way it merges as one scene into the next is NOTHING like I have ever seen before. That definitely kept me enticed. The story line as well kept me watching it. The way it ended made me think, "Could there possibly be another way they could have found each other?" Hmm...
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A treatise on the nature of being a graduate
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    sunshinebeachcinema
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    In following up those cinematic classics that I'm somehow still catching up on, I recently saw The Graduate for the first time. I inevitably went into it with some idea of what was going to happen, but little more than an expectation for Dustin Hoffman to pursue a relationship with an older woman, to the sound of Simon & Garfunkel. Hoffman is Benjamin Braddock, the disaffected young university graduate who returns from his studies to a summer without direction. He is swiftly seduced by Mrs. Robinson, the wife of his father's business partner, and embarks on a lengthy affair, but his affection soon turns to her daughter, Elaine. Yet this is merely the bare bones of the plot: it's more complex than a simple romantic comedy, and the ending, notably, is ambiguous. It's impossible to complain about spoilers for a film that came out over forty years ago; it has seeped into popular culture, and been subjected to merciless parody. The iconic ending sequence is especially strange to watch for someone who grew up repeatedly watching Wayne's World 2 (1993), where it is replicated shot for shot. The critical eye has been on the film for so long, and it has passed through so many generations that its contemporary relevance can be questioned. Though a product of the late 1960s, the counterculture elements we associate with the period, such as free love, psychedelia, or hard rock. Benjamin's sexual experiences are not part of a revolution, and he remains trapped firmly within the rigid framework of upper middle class suburbia. While there's a certain fascination to looking back on a snapshot of the past, many of us no longer have the same relationship with our parents and the older generation. Do we look back at a history of steady liberalisation, but no massive social upheaval, and see further subversion as unnecessary? Do our parents, the children of the past, simply provide us with a system we no longer need to escape? Maybe modern youth have it worse than Benjamin; our coming of age is not so straightforward. We are no longer afforded the opportunity of clear rebellion, and are left to wallow in the established structure. What does hold true is the portrayal of a graduate with no clear future, returning to inhabit the fading skeleton of a life that's somehow no longer his own, and the dull resignation that there's little incentive to do anything about it. As a graduate myself (Though my current social circle suffers an absence of attractive lonely women) I can largely sympathise with Benjamin's predicament. After all, what does the immediate future hold? The prospects of the graduate are numerous and varied. Will it be more of the same on a postgraduate course? Are we heading for the city for a mysterious role as an analyst or consultant (when we're really just brewing tea for executives)? Perhaps it's just going to be a couple more months playing video games in pyjamas before we make a final decision. We still need something. A last hurrah before we're thrown to the world of work and responsibility for good. Could the modern rebellion be merely the fabled gap year abroad? At any rate, it seems coming of age requires something extreme, ditching the world and obligations, the way that Benjamin does at the end of The Graduate. The whole film is an exploration of these questions, symbolically relayed through the central relationships. The choices the characters make in their attachments are reflective of the choices that can be made in all facets of life. This is emphasised stylistically through a number of visually captivating shots and transitions that underline the sense of emptiness and alienation. Water (swimming pools, aquariums, and rain) appears frequently as a tool of separation. The soundtrack contains little youthful euphoria, but is melancholic, featuring repeated motifs that again, accentuate loneliness. These are played during moments that could otherwise be seen as positive steps in Benjamin's life, at the height of his relationship with Mrs. Robinson, and during his final elopement, elevating the drama above mere comedy. His obsession with Elaine is far from romantic destiny, and exists primarily as an escape from his relationship with her mother, and a chance to give his life some purpose outside an unhealthy liaison that makes him feel increasingly trapped. Compared with Mrs. Robinson, Elaine's character is chronically underdeveloped, though she responds positively to Benjamin's pseudo-philosophical ramblings. While she is disgusted to learn of Benjamin's affair with her mother, we learn little else of her thoughts on home, and where she fits in do the loveless dynamic in the Robinson household. We do not know if she as desperate to break free as Benjamin is. She ultimately follows him on impulse, having initially been happy to marry another at her parents' request. The separation from the character of Elaine forces us to experience the relationship purely from the perspective of Benjamin, who has put her on a pedestal and made her the object of his salvation. Despite the vein of sympathy I have as a fellow graduate, Benjamin is at times an insufferable and frustrating character to watch, and ultimately, Mrs. Robinson comes off as more sympathetic. She is the one who is truly lost and trapped. Benjamin still has his whole life ahead of him, once he finally decides what he's going to do with it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An Under-appreciated Classic!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    FilmMuscle
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I find it disappointing that the Graduate isn't one of those constantly-talked-about classics like The Godfather, Kramer vs. Kramer, Apocalypse Now, The Shawshank Redemption, etc. I had mixed expectations for the film since I heard, prior to viewing, some negative opinions and positive ones from individuals who'd recently watched it. Now, let's talk about why this film should be just as remembered of a classic as the others above. First of all and- in my opinion- most importantly, the film carries with it a highly intriguing and interesting story that keeps you entertained the entire way as the clever plot unravels. You're presented with this socially angsty twenty-year-old who's basically helpless, surrounded by intimidating people and frightening situations. He's a character that the audience can't help but love. For me, I could find myself relating to his personality quite a bit. I, too, attempt to stray away from great attention and prefer a much calmer and less crowded environment. The story, itself, keeps your attention because it's just strongly gripping insofar as this character finds himself in extremely awkward and threatening situations. Personally- like with the scene where Benjamin is awkwardly attempting to avoid suspicion while getting a hotel room- I recalled similar instances with myself where I was about to engage in something that could be regrettable and had to deal with suspicious or curious bystanders, family members, or whatnot. While we're still on it, the acting was unbelievably good, especially Dustin Hoffman's break-out performance as Benjamin. The way he portrayed a timid and awkward character surely blew away the moviegoers that night of its release. His timing and speech delivery, overall, creates an absolutely believable story about this fully realistic outcast. The way he would retreat under the pool whenever he felt vulnerable or faced his imposing parents definitely moved me because I could honestly understand him in any given predicament. At times, I feel like finding some peaceful and impenetrable spot to socially leave the world and obtain some time to breathe. The script of this picture is brilliant from the convincing dialogue to the intelligent build-up of relationships and their interconnections. For the moment, let's delve into the more technical side of The Graduate since its cinematography and editing is exceptional- excellent, might I say. The evolution of filmmaking over the decades from when Hollywood first stemmed truly and impressively proved itself in this movie. For example, there's a particular scene where Benjamin is "drifting" on the pool's air mattress, and he's interrupted by his irritating parents and the Robinsons themselves, and as they begin discussing his current uneventful life, the camera perfectly displays these incredibly condescending figures looking down at him with the sun shining so brightly that it seems to be blinding both the viewer and Benjamin as he's forced to look up at them. You sympathize with Benjamin because you feel their aggression and- again- condescending conversation about how he's not doing anything with his life, and I'm sure everyone's been in that sort of position, mentally or physically. Then, another shot shows Elaine as her confused face gets less and less blurry (indicating her progression towards fully understanding the mystery) until she finally realizes what's essentially transpiring between Benjamin and her own mother. In terms of editing, an instance showcases fast cutting to Mrs. Robinson's naked body as Benjamin attempts to ignore it but can't help his lust in a way. The film also smoothly and uniquely transitions to new settings without the audience even noticing at first as Benjamin exits the pool, walks to his room, and is suddenly found entering Mrs. Robinson's bed. Another strength of the camera-work is the noticeably lengthy shots where we witness entire conversations occurring in one single take or the scuba mask scene where a few minutes or so are filmed from a first-person perspective as Benjamin dives into his pool. In sum, the film seemed like a breath of fresh air that was affected by an unquestionably relatable protagonist that you felt for and his escape with the love of his life seemed utterly satisfying as well. Usually, happy endings done the way The Graduate did it come off as corny and clich&eacute;d, but your liking for the characters and their success overshadowed that aspect. So far, I've been loving all the films in class as this is yet another one I can't help but give high praise to.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not A Classic.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    AaronCapenBanner
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Mike Nichols directed this film about Ben Braddock, a confused young man trying to decide on his future in a society he can't understand, but instead becomes involved with the married mother of his reluctant girlfriend, and the various complications that ensue as a result. Dustin Hoffman leads a good cast, it has haunting songs by Simon & Garfunkel, is beloved by many of that generation, and even won Nichols an Academy Award for best director. So what's not to like? For a film that reacts negatively to the word "plastic", that's just how I feel about the characters and setting. Nothing about this film feels particularly real, certainly not the affair of Ben and Mrs. Robinson(Anne Bancroft) which not only isn't believable, it doesn't make sense, feels utterly manufactured and wrong. Katharine Ross as his girlfriend reacts to the news believably, but the ending will leave the viewer up in the air, since it, while dramatically staged, feels forced and unsatisfying. It just doesn't work for me.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    If anyone was born to play an awkward 21 year old...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    cleary-joshua
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    If anyone was born to play an awkward 21 year old deciding what to do with his life, it has to be 30 year old Dustin Hoffman, who steals this movie with his brilliant portrayal of Benjamin Braddock. It's a performance with humour and emotion all rolled into one. For example, Hoffman's performance when he first takes Mrs. Robinson home is hilarious, with his constant nervous stammering and occasional high-pitched squeaks. The final shot of Elaine and Benjamin has so much drama in both of their expressions, and you can tell how great the pair are as actors. They've just run away together, and she's already married. Are they completely happy? Not really, and both of their faces have a sort of "now what?" expression, leaving the audience thinking about whether it was the right decision. As for the story itself, it's comical without becoming too farcical, and has enough drama later on to keep the audience interested. It's also beautifully shot, with a lot of clever cutting and images, such as the fact that Benjamin is always being shot through other objects, like the hotel woodwork, or Mrs. Robinson's leg. The music too is great, and Simon and Garfunkel's songs, though some of them are used almost too much, manage to create just the right atmosphere for the film. The late Roger Ebert originally gave this film 4 stars, but thirty years later, dropped his score down to 3, something I'm not sure I've ever heard of a critic doing. He states in his later review that it's not a film that has stood the test of time, that modern audiences wouldn't find it as funny. I disagree with this, and managed to find humour in a lot of the film. However his main reason for doing so is the character of Benjamin, whom he calls an 'insufferable creep', and now I think about it, Ebert is kind of right. Perhaps the awkwardness does go a bit too far at points, and he is just a bit strange and horrible in taking Elaine to the strip club and stalking her for a long time. This detail aside, I still found it to be a hugely enjoyable film which left a lot to think about afterwards, as well as a lot of laughs, and it's worth watching if only for Hoffman's performance and delivery of that classic line: "Mrs. Robinson, you're trying to seduce me, aren't you."
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    It's Graduation Day! I think this movie is seducing me. You're trying to seduce me. Aren't you?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ironhorse_iv
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The movie has this great 1960's Hollywood New Wave feel to it. This is a coming of age movie that works for me. A lot of coming of age movies seem to try to make their character innocent, but they never actually are. They do a bunch of irresponsible stuff and at the end of the day a lot of people call them "innocent and lost", but it just feels like an excuse to sympathize for being an idiot. However I do sympathize for this character, Benjamin Braddock (Dustin Hoffman). It seemed like he was forced into a pool and not allowed to come back up. The theme of an innocent and confused youth who is exploited, misdirected, seduced and betrayed by a corrupt older generation was well understood by film audiences and captured the spirit of the times. One of the film's posters proclaimed the difficult coming-of-age for college graduate. Directed by Mike Nichols, the film is based on the 1963 novel The Graduate by Charles Webb. The movie opens to one of the best songs of the 1960's, Simon & Garfunkel - The Sound of Silence. This is one of the best songs I've ever listened to. I think the soundtrack pretty much made Simon & Garfunkel from nearly unknown folk singers, to legends of the music industry. You can also hear an earlier version of Mrs. Robinson in the movie. The song as it appears in the film is different from the familiar hit single version, as only the chorus of the song appears late in the film and with slightly different lyrics. It was only later on that Paul Simon and Art Garfunkel re-recorded the song by employing additional lyrics to form the hit single. It's kinda funny that the original song was call 'Mrs. Roosevelt'. It would really be funny to see Eleanor Roosevelt have an affair with a younger man. The Sound of Silence song work for the film as it really fit in with the plot regarding the lack of communication between the controlling parents and the young adults. Anyways, Benjamin Braddock has just arrive back home, after years in College. Dustin Hoffman played the part of the awkward post-graduate student perfectly. I can't see Mike Nichols first choice, Robert Redford in this role. Dustin is kind of awkward that works, he isn't to an abnormal extent creep, he more just describes the entire situation to the woman. Unsure of himself, by being uncomfortable and anxious, and force to hear others decide for him what he will do with his future. Benjamin Braddock soon find himself, seduce by an older woman, Mrs. Robinson (Anne Bancroft) and find himself tempt into an affair. Anne Bancroft is a cougar on the prowl, really to pounce on her prey. She was really pretty in the room. Even though her character is sympathetic, it doesn't change the fact that her character is a vindictive sexual predator. Just the line 'You've known me nearly all your life." Is just disturbing. Mrs. Robinson wanting to bang a kid she watched grow up? That's gross, and just a step below Woody Allen marrying his stepdaughter. She was marry too, so not only is she wanting to date a younger man, she watch when he was kid, but she's also cheating on her husband. It is pure flesh, but she is nice about it. It is just natural, pragmatic and not that romantic-idealistic. She's still the Queen of all Milfs. Her personal life isn't the only thing she's opening. Some people might hate the fact, that the two main characters are two of the most shallow, childish characters. Mrs. Robinson can be especially hateful without any specific motivation, while Benjamin is bit spineless. I do love Dustin Hoffman in the role, but he was way too old for this part. He was playing a 20 year old, and he himself was 30 at the time. Also Anne Bancroft was only 35 during the time of filming. It also kinda funny that the actress Katharine Ross who played Anne Bancroft's daughter Elaine was only 8 years younger than her 35 and 27, miscasting. Katherine Ross looks lovely as Elaine, but she's barely one-dimensional and looks like a girl who would never go for a guy like Dustin Hoffman in a million years. She only went with him, because of her over controlling parents. Anyways, Benjamin soon fall in love with Elaine, and is in a dilemma. Should be continue to live with people telling what to do with his life like Mrs. Robinson or should he set his own future with a girl like Elaine? Find out, by watching it. The ending is up to question, if these two would work out. It leaves a deep interpretation of risky love. This is a classic film: tightly written, intelligent, funny, wonderfully acted, with a great climax with the church, so to speak. You will get seduce into watching the film by how brilliant it is.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of the most overvalued films of all times
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Turin_Horse
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The great and classical soundtrack by Simon & Garfunkel, a group of good actors and one of the most famous scenes in cinema history with Anne Bancroft and Dustin Hoffman as protagonists cannot make up a poor, even lame plot, an incoherent and silly story full of holes and a dull direction and editing. One wonders how such a film could make its way through time to still be considered a "classic" and seemingly appreciated by a high number of people; maybe, for people in the sixties this film meant something, or touched something inside them or whatever, but nowadays The Graduate should long have been put in the bag of dated unworthy-to-watch films. The final scenes with Benjamin trying to prevent the wedding of his sweetheart and taking her with him are just shameful!. There are some very good films from the sixties, try Midnight Cowboy for instance, but skip this over-overvalued film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Creative, compelling & classic
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    stephparsons
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    You've gotta love The Graduate.&nbsp; Even after 44 years, it's still relevant, highly watchable, funny, a titchy bit avant-garde, and boasts a top notch, flawless script.&nbsp; Dustin Hoffman as Ben does a bang up job playing the hapless graduate who desperately wants to escape his boring, careerist fate (as predetermined by&nbsp; his parents and society at large).&nbsp; He exudes 'sullen-youth-ness', boredom-with-life, naivet&eacute;, awkwardness and an (almost) 'aspergers' style of speech which are amusing and poignant.&nbsp; Despite all the drama that unfolds; the seduction followed by the 'coming-of-age' sex with an older woman, the falling in love with a fresh, vibrant young woman, The Graduate is, ultimately, a film about ennui; that dull, thudding, inexorable grind we face upon leaving school and being forced to 'decide what to do' for the rest of our sad, pathetic , predictable lives.&nbsp; Career paths being far more restrictive in the '60s,&nbsp; the sense of doom and pointlessness that Ben feels is exacerbated and he portrays it so very well.&nbsp;&nbsp; The friend of his parents who says, "I have one word for you Ben...plastics", sums up the soulless, futile, and arid future that Ben fears is his destiny. &nbsp;The Graduate experiments successfully with some creative cinematography including unusual camera angles, and interesting switches from one milieu to another e.g. Ben jumping into the swimming pool but ending up on the bed with Mrs Robinson.&nbsp;&nbsp; The swimming pool scene where Ben must walk under water in his birthday present - an old fashioned diving suit- is especially memorable and provides a convincing metaphor for the restrictiveness, loneliness and entrapment that he fears is to be his fate.&nbsp; There is nothing 'awkward' or dated about this classic film, it holds one's attention from start to finish.&nbsp; The ending steers clear of that typical 'happily ever after' Hollywood schmaltz&nbsp; and, in subtle tones presents us with 'ennui in a nutshell' as Ben and Elaine exchange smiles, then worried looks, and then expressions devoid of all emotion.&nbsp; There is nothing I would change about The Graduate, it's a classic and always will be.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Loved it!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    oliviadoerrer17
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Personally thought this particular film was great! I have heard many things about it's wonderful storyline and acting, I definitely had high expectations going into the film and it exceeded those. I always love a movie that is scandalous, and makes you wonder every second if someone is going to get caught. Dustin Hoffman really took on his role and made it believable to his shy nervous personality. He managed to make most scenes awkward which made it very funny. My personal favorite was the scene where Mrs Robinson tried to seduce him, you could tell by his facial expression and sweat he was extremely nervous and uncomfortable. The shots of Mrs Robinson's nude body then to Benjamin's face then back to her body and so on really was comical. The storyline did end up becoming interesting and complicated due to obvious reasons which overall added to the film. I liked the fact that Benjamin never gave up in what he wanted and fought to the end.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Hysterical
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    RoseXGold
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I loved this movie. It was the perfect blend of comedy, drama,love and action. The overall plot was very intriguing. I feel like everyone has been in the main characters shoes before( not knowing exactly what you want to do with your life). The theme was very relate-able. I feel as though everyone had a specific character that they could some how relate to. The music in this film was something that stood out to me. It was a bit more modern. I adored the fact that they not only made this movie a drama. But they also fit a lot of comedy into the film. I feel as though Dustin Hoffman played the role of a personality actor. I felt like I've seen the same persona played in other films he has starred in as well.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Graduate
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    stephypoo912
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I like this film. Even after seeing it three times! Seeing it every time, I have different feelings towards this film. Any way, i still end up liking it and loving the ending. It is a film that is predictable in some ways, but in others it definitely isn't. The whole movie, in itself is great. The editing is a great way to start the break-down. One of my favorite shots is the triple take in the beginning half of the movie. Another editing part that ALWAYS catches my eye is the pool shot then the hotel shot. The way it merges as one scene into the next is NOTHING like I have ever seen before. That definitely kept me enticed. The story line as well kept me watching it. The way it ended made me think, "Could there possibly be another way they could have found each other?" Hmm...
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A treatise on the nature of being a graduate
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    sunshinebeachcinema
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    In following up those cinematic classics that I'm somehow still catching up on, I recently saw The Graduate for the first time. I inevitably went into it with some idea of what was going to happen, but little more than an expectation for Dustin Hoffman to pursue a relationship with an older woman, to the sound of Simon & Garfunkel. Hoffman is Benjamin Braddock, the disaffected young university graduate who returns from his studies to a summer without direction. He is swiftly seduced by Mrs. Robinson, the wife of his father's business partner, and embarks on a lengthy affair, but his affection soon turns to her daughter, Elaine. Yet this is merely the bare bones of the plot: it's more complex than a simple romantic comedy, and the ending, notably, is ambiguous. It's impossible to complain about spoilers for a film that came out over forty years ago; it has seeped into popular culture, and been subjected to merciless parody. The iconic ending sequence is especially strange to watch for someone who grew up repeatedly watching Wayne's World 2 (1993), where it is replicated shot for shot. The critical eye has been on the film for so long, and it has passed through so many generations that its contemporary relevance can be questioned. Though a product of the late 1960s, the counterculture elements we associate with the period, such as free love, psychedelia, or hard rock. Benjamin's sexual experiences are not part of a revolution, and he remains trapped firmly within the rigid framework of upper middle class suburbia. While there's a certain fascination to looking back on a snapshot of the past, many of us no longer have the same relationship with our parents and the older generation. Do we look back at a history of steady liberalisation, but no massive social upheaval, and see further subversion as unnecessary? Do our parents, the children of the past, simply provide us with a system we no longer need to escape? Maybe modern youth have it worse than Benjamin; our coming of age is not so straightforward. We are no longer afforded the opportunity of clear rebellion, and are left to wallow in the established structure. What does hold true is the portrayal of a graduate with no clear future, returning to inhabit the fading skeleton of a life that's somehow no longer his own, and the dull resignation that there's little incentive to do anything about it. As a graduate myself (Though my current social circle suffers an absence of attractive lonely women) I can largely sympathise with Benjamin's predicament. After all, what does the immediate future hold? The prospects of the graduate are numerous and varied. Will it be more of the same on a postgraduate course? Are we heading for the city for a mysterious role as an analyst or consultant (when we're really just brewing tea for executives)? Perhaps it's just going to be a couple more months playing video games in pyjamas before we make a final decision. We still need something. A last hurrah before we're thrown to the world of work and responsibility for good. Could the modern rebellion be merely the fabled gap year abroad? At any rate, it seems coming of age requires something extreme, ditching the world and obligations, the way that Benjamin does at the end of The Graduate. The whole film is an exploration of these questions, symbolically relayed through the central relationships. The choices the characters make in their attachments are reflective of the choices that can be made in all facets of life. This is emphasised stylistically through a number of visually captivating shots and transitions that underline the sense of emptiness and alienation. Water (swimming pools, aquariums, and rain) appears frequently as a tool of separation. The soundtrack contains little youthful euphoria, but is melancholic, featuring repeated motifs that again, accentuate loneliness. These are played during moments that could otherwise be seen as positive steps in Benjamin's life, at the height of his relationship with Mrs. Robinson, and during his final elopement, elevating the drama above mere comedy. His obsession with Elaine is far from romantic destiny, and exists primarily as an escape from his relationship with her mother, and a chance to give his life some purpose outside an unhealthy liaison that makes him feel increasingly trapped. Compared with Mrs. Robinson, Elaine's character is chronically underdeveloped, though she responds positively to Benjamin's pseudo-philosophical ramblings. While she is disgusted to learn of Benjamin's affair with her mother, we learn little else of her thoughts on home, and where she fits in do the loveless dynamic in the Robinson household. We do not know if she as desperate to break free as Benjamin is. She ultimately follows him on impulse, having initially been happy to marry another at her parents' request. The separation from the character of Elaine forces us to experience the relationship purely from the perspective of Benjamin, who has put her on a pedestal and made her the object of his salvation. Despite the vein of sympathy I have as a fellow graduate, Benjamin is at times an insufferable and frustrating character to watch, and ultimately, Mrs. Robinson comes off as more sympathetic. She is the one who is truly lost and trapped. Benjamin still has his whole life ahead of him, once he finally decides what he's going to do with it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An Under-appreciated Classic!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    FilmMuscle
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I find it disappointing that the Graduate isn't one of those constantly-talked-about classics like The Godfather, Kramer vs. Kramer, Apocalypse Now, The Shawshank Redemption, etc. I had mixed expectations for the film since I heard, prior to viewing, some negative opinions and positive ones from individuals who'd recently watched it. Now, let's talk about why this film should be just as remembered of a classic as the others above. First of all and- in my opinion- most importantly, the film carries with it a highly intriguing and interesting story that keeps you entertained the entire way as the clever plot unravels. You're presented with this socially angsty twenty-year-old who's basically helpless, surrounded by intimidating people and frightening situations. He's a character that the audience can't help but love. For me, I could find myself relating to his personality quite a bit. I, too, attempt to stray away from great attention and prefer a much calmer and less crowded environment. The story, itself, keeps your attention because it's just strongly gripping insofar as this character finds himself in extremely awkward and threatening situations. Personally- like with the scene where Benjamin is awkwardly attempting to avoid suspicion while getting a hotel room- I recalled similar instances with myself where I was about to engage in something that could be regrettable and had to deal with suspicious or curious bystanders, family members, or whatnot. While we're still on it, the acting was unbelievably good, especially Dustin Hoffman's break-out performance as Benjamin. The way he portrayed a timid and awkward character surely blew away the moviegoers that night of its release. His timing and speech delivery, overall, creates an absolutely believable story about this fully realistic outcast. The way he would retreat under the pool whenever he felt vulnerable or faced his imposing parents definitely moved me because I could honestly understand him in any given predicament. At times, I feel like finding some peaceful and impenetrable spot to socially leave the world and obtain some time to breathe. The script of this picture is brilliant from the convincing dialogue to the intelligent build-up of relationships and their interconnections. For the moment, let's delve into the more technical side of The Graduate since its cinematography and editing is exceptional- excellent, might I say. The evolution of filmmaking over the decades from when Hollywood first stemmed truly and impressively proved itself in this movie. For example, there's a particular scene where Benjamin is "drifting" on the pool's air mattress, and he's interrupted by his irritating parents and the Robinsons themselves, and as they begin discussing his current uneventful life, the camera perfectly displays these incredibly condescending figures looking down at him with the sun shining so brightly that it seems to be blinding both the viewer and Benjamin as he's forced to look up at them. You sympathize with Benjamin because you feel their aggression and- again- condescending conversation about how he's not doing anything with his life, and I'm sure everyone's been in that sort of position, mentally or physically. Then, another shot shows Elaine as her confused face gets less and less blurry (indicating her progression towards fully understanding the mystery) until she finally realizes what's essentially transpiring between Benjamin and her own mother. In terms of editing, an instance showcases fast cutting to Mrs. Robinson's naked body as Benjamin attempts to ignore it but can't help his lust in a way. The film also smoothly and uniquely transitions to new settings without the audience even noticing at first as Benjamin exits the pool, walks to his room, and is suddenly found entering Mrs. Robinson's bed. Another strength of the camera-work is the noticeably lengthy shots where we witness entire conversations occurring in one single take or the scuba mask scene where a few minutes or so are filmed from a first-person perspective as Benjamin dives into his pool. In sum, the film seemed like a breath of fresh air that was affected by an unquestionably relatable protagonist that you felt for and his escape with the love of his life seemed utterly satisfying as well. Usually, happy endings done the way The Graduate did it come off as corny and clich&eacute;d, but your liking for the characters and their success overshadowed that aspect. So far, I've been loving all the films in class as this is yet another one I can't help but give high praise to.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not A Classic.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    AaronCapenBanner
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Mike Nichols directed this film about Ben Braddock, a confused young man trying to decide on his future in a society he can't understand, but instead becomes involved with the married mother of his reluctant girlfriend, and the various complications that ensue as a result. Dustin Hoffman leads a good cast, it has haunting songs by Simon & Garfunkel, is beloved by many of that generation, and even won Nichols an Academy Award for best director. So what's not to like? For a film that reacts negatively to the word "plastic", that's just how I feel about the characters and setting. Nothing about this film feels particularly real, certainly not the affair of Ben and Mrs. Robinson(Anne Bancroft) which not only isn't believable, it doesn't make sense, feels utterly manufactured and wrong. Katharine Ross as his girlfriend reacts to the news believably, but the ending will leave the viewer up in the air, since it, while dramatically staged, feels forced and unsatisfying. It just doesn't work for me.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    If anyone was born to play an awkward 21 year old...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    cleary-joshua
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    If anyone was born to play an awkward 21 year old deciding what to do with his life, it has to be 30 year old Dustin Hoffman, who steals this movie with his brilliant portrayal of Benjamin Braddock. It's a performance with humour and emotion all rolled into one. For example, Hoffman's performance when he first takes Mrs. Robinson home is hilarious, with his constant nervous stammering and occasional high-pitched squeaks. The final shot of Elaine and Benjamin has so much drama in both of their expressions, and you can tell how great the pair are as actors. They've just run away together, and she's already married. Are they completely happy? Not really, and both of their faces have a sort of "now what?" expression, leaving the audience thinking about whether it was the right decision. As for the story itself, it's comical without becoming too farcical, and has enough drama later on to keep the audience interested. It's also beautifully shot, with a lot of clever cutting and images, such as the fact that Benjamin is always being shot through other objects, like the hotel woodwork, or Mrs. Robinson's leg. The music too is great, and Simon and Garfunkel's songs, though some of them are used almost too much, manage to create just the right atmosphere for the film. The late Roger Ebert originally gave this film 4 stars, but thirty years later, dropped his score down to 3, something I'm not sure I've ever heard of a critic doing. He states in his later review that it's not a film that has stood the test of time, that modern audiences wouldn't find it as funny. I disagree with this, and managed to find humour in a lot of the film. However his main reason for doing so is the character of Benjamin, whom he calls an 'insufferable creep', and now I think about it, Ebert is kind of right. Perhaps the awkwardness does go a bit too far at points, and he is just a bit strange and horrible in taking Elaine to the strip club and stalking her for a long time. This detail aside, I still found it to be a hugely enjoyable film which left a lot to think about afterwards, as well as a lot of laughs, and it's worth watching if only for Hoffman's performance and delivery of that classic line: "Mrs. Robinson, you're trying to seduce me, aren't you."
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    It's Graduation Day! I think this movie is seducing me. You're trying to seduce me. Aren't you?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ironhorse_iv
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The movie has this great 1960's Hollywood New Wave feel to it. This is a coming of age movie that works for me. A lot of coming of age movies seem to try to make their character innocent, but they never actually are. They do a bunch of irresponsible stuff and at the end of the day a lot of people call them "innocent and lost", but it just feels like an excuse to sympathize for being an idiot. However I do sympathize for this character, Benjamin Braddock (Dustin Hoffman). It seemed like he was forced into a pool and not allowed to come back up. The theme of an innocent and confused youth who is exploited, misdirected, seduced and betrayed by a corrupt older generation was well understood by film audiences and captured the spirit of the times. One of the film's posters proclaimed the difficult coming-of-age for college graduate. Directed by Mike Nichols, the film is based on the 1963 novel The Graduate by Charles Webb. The movie opens to one of the best songs of the 1960's, Simon & Garfunkel - The Sound of Silence. This is one of the best songs I've ever listened to. I think the soundtrack pretty much made Simon & Garfunkel from nearly unknown folk singers, to legends of the music industry. You can also hear an earlier version of Mrs. Robinson in the movie. The song as it appears in the film is different from the familiar hit single version, as only the chorus of the song appears late in the film and with slightly different lyrics. It was only later on that Paul Simon and Art Garfunkel re-recorded the song by employing additional lyrics to form the hit single. It's kinda funny that the original song was call 'Mrs. Roosevelt'. It would really be funny to see Eleanor Roosevelt have an affair with a younger man. The Sound of Silence song work for the film as it really fit in with the plot regarding the lack of communication between the controlling parents and the young adults. Anyways, Benjamin Braddock has just arrive back home, after years in College. Dustin Hoffman played the part of the awkward post-graduate student perfectly. I can't see Mike Nichols first choice, Robert Redford in this role. Dustin is kind of awkward that works, he isn't to an abnormal extent creep, he more just describes the entire situation to the woman. Unsure of himself, by being uncomfortable and anxious, and force to hear others decide for him what he will do with his future. Benjamin Braddock soon find himself, seduce by an older woman, Mrs. Robinson (Anne Bancroft) and find himself tempt into an affair. Anne Bancroft is a cougar on the prowl, really to pounce on her prey. She was really pretty in the room. Even though her character is sympathetic, it doesn't change the fact that her character is a vindictive sexual predator. Just the line 'You've known me nearly all your life." Is just disturbing. Mrs. Robinson wanting to bang a kid she watched grow up? That's gross, and just a step below Woody Allen marrying his stepdaughter. She was marry too, so not only is she wanting to date a younger man, she watch when he was kid, but she's also cheating on her husband. It is pure flesh, but she is nice about it. It is just natural, pragmatic and not that romantic-idealistic. She's still the Queen of all Milfs. Her personal life isn't the only thing she's opening. Some people might hate the fact, that the two main characters are two of the most shallow, childish characters. Mrs. Robinson can be especially hateful without any specific motivation, while Benjamin is bit spineless. I do love Dustin Hoffman in the role, but he was way too old for this part. He was playing a 20 year old, and he himself was 30 at the time. Also Anne Bancroft was only 35 during the time of filming. It also kinda funny that the actress Katharine Ross who played Anne Bancroft's daughter Elaine was only 8 years younger than her 35 and 27, miscasting. Katherine Ross looks lovely as Elaine, but she's barely one-dimensional and looks like a girl who would never go for a guy like Dustin Hoffman in a million years. She only went with him, because of her over controlling parents. Anyways, Benjamin soon fall in love with Elaine, and is in a dilemma. Should be continue to live with people telling what to do with his life like Mrs. Robinson or should he set his own future with a girl like Elaine? Find out, by watching it. The ending is up to question, if these two would work out. It leaves a deep interpretation of risky love. This is a classic film: tightly written, intelligent, funny, wonderfully acted, with a great climax with the church, so to speak. You will get seduce into watching the film by how brilliant it is.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of the most overvalued films of all times
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Turin_Horse
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The great and classical soundtrack by Simon & Garfunkel, a group of good actors and one of the most famous scenes in cinema history with Anne Bancroft and Dustin Hoffman as protagonists cannot make up a poor, even lame plot, an incoherent and silly story full of holes and a dull direction and editing. One wonders how such a film could make its way through time to still be considered a "classic" and seemingly appreciated by a high number of people; maybe, for people in the sixties this film meant something, or touched something inside them or whatever, but nowadays The Graduate should long have been put in the bag of dated unworthy-to-watch films. The final scenes with Benjamin trying to prevent the wedding of his sweetheart and taking her with him are just shameful!. There are some very good films from the sixties, try Midnight Cowboy for instance, but skip this over-overvalued film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Creative, compelling & classic
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    stephparsons
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    You've gotta love The Graduate.&nbsp; Even after 44 years, it's still relevant, highly watchable, funny, a titchy bit avant-garde, and boasts a top notch, flawless script.&nbsp; Dustin Hoffman as Ben does a bang up job playing the hapless graduate who desperately wants to escape his boring, careerist fate (as predetermined by&nbsp; his parents and society at large).&nbsp; He exudes 'sullen-youth-ness', boredom-with-life, naivet&eacute;, awkwardness and an (almost) 'aspergers' style of speech which are amusing and poignant.&nbsp; Despite all the drama that unfolds; the seduction followed by the 'coming-of-age' sex with an older woman, the falling in love with a fresh, vibrant young woman, The Graduate is, ultimately, a film about ennui; that dull, thudding, inexorable grind we face upon leaving school and being forced to 'decide what to do' for the rest of our sad, pathetic , predictable lives.&nbsp; Career paths being far more restrictive in the '60s,&nbsp; the sense of doom and pointlessness that Ben feels is exacerbated and he portrays it so very well.&nbsp;&nbsp; The friend of his parents who says, "I have one word for you Ben...plastics", sums up the soulless, futile, and arid future that Ben fears is his destiny. &nbsp;The Graduate experiments successfully with some creative cinematography including unusual camera angles, and interesting switches from one milieu to another e.g. Ben jumping into the swimming pool but ending up on the bed with Mrs Robinson.&nbsp;&nbsp; The swimming pool scene where Ben must walk under water in his birthday present - an old fashioned diving suit- is especially memorable and provides a convincing metaphor for the restrictiveness, loneliness and entrapment that he fears is to be his fate.&nbsp; There is nothing 'awkward' or dated about this classic film, it holds one's attention from start to finish.&nbsp; The ending steers clear of that typical 'happily ever after' Hollywood schmaltz&nbsp; and, in subtle tones presents us with 'ennui in a nutshell' as Ben and Elaine exchange smiles, then worried looks, and then expressions devoid of all emotion.&nbsp; There is nothing I would change about The Graduate, it's a classic and always will be.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Loved it!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    oliviadoerrer17
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Personally thought this particular film was great! I have heard many things about it's wonderful storyline and acting, I definitely had high expectations going into the film and it exceeded those. I always love a movie that is scandalous, and makes you wonder every second if someone is going to get caught. Dustin Hoffman really took on his role and made it believable to his shy nervous personality. He managed to make most scenes awkward which made it very funny. My personal favorite was the scene where Mrs Robinson tried to seduce him, you could tell by his facial expression and sweat he was extremely nervous and uncomfortable. The shots of Mrs Robinson's nude body then to Benjamin's face then back to her body and so on really was comical. The storyline did end up becoming interesting and complicated due to obvious reasons which overall added to the film. I liked the fact that Benjamin never gave up in what he wanted and fought to the end.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Hysterical
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    RoseXGold
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I loved this movie. It was the perfect blend of comedy, drama,love and action. The overall plot was very intriguing. I feel like everyone has been in the main characters shoes before( not knowing exactly what you want to do with your life). The theme was very relate-able. I feel as though everyone had a specific character that they could some how relate to. The music in this film was something that stood out to me. It was a bit more modern. I adored the fact that they not only made this movie a drama. But they also fit a lot of comedy into the film. I feel as though Dustin Hoffman played the role of a personality actor. I felt like I've seen the same persona played in other films he has starred in as well.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Graduate
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    stephypoo912
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I like this film. Even after seeing it three times! Seeing it every time, I have different feelings towards this film. Any way, i still end up liking it and loving the ending. It is a film that is predictable in some ways, but in others it definitely isn't. The whole movie, in itself is great. The editing is a great way to start the break-down. One of my favorite shots is the triple take in the beginning half of the movie. Another editing part that ALWAYS catches my eye is the pool shot then the hotel shot. The way it merges as one scene into the next is NOTHING like I have ever seen before. That definitely kept me enticed. The story line as well kept me watching it. The way it ended made me think, "Could there possibly be another way they could have found each other?" Hmm...
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A treatise on the nature of being a graduate
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    sunshinebeachcinema
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    In following up those cinematic classics that I'm somehow still catching up on, I recently saw The Graduate for the first time. I inevitably went into it with some idea of what was going to happen, but little more than an expectation for Dustin Hoffman to pursue a relationship with an older woman, to the sound of Simon & Garfunkel. Hoffman is Benjamin Braddock, the disaffected young university graduate who returns from his studies to a summer without direction. He is swiftly seduced by Mrs. Robinson, the wife of his father's business partner, and embarks on a lengthy affair, but his affection soon turns to her daughter, Elaine. Yet this is merely the bare bones of the plot: it's more complex than a simple romantic comedy, and the ending, notably, is ambiguous. It's impossible to complain about spoilers for a film that came out over forty years ago; it has seeped into popular culture, and been subjected to merciless parody. The iconic ending sequence is especially strange to watch for someone who grew up repeatedly watching Wayne's World 2 (1993), where it is replicated shot for shot. The critical eye has been on the film for so long, and it has passed through so many generations that its contemporary relevance can be questioned. Though a product of the late 1960s, the counterculture elements we associate with the period, such as free love, psychedelia, or hard rock. Benjamin's sexual experiences are not part of a revolution, and he remains trapped firmly within the rigid framework of upper middle class suburbia. While there's a certain fascination to looking back on a snapshot of the past, many of us no longer have the same relationship with our parents and the older generation. Do we look back at a history of steady liberalisation, but no massive social upheaval, and see further subversion as unnecessary? Do our parents, the children of the past, simply provide us with a system we no longer need to escape? Maybe modern youth have it worse than Benjamin; our coming of age is not so straightforward. We are no longer afforded the opportunity of clear rebellion, and are left to wallow in the established structure. What does hold true is the portrayal of a graduate with no clear future, returning to inhabit the fading skeleton of a life that's somehow no longer his own, and the dull resignation that there's little incentive to do anything about it. As a graduate myself (Though my current social circle suffers an absence of attractive lonely women) I can largely sympathise with Benjamin's predicament. After all, what does the immediate future hold? The prospects of the graduate are numerous and varied. Will it be more of the same on a postgraduate course? Are we heading for the city for a mysterious role as an analyst or consultant (when we're really just brewing tea for executives)? Perhaps it's just going to be a couple more months playing video games in pyjamas before we make a final decision. We still need something. A last hurrah before we're thrown to the world of work and responsibility for good. Could the modern rebellion be merely the fabled gap year abroad? At any rate, it seems coming of age requires something extreme, ditching the world and obligations, the way that Benjamin does at the end of The Graduate. The whole film is an exploration of these questions, symbolically relayed through the central relationships. The choices the characters make in their attachments are reflective of the choices that can be made in all facets of life. This is emphasised stylistically through a number of visually captivating shots and transitions that underline the sense of emptiness and alienation. Water (swimming pools, aquariums, and rain) appears frequently as a tool of separation. The soundtrack contains little youthful euphoria, but is melancholic, featuring repeated motifs that again, accentuate loneliness. These are played during moments that could otherwise be seen as positive steps in Benjamin's life, at the height of his relationship with Mrs. Robinson, and during his final elopement, elevating the drama above mere comedy. His obsession with Elaine is far from romantic destiny, and exists primarily as an escape from his relationship with her mother, and a chance to give his life some purpose outside an unhealthy liaison that makes him feel increasingly trapped. Compared with Mrs. Robinson, Elaine's character is chronically underdeveloped, though she responds positively to Benjamin's pseudo-philosophical ramblings. While she is disgusted to learn of Benjamin's affair with her mother, we learn little else of her thoughts on home, and where she fits in do the loveless dynamic in the Robinson household. We do not know if she as desperate to break free as Benjamin is. She ultimately follows him on impulse, having initially been happy to marry another at her parents' request. The separation from the character of Elaine forces us to experience the relationship purely from the perspective of Benjamin, who has put her on a pedestal and made her the object of his salvation. Despite the vein of sympathy I have as a fellow graduate, Benjamin is at times an insufferable and frustrating character to watch, and ultimately, Mrs. Robinson comes off as more sympathetic. She is the one who is truly lost and trapped. Benjamin still has his whole life ahead of him, once he finally decides what he's going to do with it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An Under-appreciated Classic!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    FilmMuscle
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I find it disappointing that the Graduate isn't one of those constantly-talked-about classics like The Godfather, Kramer vs. Kramer, Apocalypse Now, The Shawshank Redemption, etc. I had mixed expectations for the film since I heard, prior to viewing, some negative opinions and positive ones from individuals who'd recently watched it. Now, let's talk about why this film should be just as remembered of a classic as the others above. First of all and- in my opinion- most importantly, the film carries with it a highly intriguing and interesting story that keeps you entertained the entire way as the clever plot unravels. You're presented with this socially angsty twenty-year-old who's basically helpless, surrounded by intimidating people and frightening situations. He's a character that the audience can't help but love. For me, I could find myself relating to his personality quite a bit. I, too, attempt to stray away from great attention and prefer a much calmer and less crowded environment. The story, itself, keeps your attention because it's just strongly gripping insofar as this character finds himself in extremely awkward and threatening situations. Personally- like with the scene where Benjamin is awkwardly attempting to avoid suspicion while getting a hotel room- I recalled similar instances with myself where I was about to engage in something that could be regrettable and had to deal with suspicious or curious bystanders, family members, or whatnot. While we're still on it, the acting was unbelievably good, especially Dustin Hoffman's break-out performance as Benjamin. The way he portrayed a timid and awkward character surely blew away the moviegoers that night of its release. His timing and speech delivery, overall, creates an absolutely believable story about this fully realistic outcast. The way he would retreat under the pool whenever he felt vulnerable or faced his imposing parents definitely moved me because I could honestly understand him in any given predicament. At times, I feel like finding some peaceful and impenetrable spot to socially leave the world and obtain some time to breathe. The script of this picture is brilliant from the convincing dialogue to the intelligent build-up of relationships and their interconnections. For the moment, let's delve into the more technical side of The Graduate since its cinematography and editing is exceptional- excellent, might I say. The evolution of filmmaking over the decades from when Hollywood first stemmed truly and impressively proved itself in this movie. For example, there's a particular scene where Benjamin is "drifting" on the pool's air mattress, and he's interrupted by his irritating parents and the Robinsons themselves, and as they begin discussing his current uneventful life, the camera perfectly displays these incredibly condescending figures looking down at him with the sun shining so brightly that it seems to be blinding both the viewer and Benjamin as he's forced to look up at them. You sympathize with Benjamin because you feel their aggression and- again- condescending conversation about how he's not doing anything with his life, and I'm sure everyone's been in that sort of position, mentally or physically. Then, another shot shows Elaine as her confused face gets less and less blurry (indicating her progression towards fully understanding the mystery) until she finally realizes what's essentially transpiring between Benjamin and her own mother. In terms of editing, an instance showcases fast cutting to Mrs. Robinson's naked body as Benjamin attempts to ignore it but can't help his lust in a way. The film also smoothly and uniquely transitions to new settings without the audience even noticing at first as Benjamin exits the pool, walks to his room, and is suddenly found entering Mrs. Robinson's bed. Another strength of the camera-work is the noticeably lengthy shots where we witness entire conversations occurring in one single take or the scuba mask scene where a few minutes or so are filmed from a first-person perspective as Benjamin dives into his pool. In sum, the film seemed like a breath of fresh air that was affected by an unquestionably relatable protagonist that you felt for and his escape with the love of his life seemed utterly satisfying as well. Usually, happy endings done the way The Graduate did it come off as corny and clich&eacute;d, but your liking for the characters and their success overshadowed that aspect. So far, I've been loving all the films in class as this is yet another one I can't help but give high praise to.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not A Classic.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    AaronCapenBanner
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Mike Nichols directed this film about Ben Braddock, a confused young man trying to decide on his future in a society he can't understand, but instead becomes involved with the married mother of his reluctant girlfriend, and the various complications that ensue as a result. Dustin Hoffman leads a good cast, it has haunting songs by Simon & Garfunkel, is beloved by many of that generation, and even won Nichols an Academy Award for best director. So what's not to like? For a film that reacts negatively to the word "plastic", that's just how I feel about the characters and setting. Nothing about this film feels particularly real, certainly not the affair of Ben and Mrs. Robinson(Anne Bancroft) which not only isn't believable, it doesn't make sense, feels utterly manufactured and wrong. Katharine Ross as his girlfriend reacts to the news believably, but the ending will leave the viewer up in the air, since it, while dramatically staged, feels forced and unsatisfying. It just doesn't work for me.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    If anyone was born to play an awkward 21 year old...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    cleary-joshua
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    If anyone was born to play an awkward 21 year old deciding what to do with his life, it has to be 30 year old Dustin Hoffman, who steals this movie with his brilliant portrayal of Benjamin Braddock. It's a performance with humour and emotion all rolled into one. For example, Hoffman's performance when he first takes Mrs. Robinson home is hilarious, with his constant nervous stammering and occasional high-pitched squeaks. The final shot of Elaine and Benjamin has so much drama in both of their expressions, and you can tell how great the pair are as actors. They've just run away together, and she's already married. Are they completely happy? Not really, and both of their faces have a sort of "now what?" expression, leaving the audience thinking about whether it was the right decision. As for the story itself, it's comical without becoming too farcical, and has enough drama later on to keep the audience interested. It's also beautifully shot, with a lot of clever cutting and images, such as the fact that Benjamin is always being shot through other objects, like the hotel woodwork, or Mrs. Robinson's leg. The music too is great, and Simon and Garfunkel's songs, though some of them are used almost too much, manage to create just the right atmosphere for the film. The late Roger Ebert originally gave this film 4 stars, but thirty years later, dropped his score down to 3, something I'm not sure I've ever heard of a critic doing. He states in his later review that it's not a film that has stood the test of time, that modern audiences wouldn't find it as funny. I disagree with this, and managed to find humour in a lot of the film. However his main reason for doing so is the character of Benjamin, whom he calls an 'insufferable creep', and now I think about it, Ebert is kind of right. Perhaps the awkwardness does go a bit too far at points, and he is just a bit strange and horrible in taking Elaine to the strip club and stalking her for a long time. This detail aside, I still found it to be a hugely enjoyable film which left a lot to think about afterwards, as well as a lot of laughs, and it's worth watching if only for Hoffman's performance and delivery of that classic line: "Mrs. Robinson, you're trying to seduce me, aren't you."
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    It's Graduation Day! I think this movie is seducing me. You're trying to seduce me. Aren't you?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ironhorse_iv
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The movie has this great 1960's Hollywood New Wave feel to it. This is a coming of age movie that works for me. A lot of coming of age movies seem to try to make their character innocent, but they never actually are. They do a bunch of irresponsible stuff and at the end of the day a lot of people call them "innocent and lost", but it just feels like an excuse to sympathize for being an idiot. However I do sympathize for this character, Benjamin Braddock (Dustin Hoffman). It seemed like he was forced into a pool and not allowed to come back up. The theme of an innocent and confused youth who is exploited, misdirected, seduced and betrayed by a corrupt older generation was well understood by film audiences and captured the spirit of the times. One of the film's posters proclaimed the difficult coming-of-age for college graduate. Directed by Mike Nichols, the film is based on the 1963 novel The Graduate by Charles Webb. The movie opens to one of the best songs of the 1960's, Simon & Garfunkel - The Sound of Silence. This is one of the best songs I've ever listened to. I think the soundtrack pretty much made Simon & Garfunkel from nearly unknown folk singers, to legends of the music industry. You can also hear an earlier version of Mrs. Robinson in the movie. The song as it appears in the film is different from the familiar hit single version, as only the chorus of the song appears late in the film and with slightly different lyrics. It was only later on that Paul Simon and Art Garfunkel re-recorded the song by employing additional lyrics to form the hit single. It's kinda funny that the original song was call 'Mrs. Roosevelt'. It would really be funny to see Eleanor Roosevelt have an affair with a younger man. The Sound of Silence song work for the film as it really fit in with the plot regarding the lack of communication between the controlling parents and the young adults. Anyways, Benjamin Braddock has just arrive back home, after years in College. Dustin Hoffman played the part of the awkward post-graduate student perfectly. I can't see Mike Nichols first choice, Robert Redford in this role. Dustin is kind of awkward that works, he isn't to an abnormal extent creep, he more just describes the entire situation to the woman. Unsure of himself, by being uncomfortable and anxious, and force to hear others decide for him what he will do with his future. Benjamin Braddock soon find himself, seduce by an older woman, Mrs. Robinson (Anne Bancroft) and find himself tempt into an affair. Anne Bancroft is a cougar on the prowl, really to pounce on her prey. She was really pretty in the room. Even though her character is sympathetic, it doesn't change the fact that her character is a vindictive sexual predator. Just the line 'You've known me nearly all your life." Is just disturbing. Mrs. Robinson wanting to bang a kid she watched grow up? That's gross, and just a step below Woody Allen marrying his stepdaughter. She was marry too, so not only is she wanting to date a younger man, she watch when he was kid, but she's also cheating on her husband. It is pure flesh, but she is nice about it. It is just natural, pragmatic and not that romantic-idealistic. She's still the Queen of all Milfs. Her personal life isn't the only thing she's opening. Some people might hate the fact, that the two main characters are two of the most shallow, childish characters. Mrs. Robinson can be especially hateful without any specific motivation, while Benjamin is bit spineless. I do love Dustin Hoffman in the role, but he was way too old for this part. He was playing a 20 year old, and he himself was 30 at the time. Also Anne Bancroft was only 35 during the time of filming. It also kinda funny that the actress Katharine Ross who played Anne Bancroft's daughter Elaine was only 8 years younger than her 35 and 27, miscasting. Katherine Ross looks lovely as Elaine, but she's barely one-dimensional and looks like a girl who would never go for a guy like Dustin Hoffman in a million years. She only went with him, because of her over controlling parents. Anyways, Benjamin soon fall in love with Elaine, and is in a dilemma. Should be continue to live with people telling what to do with his life like Mrs. Robinson or should he set his own future with a girl like Elaine? Find out, by watching it. The ending is up to question, if these two would work out. It leaves a deep interpretation of risky love. This is a classic film: tightly written, intelligent, funny, wonderfully acted, with a great climax with the church, so to speak. You will get seduce into watching the film by how brilliant it is.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of the most overvalued films of all times
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Turin_Horse
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The great and classical soundtrack by Simon & Garfunkel, a group of good actors and one of the most famous scenes in cinema history with Anne Bancroft and Dustin Hoffman as protagonists cannot make up a poor, even lame plot, an incoherent and silly story full of holes and a dull direction and editing. One wonders how such a film could make its way through time to still be considered a "classic" and seemingly appreciated by a high number of people; maybe, for people in the sixties this film meant something, or touched something inside them or whatever, but nowadays The Graduate should long have been put in the bag of dated unworthy-to-watch films. The final scenes with Benjamin trying to prevent the wedding of his sweetheart and taking her with him are just shameful!. There are some very good films from the sixties, try Midnight Cowboy for instance, but skip this over-overvalued film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Creative, compelling & classic
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    stephparsons
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    You've gotta love The Graduate.&nbsp; Even after 44 years, it's still relevant, highly watchable, funny, a titchy bit avant-garde, and boasts a top notch, flawless script.&nbsp; Dustin Hoffman as Ben does a bang up job playing the hapless graduate who desperately wants to escape his boring, careerist fate (as predetermined by&nbsp; his parents and society at large).&nbsp; He exudes 'sullen-youth-ness', boredom-with-life, naivet&eacute;, awkwardness and an (almost) 'aspergers' style of speech which are amusing and poignant.&nbsp; Despite all the drama that unfolds; the seduction followed by the 'coming-of-age' sex with an older woman, the falling in love with a fresh, vibrant young woman, The Graduate is, ultimately, a film about ennui; that dull, thudding, inexorable grind we face upon leaving school and being forced to 'decide what to do' for the rest of our sad, pathetic , predictable lives.&nbsp; Career paths being far more restrictive in the '60s,&nbsp; the sense of doom and pointlessness that Ben feels is exacerbated and he portrays it so very well.&nbsp;&nbsp; The friend of his parents who says, "I have one word for you Ben...plastics", sums up the soulless, futile, and arid future that Ben fears is his destiny. &nbsp;The Graduate experiments successfully with some creative cinematography including unusual camera angles, and interesting switches from one milieu to another e.g. Ben jumping into the swimming pool but ending up on the bed with Mrs Robinson.&nbsp;&nbsp; The swimming pool scene where Ben must walk under water in his birthday present - an old fashioned diving suit- is especially memorable and provides a convincing metaphor for the restrictiveness, loneliness and entrapment that he fears is to be his fate.&nbsp; There is nothing 'awkward' or dated about this classic film, it holds one's attention from start to finish.&nbsp; The ending steers clear of that typical 'happily ever after' Hollywood schmaltz&nbsp; and, in subtle tones presents us with 'ennui in a nutshell' as Ben and Elaine exchange smiles, then worried looks, and then expressions devoid of all emotion.&nbsp; There is nothing I would change about The Graduate, it's a classic and always will be.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Loved it!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    oliviadoerrer17
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Personally thought this particular film was great! I have heard many things about it's wonderful storyline and acting, I definitely had high expectations going into the film and it exceeded those. I always love a movie that is scandalous, and makes you wonder every second if someone is going to get caught. Dustin Hoffman really took on his role and made it believable to his shy nervous personality. He managed to make most scenes awkward which made it very funny. My personal favorite was the scene where Mrs Robinson tried to seduce him, you could tell by his facial expression and sweat he was extremely nervous and uncomfortable. The shots of Mrs Robinson's nude body then to Benjamin's face then back to her body and so on really was comical. The storyline did end up becoming interesting and complicated due to obvious reasons which overall added to the film. I liked the fact that Benjamin never gave up in what he wanted and fought to the end.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Hysterical
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    RoseXGold
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I loved this movie. It was the perfect blend of comedy, drama,love and action. The overall plot was very intriguing. I feel like everyone has been in the main characters shoes before( not knowing exactly what you want to do with your life). The theme was very relate-able. I feel as though everyone had a specific character that they could some how relate to. The music in this film was something that stood out to me. It was a bit more modern. I adored the fact that they not only made this movie a drama. But they also fit a lot of comedy into the film. I feel as though Dustin Hoffman played the role of a personality actor. I felt like I've seen the same persona played in other films he has starred in as well.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Graduate
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    stephypoo912
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I like this film. Even after seeing it three times! Seeing it every time, I have different feelings towards this film. Any way, i still end up liking it and loving the ending. It is a film that is predictable in some ways, but in others it definitely isn't. The whole movie, in itself is great. The editing is a great way to start the break-down. One of my favorite shots is the triple take in the beginning half of the movie. Another editing part that ALWAYS catches my eye is the pool shot then the hotel shot. The way it merges as one scene into the next is NOTHING like I have ever seen before. That definitely kept me enticed. The story line as well kept me watching it. The way it ended made me think, "Could there possibly be another way they could have found each other?" Hmm...
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A treatise on the nature of being a graduate
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    sunshinebeachcinema
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    In following up those cinematic classics that I'm somehow still catching up on, I recently saw The Graduate for the first time. I inevitably went into it with some idea of what was going to happen, but little more than an expectation for Dustin Hoffman to pursue a relationship with an older woman, to the sound of Simon & Garfunkel. Hoffman is Benjamin Braddock, the disaffected young university graduate who returns from his studies to a summer without direction. He is swiftly seduced by Mrs. Robinson, the wife of his father's business partner, and embarks on a lengthy affair, but his affection soon turns to her daughter, Elaine. Yet this is merely the bare bones of the plot: it's more complex than a simple romantic comedy, and the ending, notably, is ambiguous. It's impossible to complain about spoilers for a film that came out over forty years ago; it has seeped into popular culture, and been subjected to merciless parody. The iconic ending sequence is especially strange to watch for someone who grew up repeatedly watching Wayne's World 2 (1993), where it is replicated shot for shot. The critical eye has been on the film for so long, and it has passed through so many generations that its contemporary relevance can be questioned. Though a product of the late 1960s, the counterculture elements we associate with the period, such as free love, psychedelia, or hard rock. Benjamin's sexual experiences are not part of a revolution, and he remains trapped firmly within the rigid framework of upper middle class suburbia. While there's a certain fascination to looking back on a snapshot of the past, many of us no longer have the same relationship with our parents and the older generation. Do we look back at a history of steady liberalisation, but no massive social upheaval, and see further subversion as unnecessary? Do our parents, the children of the past, simply provide us with a system we no longer need to escape? Maybe modern youth have it worse than Benjamin; our coming of age is not so straightforward. We are no longer afforded the opportunity of clear rebellion, and are left to wallow in the established structure. What does hold true is the portrayal of a graduate with no clear future, returning to inhabit the fading skeleton of a life that's somehow no longer his own, and the dull resignation that there's little incentive to do anything about it. As a graduate myself (Though my current social circle suffers an absence of attractive lonely women) I can largely sympathise with Benjamin's predicament. After all, what does the immediate future hold? The prospects of the graduate are numerous and varied. Will it be more of the same on a postgraduate course? Are we heading for the city for a mysterious role as an analyst or consultant (when we're really just brewing tea for executives)? Perhaps it's just going to be a couple more months playing video games in pyjamas before we make a final decision. We still need something. A last hurrah before we're thrown to the world of work and responsibility for good. Could the modern rebellion be merely the fabled gap year abroad? At any rate, it seems coming of age requires something extreme, ditching the world and obligations, the way that Benjamin does at the end of The Graduate. The whole film is an exploration of these questions, symbolically relayed through the central relationships. The choices the characters make in their attachments are reflective of the choices that can be made in all facets of life. This is emphasised stylistically through a number of visually captivating shots and transitions that underline the sense of emptiness and alienation. Water (swimming pools, aquariums, and rain) appears frequently as a tool of separation. The soundtrack contains little youthful euphoria, but is melancholic, featuring repeated motifs that again, accentuate loneliness. These are played during moments that could otherwise be seen as positive steps in Benjamin's life, at the height of his relationship with Mrs. Robinson, and during his final elopement, elevating the drama above mere comedy. His obsession with Elaine is far from romantic destiny, and exists primarily as an escape from his relationship with her mother, and a chance to give his life some purpose outside an unhealthy liaison that makes him feel increasingly trapped. Compared with Mrs. Robinson, Elaine's character is chronically underdeveloped, though she responds positively to Benjamin's pseudo-philosophical ramblings. While she is disgusted to learn of Benjamin's affair with her mother, we learn little else of her thoughts on home, and where she fits in do the loveless dynamic in the Robinson household. We do not know if she as desperate to break free as Benjamin is. She ultimately follows him on impulse, having initially been happy to marry another at her parents' request. The separation from the character of Elaine forces us to experience the relationship purely from the perspective of Benjamin, who has put her on a pedestal and made her the object of his salvation. Despite the vein of sympathy I have as a fellow graduate, Benjamin is at times an insufferable and frustrating character to watch, and ultimately, Mrs. Robinson comes off as more sympathetic. She is the one who is truly lost and trapped. Benjamin still has his whole life ahead of him, once he finally decides what he's going to do with it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An Under-appreciated Classic!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    FilmMuscle
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I find it disappointing that the Graduate isn't one of those constantly-talked-about classics like The Godfather, Kramer vs. Kramer, Apocalypse Now, The Shawshank Redemption, etc. I had mixed expectations for the film since I heard, prior to viewing, some negative opinions and positive ones from individuals who'd recently watched it. Now, let's talk about why this film should be just as remembered of a classic as the others above. First of all and- in my opinion- most importantly, the film carries with it a highly intriguing and interesting story that keeps you entertained the entire way as the clever plot unravels. You're presented with this socially angsty twenty-year-old who's basically helpless, surrounded by intimidating people and frightening situations. He's a character that the audience can't help but love. For me, I could find myself relating to his personality quite a bit. I, too, attempt to stray away from great attention and prefer a much calmer and less crowded environment. The story, itself, keeps your attention because it's just strongly gripping insofar as this character finds himself in extremely awkward and threatening situations. Personally- like with the scene where Benjamin is awkwardly attempting to avoid suspicion while getting a hotel room- I recalled similar instances with myself where I was about to engage in something that could be regrettable and had to deal with suspicious or curious bystanders, family members, or whatnot. While we're still on it, the acting was unbelievably good, especially Dustin Hoffman's break-out performance as Benjamin. The way he portrayed a timid and awkward character surely blew away the moviegoers that night of its release. His timing and speech delivery, overall, creates an absolutely believable story about this fully realistic outcast. The way he would retreat under the pool whenever he felt vulnerable or faced his imposing parents definitely moved me because I could honestly understand him in any given predicament. At times, I feel like finding some peaceful and impenetrable spot to socially leave the world and obtain some time to breathe. The script of this picture is brilliant from the convincing dialogue to the intelligent build-up of relationships and their interconnections. For the moment, let's delve into the more technical side of The Graduate since its cinematography and editing is exceptional- excellent, might I say. The evolution of filmmaking over the decades from when Hollywood first stemmed truly and impressively proved itself in this movie. For example, there's a particular scene where Benjamin is "drifting" on the pool's air mattress, and he's interrupted by his irritating parents and the Robinsons themselves, and as they begin discussing his current uneventful life, the camera perfectly displays these incredibly condescending figures looking down at him with the sun shining so brightly that it seems to be blinding both the viewer and Benjamin as he's forced to look up at them. You sympathize with Benjamin because you feel their aggression and- again- condescending conversation about how he's not doing anything with his life, and I'm sure everyone's been in that sort of position, mentally or physically. Then, another shot shows Elaine as her confused face gets less and less blurry (indicating her progression towards fully understanding the mystery) until she finally realizes what's essentially transpiring between Benjamin and her own mother. In terms of editing, an instance showcases fast cutting to Mrs. Robinson's naked body as Benjamin attempts to ignore it but can't help his lust in a way. The film also smoothly and uniquely transitions to new settings without the audience even noticing at first as Benjamin exits the pool, walks to his room, and is suddenly found entering Mrs. Robinson's bed. Another strength of the camera-work is the noticeably lengthy shots where we witness entire conversations occurring in one single take or the scuba mask scene where a few minutes or so are filmed from a first-person perspective as Benjamin dives into his pool. In sum, the film seemed like a breath of fresh air that was affected by an unquestionably relatable protagonist that you felt for and his escape with the love of his life seemed utterly satisfying as well. Usually, happy endings done the way The Graduate did it come off as corny and clich&eacute;d, but your liking for the characters and their success overshadowed that aspect. So far, I've been loving all the films in class as this is yet another one I can't help but give high praise to.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not A Classic.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    AaronCapenBanner
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Mike Nichols directed this film about Ben Braddock, a confused young man trying to decide on his future in a society he can't understand, but instead becomes involved with the married mother of his reluctant girlfriend, and the various complications that ensue as a result. Dustin Hoffman leads a good cast, it has haunting songs by Simon & Garfunkel, is beloved by many of that generation, and even won Nichols an Academy Award for best director. So what's not to like? For a film that reacts negatively to the word "plastic", that's just how I feel about the characters and setting. Nothing about this film feels particularly real, certainly not the affair of Ben and Mrs. Robinson(Anne Bancroft) which not only isn't believable, it doesn't make sense, feels utterly manufactured and wrong. Katharine Ross as his girlfriend reacts to the news believably, but the ending will leave the viewer up in the air, since it, while dramatically staged, feels forced and unsatisfying. It just doesn't work for me.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    If anyone was born to play an awkward 21 year old...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    cleary-joshua
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    If anyone was born to play an awkward 21 year old deciding what to do with his life, it has to be 30 year old Dustin Hoffman, who steals this movie with his brilliant portrayal of Benjamin Braddock. It's a performance with humour and emotion all rolled into one. For example, Hoffman's performance when he first takes Mrs. Robinson home is hilarious, with his constant nervous stammering and occasional high-pitched squeaks. The final shot of Elaine and Benjamin has so much drama in both of their expressions, and you can tell how great the pair are as actors. They've just run away together, and she's already married. Are they completely happy? Not really, and both of their faces have a sort of "now what?" expression, leaving the audience thinking about whether it was the right decision. As for the story itself, it's comical without becoming too farcical, and has enough drama later on to keep the audience interested. It's also beautifully shot, with a lot of clever cutting and images, such as the fact that Benjamin is always being shot through other objects, like the hotel woodwork, or Mrs. Robinson's leg. The music too is great, and Simon and Garfunkel's songs, though some of them are used almost too much, manage to create just the right atmosphere for the film. The late Roger Ebert originally gave this film 4 stars, but thirty years later, dropped his score down to 3, something I'm not sure I've ever heard of a critic doing. He states in his later review that it's not a film that has stood the test of time, that modern audiences wouldn't find it as funny. I disagree with this, and managed to find humour in a lot of the film. However his main reason for doing so is the character of Benjamin, whom he calls an 'insufferable creep', and now I think about it, Ebert is kind of right. Perhaps the awkwardness does go a bit too far at points, and he is just a bit strange and horrible in taking Elaine to the strip club and stalking her for a long time. This detail aside, I still found it to be a hugely enjoyable film which left a lot to think about afterwards, as well as a lot of laughs, and it's worth watching if only for Hoffman's performance and delivery of that classic line: "Mrs. Robinson, you're trying to seduce me, aren't you."
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    It's Graduation Day! I think this movie is seducing me. You're trying to seduce me. Aren't you?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ironhorse_iv
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The movie has this great 1960's Hollywood New Wave feel to it. This is a coming of age movie that works for me. A lot of coming of age movies seem to try to make their character innocent, but they never actually are. They do a bunch of irresponsible stuff and at the end of the day a lot of people call them "innocent and lost", but it just feels like an excuse to sympathize for being an idiot. However I do sympathize for this character, Benjamin Braddock (Dustin Hoffman). It seemed like he was forced into a pool and not allowed to come back up. The theme of an innocent and confused youth who is exploited, misdirected, seduced and betrayed by a corrupt older generation was well understood by film audiences and captured the spirit of the times. One of the film's posters proclaimed the difficult coming-of-age for college graduate. Directed by Mike Nichols, the film is based on the 1963 novel The Graduate by Charles Webb. The movie opens to one of the best songs of the 1960's, Simon & Garfunkel - The Sound of Silence. This is one of the best songs I've ever listened to. I think the soundtrack pretty much made Simon & Garfunkel from nearly unknown folk singers, to legends of the music industry. You can also hear an earlier version of Mrs. Robinson in the movie. The song as it appears in the film is different from the familiar hit single version, as only the chorus of the song appears late in the film and with slightly different lyrics. It was only later on that Paul Simon and Art Garfunkel re-recorded the song by employing additional lyrics to form the hit single. It's kinda funny that the original song was call 'Mrs. Roosevelt'. It would really be funny to see Eleanor Roosevelt have an affair with a younger man. The Sound of Silence song work for the film as it really fit in with the plot regarding the lack of communication between the controlling parents and the young adults. Anyways, Benjamin Braddock has just arrive back home, after years in College. Dustin Hoffman played the part of the awkward post-graduate student perfectly. I can't see Mike Nichols first choice, Robert Redford in this role. Dustin is kind of awkward that works, he isn't to an abnormal extent creep, he more just describes the entire situation to the woman. Unsure of himself, by being uncomfortable and anxious, and force to hear others decide for him what he will do with his future. Benjamin Braddock soon find himself, seduce by an older woman, Mrs. Robinson (Anne Bancroft) and find himself tempt into an affair. Anne Bancroft is a cougar on the prowl, really to pounce on her prey. She was really pretty in the room. Even though her character is sympathetic, it doesn't change the fact that her character is a vindictive sexual predator. Just the line 'You've known me nearly all your life." Is just disturbing. Mrs. Robinson wanting to bang a kid she watched grow up? That's gross, and just a step below Woody Allen marrying his stepdaughter. She was marry too, so not only is she wanting to date a younger man, she watch when he was kid, but she's also cheating on her husband. It is pure flesh, but she is nice about it. It is just natural, pragmatic and not that romantic-idealistic. She's still the Queen of all Milfs. Her personal life isn't the only thing she's opening. Some people might hate the fact, that the two main characters are two of the most shallow, childish characters. Mrs. Robinson can be especially hateful without any specific motivation, while Benjamin is bit spineless. I do love Dustin Hoffman in the role, but he was way too old for this part. He was playing a 20 year old, and he himself was 30 at the time. Also Anne Bancroft was only 35 during the time of filming. It also kinda funny that the actress Katharine Ross who played Anne Bancroft's daughter Elaine was only 8 years younger than her 35 and 27, miscasting. Katherine Ross looks lovely as Elaine, but she's barely one-dimensional and looks like a girl who would never go for a guy like Dustin Hoffman in a million years. She only went with him, because of her over controlling parents. Anyways, Benjamin soon fall in love with Elaine, and is in a dilemma. Should be continue to live with people telling what to do with his life like Mrs. Robinson or should he set his own future with a girl like Elaine? Find out, by watching it. The ending is up to question, if these two would work out. It leaves a deep interpretation of risky love. This is a classic film: tightly written, intelligent, funny, wonderfully acted, with a great climax with the church, so to speak. You will get seduce into watching the film by how brilliant it is.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of the most overvalued films of all times
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Turin_Horse
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The great and classical soundtrack by Simon & Garfunkel, a group of good actors and one of the most famous scenes in cinema history with Anne Bancroft and Dustin Hoffman as protagonists cannot make up a poor, even lame plot, an incoherent and silly story full of holes and a dull direction and editing. One wonders how such a film could make its way through time to still be considered a "classic" and seemingly appreciated by a high number of people; maybe, for people in the sixties this film meant something, or touched something inside them or whatever, but nowadays The Graduate should long have been put in the bag of dated unworthy-to-watch films. The final scenes with Benjamin trying to prevent the wedding of his sweetheart and taking her with him are just shameful!. There are some very good films from the sixties, try Midnight Cowboy for instance, but skip this over-overvalued film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Creative, compelling & classic
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    stephparsons
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    You've gotta love The Graduate.&nbsp; Even after 44 years, it's still relevant, highly watchable, funny, a titchy bit avant-garde, and boasts a top notch, flawless script.&nbsp; Dustin Hoffman as Ben does a bang up job playing the hapless graduate who desperately wants to escape his boring, careerist fate (as predetermined by&nbsp; his parents and society at large).&nbsp; He exudes 'sullen-youth-ness', boredom-with-life, naivet&eacute;, awkwardness and an (almost) 'aspergers' style of speech which are amusing and poignant.&nbsp; Despite all the drama that unfolds; the seduction followed by the 'coming-of-age' sex with an older woman, the falling in love with a fresh, vibrant young woman, The Graduate is, ultimately, a film about ennui; that dull, thudding, inexorable grind we face upon leaving school and being forced to 'decide what to do' for the rest of our sad, pathetic , predictable lives.&nbsp; Career paths being far more restrictive in the '60s,&nbsp; the sense of doom and pointlessness that Ben feels is exacerbated and he portrays it so very well.&nbsp;&nbsp; The friend of his parents who says, "I have one word for you Ben...plastics", sums up the soulless, futile, and arid future that Ben fears is his destiny. &nbsp;The Graduate experiments successfully with some creative cinematography including unusual camera angles, and interesting switches from one milieu to another e.g. Ben jumping into the swimming pool but ending up on the bed with Mrs Robinson.&nbsp;&nbsp; The swimming pool scene where Ben must walk under water in his birthday present - an old fashioned diving suit- is especially memorable and provides a convincing metaphor for the restrictiveness, loneliness and entrapment that he fears is to be his fate.&nbsp; There is nothing 'awkward' or dated about this classic film, it holds one's attention from start to finish.&nbsp; The ending steers clear of that typical 'happily ever after' Hollywood schmaltz&nbsp; and, in subtle tones presents us with 'ennui in a nutshell' as Ben and Elaine exchange smiles, then worried looks, and then expressions devoid of all emotion.&nbsp; There is nothing I would change about The Graduate, it's a classic and always will be.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Loved it!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    oliviadoerrer17
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Personally thought this particular film was great! I have heard many things about it's wonderful storyline and acting, I definitely had high expectations going into the film and it exceeded those. I always love a movie that is scandalous, and makes you wonder every second if someone is going to get caught. Dustin Hoffman really took on his role and made it believable to his shy nervous personality. He managed to make most scenes awkward which made it very funny. My personal favorite was the scene where Mrs Robinson tried to seduce him, you could tell by his facial expression and sweat he was extremely nervous and uncomfortable. The shots of Mrs Robinson's nude body then to Benjamin's face then back to her body and so on really was comical. The storyline did end up becoming interesting and complicated due to obvious reasons which overall added to the film. I liked the fact that Benjamin never gave up in what he wanted and fought to the end.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Hysterical
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    RoseXGold
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I loved this movie. It was the perfect blend of comedy, drama,love and action. The overall plot was very intriguing. I feel like everyone has been in the main characters shoes before( not knowing exactly what you want to do with your life). The theme was very relate-able. I feel as though everyone had a specific character that they could some how relate to. The music in this film was something that stood out to me. It was a bit more modern. I adored the fact that they not only made this movie a drama. But they also fit a lot of comedy into the film. I feel as though Dustin Hoffman played the role of a personality actor. I felt like I've seen the same persona played in other films he has starred in as well.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Graduate
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    stephypoo912
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I like this film. Even after seeing it three times! Seeing it every time, I have different feelings towards this film. Any way, i still end up liking it and loving the ending. It is a film that is predictable in some ways, but in others it definitely isn't. The whole movie, in itself is great. The editing is a great way to start the break-down. One of my favorite shots is the triple take in the beginning half of the movie. Another editing part that ALWAYS catches my eye is the pool shot then the hotel shot. The way it merges as one scene into the next is NOTHING like I have ever seen before. That definitely kept me enticed. The story line as well kept me watching it. The way it ended made me think, "Could there possibly be another way they could have found each other?" Hmm...
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A treatise on the nature of being a graduate
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    sunshinebeachcinema
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    In following up those cinematic classics that I'm somehow still catching up on, I recently saw The Graduate for the first time. I inevitably went into it with some idea of what was going to happen, but little more than an expectation for Dustin Hoffman to pursue a relationship with an older woman, to the sound of Simon & Garfunkel. Hoffman is Benjamin Braddock, the disaffected young university graduate who returns from his studies to a summer without direction. He is swiftly seduced by Mrs. Robinson, the wife of his father's business partner, and embarks on a lengthy affair, but his affection soon turns to her daughter, Elaine. Yet this is merely the bare bones of the plot: it's more complex than a simple romantic comedy, and the ending, notably, is ambiguous. It's impossible to complain about spoilers for a film that came out over forty years ago; it has seeped into popular culture, and been subjected to merciless parody. The iconic ending sequence is especially strange to watch for someone who grew up repeatedly watching Wayne's World 2 (1993), where it is replicated shot for shot. The critical eye has been on the film for so long, and it has passed through so many generations that its contemporary relevance can be questioned. Though a product of the late 1960s, the counterculture elements we associate with the period, such as free love, psychedelia, or hard rock. Benjamin's sexual experiences are not part of a revolution, and he remains trapped firmly within the rigid framework of upper middle class suburbia. While there's a certain fascination to looking back on a snapshot of the past, many of us no longer have the same relationship with our parents and the older generation. Do we look back at a history of steady liberalisation, but no massive social upheaval, and see further subversion as unnecessary? Do our parents, the children of the past, simply provide us with a system we no longer need to escape? Maybe modern youth have it worse than Benjamin; our coming of age is not so straightforward. We are no longer afforded the opportunity of clear rebellion, and are left to wallow in the established structure. What does hold true is the portrayal of a graduate with no clear future, returning to inhabit the fading skeleton of a life that's somehow no longer his own, and the dull resignation that there's little incentive to do anything about it. As a graduate myself (Though my current social circle suffers an absence of attractive lonely women) I can largely sympathise with Benjamin's predicament. After all, what does the immediate future hold? The prospects of the graduate are numerous and varied. Will it be more of the same on a postgraduate course? Are we heading for the city for a mysterious role as an analyst or consultant (when we're really just brewing tea for executives)? Perhaps it's just going to be a couple more months playing video games in pyjamas before we make a final decision. We still need something. A last hurrah before we're thrown to the world of work and responsibility for good. Could the modern rebellion be merely the fabled gap year abroad? At any rate, it seems coming of age requires something extreme, ditching the world and obligations, the way that Benjamin does at the end of The Graduate. The whole film is an exploration of these questions, symbolically relayed through the central relationships. The choices the characters make in their attachments are reflective of the choices that can be made in all facets of life. This is emphasised stylistically through a number of visually captivating shots and transitions that underline the sense of emptiness and alienation. Water (swimming pools, aquariums, and rain) appears frequently as a tool of separation. The soundtrack contains little youthful euphoria, but is melancholic, featuring repeated motifs that again, accentuate loneliness. These are played during moments that could otherwise be seen as positive steps in Benjamin's life, at the height of his relationship with Mrs. Robinson, and during his final elopement, elevating the drama above mere comedy. His obsession with Elaine is far from romantic destiny, and exists primarily as an escape from his relationship with her mother, and a chance to give his life some purpose outside an unhealthy liaison that makes him feel increasingly trapped. Compared with Mrs. Robinson, Elaine's character is chronically underdeveloped, though she responds positively to Benjamin's pseudo-philosophical ramblings. While she is disgusted to learn of Benjamin's affair with her mother, we learn little else of her thoughts on home, and where she fits in do the loveless dynamic in the Robinson household. We do not know if she as desperate to break free as Benjamin is. She ultimately follows him on impulse, having initially been happy to marry another at her parents' request. The separation from the character of Elaine forces us to experience the relationship purely from the perspective of Benjamin, who has put her on a pedestal and made her the object of his salvation. Despite the vein of sympathy I have as a fellow graduate, Benjamin is at times an insufferable and frustrating character to watch, and ultimately, Mrs. Robinson comes off as more sympathetic. She is the one who is truly lost and trapped. Benjamin still has his whole life ahead of him, once he finally decides what he's going to do with it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An Under-appreciated Classic!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    FilmMuscle
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I find it disappointing that the Graduate isn't one of those constantly-talked-about classics like The Godfather, Kramer vs. Kramer, Apocalypse Now, The Shawshank Redemption, etc. I had mixed expectations for the film since I heard, prior to viewing, some negative opinions and positive ones from individuals who'd recently watched it. Now, let's talk about why this film should be just as remembered of a classic as the others above. First of all and- in my opinion- most importantly, the film carries with it a highly intriguing and interesting story that keeps you entertained the entire way as the clever plot unravels. You're presented with this socially angsty twenty-year-old who's basically helpless, surrounded by intimidating people and frightening situations. He's a character that the audience can't help but love. For me, I could find myself relating to his personality quite a bit. I, too, attempt to stray away from great attention and prefer a much calmer and less crowded environment. The story, itself, keeps your attention because it's just strongly gripping insofar as this character finds himself in extremely awkward and threatening situations. Personally- like with the scene where Benjamin is awkwardly attempting to avoid suspicion while getting a hotel room- I recalled similar instances with myself where I was about to engage in something that could be regrettable and had to deal with suspicious or curious bystanders, family members, or whatnot. While we're still on it, the acting was unbelievably good, especially Dustin Hoffman's break-out performance as Benjamin. The way he portrayed a timid and awkward character surely blew away the moviegoers that night of its release. His timing and speech delivery, overall, creates an absolutely believable story about this fully realistic outcast. The way he would retreat under the pool whenever he felt vulnerable or faced his imposing parents definitely moved me because I could honestly understand him in any given predicament. At times, I feel like finding some peaceful and impenetrable spot to socially leave the world and obtain some time to breathe. The script of this picture is brilliant from the convincing dialogue to the intelligent build-up of relationships and their interconnections. For the moment, let's delve into the more technical side of The Graduate since its cinematography and editing is exceptional- excellent, might I say. The evolution of filmmaking over the decades from when Hollywood first stemmed truly and impressively proved itself in this movie. For example, there's a particular scene where Benjamin is "drifting" on the pool's air mattress, and he's interrupted by his irritating parents and the Robinsons themselves, and as they begin discussing his current uneventful life, the camera perfectly displays these incredibly condescending figures looking down at him with the sun shining so brightly that it seems to be blinding both the viewer and Benjamin as he's forced to look up at them. You sympathize with Benjamin because you feel their aggression and- again- condescending conversation about how he's not doing anything with his life, and I'm sure everyone's been in that sort of position, mentally or physically. Then, another shot shows Elaine as her confused face gets less and less blurry (indicating her progression towards fully understanding the mystery) until she finally realizes what's essentially transpiring between Benjamin and her own mother. In terms of editing, an instance showcases fast cutting to Mrs. Robinson's naked body as Benjamin attempts to ignore it but can't help his lust in a way. The film also smoothly and uniquely transitions to new settings without the audience even noticing at first as Benjamin exits the pool, walks to his room, and is suddenly found entering Mrs. Robinson's bed. Another strength of the camera-work is the noticeably lengthy shots where we witness entire conversations occurring in one single take or the scuba mask scene where a few minutes or so are filmed from a first-person perspective as Benjamin dives into his pool. In sum, the film seemed like a breath of fresh air that was affected by an unquestionably relatable protagonist that you felt for and his escape with the love of his life seemed utterly satisfying as well. Usually, happy endings done the way The Graduate did it come off as corny and clich&eacute;d, but your liking for the characters and their success overshadowed that aspect. So far, I've been loving all the films in class as this is yet another one I can't help but give high praise to.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not A Classic.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    AaronCapenBanner
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Mike Nichols directed this film about Ben Braddock, a confused young man trying to decide on his future in a society he can't understand, but instead becomes involved with the married mother of his reluctant girlfriend, and the various complications that ensue as a result. Dustin Hoffman leads a good cast, it has haunting songs by Simon & Garfunkel, is beloved by many of that generation, and even won Nichols an Academy Award for best director. So what's not to like? For a film that reacts negatively to the word "plastic", that's just how I feel about the characters and setting. Nothing about this film feels particularly real, certainly not the affair of Ben and Mrs. Robinson(Anne Bancroft) which not only isn't believable, it doesn't make sense, feels utterly manufactured and wrong. Katharine Ross as his girlfriend reacts to the news believably, but the ending will leave the viewer up in the air, since it, while dramatically staged, feels forced and unsatisfying. It just doesn't work for me.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    If anyone was born to play an awkward 21 year old...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    cleary-joshua
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    If anyone was born to play an awkward 21 year old deciding what to do with his life, it has to be 30 year old Dustin Hoffman, who steals this movie with his brilliant portrayal of Benjamin Braddock. It's a performance with humour and emotion all rolled into one. For example, Hoffman's performance when he first takes Mrs. Robinson home is hilarious, with his constant nervous stammering and occasional high-pitched squeaks. The final shot of Elaine and Benjamin has so much drama in both of their expressions, and you can tell how great the pair are as actors. They've just run away together, and she's already married. Are they completely happy? Not really, and both of their faces have a sort of "now what?" expression, leaving the audience thinking about whether it was the right decision. As for the story itself, it's comical without becoming too farcical, and has enough drama later on to keep the audience interested. It's also beautifully shot, with a lot of clever cutting and images, such as the fact that Benjamin is always being shot through other objects, like the hotel woodwork, or Mrs. Robinson's leg. The music too is great, and Simon and Garfunkel's songs, though some of them are used almost too much, manage to create just the right atmosphere for the film. The late Roger Ebert originally gave this film 4 stars, but thirty years later, dropped his score down to 3, something I'm not sure I've ever heard of a critic doing. He states in his later review that it's not a film that has stood the test of time, that modern audiences wouldn't find it as funny. I disagree with this, and managed to find humour in a lot of the film. However his main reason for doing so is the character of Benjamin, whom he calls an 'insufferable creep', and now I think about it, Ebert is kind of right. Perhaps the awkwardness does go a bit too far at points, and he is just a bit strange and horrible in taking Elaine to the strip club and stalking her for a long time. This detail aside, I still found it to be a hugely enjoyable film which left a lot to think about afterwards, as well as a lot of laughs, and it's worth watching if only for Hoffman's performance and delivery of that classic line: "Mrs. Robinson, you're trying to seduce me, aren't you."
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    It's Graduation Day! I think this movie is seducing me. You're trying to seduce me. Aren't you?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ironhorse_iv
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The movie has this great 1960's Hollywood New Wave feel to it. This is a coming of age movie that works for me. A lot of coming of age movies seem to try to make their character innocent, but they never actually are. They do a bunch of irresponsible stuff and at the end of the day a lot of people call them "innocent and lost", but it just feels like an excuse to sympathize for being an idiot. However I do sympathize for this character, Benjamin Braddock (Dustin Hoffman). It seemed like he was forced into a pool and not allowed to come back up. The theme of an innocent and confused youth who is exploited, misdirected, seduced and betrayed by a corrupt older generation was well understood by film audiences and captured the spirit of the times. One of the film's posters proclaimed the difficult coming-of-age for college graduate. Directed by Mike Nichols, the film is based on the 1963 novel The Graduate by Charles Webb. The movie opens to one of the best songs of the 1960's, Simon & Garfunkel - The Sound of Silence. This is one of the best songs I've ever listened to. I think the soundtrack pretty much made Simon & Garfunkel from nearly unknown folk singers, to legends of the music industry. You can also hear an earlier version of Mrs. Robinson in the movie. The song as it appears in the film is different from the familiar hit single version, as only the chorus of the song appears late in the film and with slightly different lyrics. It was only later on that Paul Simon and Art Garfunkel re-recorded the song by employing additional lyrics to form the hit single. It's kinda funny that the original song was call 'Mrs. Roosevelt'. It would really be funny to see Eleanor Roosevelt have an affair with a younger man. The Sound of Silence song work for the film as it really fit in with the plot regarding the lack of communication between the controlling parents and the young adults. Anyways, Benjamin Braddock has just arrive back home, after years in College. Dustin Hoffman played the part of the awkward post-graduate student perfectly. I can't see Mike Nichols first choice, Robert Redford in this role. Dustin is kind of awkward that works, he isn't to an abnormal extent creep, he more just describes the entire situation to the woman. Unsure of himself, by being uncomfortable and anxious, and force to hear others decide for him what he will do with his future. Benjamin Braddock soon find himself, seduce by an older woman, Mrs. Robinson (Anne Bancroft) and find himself tempt into an affair. Anne Bancroft is a cougar on the prowl, really to pounce on her prey. She was really pretty in the room. Even though her character is sympathetic, it doesn't change the fact that her character is a vindictive sexual predator. Just the line 'You've known me nearly all your life." Is just disturbing. Mrs. Robinson wanting to bang a kid she watched grow up? That's gross, and just a step below Woody Allen marrying his stepdaughter. She was marry too, so not only is she wanting to date a younger man, she watch when he was kid, but she's also cheating on her husband. It is pure flesh, but she is nice about it. It is just natural, pragmatic and not that romantic-idealistic. She's still the Queen of all Milfs. Her personal life isn't the only thing she's opening. Some people might hate the fact, that the two main characters are two of the most shallow, childish characters. Mrs. Robinson can be especially hateful without any specific motivation, while Benjamin is bit spineless. I do love Dustin Hoffman in the role, but he was way too old for this part. He was playing a 20 year old, and he himself was 30 at the time. Also Anne Bancroft was only 35 during the time of filming. It also kinda funny that the actress Katharine Ross who played Anne Bancroft's daughter Elaine was only 8 years younger than her 35 and 27, miscasting. Katherine Ross looks lovely as Elaine, but she's barely one-dimensional and looks like a girl who would never go for a guy like Dustin Hoffman in a million years. She only went with him, because of her over controlling parents. Anyways, Benjamin soon fall in love with Elaine, and is in a dilemma. Should be continue to live with people telling what to do with his life like Mrs. Robinson or should he set his own future with a girl like Elaine? Find out, by watching it. The ending is up to question, if these two would work out. It leaves a deep interpretation of risky love. This is a classic film: tightly written, intelligent, funny, wonderfully acted, with a great climax with the church, so to speak. You will get seduce into watching the film by how brilliant it is.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of the most overvalued films of all times
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Turin_Horse
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The great and classical soundtrack by Simon & Garfunkel, a group of good actors and one of the most famous scenes in cinema history with Anne Bancroft and Dustin Hoffman as protagonists cannot make up a poor, even lame plot, an incoherent and silly story full of holes and a dull direction and editing. One wonders how such a film could make its way through time to still be considered a "classic" and seemingly appreciated by a high number of people; maybe, for people in the sixties this film meant something, or touched something inside them or whatever, but nowadays The Graduate should long have been put in the bag of dated unworthy-to-watch films. The final scenes with Benjamin trying to prevent the wedding of his sweetheart and taking her with him are just shameful!. There are some very good films from the sixties, try Midnight Cowboy for instance, but skip this over-overvalued film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Creative, compelling & classic
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    stephparsons
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    You've gotta love The Graduate.&nbsp; Even after 44 years, it's still relevant, highly watchable, funny, a titchy bit avant-garde, and boasts a top notch, flawless script.&nbsp; Dustin Hoffman as Ben does a bang up job playing the hapless graduate who desperately wants to escape his boring, careerist fate (as predetermined by&nbsp; his parents and society at large).&nbsp; He exudes 'sullen-youth-ness', boredom-with-life, naivet&eacute;, awkwardness and an (almost) 'aspergers' style of speech which are amusing and poignant.&nbsp; Despite all the drama that unfolds; the seduction followed by the 'coming-of-age' sex with an older woman, the falling in love with a fresh, vibrant young woman, The Graduate is, ultimately, a film about ennui; that dull, thudding, inexorable grind we face upon leaving school and being forced to 'decide what to do' for the rest of our sad, pathetic , predictable lives.&nbsp; Career paths being far more restrictive in the '60s,&nbsp; the sense of doom and pointlessness that Ben feels is exacerbated and he portrays it so very well.&nbsp;&nbsp; The friend of his parents who says, "I have one word for you Ben...plastics", sums up the soulless, futile, and arid future that Ben fears is his destiny. &nbsp;The Graduate experiments successfully with some creative cinematography including unusual camera angles, and interesting switches from one milieu to another e.g. Ben jumping into the swimming pool but ending up on the bed with Mrs Robinson.&nbsp;&nbsp; The swimming pool scene where Ben must walk under water in his birthday present - an old fashioned diving suit- is especially memorable and provides a convincing metaphor for the restrictiveness, loneliness and entrapment that he fears is to be his fate.&nbsp; There is nothing 'awkward' or dated about this classic film, it holds one's attention from start to finish.&nbsp; The ending steers clear of that typical 'happily ever after' Hollywood schmaltz&nbsp; and, in subtle tones presents us with 'ennui in a nutshell' as Ben and Elaine exchange smiles, then worried looks, and then expressions devoid of all emotion.&nbsp; There is nothing I would change about The Graduate, it's a classic and always will be.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Loved it!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    oliviadoerrer17
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Personally thought this particular film was great! I have heard many things about it's wonderful storyline and acting, I definitely had high expectations going into the film and it exceeded those. I always love a movie that is scandalous, and makes you wonder every second if someone is going to get caught. Dustin Hoffman really took on his role and made it believable to his shy nervous personality. He managed to make most scenes awkward which made it very funny. My personal favorite was the scene where Mrs Robinson tried to seduce him, you could tell by his facial expression and sweat he was extremely nervous and uncomfortable. The shots of Mrs Robinson's nude body then to Benjamin's face then back to her body and so on really was comical. The storyline did end up becoming interesting and complicated due to obvious reasons which overall added to the film. I liked the fact that Benjamin never gave up in what he wanted and fought to the end.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Hysterical
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    RoseXGold
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I loved this movie. It was the perfect blend of comedy, drama,love and action. The overall plot was very intriguing. I feel like everyone has been in the main characters shoes before( not knowing exactly what you want to do with your life). The theme was very relate-able. I feel as though everyone had a specific character that they could some how relate to. The music in this film was something that stood out to me. It was a bit more modern. I adored the fact that they not only made this movie a drama. But they also fit a lot of comedy into the film. I feel as though Dustin Hoffman played the role of a personality actor. I felt like I've seen the same persona played in other films he has starred in as well.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Graduate
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    stephypoo912
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I like this film. Even after seeing it three times! Seeing it every time, I have different feelings towards this film. Any way, i still end up liking it and loving the ending. It is a film that is predictable in some ways, but in others it definitely isn't. The whole movie, in itself is great. The editing is a great way to start the break-down. One of my favorite shots is the triple take in the beginning half of the movie. Another editing part that ALWAYS catches my eye is the pool shot then the hotel shot. The way it merges as one scene into the next is NOTHING like I have ever seen before. That definitely kept me enticed. The story line as well kept me watching it. The way it ended made me think, "Could there possibly be another way they could have found each other?" Hmm...
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A treatise on the nature of being a graduate
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    sunshinebeachcinema
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    In following up those cinematic classics that I'm somehow still catching up on, I recently saw The Graduate for the first time. I inevitably went into it with some idea of what was going to happen, but little more than an expectation for Dustin Hoffman to pursue a relationship with an older woman, to the sound of Simon & Garfunkel. Hoffman is Benjamin Braddock, the disaffected young university graduate who returns from his studies to a summer without direction. He is swiftly seduced by Mrs. Robinson, the wife of his father's business partner, and embarks on a lengthy affair, but his affection soon turns to her daughter, Elaine. Yet this is merely the bare bones of the plot: it's more complex than a simple romantic comedy, and the ending, notably, is ambiguous. It's impossible to complain about spoilers for a film that came out over forty years ago; it has seeped into popular culture, and been subjected to merciless parody. The iconic ending sequence is especially strange to watch for someone who grew up repeatedly watching Wayne's World 2 (1993), where it is replicated shot for shot. The critical eye has been on the film for so long, and it has passed through so many generations that its contemporary relevance can be questioned. Though a product of the late 1960s, the counterculture elements we associate with the period, such as free love, psychedelia, or hard rock. Benjamin's sexual experiences are not part of a revolution, and he remains trapped firmly within the rigid framework of upper middle class suburbia. While there's a certain fascination to looking back on a snapshot of the past, many of us no longer have the same relationship with our parents and the older generation. Do we look back at a history of steady liberalisation, but no massive social upheaval, and see further subversion as unnecessary? Do our parents, the children of the past, simply provide us with a system we no longer need to escape? Maybe modern youth have it worse than Benjamin; our coming of age is not so straightforward. We are no longer afforded the opportunity of clear rebellion, and are left to wallow in the established structure. What does hold true is the portrayal of a graduate with no clear future, returning to inhabit the fading skeleton of a life that's somehow no longer his own, and the dull resignation that there's little incentive to do anything about it. As a graduate myself (Though my current social circle suffers an absence of attractive lonely women) I can largely sympathise with Benjamin's predicament. After all, what does the immediate future hold? The prospects of the graduate are numerous and varied. Will it be more of the same on a postgraduate course? Are we heading for the city for a mysterious role as an analyst or consultant (when we're really just brewing tea for executives)? Perhaps it's just going to be a couple more months playing video games in pyjamas before we make a final decision. We still need something. A last hurrah before we're thrown to the world of work and responsibility for good. Could the modern rebellion be merely the fabled gap year abroad? At any rate, it seems coming of age requires something extreme, ditching the world and obligations, the way that Benjamin does at the end of The Graduate. The whole film is an exploration of these questions, symbolically relayed through the central relationships. The choices the characters make in their attachments are reflective of the choices that can be made in all facets of life. This is emphasised stylistically through a number of visually captivating shots and transitions that underline the sense of emptiness and alienation. Water (swimming pools, aquariums, and rain) appears frequently as a tool of separation. The soundtrack contains little youthful euphoria, but is melancholic, featuring repeated motifs that again, accentuate loneliness. These are played during moments that could otherwise be seen as positive steps in Benjamin's life, at the height of his relationship with Mrs. Robinson, and during his final elopement, elevating the drama above mere comedy. His obsession with Elaine is far from romantic destiny, and exists primarily as an escape from his relationship with her mother, and a chance to give his life some purpose outside an unhealthy liaison that makes him feel increasingly trapped. Compared with Mrs. Robinson, Elaine's character is chronically underdeveloped, though she responds positively to Benjamin's pseudo-philosophical ramblings. While she is disgusted to learn of Benjamin's affair with her mother, we learn little else of her thoughts on home, and where she fits in do the loveless dynamic in the Robinson household. We do not know if she as desperate to break free as Benjamin is. She ultimately follows him on impulse, having initially been happy to marry another at her parents' request. The separation from the character of Elaine forces us to experience the relationship purely from the perspective of Benjamin, who has put her on a pedestal and made her the object of his salvation. Despite the vein of sympathy I have as a fellow graduate, Benjamin is at times an insufferable and frustrating character to watch, and ultimately, Mrs. Robinson comes off as more sympathetic. She is the one who is truly lost and trapped. Benjamin still has his whole life ahead of him, once he finally decides what he's going to do with it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An Under-appreciated Classic!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    FilmMuscle
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I find it disappointing that the Graduate isn't one of those constantly-talked-about classics like The Godfather, Kramer vs. Kramer, Apocalypse Now, The Shawshank Redemption, etc. I had mixed expectations for the film since I heard, prior to viewing, some negative opinions and positive ones from individuals who'd recently watched it. Now, let's talk about why this film should be just as remembered of a classic as the others above. First of all and- in my opinion- most importantly, the film carries with it a highly intriguing and interesting story that keeps you entertained the entire way as the clever plot unravels. You're presented with this socially angsty twenty-year-old who's basically helpless, surrounded by intimidating people and frightening situations. He's a character that the audience can't help but love. For me, I could find myself relating to his personality quite a bit. I, too, attempt to stray away from great attention and prefer a much calmer and less crowded environment. The story, itself, keeps your attention because it's just strongly gripping insofar as this character finds himself in extremely awkward and threatening situations. Personally- like with the scene where Benjamin is awkwardly attempting to avoid suspicion while getting a hotel room- I recalled similar instances with myself where I was about to engage in something that could be regrettable and had to deal with suspicious or curious bystanders, family members, or whatnot. While we're still on it, the acting was unbelievably good, especially Dustin Hoffman's break-out performance as Benjamin. The way he portrayed a timid and awkward character surely blew away the moviegoers that night of its release. His timing and speech delivery, overall, creates an absolutely believable story about this fully realistic outcast. The way he would retreat under the pool whenever he felt vulnerable or faced his imposing parents definitely moved me because I could honestly understand him in any given predicament. At times, I feel like finding some peaceful and impenetrable spot to socially leave the world and obtain some time to breathe. The script of this picture is brilliant from the convincing dialogue to the intelligent build-up of relationships and their interconnections. For the moment, let's delve into the more technical side of The Graduate since its cinematography and editing is exceptional- excellent, might I say. The evolution of filmmaking over the decades from when Hollywood first stemmed truly and impressively proved itself in this movie. For example, there's a particular scene where Benjamin is "drifting" on the pool's air mattress, and he's interrupted by his irritating parents and the Robinsons themselves, and as they begin discussing his current uneventful life, the camera perfectly displays these incredibly condescending figures looking down at him with the sun shining so brightly that it seems to be blinding both the viewer and Benjamin as he's forced to look up at them. You sympathize with Benjamin because you feel their aggression and- again- condescending conversation about how he's not doing anything with his life, and I'm sure everyone's been in that sort of position, mentally or physically. Then, another shot shows Elaine as her confused face gets less and less blurry (indicating her progression towards fully understanding the mystery) until she finally realizes what's essentially transpiring between Benjamin and her own mother. In terms of editing, an instance showcases fast cutting to Mrs. Robinson's naked body as Benjamin attempts to ignore it but can't help his lust in a way. The film also smoothly and uniquely transitions to new settings without the audience even noticing at first as Benjamin exits the pool, walks to his room, and is suddenly found entering Mrs. Robinson's bed. Another strength of the camera-work is the noticeably lengthy shots where we witness entire conversations occurring in one single take or the scuba mask scene where a few minutes or so are filmed from a first-person perspective as Benjamin dives into his pool. In sum, the film seemed like a breath of fresh air that was affected by an unquestionably relatable protagonist that you felt for and his escape with the love of his life seemed utterly satisfying as well. Usually, happy endings done the way The Graduate did it come off as corny and clich&eacute;d, but your liking for the characters and their success overshadowed that aspect. So far, I've been loving all the films in class as this is yet another one I can't help but give high praise to.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not A Classic.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    AaronCapenBanner
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Mike Nichols directed this film about Ben Braddock, a confused young man trying to decide on his future in a society he can't understand, but instead becomes involved with the married mother of his reluctant girlfriend, and the various complications that ensue as a result. Dustin Hoffman leads a good cast, it has haunting songs by Simon & Garfunkel, is beloved by many of that generation, and even won Nichols an Academy Award for best director. So what's not to like? For a film that reacts negatively to the word "plastic", that's just how I feel about the characters and setting. Nothing about this film feels particularly real, certainly not the affair of Ben and Mrs. Robinson(Anne Bancroft) which not only isn't believable, it doesn't make sense, feels utterly manufactured and wrong. Katharine Ross as his girlfriend reacts to the news believably, but the ending will leave the viewer up in the air, since it, while dramatically staged, feels forced and unsatisfying. It just doesn't work for me.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    If anyone was born to play an awkward 21 year old...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    cleary-joshua
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    If anyone was born to play an awkward 21 year old deciding what to do with his life, it has to be 30 year old Dustin Hoffman, who steals this movie with his brilliant portrayal of Benjamin Braddock. It's a performance with humour and emotion all rolled into one. For example, Hoffman's performance when he first takes Mrs. Robinson home is hilarious, with his constant nervous stammering and occasional high-pitched squeaks. The final shot of Elaine and Benjamin has so much drama in both of their expressions, and you can tell how great the pair are as actors. They've just run away together, and she's already married. Are they completely happy? Not really, and both of their faces have a sort of "now what?" expression, leaving the audience thinking about whether it was the right decision. As for the story itself, it's comical without becoming too farcical, and has enough drama later on to keep the audience interested. It's also beautifully shot, with a lot of clever cutting and images, such as the fact that Benjamin is always being shot through other objects, like the hotel woodwork, or Mrs. Robinson's leg. The music too is great, and Simon and Garfunkel's songs, though some of them are used almost too much, manage to create just the right atmosphere for the film. The late Roger Ebert originally gave this film 4 stars, but thirty years later, dropped his score down to 3, something I'm not sure I've ever heard of a critic doing. He states in his later review that it's not a film that has stood the test of time, that modern audiences wouldn't find it as funny. I disagree with this, and managed to find humour in a lot of the film. However his main reason for doing so is the character of Benjamin, whom he calls an 'insufferable creep', and now I think about it, Ebert is kind of right. Perhaps the awkwardness does go a bit too far at points, and he is just a bit strange and horrible in taking Elaine to the strip club and stalking her for a long time. This detail aside, I still found it to be a hugely enjoyable film which left a lot to think about afterwards, as well as a lot of laughs, and it's worth watching if only for Hoffman's performance and delivery of that classic line: "Mrs. Robinson, you're trying to seduce me, aren't you."
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    It's Graduation Day! I think this movie is seducing me. You're trying to seduce me. Aren't you?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ironhorse_iv
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The movie has this great 1960's Hollywood New Wave feel to it. This is a coming of age movie that works for me. A lot of coming of age movies seem to try to make their character innocent, but they never actually are. They do a bunch of irresponsible stuff and at the end of the day a lot of people call them "innocent and lost", but it just feels like an excuse to sympathize for being an idiot. However I do sympathize for this character, Benjamin Braddock (Dustin Hoffman). It seemed like he was forced into a pool and not allowed to come back up. The theme of an innocent and confused youth who is exploited, misdirected, seduced and betrayed by a corrupt older generation was well understood by film audiences and captured the spirit of the times. One of the film's posters proclaimed the difficult coming-of-age for college graduate. Directed by Mike Nichols, the film is based on the 1963 novel The Graduate by Charles Webb. The movie opens to one of the best songs of the 1960's, Simon & Garfunkel - The Sound of Silence. This is one of the best songs I've ever listened to. I think the soundtrack pretty much made Simon & Garfunkel from nearly unknown folk singers, to legends of the music industry. You can also hear an earlier version of Mrs. Robinson in the movie. The song as it appears in the film is different from the familiar hit single version, as only the chorus of the song appears late in the film and with slightly different lyrics. It was only later on that Paul Simon and Art Garfunkel re-recorded the song by employing additional lyrics to form the hit single. It's kinda funny that the original song was call 'Mrs. Roosevelt'. It would really be funny to see Eleanor Roosevelt have an affair with a younger man. The Sound of Silence song work for the film as it really fit in with the plot regarding the lack of communication between the controlling parents and the young adults. Anyways, Benjamin Braddock has just arrive back home, after years in College. Dustin Hoffman played the part of the awkward post-graduate student perfectly. I can't see Mike Nichols first choice, Robert Redford in this role. Dustin is kind of awkward that works, he isn't to an abnormal extent creep, he more just describes the entire situation to the woman. Unsure of himself, by being uncomfortable and anxious, and force to hear others decide for him what he will do with his future. Benjamin Braddock soon find himself, seduce by an older woman, Mrs. Robinson (Anne Bancroft) and find himself tempt into an affair. Anne Bancroft is a cougar on the prowl, really to pounce on her prey. She was really pretty in the room. Even though her character is sympathetic, it doesn't change the fact that her character is a vindictive sexual predator. Just the line 'You've known me nearly all your life." Is just disturbing. Mrs. Robinson wanting to bang a kid she watched grow up? That's gross, and just a step below Woody Allen marrying his stepdaughter. She was marry too, so not only is she wanting to date a younger man, she watch when he was kid, but she's also cheating on her husband. It is pure flesh, but she is nice about it. It is just natural, pragmatic and not that romantic-idealistic. She's still the Queen of all Milfs. Her personal life isn't the only thing she's opening. Some people might hate the fact, that the two main characters are two of the most shallow, childish characters. Mrs. Robinson can be especially hateful without any specific motivation, while Benjamin is bit spineless. I do love Dustin Hoffman in the role, but he was way too old for this part. He was playing a 20 year old, and he himself was 30 at the time. Also Anne Bancroft was only 35 during the time of filming. It also kinda funny that the actress Katharine Ross who played Anne Bancroft's daughter Elaine was only 8 years younger than her 35 and 27, miscasting. Katherine Ross looks lovely as Elaine, but she's barely one-dimensional and looks like a girl who would never go for a guy like Dustin Hoffman in a million years. She only went with him, because of her over controlling parents. Anyways, Benjamin soon fall in love with Elaine, and is in a dilemma. Should be continue to live with people telling what to do with his life like Mrs. Robinson or should he set his own future with a girl like Elaine? Find out, by watching it. The ending is up to question, if these two would work out. It leaves a deep interpretation of risky love. This is a classic film: tightly written, intelligent, funny, wonderfully acted, with a great climax with the church, so to speak. You will get seduce into watching the film by how brilliant it is.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of the most overvalued films of all times
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Turin_Horse
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The great and classical soundtrack by Simon & Garfunkel, a group of good actors and one of the most famous scenes in cinema history with Anne Bancroft and Dustin Hoffman as protagonists cannot make up a poor, even lame plot, an incoherent and silly story full of holes and a dull direction and editing. One wonders how such a film could make its way through time to still be considered a "classic" and seemingly appreciated by a high number of people; maybe, for people in the sixties this film meant something, or touched something inside them or whatever, but nowadays The Graduate should long have been put in the bag of dated unworthy-to-watch films. The final scenes with Benjamin trying to prevent the wedding of his sweetheart and taking her with him are just shameful!. There are some very good films from the sixties, try Midnight Cowboy for instance, but skip this over-overvalued film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Creative, compelling & classic
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    stephparsons
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    You've gotta love The Graduate.&nbsp; Even after 44 years, it's still relevant, highly watchable, funny, a titchy bit avant-garde, and boasts a top notch, flawless script.&nbsp; Dustin Hoffman as Ben does a bang up job playing the hapless graduate who desperately wants to escape his boring, careerist fate (as predetermined by&nbsp; his parents and society at large).&nbsp; He exudes 'sullen-youth-ness', boredom-with-life, naivet&eacute;, awkwardness and an (almost) 'aspergers' style of speech which are amusing and poignant.&nbsp; Despite all the drama that unfolds; the seduction followed by the 'coming-of-age' sex with an older woman, the falling in love with a fresh, vibrant young woman, The Graduate is, ultimately, a film about ennui; that dull, thudding, inexorable grind we face upon leaving school and being forced to 'decide what to do' for the rest of our sad, pathetic , predictable lives.&nbsp; Career paths being far more restrictive in the '60s,&nbsp; the sense of doom and pointlessness that Ben feels is exacerbated and he portrays it so very well.&nbsp;&nbsp; The friend of his parents who says, "I have one word for you Ben...plastics", sums up the soulless, futile, and arid future that Ben fears is his destiny. &nbsp;The Graduate experiments successfully with some creative cinematography including unusual camera angles, and interesting switches from one milieu to another e.g. Ben jumping into the swimming pool but ending up on the bed with Mrs Robinson.&nbsp;&nbsp; The swimming pool scene where Ben must walk under water in his birthday present - an old fashioned diving suit- is especially memorable and provides a convincing metaphor for the restrictiveness, loneliness and entrapment that he fears is to be his fate.&nbsp; There is nothing 'awkward' or dated about this classic film, it holds one's attention from start to finish.&nbsp; The ending steers clear of that typical 'happily ever after' Hollywood schmaltz&nbsp; and, in subtle tones presents us with 'ennui in a nutshell' as Ben and Elaine exchange smiles, then worried looks, and then expressions devoid of all emotion.&nbsp; There is nothing I would change about The Graduate, it's a classic and always will be.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Loved it!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    oliviadoerrer17
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Personally thought this particular film was great! I have heard many things about it's wonderful storyline and acting, I definitely had high expectations going into the film and it exceeded those. I always love a movie that is scandalous, and makes you wonder every second if someone is going to get caught. Dustin Hoffman really took on his role and made it believable to his shy nervous personality. He managed to make most scenes awkward which made it very funny. My personal favorite was the scene where Mrs Robinson tried to seduce him, you could tell by his facial expression and sweat he was extremely nervous and uncomfortable. The shots of Mrs Robinson's nude body then to Benjamin's face then back to her body and so on really was comical. The storyline did end up becoming interesting and complicated due to obvious reasons which overall added to the film. I liked the fact that Benjamin never gave up in what he wanted and fought to the end.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Hysterical
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    RoseXGold
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I loved this movie. It was the perfect blend of comedy, drama,love and action. The overall plot was very intriguing. I feel like everyone has been in the main characters shoes before( not knowing exactly what you want to do with your life). The theme was very relate-able. I feel as though everyone had a specific character that they could some how relate to. The music in this film was something that stood out to me. It was a bit more modern. I adored the fact that they not only made this movie a drama. But they also fit a lot of comedy into the film. I feel as though Dustin Hoffman played the role of a personality actor. I felt like I've seen the same persona played in other films he has starred in as well.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Graduate
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    stephypoo912
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I like this film. Even after seeing it three times! Seeing it every time, I have different feelings towards this film. Any way, i still end up liking it and loving the ending. It is a film that is predictable in some ways, but in others it definitely isn't. The whole movie, in itself is great. The editing is a great way to start the break-down. One of my favorite shots is the triple take in the beginning half of the movie. Another editing part that ALWAYS catches my eye is the pool shot then the hotel shot. The way it merges as one scene into the next is NOTHING like I have ever seen before. That definitely kept me enticed. The story line as well kept me watching it. The way it ended made me think, "Could there possibly be another way they could have found each other?" Hmm...
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A treatise on the nature of being a graduate
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    sunshinebeachcinema
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    In following up those cinematic classics that I'm somehow still catching up on, I recently saw The Graduate for the first time. I inevitably went into it with some idea of what was going to happen, but little more than an expectation for Dustin Hoffman to pursue a relationship with an older woman, to the sound of Simon & Garfunkel. Hoffman is Benjamin Braddock, the disaffected young university graduate who returns from his studies to a summer without direction. He is swiftly seduced by Mrs. Robinson, the wife of his father's business partner, and embarks on a lengthy affair, but his affection soon turns to her daughter, Elaine. Yet this is merely the bare bones of the plot: it's more complex than a simple romantic comedy, and the ending, notably, is ambiguous. It's impossible to complain about spoilers for a film that came out over forty years ago; it has seeped into popular culture, and been subjected to merciless parody. The iconic ending sequence is especially strange to watch for someone who grew up repeatedly watching Wayne's World 2 (1993), where it is replicated shot for shot. The critical eye has been on the film for so long, and it has passed through so many generations that its contemporary relevance can be questioned. Though a product of the late 1960s, the counterculture elements we associate with the period, such as free love, psychedelia, or hard rock. Benjamin's sexual experiences are not part of a revolution, and he remains trapped firmly within the rigid framework of upper middle class suburbia. While there's a certain fascination to looking back on a snapshot of the past, many of us no longer have the same relationship with our parents and the older generation. Do we look back at a history of steady liberalisation, but no massive social upheaval, and see further subversion as unnecessary? Do our parents, the children of the past, simply provide us with a system we no longer need to escape? Maybe modern youth have it worse than Benjamin; our coming of age is not so straightforward. We are no longer afforded the opportunity of clear rebellion, and are left to wallow in the established structure. What does hold true is the portrayal of a graduate with no clear future, returning to inhabit the fading skeleton of a life that's somehow no longer his own, and the dull resignation that there's little incentive to do anything about it. As a graduate myself (Though my current social circle suffers an absence of attractive lonely women) I can largely sympathise with Benjamin's predicament. After all, what does the immediate future hold? The prospects of the graduate are numerous and varied. Will it be more of the same on a postgraduate course? Are we heading for the city for a mysterious role as an analyst or consultant (when we're really just brewing tea for executives)? Perhaps it's just going to be a couple more months playing video games in pyjamas before we make a final decision. We still need something. A last hurrah before we're thrown to the world of work and responsibility for good. Could the modern rebellion be merely the fabled gap year abroad? At any rate, it seems coming of age requires something extreme, ditching the world and obligations, the way that Benjamin does at the end of The Graduate. The whole film is an exploration of these questions, symbolically relayed through the central relationships. The choices the characters make in their attachments are reflective of the choices that can be made in all facets of life. This is emphasised stylistically through a number of visually captivating shots and transitions that underline the sense of emptiness and alienation. Water (swimming pools, aquariums, and rain) appears frequently as a tool of separation. The soundtrack contains little youthful euphoria, but is melancholic, featuring repeated motifs that again, accentuate loneliness. These are played during moments that could otherwise be seen as positive steps in Benjamin's life, at the height of his relationship with Mrs. Robinson, and during his final elopement, elevating the drama above mere comedy. His obsession with Elaine is far from romantic destiny, and exists primarily as an escape from his relationship with her mother, and a chance to give his life some purpose outside an unhealthy liaison that makes him feel increasingly trapped. Compared with Mrs. Robinson, Elaine's character is chronically underdeveloped, though she responds positively to Benjamin's pseudo-philosophical ramblings. While she is disgusted to learn of Benjamin's affair with her mother, we learn little else of her thoughts on home, and where she fits in do the loveless dynamic in the Robinson household. We do not know if she as desperate to break free as Benjamin is. She ultimately follows him on impulse, having initially been happy to marry another at her parents' request. The separation from the character of Elaine forces us to experience the relationship purely from the perspective of Benjamin, who has put her on a pedestal and made her the object of his salvation. Despite the vein of sympathy I have as a fellow graduate, Benjamin is at times an insufferable and frustrating character to watch, and ultimately, Mrs. Robinson comes off as more sympathetic. She is the one who is truly lost and trapped. Benjamin still has his whole life ahead of him, once he finally decides what he's going to do with it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An Under-appreciated Classic!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    FilmMuscle
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I find it disappointing that the Graduate isn't one of those constantly-talked-about classics like The Godfather, Kramer vs. Kramer, Apocalypse Now, The Shawshank Redemption, etc. I had mixed expectations for the film since I heard, prior to viewing, some negative opinions and positive ones from individuals who'd recently watched it. Now, let's talk about why this film should be just as remembered of a classic as the others above. First of all and- in my opinion- most importantly, the film carries with it a highly intriguing and interesting story that keeps you entertained the entire way as the clever plot unravels. You're presented with this socially angsty twenty-year-old who's basically helpless, surrounded by intimidating people and frightening situations. He's a character that the audience can't help but love. For me, I could find myself relating to his personality quite a bit. I, too, attempt to stray away from great attention and prefer a much calmer and less crowded environment. The story, itself, keeps your attention because it's just strongly gripping insofar as this character finds himself in extremely awkward and threatening situations. Personally- like with the scene where Benjamin is awkwardly attempting to avoid suspicion while getting a hotel room- I recalled similar instances with myself where I was about to engage in something that could be regrettable and had to deal with suspicious or curious bystanders, family members, or whatnot. While we're still on it, the acting was unbelievably good, especially Dustin Hoffman's break-out performance as Benjamin. The way he portrayed a timid and awkward character surely blew away the moviegoers that night of its release. His timing and speech delivery, overall, creates an absolutely believable story about this fully realistic outcast. The way he would retreat under the pool whenever he felt vulnerable or faced his imposing parents definitely moved me because I could honestly understand him in any given predicament. At times, I feel like finding some peaceful and impenetrable spot to socially leave the world and obtain some time to breathe. The script of this picture is brilliant from the convincing dialogue to the intelligent build-up of relationships and their interconnections. For the moment, let's delve into the more technical side of The Graduate since its cinematography and editing is exceptional- excellent, might I say. The evolution of filmmaking over the decades from when Hollywood first stemmed truly and impressively proved itself in this movie. For example, there's a particular scene where Benjamin is "drifting" on the pool's air mattress, and he's interrupted by his irritating parents and the Robinsons themselves, and as they begin discussing his current uneventful life, the camera perfectly displays these incredibly condescending figures looking down at him with the sun shining so brightly that it seems to be blinding both the viewer and Benjamin as he's forced to look up at them. You sympathize with Benjamin because you feel their aggression and- again- condescending conversation about how he's not doing anything with his life, and I'm sure everyone's been in that sort of position, mentally or physically. Then, another shot shows Elaine as her confused face gets less and less blurry (indicating her progression towards fully understanding the mystery) until she finally realizes what's essentially transpiring between Benjamin and her own mother. In terms of editing, an instance showcases fast cutting to Mrs. Robinson's naked body as Benjamin attempts to ignore it but can't help his lust in a way. The film also smoothly and uniquely transitions to new settings without the audience even noticing at first as Benjamin exits the pool, walks to his room, and is suddenly found entering Mrs. Robinson's bed. Another strength of the camera-work is the noticeably lengthy shots where we witness entire conversations occurring in one single take or the scuba mask scene where a few minutes or so are filmed from a first-person perspective as Benjamin dives into his pool. In sum, the film seemed like a breath of fresh air that was affected by an unquestionably relatable protagonist that you felt for and his escape with the love of his life seemed utterly satisfying as well. Usually, happy endings done the way The Graduate did it come off as corny and clich&eacute;d, but your liking for the characters and their success overshadowed that aspect. So far, I've been loving all the films in class as this is yet another one I can't help but give high praise to.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not A Classic.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    AaronCapenBanner
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Mike Nichols directed this film about Ben Braddock, a confused young man trying to decide on his future in a society he can't understand, but instead becomes involved with the married mother of his reluctant girlfriend, and the various complications that ensue as a result. Dustin Hoffman leads a good cast, it has haunting songs by Simon & Garfunkel, is beloved by many of that generation, and even won Nichols an Academy Award for best director. So what's not to like? For a film that reacts negatively to the word "plastic", that's just how I feel about the characters and setting. Nothing about this film feels particularly real, certainly not the affair of Ben and Mrs. Robinson(Anne Bancroft) which not only isn't believable, it doesn't make sense, feels utterly manufactured and wrong. Katharine Ross as his girlfriend reacts to the news believably, but the ending will leave the viewer up in the air, since it, while dramatically staged, feels forced and unsatisfying. It just doesn't work for me.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    If anyone was born to play an awkward 21 year old...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    cleary-joshua
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    If anyone was born to play an awkward 21 year old deciding what to do with his life, it has to be 30 year old Dustin Hoffman, who steals this movie with his brilliant portrayal of Benjamin Braddock. It's a performance with humour and emotion all rolled into one. For example, Hoffman's performance when he first takes Mrs. Robinson home is hilarious, with his constant nervous stammering and occasional high-pitched squeaks. The final shot of Elaine and Benjamin has so much drama in both of their expressions, and you can tell how great the pair are as actors. They've just run away together, and she's already married. Are they completely happy? Not really, and both of their faces have a sort of "now what?" expression, leaving the audience thinking about whether it was the right decision. As for the story itself, it's comical without becoming too farcical, and has enough drama later on to keep the audience interested. It's also beautifully shot, with a lot of clever cutting and images, such as the fact that Benjamin is always being shot through other objects, like the hotel woodwork, or Mrs. Robinson's leg. The music too is great, and Simon and Garfunkel's songs, though some of them are used almost too much, manage to create just the right atmosphere for the film. The late Roger Ebert originally gave this film 4 stars, but thirty years later, dropped his score down to 3, something I'm not sure I've ever heard of a critic doing. He states in his later review that it's not a film that has stood the test of time, that modern audiences wouldn't find it as funny. I disagree with this, and managed to find humour in a lot of the film. However his main reason for doing so is the character of Benjamin, whom he calls an 'insufferable creep', and now I think about it, Ebert is kind of right. Perhaps the awkwardness does go a bit too far at points, and he is just a bit strange and horrible in taking Elaine to the strip club and stalking her for a long time. This detail aside, I still found it to be a hugely enjoyable film which left a lot to think about afterwards, as well as a lot of laughs, and it's worth watching if only for Hoffman's performance and delivery of that classic line: "Mrs. Robinson, you're trying to seduce me, aren't you."
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    It's Graduation Day! I think this movie is seducing me. You're trying to seduce me. Aren't you?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ironhorse_iv
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The movie has this great 1960's Hollywood New Wave feel to it. This is a coming of age movie that works for me. A lot of coming of age movies seem to try to make their character innocent, but they never actually are. They do a bunch of irresponsible stuff and at the end of the day a lot of people call them "innocent and lost", but it just feels like an excuse to sympathize for being an idiot. However I do sympathize for this character, Benjamin Braddock (Dustin Hoffman). It seemed like he was forced into a pool and not allowed to come back up. The theme of an innocent and confused youth who is exploited, misdirected, seduced and betrayed by a corrupt older generation was well understood by film audiences and captured the spirit of the times. One of the film's posters proclaimed the difficult coming-of-age for college graduate. Directed by Mike Nichols, the film is based on the 1963 novel The Graduate by Charles Webb. The movie opens to one of the best songs of the 1960's, Simon & Garfunkel - The Sound of Silence. This is one of the best songs I've ever listened to. I think the soundtrack pretty much made Simon & Garfunkel from nearly unknown folk singers, to legends of the music industry. You can also hear an earlier version of Mrs. Robinson in the movie. The song as it appears in the film is different from the familiar hit single version, as only the chorus of the song appears late in the film and with slightly different lyrics. It was only later on that Paul Simon and Art Garfunkel re-recorded the song by employing additional lyrics to form the hit single. It's kinda funny that the original song was call 'Mrs. Roosevelt'. It would really be funny to see Eleanor Roosevelt have an affair with a younger man. The Sound of Silence song work for the film as it really fit in with the plot regarding the lack of communication between the controlling parents and the young adults. Anyways, Benjamin Braddock has just arrive back home, after years in College. Dustin Hoffman played the part of the awkward post-graduate student perfectly. I can't see Mike Nichols first choice, Robert Redford in this role. Dustin is kind of awkward that works, he isn't to an abnormal extent creep, he more just describes the entire situation to the woman. Unsure of himself, by being uncomfortable and anxious, and force to hear others decide for him what he will do with his future. Benjamin Braddock soon find himself, seduce by an older woman, Mrs. Robinson (Anne Bancroft) and find himself tempt into an affair. Anne Bancroft is a cougar on the prowl, really to pounce on her prey. She was really pretty in the room. Even though her character is sympathetic, it doesn't change the fact that her character is a vindictive sexual predator. Just the line 'You've known me nearly all your life." Is just disturbing. Mrs. Robinson wanting to bang a kid she watched grow up? That's gross, and just a step below Woody Allen marrying his stepdaughter. She was marry too, so not only is she wanting to date a younger man, she watch when he was kid, but she's also cheating on her husband. It is pure flesh, but she is nice about it. It is just natural, pragmatic and not that romantic-idealistic. She's still the Queen of all Milfs. Her personal life isn't the only thing she's opening. Some people might hate the fact, that the two main characters are two of the most shallow, childish characters. Mrs. Robinson can be especially hateful without any specific motivation, while Benjamin is bit spineless. I do love Dustin Hoffman in the role, but he was way too old for this part. He was playing a 20 year old, and he himself was 30 at the time. Also Anne Bancroft was only 35 during the time of filming. It also kinda funny that the actress Katharine Ross who played Anne Bancroft's daughter Elaine was only 8 years younger than her 35 and 27, miscasting. Katherine Ross looks lovely as Elaine, but she's barely one-dimensional and looks like a girl who would never go for a guy like Dustin Hoffman in a million years. She only went with him, because of her over controlling parents. Anyways, Benjamin soon fall in love with Elaine, and is in a dilemma. Should be continue to live with people telling what to do with his life like Mrs. Robinson or should he set his own future with a girl like Elaine? Find out, by watching it. The ending is up to question, if these two would work out. It leaves a deep interpretation of risky love. This is a classic film: tightly written, intelligent, funny, wonderfully acted, with a great climax with the church, so to speak. You will get seduce into watching the film by how brilliant it is.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of the most overvalued films of all times
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Turin_Horse
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The great and classical soundtrack by Simon & Garfunkel, a group of good actors and one of the most famous scenes in cinema history with Anne Bancroft and Dustin Hoffman as protagonists cannot make up a poor, even lame plot, an incoherent and silly story full of holes and a dull direction and editing. One wonders how such a film could make its way through time to still be considered a "classic" and seemingly appreciated by a high number of people; maybe, for people in the sixties this film meant something, or touched something inside them or whatever, but nowadays The Graduate should long have been put in the bag of dated unworthy-to-watch films. The final scenes with Benjamin trying to prevent the wedding of his sweetheart and taking her with him are just shameful!. There are some very good films from the sixties, try Midnight Cowboy for instance, but skip this over-overvalued film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Creative, compelling & classic
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    stephparsons
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    You've gotta love The Graduate.&nbsp; Even after 44 years, it's still relevant, highly watchable, funny, a titchy bit avant-garde, and boasts a top notch, flawless script.&nbsp; Dustin Hoffman as Ben does a bang up job playing the hapless graduate who desperately wants to escape his boring, careerist fate (as predetermined by&nbsp; his parents and society at large).&nbsp; He exudes 'sullen-youth-ness', boredom-with-life, naivet&eacute;, awkwardness and an (almost) 'aspergers' style of speech which are amusing and poignant.&nbsp; Despite all the drama that unfolds; the seduction followed by the 'coming-of-age' sex with an older woman, the falling in love with a fresh, vibrant young woman, The Graduate is, ultimately, a film about ennui; that dull, thudding, inexorable grind we face upon leaving school and being forced to 'decide what to do' for the rest of our sad, pathetic , predictable lives.&nbsp; Career paths being far more restrictive in the '60s,&nbsp; the sense of doom and pointlessness that Ben feels is exacerbated and he portrays it so very well.&nbsp;&nbsp; The friend of his parents who says, "I have one word for you Ben...plastics", sums up the soulless, futile, and arid future that Ben fears is his destiny. &nbsp;The Graduate experiments successfully with some creative cinematography including unusual camera angles, and interesting switches from one milieu to another e.g. Ben jumping into the swimming pool but ending up on the bed with Mrs Robinson.&nbsp;&nbsp; The swimming pool scene where Ben must walk under water in his birthday present - an old fashioned diving suit- is especially memorable and provides a convincing metaphor for the restrictiveness, loneliness and entrapment that he fears is to be his fate.&nbsp; There is nothing 'awkward' or dated about this classic film, it holds one's attention from start to finish.&nbsp; The ending steers clear of that typical 'happily ever after' Hollywood schmaltz&nbsp; and, in subtle tones presents us with 'ennui in a nutshell' as Ben and Elaine exchange smiles, then worried looks, and then expressions devoid of all emotion.&nbsp; There is nothing I would change about The Graduate, it's a classic and always will be.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Loved it!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    oliviadoerrer17
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Personally thought this particular film was great! I have heard many things about it's wonderful storyline and acting, I definitely had high expectations going into the film and it exceeded those. I always love a movie that is scandalous, and makes you wonder every second if someone is going to get caught. Dustin Hoffman really took on his role and made it believable to his shy nervous personality. He managed to make most scenes awkward which made it very funny. My personal favorite was the scene where Mrs Robinson tried to seduce him, you could tell by his facial expression and sweat he was extremely nervous and uncomfortable. The shots of Mrs Robinson's nude body then to Benjamin's face then back to her body and so on really was comical. The storyline did end up becoming interesting and complicated due to obvious reasons which overall added to the film. I liked the fact that Benjamin never gave up in what he wanted and fought to the end.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Hysterical
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    RoseXGold
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I loved this movie. It was the perfect blend of comedy, drama,love and action. The overall plot was very intriguing. I feel like everyone has been in the main characters shoes before( not knowing exactly what you want to do with your life). The theme was very relate-able. I feel as though everyone had a specific character that they could some how relate to. The music in this film was something that stood out to me. It was a bit more modern. I adored the fact that they not only made this movie a drama. But they also fit a lot of comedy into the film. I feel as though Dustin Hoffman played the role of a personality actor. I felt like I've seen the same persona played in other films he has starred in as well.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Graduate
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    stephypoo912
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I like this film. Even after seeing it three times! Seeing it every time, I have different feelings towards this film. Any way, i still end up liking it and loving the ending. It is a film that is predictable in some ways, but in others it definitely isn't. The whole movie, in itself is great. The editing is a great way to start the break-down. One of my favorite shots is the triple take in the beginning half of the movie. Another editing part that ALWAYS catches my eye is the pool shot then the hotel shot. The way it merges as one scene into the next is NOTHING like I have ever seen before. That definitely kept me enticed. The story line as well kept me watching it. The way it ended made me think, "Could there possibly be another way they could have found each other?" Hmm...
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A treatise on the nature of being a graduate
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    sunshinebeachcinema
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    In following up those cinematic classics that I'm somehow still catching up on, I recently saw The Graduate for the first time. I inevitably went into it with some idea of what was going to happen, but little more than an expectation for Dustin Hoffman to pursue a relationship with an older woman, to the sound of Simon & Garfunkel. Hoffman is Benjamin Braddock, the disaffected young university graduate who returns from his studies to a summer without direction. He is swiftly seduced by Mrs. Robinson, the wife of his father's business partner, and embarks on a lengthy affair, but his affection soon turns to her daughter, Elaine. Yet this is merely the bare bones of the plot: it's more complex than a simple romantic comedy, and the ending, notably, is ambiguous. It's impossible to complain about spoilers for a film that came out over forty years ago; it has seeped into popular culture, and been subjected to merciless parody. The iconic ending sequence is especially strange to watch for someone who grew up repeatedly watching Wayne's World 2 (1993), where it is replicated shot for shot. The critical eye has been on the film for so long, and it has passed through so many generations that its contemporary relevance can be questioned. Though a product of the late 1960s, the counterculture elements we associate with the period, such as free love, psychedelia, or hard rock. Benjamin's sexual experiences are not part of a revolution, and he remains trapped firmly within the rigid framework of upper middle class suburbia. While there's a certain fascination to looking back on a snapshot of the past, many of us no longer have the same relationship with our parents and the older generation. Do we look back at a history of steady liberalisation, but no massive social upheaval, and see further subversion as unnecessary? Do our parents, the children of the past, simply provide us with a system we no longer need to escape? Maybe modern youth have it worse than Benjamin; our coming of age is not so straightforward. We are no longer afforded the opportunity of clear rebellion, and are left to wallow in the established structure. What does hold true is the portrayal of a graduate with no clear future, returning to inhabit the fading skeleton of a life that's somehow no longer his own, and the dull resignation that there's little incentive to do anything about it. As a graduate myself (Though my current social circle suffers an absence of attractive lonely women) I can largely sympathise with Benjamin's predicament. After all, what does the immediate future hold? The prospects of the graduate are numerous and varied. Will it be more of the same on a postgraduate course? Are we heading for the city for a mysterious role as an analyst or consultant (when we're really just brewing tea for executives)? Perhaps it's just going to be a couple more months playing video games in pyjamas before we make a final decision. We still need something. A last hurrah before we're thrown to the world of work and responsibility for good. Could the modern rebellion be merely the fabled gap year abroad? At any rate, it seems coming of age requires something extreme, ditching the world and obligations, the way that Benjamin does at the end of The Graduate. The whole film is an exploration of these questions, symbolically relayed through the central relationships. The choices the characters make in their attachments are reflective of the choices that can be made in all facets of life. This is emphasised stylistically through a number of visually captivating shots and transitions that underline the sense of emptiness and alienation. Water (swimming pools, aquariums, and rain) appears frequently as a tool of separation. The soundtrack contains little youthful euphoria, but is melancholic, featuring repeated motifs that again, accentuate loneliness. These are played during moments that could otherwise be seen as positive steps in Benjamin's life, at the height of his relationship with Mrs. Robinson, and during his final elopement, elevating the drama above mere comedy. His obsession with Elaine is far from romantic destiny, and exists primarily as an escape from his relationship with her mother, and a chance to give his life some purpose outside an unhealthy liaison that makes him feel increasingly trapped. Compared with Mrs. Robinson, Elaine's character is chronically underdeveloped, though she responds positively to Benjamin's pseudo-philosophical ramblings. While she is disgusted to learn of Benjamin's affair with her mother, we learn little else of her thoughts on home, and where she fits in do the loveless dynamic in the Robinson household. We do not know if she as desperate to break free as Benjamin is. She ultimately follows him on impulse, having initially been happy to marry another at her parents' request. The separation from the character of Elaine forces us to experience the relationship purely from the perspective of Benjamin, who has put her on a pedestal and made her the object of his salvation. Despite the vein of sympathy I have as a fellow graduate, Benjamin is at times an insufferable and frustrating character to watch, and ultimately, Mrs. Robinson comes off as more sympathetic. She is the one who is truly lost and trapped. Benjamin still has his whole life ahead of him, once he finally decides what he's going to do with it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An Under-appreciated Classic!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    FilmMuscle
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I find it disappointing that the Graduate isn't one of those constantly-talked-about classics like The Godfather, Kramer vs. Kramer, Apocalypse Now, The Shawshank Redemption, etc. I had mixed expectations for the film since I heard, prior to viewing, some negative opinions and positive ones from individuals who'd recently watched it. Now, let's talk about why this film should be just as remembered of a classic as the others above. First of all and- in my opinion- most importantly, the film carries with it a highly intriguing and interesting story that keeps you entertained the entire way as the clever plot unravels. You're presented with this socially angsty twenty-year-old who's basically helpless, surrounded by intimidating people and frightening situations. He's a character that the audience can't help but love. For me, I could find myself relating to his personality quite a bit. I, too, attempt to stray away from great attention and prefer a much calmer and less crowded environment. The story, itself, keeps your attention because it's just strongly gripping insofar as this character finds himself in extremely awkward and threatening situations. Personally- like with the scene where Benjamin is awkwardly attempting to avoid suspicion while getting a hotel room- I recalled similar instances with myself where I was about to engage in something that could be regrettable and had to deal with suspicious or curious bystanders, family members, or whatnot. While we're still on it, the acting was unbelievably good, especially Dustin Hoffman's break-out performance as Benjamin. The way he portrayed a timid and awkward character surely blew away the moviegoers that night of its release. His timing and speech delivery, overall, creates an absolutely believable story about this fully realistic outcast. The way he would retreat under the pool whenever he felt vulnerable or faced his imposing parents definitely moved me because I could honestly understand him in any given predicament. At times, I feel like finding some peaceful and impenetrable spot to socially leave the world and obtain some time to breathe. The script of this picture is brilliant from the convincing dialogue to the intelligent build-up of relationships and their interconnections. For the moment, let's delve into the more technical side of The Graduate since its cinematography and editing is exceptional- excellent, might I say. The evolution of filmmaking over the decades from when Hollywood first stemmed truly and impressively proved itself in this movie. For example, there's a particular scene where Benjamin is "drifting" on the pool's air mattress, and he's interrupted by his irritating parents and the Robinsons themselves, and as they begin discussing his current uneventful life, the camera perfectly displays these incredibly condescending figures looking down at him with the sun shining so brightly that it seems to be blinding both the viewer and Benjamin as he's forced to look up at them. You sympathize with Benjamin because you feel their aggression and- again- condescending conversation about how he's not doing anything with his life, and I'm sure everyone's been in that sort of position, mentally or physically. Then, another shot shows Elaine as her confused face gets less and less blurry (indicating her progression towards fully understanding the mystery) until she finally realizes what's essentially transpiring between Benjamin and her own mother. In terms of editing, an instance showcases fast cutting to Mrs. Robinson's naked body as Benjamin attempts to ignore it but can't help his lust in a way. The film also smoothly and uniquely transitions to new settings without the audience even noticing at first as Benjamin exits the pool, walks to his room, and is suddenly found entering Mrs. Robinson's bed. Another strength of the camera-work is the noticeably lengthy shots where we witness entire conversations occurring in one single take or the scuba mask scene where a few minutes or so are filmed from a first-person perspective as Benjamin dives into his pool. In sum, the film seemed like a breath of fresh air that was affected by an unquestionably relatable protagonist that you felt for and his escape with the love of his life seemed utterly satisfying as well. Usually, happy endings done the way The Graduate did it come off as corny and clich&eacute;d, but your liking for the characters and their success overshadowed that aspect. So far, I've been loving all the films in class as this is yet another one I can't help but give high praise to.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not A Classic.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    AaronCapenBanner
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Mike Nichols directed this film about Ben Braddock, a confused young man trying to decide on his future in a society he can't understand, but instead becomes involved with the married mother of his reluctant girlfriend, and the various complications that ensue as a result. Dustin Hoffman leads a good cast, it has haunting songs by Simon & Garfunkel, is beloved by many of that generation, and even won Nichols an Academy Award for best director. So what's not to like? For a film that reacts negatively to the word "plastic", that's just how I feel about the characters and setting. Nothing about this film feels particularly real, certainly not the affair of Ben and Mrs. Robinson(Anne Bancroft) which not only isn't believable, it doesn't make sense, feels utterly manufactured and wrong. Katharine Ross as his girlfriend reacts to the news believably, but the ending will leave the viewer up in the air, since it, while dramatically staged, feels forced and unsatisfying. It just doesn't work for me.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    If anyone was born to play an awkward 21 year old...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    cleary-joshua
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    If anyone was born to play an awkward 21 year old deciding what to do with his life, it has to be 30 year old Dustin Hoffman, who steals this movie with his brilliant portrayal of Benjamin Braddock. It's a performance with humour and emotion all rolled into one. For example, Hoffman's performance when he first takes Mrs. Robinson home is hilarious, with his constant nervous stammering and occasional high-pitched squeaks. The final shot of Elaine and Benjamin has so much drama in both of their expressions, and you can tell how great the pair are as actors. They've just run away together, and she's already married. Are they completely happy? Not really, and both of their faces have a sort of "now what?" expression, leaving the audience thinking about whether it was the right decision. As for the story itself, it's comical without becoming too farcical, and has enough drama later on to keep the audience interested. It's also beautifully shot, with a lot of clever cutting and images, such as the fact that Benjamin is always being shot through other objects, like the hotel woodwork, or Mrs. Robinson's leg. The music too is great, and Simon and Garfunkel's songs, though some of them are used almost too much, manage to create just the right atmosphere for the film. The late Roger Ebert originally gave this film 4 stars, but thirty years later, dropped his score down to 3, something I'm not sure I've ever heard of a critic doing. He states in his later review that it's not a film that has stood the test of time, that modern audiences wouldn't find it as funny. I disagree with this, and managed to find humour in a lot of the film. However his main reason for doing so is the character of Benjamin, whom he calls an 'insufferable creep', and now I think about it, Ebert is kind of right. Perhaps the awkwardness does go a bit too far at points, and he is just a bit strange and horrible in taking Elaine to the strip club and stalking her for a long time. This detail aside, I still found it to be a hugely enjoyable film which left a lot to think about afterwards, as well as a lot of laughs, and it's worth watching if only for Hoffman's performance and delivery of that classic line: "Mrs. Robinson, you're trying to seduce me, aren't you."
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    It's Graduation Day! I think this movie is seducing me. You're trying to seduce me. Aren't you?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ironhorse_iv
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The movie has this great 1960's Hollywood New Wave feel to it. This is a coming of age movie that works for me. A lot of coming of age movies seem to try to make their character innocent, but they never actually are. They do a bunch of irresponsible stuff and at the end of the day a lot of people call them "innocent and lost", but it just feels like an excuse to sympathize for being an idiot. However I do sympathize for this character, Benjamin Braddock (Dustin Hoffman). It seemed like he was forced into a pool and not allowed to come back up. The theme of an innocent and confused youth who is exploited, misdirected, seduced and betrayed by a corrupt older generation was well understood by film audiences and captured the spirit of the times. One of the film's posters proclaimed the difficult coming-of-age for college graduate. Directed by Mike Nichols, the film is based on the 1963 novel The Graduate by Charles Webb. The movie opens to one of the best songs of the 1960's, Simon & Garfunkel - The Sound of Silence. This is one of the best songs I've ever listened to. I think the soundtrack pretty much made Simon & Garfunkel from nearly unknown folk singers, to legends of the music industry. You can also hear an earlier version of Mrs. Robinson in the movie. The song as it appears in the film is different from the familiar hit single version, as only the chorus of the song appears late in the film and with slightly different lyrics. It was only later on that Paul Simon and Art Garfunkel re-recorded the song by employing additional lyrics to form the hit single. It's kinda funny that the original song was call 'Mrs. Roosevelt'. It would really be funny to see Eleanor Roosevelt have an affair with a younger man. The Sound of Silence song work for the film as it really fit in with the plot regarding the lack of communication between the controlling parents and the young adults. Anyways, Benjamin Braddock has just arrive back home, after years in College. Dustin Hoffman played the part of the awkward post-graduate student perfectly. I can't see Mike Nichols first choice, Robert Redford in this role. Dustin is kind of awkward that works, he isn't to an abnormal extent creep, he more just describes the entire situation to the woman. Unsure of himself, by being uncomfortable and anxious, and force to hear others decide for him what he will do with his future. Benjamin Braddock soon find himself, seduce by an older woman, Mrs. Robinson (Anne Bancroft) and find himself tempt into an affair. Anne Bancroft is a cougar on the prowl, really to pounce on her prey. She was really pretty in the room. Even though her character is sympathetic, it doesn't change the fact that her character is a vindictive sexual predator. Just the line 'You've known me nearly all your life." Is just disturbing. Mrs. Robinson wanting to bang a kid she watched grow up? That's gross, and just a step below Woody Allen marrying his stepdaughter. She was marry too, so not only is she wanting to date a younger man, she watch when he was kid, but she's also cheating on her husband. It is pure flesh, but she is nice about it. It is just natural, pragmatic and not that romantic-idealistic. She's still the Queen of all Milfs. Her personal life isn't the only thing she's opening. Some people might hate the fact, that the two main characters are two of the most shallow, childish characters. Mrs. Robinson can be especially hateful without any specific motivation, while Benjamin is bit spineless. I do love Dustin Hoffman in the role, but he was way too old for this part. He was playing a 20 year old, and he himself was 30 at the time. Also Anne Bancroft was only 35 during the time of filming. It also kinda funny that the actress Katharine Ross who played Anne Bancroft's daughter Elaine was only 8 years younger than her 35 and 27, miscasting. Katherine Ross looks lovely as Elaine, but she's barely one-dimensional and looks like a girl who would never go for a guy like Dustin Hoffman in a million years. She only went with him, because of her over controlling parents. Anyways, Benjamin soon fall in love with Elaine, and is in a dilemma. Should be continue to live with people telling what to do with his life like Mrs. Robinson or should he set his own future with a girl like Elaine? Find out, by watching it. The ending is up to question, if these two would work out. It leaves a deep interpretation of risky love. This is a classic film: tightly written, intelligent, funny, wonderfully acted, with a great climax with the church, so to speak. You will get seduce into watching the film by how brilliant it is.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of the most overvalued films of all times
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Turin_Horse
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The great and classical soundtrack by Simon & Garfunkel, a group of good actors and one of the most famous scenes in cinema history with Anne Bancroft and Dustin Hoffman as protagonists cannot make up a poor, even lame plot, an incoherent and silly story full of holes and a dull direction and editing. One wonders how such a film could make its way through time to still be considered a "classic" and seemingly appreciated by a high number of people; maybe, for people in the sixties this film meant something, or touched something inside them or whatever, but nowadays The Graduate should long have been put in the bag of dated unworthy-to-watch films. The final scenes with Benjamin trying to prevent the wedding of his sweetheart and taking her with him are just shameful!. There are some very good films from the sixties, try Midnight Cowboy for instance, but skip this over-overvalued film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Creative, compelling & classic
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    stephparsons
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    You've gotta love The Graduate.&nbsp; Even after 44 years, it's still relevant, highly watchable, funny, a titchy bit avant-garde, and boasts a top notch, flawless script.&nbsp; Dustin Hoffman as Ben does a bang up job playing the hapless graduate who desperately wants to escape his boring, careerist fate (as predetermined by&nbsp; his parents and society at large).&nbsp; He exudes 'sullen-youth-ness', boredom-with-life, naivet&eacute;, awkwardness and an (almost) 'aspergers' style of speech which are amusing and poignant.&nbsp; Despite all the drama that unfolds; the seduction followed by the 'coming-of-age' sex with an older woman, the falling in love with a fresh, vibrant young woman, The Graduate is, ultimately, a film about ennui; that dull, thudding, inexorable grind we face upon leaving school and being forced to 'decide what to do' for the rest of our sad, pathetic , predictable lives.&nbsp; Career paths being far more restrictive in the '60s,&nbsp; the sense of doom and pointlessness that Ben feels is exacerbated and he portrays it so very well.&nbsp;&nbsp; The friend of his parents who says, "I have one word for you Ben...plastics", sums up the soulless, futile, and arid future that Ben fears is his destiny. &nbsp;The Graduate experiments successfully with some creative cinematography including unusual camera angles, and interesting switches from one milieu to another e.g. Ben jumping into the swimming pool but ending up on the bed with Mrs Robinson.&nbsp;&nbsp; The swimming pool scene where Ben must walk under water in his birthday present - an old fashioned diving suit- is especially memorable and provides a convincing metaphor for the restrictiveness, loneliness and entrapment that he fears is to be his fate.&nbsp; There is nothing 'awkward' or dated about this classic film, it holds one's attention from start to finish.&nbsp; The ending steers clear of that typical 'happily ever after' Hollywood schmaltz&nbsp; and, in subtle tones presents us with 'ennui in a nutshell' as Ben and Elaine exchange smiles, then worried looks, and then expressions devoid of all emotion.&nbsp; There is nothing I would change about The Graduate, it's a classic and always will be.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Loved it!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    oliviadoerrer17
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Personally thought this particular film was great! I have heard many things about it's wonderful storyline and acting, I definitely had high expectations going into the film and it exceeded those. I always love a movie that is scandalous, and makes you wonder every second if someone is going to get caught. Dustin Hoffman really took on his role and made it believable to his shy nervous personality. He managed to make most scenes awkward which made it very funny. My personal favorite was the scene where Mrs Robinson tried to seduce him, you could tell by his facial expression and sweat he was extremely nervous and uncomfortable. The shots of Mrs Robinson's nude body then to Benjamin's face then back to her body and so on really was comical. The storyline did end up becoming interesting and complicated due to obvious reasons which overall added to the film. I liked the fact that Benjamin never gave up in what he wanted and fought to the end.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Hysterical
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    RoseXGold
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I loved this movie. It was the perfect blend of comedy, drama,love and action. The overall plot was very intriguing. I feel like everyone has been in the main characters shoes before( not knowing exactly what you want to do with your life). The theme was very relate-able. I feel as though everyone had a specific character that they could some how relate to. The music in this film was something that stood out to me. It was a bit more modern. I adored the fact that they not only made this movie a drama. But they also fit a lot of comedy into the film. I feel as though Dustin Hoffman played the role of a personality actor. I felt like I've seen the same persona played in other films he has starred in as well.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Graduate
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    stephypoo912
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I like this film. Even after seeing it three times! Seeing it every time, I have different feelings towards this film. Any way, i still end up liking it and loving the ending. It is a film that is predictable in some ways, but in others it definitely isn't. The whole movie, in itself is great. The editing is a great way to start the break-down. One of my favorite shots is the triple take in the beginning half of the movie. Another editing part that ALWAYS catches my eye is the pool shot then the hotel shot. The way it merges as one scene into the next is NOTHING like I have ever seen before. That definitely kept me enticed. The story line as well kept me watching it. The way it ended made me think, "Could there possibly be another way they could have found each other?" Hmm...
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A treatise on the nature of being a graduate
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    sunshinebeachcinema
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    In following up those cinematic classics that I'm somehow still catching up on, I recently saw The Graduate for the first time. I inevitably went into it with some idea of what was going to happen, but little more than an expectation for Dustin Hoffman to pursue a relationship with an older woman, to the sound of Simon & Garfunkel. Hoffman is Benjamin Braddock, the disaffected young university graduate who returns from his studies to a summer without direction. He is swiftly seduced by Mrs. Robinson, the wife of his father's business partner, and embarks on a lengthy affair, but his affection soon turns to her daughter, Elaine. Yet this is merely the bare bones of the plot: it's more complex than a simple romantic comedy, and the ending, notably, is ambiguous. It's impossible to complain about spoilers for a film that came out over forty years ago; it has seeped into popular culture, and been subjected to merciless parody. The iconic ending sequence is especially strange to watch for someone who grew up repeatedly watching Wayne's World 2 (1993), where it is replicated shot for shot. The critical eye has been on the film for so long, and it has passed through so many generations that its contemporary relevance can be questioned. Though a product of the late 1960s, the counterculture elements we associate with the period, such as free love, psychedelia, or hard rock. Benjamin's sexual experiences are not part of a revolution, and he remains trapped firmly within the rigid framework of upper middle class suburbia. While there's a certain fascination to looking back on a snapshot of the past, many of us no longer have the same relationship with our parents and the older generation. Do we look back at a history of steady liberalisation, but no massive social upheaval, and see further subversion as unnecessary? Do our parents, the children of the past, simply provide us with a system we no longer need to escape? Maybe modern youth have it worse than Benjamin; our coming of age is not so straightforward. We are no longer afforded the opportunity of clear rebellion, and are left to wallow in the established structure. What does hold true is the portrayal of a graduate with no clear future, returning to inhabit the fading skeleton of a life that's somehow no longer his own, and the dull resignation that there's little incentive to do anything about it. As a graduate myself (Though my current social circle suffers an absence of attractive lonely women) I can largely sympathise with Benjamin's predicament. After all, what does the immediate future hold? The prospects of the graduate are numerous and varied. Will it be more of the same on a postgraduate course? Are we heading for the city for a mysterious role as an analyst or consultant (when we're really just brewing tea for executives)? Perhaps it's just going to be a couple more months playing video games in pyjamas before we make a final decision. We still need something. A last hurrah before we're thrown to the world of work and responsibility for good. Could the modern rebellion be merely the fabled gap year abroad? At any rate, it seems coming of age requires something extreme, ditching the world and obligations, the way that Benjamin does at the end of The Graduate. The whole film is an exploration of these questions, symbolically relayed through the central relationships. The choices the characters make in their attachments are reflective of the choices that can be made in all facets of life. This is emphasised stylistically through a number of visually captivating shots and transitions that underline the sense of emptiness and alienation. Water (swimming pools, aquariums, and rain) appears frequently as a tool of separation. The soundtrack contains little youthful euphoria, but is melancholic, featuring repeated motifs that again, accentuate loneliness. These are played during moments that could otherwise be seen as positive steps in Benjamin's life, at the height of his relationship with Mrs. Robinson, and during his final elopement, elevating the drama above mere comedy. His obsession with Elaine is far from romantic destiny, and exists primarily as an escape from his relationship with her mother, and a chance to give his life some purpose outside an unhealthy liaison that makes him feel increasingly trapped. Compared with Mrs. Robinson, Elaine's character is chronically underdeveloped, though she responds positively to Benjamin's pseudo-philosophical ramblings. While she is disgusted to learn of Benjamin's affair with her mother, we learn little else of her thoughts on home, and where she fits in do the loveless dynamic in the Robinson household. We do not know if she as desperate to break free as Benjamin is. She ultimately follows him on impulse, having initially been happy to marry another at her parents' request. The separation from the character of Elaine forces us to experience the relationship purely from the perspective of Benjamin, who has put her on a pedestal and made her the object of his salvation. Despite the vein of sympathy I have as a fellow graduate, Benjamin is at times an insufferable and frustrating character to watch, and ultimately, Mrs. Robinson comes off as more sympathetic. She is the one who is truly lost and trapped. Benjamin still has his whole life ahead of him, once he finally decides what he's going to do with it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An Under-appreciated Classic!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    FilmMuscle
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I find it disappointing that the Graduate isn't one of those constantly-talked-about classics like The Godfather, Kramer vs. Kramer, Apocalypse Now, The Shawshank Redemption, etc. I had mixed expectations for the film since I heard, prior to viewing, some negative opinions and positive ones from individuals who'd recently watched it. Now, let's talk about why this film should be just as remembered of a classic as the others above. First of all and- in my opinion- most importantly, the film carries with it a highly intriguing and interesting story that keeps you entertained the entire way as the clever plot unravels. You're presented with this socially angsty twenty-year-old who's basically helpless, surrounded by intimidating people and frightening situations. He's a character that the audience can't help but love. For me, I could find myself relating to his personality quite a bit. I, too, attempt to stray away from great attention and prefer a much calmer and less crowded environment. The story, itself, keeps your attention because it's just strongly gripping insofar as this character finds himself in extremely awkward and threatening situations. Personally- like with the scene where Benjamin is awkwardly attempting to avoid suspicion while getting a hotel room- I recalled similar instances with myself where I was about to engage in something that could be regrettable and had to deal with suspicious or curious bystanders, family members, or whatnot. While we're still on it, the acting was unbelievably good, especially Dustin Hoffman's break-out performance as Benjamin. The way he portrayed a timid and awkward character surely blew away the moviegoers that night of its release. His timing and speech delivery, overall, creates an absolutely believable story about this fully realistic outcast. The way he would retreat under the pool whenever he felt vulnerable or faced his imposing parents definitely moved me because I could honestly understand him in any given predicament. At times, I feel like finding some peaceful and impenetrable spot to socially leave the world and obtain some time to breathe. The script of this picture is brilliant from the convincing dialogue to the intelligent build-up of relationships and their interconnections. For the moment, let's delve into the more technical side of The Graduate since its cinematography and editing is exceptional- excellent, might I say. The evolution of filmmaking over the decades from when Hollywood first stemmed truly and impressively proved itself in this movie. For example, there's a particular scene where Benjamin is "drifting" on the pool's air mattress, and he's interrupted by his irritating parents and the Robinsons themselves, and as they begin discussing his current uneventful life, the camera perfectly displays these incredibly condescending figures looking down at him with the sun shining so brightly that it seems to be blinding both the viewer and Benjamin as he's forced to look up at them. You sympathize with Benjamin because you feel their aggression and- again- condescending conversation about how he's not doing anything with his life, and I'm sure everyone's been in that sort of position, mentally or physically. Then, another shot shows Elaine as her confused face gets less and less blurry (indicating her progression towards fully understanding the mystery) until she finally realizes what's essentially transpiring between Benjamin and her own mother. In terms of editing, an instance showcases fast cutting to Mrs. Robinson's naked body as Benjamin attempts to ignore it but can't help his lust in a way. The film also smoothly and uniquely transitions to new settings without the audience even noticing at first as Benjamin exits the pool, walks to his room, and is suddenly found entering Mrs. Robinson's bed. Another strength of the camera-work is the noticeably lengthy shots where we witness entire conversations occurring in one single take or the scuba mask scene where a few minutes or so are filmed from a first-person perspective as Benjamin dives into his pool. In sum, the film seemed like a breath of fresh air that was affected by an unquestionably relatable protagonist that you felt for and his escape with the love of his life seemed utterly satisfying as well. Usually, happy endings done the way The Graduate did it come off as corny and clich&eacute;d, but your liking for the characters and their success overshadowed that aspect. So far, I've been loving all the films in class as this is yet another one I can't help but give high praise to.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not A Classic.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    AaronCapenBanner
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Mike Nichols directed this film about Ben Braddock, a confused young man trying to decide on his future in a society he can't understand, but instead becomes involved with the married mother of his reluctant girlfriend, and the various complications that ensue as a result. Dustin Hoffman leads a good cast, it has haunting songs by Simon & Garfunkel, is beloved by many of that generation, and even won Nichols an Academy Award for best director. So what's not to like? For a film that reacts negatively to the word "plastic", that's just how I feel about the characters and setting. Nothing about this film feels particularly real, certainly not the affair of Ben and Mrs. Robinson(Anne Bancroft) which not only isn't believable, it doesn't make sense, feels utterly manufactured and wrong. Katharine Ross as his girlfriend reacts to the news believably, but the ending will leave the viewer up in the air, since it, while dramatically staged, feels forced and unsatisfying. It just doesn't work for me.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    If anyone was born to play an awkward 21 year old...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    cleary-joshua
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    If anyone was born to play an awkward 21 year old deciding what to do with his life, it has to be 30 year old Dustin Hoffman, who steals this movie with his brilliant portrayal of Benjamin Braddock. It's a performance with humour and emotion all rolled into one. For example, Hoffman's performance when he first takes Mrs. Robinson home is hilarious, with his constant nervous stammering and occasional high-pitched squeaks. The final shot of Elaine and Benjamin has so much drama in both of their expressions, and you can tell how great the pair are as actors. They've just run away together, and she's already married. Are they completely happy? Not really, and both of their faces have a sort of "now what?" expression, leaving the audience thinking about whether it was the right decision. As for the story itself, it's comical without becoming too farcical, and has enough drama later on to keep the audience interested. It's also beautifully shot, with a lot of clever cutting and images, such as the fact that Benjamin is always being shot through other objects, like the hotel woodwork, or Mrs. Robinson's leg. The music too is great, and Simon and Garfunkel's songs, though some of them are used almost too much, manage to create just the right atmosphere for the film. The late Roger Ebert originally gave this film 4 stars, but thirty years later, dropped his score down to 3, something I'm not sure I've ever heard of a critic doing. He states in his later review that it's not a film that has stood the test of time, that modern audiences wouldn't find it as funny. I disagree with this, and managed to find humour in a lot of the film. However his main reason for doing so is the character of Benjamin, whom he calls an 'insufferable creep', and now I think about it, Ebert is kind of right. Perhaps the awkwardness does go a bit too far at points, and he is just a bit strange and horrible in taking Elaine to the strip club and stalking her for a long time. This detail aside, I still found it to be a hugely enjoyable film which left a lot to think about afterwards, as well as a lot of laughs, and it's worth watching if only for Hoffman's performance and delivery of that classic line: "Mrs. Robinson, you're trying to seduce me, aren't you."
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    It's Graduation Day! I think this movie is seducing me. You're trying to seduce me. Aren't you?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ironhorse_iv
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The movie has this great 1960's Hollywood New Wave feel to it. This is a coming of age movie that works for me. A lot of coming of age movies seem to try to make their character innocent, but they never actually are. They do a bunch of irresponsible stuff and at the end of the day a lot of people call them "innocent and lost", but it just feels like an excuse to sympathize for being an idiot. However I do sympathize for this character, Benjamin Braddock (Dustin Hoffman). It seemed like he was forced into a pool and not allowed to come back up. The theme of an innocent and confused youth who is exploited, misdirected, seduced and betrayed by a corrupt older generation was well understood by film audiences and captured the spirit of the times. One of the film's posters proclaimed the difficult coming-of-age for college graduate. Directed by Mike Nichols, the film is based on the 1963 novel The Graduate by Charles Webb. The movie opens to one of the best songs of the 1960's, Simon & Garfunkel - The Sound of Silence. This is one of the best songs I've ever listened to. I think the soundtrack pretty much made Simon & Garfunkel from nearly unknown folk singers, to legends of the music industry. You can also hear an earlier version of Mrs. Robinson in the movie. The song as it appears in the film is different from the familiar hit single version, as only the chorus of the song appears late in the film and with slightly different lyrics. It was only later on that Paul Simon and Art Garfunkel re-recorded the song by employing additional lyrics to form the hit single. It's kinda funny that the original song was call 'Mrs. Roosevelt'. It would really be funny to see Eleanor Roosevelt have an affair with a younger man. The Sound of Silence song work for the film as it really fit in with the plot regarding the lack of communication between the controlling parents and the young adults. Anyways, Benjamin Braddock has just arrive back home, after years in College. Dustin Hoffman played the part of the awkward post-graduate student perfectly. I can't see Mike Nichols first choice, Robert Redford in this role. Dustin is kind of awkward that works, he isn't to an abnormal extent creep, he more just describes the entire situation to the woman. Unsure of himself, by being uncomfortable and anxious, and force to hear others decide for him what he will do with his future. Benjamin Braddock soon find himself, seduce by an older woman, Mrs. Robinson (Anne Bancroft) and find himself tempt into an affair. Anne Bancroft is a cougar on the prowl, really to pounce on her prey. She was really pretty in the room. Even though her character is sympathetic, it doesn't change the fact that her character is a vindictive sexual predator. Just the line 'You've known me nearly all your life." Is just disturbing. Mrs. Robinson wanting to bang a kid she watched grow up? That's gross, and just a step below Woody Allen marrying his stepdaughter. She was marry too, so not only is she wanting to date a younger man, she watch when he was kid, but she's also cheating on her husband. It is pure flesh, but she is nice about it. It is just natural, pragmatic and not that romantic-idealistic. She's still the Queen of all Milfs. Her personal life isn't the only thing she's opening. Some people might hate the fact, that the two main characters are two of the most shallow, childish characters. Mrs. Robinson can be especially hateful without any specific motivation, while Benjamin is bit spineless. I do love Dustin Hoffman in the role, but he was way too old for this part. He was playing a 20 year old, and he himself was 30 at the time. Also Anne Bancroft was only 35 during the time of filming. It also kinda funny that the actress Katharine Ross who played Anne Bancroft's daughter Elaine was only 8 years younger than her 35 and 27, miscasting. Katherine Ross looks lovely as Elaine, but she's barely one-dimensional and looks like a girl who would never go for a guy like Dustin Hoffman in a million years. She only went with him, because of her over controlling parents. Anyways, Benjamin soon fall in love with Elaine, and is in a dilemma. Should be continue to live with people telling what to do with his life like Mrs. Robinson or should he set his own future with a girl like Elaine? Find out, by watching it. The ending is up to question, if these two would work out. It leaves a deep interpretation of risky love. This is a classic film: tightly written, intelligent, funny, wonderfully acted, with a great climax with the church, so to speak. You will get seduce into watching the film by how brilliant it is.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of the most overvalued films of all times
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Turin_Horse
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The great and classical soundtrack by Simon & Garfunkel, a group of good actors and one of the most famous scenes in cinema history with Anne Bancroft and Dustin Hoffman as protagonists cannot make up a poor, even lame plot, an incoherent and silly story full of holes and a dull direction and editing. One wonders how such a film could make its way through time to still be considered a "classic" and seemingly appreciated by a high number of people; maybe, for people in the sixties this film meant something, or touched something inside them or whatever, but nowadays The Graduate should long have been put in the bag of dated unworthy-to-watch films. The final scenes with Benjamin trying to prevent the wedding of his sweetheart and taking her with him are just shameful!. There are some very good films from the sixties, try Midnight Cowboy for instance, but skip this over-overvalued film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Creative, compelling & classic
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    stephparsons
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    You've gotta love The Graduate.&nbsp; Even after 44 years, it's still relevant, highly watchable, funny, a titchy bit avant-garde, and boasts a top notch, flawless script.&nbsp; Dustin Hoffman as Ben does a bang up job playing the hapless graduate who desperately wants to escape his boring, careerist fate (as predetermined by&nbsp; his parents and society at large).&nbsp; He exudes 'sullen-youth-ness', boredom-with-life, naivet&eacute;, awkwardness and an (almost) 'aspergers' style of speech which are amusing and poignant.&nbsp; Despite all the drama that unfolds; the seduction followed by the 'coming-of-age' sex with an older woman, the falling in love with a fresh, vibrant young woman, The Graduate is, ultimately, a film about ennui; that dull, thudding, inexorable grind we face upon leaving school and being forced to 'decide what to do' for the rest of our sad, pathetic , predictable lives.&nbsp; Career paths being far more restrictive in the '60s,&nbsp; the sense of doom and pointlessness that Ben feels is exacerbated and he portrays it so very well.&nbsp;&nbsp; The friend of his parents who says, "I have one word for you Ben...plastics", sums up the soulless, futile, and arid future that Ben fears is his destiny. &nbsp;The Graduate experiments successfully with some creative cinematography including unusual camera angles, and interesting switches from one milieu to another e.g. Ben jumping into the swimming pool but ending up on the bed with Mrs Robinson.&nbsp;&nbsp; The swimming pool scene where Ben must walk under water in his birthday present - an old fashioned diving suit- is especially memorable and provides a convincing metaphor for the restrictiveness, loneliness and entrapment that he fears is to be his fate.&nbsp; There is nothing 'awkward' or dated about this classic film, it holds one's attention from start to finish.&nbsp; The ending steers clear of that typical 'happily ever after' Hollywood schmaltz&nbsp; and, in subtle tones presents us with 'ennui in a nutshell' as Ben and Elaine exchange smiles, then worried looks, and then expressions devoid of all emotion.&nbsp; There is nothing I would change about The Graduate, it's a classic and always will be.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Loved it!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    oliviadoerrer17
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Personally thought this particular film was great! I have heard many things about it's wonderful storyline and acting, I definitely had high expectations going into the film and it exceeded those. I always love a movie that is scandalous, and makes you wonder every second if someone is going to get caught. Dustin Hoffman really took on his role and made it believable to his shy nervous personality. He managed to make most scenes awkward which made it very funny. My personal favorite was the scene where Mrs Robinson tried to seduce him, you could tell by his facial expression and sweat he was extremely nervous and uncomfortable. The shots of Mrs Robinson's nude body then to Benjamin's face then back to her body and so on really was comical. The storyline did end up becoming interesting and complicated due to obvious reasons which overall added to the film. I liked the fact that Benjamin never gave up in what he wanted and fought to the end.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Hysterical
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    RoseXGold
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I loved this movie. It was the perfect blend of comedy, drama,love and action. The overall plot was very intriguing. I feel like everyone has been in the main characters shoes before( not knowing exactly what you want to do with your life). The theme was very relate-able. I feel as though everyone had a specific character that they could some how relate to. The music in this film was something that stood out to me. It was a bit more modern. I adored the fact that they not only made this movie a drama. But they also fit a lot of comedy into the film. I feel as though Dustin Hoffman played the role of a personality actor. I felt like I've seen the same persona played in other films he has starred in as well.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Graduate
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    stephypoo912
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I like this film. Even after seeing it three times! Seeing it every time, I have different feelings towards this film. Any way, i still end up liking it and loving the ending. It is a film that is predictable in some ways, but in others it definitely isn't. The whole movie, in itself is great. The editing is a great way to start the break-down. One of my favorite shots is the triple take in the beginning half of the movie. Another editing part that ALWAYS catches my eye is the pool shot then the hotel shot. The way it merges as one scene into the next is NOTHING like I have ever seen before. That definitely kept me enticed. The story line as well kept me watching it. The way it ended made me think, "Could there possibly be another way they could have found each other?" Hmm...
   </conteudo>
  </review>
 </reviews>
</filme>
