<filme>
 <id>
  199
 </id>
 <imdburl>
  http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0050212
 </imdburl>
 <ano>
  1957
 </ano>
 <titulo>
  A Ponte do Rio Kwai
 </titulo>
 <rating>
  8.3
 </rating>
 <sinopse>
  After settling his differences with a Japanese PoW camp commander, a British colonel co-operates to oversee his men's construction of a railway bridge for their captors - while oblivious to a plan by the Allies to destroy it.
 </sinopse>
 <storyline>
  The film deals with the situation of British prisoners of war during World War II who are ordered to build a bridge to accommodate the Burma-Siam railway. Their instinct is to sabotage the bridge but, under the leadership of Colonel Nicholson, they are persuaded that the bridge should be constructed as a symbol of British morale, spirit and dignity in adverse circumstances. At first, the prisoners admire Nicholson when he bravely endures torture rather than compromise his principles for the benefit of the Japanese commandant Saito. He is an honorable but arrogant man, who is slowly revealed to be a deluded obsessive. He convinces himself that the bridge is a monument to British character, but actually is a monument to himself, and his insistence on its construction becomes a subtle form of collaboration with the enemy. Unknown to him, the Allies have sent a mission into the jungle, led by Warden and an American, Shears, to blow up the bridge.
 </storyline>
 <generos>
  <genero>
   Adventure
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Drama
  </genero>
  <genero>
   War
  </genero>
 </generos>
 <keywords>
  <keyword>
   bridge
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   jungle
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   construction
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   torture
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   river
  </keyword>
 </keywords>
 <diretores>
  <diretor>
   David Lean
  </diretor>
 </diretores>
 <escritores>
  <escritor>
   Michael Wilson
  </escritor>
  <escritor>
   Carl Foreman
  </escritor>
 </escritores>
 <atores>
  <ator>
   William Holden
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Alec Guinness
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Jack Hawkins
  </ator>
 </atores>
 <reviews>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I hate the British! You are defeated but you have no shame. You are stubborn but you have no pride. You endure but you have no courage. I hate the British!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Ben Larson
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    What could one possibly add to the accolades this film has had heaped upon it. The fact that it may not be historically accurate is of no consequence, as it was made for the theater, not the History Channel. David Lean's master piece showing the madness of war stands the test of time. It swept the Oscars in 1958, winning Best Picture, Best Director for Lean, Best Actor for Alec Guinness in the role that defines him, and a Best Supporting Actor nomination for Sessue Hayakawa. It also took the awards for Writing. Music, Editing and Cinematography. Guinness was a perfect example of British pride. If you are going to do a job, then do it right. In that, he managed to take care of his men at the same time. William Holden was a perfect example of a soldier who just wanted to go home, as I am sure was the feeling of most. He recognized the madness of war long before the good doctor. This is a film that you can watch year after year and never get tired of it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Utter trash.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Blueghost
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    My uncle lived through the Bataan march, and was a POW in a Japanese labor camp. According to his daughter the one comment he made about this movie was as follows; "*Explicative*, we never had it that good!" He then reportedly stormed out of the TV room. You know, I have to say that I saw this film a couple times as a kid, and I never thought much of it. Initially I was going to title my review "Egomania 3" because that's kind of what we have here. The "drama" between the leads is manufactured in the extreme. The squaring off between Guiness and Mifune puts a grim smirk (if you could call it that) on this viewer's face. The film just doesn't ring true as to what happened to American, British, Australian, New Zealander and even French or Dutch POWs taken by the Japanese. The Imperial Japanese military didn't have the wanton industrial slaughter mechanism of the Nazi regime in Europe, but instead had the "work them until they're dead" ethic derived partially from Bushido, the code of the samurai. The acting was over the top. The story was so detached from reality as to be insulting, and by that I don't just mean my family's anecdote, but the interviews with survivors who went through that atrocity tell a very different and tragic story. During the Bataan march itself Japanese soldiers routinely shot anyone who looked weak or didn't look like they could make it, or rested. Then, once they got to the camps, it was hell baking in corrugated iron huts, laboring in hot and disease infested regions. And that's just for starters; the treatment, the food, the sheer and utter abuse; NONE of that is in this film. This film is about Hollywood parading its stars for what some idiot asinine producer thought would be a good patriotic film showing Americans and British being defiant in the face of the odds. Wrong. Look, I love Japanese culture. I love the food, I love the movies, I love the clean and polite society, and the people themselves, and I certainly don't hold any grudges whatsoever. In fact I want to retire there. And, I'm not the only one. Therefore, why not make a movie that shows the REAL EXPERIENCE? I can't answer that, but what I do know is that this piece of cinematic trash is just another notch in a southern Californian metroplex film industry that seems to never get anything write when it comes to history. What's even more insulting is that people have voted it so high as a quality film. Between the Russians not getting credit for their massive effort in what they call "the Great Patriotic War" and people like my family who were there when it happened, it's a wonder the entire film industry hasn't been run out of town and forced to setup shop in Mexico. Respectably shot, egotistical acting, poor SFX (notably the miniature), and a script that is just so idiotic I can't believe anyone green-lit this thing, it's a film that's definitely got some massive flaws. If you need to see a WW2 film about the Pacific Theatre, then check out Tora Tora Tora (Tiger Tiger Tiger). See this movie once, then do your brain a favor and pick up a book on the subject to learn what REALLY happened.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Ultimate Test of Survival-with some real life facts
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Admiraljames11
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie is the extremely accurate rendition of the incredible heroics of the brave men in Japanese prison camps that were made to build railroads. Many of these men after surviving battle on ships, ship sinkings, environmental and weather elements, were then subjected to cruel and inhuman treatment of Japanese soldiers. This movie is an accurate portrayal of these conditions with a few exceptions: (1) They did not whistle when entering the camp(although they did march in military formation, even when captured). (2) In the movie, Cdr. Shears tells the story of how he was on the USS Houston at the time she was sunk ,and how he and a Commander was separated from everyone else and drifted to the other side of the island. The commander died and he took his rank...etc. In real life, there was a USS Houston that was sunk and there was a Commander Maer that did drift to the other side of the island with a Seaman Elam ,which is consistent with Cdr. Shears story of the Houston sinking. However, both Cdr. Maer and Seaman Elam survived and were captured.(3) Real conditions of the prison camps were far more deplorable than depicted ,as well as the work details. (Men that couldn't walk were put on stretchers and given a hammer to bust up rock etc). (4) There were more American POWS than depicted in the movie, (the British often referred to the Americans as "Rabble"). and (5) They did not blow up the Bridge in the end and Col Nicholson certainly didn't turn on his own people to attempt to keep the bridge from blowing up. Still an awesome movie that is a must see.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A rather odd story,but entertaining
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    SmileysWorld
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I thoroughly enjoy this film,though I find it to be a rather odd story.Looking at it realistically,I find it hard to believe that a British commander,or any other commander,would give in to the will of the enemy under any circumstances,but I realize that even films based on true events can never be told 100% accurately,so I have no problem seeing as a great fictionalized account of true events.All the performances were excellent,particularly those of Alec Guiness and Bill Holden.If you are looking for a different type of war story,you have a winner in this one,but I would advise not reading up on how things really happened on The River Kwaiuntil after viewing it.It may make the film a disappointment to you.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A David Lean War Movie !
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Umar Mansoor Bajwa (umar_mansoor@yahoo.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The story is well laden with excitement, thrill and adventure. The characterization of different roles is uniquely perfect. The intrinsic conflicts, valor and stoic fortitude displayed by Col. Nicholson played by Alec Guinness is indeed commendable. Needless to mention is the daredevil nature of the commando action steered by a British Major to blow the bridge, laboriously built by another British Colonel is a striking coincidence. However, tragedy awaited Shears (William Holden) the US Navy Officer who had earlier miraculously escaped from the POW camp run by an intransigent Col. Saitu. Above all is the magnificent direction of Sir David Lean, who has captured marvelous locations for filming the army offices and bungalows situated at uniquely picturesque spots. It requires a keen eye to identify the meticulous details of the sets, like the revolving pedestal fan and wartime furniture, when Major Warden convinces Shears to join the death defying plot. The screenplay is a feast for the eyes. The dialogues and script goes hand in hand with the majestic flow of thrill in this commando mission movie. A must see for all war movie buffs.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Stretch Too Far
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    robinmcis966
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/9/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Certainly 'The Bridge on the River Kwai' has a gorgeous and epic sweep. If viewers simply want an entertaining evening, just cue it up and enjoy. For that matter, if you want encouragement, The AFI 100 once placed 'The Bridge' as the 13th best film ever and it has garnered more 4 of 4 and 5 of 5 star reviews than can be counted. However, The AFI now places the Film 37th and perhaps it is past due for re-vision. Although larger problems develop more slowly, it is a bad sign when there are not one, but two, obvious editing problems before the end of the credits! We are right behind the mounted machine gun on a train. The view is of the at least 2 carloads of wood for fuel and the engine. But now we see the same view with no fuel cars, OR EVEN THE ENGINE. Where did they go? In the same scene, the train now stops as the rail ends amidst about 15 workers. But now the dramatic score kicks in and there suddenly are several dozen workers on the rail line. In a low-budget film, this could be overlooked. But this is a major production that won an Oscar....for best direction AND editing! Moving on to the more serious issues, we are told that the British Commander (Alec Guinness) has been ordered to surrender, along with over 100 men and about a dozen officers. No explanation is offered for this. Really? He was just 'ordered to surrender'? According to historical estimates, over 100,000 men died building this railroad. For that matter, although there are ample references to men dying in this prison camp, all the men who have already been imprisoned there, even those in the infirmary, look well-fed, some even in 'beef-cake' condition. Again, this sort of over-sight would be fine for a 2nd rate 'action-genre' flick. It's Bill Holden-he's tanned, buff, and sweaty. Enough said? The central problem with 'The Bridge on the River Kwai' has at least been occasionally mentioned. Guinness' Commander not only helps the Japanese build a crucial bridge in their supply line, he goes to great lengths to make sure the bridge will hold and be finished on time. This to prove superior British logistics and character. Along the way, he is warned of the possibly treasonous nature of his collaboration, and yet he continues on without a doubt. Nothing is made of this...he just comes across as 'funny that way'. However, as far as I know, it has not been pointed out that all of his men and his officers would therefore have had to join him in this inexplicable lapse. This despite what appears to be a very democratic officers meeting and over two months time to reflect on the matter. Treason?...well...no problem! What a credulous bunch of guys. And more to the point, what a credulous bunch of reviewers have failed to notice this. Clearly the original 1957 release of 'The Bridge on the River Kwai' struck a cord. To portray an American, (British in the book), played by William Holden, as cynically detached from the war effort and yet ultimately humane was not new. Several Bogart films prepared audiences for this. But to sum it all up as 'Madness', this before Catch-22 and Mash, was ahead of it's time. This progressive spirit, some great cinematography, and a rousing combination of star-power and studio support make for an entertaining evening. But as a 'Closely Watched Film', it is almost as much train-wreck as classic.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    All you need is love.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    frizb
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/7/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Real Billy Shears Bridge on the River Kwai was written by a French author, Pierre Boulle. In the movie William Holden plays Commander Shears, an American captured when his ship the USS Houston is sunk. He is a POW in a camp full of British sailors and Australians and does his best to avoid any really hard work by becoming a grave digger. But then Alec Guinnes (Obi Wan Kenobi) shows up and is the senior officer, Lt Colonel Nicholson. He refuses to let any of the officers do manual labor, so Shears says that Nicholson is a maniac and makes an escape. Then Nicholson says that the Japanese camp commander is mad. When Shears reaches a British base in Ceylon it turns out that he is not an officer. He is just a sailor named Shears impersonating an officer in order to get better treatment. After he escaped he decided to continue playing an officer and was going to say that being lost in the jungle drove him mad. But the British Force 316, commandos, wanted Shears to lead them back to the POW camp so they could blow up the bridge that the prisoners were building. They made Shears a simulated major. Ian Fleming was the head of a force of British Commandoes in France called Force 54, along with "Q" and "U" and Bertrand, and the real James Bond, who Fleming once met according to his biographer. Shears, also called "Number One", gets to the bridge but not before telling the Professor he is as crazy as Nicholson. Nicholson tries to stop them from destroying the bridge. Lt Joyce kills a few Japanese soldiers and Nicholson fights with Lt Joyce. The Professor starts a mortar barrage, and Shears swims across the river to set off the explosives. Just as Shears reaches Nicholson they recognize each other, and Nicholson realizes that he is himself mad. Shears is killed by rifle fire and the mortar kills Nicholson who falls on the detonator and the bridge is destroyed. The British doctor stands on the riverbank and says everyone is mad. But earlier in the movie Shears is sitting on a Ceylon beach with a blonde nurse and a thermos of martinis. He complains jokingly about how the nurse gives him pills, powders, shots, thermometers and all he really needs is love. The nurse says "Yes that is true. All you really need is love!"
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    David Lean's First Best Picture Winner Is One Of The Greatest!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Humphrey Fish
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/5/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    After settling his differences with a Japanese PoW camp commander, a British colonel co-operates to oversee his men's construction of a railway bridge for their captors - while oblivious to a plan by the Allies to destroy it. Speaking as someone who has seen a wide variety of movies, this movie is awesome, totally and completely awesome! The Bridge On The River Kwai is a milestone in the history of film, the results are groundbreaking and breathtaking. I watched this on TCM as part of a Memorial Day celebration, and when I watched it, I was astonished by what I had seen. I had seen one of the greatest movies of all time, a movie that is directed by a master of epic films, the great British film director, David Lean. David Lean's first Best Picture winner is one of the greatest, and only a few years after this movie, he would direct his second Best Picture Winner, Lawrence Of Arabia, and three years after that, he would direct another great movie, Doctor Zhivago. Like Martin Scorsese, David Lean was a man who could do no wrong, I repeat, absolutely no wrong. This film also won numerous Academy Awards, the biggest ones being Best Picture, Best Director, and Best Actor. Alec Guinness won the Academy Award for Best Actor for his role as Col. Nicholson. And I can say that that win was a win that was well deserved, as he was great in this movie! William Holden also gives a good performance as the secondary protagonist, Shears. By the way, this movie was written by Carl Foreman and Michael Wilson, but they had to keep a low profile because a few years earlier, they had been accused of being Communists and they ended up getting blacklisted, much to their misfortune. David Lean's direction is masterful, it's the direction of a master film director. And as proof of that, he won the Academy Award For Best Director, and he would repeat that when he made Lawrence Of Arabia. David Lean was another one of those directors who if he had never existed, the movie industry would be a whole lot different. So all in all, The Bridge On The River Kwai is another movie that I can say is one of the greatest movies that I have ever seen. When I watched it, I was thrilled with it, every minute of it, from the very minute that it began to the very minute that it ended, I was absolutely impressed with every last second of it! And I guess that you know what this means, this means that you too are going to watch to watch this remarkably fabulous movie, because it's simply incredible, when you watch it, you will say that it is one of the greatest movies that you have ever seen, you will say that it deserved all of the Academy Awards that it won! Bravo to the remarkable David Lean for making a movie that I totally and completely loved! So if you haven't seen this movie, then take the time to watch it, because you will love it, you will say that it's one of the greatest movies you've ever seen! 10/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A World War II Odyssey
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Nick-leonardi
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/5/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    POW English soldiers are instructed by their rulers, the Japanese, to build a bridge. At the same time, a group of free Englishmen plan to destroy the bridge as soon as it's done. Majestic triumph at the Oscars (it won seven Academy Awards), as well as great commercial success, the film proves how David Lean brings a sense of epic and grandiose in everything he touches, inserting also themes like the meaning and weight of law, honor, pride, duty, and of course, the futility of war. Engaging even with a concept that might indicate otherwise (the construction of a bridge), the film boasts memorable performances by Alec Guinness and William Holden that compliment even more the importance of this British film. Based on the novel by Pierre Boulle.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The madness of war
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Christopher Reynolds
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/3/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Looking at this movie as a whole, it works brilliantly in conveying its theme of the madness of war, and how it drives good men to do bad things. Great direction, acting across the board, and cinematography all add a lot to the movie. **** SPOILERS ***** As I was watching the movie, for the first hour I felt increasingly annoyed by Col. Nicholson's "play by the rules and do what you're told" philosophy. Then as the movie went on, and we follow the British plan to blow up the bridge, I realised that this was how the movie wanted me to feel, and then the finale pulled off a brilliant reversal, and a sort of redemption for Nicholson. Standout scenes are the killing of the Japanese soldiers while clouds of bats whirl over the jungle, and, of course, the incredibly tense and powerful finale.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I hate the British! You are defeated but you have no shame. You are stubborn but you have no pride. You endure but you have no courage. I hate the British!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Ben Larson
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    What could one possibly add to the accolades this film has had heaped upon it. The fact that it may not be historically accurate is of no consequence, as it was made for the theater, not the History Channel. David Lean's master piece showing the madness of war stands the test of time. It swept the Oscars in 1958, winning Best Picture, Best Director for Lean, Best Actor for Alec Guinness in the role that defines him, and a Best Supporting Actor nomination for Sessue Hayakawa. It also took the awards for Writing. Music, Editing and Cinematography. Guinness was a perfect example of British pride. If you are going to do a job, then do it right. In that, he managed to take care of his men at the same time. William Holden was a perfect example of a soldier who just wanted to go home, as I am sure was the feeling of most. He recognized the madness of war long before the good doctor. This is a film that you can watch year after year and never get tired of it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Utter trash.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Blueghost
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    My uncle lived through the Bataan march, and was a POW in a Japanese labor camp. According to his daughter the one comment he made about this movie was as follows; "*Explicative*, we never had it that good!" He then reportedly stormed out of the TV room. You know, I have to say that I saw this film a couple times as a kid, and I never thought much of it. Initially I was going to title my review "Egomania 3" because that's kind of what we have here. The "drama" between the leads is manufactured in the extreme. The squaring off between Guiness and Mifune puts a grim smirk (if you could call it that) on this viewer's face. The film just doesn't ring true as to what happened to American, British, Australian, New Zealander and even French or Dutch POWs taken by the Japanese. The Imperial Japanese military didn't have the wanton industrial slaughter mechanism of the Nazi regime in Europe, but instead had the "work them until they're dead" ethic derived partially from Bushido, the code of the samurai. The acting was over the top. The story was so detached from reality as to be insulting, and by that I don't just mean my family's anecdote, but the interviews with survivors who went through that atrocity tell a very different and tragic story. During the Bataan march itself Japanese soldiers routinely shot anyone who looked weak or didn't look like they could make it, or rested. Then, once they got to the camps, it was hell baking in corrugated iron huts, laboring in hot and disease infested regions. And that's just for starters; the treatment, the food, the sheer and utter abuse; NONE of that is in this film. This film is about Hollywood parading its stars for what some idiot asinine producer thought would be a good patriotic film showing Americans and British being defiant in the face of the odds. Wrong. Look, I love Japanese culture. I love the food, I love the movies, I love the clean and polite society, and the people themselves, and I certainly don't hold any grudges whatsoever. In fact I want to retire there. And, I'm not the only one. Therefore, why not make a movie that shows the REAL EXPERIENCE? I can't answer that, but what I do know is that this piece of cinematic trash is just another notch in a southern Californian metroplex film industry that seems to never get anything write when it comes to history. What's even more insulting is that people have voted it so high as a quality film. Between the Russians not getting credit for their massive effort in what they call "the Great Patriotic War" and people like my family who were there when it happened, it's a wonder the entire film industry hasn't been run out of town and forced to setup shop in Mexico. Respectably shot, egotistical acting, poor SFX (notably the miniature), and a script that is just so idiotic I can't believe anyone green-lit this thing, it's a film that's definitely got some massive flaws. If you need to see a WW2 film about the Pacific Theatre, then check out Tora Tora Tora (Tiger Tiger Tiger). See this movie once, then do your brain a favor and pick up a book on the subject to learn what REALLY happened.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Ultimate Test of Survival-with some real life facts
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Admiraljames11
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie is the extremely accurate rendition of the incredible heroics of the brave men in Japanese prison camps that were made to build railroads. Many of these men after surviving battle on ships, ship sinkings, environmental and weather elements, were then subjected to cruel and inhuman treatment of Japanese soldiers. This movie is an accurate portrayal of these conditions with a few exceptions: (1) They did not whistle when entering the camp(although they did march in military formation, even when captured). (2) In the movie, Cdr. Shears tells the story of how he was on the USS Houston at the time she was sunk ,and how he and a Commander was separated from everyone else and drifted to the other side of the island. The commander died and he took his rank...etc. In real life, there was a USS Houston that was sunk and there was a Commander Maer that did drift to the other side of the island with a Seaman Elam ,which is consistent with Cdr. Shears story of the Houston sinking. However, both Cdr. Maer and Seaman Elam survived and were captured.(3) Real conditions of the prison camps were far more deplorable than depicted ,as well as the work details. (Men that couldn't walk were put on stretchers and given a hammer to bust up rock etc). (4) There were more American POWS than depicted in the movie, (the British often referred to the Americans as "Rabble"). and (5) They did not blow up the Bridge in the end and Col Nicholson certainly didn't turn on his own people to attempt to keep the bridge from blowing up. Still an awesome movie that is a must see.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A rather odd story,but entertaining
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    SmileysWorld
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I thoroughly enjoy this film,though I find it to be a rather odd story.Looking at it realistically,I find it hard to believe that a British commander,or any other commander,would give in to the will of the enemy under any circumstances,but I realize that even films based on true events can never be told 100% accurately,so I have no problem seeing as a great fictionalized account of true events.All the performances were excellent,particularly those of Alec Guiness and Bill Holden.If you are looking for a different type of war story,you have a winner in this one,but I would advise not reading up on how things really happened on The River Kwaiuntil after viewing it.It may make the film a disappointment to you.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A David Lean War Movie !
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Umar Mansoor Bajwa (umar_mansoor@yahoo.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The story is well laden with excitement, thrill and adventure. The characterization of different roles is uniquely perfect. The intrinsic conflicts, valor and stoic fortitude displayed by Col. Nicholson played by Alec Guinness is indeed commendable. Needless to mention is the daredevil nature of the commando action steered by a British Major to blow the bridge, laboriously built by another British Colonel is a striking coincidence. However, tragedy awaited Shears (William Holden) the US Navy Officer who had earlier miraculously escaped from the POW camp run by an intransigent Col. Saitu. Above all is the magnificent direction of Sir David Lean, who has captured marvelous locations for filming the army offices and bungalows situated at uniquely picturesque spots. It requires a keen eye to identify the meticulous details of the sets, like the revolving pedestal fan and wartime furniture, when Major Warden convinces Shears to join the death defying plot. The screenplay is a feast for the eyes. The dialogues and script goes hand in hand with the majestic flow of thrill in this commando mission movie. A must see for all war movie buffs.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Stretch Too Far
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    robinmcis966
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/9/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Certainly 'The Bridge on the River Kwai' has a gorgeous and epic sweep. If viewers simply want an entertaining evening, just cue it up and enjoy. For that matter, if you want encouragement, The AFI 100 once placed 'The Bridge' as the 13th best film ever and it has garnered more 4 of 4 and 5 of 5 star reviews than can be counted. However, The AFI now places the Film 37th and perhaps it is past due for re-vision. Although larger problems develop more slowly, it is a bad sign when there are not one, but two, obvious editing problems before the end of the credits! We are right behind the mounted machine gun on a train. The view is of the at least 2 carloads of wood for fuel and the engine. But now we see the same view with no fuel cars, OR EVEN THE ENGINE. Where did they go? In the same scene, the train now stops as the rail ends amidst about 15 workers. But now the dramatic score kicks in and there suddenly are several dozen workers on the rail line. In a low-budget film, this could be overlooked. But this is a major production that won an Oscar....for best direction AND editing! Moving on to the more serious issues, we are told that the British Commander (Alec Guinness) has been ordered to surrender, along with over 100 men and about a dozen officers. No explanation is offered for this. Really? He was just 'ordered to surrender'? According to historical estimates, over 100,000 men died building this railroad. For that matter, although there are ample references to men dying in this prison camp, all the men who have already been imprisoned there, even those in the infirmary, look well-fed, some even in 'beef-cake' condition. Again, this sort of over-sight would be fine for a 2nd rate 'action-genre' flick. It's Bill Holden-he's tanned, buff, and sweaty. Enough said? The central problem with 'The Bridge on the River Kwai' has at least been occasionally mentioned. Guinness' Commander not only helps the Japanese build a crucial bridge in their supply line, he goes to great lengths to make sure the bridge will hold and be finished on time. This to prove superior British logistics and character. Along the way, he is warned of the possibly treasonous nature of his collaboration, and yet he continues on without a doubt. Nothing is made of this...he just comes across as 'funny that way'. However, as far as I know, it has not been pointed out that all of his men and his officers would therefore have had to join him in this inexplicable lapse. This despite what appears to be a very democratic officers meeting and over two months time to reflect on the matter. Treason?...well...no problem! What a credulous bunch of guys. And more to the point, what a credulous bunch of reviewers have failed to notice this. Clearly the original 1957 release of 'The Bridge on the River Kwai' struck a cord. To portray an American, (British in the book), played by William Holden, as cynically detached from the war effort and yet ultimately humane was not new. Several Bogart films prepared audiences for this. But to sum it all up as 'Madness', this before Catch-22 and Mash, was ahead of it's time. This progressive spirit, some great cinematography, and a rousing combination of star-power and studio support make for an entertaining evening. But as a 'Closely Watched Film', it is almost as much train-wreck as classic.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    All you need is love.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    frizb
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/7/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Real Billy Shears Bridge on the River Kwai was written by a French author, Pierre Boulle. In the movie William Holden plays Commander Shears, an American captured when his ship the USS Houston is sunk. He is a POW in a camp full of British sailors and Australians and does his best to avoid any really hard work by becoming a grave digger. But then Alec Guinnes (Obi Wan Kenobi) shows up and is the senior officer, Lt Colonel Nicholson. He refuses to let any of the officers do manual labor, so Shears says that Nicholson is a maniac and makes an escape. Then Nicholson says that the Japanese camp commander is mad. When Shears reaches a British base in Ceylon it turns out that he is not an officer. He is just a sailor named Shears impersonating an officer in order to get better treatment. After he escaped he decided to continue playing an officer and was going to say that being lost in the jungle drove him mad. But the British Force 316, commandos, wanted Shears to lead them back to the POW camp so they could blow up the bridge that the prisoners were building. They made Shears a simulated major. Ian Fleming was the head of a force of British Commandoes in France called Force 54, along with "Q" and "U" and Bertrand, and the real James Bond, who Fleming once met according to his biographer. Shears, also called "Number One", gets to the bridge but not before telling the Professor he is as crazy as Nicholson. Nicholson tries to stop them from destroying the bridge. Lt Joyce kills a few Japanese soldiers and Nicholson fights with Lt Joyce. The Professor starts a mortar barrage, and Shears swims across the river to set off the explosives. Just as Shears reaches Nicholson they recognize each other, and Nicholson realizes that he is himself mad. Shears is killed by rifle fire and the mortar kills Nicholson who falls on the detonator and the bridge is destroyed. The British doctor stands on the riverbank and says everyone is mad. But earlier in the movie Shears is sitting on a Ceylon beach with a blonde nurse and a thermos of martinis. He complains jokingly about how the nurse gives him pills, powders, shots, thermometers and all he really needs is love. The nurse says "Yes that is true. All you really need is love!"
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    David Lean's First Best Picture Winner Is One Of The Greatest!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Humphrey Fish
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/5/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    After settling his differences with a Japanese PoW camp commander, a British colonel co-operates to oversee his men's construction of a railway bridge for their captors - while oblivious to a plan by the Allies to destroy it. Speaking as someone who has seen a wide variety of movies, this movie is awesome, totally and completely awesome! The Bridge On The River Kwai is a milestone in the history of film, the results are groundbreaking and breathtaking. I watched this on TCM as part of a Memorial Day celebration, and when I watched it, I was astonished by what I had seen. I had seen one of the greatest movies of all time, a movie that is directed by a master of epic films, the great British film director, David Lean. David Lean's first Best Picture winner is one of the greatest, and only a few years after this movie, he would direct his second Best Picture Winner, Lawrence Of Arabia, and three years after that, he would direct another great movie, Doctor Zhivago. Like Martin Scorsese, David Lean was a man who could do no wrong, I repeat, absolutely no wrong. This film also won numerous Academy Awards, the biggest ones being Best Picture, Best Director, and Best Actor. Alec Guinness won the Academy Award for Best Actor for his role as Col. Nicholson. And I can say that that win was a win that was well deserved, as he was great in this movie! William Holden also gives a good performance as the secondary protagonist, Shears. By the way, this movie was written by Carl Foreman and Michael Wilson, but they had to keep a low profile because a few years earlier, they had been accused of being Communists and they ended up getting blacklisted, much to their misfortune. David Lean's direction is masterful, it's the direction of a master film director. And as proof of that, he won the Academy Award For Best Director, and he would repeat that when he made Lawrence Of Arabia. David Lean was another one of those directors who if he had never existed, the movie industry would be a whole lot different. So all in all, The Bridge On The River Kwai is another movie that I can say is one of the greatest movies that I have ever seen. When I watched it, I was thrilled with it, every minute of it, from the very minute that it began to the very minute that it ended, I was absolutely impressed with every last second of it! And I guess that you know what this means, this means that you too are going to watch to watch this remarkably fabulous movie, because it's simply incredible, when you watch it, you will say that it is one of the greatest movies that you have ever seen, you will say that it deserved all of the Academy Awards that it won! Bravo to the remarkable David Lean for making a movie that I totally and completely loved! So if you haven't seen this movie, then take the time to watch it, because you will love it, you will say that it's one of the greatest movies you've ever seen! 10/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A World War II Odyssey
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Nick-leonardi
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/5/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    POW English soldiers are instructed by their rulers, the Japanese, to build a bridge. At the same time, a group of free Englishmen plan to destroy the bridge as soon as it's done. Majestic triumph at the Oscars (it won seven Academy Awards), as well as great commercial success, the film proves how David Lean brings a sense of epic and grandiose in everything he touches, inserting also themes like the meaning and weight of law, honor, pride, duty, and of course, the futility of war. Engaging even with a concept that might indicate otherwise (the construction of a bridge), the film boasts memorable performances by Alec Guinness and William Holden that compliment even more the importance of this British film. Based on the novel by Pierre Boulle.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The madness of war
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Christopher Reynolds
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/3/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Looking at this movie as a whole, it works brilliantly in conveying its theme of the madness of war, and how it drives good men to do bad things. Great direction, acting across the board, and cinematography all add a lot to the movie. **** SPOILERS ***** As I was watching the movie, for the first hour I felt increasingly annoyed by Col. Nicholson's "play by the rules and do what you're told" philosophy. Then as the movie went on, and we follow the British plan to blow up the bridge, I realised that this was how the movie wanted me to feel, and then the finale pulled off a brilliant reversal, and a sort of redemption for Nicholson. Standout scenes are the killing of the Japanese soldiers while clouds of bats whirl over the jungle, and, of course, the incredibly tense and powerful finale.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I hate the British! You are defeated but you have no shame. You are stubborn but you have no pride. You endure but you have no courage. I hate the British!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Ben Larson
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    What could one possibly add to the accolades this film has had heaped upon it. The fact that it may not be historically accurate is of no consequence, as it was made for the theater, not the History Channel. David Lean's master piece showing the madness of war stands the test of time. It swept the Oscars in 1958, winning Best Picture, Best Director for Lean, Best Actor for Alec Guinness in the role that defines him, and a Best Supporting Actor nomination for Sessue Hayakawa. It also took the awards for Writing. Music, Editing and Cinematography. Guinness was a perfect example of British pride. If you are going to do a job, then do it right. In that, he managed to take care of his men at the same time. William Holden was a perfect example of a soldier who just wanted to go home, as I am sure was the feeling of most. He recognized the madness of war long before the good doctor. This is a film that you can watch year after year and never get tired of it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Utter trash.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Blueghost
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    My uncle lived through the Bataan march, and was a POW in a Japanese labor camp. According to his daughter the one comment he made about this movie was as follows; "*Explicative*, we never had it that good!" He then reportedly stormed out of the TV room. You know, I have to say that I saw this film a couple times as a kid, and I never thought much of it. Initially I was going to title my review "Egomania 3" because that's kind of what we have here. The "drama" between the leads is manufactured in the extreme. The squaring off between Guiness and Mifune puts a grim smirk (if you could call it that) on this viewer's face. The film just doesn't ring true as to what happened to American, British, Australian, New Zealander and even French or Dutch POWs taken by the Japanese. The Imperial Japanese military didn't have the wanton industrial slaughter mechanism of the Nazi regime in Europe, but instead had the "work them until they're dead" ethic derived partially from Bushido, the code of the samurai. The acting was over the top. The story was so detached from reality as to be insulting, and by that I don't just mean my family's anecdote, but the interviews with survivors who went through that atrocity tell a very different and tragic story. During the Bataan march itself Japanese soldiers routinely shot anyone who looked weak or didn't look like they could make it, or rested. Then, once they got to the camps, it was hell baking in corrugated iron huts, laboring in hot and disease infested regions. And that's just for starters; the treatment, the food, the sheer and utter abuse; NONE of that is in this film. This film is about Hollywood parading its stars for what some idiot asinine producer thought would be a good patriotic film showing Americans and British being defiant in the face of the odds. Wrong. Look, I love Japanese culture. I love the food, I love the movies, I love the clean and polite society, and the people themselves, and I certainly don't hold any grudges whatsoever. In fact I want to retire there. And, I'm not the only one. Therefore, why not make a movie that shows the REAL EXPERIENCE? I can't answer that, but what I do know is that this piece of cinematic trash is just another notch in a southern Californian metroplex film industry that seems to never get anything write when it comes to history. What's even more insulting is that people have voted it so high as a quality film. Between the Russians not getting credit for their massive effort in what they call "the Great Patriotic War" and people like my family who were there when it happened, it's a wonder the entire film industry hasn't been run out of town and forced to setup shop in Mexico. Respectably shot, egotistical acting, poor SFX (notably the miniature), and a script that is just so idiotic I can't believe anyone green-lit this thing, it's a film that's definitely got some massive flaws. If you need to see a WW2 film about the Pacific Theatre, then check out Tora Tora Tora (Tiger Tiger Tiger). See this movie once, then do your brain a favor and pick up a book on the subject to learn what REALLY happened.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Ultimate Test of Survival-with some real life facts
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Admiraljames11
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie is the extremely accurate rendition of the incredible heroics of the brave men in Japanese prison camps that were made to build railroads. Many of these men after surviving battle on ships, ship sinkings, environmental and weather elements, were then subjected to cruel and inhuman treatment of Japanese soldiers. This movie is an accurate portrayal of these conditions with a few exceptions: (1) They did not whistle when entering the camp(although they did march in military formation, even when captured). (2) In the movie, Cdr. Shears tells the story of how he was on the USS Houston at the time she was sunk ,and how he and a Commander was separated from everyone else and drifted to the other side of the island. The commander died and he took his rank...etc. In real life, there was a USS Houston that was sunk and there was a Commander Maer that did drift to the other side of the island with a Seaman Elam ,which is consistent with Cdr. Shears story of the Houston sinking. However, both Cdr. Maer and Seaman Elam survived and were captured.(3) Real conditions of the prison camps were far more deplorable than depicted ,as well as the work details. (Men that couldn't walk were put on stretchers and given a hammer to bust up rock etc). (4) There were more American POWS than depicted in the movie, (the British often referred to the Americans as "Rabble"). and (5) They did not blow up the Bridge in the end and Col Nicholson certainly didn't turn on his own people to attempt to keep the bridge from blowing up. Still an awesome movie that is a must see.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A rather odd story,but entertaining
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    SmileysWorld
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I thoroughly enjoy this film,though I find it to be a rather odd story.Looking at it realistically,I find it hard to believe that a British commander,or any other commander,would give in to the will of the enemy under any circumstances,but I realize that even films based on true events can never be told 100% accurately,so I have no problem seeing as a great fictionalized account of true events.All the performances were excellent,particularly those of Alec Guiness and Bill Holden.If you are looking for a different type of war story,you have a winner in this one,but I would advise not reading up on how things really happened on The River Kwaiuntil after viewing it.It may make the film a disappointment to you.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A David Lean War Movie !
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Umar Mansoor Bajwa (umar_mansoor@yahoo.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The story is well laden with excitement, thrill and adventure. The characterization of different roles is uniquely perfect. The intrinsic conflicts, valor and stoic fortitude displayed by Col. Nicholson played by Alec Guinness is indeed commendable. Needless to mention is the daredevil nature of the commando action steered by a British Major to blow the bridge, laboriously built by another British Colonel is a striking coincidence. However, tragedy awaited Shears (William Holden) the US Navy Officer who had earlier miraculously escaped from the POW camp run by an intransigent Col. Saitu. Above all is the magnificent direction of Sir David Lean, who has captured marvelous locations for filming the army offices and bungalows situated at uniquely picturesque spots. It requires a keen eye to identify the meticulous details of the sets, like the revolving pedestal fan and wartime furniture, when Major Warden convinces Shears to join the death defying plot. The screenplay is a feast for the eyes. The dialogues and script goes hand in hand with the majestic flow of thrill in this commando mission movie. A must see for all war movie buffs.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Stretch Too Far
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    robinmcis966
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/9/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Certainly 'The Bridge on the River Kwai' has a gorgeous and epic sweep. If viewers simply want an entertaining evening, just cue it up and enjoy. For that matter, if you want encouragement, The AFI 100 once placed 'The Bridge' as the 13th best film ever and it has garnered more 4 of 4 and 5 of 5 star reviews than can be counted. However, The AFI now places the Film 37th and perhaps it is past due for re-vision. Although larger problems develop more slowly, it is a bad sign when there are not one, but two, obvious editing problems before the end of the credits! We are right behind the mounted machine gun on a train. The view is of the at least 2 carloads of wood for fuel and the engine. But now we see the same view with no fuel cars, OR EVEN THE ENGINE. Where did they go? In the same scene, the train now stops as the rail ends amidst about 15 workers. But now the dramatic score kicks in and there suddenly are several dozen workers on the rail line. In a low-budget film, this could be overlooked. But this is a major production that won an Oscar....for best direction AND editing! Moving on to the more serious issues, we are told that the British Commander (Alec Guinness) has been ordered to surrender, along with over 100 men and about a dozen officers. No explanation is offered for this. Really? He was just 'ordered to surrender'? According to historical estimates, over 100,000 men died building this railroad. For that matter, although there are ample references to men dying in this prison camp, all the men who have already been imprisoned there, even those in the infirmary, look well-fed, some even in 'beef-cake' condition. Again, this sort of over-sight would be fine for a 2nd rate 'action-genre' flick. It's Bill Holden-he's tanned, buff, and sweaty. Enough said? The central problem with 'The Bridge on the River Kwai' has at least been occasionally mentioned. Guinness' Commander not only helps the Japanese build a crucial bridge in their supply line, he goes to great lengths to make sure the bridge will hold and be finished on time. This to prove superior British logistics and character. Along the way, he is warned of the possibly treasonous nature of his collaboration, and yet he continues on without a doubt. Nothing is made of this...he just comes across as 'funny that way'. However, as far as I know, it has not been pointed out that all of his men and his officers would therefore have had to join him in this inexplicable lapse. This despite what appears to be a very democratic officers meeting and over two months time to reflect on the matter. Treason?...well...no problem! What a credulous bunch of guys. And more to the point, what a credulous bunch of reviewers have failed to notice this. Clearly the original 1957 release of 'The Bridge on the River Kwai' struck a cord. To portray an American, (British in the book), played by William Holden, as cynically detached from the war effort and yet ultimately humane was not new. Several Bogart films prepared audiences for this. But to sum it all up as 'Madness', this before Catch-22 and Mash, was ahead of it's time. This progressive spirit, some great cinematography, and a rousing combination of star-power and studio support make for an entertaining evening. But as a 'Closely Watched Film', it is almost as much train-wreck as classic.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    All you need is love.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    frizb
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/7/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Real Billy Shears Bridge on the River Kwai was written by a French author, Pierre Boulle. In the movie William Holden plays Commander Shears, an American captured when his ship the USS Houston is sunk. He is a POW in a camp full of British sailors and Australians and does his best to avoid any really hard work by becoming a grave digger. But then Alec Guinnes (Obi Wan Kenobi) shows up and is the senior officer, Lt Colonel Nicholson. He refuses to let any of the officers do manual labor, so Shears says that Nicholson is a maniac and makes an escape. Then Nicholson says that the Japanese camp commander is mad. When Shears reaches a British base in Ceylon it turns out that he is not an officer. He is just a sailor named Shears impersonating an officer in order to get better treatment. After he escaped he decided to continue playing an officer and was going to say that being lost in the jungle drove him mad. But the British Force 316, commandos, wanted Shears to lead them back to the POW camp so they could blow up the bridge that the prisoners were building. They made Shears a simulated major. Ian Fleming was the head of a force of British Commandoes in France called Force 54, along with "Q" and "U" and Bertrand, and the real James Bond, who Fleming once met according to his biographer. Shears, also called "Number One", gets to the bridge but not before telling the Professor he is as crazy as Nicholson. Nicholson tries to stop them from destroying the bridge. Lt Joyce kills a few Japanese soldiers and Nicholson fights with Lt Joyce. The Professor starts a mortar barrage, and Shears swims across the river to set off the explosives. Just as Shears reaches Nicholson they recognize each other, and Nicholson realizes that he is himself mad. Shears is killed by rifle fire and the mortar kills Nicholson who falls on the detonator and the bridge is destroyed. The British doctor stands on the riverbank and says everyone is mad. But earlier in the movie Shears is sitting on a Ceylon beach with a blonde nurse and a thermos of martinis. He complains jokingly about how the nurse gives him pills, powders, shots, thermometers and all he really needs is love. The nurse says "Yes that is true. All you really need is love!"
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    David Lean's First Best Picture Winner Is One Of The Greatest!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Humphrey Fish
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/5/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    After settling his differences with a Japanese PoW camp commander, a British colonel co-operates to oversee his men's construction of a railway bridge for their captors - while oblivious to a plan by the Allies to destroy it. Speaking as someone who has seen a wide variety of movies, this movie is awesome, totally and completely awesome! The Bridge On The River Kwai is a milestone in the history of film, the results are groundbreaking and breathtaking. I watched this on TCM as part of a Memorial Day celebration, and when I watched it, I was astonished by what I had seen. I had seen one of the greatest movies of all time, a movie that is directed by a master of epic films, the great British film director, David Lean. David Lean's first Best Picture winner is one of the greatest, and only a few years after this movie, he would direct his second Best Picture Winner, Lawrence Of Arabia, and three years after that, he would direct another great movie, Doctor Zhivago. Like Martin Scorsese, David Lean was a man who could do no wrong, I repeat, absolutely no wrong. This film also won numerous Academy Awards, the biggest ones being Best Picture, Best Director, and Best Actor. Alec Guinness won the Academy Award for Best Actor for his role as Col. Nicholson. And I can say that that win was a win that was well deserved, as he was great in this movie! William Holden also gives a good performance as the secondary protagonist, Shears. By the way, this movie was written by Carl Foreman and Michael Wilson, but they had to keep a low profile because a few years earlier, they had been accused of being Communists and they ended up getting blacklisted, much to their misfortune. David Lean's direction is masterful, it's the direction of a master film director. And as proof of that, he won the Academy Award For Best Director, and he would repeat that when he made Lawrence Of Arabia. David Lean was another one of those directors who if he had never existed, the movie industry would be a whole lot different. So all in all, The Bridge On The River Kwai is another movie that I can say is one of the greatest movies that I have ever seen. When I watched it, I was thrilled with it, every minute of it, from the very minute that it began to the very minute that it ended, I was absolutely impressed with every last second of it! And I guess that you know what this means, this means that you too are going to watch to watch this remarkably fabulous movie, because it's simply incredible, when you watch it, you will say that it is one of the greatest movies that you have ever seen, you will say that it deserved all of the Academy Awards that it won! Bravo to the remarkable David Lean for making a movie that I totally and completely loved! So if you haven't seen this movie, then take the time to watch it, because you will love it, you will say that it's one of the greatest movies you've ever seen! 10/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A World War II Odyssey
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Nick-leonardi
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/5/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    POW English soldiers are instructed by their rulers, the Japanese, to build a bridge. At the same time, a group of free Englishmen plan to destroy the bridge as soon as it's done. Majestic triumph at the Oscars (it won seven Academy Awards), as well as great commercial success, the film proves how David Lean brings a sense of epic and grandiose in everything he touches, inserting also themes like the meaning and weight of law, honor, pride, duty, and of course, the futility of war. Engaging even with a concept that might indicate otherwise (the construction of a bridge), the film boasts memorable performances by Alec Guinness and William Holden that compliment even more the importance of this British film. Based on the novel by Pierre Boulle.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The madness of war
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Christopher Reynolds
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/3/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Looking at this movie as a whole, it works brilliantly in conveying its theme of the madness of war, and how it drives good men to do bad things. Great direction, acting across the board, and cinematography all add a lot to the movie. **** SPOILERS ***** As I was watching the movie, for the first hour I felt increasingly annoyed by Col. Nicholson's "play by the rules and do what you're told" philosophy. Then as the movie went on, and we follow the British plan to blow up the bridge, I realised that this was how the movie wanted me to feel, and then the finale pulled off a brilliant reversal, and a sort of redemption for Nicholson. Standout scenes are the killing of the Japanese soldiers while clouds of bats whirl over the jungle, and, of course, the incredibly tense and powerful finale.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I hate the British! You are defeated but you have no shame. You are stubborn but you have no pride. You endure but you have no courage. I hate the British!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Ben Larson
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    What could one possibly add to the accolades this film has had heaped upon it. The fact that it may not be historically accurate is of no consequence, as it was made for the theater, not the History Channel. David Lean's master piece showing the madness of war stands the test of time. It swept the Oscars in 1958, winning Best Picture, Best Director for Lean, Best Actor for Alec Guinness in the role that defines him, and a Best Supporting Actor nomination for Sessue Hayakawa. It also took the awards for Writing. Music, Editing and Cinematography. Guinness was a perfect example of British pride. If you are going to do a job, then do it right. In that, he managed to take care of his men at the same time. William Holden was a perfect example of a soldier who just wanted to go home, as I am sure was the feeling of most. He recognized the madness of war long before the good doctor. This is a film that you can watch year after year and never get tired of it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Utter trash.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Blueghost
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    My uncle lived through the Bataan march, and was a POW in a Japanese labor camp. According to his daughter the one comment he made about this movie was as follows; "*Explicative*, we never had it that good!" He then reportedly stormed out of the TV room. You know, I have to say that I saw this film a couple times as a kid, and I never thought much of it. Initially I was going to title my review "Egomania 3" because that's kind of what we have here. The "drama" between the leads is manufactured in the extreme. The squaring off between Guiness and Mifune puts a grim smirk (if you could call it that) on this viewer's face. The film just doesn't ring true as to what happened to American, British, Australian, New Zealander and even French or Dutch POWs taken by the Japanese. The Imperial Japanese military didn't have the wanton industrial slaughter mechanism of the Nazi regime in Europe, but instead had the "work them until they're dead" ethic derived partially from Bushido, the code of the samurai. The acting was over the top. The story was so detached from reality as to be insulting, and by that I don't just mean my family's anecdote, but the interviews with survivors who went through that atrocity tell a very different and tragic story. During the Bataan march itself Japanese soldiers routinely shot anyone who looked weak or didn't look like they could make it, or rested. Then, once they got to the camps, it was hell baking in corrugated iron huts, laboring in hot and disease infested regions. And that's just for starters; the treatment, the food, the sheer and utter abuse; NONE of that is in this film. This film is about Hollywood parading its stars for what some idiot asinine producer thought would be a good patriotic film showing Americans and British being defiant in the face of the odds. Wrong. Look, I love Japanese culture. I love the food, I love the movies, I love the clean and polite society, and the people themselves, and I certainly don't hold any grudges whatsoever. In fact I want to retire there. And, I'm not the only one. Therefore, why not make a movie that shows the REAL EXPERIENCE? I can't answer that, but what I do know is that this piece of cinematic trash is just another notch in a southern Californian metroplex film industry that seems to never get anything write when it comes to history. What's even more insulting is that people have voted it so high as a quality film. Between the Russians not getting credit for their massive effort in what they call "the Great Patriotic War" and people like my family who were there when it happened, it's a wonder the entire film industry hasn't been run out of town and forced to setup shop in Mexico. Respectably shot, egotistical acting, poor SFX (notably the miniature), and a script that is just so idiotic I can't believe anyone green-lit this thing, it's a film that's definitely got some massive flaws. If you need to see a WW2 film about the Pacific Theatre, then check out Tora Tora Tora (Tiger Tiger Tiger). See this movie once, then do your brain a favor and pick up a book on the subject to learn what REALLY happened.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Ultimate Test of Survival-with some real life facts
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Admiraljames11
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie is the extremely accurate rendition of the incredible heroics of the brave men in Japanese prison camps that were made to build railroads. Many of these men after surviving battle on ships, ship sinkings, environmental and weather elements, were then subjected to cruel and inhuman treatment of Japanese soldiers. This movie is an accurate portrayal of these conditions with a few exceptions: (1) They did not whistle when entering the camp(although they did march in military formation, even when captured). (2) In the movie, Cdr. Shears tells the story of how he was on the USS Houston at the time she was sunk ,and how he and a Commander was separated from everyone else and drifted to the other side of the island. The commander died and he took his rank...etc. In real life, there was a USS Houston that was sunk and there was a Commander Maer that did drift to the other side of the island with a Seaman Elam ,which is consistent with Cdr. Shears story of the Houston sinking. However, both Cdr. Maer and Seaman Elam survived and were captured.(3) Real conditions of the prison camps were far more deplorable than depicted ,as well as the work details. (Men that couldn't walk were put on stretchers and given a hammer to bust up rock etc). (4) There were more American POWS than depicted in the movie, (the British often referred to the Americans as "Rabble"). and (5) They did not blow up the Bridge in the end and Col Nicholson certainly didn't turn on his own people to attempt to keep the bridge from blowing up. Still an awesome movie that is a must see.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A rather odd story,but entertaining
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    SmileysWorld
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I thoroughly enjoy this film,though I find it to be a rather odd story.Looking at it realistically,I find it hard to believe that a British commander,or any other commander,would give in to the will of the enemy under any circumstances,but I realize that even films based on true events can never be told 100% accurately,so I have no problem seeing as a great fictionalized account of true events.All the performances were excellent,particularly those of Alec Guiness and Bill Holden.If you are looking for a different type of war story,you have a winner in this one,but I would advise not reading up on how things really happened on The River Kwaiuntil after viewing it.It may make the film a disappointment to you.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A David Lean War Movie !
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Umar Mansoor Bajwa (umar_mansoor@yahoo.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The story is well laden with excitement, thrill and adventure. The characterization of different roles is uniquely perfect. The intrinsic conflicts, valor and stoic fortitude displayed by Col. Nicholson played by Alec Guinness is indeed commendable. Needless to mention is the daredevil nature of the commando action steered by a British Major to blow the bridge, laboriously built by another British Colonel is a striking coincidence. However, tragedy awaited Shears (William Holden) the US Navy Officer who had earlier miraculously escaped from the POW camp run by an intransigent Col. Saitu. Above all is the magnificent direction of Sir David Lean, who has captured marvelous locations for filming the army offices and bungalows situated at uniquely picturesque spots. It requires a keen eye to identify the meticulous details of the sets, like the revolving pedestal fan and wartime furniture, when Major Warden convinces Shears to join the death defying plot. The screenplay is a feast for the eyes. The dialogues and script goes hand in hand with the majestic flow of thrill in this commando mission movie. A must see for all war movie buffs.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Stretch Too Far
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    robinmcis966
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/9/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Certainly 'The Bridge on the River Kwai' has a gorgeous and epic sweep. If viewers simply want an entertaining evening, just cue it up and enjoy. For that matter, if you want encouragement, The AFI 100 once placed 'The Bridge' as the 13th best film ever and it has garnered more 4 of 4 and 5 of 5 star reviews than can be counted. However, The AFI now places the Film 37th and perhaps it is past due for re-vision. Although larger problems develop more slowly, it is a bad sign when there are not one, but two, obvious editing problems before the end of the credits! We are right behind the mounted machine gun on a train. The view is of the at least 2 carloads of wood for fuel and the engine. But now we see the same view with no fuel cars, OR EVEN THE ENGINE. Where did they go? In the same scene, the train now stops as the rail ends amidst about 15 workers. But now the dramatic score kicks in and there suddenly are several dozen workers on the rail line. In a low-budget film, this could be overlooked. But this is a major production that won an Oscar....for best direction AND editing! Moving on to the more serious issues, we are told that the British Commander (Alec Guinness) has been ordered to surrender, along with over 100 men and about a dozen officers. No explanation is offered for this. Really? He was just 'ordered to surrender'? According to historical estimates, over 100,000 men died building this railroad. For that matter, although there are ample references to men dying in this prison camp, all the men who have already been imprisoned there, even those in the infirmary, look well-fed, some even in 'beef-cake' condition. Again, this sort of over-sight would be fine for a 2nd rate 'action-genre' flick. It's Bill Holden-he's tanned, buff, and sweaty. Enough said? The central problem with 'The Bridge on the River Kwai' has at least been occasionally mentioned. Guinness' Commander not only helps the Japanese build a crucial bridge in their supply line, he goes to great lengths to make sure the bridge will hold and be finished on time. This to prove superior British logistics and character. Along the way, he is warned of the possibly treasonous nature of his collaboration, and yet he continues on without a doubt. Nothing is made of this...he just comes across as 'funny that way'. However, as far as I know, it has not been pointed out that all of his men and his officers would therefore have had to join him in this inexplicable lapse. This despite what appears to be a very democratic officers meeting and over two months time to reflect on the matter. Treason?...well...no problem! What a credulous bunch of guys. And more to the point, what a credulous bunch of reviewers have failed to notice this. Clearly the original 1957 release of 'The Bridge on the River Kwai' struck a cord. To portray an American, (British in the book), played by William Holden, as cynically detached from the war effort and yet ultimately humane was not new. Several Bogart films prepared audiences for this. But to sum it all up as 'Madness', this before Catch-22 and Mash, was ahead of it's time. This progressive spirit, some great cinematography, and a rousing combination of star-power and studio support make for an entertaining evening. But as a 'Closely Watched Film', it is almost as much train-wreck as classic.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    All you need is love.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    frizb
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/7/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Real Billy Shears Bridge on the River Kwai was written by a French author, Pierre Boulle. In the movie William Holden plays Commander Shears, an American captured when his ship the USS Houston is sunk. He is a POW in a camp full of British sailors and Australians and does his best to avoid any really hard work by becoming a grave digger. But then Alec Guinnes (Obi Wan Kenobi) shows up and is the senior officer, Lt Colonel Nicholson. He refuses to let any of the officers do manual labor, so Shears says that Nicholson is a maniac and makes an escape. Then Nicholson says that the Japanese camp commander is mad. When Shears reaches a British base in Ceylon it turns out that he is not an officer. He is just a sailor named Shears impersonating an officer in order to get better treatment. After he escaped he decided to continue playing an officer and was going to say that being lost in the jungle drove him mad. But the British Force 316, commandos, wanted Shears to lead them back to the POW camp so they could blow up the bridge that the prisoners were building. They made Shears a simulated major. Ian Fleming was the head of a force of British Commandoes in France called Force 54, along with "Q" and "U" and Bertrand, and the real James Bond, who Fleming once met according to his biographer. Shears, also called "Number One", gets to the bridge but not before telling the Professor he is as crazy as Nicholson. Nicholson tries to stop them from destroying the bridge. Lt Joyce kills a few Japanese soldiers and Nicholson fights with Lt Joyce. The Professor starts a mortar barrage, and Shears swims across the river to set off the explosives. Just as Shears reaches Nicholson they recognize each other, and Nicholson realizes that he is himself mad. Shears is killed by rifle fire and the mortar kills Nicholson who falls on the detonator and the bridge is destroyed. The British doctor stands on the riverbank and says everyone is mad. But earlier in the movie Shears is sitting on a Ceylon beach with a blonde nurse and a thermos of martinis. He complains jokingly about how the nurse gives him pills, powders, shots, thermometers and all he really needs is love. The nurse says "Yes that is true. All you really need is love!"
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    David Lean's First Best Picture Winner Is One Of The Greatest!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Humphrey Fish
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/5/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    After settling his differences with a Japanese PoW camp commander, a British colonel co-operates to oversee his men's construction of a railway bridge for their captors - while oblivious to a plan by the Allies to destroy it. Speaking as someone who has seen a wide variety of movies, this movie is awesome, totally and completely awesome! The Bridge On The River Kwai is a milestone in the history of film, the results are groundbreaking and breathtaking. I watched this on TCM as part of a Memorial Day celebration, and when I watched it, I was astonished by what I had seen. I had seen one of the greatest movies of all time, a movie that is directed by a master of epic films, the great British film director, David Lean. David Lean's first Best Picture winner is one of the greatest, and only a few years after this movie, he would direct his second Best Picture Winner, Lawrence Of Arabia, and three years after that, he would direct another great movie, Doctor Zhivago. Like Martin Scorsese, David Lean was a man who could do no wrong, I repeat, absolutely no wrong. This film also won numerous Academy Awards, the biggest ones being Best Picture, Best Director, and Best Actor. Alec Guinness won the Academy Award for Best Actor for his role as Col. Nicholson. And I can say that that win was a win that was well deserved, as he was great in this movie! William Holden also gives a good performance as the secondary protagonist, Shears. By the way, this movie was written by Carl Foreman and Michael Wilson, but they had to keep a low profile because a few years earlier, they had been accused of being Communists and they ended up getting blacklisted, much to their misfortune. David Lean's direction is masterful, it's the direction of a master film director. And as proof of that, he won the Academy Award For Best Director, and he would repeat that when he made Lawrence Of Arabia. David Lean was another one of those directors who if he had never existed, the movie industry would be a whole lot different. So all in all, The Bridge On The River Kwai is another movie that I can say is one of the greatest movies that I have ever seen. When I watched it, I was thrilled with it, every minute of it, from the very minute that it began to the very minute that it ended, I was absolutely impressed with every last second of it! And I guess that you know what this means, this means that you too are going to watch to watch this remarkably fabulous movie, because it's simply incredible, when you watch it, you will say that it is one of the greatest movies that you have ever seen, you will say that it deserved all of the Academy Awards that it won! Bravo to the remarkable David Lean for making a movie that I totally and completely loved! So if you haven't seen this movie, then take the time to watch it, because you will love it, you will say that it's one of the greatest movies you've ever seen! 10/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A World War II Odyssey
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Nick-leonardi
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/5/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    POW English soldiers are instructed by their rulers, the Japanese, to build a bridge. At the same time, a group of free Englishmen plan to destroy the bridge as soon as it's done. Majestic triumph at the Oscars (it won seven Academy Awards), as well as great commercial success, the film proves how David Lean brings a sense of epic and grandiose in everything he touches, inserting also themes like the meaning and weight of law, honor, pride, duty, and of course, the futility of war. Engaging even with a concept that might indicate otherwise (the construction of a bridge), the film boasts memorable performances by Alec Guinness and William Holden that compliment even more the importance of this British film. Based on the novel by Pierre Boulle.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The madness of war
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Christopher Reynolds
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/3/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Looking at this movie as a whole, it works brilliantly in conveying its theme of the madness of war, and how it drives good men to do bad things. Great direction, acting across the board, and cinematography all add a lot to the movie. **** SPOILERS ***** As I was watching the movie, for the first hour I felt increasingly annoyed by Col. Nicholson's "play by the rules and do what you're told" philosophy. Then as the movie went on, and we follow the British plan to blow up the bridge, I realised that this was how the movie wanted me to feel, and then the finale pulled off a brilliant reversal, and a sort of redemption for Nicholson. Standout scenes are the killing of the Japanese soldiers while clouds of bats whirl over the jungle, and, of course, the incredibly tense and powerful finale.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I hate the British! You are defeated but you have no shame. You are stubborn but you have no pride. You endure but you have no courage. I hate the British!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Ben Larson
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    What could one possibly add to the accolades this film has had heaped upon it. The fact that it may not be historically accurate is of no consequence, as it was made for the theater, not the History Channel. David Lean's master piece showing the madness of war stands the test of time. It swept the Oscars in 1958, winning Best Picture, Best Director for Lean, Best Actor for Alec Guinness in the role that defines him, and a Best Supporting Actor nomination for Sessue Hayakawa. It also took the awards for Writing. Music, Editing and Cinematography. Guinness was a perfect example of British pride. If you are going to do a job, then do it right. In that, he managed to take care of his men at the same time. William Holden was a perfect example of a soldier who just wanted to go home, as I am sure was the feeling of most. He recognized the madness of war long before the good doctor. This is a film that you can watch year after year and never get tired of it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Utter trash.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Blueghost
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    My uncle lived through the Bataan march, and was a POW in a Japanese labor camp. According to his daughter the one comment he made about this movie was as follows; "*Explicative*, we never had it that good!" He then reportedly stormed out of the TV room. You know, I have to say that I saw this film a couple times as a kid, and I never thought much of it. Initially I was going to title my review "Egomania 3" because that's kind of what we have here. The "drama" between the leads is manufactured in the extreme. The squaring off between Guiness and Mifune puts a grim smirk (if you could call it that) on this viewer's face. The film just doesn't ring true as to what happened to American, British, Australian, New Zealander and even French or Dutch POWs taken by the Japanese. The Imperial Japanese military didn't have the wanton industrial slaughter mechanism of the Nazi regime in Europe, but instead had the "work them until they're dead" ethic derived partially from Bushido, the code of the samurai. The acting was over the top. The story was so detached from reality as to be insulting, and by that I don't just mean my family's anecdote, but the interviews with survivors who went through that atrocity tell a very different and tragic story. During the Bataan march itself Japanese soldiers routinely shot anyone who looked weak or didn't look like they could make it, or rested. Then, once they got to the camps, it was hell baking in corrugated iron huts, laboring in hot and disease infested regions. And that's just for starters; the treatment, the food, the sheer and utter abuse; NONE of that is in this film. This film is about Hollywood parading its stars for what some idiot asinine producer thought would be a good patriotic film showing Americans and British being defiant in the face of the odds. Wrong. Look, I love Japanese culture. I love the food, I love the movies, I love the clean and polite society, and the people themselves, and I certainly don't hold any grudges whatsoever. In fact I want to retire there. And, I'm not the only one. Therefore, why not make a movie that shows the REAL EXPERIENCE? I can't answer that, but what I do know is that this piece of cinematic trash is just another notch in a southern Californian metroplex film industry that seems to never get anything write when it comes to history. What's even more insulting is that people have voted it so high as a quality film. Between the Russians not getting credit for their massive effort in what they call "the Great Patriotic War" and people like my family who were there when it happened, it's a wonder the entire film industry hasn't been run out of town and forced to setup shop in Mexico. Respectably shot, egotistical acting, poor SFX (notably the miniature), and a script that is just so idiotic I can't believe anyone green-lit this thing, it's a film that's definitely got some massive flaws. If you need to see a WW2 film about the Pacific Theatre, then check out Tora Tora Tora (Tiger Tiger Tiger). See this movie once, then do your brain a favor and pick up a book on the subject to learn what REALLY happened.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Ultimate Test of Survival-with some real life facts
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Admiraljames11
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie is the extremely accurate rendition of the incredible heroics of the brave men in Japanese prison camps that were made to build railroads. Many of these men after surviving battle on ships, ship sinkings, environmental and weather elements, were then subjected to cruel and inhuman treatment of Japanese soldiers. This movie is an accurate portrayal of these conditions with a few exceptions: (1) They did not whistle when entering the camp(although they did march in military formation, even when captured). (2) In the movie, Cdr. Shears tells the story of how he was on the USS Houston at the time she was sunk ,and how he and a Commander was separated from everyone else and drifted to the other side of the island. The commander died and he took his rank...etc. In real life, there was a USS Houston that was sunk and there was a Commander Maer that did drift to the other side of the island with a Seaman Elam ,which is consistent with Cdr. Shears story of the Houston sinking. However, both Cdr. Maer and Seaman Elam survived and were captured.(3) Real conditions of the prison camps were far more deplorable than depicted ,as well as the work details. (Men that couldn't walk were put on stretchers and given a hammer to bust up rock etc). (4) There were more American POWS than depicted in the movie, (the British often referred to the Americans as "Rabble"). and (5) They did not blow up the Bridge in the end and Col Nicholson certainly didn't turn on his own people to attempt to keep the bridge from blowing up. Still an awesome movie that is a must see.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A rather odd story,but entertaining
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    SmileysWorld
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I thoroughly enjoy this film,though I find it to be a rather odd story.Looking at it realistically,I find it hard to believe that a British commander,or any other commander,would give in to the will of the enemy under any circumstances,but I realize that even films based on true events can never be told 100% accurately,so I have no problem seeing as a great fictionalized account of true events.All the performances were excellent,particularly those of Alec Guiness and Bill Holden.If you are looking for a different type of war story,you have a winner in this one,but I would advise not reading up on how things really happened on The River Kwaiuntil after viewing it.It may make the film a disappointment to you.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A David Lean War Movie !
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Umar Mansoor Bajwa (umar_mansoor@yahoo.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The story is well laden with excitement, thrill and adventure. The characterization of different roles is uniquely perfect. The intrinsic conflicts, valor and stoic fortitude displayed by Col. Nicholson played by Alec Guinness is indeed commendable. Needless to mention is the daredevil nature of the commando action steered by a British Major to blow the bridge, laboriously built by another British Colonel is a striking coincidence. However, tragedy awaited Shears (William Holden) the US Navy Officer who had earlier miraculously escaped from the POW camp run by an intransigent Col. Saitu. Above all is the magnificent direction of Sir David Lean, who has captured marvelous locations for filming the army offices and bungalows situated at uniquely picturesque spots. It requires a keen eye to identify the meticulous details of the sets, like the revolving pedestal fan and wartime furniture, when Major Warden convinces Shears to join the death defying plot. The screenplay is a feast for the eyes. The dialogues and script goes hand in hand with the majestic flow of thrill in this commando mission movie. A must see for all war movie buffs.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Stretch Too Far
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    robinmcis966
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/9/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Certainly 'The Bridge on the River Kwai' has a gorgeous and epic sweep. If viewers simply want an entertaining evening, just cue it up and enjoy. For that matter, if you want encouragement, The AFI 100 once placed 'The Bridge' as the 13th best film ever and it has garnered more 4 of 4 and 5 of 5 star reviews than can be counted. However, The AFI now places the Film 37th and perhaps it is past due for re-vision. Although larger problems develop more slowly, it is a bad sign when there are not one, but two, obvious editing problems before the end of the credits! We are right behind the mounted machine gun on a train. The view is of the at least 2 carloads of wood for fuel and the engine. But now we see the same view with no fuel cars, OR EVEN THE ENGINE. Where did they go? In the same scene, the train now stops as the rail ends amidst about 15 workers. But now the dramatic score kicks in and there suddenly are several dozen workers on the rail line. In a low-budget film, this could be overlooked. But this is a major production that won an Oscar....for best direction AND editing! Moving on to the more serious issues, we are told that the British Commander (Alec Guinness) has been ordered to surrender, along with over 100 men and about a dozen officers. No explanation is offered for this. Really? He was just 'ordered to surrender'? According to historical estimates, over 100,000 men died building this railroad. For that matter, although there are ample references to men dying in this prison camp, all the men who have already been imprisoned there, even those in the infirmary, look well-fed, some even in 'beef-cake' condition. Again, this sort of over-sight would be fine for a 2nd rate 'action-genre' flick. It's Bill Holden-he's tanned, buff, and sweaty. Enough said? The central problem with 'The Bridge on the River Kwai' has at least been occasionally mentioned. Guinness' Commander not only helps the Japanese build a crucial bridge in their supply line, he goes to great lengths to make sure the bridge will hold and be finished on time. This to prove superior British logistics and character. Along the way, he is warned of the possibly treasonous nature of his collaboration, and yet he continues on without a doubt. Nothing is made of this...he just comes across as 'funny that way'. However, as far as I know, it has not been pointed out that all of his men and his officers would therefore have had to join him in this inexplicable lapse. This despite what appears to be a very democratic officers meeting and over two months time to reflect on the matter. Treason?...well...no problem! What a credulous bunch of guys. And more to the point, what a credulous bunch of reviewers have failed to notice this. Clearly the original 1957 release of 'The Bridge on the River Kwai' struck a cord. To portray an American, (British in the book), played by William Holden, as cynically detached from the war effort and yet ultimately humane was not new. Several Bogart films prepared audiences for this. But to sum it all up as 'Madness', this before Catch-22 and Mash, was ahead of it's time. This progressive spirit, some great cinematography, and a rousing combination of star-power and studio support make for an entertaining evening. But as a 'Closely Watched Film', it is almost as much train-wreck as classic.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    All you need is love.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    frizb
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/7/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Real Billy Shears Bridge on the River Kwai was written by a French author, Pierre Boulle. In the movie William Holden plays Commander Shears, an American captured when his ship the USS Houston is sunk. He is a POW in a camp full of British sailors and Australians and does his best to avoid any really hard work by becoming a grave digger. But then Alec Guinnes (Obi Wan Kenobi) shows up and is the senior officer, Lt Colonel Nicholson. He refuses to let any of the officers do manual labor, so Shears says that Nicholson is a maniac and makes an escape. Then Nicholson says that the Japanese camp commander is mad. When Shears reaches a British base in Ceylon it turns out that he is not an officer. He is just a sailor named Shears impersonating an officer in order to get better treatment. After he escaped he decided to continue playing an officer and was going to say that being lost in the jungle drove him mad. But the British Force 316, commandos, wanted Shears to lead them back to the POW camp so they could blow up the bridge that the prisoners were building. They made Shears a simulated major. Ian Fleming was the head of a force of British Commandoes in France called Force 54, along with "Q" and "U" and Bertrand, and the real James Bond, who Fleming once met according to his biographer. Shears, also called "Number One", gets to the bridge but not before telling the Professor he is as crazy as Nicholson. Nicholson tries to stop them from destroying the bridge. Lt Joyce kills a few Japanese soldiers and Nicholson fights with Lt Joyce. The Professor starts a mortar barrage, and Shears swims across the river to set off the explosives. Just as Shears reaches Nicholson they recognize each other, and Nicholson realizes that he is himself mad. Shears is killed by rifle fire and the mortar kills Nicholson who falls on the detonator and the bridge is destroyed. The British doctor stands on the riverbank and says everyone is mad. But earlier in the movie Shears is sitting on a Ceylon beach with a blonde nurse and a thermos of martinis. He complains jokingly about how the nurse gives him pills, powders, shots, thermometers and all he really needs is love. The nurse says "Yes that is true. All you really need is love!"
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    David Lean's First Best Picture Winner Is One Of The Greatest!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Humphrey Fish
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/5/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    After settling his differences with a Japanese PoW camp commander, a British colonel co-operates to oversee his men's construction of a railway bridge for their captors - while oblivious to a plan by the Allies to destroy it. Speaking as someone who has seen a wide variety of movies, this movie is awesome, totally and completely awesome! The Bridge On The River Kwai is a milestone in the history of film, the results are groundbreaking and breathtaking. I watched this on TCM as part of a Memorial Day celebration, and when I watched it, I was astonished by what I had seen. I had seen one of the greatest movies of all time, a movie that is directed by a master of epic films, the great British film director, David Lean. David Lean's first Best Picture winner is one of the greatest, and only a few years after this movie, he would direct his second Best Picture Winner, Lawrence Of Arabia, and three years after that, he would direct another great movie, Doctor Zhivago. Like Martin Scorsese, David Lean was a man who could do no wrong, I repeat, absolutely no wrong. This film also won numerous Academy Awards, the biggest ones being Best Picture, Best Director, and Best Actor. Alec Guinness won the Academy Award for Best Actor for his role as Col. Nicholson. And I can say that that win was a win that was well deserved, as he was great in this movie! William Holden also gives a good performance as the secondary protagonist, Shears. By the way, this movie was written by Carl Foreman and Michael Wilson, but they had to keep a low profile because a few years earlier, they had been accused of being Communists and they ended up getting blacklisted, much to their misfortune. David Lean's direction is masterful, it's the direction of a master film director. And as proof of that, he won the Academy Award For Best Director, and he would repeat that when he made Lawrence Of Arabia. David Lean was another one of those directors who if he had never existed, the movie industry would be a whole lot different. So all in all, The Bridge On The River Kwai is another movie that I can say is one of the greatest movies that I have ever seen. When I watched it, I was thrilled with it, every minute of it, from the very minute that it began to the very minute that it ended, I was absolutely impressed with every last second of it! And I guess that you know what this means, this means that you too are going to watch to watch this remarkably fabulous movie, because it's simply incredible, when you watch it, you will say that it is one of the greatest movies that you have ever seen, you will say that it deserved all of the Academy Awards that it won! Bravo to the remarkable David Lean for making a movie that I totally and completely loved! So if you haven't seen this movie, then take the time to watch it, because you will love it, you will say that it's one of the greatest movies you've ever seen! 10/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A World War II Odyssey
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Nick-leonardi
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/5/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    POW English soldiers are instructed by their rulers, the Japanese, to build a bridge. At the same time, a group of free Englishmen plan to destroy the bridge as soon as it's done. Majestic triumph at the Oscars (it won seven Academy Awards), as well as great commercial success, the film proves how David Lean brings a sense of epic and grandiose in everything he touches, inserting also themes like the meaning and weight of law, honor, pride, duty, and of course, the futility of war. Engaging even with a concept that might indicate otherwise (the construction of a bridge), the film boasts memorable performances by Alec Guinness and William Holden that compliment even more the importance of this British film. Based on the novel by Pierre Boulle.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The madness of war
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Christopher Reynolds
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/3/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Looking at this movie as a whole, it works brilliantly in conveying its theme of the madness of war, and how it drives good men to do bad things. Great direction, acting across the board, and cinematography all add a lot to the movie. **** SPOILERS ***** As I was watching the movie, for the first hour I felt increasingly annoyed by Col. Nicholson's "play by the rules and do what you're told" philosophy. Then as the movie went on, and we follow the British plan to blow up the bridge, I realised that this was how the movie wanted me to feel, and then the finale pulled off a brilliant reversal, and a sort of redemption for Nicholson. Standout scenes are the killing of the Japanese soldiers while clouds of bats whirl over the jungle, and, of course, the incredibly tense and powerful finale.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I hate the British! You are defeated but you have no shame. You are stubborn but you have no pride. You endure but you have no courage. I hate the British!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Ben Larson
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    What could one possibly add to the accolades this film has had heaped upon it. The fact that it may not be historically accurate is of no consequence, as it was made for the theater, not the History Channel. David Lean's master piece showing the madness of war stands the test of time. It swept the Oscars in 1958, winning Best Picture, Best Director for Lean, Best Actor for Alec Guinness in the role that defines him, and a Best Supporting Actor nomination for Sessue Hayakawa. It also took the awards for Writing. Music, Editing and Cinematography. Guinness was a perfect example of British pride. If you are going to do a job, then do it right. In that, he managed to take care of his men at the same time. William Holden was a perfect example of a soldier who just wanted to go home, as I am sure was the feeling of most. He recognized the madness of war long before the good doctor. This is a film that you can watch year after year and never get tired of it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Utter trash.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Blueghost
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    My uncle lived through the Bataan march, and was a POW in a Japanese labor camp. According to his daughter the one comment he made about this movie was as follows; "*Explicative*, we never had it that good!" He then reportedly stormed out of the TV room. You know, I have to say that I saw this film a couple times as a kid, and I never thought much of it. Initially I was going to title my review "Egomania 3" because that's kind of what we have here. The "drama" between the leads is manufactured in the extreme. The squaring off between Guiness and Mifune puts a grim smirk (if you could call it that) on this viewer's face. The film just doesn't ring true as to what happened to American, British, Australian, New Zealander and even French or Dutch POWs taken by the Japanese. The Imperial Japanese military didn't have the wanton industrial slaughter mechanism of the Nazi regime in Europe, but instead had the "work them until they're dead" ethic derived partially from Bushido, the code of the samurai. The acting was over the top. The story was so detached from reality as to be insulting, and by that I don't just mean my family's anecdote, but the interviews with survivors who went through that atrocity tell a very different and tragic story. During the Bataan march itself Japanese soldiers routinely shot anyone who looked weak or didn't look like they could make it, or rested. Then, once they got to the camps, it was hell baking in corrugated iron huts, laboring in hot and disease infested regions. And that's just for starters; the treatment, the food, the sheer and utter abuse; NONE of that is in this film. This film is about Hollywood parading its stars for what some idiot asinine producer thought would be a good patriotic film showing Americans and British being defiant in the face of the odds. Wrong. Look, I love Japanese culture. I love the food, I love the movies, I love the clean and polite society, and the people themselves, and I certainly don't hold any grudges whatsoever. In fact I want to retire there. And, I'm not the only one. Therefore, why not make a movie that shows the REAL EXPERIENCE? I can't answer that, but what I do know is that this piece of cinematic trash is just another notch in a southern Californian metroplex film industry that seems to never get anything write when it comes to history. What's even more insulting is that people have voted it so high as a quality film. Between the Russians not getting credit for their massive effort in what they call "the Great Patriotic War" and people like my family who were there when it happened, it's a wonder the entire film industry hasn't been run out of town and forced to setup shop in Mexico. Respectably shot, egotistical acting, poor SFX (notably the miniature), and a script that is just so idiotic I can't believe anyone green-lit this thing, it's a film that's definitely got some massive flaws. If you need to see a WW2 film about the Pacific Theatre, then check out Tora Tora Tora (Tiger Tiger Tiger). See this movie once, then do your brain a favor and pick up a book on the subject to learn what REALLY happened.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Ultimate Test of Survival-with some real life facts
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Admiraljames11
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie is the extremely accurate rendition of the incredible heroics of the brave men in Japanese prison camps that were made to build railroads. Many of these men after surviving battle on ships, ship sinkings, environmental and weather elements, were then subjected to cruel and inhuman treatment of Japanese soldiers. This movie is an accurate portrayal of these conditions with a few exceptions: (1) They did not whistle when entering the camp(although they did march in military formation, even when captured). (2) In the movie, Cdr. Shears tells the story of how he was on the USS Houston at the time she was sunk ,and how he and a Commander was separated from everyone else and drifted to the other side of the island. The commander died and he took his rank...etc. In real life, there was a USS Houston that was sunk and there was a Commander Maer that did drift to the other side of the island with a Seaman Elam ,which is consistent with Cdr. Shears story of the Houston sinking. However, both Cdr. Maer and Seaman Elam survived and were captured.(3) Real conditions of the prison camps were far more deplorable than depicted ,as well as the work details. (Men that couldn't walk were put on stretchers and given a hammer to bust up rock etc). (4) There were more American POWS than depicted in the movie, (the British often referred to the Americans as "Rabble"). and (5) They did not blow up the Bridge in the end and Col Nicholson certainly didn't turn on his own people to attempt to keep the bridge from blowing up. Still an awesome movie that is a must see.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A rather odd story,but entertaining
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    SmileysWorld
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I thoroughly enjoy this film,though I find it to be a rather odd story.Looking at it realistically,I find it hard to believe that a British commander,or any other commander,would give in to the will of the enemy under any circumstances,but I realize that even films based on true events can never be told 100% accurately,so I have no problem seeing as a great fictionalized account of true events.All the performances were excellent,particularly those of Alec Guiness and Bill Holden.If you are looking for a different type of war story,you have a winner in this one,but I would advise not reading up on how things really happened on The River Kwaiuntil after viewing it.It may make the film a disappointment to you.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A David Lean War Movie !
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Umar Mansoor Bajwa (umar_mansoor@yahoo.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The story is well laden with excitement, thrill and adventure. The characterization of different roles is uniquely perfect. The intrinsic conflicts, valor and stoic fortitude displayed by Col. Nicholson played by Alec Guinness is indeed commendable. Needless to mention is the daredevil nature of the commando action steered by a British Major to blow the bridge, laboriously built by another British Colonel is a striking coincidence. However, tragedy awaited Shears (William Holden) the US Navy Officer who had earlier miraculously escaped from the POW camp run by an intransigent Col. Saitu. Above all is the magnificent direction of Sir David Lean, who has captured marvelous locations for filming the army offices and bungalows situated at uniquely picturesque spots. It requires a keen eye to identify the meticulous details of the sets, like the revolving pedestal fan and wartime furniture, when Major Warden convinces Shears to join the death defying plot. The screenplay is a feast for the eyes. The dialogues and script goes hand in hand with the majestic flow of thrill in this commando mission movie. A must see for all war movie buffs.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Stretch Too Far
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    robinmcis966
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/9/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Certainly 'The Bridge on the River Kwai' has a gorgeous and epic sweep. If viewers simply want an entertaining evening, just cue it up and enjoy. For that matter, if you want encouragement, The AFI 100 once placed 'The Bridge' as the 13th best film ever and it has garnered more 4 of 4 and 5 of 5 star reviews than can be counted. However, The AFI now places the Film 37th and perhaps it is past due for re-vision. Although larger problems develop more slowly, it is a bad sign when there are not one, but two, obvious editing problems before the end of the credits! We are right behind the mounted machine gun on a train. The view is of the at least 2 carloads of wood for fuel and the engine. But now we see the same view with no fuel cars, OR EVEN THE ENGINE. Where did they go? In the same scene, the train now stops as the rail ends amidst about 15 workers. But now the dramatic score kicks in and there suddenly are several dozen workers on the rail line. In a low-budget film, this could be overlooked. But this is a major production that won an Oscar....for best direction AND editing! Moving on to the more serious issues, we are told that the British Commander (Alec Guinness) has been ordered to surrender, along with over 100 men and about a dozen officers. No explanation is offered for this. Really? He was just 'ordered to surrender'? According to historical estimates, over 100,000 men died building this railroad. For that matter, although there are ample references to men dying in this prison camp, all the men who have already been imprisoned there, even those in the infirmary, look well-fed, some even in 'beef-cake' condition. Again, this sort of over-sight would be fine for a 2nd rate 'action-genre' flick. It's Bill Holden-he's tanned, buff, and sweaty. Enough said? The central problem with 'The Bridge on the River Kwai' has at least been occasionally mentioned. Guinness' Commander not only helps the Japanese build a crucial bridge in their supply line, he goes to great lengths to make sure the bridge will hold and be finished on time. This to prove superior British logistics and character. Along the way, he is warned of the possibly treasonous nature of his collaboration, and yet he continues on without a doubt. Nothing is made of this...he just comes across as 'funny that way'. However, as far as I know, it has not been pointed out that all of his men and his officers would therefore have had to join him in this inexplicable lapse. This despite what appears to be a very democratic officers meeting and over two months time to reflect on the matter. Treason?...well...no problem! What a credulous bunch of guys. And more to the point, what a credulous bunch of reviewers have failed to notice this. Clearly the original 1957 release of 'The Bridge on the River Kwai' struck a cord. To portray an American, (British in the book), played by William Holden, as cynically detached from the war effort and yet ultimately humane was not new. Several Bogart films prepared audiences for this. But to sum it all up as 'Madness', this before Catch-22 and Mash, was ahead of it's time. This progressive spirit, some great cinematography, and a rousing combination of star-power and studio support make for an entertaining evening. But as a 'Closely Watched Film', it is almost as much train-wreck as classic.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    All you need is love.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    frizb
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/7/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Real Billy Shears Bridge on the River Kwai was written by a French author, Pierre Boulle. In the movie William Holden plays Commander Shears, an American captured when his ship the USS Houston is sunk. He is a POW in a camp full of British sailors and Australians and does his best to avoid any really hard work by becoming a grave digger. But then Alec Guinnes (Obi Wan Kenobi) shows up and is the senior officer, Lt Colonel Nicholson. He refuses to let any of the officers do manual labor, so Shears says that Nicholson is a maniac and makes an escape. Then Nicholson says that the Japanese camp commander is mad. When Shears reaches a British base in Ceylon it turns out that he is not an officer. He is just a sailor named Shears impersonating an officer in order to get better treatment. After he escaped he decided to continue playing an officer and was going to say that being lost in the jungle drove him mad. But the British Force 316, commandos, wanted Shears to lead them back to the POW camp so they could blow up the bridge that the prisoners were building. They made Shears a simulated major. Ian Fleming was the head of a force of British Commandoes in France called Force 54, along with "Q" and "U" and Bertrand, and the real James Bond, who Fleming once met according to his biographer. Shears, also called "Number One", gets to the bridge but not before telling the Professor he is as crazy as Nicholson. Nicholson tries to stop them from destroying the bridge. Lt Joyce kills a few Japanese soldiers and Nicholson fights with Lt Joyce. The Professor starts a mortar barrage, and Shears swims across the river to set off the explosives. Just as Shears reaches Nicholson they recognize each other, and Nicholson realizes that he is himself mad. Shears is killed by rifle fire and the mortar kills Nicholson who falls on the detonator and the bridge is destroyed. The British doctor stands on the riverbank and says everyone is mad. But earlier in the movie Shears is sitting on a Ceylon beach with a blonde nurse and a thermos of martinis. He complains jokingly about how the nurse gives him pills, powders, shots, thermometers and all he really needs is love. The nurse says "Yes that is true. All you really need is love!"
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    David Lean's First Best Picture Winner Is One Of The Greatest!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Humphrey Fish
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/5/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    After settling his differences with a Japanese PoW camp commander, a British colonel co-operates to oversee his men's construction of a railway bridge for their captors - while oblivious to a plan by the Allies to destroy it. Speaking as someone who has seen a wide variety of movies, this movie is awesome, totally and completely awesome! The Bridge On The River Kwai is a milestone in the history of film, the results are groundbreaking and breathtaking. I watched this on TCM as part of a Memorial Day celebration, and when I watched it, I was astonished by what I had seen. I had seen one of the greatest movies of all time, a movie that is directed by a master of epic films, the great British film director, David Lean. David Lean's first Best Picture winner is one of the greatest, and only a few years after this movie, he would direct his second Best Picture Winner, Lawrence Of Arabia, and three years after that, he would direct another great movie, Doctor Zhivago. Like Martin Scorsese, David Lean was a man who could do no wrong, I repeat, absolutely no wrong. This film also won numerous Academy Awards, the biggest ones being Best Picture, Best Director, and Best Actor. Alec Guinness won the Academy Award for Best Actor for his role as Col. Nicholson. And I can say that that win was a win that was well deserved, as he was great in this movie! William Holden also gives a good performance as the secondary protagonist, Shears. By the way, this movie was written by Carl Foreman and Michael Wilson, but they had to keep a low profile because a few years earlier, they had been accused of being Communists and they ended up getting blacklisted, much to their misfortune. David Lean's direction is masterful, it's the direction of a master film director. And as proof of that, he won the Academy Award For Best Director, and he would repeat that when he made Lawrence Of Arabia. David Lean was another one of those directors who if he had never existed, the movie industry would be a whole lot different. So all in all, The Bridge On The River Kwai is another movie that I can say is one of the greatest movies that I have ever seen. When I watched it, I was thrilled with it, every minute of it, from the very minute that it began to the very minute that it ended, I was absolutely impressed with every last second of it! And I guess that you know what this means, this means that you too are going to watch to watch this remarkably fabulous movie, because it's simply incredible, when you watch it, you will say that it is one of the greatest movies that you have ever seen, you will say that it deserved all of the Academy Awards that it won! Bravo to the remarkable David Lean for making a movie that I totally and completely loved! So if you haven't seen this movie, then take the time to watch it, because you will love it, you will say that it's one of the greatest movies you've ever seen! 10/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A World War II Odyssey
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Nick-leonardi
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/5/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    POW English soldiers are instructed by their rulers, the Japanese, to build a bridge. At the same time, a group of free Englishmen plan to destroy the bridge as soon as it's done. Majestic triumph at the Oscars (it won seven Academy Awards), as well as great commercial success, the film proves how David Lean brings a sense of epic and grandiose in everything he touches, inserting also themes like the meaning and weight of law, honor, pride, duty, and of course, the futility of war. Engaging even with a concept that might indicate otherwise (the construction of a bridge), the film boasts memorable performances by Alec Guinness and William Holden that compliment even more the importance of this British film. Based on the novel by Pierre Boulle.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The madness of war
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Christopher Reynolds
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/3/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Looking at this movie as a whole, it works brilliantly in conveying its theme of the madness of war, and how it drives good men to do bad things. Great direction, acting across the board, and cinematography all add a lot to the movie. **** SPOILERS ***** As I was watching the movie, for the first hour I felt increasingly annoyed by Col. Nicholson's "play by the rules and do what you're told" philosophy. Then as the movie went on, and we follow the British plan to blow up the bridge, I realised that this was how the movie wanted me to feel, and then the finale pulled off a brilliant reversal, and a sort of redemption for Nicholson. Standout scenes are the killing of the Japanese soldiers while clouds of bats whirl over the jungle, and, of course, the incredibly tense and powerful finale.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I hate the British! You are defeated but you have no shame. You are stubborn but you have no pride. You endure but you have no courage. I hate the British!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Ben Larson
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    What could one possibly add to the accolades this film has had heaped upon it. The fact that it may not be historically accurate is of no consequence, as it was made for the theater, not the History Channel. David Lean's master piece showing the madness of war stands the test of time. It swept the Oscars in 1958, winning Best Picture, Best Director for Lean, Best Actor for Alec Guinness in the role that defines him, and a Best Supporting Actor nomination for Sessue Hayakawa. It also took the awards for Writing. Music, Editing and Cinematography. Guinness was a perfect example of British pride. If you are going to do a job, then do it right. In that, he managed to take care of his men at the same time. William Holden was a perfect example of a soldier who just wanted to go home, as I am sure was the feeling of most. He recognized the madness of war long before the good doctor. This is a film that you can watch year after year and never get tired of it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Utter trash.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Blueghost
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    My uncle lived through the Bataan march, and was a POW in a Japanese labor camp. According to his daughter the one comment he made about this movie was as follows; "*Explicative*, we never had it that good!" He then reportedly stormed out of the TV room. You know, I have to say that I saw this film a couple times as a kid, and I never thought much of it. Initially I was going to title my review "Egomania 3" because that's kind of what we have here. The "drama" between the leads is manufactured in the extreme. The squaring off between Guiness and Mifune puts a grim smirk (if you could call it that) on this viewer's face. The film just doesn't ring true as to what happened to American, British, Australian, New Zealander and even French or Dutch POWs taken by the Japanese. The Imperial Japanese military didn't have the wanton industrial slaughter mechanism of the Nazi regime in Europe, but instead had the "work them until they're dead" ethic derived partially from Bushido, the code of the samurai. The acting was over the top. The story was so detached from reality as to be insulting, and by that I don't just mean my family's anecdote, but the interviews with survivors who went through that atrocity tell a very different and tragic story. During the Bataan march itself Japanese soldiers routinely shot anyone who looked weak or didn't look like they could make it, or rested. Then, once they got to the camps, it was hell baking in corrugated iron huts, laboring in hot and disease infested regions. And that's just for starters; the treatment, the food, the sheer and utter abuse; NONE of that is in this film. This film is about Hollywood parading its stars for what some idiot asinine producer thought would be a good patriotic film showing Americans and British being defiant in the face of the odds. Wrong. Look, I love Japanese culture. I love the food, I love the movies, I love the clean and polite society, and the people themselves, and I certainly don't hold any grudges whatsoever. In fact I want to retire there. And, I'm not the only one. Therefore, why not make a movie that shows the REAL EXPERIENCE? I can't answer that, but what I do know is that this piece of cinematic trash is just another notch in a southern Californian metroplex film industry that seems to never get anything write when it comes to history. What's even more insulting is that people have voted it so high as a quality film. Between the Russians not getting credit for their massive effort in what they call "the Great Patriotic War" and people like my family who were there when it happened, it's a wonder the entire film industry hasn't been run out of town and forced to setup shop in Mexico. Respectably shot, egotistical acting, poor SFX (notably the miniature), and a script that is just so idiotic I can't believe anyone green-lit this thing, it's a film that's definitely got some massive flaws. If you need to see a WW2 film about the Pacific Theatre, then check out Tora Tora Tora (Tiger Tiger Tiger). See this movie once, then do your brain a favor and pick up a book on the subject to learn what REALLY happened.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Ultimate Test of Survival-with some real life facts
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Admiraljames11
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie is the extremely accurate rendition of the incredible heroics of the brave men in Japanese prison camps that were made to build railroads. Many of these men after surviving battle on ships, ship sinkings, environmental and weather elements, were then subjected to cruel and inhuman treatment of Japanese soldiers. This movie is an accurate portrayal of these conditions with a few exceptions: (1) They did not whistle when entering the camp(although they did march in military formation, even when captured). (2) In the movie, Cdr. Shears tells the story of how he was on the USS Houston at the time she was sunk ,and how he and a Commander was separated from everyone else and drifted to the other side of the island. The commander died and he took his rank...etc. In real life, there was a USS Houston that was sunk and there was a Commander Maer that did drift to the other side of the island with a Seaman Elam ,which is consistent with Cdr. Shears story of the Houston sinking. However, both Cdr. Maer and Seaman Elam survived and were captured.(3) Real conditions of the prison camps were far more deplorable than depicted ,as well as the work details. (Men that couldn't walk were put on stretchers and given a hammer to bust up rock etc). (4) There were more American POWS than depicted in the movie, (the British often referred to the Americans as "Rabble"). and (5) They did not blow up the Bridge in the end and Col Nicholson certainly didn't turn on his own people to attempt to keep the bridge from blowing up. Still an awesome movie that is a must see.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A rather odd story,but entertaining
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    SmileysWorld
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I thoroughly enjoy this film,though I find it to be a rather odd story.Looking at it realistically,I find it hard to believe that a British commander,or any other commander,would give in to the will of the enemy under any circumstances,but I realize that even films based on true events can never be told 100% accurately,so I have no problem seeing as a great fictionalized account of true events.All the performances were excellent,particularly those of Alec Guiness and Bill Holden.If you are looking for a different type of war story,you have a winner in this one,but I would advise not reading up on how things really happened on The River Kwaiuntil after viewing it.It may make the film a disappointment to you.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A David Lean War Movie !
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Umar Mansoor Bajwa (umar_mansoor@yahoo.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The story is well laden with excitement, thrill and adventure. The characterization of different roles is uniquely perfect. The intrinsic conflicts, valor and stoic fortitude displayed by Col. Nicholson played by Alec Guinness is indeed commendable. Needless to mention is the daredevil nature of the commando action steered by a British Major to blow the bridge, laboriously built by another British Colonel is a striking coincidence. However, tragedy awaited Shears (William Holden) the US Navy Officer who had earlier miraculously escaped from the POW camp run by an intransigent Col. Saitu. Above all is the magnificent direction of Sir David Lean, who has captured marvelous locations for filming the army offices and bungalows situated at uniquely picturesque spots. It requires a keen eye to identify the meticulous details of the sets, like the revolving pedestal fan and wartime furniture, when Major Warden convinces Shears to join the death defying plot. The screenplay is a feast for the eyes. The dialogues and script goes hand in hand with the majestic flow of thrill in this commando mission movie. A must see for all war movie buffs.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Stretch Too Far
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    robinmcis966
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/9/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Certainly 'The Bridge on the River Kwai' has a gorgeous and epic sweep. If viewers simply want an entertaining evening, just cue it up and enjoy. For that matter, if you want encouragement, The AFI 100 once placed 'The Bridge' as the 13th best film ever and it has garnered more 4 of 4 and 5 of 5 star reviews than can be counted. However, The AFI now places the Film 37th and perhaps it is past due for re-vision. Although larger problems develop more slowly, it is a bad sign when there are not one, but two, obvious editing problems before the end of the credits! We are right behind the mounted machine gun on a train. The view is of the at least 2 carloads of wood for fuel and the engine. But now we see the same view with no fuel cars, OR EVEN THE ENGINE. Where did they go? In the same scene, the train now stops as the rail ends amidst about 15 workers. But now the dramatic score kicks in and there suddenly are several dozen workers on the rail line. In a low-budget film, this could be overlooked. But this is a major production that won an Oscar....for best direction AND editing! Moving on to the more serious issues, we are told that the British Commander (Alec Guinness) has been ordered to surrender, along with over 100 men and about a dozen officers. No explanation is offered for this. Really? He was just 'ordered to surrender'? According to historical estimates, over 100,000 men died building this railroad. For that matter, although there are ample references to men dying in this prison camp, all the men who have already been imprisoned there, even those in the infirmary, look well-fed, some even in 'beef-cake' condition. Again, this sort of over-sight would be fine for a 2nd rate 'action-genre' flick. It's Bill Holden-he's tanned, buff, and sweaty. Enough said? The central problem with 'The Bridge on the River Kwai' has at least been occasionally mentioned. Guinness' Commander not only helps the Japanese build a crucial bridge in their supply line, he goes to great lengths to make sure the bridge will hold and be finished on time. This to prove superior British logistics and character. Along the way, he is warned of the possibly treasonous nature of his collaboration, and yet he continues on without a doubt. Nothing is made of this...he just comes across as 'funny that way'. However, as far as I know, it has not been pointed out that all of his men and his officers would therefore have had to join him in this inexplicable lapse. This despite what appears to be a very democratic officers meeting and over two months time to reflect on the matter. Treason?...well...no problem! What a credulous bunch of guys. And more to the point, what a credulous bunch of reviewers have failed to notice this. Clearly the original 1957 release of 'The Bridge on the River Kwai' struck a cord. To portray an American, (British in the book), played by William Holden, as cynically detached from the war effort and yet ultimately humane was not new. Several Bogart films prepared audiences for this. But to sum it all up as 'Madness', this before Catch-22 and Mash, was ahead of it's time. This progressive spirit, some great cinematography, and a rousing combination of star-power and studio support make for an entertaining evening. But as a 'Closely Watched Film', it is almost as much train-wreck as classic.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    All you need is love.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    frizb
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/7/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Real Billy Shears Bridge on the River Kwai was written by a French author, Pierre Boulle. In the movie William Holden plays Commander Shears, an American captured when his ship the USS Houston is sunk. He is a POW in a camp full of British sailors and Australians and does his best to avoid any really hard work by becoming a grave digger. But then Alec Guinnes (Obi Wan Kenobi) shows up and is the senior officer, Lt Colonel Nicholson. He refuses to let any of the officers do manual labor, so Shears says that Nicholson is a maniac and makes an escape. Then Nicholson says that the Japanese camp commander is mad. When Shears reaches a British base in Ceylon it turns out that he is not an officer. He is just a sailor named Shears impersonating an officer in order to get better treatment. After he escaped he decided to continue playing an officer and was going to say that being lost in the jungle drove him mad. But the British Force 316, commandos, wanted Shears to lead them back to the POW camp so they could blow up the bridge that the prisoners were building. They made Shears a simulated major. Ian Fleming was the head of a force of British Commandoes in France called Force 54, along with "Q" and "U" and Bertrand, and the real James Bond, who Fleming once met according to his biographer. Shears, also called "Number One", gets to the bridge but not before telling the Professor he is as crazy as Nicholson. Nicholson tries to stop them from destroying the bridge. Lt Joyce kills a few Japanese soldiers and Nicholson fights with Lt Joyce. The Professor starts a mortar barrage, and Shears swims across the river to set off the explosives. Just as Shears reaches Nicholson they recognize each other, and Nicholson realizes that he is himself mad. Shears is killed by rifle fire and the mortar kills Nicholson who falls on the detonator and the bridge is destroyed. The British doctor stands on the riverbank and says everyone is mad. But earlier in the movie Shears is sitting on a Ceylon beach with a blonde nurse and a thermos of martinis. He complains jokingly about how the nurse gives him pills, powders, shots, thermometers and all he really needs is love. The nurse says "Yes that is true. All you really need is love!"
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    David Lean's First Best Picture Winner Is One Of The Greatest!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Humphrey Fish
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/5/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    After settling his differences with a Japanese PoW camp commander, a British colonel co-operates to oversee his men's construction of a railway bridge for their captors - while oblivious to a plan by the Allies to destroy it. Speaking as someone who has seen a wide variety of movies, this movie is awesome, totally and completely awesome! The Bridge On The River Kwai is a milestone in the history of film, the results are groundbreaking and breathtaking. I watched this on TCM as part of a Memorial Day celebration, and when I watched it, I was astonished by what I had seen. I had seen one of the greatest movies of all time, a movie that is directed by a master of epic films, the great British film director, David Lean. David Lean's first Best Picture winner is one of the greatest, and only a few years after this movie, he would direct his second Best Picture Winner, Lawrence Of Arabia, and three years after that, he would direct another great movie, Doctor Zhivago. Like Martin Scorsese, David Lean was a man who could do no wrong, I repeat, absolutely no wrong. This film also won numerous Academy Awards, the biggest ones being Best Picture, Best Director, and Best Actor. Alec Guinness won the Academy Award for Best Actor for his role as Col. Nicholson. And I can say that that win was a win that was well deserved, as he was great in this movie! William Holden also gives a good performance as the secondary protagonist, Shears. By the way, this movie was written by Carl Foreman and Michael Wilson, but they had to keep a low profile because a few years earlier, they had been accused of being Communists and they ended up getting blacklisted, much to their misfortune. David Lean's direction is masterful, it's the direction of a master film director. And as proof of that, he won the Academy Award For Best Director, and he would repeat that when he made Lawrence Of Arabia. David Lean was another one of those directors who if he had never existed, the movie industry would be a whole lot different. So all in all, The Bridge On The River Kwai is another movie that I can say is one of the greatest movies that I have ever seen. When I watched it, I was thrilled with it, every minute of it, from the very minute that it began to the very minute that it ended, I was absolutely impressed with every last second of it! And I guess that you know what this means, this means that you too are going to watch to watch this remarkably fabulous movie, because it's simply incredible, when you watch it, you will say that it is one of the greatest movies that you have ever seen, you will say that it deserved all of the Academy Awards that it won! Bravo to the remarkable David Lean for making a movie that I totally and completely loved! So if you haven't seen this movie, then take the time to watch it, because you will love it, you will say that it's one of the greatest movies you've ever seen! 10/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A World War II Odyssey
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Nick-leonardi
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/5/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    POW English soldiers are instructed by their rulers, the Japanese, to build a bridge. At the same time, a group of free Englishmen plan to destroy the bridge as soon as it's done. Majestic triumph at the Oscars (it won seven Academy Awards), as well as great commercial success, the film proves how David Lean brings a sense of epic and grandiose in everything he touches, inserting also themes like the meaning and weight of law, honor, pride, duty, and of course, the futility of war. Engaging even with a concept that might indicate otherwise (the construction of a bridge), the film boasts memorable performances by Alec Guinness and William Holden that compliment even more the importance of this British film. Based on the novel by Pierre Boulle.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The madness of war
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Christopher Reynolds
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/3/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Looking at this movie as a whole, it works brilliantly in conveying its theme of the madness of war, and how it drives good men to do bad things. Great direction, acting across the board, and cinematography all add a lot to the movie. **** SPOILERS ***** As I was watching the movie, for the first hour I felt increasingly annoyed by Col. Nicholson's "play by the rules and do what you're told" philosophy. Then as the movie went on, and we follow the British plan to blow up the bridge, I realised that this was how the movie wanted me to feel, and then the finale pulled off a brilliant reversal, and a sort of redemption for Nicholson. Standout scenes are the killing of the Japanese soldiers while clouds of bats whirl over the jungle, and, of course, the incredibly tense and powerful finale.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I hate the British! You are defeated but you have no shame. You are stubborn but you have no pride. You endure but you have no courage. I hate the British!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Ben Larson
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    What could one possibly add to the accolades this film has had heaped upon it. The fact that it may not be historically accurate is of no consequence, as it was made for the theater, not the History Channel. David Lean's master piece showing the madness of war stands the test of time. It swept the Oscars in 1958, winning Best Picture, Best Director for Lean, Best Actor for Alec Guinness in the role that defines him, and a Best Supporting Actor nomination for Sessue Hayakawa. It also took the awards for Writing. Music, Editing and Cinematography. Guinness was a perfect example of British pride. If you are going to do a job, then do it right. In that, he managed to take care of his men at the same time. William Holden was a perfect example of a soldier who just wanted to go home, as I am sure was the feeling of most. He recognized the madness of war long before the good doctor. This is a film that you can watch year after year and never get tired of it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Utter trash.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Blueghost
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    My uncle lived through the Bataan march, and was a POW in a Japanese labor camp. According to his daughter the one comment he made about this movie was as follows; "*Explicative*, we never had it that good!" He then reportedly stormed out of the TV room. You know, I have to say that I saw this film a couple times as a kid, and I never thought much of it. Initially I was going to title my review "Egomania 3" because that's kind of what we have here. The "drama" between the leads is manufactured in the extreme. The squaring off between Guiness and Mifune puts a grim smirk (if you could call it that) on this viewer's face. The film just doesn't ring true as to what happened to American, British, Australian, New Zealander and even French or Dutch POWs taken by the Japanese. The Imperial Japanese military didn't have the wanton industrial slaughter mechanism of the Nazi regime in Europe, but instead had the "work them until they're dead" ethic derived partially from Bushido, the code of the samurai. The acting was over the top. The story was so detached from reality as to be insulting, and by that I don't just mean my family's anecdote, but the interviews with survivors who went through that atrocity tell a very different and tragic story. During the Bataan march itself Japanese soldiers routinely shot anyone who looked weak or didn't look like they could make it, or rested. Then, once they got to the camps, it was hell baking in corrugated iron huts, laboring in hot and disease infested regions. And that's just for starters; the treatment, the food, the sheer and utter abuse; NONE of that is in this film. This film is about Hollywood parading its stars for what some idiot asinine producer thought would be a good patriotic film showing Americans and British being defiant in the face of the odds. Wrong. Look, I love Japanese culture. I love the food, I love the movies, I love the clean and polite society, and the people themselves, and I certainly don't hold any grudges whatsoever. In fact I want to retire there. And, I'm not the only one. Therefore, why not make a movie that shows the REAL EXPERIENCE? I can't answer that, but what I do know is that this piece of cinematic trash is just another notch in a southern Californian metroplex film industry that seems to never get anything write when it comes to history. What's even more insulting is that people have voted it so high as a quality film. Between the Russians not getting credit for their massive effort in what they call "the Great Patriotic War" and people like my family who were there when it happened, it's a wonder the entire film industry hasn't been run out of town and forced to setup shop in Mexico. Respectably shot, egotistical acting, poor SFX (notably the miniature), and a script that is just so idiotic I can't believe anyone green-lit this thing, it's a film that's definitely got some massive flaws. If you need to see a WW2 film about the Pacific Theatre, then check out Tora Tora Tora (Tiger Tiger Tiger). See this movie once, then do your brain a favor and pick up a book on the subject to learn what REALLY happened.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Ultimate Test of Survival-with some real life facts
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Admiraljames11
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie is the extremely accurate rendition of the incredible heroics of the brave men in Japanese prison camps that were made to build railroads. Many of these men after surviving battle on ships, ship sinkings, environmental and weather elements, were then subjected to cruel and inhuman treatment of Japanese soldiers. This movie is an accurate portrayal of these conditions with a few exceptions: (1) They did not whistle when entering the camp(although they did march in military formation, even when captured). (2) In the movie, Cdr. Shears tells the story of how he was on the USS Houston at the time she was sunk ,and how he and a Commander was separated from everyone else and drifted to the other side of the island. The commander died and he took his rank...etc. In real life, there was a USS Houston that was sunk and there was a Commander Maer that did drift to the other side of the island with a Seaman Elam ,which is consistent with Cdr. Shears story of the Houston sinking. However, both Cdr. Maer and Seaman Elam survived and were captured.(3) Real conditions of the prison camps were far more deplorable than depicted ,as well as the work details. (Men that couldn't walk were put on stretchers and given a hammer to bust up rock etc). (4) There were more American POWS than depicted in the movie, (the British often referred to the Americans as "Rabble"). and (5) They did not blow up the Bridge in the end and Col Nicholson certainly didn't turn on his own people to attempt to keep the bridge from blowing up. Still an awesome movie that is a must see.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A rather odd story,but entertaining
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    SmileysWorld
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I thoroughly enjoy this film,though I find it to be a rather odd story.Looking at it realistically,I find it hard to believe that a British commander,or any other commander,would give in to the will of the enemy under any circumstances,but I realize that even films based on true events can never be told 100% accurately,so I have no problem seeing as a great fictionalized account of true events.All the performances were excellent,particularly those of Alec Guiness and Bill Holden.If you are looking for a different type of war story,you have a winner in this one,but I would advise not reading up on how things really happened on The River Kwaiuntil after viewing it.It may make the film a disappointment to you.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A David Lean War Movie !
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Umar Mansoor Bajwa (umar_mansoor@yahoo.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The story is well laden with excitement, thrill and adventure. The characterization of different roles is uniquely perfect. The intrinsic conflicts, valor and stoic fortitude displayed by Col. Nicholson played by Alec Guinness is indeed commendable. Needless to mention is the daredevil nature of the commando action steered by a British Major to blow the bridge, laboriously built by another British Colonel is a striking coincidence. However, tragedy awaited Shears (William Holden) the US Navy Officer who had earlier miraculously escaped from the POW camp run by an intransigent Col. Saitu. Above all is the magnificent direction of Sir David Lean, who has captured marvelous locations for filming the army offices and bungalows situated at uniquely picturesque spots. It requires a keen eye to identify the meticulous details of the sets, like the revolving pedestal fan and wartime furniture, when Major Warden convinces Shears to join the death defying plot. The screenplay is a feast for the eyes. The dialogues and script goes hand in hand with the majestic flow of thrill in this commando mission movie. A must see for all war movie buffs.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Stretch Too Far
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    robinmcis966
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/9/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Certainly 'The Bridge on the River Kwai' has a gorgeous and epic sweep. If viewers simply want an entertaining evening, just cue it up and enjoy. For that matter, if you want encouragement, The AFI 100 once placed 'The Bridge' as the 13th best film ever and it has garnered more 4 of 4 and 5 of 5 star reviews than can be counted. However, The AFI now places the Film 37th and perhaps it is past due for re-vision. Although larger problems develop more slowly, it is a bad sign when there are not one, but two, obvious editing problems before the end of the credits! We are right behind the mounted machine gun on a train. The view is of the at least 2 carloads of wood for fuel and the engine. But now we see the same view with no fuel cars, OR EVEN THE ENGINE. Where did they go? In the same scene, the train now stops as the rail ends amidst about 15 workers. But now the dramatic score kicks in and there suddenly are several dozen workers on the rail line. In a low-budget film, this could be overlooked. But this is a major production that won an Oscar....for best direction AND editing! Moving on to the more serious issues, we are told that the British Commander (Alec Guinness) has been ordered to surrender, along with over 100 men and about a dozen officers. No explanation is offered for this. Really? He was just 'ordered to surrender'? According to historical estimates, over 100,000 men died building this railroad. For that matter, although there are ample references to men dying in this prison camp, all the men who have already been imprisoned there, even those in the infirmary, look well-fed, some even in 'beef-cake' condition. Again, this sort of over-sight would be fine for a 2nd rate 'action-genre' flick. It's Bill Holden-he's tanned, buff, and sweaty. Enough said? The central problem with 'The Bridge on the River Kwai' has at least been occasionally mentioned. Guinness' Commander not only helps the Japanese build a crucial bridge in their supply line, he goes to great lengths to make sure the bridge will hold and be finished on time. This to prove superior British logistics and character. Along the way, he is warned of the possibly treasonous nature of his collaboration, and yet he continues on without a doubt. Nothing is made of this...he just comes across as 'funny that way'. However, as far as I know, it has not been pointed out that all of his men and his officers would therefore have had to join him in this inexplicable lapse. This despite what appears to be a very democratic officers meeting and over two months time to reflect on the matter. Treason?...well...no problem! What a credulous bunch of guys. And more to the point, what a credulous bunch of reviewers have failed to notice this. Clearly the original 1957 release of 'The Bridge on the River Kwai' struck a cord. To portray an American, (British in the book), played by William Holden, as cynically detached from the war effort and yet ultimately humane was not new. Several Bogart films prepared audiences for this. But to sum it all up as 'Madness', this before Catch-22 and Mash, was ahead of it's time. This progressive spirit, some great cinematography, and a rousing combination of star-power and studio support make for an entertaining evening. But as a 'Closely Watched Film', it is almost as much train-wreck as classic.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    All you need is love.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    frizb
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/7/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Real Billy Shears Bridge on the River Kwai was written by a French author, Pierre Boulle. In the movie William Holden plays Commander Shears, an American captured when his ship the USS Houston is sunk. He is a POW in a camp full of British sailors and Australians and does his best to avoid any really hard work by becoming a grave digger. But then Alec Guinnes (Obi Wan Kenobi) shows up and is the senior officer, Lt Colonel Nicholson. He refuses to let any of the officers do manual labor, so Shears says that Nicholson is a maniac and makes an escape. Then Nicholson says that the Japanese camp commander is mad. When Shears reaches a British base in Ceylon it turns out that he is not an officer. He is just a sailor named Shears impersonating an officer in order to get better treatment. After he escaped he decided to continue playing an officer and was going to say that being lost in the jungle drove him mad. But the British Force 316, commandos, wanted Shears to lead them back to the POW camp so they could blow up the bridge that the prisoners were building. They made Shears a simulated major. Ian Fleming was the head of a force of British Commandoes in France called Force 54, along with "Q" and "U" and Bertrand, and the real James Bond, who Fleming once met according to his biographer. Shears, also called "Number One", gets to the bridge but not before telling the Professor he is as crazy as Nicholson. Nicholson tries to stop them from destroying the bridge. Lt Joyce kills a few Japanese soldiers and Nicholson fights with Lt Joyce. The Professor starts a mortar barrage, and Shears swims across the river to set off the explosives. Just as Shears reaches Nicholson they recognize each other, and Nicholson realizes that he is himself mad. Shears is killed by rifle fire and the mortar kills Nicholson who falls on the detonator and the bridge is destroyed. The British doctor stands on the riverbank and says everyone is mad. But earlier in the movie Shears is sitting on a Ceylon beach with a blonde nurse and a thermos of martinis. He complains jokingly about how the nurse gives him pills, powders, shots, thermometers and all he really needs is love. The nurse says "Yes that is true. All you really need is love!"
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    David Lean's First Best Picture Winner Is One Of The Greatest!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Humphrey Fish
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/5/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    After settling his differences with a Japanese PoW camp commander, a British colonel co-operates to oversee his men's construction of a railway bridge for their captors - while oblivious to a plan by the Allies to destroy it. Speaking as someone who has seen a wide variety of movies, this movie is awesome, totally and completely awesome! The Bridge On The River Kwai is a milestone in the history of film, the results are groundbreaking and breathtaking. I watched this on TCM as part of a Memorial Day celebration, and when I watched it, I was astonished by what I had seen. I had seen one of the greatest movies of all time, a movie that is directed by a master of epic films, the great British film director, David Lean. David Lean's first Best Picture winner is one of the greatest, and only a few years after this movie, he would direct his second Best Picture Winner, Lawrence Of Arabia, and three years after that, he would direct another great movie, Doctor Zhivago. Like Martin Scorsese, David Lean was a man who could do no wrong, I repeat, absolutely no wrong. This film also won numerous Academy Awards, the biggest ones being Best Picture, Best Director, and Best Actor. Alec Guinness won the Academy Award for Best Actor for his role as Col. Nicholson. And I can say that that win was a win that was well deserved, as he was great in this movie! William Holden also gives a good performance as the secondary protagonist, Shears. By the way, this movie was written by Carl Foreman and Michael Wilson, but they had to keep a low profile because a few years earlier, they had been accused of being Communists and they ended up getting blacklisted, much to their misfortune. David Lean's direction is masterful, it's the direction of a master film director. And as proof of that, he won the Academy Award For Best Director, and he would repeat that when he made Lawrence Of Arabia. David Lean was another one of those directors who if he had never existed, the movie industry would be a whole lot different. So all in all, The Bridge On The River Kwai is another movie that I can say is one of the greatest movies that I have ever seen. When I watched it, I was thrilled with it, every minute of it, from the very minute that it began to the very minute that it ended, I was absolutely impressed with every last second of it! And I guess that you know what this means, this means that you too are going to watch to watch this remarkably fabulous movie, because it's simply incredible, when you watch it, you will say that it is one of the greatest movies that you have ever seen, you will say that it deserved all of the Academy Awards that it won! Bravo to the remarkable David Lean for making a movie that I totally and completely loved! So if you haven't seen this movie, then take the time to watch it, because you will love it, you will say that it's one of the greatest movies you've ever seen! 10/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A World War II Odyssey
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Nick-leonardi
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/5/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    POW English soldiers are instructed by their rulers, the Japanese, to build a bridge. At the same time, a group of free Englishmen plan to destroy the bridge as soon as it's done. Majestic triumph at the Oscars (it won seven Academy Awards), as well as great commercial success, the film proves how David Lean brings a sense of epic and grandiose in everything he touches, inserting also themes like the meaning and weight of law, honor, pride, duty, and of course, the futility of war. Engaging even with a concept that might indicate otherwise (the construction of a bridge), the film boasts memorable performances by Alec Guinness and William Holden that compliment even more the importance of this British film. Based on the novel by Pierre Boulle.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The madness of war
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Christopher Reynolds
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/3/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Looking at this movie as a whole, it works brilliantly in conveying its theme of the madness of war, and how it drives good men to do bad things. Great direction, acting across the board, and cinematography all add a lot to the movie. **** SPOILERS ***** As I was watching the movie, for the first hour I felt increasingly annoyed by Col. Nicholson's "play by the rules and do what you're told" philosophy. Then as the movie went on, and we follow the British plan to blow up the bridge, I realised that this was how the movie wanted me to feel, and then the finale pulled off a brilliant reversal, and a sort of redemption for Nicholson. Standout scenes are the killing of the Japanese soldiers while clouds of bats whirl over the jungle, and, of course, the incredibly tense and powerful finale.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I hate the British! You are defeated but you have no shame. You are stubborn but you have no pride. You endure but you have no courage. I hate the British!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Ben Larson
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    What could one possibly add to the accolades this film has had heaped upon it. The fact that it may not be historically accurate is of no consequence, as it was made for the theater, not the History Channel. David Lean's master piece showing the madness of war stands the test of time. It swept the Oscars in 1958, winning Best Picture, Best Director for Lean, Best Actor for Alec Guinness in the role that defines him, and a Best Supporting Actor nomination for Sessue Hayakawa. It also took the awards for Writing. Music, Editing and Cinematography. Guinness was a perfect example of British pride. If you are going to do a job, then do it right. In that, he managed to take care of his men at the same time. William Holden was a perfect example of a soldier who just wanted to go home, as I am sure was the feeling of most. He recognized the madness of war long before the good doctor. This is a film that you can watch year after year and never get tired of it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Utter trash.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Blueghost
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    My uncle lived through the Bataan march, and was a POW in a Japanese labor camp. According to his daughter the one comment he made about this movie was as follows; "*Explicative*, we never had it that good!" He then reportedly stormed out of the TV room. You know, I have to say that I saw this film a couple times as a kid, and I never thought much of it. Initially I was going to title my review "Egomania 3" because that's kind of what we have here. The "drama" between the leads is manufactured in the extreme. The squaring off between Guiness and Mifune puts a grim smirk (if you could call it that) on this viewer's face. The film just doesn't ring true as to what happened to American, British, Australian, New Zealander and even French or Dutch POWs taken by the Japanese. The Imperial Japanese military didn't have the wanton industrial slaughter mechanism of the Nazi regime in Europe, but instead had the "work them until they're dead" ethic derived partially from Bushido, the code of the samurai. The acting was over the top. The story was so detached from reality as to be insulting, and by that I don't just mean my family's anecdote, but the interviews with survivors who went through that atrocity tell a very different and tragic story. During the Bataan march itself Japanese soldiers routinely shot anyone who looked weak or didn't look like they could make it, or rested. Then, once they got to the camps, it was hell baking in corrugated iron huts, laboring in hot and disease infested regions. And that's just for starters; the treatment, the food, the sheer and utter abuse; NONE of that is in this film. This film is about Hollywood parading its stars for what some idiot asinine producer thought would be a good patriotic film showing Americans and British being defiant in the face of the odds. Wrong. Look, I love Japanese culture. I love the food, I love the movies, I love the clean and polite society, and the people themselves, and I certainly don't hold any grudges whatsoever. In fact I want to retire there. And, I'm not the only one. Therefore, why not make a movie that shows the REAL EXPERIENCE? I can't answer that, but what I do know is that this piece of cinematic trash is just another notch in a southern Californian metroplex film industry that seems to never get anything write when it comes to history. What's even more insulting is that people have voted it so high as a quality film. Between the Russians not getting credit for their massive effort in what they call "the Great Patriotic War" and people like my family who were there when it happened, it's a wonder the entire film industry hasn't been run out of town and forced to setup shop in Mexico. Respectably shot, egotistical acting, poor SFX (notably the miniature), and a script that is just so idiotic I can't believe anyone green-lit this thing, it's a film that's definitely got some massive flaws. If you need to see a WW2 film about the Pacific Theatre, then check out Tora Tora Tora (Tiger Tiger Tiger). See this movie once, then do your brain a favor and pick up a book on the subject to learn what REALLY happened.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Ultimate Test of Survival-with some real life facts
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Admiraljames11
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie is the extremely accurate rendition of the incredible heroics of the brave men in Japanese prison camps that were made to build railroads. Many of these men after surviving battle on ships, ship sinkings, environmental and weather elements, were then subjected to cruel and inhuman treatment of Japanese soldiers. This movie is an accurate portrayal of these conditions with a few exceptions: (1) They did not whistle when entering the camp(although they did march in military formation, even when captured). (2) In the movie, Cdr. Shears tells the story of how he was on the USS Houston at the time she was sunk ,and how he and a Commander was separated from everyone else and drifted to the other side of the island. The commander died and he took his rank...etc. In real life, there was a USS Houston that was sunk and there was a Commander Maer that did drift to the other side of the island with a Seaman Elam ,which is consistent with Cdr. Shears story of the Houston sinking. However, both Cdr. Maer and Seaman Elam survived and were captured.(3) Real conditions of the prison camps were far more deplorable than depicted ,as well as the work details. (Men that couldn't walk were put on stretchers and given a hammer to bust up rock etc). (4) There were more American POWS than depicted in the movie, (the British often referred to the Americans as "Rabble"). and (5) They did not blow up the Bridge in the end and Col Nicholson certainly didn't turn on his own people to attempt to keep the bridge from blowing up. Still an awesome movie that is a must see.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A rather odd story,but entertaining
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    SmileysWorld
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I thoroughly enjoy this film,though I find it to be a rather odd story.Looking at it realistically,I find it hard to believe that a British commander,or any other commander,would give in to the will of the enemy under any circumstances,but I realize that even films based on true events can never be told 100% accurately,so I have no problem seeing as a great fictionalized account of true events.All the performances were excellent,particularly those of Alec Guiness and Bill Holden.If you are looking for a different type of war story,you have a winner in this one,but I would advise not reading up on how things really happened on The River Kwaiuntil after viewing it.It may make the film a disappointment to you.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A David Lean War Movie !
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Umar Mansoor Bajwa (umar_mansoor@yahoo.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The story is well laden with excitement, thrill and adventure. The characterization of different roles is uniquely perfect. The intrinsic conflicts, valor and stoic fortitude displayed by Col. Nicholson played by Alec Guinness is indeed commendable. Needless to mention is the daredevil nature of the commando action steered by a British Major to blow the bridge, laboriously built by another British Colonel is a striking coincidence. However, tragedy awaited Shears (William Holden) the US Navy Officer who had earlier miraculously escaped from the POW camp run by an intransigent Col. Saitu. Above all is the magnificent direction of Sir David Lean, who has captured marvelous locations for filming the army offices and bungalows situated at uniquely picturesque spots. It requires a keen eye to identify the meticulous details of the sets, like the revolving pedestal fan and wartime furniture, when Major Warden convinces Shears to join the death defying plot. The screenplay is a feast for the eyes. The dialogues and script goes hand in hand with the majestic flow of thrill in this commando mission movie. A must see for all war movie buffs.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Stretch Too Far
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    robinmcis966
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/9/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Certainly 'The Bridge on the River Kwai' has a gorgeous and epic sweep. If viewers simply want an entertaining evening, just cue it up and enjoy. For that matter, if you want encouragement, The AFI 100 once placed 'The Bridge' as the 13th best film ever and it has garnered more 4 of 4 and 5 of 5 star reviews than can be counted. However, The AFI now places the Film 37th and perhaps it is past due for re-vision. Although larger problems develop more slowly, it is a bad sign when there are not one, but two, obvious editing problems before the end of the credits! We are right behind the mounted machine gun on a train. The view is of the at least 2 carloads of wood for fuel and the engine. But now we see the same view with no fuel cars, OR EVEN THE ENGINE. Where did they go? In the same scene, the train now stops as the rail ends amidst about 15 workers. But now the dramatic score kicks in and there suddenly are several dozen workers on the rail line. In a low-budget film, this could be overlooked. But this is a major production that won an Oscar....for best direction AND editing! Moving on to the more serious issues, we are told that the British Commander (Alec Guinness) has been ordered to surrender, along with over 100 men and about a dozen officers. No explanation is offered for this. Really? He was just 'ordered to surrender'? According to historical estimates, over 100,000 men died building this railroad. For that matter, although there are ample references to men dying in this prison camp, all the men who have already been imprisoned there, even those in the infirmary, look well-fed, some even in 'beef-cake' condition. Again, this sort of over-sight would be fine for a 2nd rate 'action-genre' flick. It's Bill Holden-he's tanned, buff, and sweaty. Enough said? The central problem with 'The Bridge on the River Kwai' has at least been occasionally mentioned. Guinness' Commander not only helps the Japanese build a crucial bridge in their supply line, he goes to great lengths to make sure the bridge will hold and be finished on time. This to prove superior British logistics and character. Along the way, he is warned of the possibly treasonous nature of his collaboration, and yet he continues on without a doubt. Nothing is made of this...he just comes across as 'funny that way'. However, as far as I know, it has not been pointed out that all of his men and his officers would therefore have had to join him in this inexplicable lapse. This despite what appears to be a very democratic officers meeting and over two months time to reflect on the matter. Treason?...well...no problem! What a credulous bunch of guys. And more to the point, what a credulous bunch of reviewers have failed to notice this. Clearly the original 1957 release of 'The Bridge on the River Kwai' struck a cord. To portray an American, (British in the book), played by William Holden, as cynically detached from the war effort and yet ultimately humane was not new. Several Bogart films prepared audiences for this. But to sum it all up as 'Madness', this before Catch-22 and Mash, was ahead of it's time. This progressive spirit, some great cinematography, and a rousing combination of star-power and studio support make for an entertaining evening. But as a 'Closely Watched Film', it is almost as much train-wreck as classic.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    All you need is love.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    frizb
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/7/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Real Billy Shears Bridge on the River Kwai was written by a French author, Pierre Boulle. In the movie William Holden plays Commander Shears, an American captured when his ship the USS Houston is sunk. He is a POW in a camp full of British sailors and Australians and does his best to avoid any really hard work by becoming a grave digger. But then Alec Guinnes (Obi Wan Kenobi) shows up and is the senior officer, Lt Colonel Nicholson. He refuses to let any of the officers do manual labor, so Shears says that Nicholson is a maniac and makes an escape. Then Nicholson says that the Japanese camp commander is mad. When Shears reaches a British base in Ceylon it turns out that he is not an officer. He is just a sailor named Shears impersonating an officer in order to get better treatment. After he escaped he decided to continue playing an officer and was going to say that being lost in the jungle drove him mad. But the British Force 316, commandos, wanted Shears to lead them back to the POW camp so they could blow up the bridge that the prisoners were building. They made Shears a simulated major. Ian Fleming was the head of a force of British Commandoes in France called Force 54, along with "Q" and "U" and Bertrand, and the real James Bond, who Fleming once met according to his biographer. Shears, also called "Number One", gets to the bridge but not before telling the Professor he is as crazy as Nicholson. Nicholson tries to stop them from destroying the bridge. Lt Joyce kills a few Japanese soldiers and Nicholson fights with Lt Joyce. The Professor starts a mortar barrage, and Shears swims across the river to set off the explosives. Just as Shears reaches Nicholson they recognize each other, and Nicholson realizes that he is himself mad. Shears is killed by rifle fire and the mortar kills Nicholson who falls on the detonator and the bridge is destroyed. The British doctor stands on the riverbank and says everyone is mad. But earlier in the movie Shears is sitting on a Ceylon beach with a blonde nurse and a thermos of martinis. He complains jokingly about how the nurse gives him pills, powders, shots, thermometers and all he really needs is love. The nurse says "Yes that is true. All you really need is love!"
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    David Lean's First Best Picture Winner Is One Of The Greatest!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Humphrey Fish
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/5/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    After settling his differences with a Japanese PoW camp commander, a British colonel co-operates to oversee his men's construction of a railway bridge for their captors - while oblivious to a plan by the Allies to destroy it. Speaking as someone who has seen a wide variety of movies, this movie is awesome, totally and completely awesome! The Bridge On The River Kwai is a milestone in the history of film, the results are groundbreaking and breathtaking. I watched this on TCM as part of a Memorial Day celebration, and when I watched it, I was astonished by what I had seen. I had seen one of the greatest movies of all time, a movie that is directed by a master of epic films, the great British film director, David Lean. David Lean's first Best Picture winner is one of the greatest, and only a few years after this movie, he would direct his second Best Picture Winner, Lawrence Of Arabia, and three years after that, he would direct another great movie, Doctor Zhivago. Like Martin Scorsese, David Lean was a man who could do no wrong, I repeat, absolutely no wrong. This film also won numerous Academy Awards, the biggest ones being Best Picture, Best Director, and Best Actor. Alec Guinness won the Academy Award for Best Actor for his role as Col. Nicholson. And I can say that that win was a win that was well deserved, as he was great in this movie! William Holden also gives a good performance as the secondary protagonist, Shears. By the way, this movie was written by Carl Foreman and Michael Wilson, but they had to keep a low profile because a few years earlier, they had been accused of being Communists and they ended up getting blacklisted, much to their misfortune. David Lean's direction is masterful, it's the direction of a master film director. And as proof of that, he won the Academy Award For Best Director, and he would repeat that when he made Lawrence Of Arabia. David Lean was another one of those directors who if he had never existed, the movie industry would be a whole lot different. So all in all, The Bridge On The River Kwai is another movie that I can say is one of the greatest movies that I have ever seen. When I watched it, I was thrilled with it, every minute of it, from the very minute that it began to the very minute that it ended, I was absolutely impressed with every last second of it! And I guess that you know what this means, this means that you too are going to watch to watch this remarkably fabulous movie, because it's simply incredible, when you watch it, you will say that it is one of the greatest movies that you have ever seen, you will say that it deserved all of the Academy Awards that it won! Bravo to the remarkable David Lean for making a movie that I totally and completely loved! So if you haven't seen this movie, then take the time to watch it, because you will love it, you will say that it's one of the greatest movies you've ever seen! 10/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A World War II Odyssey
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Nick-leonardi
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/5/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    POW English soldiers are instructed by their rulers, the Japanese, to build a bridge. At the same time, a group of free Englishmen plan to destroy the bridge as soon as it's done. Majestic triumph at the Oscars (it won seven Academy Awards), as well as great commercial success, the film proves how David Lean brings a sense of epic and grandiose in everything he touches, inserting also themes like the meaning and weight of law, honor, pride, duty, and of course, the futility of war. Engaging even with a concept that might indicate otherwise (the construction of a bridge), the film boasts memorable performances by Alec Guinness and William Holden that compliment even more the importance of this British film. Based on the novel by Pierre Boulle.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The madness of war
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Christopher Reynolds
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/3/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Looking at this movie as a whole, it works brilliantly in conveying its theme of the madness of war, and how it drives good men to do bad things. Great direction, acting across the board, and cinematography all add a lot to the movie. **** SPOILERS ***** As I was watching the movie, for the first hour I felt increasingly annoyed by Col. Nicholson's "play by the rules and do what you're told" philosophy. Then as the movie went on, and we follow the British plan to blow up the bridge, I realised that this was how the movie wanted me to feel, and then the finale pulled off a brilliant reversal, and a sort of redemption for Nicholson. Standout scenes are the killing of the Japanese soldiers while clouds of bats whirl over the jungle, and, of course, the incredibly tense and powerful finale.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I hate the British! You are defeated but you have no shame. You are stubborn but you have no pride. You endure but you have no courage. I hate the British!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Ben Larson
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    What could one possibly add to the accolades this film has had heaped upon it. The fact that it may not be historically accurate is of no consequence, as it was made for the theater, not the History Channel. David Lean's master piece showing the madness of war stands the test of time. It swept the Oscars in 1958, winning Best Picture, Best Director for Lean, Best Actor for Alec Guinness in the role that defines him, and a Best Supporting Actor nomination for Sessue Hayakawa. It also took the awards for Writing. Music, Editing and Cinematography. Guinness was a perfect example of British pride. If you are going to do a job, then do it right. In that, he managed to take care of his men at the same time. William Holden was a perfect example of a soldier who just wanted to go home, as I am sure was the feeling of most. He recognized the madness of war long before the good doctor. This is a film that you can watch year after year and never get tired of it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Utter trash.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Blueghost
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    My uncle lived through the Bataan march, and was a POW in a Japanese labor camp. According to his daughter the one comment he made about this movie was as follows; "*Explicative*, we never had it that good!" He then reportedly stormed out of the TV room. You know, I have to say that I saw this film a couple times as a kid, and I never thought much of it. Initially I was going to title my review "Egomania 3" because that's kind of what we have here. The "drama" between the leads is manufactured in the extreme. The squaring off between Guiness and Mifune puts a grim smirk (if you could call it that) on this viewer's face. The film just doesn't ring true as to what happened to American, British, Australian, New Zealander and even French or Dutch POWs taken by the Japanese. The Imperial Japanese military didn't have the wanton industrial slaughter mechanism of the Nazi regime in Europe, but instead had the "work them until they're dead" ethic derived partially from Bushido, the code of the samurai. The acting was over the top. The story was so detached from reality as to be insulting, and by that I don't just mean my family's anecdote, but the interviews with survivors who went through that atrocity tell a very different and tragic story. During the Bataan march itself Japanese soldiers routinely shot anyone who looked weak or didn't look like they could make it, or rested. Then, once they got to the camps, it was hell baking in corrugated iron huts, laboring in hot and disease infested regions. And that's just for starters; the treatment, the food, the sheer and utter abuse; NONE of that is in this film. This film is about Hollywood parading its stars for what some idiot asinine producer thought would be a good patriotic film showing Americans and British being defiant in the face of the odds. Wrong. Look, I love Japanese culture. I love the food, I love the movies, I love the clean and polite society, and the people themselves, and I certainly don't hold any grudges whatsoever. In fact I want to retire there. And, I'm not the only one. Therefore, why not make a movie that shows the REAL EXPERIENCE? I can't answer that, but what I do know is that this piece of cinematic trash is just another notch in a southern Californian metroplex film industry that seems to never get anything write when it comes to history. What's even more insulting is that people have voted it so high as a quality film. Between the Russians not getting credit for their massive effort in what they call "the Great Patriotic War" and people like my family who were there when it happened, it's a wonder the entire film industry hasn't been run out of town and forced to setup shop in Mexico. Respectably shot, egotistical acting, poor SFX (notably the miniature), and a script that is just so idiotic I can't believe anyone green-lit this thing, it's a film that's definitely got some massive flaws. If you need to see a WW2 film about the Pacific Theatre, then check out Tora Tora Tora (Tiger Tiger Tiger). See this movie once, then do your brain a favor and pick up a book on the subject to learn what REALLY happened.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Ultimate Test of Survival-with some real life facts
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Admiraljames11
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie is the extremely accurate rendition of the incredible heroics of the brave men in Japanese prison camps that were made to build railroads. Many of these men after surviving battle on ships, ship sinkings, environmental and weather elements, were then subjected to cruel and inhuman treatment of Japanese soldiers. This movie is an accurate portrayal of these conditions with a few exceptions: (1) They did not whistle when entering the camp(although they did march in military formation, even when captured). (2) In the movie, Cdr. Shears tells the story of how he was on the USS Houston at the time she was sunk ,and how he and a Commander was separated from everyone else and drifted to the other side of the island. The commander died and he took his rank...etc. In real life, there was a USS Houston that was sunk and there was a Commander Maer that did drift to the other side of the island with a Seaman Elam ,which is consistent with Cdr. Shears story of the Houston sinking. However, both Cdr. Maer and Seaman Elam survived and were captured.(3) Real conditions of the prison camps were far more deplorable than depicted ,as well as the work details. (Men that couldn't walk were put on stretchers and given a hammer to bust up rock etc). (4) There were more American POWS than depicted in the movie, (the British often referred to the Americans as "Rabble"). and (5) They did not blow up the Bridge in the end and Col Nicholson certainly didn't turn on his own people to attempt to keep the bridge from blowing up. Still an awesome movie that is a must see.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A rather odd story,but entertaining
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    SmileysWorld
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I thoroughly enjoy this film,though I find it to be a rather odd story.Looking at it realistically,I find it hard to believe that a British commander,or any other commander,would give in to the will of the enemy under any circumstances,but I realize that even films based on true events can never be told 100% accurately,so I have no problem seeing as a great fictionalized account of true events.All the performances were excellent,particularly those of Alec Guiness and Bill Holden.If you are looking for a different type of war story,you have a winner in this one,but I would advise not reading up on how things really happened on The River Kwaiuntil after viewing it.It may make the film a disappointment to you.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A David Lean War Movie !
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Umar Mansoor Bajwa (umar_mansoor@yahoo.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The story is well laden with excitement, thrill and adventure. The characterization of different roles is uniquely perfect. The intrinsic conflicts, valor and stoic fortitude displayed by Col. Nicholson played by Alec Guinness is indeed commendable. Needless to mention is the daredevil nature of the commando action steered by a British Major to blow the bridge, laboriously built by another British Colonel is a striking coincidence. However, tragedy awaited Shears (William Holden) the US Navy Officer who had earlier miraculously escaped from the POW camp run by an intransigent Col. Saitu. Above all is the magnificent direction of Sir David Lean, who has captured marvelous locations for filming the army offices and bungalows situated at uniquely picturesque spots. It requires a keen eye to identify the meticulous details of the sets, like the revolving pedestal fan and wartime furniture, when Major Warden convinces Shears to join the death defying plot. The screenplay is a feast for the eyes. The dialogues and script goes hand in hand with the majestic flow of thrill in this commando mission movie. A must see for all war movie buffs.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Stretch Too Far
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    robinmcis966
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/9/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Certainly 'The Bridge on the River Kwai' has a gorgeous and epic sweep. If viewers simply want an entertaining evening, just cue it up and enjoy. For that matter, if you want encouragement, The AFI 100 once placed 'The Bridge' as the 13th best film ever and it has garnered more 4 of 4 and 5 of 5 star reviews than can be counted. However, The AFI now places the Film 37th and perhaps it is past due for re-vision. Although larger problems develop more slowly, it is a bad sign when there are not one, but two, obvious editing problems before the end of the credits! We are right behind the mounted machine gun on a train. The view is of the at least 2 carloads of wood for fuel and the engine. But now we see the same view with no fuel cars, OR EVEN THE ENGINE. Where did they go? In the same scene, the train now stops as the rail ends amidst about 15 workers. But now the dramatic score kicks in and there suddenly are several dozen workers on the rail line. In a low-budget film, this could be overlooked. But this is a major production that won an Oscar....for best direction AND editing! Moving on to the more serious issues, we are told that the British Commander (Alec Guinness) has been ordered to surrender, along with over 100 men and about a dozen officers. No explanation is offered for this. Really? He was just 'ordered to surrender'? According to historical estimates, over 100,000 men died building this railroad. For that matter, although there are ample references to men dying in this prison camp, all the men who have already been imprisoned there, even those in the infirmary, look well-fed, some even in 'beef-cake' condition. Again, this sort of over-sight would be fine for a 2nd rate 'action-genre' flick. It's Bill Holden-he's tanned, buff, and sweaty. Enough said? The central problem with 'The Bridge on the River Kwai' has at least been occasionally mentioned. Guinness' Commander not only helps the Japanese build a crucial bridge in their supply line, he goes to great lengths to make sure the bridge will hold and be finished on time. This to prove superior British logistics and character. Along the way, he is warned of the possibly treasonous nature of his collaboration, and yet he continues on without a doubt. Nothing is made of this...he just comes across as 'funny that way'. However, as far as I know, it has not been pointed out that all of his men and his officers would therefore have had to join him in this inexplicable lapse. This despite what appears to be a very democratic officers meeting and over two months time to reflect on the matter. Treason?...well...no problem! What a credulous bunch of guys. And more to the point, what a credulous bunch of reviewers have failed to notice this. Clearly the original 1957 release of 'The Bridge on the River Kwai' struck a cord. To portray an American, (British in the book), played by William Holden, as cynically detached from the war effort and yet ultimately humane was not new. Several Bogart films prepared audiences for this. But to sum it all up as 'Madness', this before Catch-22 and Mash, was ahead of it's time. This progressive spirit, some great cinematography, and a rousing combination of star-power and studio support make for an entertaining evening. But as a 'Closely Watched Film', it is almost as much train-wreck as classic.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    All you need is love.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    frizb
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/7/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Real Billy Shears Bridge on the River Kwai was written by a French author, Pierre Boulle. In the movie William Holden plays Commander Shears, an American captured when his ship the USS Houston is sunk. He is a POW in a camp full of British sailors and Australians and does his best to avoid any really hard work by becoming a grave digger. But then Alec Guinnes (Obi Wan Kenobi) shows up and is the senior officer, Lt Colonel Nicholson. He refuses to let any of the officers do manual labor, so Shears says that Nicholson is a maniac and makes an escape. Then Nicholson says that the Japanese camp commander is mad. When Shears reaches a British base in Ceylon it turns out that he is not an officer. He is just a sailor named Shears impersonating an officer in order to get better treatment. After he escaped he decided to continue playing an officer and was going to say that being lost in the jungle drove him mad. But the British Force 316, commandos, wanted Shears to lead them back to the POW camp so they could blow up the bridge that the prisoners were building. They made Shears a simulated major. Ian Fleming was the head of a force of British Commandoes in France called Force 54, along with "Q" and "U" and Bertrand, and the real James Bond, who Fleming once met according to his biographer. Shears, also called "Number One", gets to the bridge but not before telling the Professor he is as crazy as Nicholson. Nicholson tries to stop them from destroying the bridge. Lt Joyce kills a few Japanese soldiers and Nicholson fights with Lt Joyce. The Professor starts a mortar barrage, and Shears swims across the river to set off the explosives. Just as Shears reaches Nicholson they recognize each other, and Nicholson realizes that he is himself mad. Shears is killed by rifle fire and the mortar kills Nicholson who falls on the detonator and the bridge is destroyed. The British doctor stands on the riverbank and says everyone is mad. But earlier in the movie Shears is sitting on a Ceylon beach with a blonde nurse and a thermos of martinis. He complains jokingly about how the nurse gives him pills, powders, shots, thermometers and all he really needs is love. The nurse says "Yes that is true. All you really need is love!"
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    David Lean's First Best Picture Winner Is One Of The Greatest!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Humphrey Fish
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/5/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    After settling his differences with a Japanese PoW camp commander, a British colonel co-operates to oversee his men's construction of a railway bridge for their captors - while oblivious to a plan by the Allies to destroy it. Speaking as someone who has seen a wide variety of movies, this movie is awesome, totally and completely awesome! The Bridge On The River Kwai is a milestone in the history of film, the results are groundbreaking and breathtaking. I watched this on TCM as part of a Memorial Day celebration, and when I watched it, I was astonished by what I had seen. I had seen one of the greatest movies of all time, a movie that is directed by a master of epic films, the great British film director, David Lean. David Lean's first Best Picture winner is one of the greatest, and only a few years after this movie, he would direct his second Best Picture Winner, Lawrence Of Arabia, and three years after that, he would direct another great movie, Doctor Zhivago. Like Martin Scorsese, David Lean was a man who could do no wrong, I repeat, absolutely no wrong. This film also won numerous Academy Awards, the biggest ones being Best Picture, Best Director, and Best Actor. Alec Guinness won the Academy Award for Best Actor for his role as Col. Nicholson. And I can say that that win was a win that was well deserved, as he was great in this movie! William Holden also gives a good performance as the secondary protagonist, Shears. By the way, this movie was written by Carl Foreman and Michael Wilson, but they had to keep a low profile because a few years earlier, they had been accused of being Communists and they ended up getting blacklisted, much to their misfortune. David Lean's direction is masterful, it's the direction of a master film director. And as proof of that, he won the Academy Award For Best Director, and he would repeat that when he made Lawrence Of Arabia. David Lean was another one of those directors who if he had never existed, the movie industry would be a whole lot different. So all in all, The Bridge On The River Kwai is another movie that I can say is one of the greatest movies that I have ever seen. When I watched it, I was thrilled with it, every minute of it, from the very minute that it began to the very minute that it ended, I was absolutely impressed with every last second of it! And I guess that you know what this means, this means that you too are going to watch to watch this remarkably fabulous movie, because it's simply incredible, when you watch it, you will say that it is one of the greatest movies that you have ever seen, you will say that it deserved all of the Academy Awards that it won! Bravo to the remarkable David Lean for making a movie that I totally and completely loved! So if you haven't seen this movie, then take the time to watch it, because you will love it, you will say that it's one of the greatest movies you've ever seen! 10/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A World War II Odyssey
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Nick-leonardi
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/5/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    POW English soldiers are instructed by their rulers, the Japanese, to build a bridge. At the same time, a group of free Englishmen plan to destroy the bridge as soon as it's done. Majestic triumph at the Oscars (it won seven Academy Awards), as well as great commercial success, the film proves how David Lean brings a sense of epic and grandiose in everything he touches, inserting also themes like the meaning and weight of law, honor, pride, duty, and of course, the futility of war. Engaging even with a concept that might indicate otherwise (the construction of a bridge), the film boasts memorable performances by Alec Guinness and William Holden that compliment even more the importance of this British film. Based on the novel by Pierre Boulle.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The madness of war
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Christopher Reynolds
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/3/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Looking at this movie as a whole, it works brilliantly in conveying its theme of the madness of war, and how it drives good men to do bad things. Great direction, acting across the board, and cinematography all add a lot to the movie. **** SPOILERS ***** As I was watching the movie, for the first hour I felt increasingly annoyed by Col. Nicholson's "play by the rules and do what you're told" philosophy. Then as the movie went on, and we follow the British plan to blow up the bridge, I realised that this was how the movie wanted me to feel, and then the finale pulled off a brilliant reversal, and a sort of redemption for Nicholson. Standout scenes are the killing of the Japanese soldiers while clouds of bats whirl over the jungle, and, of course, the incredibly tense and powerful finale.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
 </reviews>
</filme>
