<filme>
 <id>
  20
 </id>
 <imdburl>
  http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0112365
 </imdburl>
 <ano>
  1995
 </ano>
 <titulo>
  Anjos E Insetos
 </titulo>
 <rating>
  6.8
 </rating>
 <sinopse>
  In the 1800s a naturalist marries into a family of British aristocrats.
 </sinopse>
 <storyline>
  The movie is a study of an aristocratic family in the Victorian England. William Adamson, a young scientist, is introduced into the aristocratic family Alabaster by reverend Alabaster who is also fascinated by insects. William marries the older daughter of the family and studies the amounts of insects in the garden of the villa. His - for the aristocrats - strange behaviours reveal at the same time their own failures and passions.
 </storyline>
 <generos>
  <genero>
   Drama
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Romance
  </genero>
 </generos>
 <keywords>
  <keyword>
   insect
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   aristocrat
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   naturalist
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   england
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   passion
  </keyword>
 </keywords>
 <diretores>
  <diretor>
   Philip Haas
  </diretor>
 </diretores>
 <escritores>
  <escritor>
   A.S. Byatt
  </escritor>
  <escritor>
   Belinda Haas
  </escritor>
 </escritores>
 <atores>
  <ator>
   Mark Rylance
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Kristin Scott Thomas
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Patsy Kensit
  </ator>
 </atores>
 <reviews>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    For the tongue-in-cheek coffee-sippers among us.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    merrywood
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    We humans come in so many different mind-sets that, astonishingly, a film like this tedious, annoyingly mundane and meaningless churning can actually have value to some. For me it was a time for slapping my face to stay awake, looking for gummed tape to hold up my eyelids. But then, there was such a marvelous pay-off, again, not for all of us but for those with iron clad stomachs. What was it? The boring protagonist discovers that all his children are really the offspring of his wife's long time sexual relationship with her brother. Indeed, he walks in on them slapping loins, at some point. One looks for meaning in all forms of literature only to find that, perhaps, life might very well be devoid of meaning. Maybe that is what those given to this drivel have objectified.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    feminist victorian nightmare
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    filmtherapy
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is one of the most visually repulsive movies I have ever watched. I enjoyed reading the other reviews for this film.I got a good laugh from the person who described the women's dresses as being like a visual jackhammer. The dresses are supposed to reflect insects the field of study of the main character. The first thing I personally noticed aside from the bumble bee and other jack hammer dresses was that the lighting was too bright indoors. It looked like flood lights were everywhere when in fact a night scene in that era would have been candle lit. Thus my first disappointment=something looks cheap or wrong herewas this filmed with some unknown color film? Second there is the revolting albino poor white trash looking group of aristocrats living in an authoritarian like atmosphere (the Alabaster family...whitest whites alabaster get it?? ) with servants cringing towards walls etc It could have easily turned into a horror movie. And finally last there is the predictable totally unbelievable modern feminist twist to the story-the unbelievably talented in every sense of unbelievable "right on" strong woman who rescues the milquetoast male lead---something guaranteed to win it Oscar nominations. What can I say....ho hum...it would get a lot of claps on Oprah. It is something you can't seem to escape from any more
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A lyrical, lush masterpiece
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    toptip
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/9/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    William Adamson (Mark Rylance) is an entymologist who marries into the aristocratic Alabaster family in Victorian England. He spends his time on his newly acquired expanse studying insects and tending to his wife, Eugenia (Patsy Kensit). Before too long he starts noticing odd behavior from his new family, and proceeds to turn the microscope on them. Careful, quietly masterful performance by Mark Rylance, who usually makes his living as the director of Shakespeare's Globe Theater. And, as Lady Alabaster (a museum piece, for sure!), Annette Badlands is perfect. It's a pretty film. There's some beautiful technique employed here and there, as evidenced by the fine closeups of butterflies and measuring devices, and the way in which the voices of the actors are interwoven with the rustle of the manicured forest that envelops them. A lyrical, lush masterpiece. One of the best films of the 90's.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Thanks, but no thanks!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mac-hawk
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/2/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A Victorian period drama with quasi erotic bits! Poorly acted, bland and boring and for much of the time very predictable for me. The main characters are pretty lame and are acted much the same. Mark Rylance, as William Adamson, seems to have perfected an expression of blank emotion (or maybe it's just boredom). Patsy Kensit's character exists to simply have a different frock on in EVERY scene she's in or get her kit off. Douglas Henshall provides the 'evil' character & is actually quite good, he doesn't overdo it so it never reaches the pantomime stage, however Annette Badland has no trouble in reaching these dizzy heights as Lady Alabaster (PK's characters mother). Kristin Scott Thomas plays a subdued second female lead and, like Henshall, comes away with some credit One has to assume it's not the actors fault as the director, Philip Haas, surely got what he asked for. How on earth this got the Evening Standard award for Best British film in 1995 beggars belief (it MUST have been a BAD year).
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    There's Definitely a Worm at the Center of This Apple
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    brocksilvey
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/6/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A fascinating and psychologically suffocating film based on a novella by A.S. Byatt. A doomed love affair and some serious family dysfunction provide the content for the story, and director Philip Haas ratchets up the sense of something rotting at the film's center to a high degree. Though all of the acting is fine, what I remember most about this film are the costumes, all designed to evoke insect imagery. The film deservedly won an Academy Award nomination for its costume design, and should have won, but the Academy decided to recognize "The English Patient's" assortment of Banana Republic outfits instead. Grade: B+
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I wish humankind would create such altruistic virtues, but sometimes I think socialism may never be realized.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    lastliberal
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/5/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A fascinating film about people acting like insects. The costuming is beyond brilliant, but it is the actions of the people that really are striking in this film. The matriarch of the family is definitely a Queen ant or bee. She constantly gorges herself as the others flutter about serving her. But it is Eugenia (Patsy Kensit) who is the focus of the film. A poor naturalist (Mark Rylance) is madly in love with her, but her racist brother (Douglas Henshall) warns him that he is not of the right class and should be real. William (Rylance) flits ever so cautiously towards Eugenia's web and is ensnared. I am sure there is something beneath the surface here; maybe the same something that caused Eugenia's former fianc&eacute;e to kill himself. But, it is not always the beautiful butterfly that attracts. Sometimes, it is a plain little ant like Matty Crompton (Kristin Scott Thomas), who is busily working on her own plans for William. This all takes place shortly after Darwin's Origin of the Species was published, and during the Civil War in America. Both colored the story. Upon the death of Mother, Eugenia ascends the role of Queen ant, continuing to produce heirs. At the same time, a collaboration of William and Matty results in a book being published. Then the shocking secret comes forth. Mark Rylance, Patsy Kensit, and Kristin Scott Thomas were all fantastic in this shocking tale.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    drab ending? possible spoilers!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gghunter09
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/1/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I loved this movie! i remember seeing the trailer for it on the movie "haunted" (also superb) and was deeply in love with it. Although the film and story is wonderful I felt the ending lacked more than most should. To me it was very easy to tell what would happen especially with the way Edgar acted towards William at the ball. Over protective much? Of course when it finally got to the end there they were in all their glory! I think the film made it too apparent that there was incest in the family but other than that fact I loved the film. It's sad to think though that most films just end leaving the audience with nothing. So much for a climax (no pun intended.)
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Black period drama
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Framescourer
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/11/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A tough AS Byatt adaptation from Philip Haas which takes a cold look at Darwinism. Rylance's Mark Adamson is a ruined botanist who takes not only the charity of his patron Sir Harald Alabaster but, in time, his daughter Eugenia's hand. Something is not right though and tragedy strikes him a second time when he discovers her secret. Haas has created a lush film, overflowing with life as if the Alabaster house were a jungle itself. This is the irony of the film. A strange transformation seems to have taken place whereby the appropriately named Alabasters have lost the warmth and colour of a moral existence, a better life of which only Sir Harald, Mark and the discreet but ardent Matty Crompton seem to be aware. Kristin Scott Thomas gives the best of the performances as the intelligent but buttoned-down Matty. It's just a shame that her role is necessarily minuscule compared to the less engaging Patsy Kensit, well-cast but not particularly memorable as the frigid Eugenia, not that an unsympathetic Ryalnce does much to help her, I'm afraid. Douglas Henshall is ideal as the insipid Edgar. 6/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Intelligent and Unsual British Drama
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Andres Salama
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/12/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    An intelligent and unusual drama, based on a short story by A.S. Byatt. In mid 18th century England, a penniless naturalist who has lost his prized specimens from the Amazon in a shipwreck (I think the movie meant him to be a young Charles Darwin, though an incident where specimens were lost in a shipwreck happened to his colleague Alfred Russell Wallace) gets a job cataloging specimens held by the Alabaster family in their country estate. He will eventually marry their daughter Eugenia (Patsy Kensit), despite the fierce opposition of her brother Edgar. Not long after having children with her, he will discover a terrible secret haunting the family. A cousin of the Alabasters, the bookish Matty (Kristin Scott Thomas) will turn out to be his only friend and ally. At times the movie looks like a strange cross between a film by James Ivory and a film by Peter Greenaway, with the Alabaster women carrying bright colored clothes that suggests different sort of insects. Even if you don't take the entomology references throughout comparing insects with humans very seriously, they are nonetheless fun. And the denouement is terrific.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of the Worst Films....Ever
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Theaterchica07
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/9/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I had to watch this film for a class about Mid-Victorian Britain...with my professors and my class...and I was shocked at the story; Not just how awful the acting was, but that the script was actually bought and given a green light for production. The costumes were stylized and the design was nominated for an Oscar...how that was possible, I don't even know. The only thing redeemable about the film is Kristen Scott Thomas. Mark Rylance and Patsy Kensit give two of the worst performances I have ever seen in my entire life. Rylance's pitch and tone of voice never changes and Kensit was overly dramatic to the point of being comical. I would only see this movie if you want to laugh. But even at that, you're going to be wasting money...even energy by renting this movie. Stay away...
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    For the tongue-in-cheek coffee-sippers among us.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    merrywood
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    We humans come in so many different mind-sets that, astonishingly, a film like this tedious, annoyingly mundane and meaningless churning can actually have value to some. For me it was a time for slapping my face to stay awake, looking for gummed tape to hold up my eyelids. But then, there was such a marvelous pay-off, again, not for all of us but for those with iron clad stomachs. What was it? The boring protagonist discovers that all his children are really the offspring of his wife's long time sexual relationship with her brother. Indeed, he walks in on them slapping loins, at some point. One looks for meaning in all forms of literature only to find that, perhaps, life might very well be devoid of meaning. Maybe that is what those given to this drivel have objectified.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    feminist victorian nightmare
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    filmtherapy
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is one of the most visually repulsive movies I have ever watched. I enjoyed reading the other reviews for this film.I got a good laugh from the person who described the women's dresses as being like a visual jackhammer. The dresses are supposed to reflect insects the field of study of the main character. The first thing I personally noticed aside from the bumble bee and other jack hammer dresses was that the lighting was too bright indoors. It looked like flood lights were everywhere when in fact a night scene in that era would have been candle lit. Thus my first disappointment=something looks cheap or wrong herewas this filmed with some unknown color film? Second there is the revolting albino poor white trash looking group of aristocrats living in an authoritarian like atmosphere (the Alabaster family...whitest whites alabaster get it?? ) with servants cringing towards walls etc It could have easily turned into a horror movie. And finally last there is the predictable totally unbelievable modern feminist twist to the story-the unbelievably talented in every sense of unbelievable "right on" strong woman who rescues the milquetoast male lead---something guaranteed to win it Oscar nominations. What can I say....ho hum...it would get a lot of claps on Oprah. It is something you can't seem to escape from any more
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A lyrical, lush masterpiece
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    toptip
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/9/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    William Adamson (Mark Rylance) is an entymologist who marries into the aristocratic Alabaster family in Victorian England. He spends his time on his newly acquired expanse studying insects and tending to his wife, Eugenia (Patsy Kensit). Before too long he starts noticing odd behavior from his new family, and proceeds to turn the microscope on them. Careful, quietly masterful performance by Mark Rylance, who usually makes his living as the director of Shakespeare's Globe Theater. And, as Lady Alabaster (a museum piece, for sure!), Annette Badlands is perfect. It's a pretty film. There's some beautiful technique employed here and there, as evidenced by the fine closeups of butterflies and measuring devices, and the way in which the voices of the actors are interwoven with the rustle of the manicured forest that envelops them. A lyrical, lush masterpiece. One of the best films of the 90's.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Thanks, but no thanks!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mac-hawk
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/2/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A Victorian period drama with quasi erotic bits! Poorly acted, bland and boring and for much of the time very predictable for me. The main characters are pretty lame and are acted much the same. Mark Rylance, as William Adamson, seems to have perfected an expression of blank emotion (or maybe it's just boredom). Patsy Kensit's character exists to simply have a different frock on in EVERY scene she's in or get her kit off. Douglas Henshall provides the 'evil' character & is actually quite good, he doesn't overdo it so it never reaches the pantomime stage, however Annette Badland has no trouble in reaching these dizzy heights as Lady Alabaster (PK's characters mother). Kristin Scott Thomas plays a subdued second female lead and, like Henshall, comes away with some credit One has to assume it's not the actors fault as the director, Philip Haas, surely got what he asked for. How on earth this got the Evening Standard award for Best British film in 1995 beggars belief (it MUST have been a BAD year).
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    There's Definitely a Worm at the Center of This Apple
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    brocksilvey
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/6/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A fascinating and psychologically suffocating film based on a novella by A.S. Byatt. A doomed love affair and some serious family dysfunction provide the content for the story, and director Philip Haas ratchets up the sense of something rotting at the film's center to a high degree. Though all of the acting is fine, what I remember most about this film are the costumes, all designed to evoke insect imagery. The film deservedly won an Academy Award nomination for its costume design, and should have won, but the Academy decided to recognize "The English Patient's" assortment of Banana Republic outfits instead. Grade: B+
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I wish humankind would create such altruistic virtues, but sometimes I think socialism may never be realized.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    lastliberal
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/5/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A fascinating film about people acting like insects. The costuming is beyond brilliant, but it is the actions of the people that really are striking in this film. The matriarch of the family is definitely a Queen ant or bee. She constantly gorges herself as the others flutter about serving her. But it is Eugenia (Patsy Kensit) who is the focus of the film. A poor naturalist (Mark Rylance) is madly in love with her, but her racist brother (Douglas Henshall) warns him that he is not of the right class and should be real. William (Rylance) flits ever so cautiously towards Eugenia's web and is ensnared. I am sure there is something beneath the surface here; maybe the same something that caused Eugenia's former fianc&eacute;e to kill himself. But, it is not always the beautiful butterfly that attracts. Sometimes, it is a plain little ant like Matty Crompton (Kristin Scott Thomas), who is busily working on her own plans for William. This all takes place shortly after Darwin's Origin of the Species was published, and during the Civil War in America. Both colored the story. Upon the death of Mother, Eugenia ascends the role of Queen ant, continuing to produce heirs. At the same time, a collaboration of William and Matty results in a book being published. Then the shocking secret comes forth. Mark Rylance, Patsy Kensit, and Kristin Scott Thomas were all fantastic in this shocking tale.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    drab ending? possible spoilers!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gghunter09
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/1/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I loved this movie! i remember seeing the trailer for it on the movie "haunted" (also superb) and was deeply in love with it. Although the film and story is wonderful I felt the ending lacked more than most should. To me it was very easy to tell what would happen especially with the way Edgar acted towards William at the ball. Over protective much? Of course when it finally got to the end there they were in all their glory! I think the film made it too apparent that there was incest in the family but other than that fact I loved the film. It's sad to think though that most films just end leaving the audience with nothing. So much for a climax (no pun intended.)
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Black period drama
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Framescourer
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/11/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A tough AS Byatt adaptation from Philip Haas which takes a cold look at Darwinism. Rylance's Mark Adamson is a ruined botanist who takes not only the charity of his patron Sir Harald Alabaster but, in time, his daughter Eugenia's hand. Something is not right though and tragedy strikes him a second time when he discovers her secret. Haas has created a lush film, overflowing with life as if the Alabaster house were a jungle itself. This is the irony of the film. A strange transformation seems to have taken place whereby the appropriately named Alabasters have lost the warmth and colour of a moral existence, a better life of which only Sir Harald, Mark and the discreet but ardent Matty Crompton seem to be aware. Kristin Scott Thomas gives the best of the performances as the intelligent but buttoned-down Matty. It's just a shame that her role is necessarily minuscule compared to the less engaging Patsy Kensit, well-cast but not particularly memorable as the frigid Eugenia, not that an unsympathetic Ryalnce does much to help her, I'm afraid. Douglas Henshall is ideal as the insipid Edgar. 6/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Intelligent and Unsual British Drama
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Andres Salama
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/12/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    An intelligent and unusual drama, based on a short story by A.S. Byatt. In mid 18th century England, a penniless naturalist who has lost his prized specimens from the Amazon in a shipwreck (I think the movie meant him to be a young Charles Darwin, though an incident where specimens were lost in a shipwreck happened to his colleague Alfred Russell Wallace) gets a job cataloging specimens held by the Alabaster family in their country estate. He will eventually marry their daughter Eugenia (Patsy Kensit), despite the fierce opposition of her brother Edgar. Not long after having children with her, he will discover a terrible secret haunting the family. A cousin of the Alabasters, the bookish Matty (Kristin Scott Thomas) will turn out to be his only friend and ally. At times the movie looks like a strange cross between a film by James Ivory and a film by Peter Greenaway, with the Alabaster women carrying bright colored clothes that suggests different sort of insects. Even if you don't take the entomology references throughout comparing insects with humans very seriously, they are nonetheless fun. And the denouement is terrific.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of the Worst Films....Ever
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Theaterchica07
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/9/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I had to watch this film for a class about Mid-Victorian Britain...with my professors and my class...and I was shocked at the story; Not just how awful the acting was, but that the script was actually bought and given a green light for production. The costumes were stylized and the design was nominated for an Oscar...how that was possible, I don't even know. The only thing redeemable about the film is Kristen Scott Thomas. Mark Rylance and Patsy Kensit give two of the worst performances I have ever seen in my entire life. Rylance's pitch and tone of voice never changes and Kensit was overly dramatic to the point of being comical. I would only see this movie if you want to laugh. But even at that, you're going to be wasting money...even energy by renting this movie. Stay away...
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    For the tongue-in-cheek coffee-sippers among us.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    merrywood
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    We humans come in so many different mind-sets that, astonishingly, a film like this tedious, annoyingly mundane and meaningless churning can actually have value to some. For me it was a time for slapping my face to stay awake, looking for gummed tape to hold up my eyelids. But then, there was such a marvelous pay-off, again, not for all of us but for those with iron clad stomachs. What was it? The boring protagonist discovers that all his children are really the offspring of his wife's long time sexual relationship with her brother. Indeed, he walks in on them slapping loins, at some point. One looks for meaning in all forms of literature only to find that, perhaps, life might very well be devoid of meaning. Maybe that is what those given to this drivel have objectified.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    feminist victorian nightmare
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    filmtherapy
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is one of the most visually repulsive movies I have ever watched. I enjoyed reading the other reviews for this film.I got a good laugh from the person who described the women's dresses as being like a visual jackhammer. The dresses are supposed to reflect insects the field of study of the main character. The first thing I personally noticed aside from the bumble bee and other jack hammer dresses was that the lighting was too bright indoors. It looked like flood lights were everywhere when in fact a night scene in that era would have been candle lit. Thus my first disappointment=something looks cheap or wrong herewas this filmed with some unknown color film? Second there is the revolting albino poor white trash looking group of aristocrats living in an authoritarian like atmosphere (the Alabaster family...whitest whites alabaster get it?? ) with servants cringing towards walls etc It could have easily turned into a horror movie. And finally last there is the predictable totally unbelievable modern feminist twist to the story-the unbelievably talented in every sense of unbelievable "right on" strong woman who rescues the milquetoast male lead---something guaranteed to win it Oscar nominations. What can I say....ho hum...it would get a lot of claps on Oprah. It is something you can't seem to escape from any more
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A lyrical, lush masterpiece
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    toptip
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/9/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    William Adamson (Mark Rylance) is an entymologist who marries into the aristocratic Alabaster family in Victorian England. He spends his time on his newly acquired expanse studying insects and tending to his wife, Eugenia (Patsy Kensit). Before too long he starts noticing odd behavior from his new family, and proceeds to turn the microscope on them. Careful, quietly masterful performance by Mark Rylance, who usually makes his living as the director of Shakespeare's Globe Theater. And, as Lady Alabaster (a museum piece, for sure!), Annette Badlands is perfect. It's a pretty film. There's some beautiful technique employed here and there, as evidenced by the fine closeups of butterflies and measuring devices, and the way in which the voices of the actors are interwoven with the rustle of the manicured forest that envelops them. A lyrical, lush masterpiece. One of the best films of the 90's.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Thanks, but no thanks!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mac-hawk
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/2/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A Victorian period drama with quasi erotic bits! Poorly acted, bland and boring and for much of the time very predictable for me. The main characters are pretty lame and are acted much the same. Mark Rylance, as William Adamson, seems to have perfected an expression of blank emotion (or maybe it's just boredom). Patsy Kensit's character exists to simply have a different frock on in EVERY scene she's in or get her kit off. Douglas Henshall provides the 'evil' character & is actually quite good, he doesn't overdo it so it never reaches the pantomime stage, however Annette Badland has no trouble in reaching these dizzy heights as Lady Alabaster (PK's characters mother). Kristin Scott Thomas plays a subdued second female lead and, like Henshall, comes away with some credit One has to assume it's not the actors fault as the director, Philip Haas, surely got what he asked for. How on earth this got the Evening Standard award for Best British film in 1995 beggars belief (it MUST have been a BAD year).
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    There's Definitely a Worm at the Center of This Apple
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    brocksilvey
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/6/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A fascinating and psychologically suffocating film based on a novella by A.S. Byatt. A doomed love affair and some serious family dysfunction provide the content for the story, and director Philip Haas ratchets up the sense of something rotting at the film's center to a high degree. Though all of the acting is fine, what I remember most about this film are the costumes, all designed to evoke insect imagery. The film deservedly won an Academy Award nomination for its costume design, and should have won, but the Academy decided to recognize "The English Patient's" assortment of Banana Republic outfits instead. Grade: B+
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I wish humankind would create such altruistic virtues, but sometimes I think socialism may never be realized.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    lastliberal
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/5/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A fascinating film about people acting like insects. The costuming is beyond brilliant, but it is the actions of the people that really are striking in this film. The matriarch of the family is definitely a Queen ant or bee. She constantly gorges herself as the others flutter about serving her. But it is Eugenia (Patsy Kensit) who is the focus of the film. A poor naturalist (Mark Rylance) is madly in love with her, but her racist brother (Douglas Henshall) warns him that he is not of the right class and should be real. William (Rylance) flits ever so cautiously towards Eugenia's web and is ensnared. I am sure there is something beneath the surface here; maybe the same something that caused Eugenia's former fianc&eacute;e to kill himself. But, it is not always the beautiful butterfly that attracts. Sometimes, it is a plain little ant like Matty Crompton (Kristin Scott Thomas), who is busily working on her own plans for William. This all takes place shortly after Darwin's Origin of the Species was published, and during the Civil War in America. Both colored the story. Upon the death of Mother, Eugenia ascends the role of Queen ant, continuing to produce heirs. At the same time, a collaboration of William and Matty results in a book being published. Then the shocking secret comes forth. Mark Rylance, Patsy Kensit, and Kristin Scott Thomas were all fantastic in this shocking tale.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    drab ending? possible spoilers!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gghunter09
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/1/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I loved this movie! i remember seeing the trailer for it on the movie "haunted" (also superb) and was deeply in love with it. Although the film and story is wonderful I felt the ending lacked more than most should. To me it was very easy to tell what would happen especially with the way Edgar acted towards William at the ball. Over protective much? Of course when it finally got to the end there they were in all their glory! I think the film made it too apparent that there was incest in the family but other than that fact I loved the film. It's sad to think though that most films just end leaving the audience with nothing. So much for a climax (no pun intended.)
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Black period drama
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Framescourer
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/11/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A tough AS Byatt adaptation from Philip Haas which takes a cold look at Darwinism. Rylance's Mark Adamson is a ruined botanist who takes not only the charity of his patron Sir Harald Alabaster but, in time, his daughter Eugenia's hand. Something is not right though and tragedy strikes him a second time when he discovers her secret. Haas has created a lush film, overflowing with life as if the Alabaster house were a jungle itself. This is the irony of the film. A strange transformation seems to have taken place whereby the appropriately named Alabasters have lost the warmth and colour of a moral existence, a better life of which only Sir Harald, Mark and the discreet but ardent Matty Crompton seem to be aware. Kristin Scott Thomas gives the best of the performances as the intelligent but buttoned-down Matty. It's just a shame that her role is necessarily minuscule compared to the less engaging Patsy Kensit, well-cast but not particularly memorable as the frigid Eugenia, not that an unsympathetic Ryalnce does much to help her, I'm afraid. Douglas Henshall is ideal as the insipid Edgar. 6/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Intelligent and Unsual British Drama
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Andres Salama
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/12/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    An intelligent and unusual drama, based on a short story by A.S. Byatt. In mid 18th century England, a penniless naturalist who has lost his prized specimens from the Amazon in a shipwreck (I think the movie meant him to be a young Charles Darwin, though an incident where specimens were lost in a shipwreck happened to his colleague Alfred Russell Wallace) gets a job cataloging specimens held by the Alabaster family in their country estate. He will eventually marry their daughter Eugenia (Patsy Kensit), despite the fierce opposition of her brother Edgar. Not long after having children with her, he will discover a terrible secret haunting the family. A cousin of the Alabasters, the bookish Matty (Kristin Scott Thomas) will turn out to be his only friend and ally. At times the movie looks like a strange cross between a film by James Ivory and a film by Peter Greenaway, with the Alabaster women carrying bright colored clothes that suggests different sort of insects. Even if you don't take the entomology references throughout comparing insects with humans very seriously, they are nonetheless fun. And the denouement is terrific.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of the Worst Films....Ever
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Theaterchica07
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/9/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I had to watch this film for a class about Mid-Victorian Britain...with my professors and my class...and I was shocked at the story; Not just how awful the acting was, but that the script was actually bought and given a green light for production. The costumes were stylized and the design was nominated for an Oscar...how that was possible, I don't even know. The only thing redeemable about the film is Kristen Scott Thomas. Mark Rylance and Patsy Kensit give two of the worst performances I have ever seen in my entire life. Rylance's pitch and tone of voice never changes and Kensit was overly dramatic to the point of being comical. I would only see this movie if you want to laugh. But even at that, you're going to be wasting money...even energy by renting this movie. Stay away...
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    For the tongue-in-cheek coffee-sippers among us.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    merrywood
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    We humans come in so many different mind-sets that, astonishingly, a film like this tedious, annoyingly mundane and meaningless churning can actually have value to some. For me it was a time for slapping my face to stay awake, looking for gummed tape to hold up my eyelids. But then, there was such a marvelous pay-off, again, not for all of us but for those with iron clad stomachs. What was it? The boring protagonist discovers that all his children are really the offspring of his wife's long time sexual relationship with her brother. Indeed, he walks in on them slapping loins, at some point. One looks for meaning in all forms of literature only to find that, perhaps, life might very well be devoid of meaning. Maybe that is what those given to this drivel have objectified.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    feminist victorian nightmare
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    filmtherapy
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is one of the most visually repulsive movies I have ever watched. I enjoyed reading the other reviews for this film.I got a good laugh from the person who described the women's dresses as being like a visual jackhammer. The dresses are supposed to reflect insects the field of study of the main character. The first thing I personally noticed aside from the bumble bee and other jack hammer dresses was that the lighting was too bright indoors. It looked like flood lights were everywhere when in fact a night scene in that era would have been candle lit. Thus my first disappointment=something looks cheap or wrong herewas this filmed with some unknown color film? Second there is the revolting albino poor white trash looking group of aristocrats living in an authoritarian like atmosphere (the Alabaster family...whitest whites alabaster get it?? ) with servants cringing towards walls etc It could have easily turned into a horror movie. And finally last there is the predictable totally unbelievable modern feminist twist to the story-the unbelievably talented in every sense of unbelievable "right on" strong woman who rescues the milquetoast male lead---something guaranteed to win it Oscar nominations. What can I say....ho hum...it would get a lot of claps on Oprah. It is something you can't seem to escape from any more
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A lyrical, lush masterpiece
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    toptip
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/9/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    William Adamson (Mark Rylance) is an entymologist who marries into the aristocratic Alabaster family in Victorian England. He spends his time on his newly acquired expanse studying insects and tending to his wife, Eugenia (Patsy Kensit). Before too long he starts noticing odd behavior from his new family, and proceeds to turn the microscope on them. Careful, quietly masterful performance by Mark Rylance, who usually makes his living as the director of Shakespeare's Globe Theater. And, as Lady Alabaster (a museum piece, for sure!), Annette Badlands is perfect. It's a pretty film. There's some beautiful technique employed here and there, as evidenced by the fine closeups of butterflies and measuring devices, and the way in which the voices of the actors are interwoven with the rustle of the manicured forest that envelops them. A lyrical, lush masterpiece. One of the best films of the 90's.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Thanks, but no thanks!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mac-hawk
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/2/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A Victorian period drama with quasi erotic bits! Poorly acted, bland and boring and for much of the time very predictable for me. The main characters are pretty lame and are acted much the same. Mark Rylance, as William Adamson, seems to have perfected an expression of blank emotion (or maybe it's just boredom). Patsy Kensit's character exists to simply have a different frock on in EVERY scene she's in or get her kit off. Douglas Henshall provides the 'evil' character & is actually quite good, he doesn't overdo it so it never reaches the pantomime stage, however Annette Badland has no trouble in reaching these dizzy heights as Lady Alabaster (PK's characters mother). Kristin Scott Thomas plays a subdued second female lead and, like Henshall, comes away with some credit One has to assume it's not the actors fault as the director, Philip Haas, surely got what he asked for. How on earth this got the Evening Standard award for Best British film in 1995 beggars belief (it MUST have been a BAD year).
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    There's Definitely a Worm at the Center of This Apple
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    brocksilvey
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/6/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A fascinating and psychologically suffocating film based on a novella by A.S. Byatt. A doomed love affair and some serious family dysfunction provide the content for the story, and director Philip Haas ratchets up the sense of something rotting at the film's center to a high degree. Though all of the acting is fine, what I remember most about this film are the costumes, all designed to evoke insect imagery. The film deservedly won an Academy Award nomination for its costume design, and should have won, but the Academy decided to recognize "The English Patient's" assortment of Banana Republic outfits instead. Grade: B+
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I wish humankind would create such altruistic virtues, but sometimes I think socialism may never be realized.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    lastliberal
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/5/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A fascinating film about people acting like insects. The costuming is beyond brilliant, but it is the actions of the people that really are striking in this film. The matriarch of the family is definitely a Queen ant or bee. She constantly gorges herself as the others flutter about serving her. But it is Eugenia (Patsy Kensit) who is the focus of the film. A poor naturalist (Mark Rylance) is madly in love with her, but her racist brother (Douglas Henshall) warns him that he is not of the right class and should be real. William (Rylance) flits ever so cautiously towards Eugenia's web and is ensnared. I am sure there is something beneath the surface here; maybe the same something that caused Eugenia's former fianc&eacute;e to kill himself. But, it is not always the beautiful butterfly that attracts. Sometimes, it is a plain little ant like Matty Crompton (Kristin Scott Thomas), who is busily working on her own plans for William. This all takes place shortly after Darwin's Origin of the Species was published, and during the Civil War in America. Both colored the story. Upon the death of Mother, Eugenia ascends the role of Queen ant, continuing to produce heirs. At the same time, a collaboration of William and Matty results in a book being published. Then the shocking secret comes forth. Mark Rylance, Patsy Kensit, and Kristin Scott Thomas were all fantastic in this shocking tale.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    drab ending? possible spoilers!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gghunter09
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/1/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I loved this movie! i remember seeing the trailer for it on the movie "haunted" (also superb) and was deeply in love with it. Although the film and story is wonderful I felt the ending lacked more than most should. To me it was very easy to tell what would happen especially with the way Edgar acted towards William at the ball. Over protective much? Of course when it finally got to the end there they were in all their glory! I think the film made it too apparent that there was incest in the family but other than that fact I loved the film. It's sad to think though that most films just end leaving the audience with nothing. So much for a climax (no pun intended.)
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Black period drama
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Framescourer
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/11/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A tough AS Byatt adaptation from Philip Haas which takes a cold look at Darwinism. Rylance's Mark Adamson is a ruined botanist who takes not only the charity of his patron Sir Harald Alabaster but, in time, his daughter Eugenia's hand. Something is not right though and tragedy strikes him a second time when he discovers her secret. Haas has created a lush film, overflowing with life as if the Alabaster house were a jungle itself. This is the irony of the film. A strange transformation seems to have taken place whereby the appropriately named Alabasters have lost the warmth and colour of a moral existence, a better life of which only Sir Harald, Mark and the discreet but ardent Matty Crompton seem to be aware. Kristin Scott Thomas gives the best of the performances as the intelligent but buttoned-down Matty. It's just a shame that her role is necessarily minuscule compared to the less engaging Patsy Kensit, well-cast but not particularly memorable as the frigid Eugenia, not that an unsympathetic Ryalnce does much to help her, I'm afraid. Douglas Henshall is ideal as the insipid Edgar. 6/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Intelligent and Unsual British Drama
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Andres Salama
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/12/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    An intelligent and unusual drama, based on a short story by A.S. Byatt. In mid 18th century England, a penniless naturalist who has lost his prized specimens from the Amazon in a shipwreck (I think the movie meant him to be a young Charles Darwin, though an incident where specimens were lost in a shipwreck happened to his colleague Alfred Russell Wallace) gets a job cataloging specimens held by the Alabaster family in their country estate. He will eventually marry their daughter Eugenia (Patsy Kensit), despite the fierce opposition of her brother Edgar. Not long after having children with her, he will discover a terrible secret haunting the family. A cousin of the Alabasters, the bookish Matty (Kristin Scott Thomas) will turn out to be his only friend and ally. At times the movie looks like a strange cross between a film by James Ivory and a film by Peter Greenaway, with the Alabaster women carrying bright colored clothes that suggests different sort of insects. Even if you don't take the entomology references throughout comparing insects with humans very seriously, they are nonetheless fun. And the denouement is terrific.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of the Worst Films....Ever
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Theaterchica07
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/9/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I had to watch this film for a class about Mid-Victorian Britain...with my professors and my class...and I was shocked at the story; Not just how awful the acting was, but that the script was actually bought and given a green light for production. The costumes were stylized and the design was nominated for an Oscar...how that was possible, I don't even know. The only thing redeemable about the film is Kristen Scott Thomas. Mark Rylance and Patsy Kensit give two of the worst performances I have ever seen in my entire life. Rylance's pitch and tone of voice never changes and Kensit was overly dramatic to the point of being comical. I would only see this movie if you want to laugh. But even at that, you're going to be wasting money...even energy by renting this movie. Stay away...
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    For the tongue-in-cheek coffee-sippers among us.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    merrywood
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    We humans come in so many different mind-sets that, astonishingly, a film like this tedious, annoyingly mundane and meaningless churning can actually have value to some. For me it was a time for slapping my face to stay awake, looking for gummed tape to hold up my eyelids. But then, there was such a marvelous pay-off, again, not for all of us but for those with iron clad stomachs. What was it? The boring protagonist discovers that all his children are really the offspring of his wife's long time sexual relationship with her brother. Indeed, he walks in on them slapping loins, at some point. One looks for meaning in all forms of literature only to find that, perhaps, life might very well be devoid of meaning. Maybe that is what those given to this drivel have objectified.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    feminist victorian nightmare
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    filmtherapy
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is one of the most visually repulsive movies I have ever watched. I enjoyed reading the other reviews for this film.I got a good laugh from the person who described the women's dresses as being like a visual jackhammer. The dresses are supposed to reflect insects the field of study of the main character. The first thing I personally noticed aside from the bumble bee and other jack hammer dresses was that the lighting was too bright indoors. It looked like flood lights were everywhere when in fact a night scene in that era would have been candle lit. Thus my first disappointment=something looks cheap or wrong herewas this filmed with some unknown color film? Second there is the revolting albino poor white trash looking group of aristocrats living in an authoritarian like atmosphere (the Alabaster family...whitest whites alabaster get it?? ) with servants cringing towards walls etc It could have easily turned into a horror movie. And finally last there is the predictable totally unbelievable modern feminist twist to the story-the unbelievably talented in every sense of unbelievable "right on" strong woman who rescues the milquetoast male lead---something guaranteed to win it Oscar nominations. What can I say....ho hum...it would get a lot of claps on Oprah. It is something you can't seem to escape from any more
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A lyrical, lush masterpiece
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    toptip
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/9/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    William Adamson (Mark Rylance) is an entymologist who marries into the aristocratic Alabaster family in Victorian England. He spends his time on his newly acquired expanse studying insects and tending to his wife, Eugenia (Patsy Kensit). Before too long he starts noticing odd behavior from his new family, and proceeds to turn the microscope on them. Careful, quietly masterful performance by Mark Rylance, who usually makes his living as the director of Shakespeare's Globe Theater. And, as Lady Alabaster (a museum piece, for sure!), Annette Badlands is perfect. It's a pretty film. There's some beautiful technique employed here and there, as evidenced by the fine closeups of butterflies and measuring devices, and the way in which the voices of the actors are interwoven with the rustle of the manicured forest that envelops them. A lyrical, lush masterpiece. One of the best films of the 90's.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Thanks, but no thanks!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mac-hawk
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/2/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A Victorian period drama with quasi erotic bits! Poorly acted, bland and boring and for much of the time very predictable for me. The main characters are pretty lame and are acted much the same. Mark Rylance, as William Adamson, seems to have perfected an expression of blank emotion (or maybe it's just boredom). Patsy Kensit's character exists to simply have a different frock on in EVERY scene she's in or get her kit off. Douglas Henshall provides the 'evil' character & is actually quite good, he doesn't overdo it so it never reaches the pantomime stage, however Annette Badland has no trouble in reaching these dizzy heights as Lady Alabaster (PK's characters mother). Kristin Scott Thomas plays a subdued second female lead and, like Henshall, comes away with some credit One has to assume it's not the actors fault as the director, Philip Haas, surely got what he asked for. How on earth this got the Evening Standard award for Best British film in 1995 beggars belief (it MUST have been a BAD year).
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    There's Definitely a Worm at the Center of This Apple
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    brocksilvey
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/6/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A fascinating and psychologically suffocating film based on a novella by A.S. Byatt. A doomed love affair and some serious family dysfunction provide the content for the story, and director Philip Haas ratchets up the sense of something rotting at the film's center to a high degree. Though all of the acting is fine, what I remember most about this film are the costumes, all designed to evoke insect imagery. The film deservedly won an Academy Award nomination for its costume design, and should have won, but the Academy decided to recognize "The English Patient's" assortment of Banana Republic outfits instead. Grade: B+
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I wish humankind would create such altruistic virtues, but sometimes I think socialism may never be realized.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    lastliberal
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/5/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A fascinating film about people acting like insects. The costuming is beyond brilliant, but it is the actions of the people that really are striking in this film. The matriarch of the family is definitely a Queen ant or bee. She constantly gorges herself as the others flutter about serving her. But it is Eugenia (Patsy Kensit) who is the focus of the film. A poor naturalist (Mark Rylance) is madly in love with her, but her racist brother (Douglas Henshall) warns him that he is not of the right class and should be real. William (Rylance) flits ever so cautiously towards Eugenia's web and is ensnared. I am sure there is something beneath the surface here; maybe the same something that caused Eugenia's former fianc&eacute;e to kill himself. But, it is not always the beautiful butterfly that attracts. Sometimes, it is a plain little ant like Matty Crompton (Kristin Scott Thomas), who is busily working on her own plans for William. This all takes place shortly after Darwin's Origin of the Species was published, and during the Civil War in America. Both colored the story. Upon the death of Mother, Eugenia ascends the role of Queen ant, continuing to produce heirs. At the same time, a collaboration of William and Matty results in a book being published. Then the shocking secret comes forth. Mark Rylance, Patsy Kensit, and Kristin Scott Thomas were all fantastic in this shocking tale.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    drab ending? possible spoilers!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gghunter09
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/1/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I loved this movie! i remember seeing the trailer for it on the movie "haunted" (also superb) and was deeply in love with it. Although the film and story is wonderful I felt the ending lacked more than most should. To me it was very easy to tell what would happen especially with the way Edgar acted towards William at the ball. Over protective much? Of course when it finally got to the end there they were in all their glory! I think the film made it too apparent that there was incest in the family but other than that fact I loved the film. It's sad to think though that most films just end leaving the audience with nothing. So much for a climax (no pun intended.)
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Black period drama
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Framescourer
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/11/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A tough AS Byatt adaptation from Philip Haas which takes a cold look at Darwinism. Rylance's Mark Adamson is a ruined botanist who takes not only the charity of his patron Sir Harald Alabaster but, in time, his daughter Eugenia's hand. Something is not right though and tragedy strikes him a second time when he discovers her secret. Haas has created a lush film, overflowing with life as if the Alabaster house were a jungle itself. This is the irony of the film. A strange transformation seems to have taken place whereby the appropriately named Alabasters have lost the warmth and colour of a moral existence, a better life of which only Sir Harald, Mark and the discreet but ardent Matty Crompton seem to be aware. Kristin Scott Thomas gives the best of the performances as the intelligent but buttoned-down Matty. It's just a shame that her role is necessarily minuscule compared to the less engaging Patsy Kensit, well-cast but not particularly memorable as the frigid Eugenia, not that an unsympathetic Ryalnce does much to help her, I'm afraid. Douglas Henshall is ideal as the insipid Edgar. 6/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Intelligent and Unsual British Drama
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Andres Salama
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/12/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    An intelligent and unusual drama, based on a short story by A.S. Byatt. In mid 18th century England, a penniless naturalist who has lost his prized specimens from the Amazon in a shipwreck (I think the movie meant him to be a young Charles Darwin, though an incident where specimens were lost in a shipwreck happened to his colleague Alfred Russell Wallace) gets a job cataloging specimens held by the Alabaster family in their country estate. He will eventually marry their daughter Eugenia (Patsy Kensit), despite the fierce opposition of her brother Edgar. Not long after having children with her, he will discover a terrible secret haunting the family. A cousin of the Alabasters, the bookish Matty (Kristin Scott Thomas) will turn out to be his only friend and ally. At times the movie looks like a strange cross between a film by James Ivory and a film by Peter Greenaway, with the Alabaster women carrying bright colored clothes that suggests different sort of insects. Even if you don't take the entomology references throughout comparing insects with humans very seriously, they are nonetheless fun. And the denouement is terrific.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of the Worst Films....Ever
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Theaterchica07
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/9/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I had to watch this film for a class about Mid-Victorian Britain...with my professors and my class...and I was shocked at the story; Not just how awful the acting was, but that the script was actually bought and given a green light for production. The costumes were stylized and the design was nominated for an Oscar...how that was possible, I don't even know. The only thing redeemable about the film is Kristen Scott Thomas. Mark Rylance and Patsy Kensit give two of the worst performances I have ever seen in my entire life. Rylance's pitch and tone of voice never changes and Kensit was overly dramatic to the point of being comical. I would only see this movie if you want to laugh. But even at that, you're going to be wasting money...even energy by renting this movie. Stay away...
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    For the tongue-in-cheek coffee-sippers among us.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    merrywood
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    We humans come in so many different mind-sets that, astonishingly, a film like this tedious, annoyingly mundane and meaningless churning can actually have value to some. For me it was a time for slapping my face to stay awake, looking for gummed tape to hold up my eyelids. But then, there was such a marvelous pay-off, again, not for all of us but for those with iron clad stomachs. What was it? The boring protagonist discovers that all his children are really the offspring of his wife's long time sexual relationship with her brother. Indeed, he walks in on them slapping loins, at some point. One looks for meaning in all forms of literature only to find that, perhaps, life might very well be devoid of meaning. Maybe that is what those given to this drivel have objectified.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    feminist victorian nightmare
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    filmtherapy
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is one of the most visually repulsive movies I have ever watched. I enjoyed reading the other reviews for this film.I got a good laugh from the person who described the women's dresses as being like a visual jackhammer. The dresses are supposed to reflect insects the field of study of the main character. The first thing I personally noticed aside from the bumble bee and other jack hammer dresses was that the lighting was too bright indoors. It looked like flood lights were everywhere when in fact a night scene in that era would have been candle lit. Thus my first disappointment=something looks cheap or wrong herewas this filmed with some unknown color film? Second there is the revolting albino poor white trash looking group of aristocrats living in an authoritarian like atmosphere (the Alabaster family...whitest whites alabaster get it?? ) with servants cringing towards walls etc It could have easily turned into a horror movie. And finally last there is the predictable totally unbelievable modern feminist twist to the story-the unbelievably talented in every sense of unbelievable "right on" strong woman who rescues the milquetoast male lead---something guaranteed to win it Oscar nominations. What can I say....ho hum...it would get a lot of claps on Oprah. It is something you can't seem to escape from any more
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A lyrical, lush masterpiece
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    toptip
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/9/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    William Adamson (Mark Rylance) is an entymologist who marries into the aristocratic Alabaster family in Victorian England. He spends his time on his newly acquired expanse studying insects and tending to his wife, Eugenia (Patsy Kensit). Before too long he starts noticing odd behavior from his new family, and proceeds to turn the microscope on them. Careful, quietly masterful performance by Mark Rylance, who usually makes his living as the director of Shakespeare's Globe Theater. And, as Lady Alabaster (a museum piece, for sure!), Annette Badlands is perfect. It's a pretty film. There's some beautiful technique employed here and there, as evidenced by the fine closeups of butterflies and measuring devices, and the way in which the voices of the actors are interwoven with the rustle of the manicured forest that envelops them. A lyrical, lush masterpiece. One of the best films of the 90's.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Thanks, but no thanks!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mac-hawk
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/2/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A Victorian period drama with quasi erotic bits! Poorly acted, bland and boring and for much of the time very predictable for me. The main characters are pretty lame and are acted much the same. Mark Rylance, as William Adamson, seems to have perfected an expression of blank emotion (or maybe it's just boredom). Patsy Kensit's character exists to simply have a different frock on in EVERY scene she's in or get her kit off. Douglas Henshall provides the 'evil' character & is actually quite good, he doesn't overdo it so it never reaches the pantomime stage, however Annette Badland has no trouble in reaching these dizzy heights as Lady Alabaster (PK's characters mother). Kristin Scott Thomas plays a subdued second female lead and, like Henshall, comes away with some credit One has to assume it's not the actors fault as the director, Philip Haas, surely got what he asked for. How on earth this got the Evening Standard award for Best British film in 1995 beggars belief (it MUST have been a BAD year).
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    There's Definitely a Worm at the Center of This Apple
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    brocksilvey
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/6/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A fascinating and psychologically suffocating film based on a novella by A.S. Byatt. A doomed love affair and some serious family dysfunction provide the content for the story, and director Philip Haas ratchets up the sense of something rotting at the film's center to a high degree. Though all of the acting is fine, what I remember most about this film are the costumes, all designed to evoke insect imagery. The film deservedly won an Academy Award nomination for its costume design, and should have won, but the Academy decided to recognize "The English Patient's" assortment of Banana Republic outfits instead. Grade: B+
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I wish humankind would create such altruistic virtues, but sometimes I think socialism may never be realized.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    lastliberal
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/5/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A fascinating film about people acting like insects. The costuming is beyond brilliant, but it is the actions of the people that really are striking in this film. The matriarch of the family is definitely a Queen ant or bee. She constantly gorges herself as the others flutter about serving her. But it is Eugenia (Patsy Kensit) who is the focus of the film. A poor naturalist (Mark Rylance) is madly in love with her, but her racist brother (Douglas Henshall) warns him that he is not of the right class and should be real. William (Rylance) flits ever so cautiously towards Eugenia's web and is ensnared. I am sure there is something beneath the surface here; maybe the same something that caused Eugenia's former fianc&eacute;e to kill himself. But, it is not always the beautiful butterfly that attracts. Sometimes, it is a plain little ant like Matty Crompton (Kristin Scott Thomas), who is busily working on her own plans for William. This all takes place shortly after Darwin's Origin of the Species was published, and during the Civil War in America. Both colored the story. Upon the death of Mother, Eugenia ascends the role of Queen ant, continuing to produce heirs. At the same time, a collaboration of William and Matty results in a book being published. Then the shocking secret comes forth. Mark Rylance, Patsy Kensit, and Kristin Scott Thomas were all fantastic in this shocking tale.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    drab ending? possible spoilers!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gghunter09
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/1/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I loved this movie! i remember seeing the trailer for it on the movie "haunted" (also superb) and was deeply in love with it. Although the film and story is wonderful I felt the ending lacked more than most should. To me it was very easy to tell what would happen especially with the way Edgar acted towards William at the ball. Over protective much? Of course when it finally got to the end there they were in all their glory! I think the film made it too apparent that there was incest in the family but other than that fact I loved the film. It's sad to think though that most films just end leaving the audience with nothing. So much for a climax (no pun intended.)
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Black period drama
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Framescourer
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/11/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A tough AS Byatt adaptation from Philip Haas which takes a cold look at Darwinism. Rylance's Mark Adamson is a ruined botanist who takes not only the charity of his patron Sir Harald Alabaster but, in time, his daughter Eugenia's hand. Something is not right though and tragedy strikes him a second time when he discovers her secret. Haas has created a lush film, overflowing with life as if the Alabaster house were a jungle itself. This is the irony of the film. A strange transformation seems to have taken place whereby the appropriately named Alabasters have lost the warmth and colour of a moral existence, a better life of which only Sir Harald, Mark and the discreet but ardent Matty Crompton seem to be aware. Kristin Scott Thomas gives the best of the performances as the intelligent but buttoned-down Matty. It's just a shame that her role is necessarily minuscule compared to the less engaging Patsy Kensit, well-cast but not particularly memorable as the frigid Eugenia, not that an unsympathetic Ryalnce does much to help her, I'm afraid. Douglas Henshall is ideal as the insipid Edgar. 6/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Intelligent and Unsual British Drama
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Andres Salama
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/12/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    An intelligent and unusual drama, based on a short story by A.S. Byatt. In mid 18th century England, a penniless naturalist who has lost his prized specimens from the Amazon in a shipwreck (I think the movie meant him to be a young Charles Darwin, though an incident where specimens were lost in a shipwreck happened to his colleague Alfred Russell Wallace) gets a job cataloging specimens held by the Alabaster family in their country estate. He will eventually marry their daughter Eugenia (Patsy Kensit), despite the fierce opposition of her brother Edgar. Not long after having children with her, he will discover a terrible secret haunting the family. A cousin of the Alabasters, the bookish Matty (Kristin Scott Thomas) will turn out to be his only friend and ally. At times the movie looks like a strange cross between a film by James Ivory and a film by Peter Greenaway, with the Alabaster women carrying bright colored clothes that suggests different sort of insects. Even if you don't take the entomology references throughout comparing insects with humans very seriously, they are nonetheless fun. And the denouement is terrific.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of the Worst Films....Ever
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Theaterchica07
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/9/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I had to watch this film for a class about Mid-Victorian Britain...with my professors and my class...and I was shocked at the story; Not just how awful the acting was, but that the script was actually bought and given a green light for production. The costumes were stylized and the design was nominated for an Oscar...how that was possible, I don't even know. The only thing redeemable about the film is Kristen Scott Thomas. Mark Rylance and Patsy Kensit give two of the worst performances I have ever seen in my entire life. Rylance's pitch and tone of voice never changes and Kensit was overly dramatic to the point of being comical. I would only see this movie if you want to laugh. But even at that, you're going to be wasting money...even energy by renting this movie. Stay away...
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    For the tongue-in-cheek coffee-sippers among us.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    merrywood
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    We humans come in so many different mind-sets that, astonishingly, a film like this tedious, annoyingly mundane and meaningless churning can actually have value to some. For me it was a time for slapping my face to stay awake, looking for gummed tape to hold up my eyelids. But then, there was such a marvelous pay-off, again, not for all of us but for those with iron clad stomachs. What was it? The boring protagonist discovers that all his children are really the offspring of his wife's long time sexual relationship with her brother. Indeed, he walks in on them slapping loins, at some point. One looks for meaning in all forms of literature only to find that, perhaps, life might very well be devoid of meaning. Maybe that is what those given to this drivel have objectified.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    feminist victorian nightmare
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    filmtherapy
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is one of the most visually repulsive movies I have ever watched. I enjoyed reading the other reviews for this film.I got a good laugh from the person who described the women's dresses as being like a visual jackhammer. The dresses are supposed to reflect insects the field of study of the main character. The first thing I personally noticed aside from the bumble bee and other jack hammer dresses was that the lighting was too bright indoors. It looked like flood lights were everywhere when in fact a night scene in that era would have been candle lit. Thus my first disappointment=something looks cheap or wrong herewas this filmed with some unknown color film? Second there is the revolting albino poor white trash looking group of aristocrats living in an authoritarian like atmosphere (the Alabaster family...whitest whites alabaster get it?? ) with servants cringing towards walls etc It could have easily turned into a horror movie. And finally last there is the predictable totally unbelievable modern feminist twist to the story-the unbelievably talented in every sense of unbelievable "right on" strong woman who rescues the milquetoast male lead---something guaranteed to win it Oscar nominations. What can I say....ho hum...it would get a lot of claps on Oprah. It is something you can't seem to escape from any more
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A lyrical, lush masterpiece
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    toptip
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/9/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    William Adamson (Mark Rylance) is an entymologist who marries into the aristocratic Alabaster family in Victorian England. He spends his time on his newly acquired expanse studying insects and tending to his wife, Eugenia (Patsy Kensit). Before too long he starts noticing odd behavior from his new family, and proceeds to turn the microscope on them. Careful, quietly masterful performance by Mark Rylance, who usually makes his living as the director of Shakespeare's Globe Theater. And, as Lady Alabaster (a museum piece, for sure!), Annette Badlands is perfect. It's a pretty film. There's some beautiful technique employed here and there, as evidenced by the fine closeups of butterflies and measuring devices, and the way in which the voices of the actors are interwoven with the rustle of the manicured forest that envelops them. A lyrical, lush masterpiece. One of the best films of the 90's.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Thanks, but no thanks!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mac-hawk
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/2/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A Victorian period drama with quasi erotic bits! Poorly acted, bland and boring and for much of the time very predictable for me. The main characters are pretty lame and are acted much the same. Mark Rylance, as William Adamson, seems to have perfected an expression of blank emotion (or maybe it's just boredom). Patsy Kensit's character exists to simply have a different frock on in EVERY scene she's in or get her kit off. Douglas Henshall provides the 'evil' character & is actually quite good, he doesn't overdo it so it never reaches the pantomime stage, however Annette Badland has no trouble in reaching these dizzy heights as Lady Alabaster (PK's characters mother). Kristin Scott Thomas plays a subdued second female lead and, like Henshall, comes away with some credit One has to assume it's not the actors fault as the director, Philip Haas, surely got what he asked for. How on earth this got the Evening Standard award for Best British film in 1995 beggars belief (it MUST have been a BAD year).
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    There's Definitely a Worm at the Center of This Apple
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    brocksilvey
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/6/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A fascinating and psychologically suffocating film based on a novella by A.S. Byatt. A doomed love affair and some serious family dysfunction provide the content for the story, and director Philip Haas ratchets up the sense of something rotting at the film's center to a high degree. Though all of the acting is fine, what I remember most about this film are the costumes, all designed to evoke insect imagery. The film deservedly won an Academy Award nomination for its costume design, and should have won, but the Academy decided to recognize "The English Patient's" assortment of Banana Republic outfits instead. Grade: B+
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I wish humankind would create such altruistic virtues, but sometimes I think socialism may never be realized.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    lastliberal
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/5/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A fascinating film about people acting like insects. The costuming is beyond brilliant, but it is the actions of the people that really are striking in this film. The matriarch of the family is definitely a Queen ant or bee. She constantly gorges herself as the others flutter about serving her. But it is Eugenia (Patsy Kensit) who is the focus of the film. A poor naturalist (Mark Rylance) is madly in love with her, but her racist brother (Douglas Henshall) warns him that he is not of the right class and should be real. William (Rylance) flits ever so cautiously towards Eugenia's web and is ensnared. I am sure there is something beneath the surface here; maybe the same something that caused Eugenia's former fianc&eacute;e to kill himself. But, it is not always the beautiful butterfly that attracts. Sometimes, it is a plain little ant like Matty Crompton (Kristin Scott Thomas), who is busily working on her own plans for William. This all takes place shortly after Darwin's Origin of the Species was published, and during the Civil War in America. Both colored the story. Upon the death of Mother, Eugenia ascends the role of Queen ant, continuing to produce heirs. At the same time, a collaboration of William and Matty results in a book being published. Then the shocking secret comes forth. Mark Rylance, Patsy Kensit, and Kristin Scott Thomas were all fantastic in this shocking tale.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    drab ending? possible spoilers!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gghunter09
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/1/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I loved this movie! i remember seeing the trailer for it on the movie "haunted" (also superb) and was deeply in love with it. Although the film and story is wonderful I felt the ending lacked more than most should. To me it was very easy to tell what would happen especially with the way Edgar acted towards William at the ball. Over protective much? Of course when it finally got to the end there they were in all their glory! I think the film made it too apparent that there was incest in the family but other than that fact I loved the film. It's sad to think though that most films just end leaving the audience with nothing. So much for a climax (no pun intended.)
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Black period drama
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Framescourer
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/11/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A tough AS Byatt adaptation from Philip Haas which takes a cold look at Darwinism. Rylance's Mark Adamson is a ruined botanist who takes not only the charity of his patron Sir Harald Alabaster but, in time, his daughter Eugenia's hand. Something is not right though and tragedy strikes him a second time when he discovers her secret. Haas has created a lush film, overflowing with life as if the Alabaster house were a jungle itself. This is the irony of the film. A strange transformation seems to have taken place whereby the appropriately named Alabasters have lost the warmth and colour of a moral existence, a better life of which only Sir Harald, Mark and the discreet but ardent Matty Crompton seem to be aware. Kristin Scott Thomas gives the best of the performances as the intelligent but buttoned-down Matty. It's just a shame that her role is necessarily minuscule compared to the less engaging Patsy Kensit, well-cast but not particularly memorable as the frigid Eugenia, not that an unsympathetic Ryalnce does much to help her, I'm afraid. Douglas Henshall is ideal as the insipid Edgar. 6/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Intelligent and Unsual British Drama
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Andres Salama
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/12/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    An intelligent and unusual drama, based on a short story by A.S. Byatt. In mid 18th century England, a penniless naturalist who has lost his prized specimens from the Amazon in a shipwreck (I think the movie meant him to be a young Charles Darwin, though an incident where specimens were lost in a shipwreck happened to his colleague Alfred Russell Wallace) gets a job cataloging specimens held by the Alabaster family in their country estate. He will eventually marry their daughter Eugenia (Patsy Kensit), despite the fierce opposition of her brother Edgar. Not long after having children with her, he will discover a terrible secret haunting the family. A cousin of the Alabasters, the bookish Matty (Kristin Scott Thomas) will turn out to be his only friend and ally. At times the movie looks like a strange cross between a film by James Ivory and a film by Peter Greenaway, with the Alabaster women carrying bright colored clothes that suggests different sort of insects. Even if you don't take the entomology references throughout comparing insects with humans very seriously, they are nonetheless fun. And the denouement is terrific.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of the Worst Films....Ever
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Theaterchica07
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/9/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I had to watch this film for a class about Mid-Victorian Britain...with my professors and my class...and I was shocked at the story; Not just how awful the acting was, but that the script was actually bought and given a green light for production. The costumes were stylized and the design was nominated for an Oscar...how that was possible, I don't even know. The only thing redeemable about the film is Kristen Scott Thomas. Mark Rylance and Patsy Kensit give two of the worst performances I have ever seen in my entire life. Rylance's pitch and tone of voice never changes and Kensit was overly dramatic to the point of being comical. I would only see this movie if you want to laugh. But even at that, you're going to be wasting money...even energy by renting this movie. Stay away...
   </conteudo>
  </review>
 </reviews>
</filme>
