<filme>
 <id>
  207
 </id>
 <imdburl>
  http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0099334
 </imdburl>
 <ano>
  1990
 </ano>
 <titulo>
  Cyrano
 </titulo>
 <rating>
  7.5
 </rating>
 <sinopse>
  Embarrassed by his large nose, a romantic poet/soldier romances his cousin by proxy.
 </sinopse>
 <storyline>
  A dashing officer of the guard and romantic poet, Cyrano de Bergerac falls in love with his cousin Roxane without her knowing. His one fault in his life, he feels, is his large nose and although it may have been a forming influence in his rapier-sharp wit, he believes that Roxane will reject him. He resorts to writing letters to her on behalf of one of his cadets, Christian, who is also in love with Roxane but just doesn't know how to tell her. She falls for the poetic charm of the letters but believes that they were written by Christian.
 </storyline>
 <generos>
  <genero>
   Biography
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Comedy
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Drama
  </genero>
 </generos>
 <keywords>
  <keyword>
   letter
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   nose
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   french
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   poet
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   sword fight
  </keyword>
 </keywords>
 <diretores>
  <diretor>
   Jean-Paul Rappeneau
  </diretor>
 </diretores>
 <escritores>
  <escritor>
   Jean-Claude Carri&egrave;re
  </escritor>
  <escritor>
   Jean-Paul Rappeneau
  </escritor>
 </escritores>
 <atores>
  <ator>
   G&eacute;rard Depardieu
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Anne Brochet
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Vincent Perez
  </ator>
 </atores>
 <reviews>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Cyrano - the representative of many a men
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Manoj Murali (manoj.back.in.action@gmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    There is a Cyrano Bergerac in majority of men. The man who can fight with hundred at a time, but doesn't have the courage to express his love. His complex, his fear is something which I myself have experienced in life. Apart from all this what makes Cyrano special is the happiness he finds in making his loved one happy. Even if that means letting her unite with the man she loves. As Cyrano himself says towards the end - " While I was down there in darkness, others climbed up and kissed the flower". This one line is valid not just in the life of Cyrano but many of us around. The film is filled with similar heart pleasing one liners. If ever you thought you are a loser who cant win hearts, turn on to this masterpiece. There is a beauty in being a loser. A beauty that is eternal..
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Cyrano De Bergerac
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    baloga09
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Cyrano De Bergerac was a very energetic and passionate movie. The actor that played Cyrano did such a great job. The enthusiasm and power that he put into the role was amazing. I love how Cyrano was so prideful. He had his own path and he did not care who he angered. I also enjoyed how the ending was not a happy ending. I feel the way they ended it was more believable than the way an American would of ended it, with the guy getting the girl and living happily ever after. The directer is Jean-Paul Rappeneau. He is a french film director, screenwriter, and actor. Rappeneau is known for creating the most elaborate film version of Cyrano De Bergerac. The film was one of the most expensive French films ever produced. A great idea is the idea about how people think very superficial about themselves. This idea is seen throughout the whole film. In the beginning Cyrano freaks out at a man in the theater and ends up in a sword and word battle with the guy because he makes fun of his nose. Also Cyrano feels no woman would want him just because of his nose. Even in the end when he is told that Roxanne loved whoever wrote the letters and did not care if the person was ugly, Cyrano still waited until his death was eminent to let her know he wrote the letters. Another good idea is that a man should stand up for what he believes in. Cyrano shows this constantly throughout the movie. First when he is in the bathhouse and Comte De Guiche comes to ask him a question. Cyrano could get one of his plays put on stage but he would have to join Comte De Guiche. Cyrano basically spits in his face and does not respect the man. The largest thing that stood out to me that made this movie French was the fact that it did not have a happy ending. If this were an American film Cyrano would of ended with Roxanne and Christian would not of died. But with having Christian die and Cyrano not tell Roxanne he loves her we get this interesting ending where no one ends up happy. It has a very dark Shakespearian feel to it. Another thing from the movie that was very French was that you were entertained by more words than fighting. In an American film there would of been more fighting and less word play, but in the French movie the people are more proud of being able to speak more diverse than be rich.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Great--with the heartwrenching story, funny rhyming script, and a terrific Depardieu lead
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    secondtake
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/7/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Cyrano de Bergerac (1990) This is Gerard Depardieu's shining moment in an up and down career. Some say the movie makes a blur of the subtle writing and emotional power of the original play by Edmond Rostand of the same title, written in 1897. And as much as the English version by Jose Ferrar (1950) is the acclaimed English language version, the play was originally French. And it's all in verse, including the subtitles, which in this case use the translation by Anthony Burgess (of Clockwork Orange fame). But the story, the story. It's all about the simple amazing plot (about which Rostand was convicted, on slim evidence, of stealing from a Chicago amateur writer). The year is something like 1680, in France. A man of great talent and fighting skill, a deep emotional life and poetic sensibility, and also with a gigantic nose, is in love with Roxane. This is poor Cyrano, who has everything but good looks. And Roxane happens to be in love with a very good looking young man who is a bit of a talentless fool. Cyrano, out of love for Roxane, steps in to help the fool by writing letters for him that succeed in wooing the beautiful Roxane. If this sounds like that crazy movie called "Roxane" starring Steve Martin, well, you've got it. That's the Cyrano story, and Martin's movie sort of kicked off the contemporary deluge of Cyrano movies in 1987 (three years before this one). Of course his is a comedy, and there are some changes from the play and this 1990 version, which tries even in its grandiose production to be true to the tightly written and scripted original. It's all pretty terrific. In a way, if you like Shakespeare, it's the play that holds the whole thing back a bit, lacking, oddly enough, complexity. An example is the funny but thin asides with the cake maker who wants to be a poet. There is no shortage of characters, there is a constant turning of events, and it does never quite ever slow down, but the main trick and drama of the situation is so central and gripping you end up waiting for it to find some kind of denouement or twist and surprise. And you do eventually get that, with great beauty and pathos (this is no comedy). But that's sort of all you get, in terms of narrative flow. And that's almost all you need, I have to admit. This production pulls out all the stops, and scene after scene is amazing in its set design and lighting, in its huge range of characters and gritty lovely evocation of 17th Century France. You could watch a bad play with such sets. And the photography is fluid, active, and formally terrific, too, which layers up the ongoing beauty of the filming. And Depardieu is terrific in his bloated, leading man way (I say this because he has detractors, those who have seen searing and cutting intensity in stage versions, but I have nothing to compare it to except Steve Martin). The two other main characters are actually a drag overall, and avoidably, I should think, with all the talent being lavishly expended. Roxane is more delighted than delightful, ornamentally pretty but also so stiff emotionally you wonder what all the fuss is about. And the foolish pretty boy is probably meant to be a bit shallow as a character, but it does leave his parts a little cardboard. Anyway, I overthink this. See the movie. If you don't like subtitles, see the American one from 1950. Don't think the Steve Martin one is enough. For one thing, the original ending is one of the most moving and memorable in all of cinema. For me, the Depardieu version of this last great scene is unmatched.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of the most beautiful films I have seen in my life
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    TheLittleSongbird
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I love films of all kinds, and since liking Gerard Depardieu and being familiar with Rostand's classic play, I knew it was going to be good. But I wasn't expecting it to be this brilliant, I can't think of a film recently that struck me with how beautiful and poignant it was as much as Cyrano De Bergerac did. There were three major assets that really blew me over. One was how beautifully translated and subtitled it had been, I have not seen subtitles or dialogue this lyrical or poetic in a while. Two was how Cyrano De Bergerac was made. The costume design and scenery are truly sumptuous, as is the cinematography. Gerard Depardieu's performance is truly exceptional and I don't think he has been better, though Jean De Florette comes close. Depardieu is passionate, witty and very moving. The support cast with Anne Brochet and Vincent Perez particularly notable do a fine job matching him. Cyrano De Bergerac's story is one that is timeless, and for those who haven't yet seen it, it is most likely to emotionally resonate with you like it did with me. The music is both rousing and quietly understated too. Overall, I have nothing bad to say about Cyrano De Bergerac, it is the very definition of beauty and poetry on film, complete with an exceptional lead performance. 10/10 Bethany Cox
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A sad story of why you should not let love go unspoken
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    david-sarkies
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/12/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Now this is interesting because I have a feeling that Roxanne, the American version of this film, was released first. I am not sure as to the release date of the first film for I believe it to be a 80's movie as opposed to a 90's movie. It was on recently but I think, no, I know that I threw out the television paper so I do not know. Anyway, Cyrano de Bergerac seriously romps all over Roxanne, as most French movies tend to do to their American counterparts. Cyrano de Bergerac is about the captain of the Gascony guard who has a big, no a whopping great nose, and he is very sensitive about its size. He considers himself a freak and that nobody will see past the nose to his soul. Cyrano is a poet and a great lover but he feels he can never be loved because of his physical appearance. The woman that he loves, Roxanne, is in love with another man, Christian, who is in Cyrano's battalion but Christian does not know how to be romantic so Cyrano becomes Christian's romantic side and uses his romantic words to create an intellectual depth to Christian that does not exist. Cyrano de Bergerac is a tragedy in a number of ways. There is no fulfillment in the romantic sequences. Christian is not what Roxanne wants and they can never really be together because Roxanne loves Christian's words and his looks and nothing else. She claims to love his soul, but it is a soul that says the words that she wants to hear. When Christian tries to confront her without Cyrano's help, she sees a brute that she wants nothing to do with. She does not love his soul but rather his words, the words that Cyrano speaks. The further tragic part deals with the Duke who also loves Roxanne, and wants to marry her. Instead, Roxanne marries Christian, with Cyrano's help and upon discovery, the duke sends them off to the Spanish Front where there is little hope of survival. They are married in word but it is not consummated and the duke makes sure that it is not, and never will be consummated. The greater tragedy is that of Cyrano. He holds a love for Roxanne, though it is really only attraction to her physical appearance, yet he does not speak of it to anyone. Christian learns before his death, and he is the only one that knows that Cyrano loves Roxanne. This he learns from the letters that are sent in his name. He has read the letters and soon realises that Cyrano gives Roxanne a love that he never could, but Cyrano is constantly held back by his deformity. There is constantly reference to love in spite of a deformity, but Cyrano feels that he is not for Roxanne and remains silent. He spends time with her, every Saturday, and even manages to crawl to visit her on his death bed, but it is a love that remains silent, and the only person that knows and can reveal it is dead. Roxanne was a comedy, Cyrano de Bergerac is a tragedy. There is no hope in the film and everything is spiraling down to a very bloody conclusion. Cyrano is a master swordsman, who defeats a hundred men by himself, but he cannot stave off the anger of a duke. He is able to fight the Spanish hordes, but he is taunted by a love that he feels that can never be fulfilled. He speaks only of it on his death bed, and even though is very reluctant. This is a very sad movie, nothing like the Hollywood rubbish that is splattered over all of the screens. This is a movie with depth that deals with the real emotions of people. It is not one where the couple get together and live happily in the end, but one in which pain strikes through it right until the end. It is a poetic movie, though much of it will be lost in the translation. In essence, I see Cyrano de Bergerac on the level of a modern Shakespeare for it seems to have lots of Shakespearian elements, including a very deep, poetical language -- even though it is in French. Cyrano de Bergerac is a film that has one overriding theme and that is Carpe Diem - seize the day. Though such a thing does not happen in this movie, it shows us that it is something that we should do. We cannot let our love kindle unspoken, especially when the woman that our love is focused on so dearly wants to hear. In my opinion, it is not something that should be done for I feel that we need to be tactful in regards to the woman that we speak with and shouldn't overwhelm them, but in Cyrano's case he feels that his nose makes him hideous and that Roxanne won't want anything to do with him, which is not true as you learn at the end. When it comes down to self-doubt then it should be cast away. One should be tactful, but one should not attack oneself in belief that no woman would even want him.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Perfection
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bopulie
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/11/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Merging Poetry and Cinematography in a perfect way. First time in history, and it hasn't been done or even tried again aftetwards. English translations may be good, but to appreciate it to its full potential you have to speak french fluently, and it's probably why it isn't in the top 20 of IMDb. This movie earns a 10 out of 10 not only because of its unique style (dialogue is 100% alexandrines), but also because of the spot on acting and because the director didn't deviate from the original play by Edmond Rostand (an absolute heart-breaking drama) in any way which is a huge achievement. Magnifique.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    beats Hollywood at its own game
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Michael Neumann
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/11/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Edmond Rostand's celebrated swordsman/poet is the ideal role for Gerard Depardieu, demanding a physical presence and a level of energy few other actors could muster. Taking its cues from the swashbuckling entertainments of Hollywood's golden years, the film may well stand the test of time to become the definitive version of the story: thrilling, romantic, literate, and larger than life in a way that not even subtitles can hide. But it isn't all swordplay and daring-do: director Jean-Paul Rappeneau and his co-writer Jean-Claude Carriere devote equal attention to the humor in Cyrano's character and to the tragedy of his unrequited love for the fair Roxanne, and Depardieu responds with a generous performance filled with bold flourishes and subtle gestures. It was a sure bet for the Best Foreign Film Oscar, but Academy voters apparently don't appreciate European features comparing so favorably to their American role models. An ill-timed and too candid interview with Depardieu, during which the actor revealed too much (for Stateside viewers) of his delinquent adolescence probably didn't do the film any favors either.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    simply a superb film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    zb95
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/7/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Just a wonderful film. So many memorable scenes but my favorite was Cyrano's sword and verbal battle with the dude who made a simple common insult of his nose which Cyrano then responded with dozens of funny and clever alternate versions he could have used instead. Just a spectacularly witty and superbly acted scene! It has to be one of the best of all time in my opinion. But the entire movie was superb top to bottom. Great lines, great costumes, great acting. The English translations appeared to be perfect -- I cannot imagine it being any better in French but I suspect it was. It deserved all the awards it got. A ten in my book!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Beautiful, Poetic, and Masterful
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    HulotderSpeiler
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/2/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Although much of the greatness of this film comes from the immortal story of the French play written hundreds of years ago, there is something special about this adaptation that sets it apart from others. It may be simply that it is French, and the French understand this play more than anyone else. It could be Depardieu's riveting performance that would make you forget that he is acting. It might be attributed to the magnificent sets and stunning cinematography, or the perfect mix of tragedy and comedy. All of those things are part of it, but the true greatness comes from the translation. Some say that it may kill the poetry to make the lines that rhyme in French rhyme in English, but in this film it is not so. Cyrano's eloquence grips you in such a way that you feel like applauding the screen. The poetic soul of the story is backed by the characters speaking in poetry. The opening scene is masterfully shot, establishing the greatest character in film or literature in one of the greatest scenes of all time. Above all, Depardiu gives a performance for the ages in a demanding role. You will see why he won the top prize for acting at Cannes
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    probably the best ending line for a period piece
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    dumsumdumfai
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/9/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Steve Martin did a commendable job in turning this classic into Roxanne - but it was too optimistic for a modern piece... and lacks that... certain.... "P" thingy. It is only through the period setting and our limited and romanticized knowledge of the past that this version can work. And no less with Depardieu's imposing figure and statue. The opening sequence is captivating enough with the atmosphere, the smoke and the candle lights and the crowded theater/bar what have you. Still you need great delivery of the lines and a top-notched translation for the non-French speaking (like me) And what a last line !!!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Cyrano - the representative of many a men
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Manoj Murali (manoj.back.in.action@gmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    There is a Cyrano Bergerac in majority of men. The man who can fight with hundred at a time, but doesn't have the courage to express his love. His complex, his fear is something which I myself have experienced in life. Apart from all this what makes Cyrano special is the happiness he finds in making his loved one happy. Even if that means letting her unite with the man she loves. As Cyrano himself says towards the end - " While I was down there in darkness, others climbed up and kissed the flower". This one line is valid not just in the life of Cyrano but many of us around. The film is filled with similar heart pleasing one liners. If ever you thought you are a loser who cant win hearts, turn on to this masterpiece. There is a beauty in being a loser. A beauty that is eternal..
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Cyrano De Bergerac
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    baloga09
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Cyrano De Bergerac was a very energetic and passionate movie. The actor that played Cyrano did such a great job. The enthusiasm and power that he put into the role was amazing. I love how Cyrano was so prideful. He had his own path and he did not care who he angered. I also enjoyed how the ending was not a happy ending. I feel the way they ended it was more believable than the way an American would of ended it, with the guy getting the girl and living happily ever after. The directer is Jean-Paul Rappeneau. He is a french film director, screenwriter, and actor. Rappeneau is known for creating the most elaborate film version of Cyrano De Bergerac. The film was one of the most expensive French films ever produced. A great idea is the idea about how people think very superficial about themselves. This idea is seen throughout the whole film. In the beginning Cyrano freaks out at a man in the theater and ends up in a sword and word battle with the guy because he makes fun of his nose. Also Cyrano feels no woman would want him just because of his nose. Even in the end when he is told that Roxanne loved whoever wrote the letters and did not care if the person was ugly, Cyrano still waited until his death was eminent to let her know he wrote the letters. Another good idea is that a man should stand up for what he believes in. Cyrano shows this constantly throughout the movie. First when he is in the bathhouse and Comte De Guiche comes to ask him a question. Cyrano could get one of his plays put on stage but he would have to join Comte De Guiche. Cyrano basically spits in his face and does not respect the man. The largest thing that stood out to me that made this movie French was the fact that it did not have a happy ending. If this were an American film Cyrano would of ended with Roxanne and Christian would not of died. But with having Christian die and Cyrano not tell Roxanne he loves her we get this interesting ending where no one ends up happy. It has a very dark Shakespearian feel to it. Another thing from the movie that was very French was that you were entertained by more words than fighting. In an American film there would of been more fighting and less word play, but in the French movie the people are more proud of being able to speak more diverse than be rich.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Great--with the heartwrenching story, funny rhyming script, and a terrific Depardieu lead
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    secondtake
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/7/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Cyrano de Bergerac (1990) This is Gerard Depardieu's shining moment in an up and down career. Some say the movie makes a blur of the subtle writing and emotional power of the original play by Edmond Rostand of the same title, written in 1897. And as much as the English version by Jose Ferrar (1950) is the acclaimed English language version, the play was originally French. And it's all in verse, including the subtitles, which in this case use the translation by Anthony Burgess (of Clockwork Orange fame). But the story, the story. It's all about the simple amazing plot (about which Rostand was convicted, on slim evidence, of stealing from a Chicago amateur writer). The year is something like 1680, in France. A man of great talent and fighting skill, a deep emotional life and poetic sensibility, and also with a gigantic nose, is in love with Roxane. This is poor Cyrano, who has everything but good looks. And Roxane happens to be in love with a very good looking young man who is a bit of a talentless fool. Cyrano, out of love for Roxane, steps in to help the fool by writing letters for him that succeed in wooing the beautiful Roxane. If this sounds like that crazy movie called "Roxane" starring Steve Martin, well, you've got it. That's the Cyrano story, and Martin's movie sort of kicked off the contemporary deluge of Cyrano movies in 1987 (three years before this one). Of course his is a comedy, and there are some changes from the play and this 1990 version, which tries even in its grandiose production to be true to the tightly written and scripted original. It's all pretty terrific. In a way, if you like Shakespeare, it's the play that holds the whole thing back a bit, lacking, oddly enough, complexity. An example is the funny but thin asides with the cake maker who wants to be a poet. There is no shortage of characters, there is a constant turning of events, and it does never quite ever slow down, but the main trick and drama of the situation is so central and gripping you end up waiting for it to find some kind of denouement or twist and surprise. And you do eventually get that, with great beauty and pathos (this is no comedy). But that's sort of all you get, in terms of narrative flow. And that's almost all you need, I have to admit. This production pulls out all the stops, and scene after scene is amazing in its set design and lighting, in its huge range of characters and gritty lovely evocation of 17th Century France. You could watch a bad play with such sets. And the photography is fluid, active, and formally terrific, too, which layers up the ongoing beauty of the filming. And Depardieu is terrific in his bloated, leading man way (I say this because he has detractors, those who have seen searing and cutting intensity in stage versions, but I have nothing to compare it to except Steve Martin). The two other main characters are actually a drag overall, and avoidably, I should think, with all the talent being lavishly expended. Roxane is more delighted than delightful, ornamentally pretty but also so stiff emotionally you wonder what all the fuss is about. And the foolish pretty boy is probably meant to be a bit shallow as a character, but it does leave his parts a little cardboard. Anyway, I overthink this. See the movie. If you don't like subtitles, see the American one from 1950. Don't think the Steve Martin one is enough. For one thing, the original ending is one of the most moving and memorable in all of cinema. For me, the Depardieu version of this last great scene is unmatched.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of the most beautiful films I have seen in my life
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    TheLittleSongbird
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I love films of all kinds, and since liking Gerard Depardieu and being familiar with Rostand's classic play, I knew it was going to be good. But I wasn't expecting it to be this brilliant, I can't think of a film recently that struck me with how beautiful and poignant it was as much as Cyrano De Bergerac did. There were three major assets that really blew me over. One was how beautifully translated and subtitled it had been, I have not seen subtitles or dialogue this lyrical or poetic in a while. Two was how Cyrano De Bergerac was made. The costume design and scenery are truly sumptuous, as is the cinematography. Gerard Depardieu's performance is truly exceptional and I don't think he has been better, though Jean De Florette comes close. Depardieu is passionate, witty and very moving. The support cast with Anne Brochet and Vincent Perez particularly notable do a fine job matching him. Cyrano De Bergerac's story is one that is timeless, and for those who haven't yet seen it, it is most likely to emotionally resonate with you like it did with me. The music is both rousing and quietly understated too. Overall, I have nothing bad to say about Cyrano De Bergerac, it is the very definition of beauty and poetry on film, complete with an exceptional lead performance. 10/10 Bethany Cox
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A sad story of why you should not let love go unspoken
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    david-sarkies
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/12/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Now this is interesting because I have a feeling that Roxanne, the American version of this film, was released first. I am not sure as to the release date of the first film for I believe it to be a 80's movie as opposed to a 90's movie. It was on recently but I think, no, I know that I threw out the television paper so I do not know. Anyway, Cyrano de Bergerac seriously romps all over Roxanne, as most French movies tend to do to their American counterparts. Cyrano de Bergerac is about the captain of the Gascony guard who has a big, no a whopping great nose, and he is very sensitive about its size. He considers himself a freak and that nobody will see past the nose to his soul. Cyrano is a poet and a great lover but he feels he can never be loved because of his physical appearance. The woman that he loves, Roxanne, is in love with another man, Christian, who is in Cyrano's battalion but Christian does not know how to be romantic so Cyrano becomes Christian's romantic side and uses his romantic words to create an intellectual depth to Christian that does not exist. Cyrano de Bergerac is a tragedy in a number of ways. There is no fulfillment in the romantic sequences. Christian is not what Roxanne wants and they can never really be together because Roxanne loves Christian's words and his looks and nothing else. She claims to love his soul, but it is a soul that says the words that she wants to hear. When Christian tries to confront her without Cyrano's help, she sees a brute that she wants nothing to do with. She does not love his soul but rather his words, the words that Cyrano speaks. The further tragic part deals with the Duke who also loves Roxanne, and wants to marry her. Instead, Roxanne marries Christian, with Cyrano's help and upon discovery, the duke sends them off to the Spanish Front where there is little hope of survival. They are married in word but it is not consummated and the duke makes sure that it is not, and never will be consummated. The greater tragedy is that of Cyrano. He holds a love for Roxanne, though it is really only attraction to her physical appearance, yet he does not speak of it to anyone. Christian learns before his death, and he is the only one that knows that Cyrano loves Roxanne. This he learns from the letters that are sent in his name. He has read the letters and soon realises that Cyrano gives Roxanne a love that he never could, but Cyrano is constantly held back by his deformity. There is constantly reference to love in spite of a deformity, but Cyrano feels that he is not for Roxanne and remains silent. He spends time with her, every Saturday, and even manages to crawl to visit her on his death bed, but it is a love that remains silent, and the only person that knows and can reveal it is dead. Roxanne was a comedy, Cyrano de Bergerac is a tragedy. There is no hope in the film and everything is spiraling down to a very bloody conclusion. Cyrano is a master swordsman, who defeats a hundred men by himself, but he cannot stave off the anger of a duke. He is able to fight the Spanish hordes, but he is taunted by a love that he feels that can never be fulfilled. He speaks only of it on his death bed, and even though is very reluctant. This is a very sad movie, nothing like the Hollywood rubbish that is splattered over all of the screens. This is a movie with depth that deals with the real emotions of people. It is not one where the couple get together and live happily in the end, but one in which pain strikes through it right until the end. It is a poetic movie, though much of it will be lost in the translation. In essence, I see Cyrano de Bergerac on the level of a modern Shakespeare for it seems to have lots of Shakespearian elements, including a very deep, poetical language -- even though it is in French. Cyrano de Bergerac is a film that has one overriding theme and that is Carpe Diem - seize the day. Though such a thing does not happen in this movie, it shows us that it is something that we should do. We cannot let our love kindle unspoken, especially when the woman that our love is focused on so dearly wants to hear. In my opinion, it is not something that should be done for I feel that we need to be tactful in regards to the woman that we speak with and shouldn't overwhelm them, but in Cyrano's case he feels that his nose makes him hideous and that Roxanne won't want anything to do with him, which is not true as you learn at the end. When it comes down to self-doubt then it should be cast away. One should be tactful, but one should not attack oneself in belief that no woman would even want him.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Perfection
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bopulie
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/11/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Merging Poetry and Cinematography in a perfect way. First time in history, and it hasn't been done or even tried again aftetwards. English translations may be good, but to appreciate it to its full potential you have to speak french fluently, and it's probably why it isn't in the top 20 of IMDb. This movie earns a 10 out of 10 not only because of its unique style (dialogue is 100% alexandrines), but also because of the spot on acting and because the director didn't deviate from the original play by Edmond Rostand (an absolute heart-breaking drama) in any way which is a huge achievement. Magnifique.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    beats Hollywood at its own game
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Michael Neumann
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/11/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Edmond Rostand's celebrated swordsman/poet is the ideal role for Gerard Depardieu, demanding a physical presence and a level of energy few other actors could muster. Taking its cues from the swashbuckling entertainments of Hollywood's golden years, the film may well stand the test of time to become the definitive version of the story: thrilling, romantic, literate, and larger than life in a way that not even subtitles can hide. But it isn't all swordplay and daring-do: director Jean-Paul Rappeneau and his co-writer Jean-Claude Carriere devote equal attention to the humor in Cyrano's character and to the tragedy of his unrequited love for the fair Roxanne, and Depardieu responds with a generous performance filled with bold flourishes and subtle gestures. It was a sure bet for the Best Foreign Film Oscar, but Academy voters apparently don't appreciate European features comparing so favorably to their American role models. An ill-timed and too candid interview with Depardieu, during which the actor revealed too much (for Stateside viewers) of his delinquent adolescence probably didn't do the film any favors either.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    simply a superb film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    zb95
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/7/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Just a wonderful film. So many memorable scenes but my favorite was Cyrano's sword and verbal battle with the dude who made a simple common insult of his nose which Cyrano then responded with dozens of funny and clever alternate versions he could have used instead. Just a spectacularly witty and superbly acted scene! It has to be one of the best of all time in my opinion. But the entire movie was superb top to bottom. Great lines, great costumes, great acting. The English translations appeared to be perfect -- I cannot imagine it being any better in French but I suspect it was. It deserved all the awards it got. A ten in my book!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Beautiful, Poetic, and Masterful
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    HulotderSpeiler
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/2/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Although much of the greatness of this film comes from the immortal story of the French play written hundreds of years ago, there is something special about this adaptation that sets it apart from others. It may be simply that it is French, and the French understand this play more than anyone else. It could be Depardieu's riveting performance that would make you forget that he is acting. It might be attributed to the magnificent sets and stunning cinematography, or the perfect mix of tragedy and comedy. All of those things are part of it, but the true greatness comes from the translation. Some say that it may kill the poetry to make the lines that rhyme in French rhyme in English, but in this film it is not so. Cyrano's eloquence grips you in such a way that you feel like applauding the screen. The poetic soul of the story is backed by the characters speaking in poetry. The opening scene is masterfully shot, establishing the greatest character in film or literature in one of the greatest scenes of all time. Above all, Depardiu gives a performance for the ages in a demanding role. You will see why he won the top prize for acting at Cannes
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    probably the best ending line for a period piece
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    dumsumdumfai
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/9/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Steve Martin did a commendable job in turning this classic into Roxanne - but it was too optimistic for a modern piece... and lacks that... certain.... "P" thingy. It is only through the period setting and our limited and romanticized knowledge of the past that this version can work. And no less with Depardieu's imposing figure and statue. The opening sequence is captivating enough with the atmosphere, the smoke and the candle lights and the crowded theater/bar what have you. Still you need great delivery of the lines and a top-notched translation for the non-French speaking (like me) And what a last line !!!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Cyrano - the representative of many a men
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Manoj Murali (manoj.back.in.action@gmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    There is a Cyrano Bergerac in majority of men. The man who can fight with hundred at a time, but doesn't have the courage to express his love. His complex, his fear is something which I myself have experienced in life. Apart from all this what makes Cyrano special is the happiness he finds in making his loved one happy. Even if that means letting her unite with the man she loves. As Cyrano himself says towards the end - " While I was down there in darkness, others climbed up and kissed the flower". This one line is valid not just in the life of Cyrano but many of us around. The film is filled with similar heart pleasing one liners. If ever you thought you are a loser who cant win hearts, turn on to this masterpiece. There is a beauty in being a loser. A beauty that is eternal..
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Cyrano De Bergerac
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    baloga09
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Cyrano De Bergerac was a very energetic and passionate movie. The actor that played Cyrano did such a great job. The enthusiasm and power that he put into the role was amazing. I love how Cyrano was so prideful. He had his own path and he did not care who he angered. I also enjoyed how the ending was not a happy ending. I feel the way they ended it was more believable than the way an American would of ended it, with the guy getting the girl and living happily ever after. The directer is Jean-Paul Rappeneau. He is a french film director, screenwriter, and actor. Rappeneau is known for creating the most elaborate film version of Cyrano De Bergerac. The film was one of the most expensive French films ever produced. A great idea is the idea about how people think very superficial about themselves. This idea is seen throughout the whole film. In the beginning Cyrano freaks out at a man in the theater and ends up in a sword and word battle with the guy because he makes fun of his nose. Also Cyrano feels no woman would want him just because of his nose. Even in the end when he is told that Roxanne loved whoever wrote the letters and did not care if the person was ugly, Cyrano still waited until his death was eminent to let her know he wrote the letters. Another good idea is that a man should stand up for what he believes in. Cyrano shows this constantly throughout the movie. First when he is in the bathhouse and Comte De Guiche comes to ask him a question. Cyrano could get one of his plays put on stage but he would have to join Comte De Guiche. Cyrano basically spits in his face and does not respect the man. The largest thing that stood out to me that made this movie French was the fact that it did not have a happy ending. If this were an American film Cyrano would of ended with Roxanne and Christian would not of died. But with having Christian die and Cyrano not tell Roxanne he loves her we get this interesting ending where no one ends up happy. It has a very dark Shakespearian feel to it. Another thing from the movie that was very French was that you were entertained by more words than fighting. In an American film there would of been more fighting and less word play, but in the French movie the people are more proud of being able to speak more diverse than be rich.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Great--with the heartwrenching story, funny rhyming script, and a terrific Depardieu lead
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    secondtake
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/7/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Cyrano de Bergerac (1990) This is Gerard Depardieu's shining moment in an up and down career. Some say the movie makes a blur of the subtle writing and emotional power of the original play by Edmond Rostand of the same title, written in 1897. And as much as the English version by Jose Ferrar (1950) is the acclaimed English language version, the play was originally French. And it's all in verse, including the subtitles, which in this case use the translation by Anthony Burgess (of Clockwork Orange fame). But the story, the story. It's all about the simple amazing plot (about which Rostand was convicted, on slim evidence, of stealing from a Chicago amateur writer). The year is something like 1680, in France. A man of great talent and fighting skill, a deep emotional life and poetic sensibility, and also with a gigantic nose, is in love with Roxane. This is poor Cyrano, who has everything but good looks. And Roxane happens to be in love with a very good looking young man who is a bit of a talentless fool. Cyrano, out of love for Roxane, steps in to help the fool by writing letters for him that succeed in wooing the beautiful Roxane. If this sounds like that crazy movie called "Roxane" starring Steve Martin, well, you've got it. That's the Cyrano story, and Martin's movie sort of kicked off the contemporary deluge of Cyrano movies in 1987 (three years before this one). Of course his is a comedy, and there are some changes from the play and this 1990 version, which tries even in its grandiose production to be true to the tightly written and scripted original. It's all pretty terrific. In a way, if you like Shakespeare, it's the play that holds the whole thing back a bit, lacking, oddly enough, complexity. An example is the funny but thin asides with the cake maker who wants to be a poet. There is no shortage of characters, there is a constant turning of events, and it does never quite ever slow down, but the main trick and drama of the situation is so central and gripping you end up waiting for it to find some kind of denouement or twist and surprise. And you do eventually get that, with great beauty and pathos (this is no comedy). But that's sort of all you get, in terms of narrative flow. And that's almost all you need, I have to admit. This production pulls out all the stops, and scene after scene is amazing in its set design and lighting, in its huge range of characters and gritty lovely evocation of 17th Century France. You could watch a bad play with such sets. And the photography is fluid, active, and formally terrific, too, which layers up the ongoing beauty of the filming. And Depardieu is terrific in his bloated, leading man way (I say this because he has detractors, those who have seen searing and cutting intensity in stage versions, but I have nothing to compare it to except Steve Martin). The two other main characters are actually a drag overall, and avoidably, I should think, with all the talent being lavishly expended. Roxane is more delighted than delightful, ornamentally pretty but also so stiff emotionally you wonder what all the fuss is about. And the foolish pretty boy is probably meant to be a bit shallow as a character, but it does leave his parts a little cardboard. Anyway, I overthink this. See the movie. If you don't like subtitles, see the American one from 1950. Don't think the Steve Martin one is enough. For one thing, the original ending is one of the most moving and memorable in all of cinema. For me, the Depardieu version of this last great scene is unmatched.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of the most beautiful films I have seen in my life
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    TheLittleSongbird
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I love films of all kinds, and since liking Gerard Depardieu and being familiar with Rostand's classic play, I knew it was going to be good. But I wasn't expecting it to be this brilliant, I can't think of a film recently that struck me with how beautiful and poignant it was as much as Cyrano De Bergerac did. There were three major assets that really blew me over. One was how beautifully translated and subtitled it had been, I have not seen subtitles or dialogue this lyrical or poetic in a while. Two was how Cyrano De Bergerac was made. The costume design and scenery are truly sumptuous, as is the cinematography. Gerard Depardieu's performance is truly exceptional and I don't think he has been better, though Jean De Florette comes close. Depardieu is passionate, witty and very moving. The support cast with Anne Brochet and Vincent Perez particularly notable do a fine job matching him. Cyrano De Bergerac's story is one that is timeless, and for those who haven't yet seen it, it is most likely to emotionally resonate with you like it did with me. The music is both rousing and quietly understated too. Overall, I have nothing bad to say about Cyrano De Bergerac, it is the very definition of beauty and poetry on film, complete with an exceptional lead performance. 10/10 Bethany Cox
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A sad story of why you should not let love go unspoken
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    david-sarkies
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/12/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Now this is interesting because I have a feeling that Roxanne, the American version of this film, was released first. I am not sure as to the release date of the first film for I believe it to be a 80's movie as opposed to a 90's movie. It was on recently but I think, no, I know that I threw out the television paper so I do not know. Anyway, Cyrano de Bergerac seriously romps all over Roxanne, as most French movies tend to do to their American counterparts. Cyrano de Bergerac is about the captain of the Gascony guard who has a big, no a whopping great nose, and he is very sensitive about its size. He considers himself a freak and that nobody will see past the nose to his soul. Cyrano is a poet and a great lover but he feels he can never be loved because of his physical appearance. The woman that he loves, Roxanne, is in love with another man, Christian, who is in Cyrano's battalion but Christian does not know how to be romantic so Cyrano becomes Christian's romantic side and uses his romantic words to create an intellectual depth to Christian that does not exist. Cyrano de Bergerac is a tragedy in a number of ways. There is no fulfillment in the romantic sequences. Christian is not what Roxanne wants and they can never really be together because Roxanne loves Christian's words and his looks and nothing else. She claims to love his soul, but it is a soul that says the words that she wants to hear. When Christian tries to confront her without Cyrano's help, she sees a brute that she wants nothing to do with. She does not love his soul but rather his words, the words that Cyrano speaks. The further tragic part deals with the Duke who also loves Roxanne, and wants to marry her. Instead, Roxanne marries Christian, with Cyrano's help and upon discovery, the duke sends them off to the Spanish Front where there is little hope of survival. They are married in word but it is not consummated and the duke makes sure that it is not, and never will be consummated. The greater tragedy is that of Cyrano. He holds a love for Roxanne, though it is really only attraction to her physical appearance, yet he does not speak of it to anyone. Christian learns before his death, and he is the only one that knows that Cyrano loves Roxanne. This he learns from the letters that are sent in his name. He has read the letters and soon realises that Cyrano gives Roxanne a love that he never could, but Cyrano is constantly held back by his deformity. There is constantly reference to love in spite of a deformity, but Cyrano feels that he is not for Roxanne and remains silent. He spends time with her, every Saturday, and even manages to crawl to visit her on his death bed, but it is a love that remains silent, and the only person that knows and can reveal it is dead. Roxanne was a comedy, Cyrano de Bergerac is a tragedy. There is no hope in the film and everything is spiraling down to a very bloody conclusion. Cyrano is a master swordsman, who defeats a hundred men by himself, but he cannot stave off the anger of a duke. He is able to fight the Spanish hordes, but he is taunted by a love that he feels that can never be fulfilled. He speaks only of it on his death bed, and even though is very reluctant. This is a very sad movie, nothing like the Hollywood rubbish that is splattered over all of the screens. This is a movie with depth that deals with the real emotions of people. It is not one where the couple get together and live happily in the end, but one in which pain strikes through it right until the end. It is a poetic movie, though much of it will be lost in the translation. In essence, I see Cyrano de Bergerac on the level of a modern Shakespeare for it seems to have lots of Shakespearian elements, including a very deep, poetical language -- even though it is in French. Cyrano de Bergerac is a film that has one overriding theme and that is Carpe Diem - seize the day. Though such a thing does not happen in this movie, it shows us that it is something that we should do. We cannot let our love kindle unspoken, especially when the woman that our love is focused on so dearly wants to hear. In my opinion, it is not something that should be done for I feel that we need to be tactful in regards to the woman that we speak with and shouldn't overwhelm them, but in Cyrano's case he feels that his nose makes him hideous and that Roxanne won't want anything to do with him, which is not true as you learn at the end. When it comes down to self-doubt then it should be cast away. One should be tactful, but one should not attack oneself in belief that no woman would even want him.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Perfection
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bopulie
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/11/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Merging Poetry and Cinematography in a perfect way. First time in history, and it hasn't been done or even tried again aftetwards. English translations may be good, but to appreciate it to its full potential you have to speak french fluently, and it's probably why it isn't in the top 20 of IMDb. This movie earns a 10 out of 10 not only because of its unique style (dialogue is 100% alexandrines), but also because of the spot on acting and because the director didn't deviate from the original play by Edmond Rostand (an absolute heart-breaking drama) in any way which is a huge achievement. Magnifique.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    beats Hollywood at its own game
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Michael Neumann
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/11/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Edmond Rostand's celebrated swordsman/poet is the ideal role for Gerard Depardieu, demanding a physical presence and a level of energy few other actors could muster. Taking its cues from the swashbuckling entertainments of Hollywood's golden years, the film may well stand the test of time to become the definitive version of the story: thrilling, romantic, literate, and larger than life in a way that not even subtitles can hide. But it isn't all swordplay and daring-do: director Jean-Paul Rappeneau and his co-writer Jean-Claude Carriere devote equal attention to the humor in Cyrano's character and to the tragedy of his unrequited love for the fair Roxanne, and Depardieu responds with a generous performance filled with bold flourishes and subtle gestures. It was a sure bet for the Best Foreign Film Oscar, but Academy voters apparently don't appreciate European features comparing so favorably to their American role models. An ill-timed and too candid interview with Depardieu, during which the actor revealed too much (for Stateside viewers) of his delinquent adolescence probably didn't do the film any favors either.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    simply a superb film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    zb95
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/7/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Just a wonderful film. So many memorable scenes but my favorite was Cyrano's sword and verbal battle with the dude who made a simple common insult of his nose which Cyrano then responded with dozens of funny and clever alternate versions he could have used instead. Just a spectacularly witty and superbly acted scene! It has to be one of the best of all time in my opinion. But the entire movie was superb top to bottom. Great lines, great costumes, great acting. The English translations appeared to be perfect -- I cannot imagine it being any better in French but I suspect it was. It deserved all the awards it got. A ten in my book!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Beautiful, Poetic, and Masterful
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    HulotderSpeiler
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/2/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Although much of the greatness of this film comes from the immortal story of the French play written hundreds of years ago, there is something special about this adaptation that sets it apart from others. It may be simply that it is French, and the French understand this play more than anyone else. It could be Depardieu's riveting performance that would make you forget that he is acting. It might be attributed to the magnificent sets and stunning cinematography, or the perfect mix of tragedy and comedy. All of those things are part of it, but the true greatness comes from the translation. Some say that it may kill the poetry to make the lines that rhyme in French rhyme in English, but in this film it is not so. Cyrano's eloquence grips you in such a way that you feel like applauding the screen. The poetic soul of the story is backed by the characters speaking in poetry. The opening scene is masterfully shot, establishing the greatest character in film or literature in one of the greatest scenes of all time. Above all, Depardiu gives a performance for the ages in a demanding role. You will see why he won the top prize for acting at Cannes
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    probably the best ending line for a period piece
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    dumsumdumfai
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/9/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Steve Martin did a commendable job in turning this classic into Roxanne - but it was too optimistic for a modern piece... and lacks that... certain.... "P" thingy. It is only through the period setting and our limited and romanticized knowledge of the past that this version can work. And no less with Depardieu's imposing figure and statue. The opening sequence is captivating enough with the atmosphere, the smoke and the candle lights and the crowded theater/bar what have you. Still you need great delivery of the lines and a top-notched translation for the non-French speaking (like me) And what a last line !!!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Cyrano - the representative of many a men
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Manoj Murali (manoj.back.in.action@gmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    There is a Cyrano Bergerac in majority of men. The man who can fight with hundred at a time, but doesn't have the courage to express his love. His complex, his fear is something which I myself have experienced in life. Apart from all this what makes Cyrano special is the happiness he finds in making his loved one happy. Even if that means letting her unite with the man she loves. As Cyrano himself says towards the end - " While I was down there in darkness, others climbed up and kissed the flower". This one line is valid not just in the life of Cyrano but many of us around. The film is filled with similar heart pleasing one liners. If ever you thought you are a loser who cant win hearts, turn on to this masterpiece. There is a beauty in being a loser. A beauty that is eternal..
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Cyrano De Bergerac
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    baloga09
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Cyrano De Bergerac was a very energetic and passionate movie. The actor that played Cyrano did such a great job. The enthusiasm and power that he put into the role was amazing. I love how Cyrano was so prideful. He had his own path and he did not care who he angered. I also enjoyed how the ending was not a happy ending. I feel the way they ended it was more believable than the way an American would of ended it, with the guy getting the girl and living happily ever after. The directer is Jean-Paul Rappeneau. He is a french film director, screenwriter, and actor. Rappeneau is known for creating the most elaborate film version of Cyrano De Bergerac. The film was one of the most expensive French films ever produced. A great idea is the idea about how people think very superficial about themselves. This idea is seen throughout the whole film. In the beginning Cyrano freaks out at a man in the theater and ends up in a sword and word battle with the guy because he makes fun of his nose. Also Cyrano feels no woman would want him just because of his nose. Even in the end when he is told that Roxanne loved whoever wrote the letters and did not care if the person was ugly, Cyrano still waited until his death was eminent to let her know he wrote the letters. Another good idea is that a man should stand up for what he believes in. Cyrano shows this constantly throughout the movie. First when he is in the bathhouse and Comte De Guiche comes to ask him a question. Cyrano could get one of his plays put on stage but he would have to join Comte De Guiche. Cyrano basically spits in his face and does not respect the man. The largest thing that stood out to me that made this movie French was the fact that it did not have a happy ending. If this were an American film Cyrano would of ended with Roxanne and Christian would not of died. But with having Christian die and Cyrano not tell Roxanne he loves her we get this interesting ending where no one ends up happy. It has a very dark Shakespearian feel to it. Another thing from the movie that was very French was that you were entertained by more words than fighting. In an American film there would of been more fighting and less word play, but in the French movie the people are more proud of being able to speak more diverse than be rich.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Great--with the heartwrenching story, funny rhyming script, and a terrific Depardieu lead
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    secondtake
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/7/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Cyrano de Bergerac (1990) This is Gerard Depardieu's shining moment in an up and down career. Some say the movie makes a blur of the subtle writing and emotional power of the original play by Edmond Rostand of the same title, written in 1897. And as much as the English version by Jose Ferrar (1950) is the acclaimed English language version, the play was originally French. And it's all in verse, including the subtitles, which in this case use the translation by Anthony Burgess (of Clockwork Orange fame). But the story, the story. It's all about the simple amazing plot (about which Rostand was convicted, on slim evidence, of stealing from a Chicago amateur writer). The year is something like 1680, in France. A man of great talent and fighting skill, a deep emotional life and poetic sensibility, and also with a gigantic nose, is in love with Roxane. This is poor Cyrano, who has everything but good looks. And Roxane happens to be in love with a very good looking young man who is a bit of a talentless fool. Cyrano, out of love for Roxane, steps in to help the fool by writing letters for him that succeed in wooing the beautiful Roxane. If this sounds like that crazy movie called "Roxane" starring Steve Martin, well, you've got it. That's the Cyrano story, and Martin's movie sort of kicked off the contemporary deluge of Cyrano movies in 1987 (three years before this one). Of course his is a comedy, and there are some changes from the play and this 1990 version, which tries even in its grandiose production to be true to the tightly written and scripted original. It's all pretty terrific. In a way, if you like Shakespeare, it's the play that holds the whole thing back a bit, lacking, oddly enough, complexity. An example is the funny but thin asides with the cake maker who wants to be a poet. There is no shortage of characters, there is a constant turning of events, and it does never quite ever slow down, but the main trick and drama of the situation is so central and gripping you end up waiting for it to find some kind of denouement or twist and surprise. And you do eventually get that, with great beauty and pathos (this is no comedy). But that's sort of all you get, in terms of narrative flow. And that's almost all you need, I have to admit. This production pulls out all the stops, and scene after scene is amazing in its set design and lighting, in its huge range of characters and gritty lovely evocation of 17th Century France. You could watch a bad play with such sets. And the photography is fluid, active, and formally terrific, too, which layers up the ongoing beauty of the filming. And Depardieu is terrific in his bloated, leading man way (I say this because he has detractors, those who have seen searing and cutting intensity in stage versions, but I have nothing to compare it to except Steve Martin). The two other main characters are actually a drag overall, and avoidably, I should think, with all the talent being lavishly expended. Roxane is more delighted than delightful, ornamentally pretty but also so stiff emotionally you wonder what all the fuss is about. And the foolish pretty boy is probably meant to be a bit shallow as a character, but it does leave his parts a little cardboard. Anyway, I overthink this. See the movie. If you don't like subtitles, see the American one from 1950. Don't think the Steve Martin one is enough. For one thing, the original ending is one of the most moving and memorable in all of cinema. For me, the Depardieu version of this last great scene is unmatched.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of the most beautiful films I have seen in my life
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    TheLittleSongbird
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I love films of all kinds, and since liking Gerard Depardieu and being familiar with Rostand's classic play, I knew it was going to be good. But I wasn't expecting it to be this brilliant, I can't think of a film recently that struck me with how beautiful and poignant it was as much as Cyrano De Bergerac did. There were three major assets that really blew me over. One was how beautifully translated and subtitled it had been, I have not seen subtitles or dialogue this lyrical or poetic in a while. Two was how Cyrano De Bergerac was made. The costume design and scenery are truly sumptuous, as is the cinematography. Gerard Depardieu's performance is truly exceptional and I don't think he has been better, though Jean De Florette comes close. Depardieu is passionate, witty and very moving. The support cast with Anne Brochet and Vincent Perez particularly notable do a fine job matching him. Cyrano De Bergerac's story is one that is timeless, and for those who haven't yet seen it, it is most likely to emotionally resonate with you like it did with me. The music is both rousing and quietly understated too. Overall, I have nothing bad to say about Cyrano De Bergerac, it is the very definition of beauty and poetry on film, complete with an exceptional lead performance. 10/10 Bethany Cox
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A sad story of why you should not let love go unspoken
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    david-sarkies
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/12/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Now this is interesting because I have a feeling that Roxanne, the American version of this film, was released first. I am not sure as to the release date of the first film for I believe it to be a 80's movie as opposed to a 90's movie. It was on recently but I think, no, I know that I threw out the television paper so I do not know. Anyway, Cyrano de Bergerac seriously romps all over Roxanne, as most French movies tend to do to their American counterparts. Cyrano de Bergerac is about the captain of the Gascony guard who has a big, no a whopping great nose, and he is very sensitive about its size. He considers himself a freak and that nobody will see past the nose to his soul. Cyrano is a poet and a great lover but he feels he can never be loved because of his physical appearance. The woman that he loves, Roxanne, is in love with another man, Christian, who is in Cyrano's battalion but Christian does not know how to be romantic so Cyrano becomes Christian's romantic side and uses his romantic words to create an intellectual depth to Christian that does not exist. Cyrano de Bergerac is a tragedy in a number of ways. There is no fulfillment in the romantic sequences. Christian is not what Roxanne wants and they can never really be together because Roxanne loves Christian's words and his looks and nothing else. She claims to love his soul, but it is a soul that says the words that she wants to hear. When Christian tries to confront her without Cyrano's help, she sees a brute that she wants nothing to do with. She does not love his soul but rather his words, the words that Cyrano speaks. The further tragic part deals with the Duke who also loves Roxanne, and wants to marry her. Instead, Roxanne marries Christian, with Cyrano's help and upon discovery, the duke sends them off to the Spanish Front where there is little hope of survival. They are married in word but it is not consummated and the duke makes sure that it is not, and never will be consummated. The greater tragedy is that of Cyrano. He holds a love for Roxanne, though it is really only attraction to her physical appearance, yet he does not speak of it to anyone. Christian learns before his death, and he is the only one that knows that Cyrano loves Roxanne. This he learns from the letters that are sent in his name. He has read the letters and soon realises that Cyrano gives Roxanne a love that he never could, but Cyrano is constantly held back by his deformity. There is constantly reference to love in spite of a deformity, but Cyrano feels that he is not for Roxanne and remains silent. He spends time with her, every Saturday, and even manages to crawl to visit her on his death bed, but it is a love that remains silent, and the only person that knows and can reveal it is dead. Roxanne was a comedy, Cyrano de Bergerac is a tragedy. There is no hope in the film and everything is spiraling down to a very bloody conclusion. Cyrano is a master swordsman, who defeats a hundred men by himself, but he cannot stave off the anger of a duke. He is able to fight the Spanish hordes, but he is taunted by a love that he feels that can never be fulfilled. He speaks only of it on his death bed, and even though is very reluctant. This is a very sad movie, nothing like the Hollywood rubbish that is splattered over all of the screens. This is a movie with depth that deals with the real emotions of people. It is not one where the couple get together and live happily in the end, but one in which pain strikes through it right until the end. It is a poetic movie, though much of it will be lost in the translation. In essence, I see Cyrano de Bergerac on the level of a modern Shakespeare for it seems to have lots of Shakespearian elements, including a very deep, poetical language -- even though it is in French. Cyrano de Bergerac is a film that has one overriding theme and that is Carpe Diem - seize the day. Though such a thing does not happen in this movie, it shows us that it is something that we should do. We cannot let our love kindle unspoken, especially when the woman that our love is focused on so dearly wants to hear. In my opinion, it is not something that should be done for I feel that we need to be tactful in regards to the woman that we speak with and shouldn't overwhelm them, but in Cyrano's case he feels that his nose makes him hideous and that Roxanne won't want anything to do with him, which is not true as you learn at the end. When it comes down to self-doubt then it should be cast away. One should be tactful, but one should not attack oneself in belief that no woman would even want him.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Perfection
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bopulie
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/11/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Merging Poetry and Cinematography in a perfect way. First time in history, and it hasn't been done or even tried again aftetwards. English translations may be good, but to appreciate it to its full potential you have to speak french fluently, and it's probably why it isn't in the top 20 of IMDb. This movie earns a 10 out of 10 not only because of its unique style (dialogue is 100% alexandrines), but also because of the spot on acting and because the director didn't deviate from the original play by Edmond Rostand (an absolute heart-breaking drama) in any way which is a huge achievement. Magnifique.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    beats Hollywood at its own game
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Michael Neumann
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/11/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Edmond Rostand's celebrated swordsman/poet is the ideal role for Gerard Depardieu, demanding a physical presence and a level of energy few other actors could muster. Taking its cues from the swashbuckling entertainments of Hollywood's golden years, the film may well stand the test of time to become the definitive version of the story: thrilling, romantic, literate, and larger than life in a way that not even subtitles can hide. But it isn't all swordplay and daring-do: director Jean-Paul Rappeneau and his co-writer Jean-Claude Carriere devote equal attention to the humor in Cyrano's character and to the tragedy of his unrequited love for the fair Roxanne, and Depardieu responds with a generous performance filled with bold flourishes and subtle gestures. It was a sure bet for the Best Foreign Film Oscar, but Academy voters apparently don't appreciate European features comparing so favorably to their American role models. An ill-timed and too candid interview with Depardieu, during which the actor revealed too much (for Stateside viewers) of his delinquent adolescence probably didn't do the film any favors either.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    simply a superb film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    zb95
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/7/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Just a wonderful film. So many memorable scenes but my favorite was Cyrano's sword and verbal battle with the dude who made a simple common insult of his nose which Cyrano then responded with dozens of funny and clever alternate versions he could have used instead. Just a spectacularly witty and superbly acted scene! It has to be one of the best of all time in my opinion. But the entire movie was superb top to bottom. Great lines, great costumes, great acting. The English translations appeared to be perfect -- I cannot imagine it being any better in French but I suspect it was. It deserved all the awards it got. A ten in my book!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Beautiful, Poetic, and Masterful
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    HulotderSpeiler
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/2/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Although much of the greatness of this film comes from the immortal story of the French play written hundreds of years ago, there is something special about this adaptation that sets it apart from others. It may be simply that it is French, and the French understand this play more than anyone else. It could be Depardieu's riveting performance that would make you forget that he is acting. It might be attributed to the magnificent sets and stunning cinematography, or the perfect mix of tragedy and comedy. All of those things are part of it, but the true greatness comes from the translation. Some say that it may kill the poetry to make the lines that rhyme in French rhyme in English, but in this film it is not so. Cyrano's eloquence grips you in such a way that you feel like applauding the screen. The poetic soul of the story is backed by the characters speaking in poetry. The opening scene is masterfully shot, establishing the greatest character in film or literature in one of the greatest scenes of all time. Above all, Depardiu gives a performance for the ages in a demanding role. You will see why he won the top prize for acting at Cannes
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    probably the best ending line for a period piece
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    dumsumdumfai
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/9/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Steve Martin did a commendable job in turning this classic into Roxanne - but it was too optimistic for a modern piece... and lacks that... certain.... "P" thingy. It is only through the period setting and our limited and romanticized knowledge of the past that this version can work. And no less with Depardieu's imposing figure and statue. The opening sequence is captivating enough with the atmosphere, the smoke and the candle lights and the crowded theater/bar what have you. Still you need great delivery of the lines and a top-notched translation for the non-French speaking (like me) And what a last line !!!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Cyrano - the representative of many a men
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Manoj Murali (manoj.back.in.action@gmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    There is a Cyrano Bergerac in majority of men. The man who can fight with hundred at a time, but doesn't have the courage to express his love. His complex, his fear is something which I myself have experienced in life. Apart from all this what makes Cyrano special is the happiness he finds in making his loved one happy. Even if that means letting her unite with the man she loves. As Cyrano himself says towards the end - " While I was down there in darkness, others climbed up and kissed the flower". This one line is valid not just in the life of Cyrano but many of us around. The film is filled with similar heart pleasing one liners. If ever you thought you are a loser who cant win hearts, turn on to this masterpiece. There is a beauty in being a loser. A beauty that is eternal..
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Cyrano De Bergerac
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    baloga09
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Cyrano De Bergerac was a very energetic and passionate movie. The actor that played Cyrano did such a great job. The enthusiasm and power that he put into the role was amazing. I love how Cyrano was so prideful. He had his own path and he did not care who he angered. I also enjoyed how the ending was not a happy ending. I feel the way they ended it was more believable than the way an American would of ended it, with the guy getting the girl and living happily ever after. The directer is Jean-Paul Rappeneau. He is a french film director, screenwriter, and actor. Rappeneau is known for creating the most elaborate film version of Cyrano De Bergerac. The film was one of the most expensive French films ever produced. A great idea is the idea about how people think very superficial about themselves. This idea is seen throughout the whole film. In the beginning Cyrano freaks out at a man in the theater and ends up in a sword and word battle with the guy because he makes fun of his nose. Also Cyrano feels no woman would want him just because of his nose. Even in the end when he is told that Roxanne loved whoever wrote the letters and did not care if the person was ugly, Cyrano still waited until his death was eminent to let her know he wrote the letters. Another good idea is that a man should stand up for what he believes in. Cyrano shows this constantly throughout the movie. First when he is in the bathhouse and Comte De Guiche comes to ask him a question. Cyrano could get one of his plays put on stage but he would have to join Comte De Guiche. Cyrano basically spits in his face and does not respect the man. The largest thing that stood out to me that made this movie French was the fact that it did not have a happy ending. If this were an American film Cyrano would of ended with Roxanne and Christian would not of died. But with having Christian die and Cyrano not tell Roxanne he loves her we get this interesting ending where no one ends up happy. It has a very dark Shakespearian feel to it. Another thing from the movie that was very French was that you were entertained by more words than fighting. In an American film there would of been more fighting and less word play, but in the French movie the people are more proud of being able to speak more diverse than be rich.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Great--with the heartwrenching story, funny rhyming script, and a terrific Depardieu lead
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    secondtake
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/7/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Cyrano de Bergerac (1990) This is Gerard Depardieu's shining moment in an up and down career. Some say the movie makes a blur of the subtle writing and emotional power of the original play by Edmond Rostand of the same title, written in 1897. And as much as the English version by Jose Ferrar (1950) is the acclaimed English language version, the play was originally French. And it's all in verse, including the subtitles, which in this case use the translation by Anthony Burgess (of Clockwork Orange fame). But the story, the story. It's all about the simple amazing plot (about which Rostand was convicted, on slim evidence, of stealing from a Chicago amateur writer). The year is something like 1680, in France. A man of great talent and fighting skill, a deep emotional life and poetic sensibility, and also with a gigantic nose, is in love with Roxane. This is poor Cyrano, who has everything but good looks. And Roxane happens to be in love with a very good looking young man who is a bit of a talentless fool. Cyrano, out of love for Roxane, steps in to help the fool by writing letters for him that succeed in wooing the beautiful Roxane. If this sounds like that crazy movie called "Roxane" starring Steve Martin, well, you've got it. That's the Cyrano story, and Martin's movie sort of kicked off the contemporary deluge of Cyrano movies in 1987 (three years before this one). Of course his is a comedy, and there are some changes from the play and this 1990 version, which tries even in its grandiose production to be true to the tightly written and scripted original. It's all pretty terrific. In a way, if you like Shakespeare, it's the play that holds the whole thing back a bit, lacking, oddly enough, complexity. An example is the funny but thin asides with the cake maker who wants to be a poet. There is no shortage of characters, there is a constant turning of events, and it does never quite ever slow down, but the main trick and drama of the situation is so central and gripping you end up waiting for it to find some kind of denouement or twist and surprise. And you do eventually get that, with great beauty and pathos (this is no comedy). But that's sort of all you get, in terms of narrative flow. And that's almost all you need, I have to admit. This production pulls out all the stops, and scene after scene is amazing in its set design and lighting, in its huge range of characters and gritty lovely evocation of 17th Century France. You could watch a bad play with such sets. And the photography is fluid, active, and formally terrific, too, which layers up the ongoing beauty of the filming. And Depardieu is terrific in his bloated, leading man way (I say this because he has detractors, those who have seen searing and cutting intensity in stage versions, but I have nothing to compare it to except Steve Martin). The two other main characters are actually a drag overall, and avoidably, I should think, with all the talent being lavishly expended. Roxane is more delighted than delightful, ornamentally pretty but also so stiff emotionally you wonder what all the fuss is about. And the foolish pretty boy is probably meant to be a bit shallow as a character, but it does leave his parts a little cardboard. Anyway, I overthink this. See the movie. If you don't like subtitles, see the American one from 1950. Don't think the Steve Martin one is enough. For one thing, the original ending is one of the most moving and memorable in all of cinema. For me, the Depardieu version of this last great scene is unmatched.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of the most beautiful films I have seen in my life
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    TheLittleSongbird
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I love films of all kinds, and since liking Gerard Depardieu and being familiar with Rostand's classic play, I knew it was going to be good. But I wasn't expecting it to be this brilliant, I can't think of a film recently that struck me with how beautiful and poignant it was as much as Cyrano De Bergerac did. There were three major assets that really blew me over. One was how beautifully translated and subtitled it had been, I have not seen subtitles or dialogue this lyrical or poetic in a while. Two was how Cyrano De Bergerac was made. The costume design and scenery are truly sumptuous, as is the cinematography. Gerard Depardieu's performance is truly exceptional and I don't think he has been better, though Jean De Florette comes close. Depardieu is passionate, witty and very moving. The support cast with Anne Brochet and Vincent Perez particularly notable do a fine job matching him. Cyrano De Bergerac's story is one that is timeless, and for those who haven't yet seen it, it is most likely to emotionally resonate with you like it did with me. The music is both rousing and quietly understated too. Overall, I have nothing bad to say about Cyrano De Bergerac, it is the very definition of beauty and poetry on film, complete with an exceptional lead performance. 10/10 Bethany Cox
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A sad story of why you should not let love go unspoken
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    david-sarkies
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/12/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Now this is interesting because I have a feeling that Roxanne, the American version of this film, was released first. I am not sure as to the release date of the first film for I believe it to be a 80's movie as opposed to a 90's movie. It was on recently but I think, no, I know that I threw out the television paper so I do not know. Anyway, Cyrano de Bergerac seriously romps all over Roxanne, as most French movies tend to do to their American counterparts. Cyrano de Bergerac is about the captain of the Gascony guard who has a big, no a whopping great nose, and he is very sensitive about its size. He considers himself a freak and that nobody will see past the nose to his soul. Cyrano is a poet and a great lover but he feels he can never be loved because of his physical appearance. The woman that he loves, Roxanne, is in love with another man, Christian, who is in Cyrano's battalion but Christian does not know how to be romantic so Cyrano becomes Christian's romantic side and uses his romantic words to create an intellectual depth to Christian that does not exist. Cyrano de Bergerac is a tragedy in a number of ways. There is no fulfillment in the romantic sequences. Christian is not what Roxanne wants and they can never really be together because Roxanne loves Christian's words and his looks and nothing else. She claims to love his soul, but it is a soul that says the words that she wants to hear. When Christian tries to confront her without Cyrano's help, she sees a brute that she wants nothing to do with. She does not love his soul but rather his words, the words that Cyrano speaks. The further tragic part deals with the Duke who also loves Roxanne, and wants to marry her. Instead, Roxanne marries Christian, with Cyrano's help and upon discovery, the duke sends them off to the Spanish Front where there is little hope of survival. They are married in word but it is not consummated and the duke makes sure that it is not, and never will be consummated. The greater tragedy is that of Cyrano. He holds a love for Roxanne, though it is really only attraction to her physical appearance, yet he does not speak of it to anyone. Christian learns before his death, and he is the only one that knows that Cyrano loves Roxanne. This he learns from the letters that are sent in his name. He has read the letters and soon realises that Cyrano gives Roxanne a love that he never could, but Cyrano is constantly held back by his deformity. There is constantly reference to love in spite of a deformity, but Cyrano feels that he is not for Roxanne and remains silent. He spends time with her, every Saturday, and even manages to crawl to visit her on his death bed, but it is a love that remains silent, and the only person that knows and can reveal it is dead. Roxanne was a comedy, Cyrano de Bergerac is a tragedy. There is no hope in the film and everything is spiraling down to a very bloody conclusion. Cyrano is a master swordsman, who defeats a hundred men by himself, but he cannot stave off the anger of a duke. He is able to fight the Spanish hordes, but he is taunted by a love that he feels that can never be fulfilled. He speaks only of it on his death bed, and even though is very reluctant. This is a very sad movie, nothing like the Hollywood rubbish that is splattered over all of the screens. This is a movie with depth that deals with the real emotions of people. It is not one where the couple get together and live happily in the end, but one in which pain strikes through it right until the end. It is a poetic movie, though much of it will be lost in the translation. In essence, I see Cyrano de Bergerac on the level of a modern Shakespeare for it seems to have lots of Shakespearian elements, including a very deep, poetical language -- even though it is in French. Cyrano de Bergerac is a film that has one overriding theme and that is Carpe Diem - seize the day. Though such a thing does not happen in this movie, it shows us that it is something that we should do. We cannot let our love kindle unspoken, especially when the woman that our love is focused on so dearly wants to hear. In my opinion, it is not something that should be done for I feel that we need to be tactful in regards to the woman that we speak with and shouldn't overwhelm them, but in Cyrano's case he feels that his nose makes him hideous and that Roxanne won't want anything to do with him, which is not true as you learn at the end. When it comes down to self-doubt then it should be cast away. One should be tactful, but one should not attack oneself in belief that no woman would even want him.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Perfection
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bopulie
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/11/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Merging Poetry and Cinematography in a perfect way. First time in history, and it hasn't been done or even tried again aftetwards. English translations may be good, but to appreciate it to its full potential you have to speak french fluently, and it's probably why it isn't in the top 20 of IMDb. This movie earns a 10 out of 10 not only because of its unique style (dialogue is 100% alexandrines), but also because of the spot on acting and because the director didn't deviate from the original play by Edmond Rostand (an absolute heart-breaking drama) in any way which is a huge achievement. Magnifique.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    beats Hollywood at its own game
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Michael Neumann
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/11/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Edmond Rostand's celebrated swordsman/poet is the ideal role for Gerard Depardieu, demanding a physical presence and a level of energy few other actors could muster. Taking its cues from the swashbuckling entertainments of Hollywood's golden years, the film may well stand the test of time to become the definitive version of the story: thrilling, romantic, literate, and larger than life in a way that not even subtitles can hide. But it isn't all swordplay and daring-do: director Jean-Paul Rappeneau and his co-writer Jean-Claude Carriere devote equal attention to the humor in Cyrano's character and to the tragedy of his unrequited love for the fair Roxanne, and Depardieu responds with a generous performance filled with bold flourishes and subtle gestures. It was a sure bet for the Best Foreign Film Oscar, but Academy voters apparently don't appreciate European features comparing so favorably to their American role models. An ill-timed and too candid interview with Depardieu, during which the actor revealed too much (for Stateside viewers) of his delinquent adolescence probably didn't do the film any favors either.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    simply a superb film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    zb95
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/7/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Just a wonderful film. So many memorable scenes but my favorite was Cyrano's sword and verbal battle with the dude who made a simple common insult of his nose which Cyrano then responded with dozens of funny and clever alternate versions he could have used instead. Just a spectacularly witty and superbly acted scene! It has to be one of the best of all time in my opinion. But the entire movie was superb top to bottom. Great lines, great costumes, great acting. The English translations appeared to be perfect -- I cannot imagine it being any better in French but I suspect it was. It deserved all the awards it got. A ten in my book!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Beautiful, Poetic, and Masterful
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    HulotderSpeiler
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/2/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Although much of the greatness of this film comes from the immortal story of the French play written hundreds of years ago, there is something special about this adaptation that sets it apart from others. It may be simply that it is French, and the French understand this play more than anyone else. It could be Depardieu's riveting performance that would make you forget that he is acting. It might be attributed to the magnificent sets and stunning cinematography, or the perfect mix of tragedy and comedy. All of those things are part of it, but the true greatness comes from the translation. Some say that it may kill the poetry to make the lines that rhyme in French rhyme in English, but in this film it is not so. Cyrano's eloquence grips you in such a way that you feel like applauding the screen. The poetic soul of the story is backed by the characters speaking in poetry. The opening scene is masterfully shot, establishing the greatest character in film or literature in one of the greatest scenes of all time. Above all, Depardiu gives a performance for the ages in a demanding role. You will see why he won the top prize for acting at Cannes
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    probably the best ending line for a period piece
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    dumsumdumfai
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/9/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Steve Martin did a commendable job in turning this classic into Roxanne - but it was too optimistic for a modern piece... and lacks that... certain.... "P" thingy. It is only through the period setting and our limited and romanticized knowledge of the past that this version can work. And no less with Depardieu's imposing figure and statue. The opening sequence is captivating enough with the atmosphere, the smoke and the candle lights and the crowded theater/bar what have you. Still you need great delivery of the lines and a top-notched translation for the non-French speaking (like me) And what a last line !!!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Cyrano - the representative of many a men
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Manoj Murali (manoj.back.in.action@gmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    There is a Cyrano Bergerac in majority of men. The man who can fight with hundred at a time, but doesn't have the courage to express his love. His complex, his fear is something which I myself have experienced in life. Apart from all this what makes Cyrano special is the happiness he finds in making his loved one happy. Even if that means letting her unite with the man she loves. As Cyrano himself says towards the end - " While I was down there in darkness, others climbed up and kissed the flower". This one line is valid not just in the life of Cyrano but many of us around. The film is filled with similar heart pleasing one liners. If ever you thought you are a loser who cant win hearts, turn on to this masterpiece. There is a beauty in being a loser. A beauty that is eternal..
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Cyrano De Bergerac
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    baloga09
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Cyrano De Bergerac was a very energetic and passionate movie. The actor that played Cyrano did such a great job. The enthusiasm and power that he put into the role was amazing. I love how Cyrano was so prideful. He had his own path and he did not care who he angered. I also enjoyed how the ending was not a happy ending. I feel the way they ended it was more believable than the way an American would of ended it, with the guy getting the girl and living happily ever after. The directer is Jean-Paul Rappeneau. He is a french film director, screenwriter, and actor. Rappeneau is known for creating the most elaborate film version of Cyrano De Bergerac. The film was one of the most expensive French films ever produced. A great idea is the idea about how people think very superficial about themselves. This idea is seen throughout the whole film. In the beginning Cyrano freaks out at a man in the theater and ends up in a sword and word battle with the guy because he makes fun of his nose. Also Cyrano feels no woman would want him just because of his nose. Even in the end when he is told that Roxanne loved whoever wrote the letters and did not care if the person was ugly, Cyrano still waited until his death was eminent to let her know he wrote the letters. Another good idea is that a man should stand up for what he believes in. Cyrano shows this constantly throughout the movie. First when he is in the bathhouse and Comte De Guiche comes to ask him a question. Cyrano could get one of his plays put on stage but he would have to join Comte De Guiche. Cyrano basically spits in his face and does not respect the man. The largest thing that stood out to me that made this movie French was the fact that it did not have a happy ending. If this were an American film Cyrano would of ended with Roxanne and Christian would not of died. But with having Christian die and Cyrano not tell Roxanne he loves her we get this interesting ending where no one ends up happy. It has a very dark Shakespearian feel to it. Another thing from the movie that was very French was that you were entertained by more words than fighting. In an American film there would of been more fighting and less word play, but in the French movie the people are more proud of being able to speak more diverse than be rich.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Great--with the heartwrenching story, funny rhyming script, and a terrific Depardieu lead
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    secondtake
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/7/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Cyrano de Bergerac (1990) This is Gerard Depardieu's shining moment in an up and down career. Some say the movie makes a blur of the subtle writing and emotional power of the original play by Edmond Rostand of the same title, written in 1897. And as much as the English version by Jose Ferrar (1950) is the acclaimed English language version, the play was originally French. And it's all in verse, including the subtitles, which in this case use the translation by Anthony Burgess (of Clockwork Orange fame). But the story, the story. It's all about the simple amazing plot (about which Rostand was convicted, on slim evidence, of stealing from a Chicago amateur writer). The year is something like 1680, in France. A man of great talent and fighting skill, a deep emotional life and poetic sensibility, and also with a gigantic nose, is in love with Roxane. This is poor Cyrano, who has everything but good looks. And Roxane happens to be in love with a very good looking young man who is a bit of a talentless fool. Cyrano, out of love for Roxane, steps in to help the fool by writing letters for him that succeed in wooing the beautiful Roxane. If this sounds like that crazy movie called "Roxane" starring Steve Martin, well, you've got it. That's the Cyrano story, and Martin's movie sort of kicked off the contemporary deluge of Cyrano movies in 1987 (three years before this one). Of course his is a comedy, and there are some changes from the play and this 1990 version, which tries even in its grandiose production to be true to the tightly written and scripted original. It's all pretty terrific. In a way, if you like Shakespeare, it's the play that holds the whole thing back a bit, lacking, oddly enough, complexity. An example is the funny but thin asides with the cake maker who wants to be a poet. There is no shortage of characters, there is a constant turning of events, and it does never quite ever slow down, but the main trick and drama of the situation is so central and gripping you end up waiting for it to find some kind of denouement or twist and surprise. And you do eventually get that, with great beauty and pathos (this is no comedy). But that's sort of all you get, in terms of narrative flow. And that's almost all you need, I have to admit. This production pulls out all the stops, and scene after scene is amazing in its set design and lighting, in its huge range of characters and gritty lovely evocation of 17th Century France. You could watch a bad play with such sets. And the photography is fluid, active, and formally terrific, too, which layers up the ongoing beauty of the filming. And Depardieu is terrific in his bloated, leading man way (I say this because he has detractors, those who have seen searing and cutting intensity in stage versions, but I have nothing to compare it to except Steve Martin). The two other main characters are actually a drag overall, and avoidably, I should think, with all the talent being lavishly expended. Roxane is more delighted than delightful, ornamentally pretty but also so stiff emotionally you wonder what all the fuss is about. And the foolish pretty boy is probably meant to be a bit shallow as a character, but it does leave his parts a little cardboard. Anyway, I overthink this. See the movie. If you don't like subtitles, see the American one from 1950. Don't think the Steve Martin one is enough. For one thing, the original ending is one of the most moving and memorable in all of cinema. For me, the Depardieu version of this last great scene is unmatched.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of the most beautiful films I have seen in my life
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    TheLittleSongbird
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I love films of all kinds, and since liking Gerard Depardieu and being familiar with Rostand's classic play, I knew it was going to be good. But I wasn't expecting it to be this brilliant, I can't think of a film recently that struck me with how beautiful and poignant it was as much as Cyrano De Bergerac did. There were three major assets that really blew me over. One was how beautifully translated and subtitled it had been, I have not seen subtitles or dialogue this lyrical or poetic in a while. Two was how Cyrano De Bergerac was made. The costume design and scenery are truly sumptuous, as is the cinematography. Gerard Depardieu's performance is truly exceptional and I don't think he has been better, though Jean De Florette comes close. Depardieu is passionate, witty and very moving. The support cast with Anne Brochet and Vincent Perez particularly notable do a fine job matching him. Cyrano De Bergerac's story is one that is timeless, and for those who haven't yet seen it, it is most likely to emotionally resonate with you like it did with me. The music is both rousing and quietly understated too. Overall, I have nothing bad to say about Cyrano De Bergerac, it is the very definition of beauty and poetry on film, complete with an exceptional lead performance. 10/10 Bethany Cox
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A sad story of why you should not let love go unspoken
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    david-sarkies
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/12/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Now this is interesting because I have a feeling that Roxanne, the American version of this film, was released first. I am not sure as to the release date of the first film for I believe it to be a 80's movie as opposed to a 90's movie. It was on recently but I think, no, I know that I threw out the television paper so I do not know. Anyway, Cyrano de Bergerac seriously romps all over Roxanne, as most French movies tend to do to their American counterparts. Cyrano de Bergerac is about the captain of the Gascony guard who has a big, no a whopping great nose, and he is very sensitive about its size. He considers himself a freak and that nobody will see past the nose to his soul. Cyrano is a poet and a great lover but he feels he can never be loved because of his physical appearance. The woman that he loves, Roxanne, is in love with another man, Christian, who is in Cyrano's battalion but Christian does not know how to be romantic so Cyrano becomes Christian's romantic side and uses his romantic words to create an intellectual depth to Christian that does not exist. Cyrano de Bergerac is a tragedy in a number of ways. There is no fulfillment in the romantic sequences. Christian is not what Roxanne wants and they can never really be together because Roxanne loves Christian's words and his looks and nothing else. She claims to love his soul, but it is a soul that says the words that she wants to hear. When Christian tries to confront her without Cyrano's help, she sees a brute that she wants nothing to do with. She does not love his soul but rather his words, the words that Cyrano speaks. The further tragic part deals with the Duke who also loves Roxanne, and wants to marry her. Instead, Roxanne marries Christian, with Cyrano's help and upon discovery, the duke sends them off to the Spanish Front where there is little hope of survival. They are married in word but it is not consummated and the duke makes sure that it is not, and never will be consummated. The greater tragedy is that of Cyrano. He holds a love for Roxanne, though it is really only attraction to her physical appearance, yet he does not speak of it to anyone. Christian learns before his death, and he is the only one that knows that Cyrano loves Roxanne. This he learns from the letters that are sent in his name. He has read the letters and soon realises that Cyrano gives Roxanne a love that he never could, but Cyrano is constantly held back by his deformity. There is constantly reference to love in spite of a deformity, but Cyrano feels that he is not for Roxanne and remains silent. He spends time with her, every Saturday, and even manages to crawl to visit her on his death bed, but it is a love that remains silent, and the only person that knows and can reveal it is dead. Roxanne was a comedy, Cyrano de Bergerac is a tragedy. There is no hope in the film and everything is spiraling down to a very bloody conclusion. Cyrano is a master swordsman, who defeats a hundred men by himself, but he cannot stave off the anger of a duke. He is able to fight the Spanish hordes, but he is taunted by a love that he feels that can never be fulfilled. He speaks only of it on his death bed, and even though is very reluctant. This is a very sad movie, nothing like the Hollywood rubbish that is splattered over all of the screens. This is a movie with depth that deals with the real emotions of people. It is not one where the couple get together and live happily in the end, but one in which pain strikes through it right until the end. It is a poetic movie, though much of it will be lost in the translation. In essence, I see Cyrano de Bergerac on the level of a modern Shakespeare for it seems to have lots of Shakespearian elements, including a very deep, poetical language -- even though it is in French. Cyrano de Bergerac is a film that has one overriding theme and that is Carpe Diem - seize the day. Though such a thing does not happen in this movie, it shows us that it is something that we should do. We cannot let our love kindle unspoken, especially when the woman that our love is focused on so dearly wants to hear. In my opinion, it is not something that should be done for I feel that we need to be tactful in regards to the woman that we speak with and shouldn't overwhelm them, but in Cyrano's case he feels that his nose makes him hideous and that Roxanne won't want anything to do with him, which is not true as you learn at the end. When it comes down to self-doubt then it should be cast away. One should be tactful, but one should not attack oneself in belief that no woman would even want him.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Perfection
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bopulie
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/11/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Merging Poetry and Cinematography in a perfect way. First time in history, and it hasn't been done or even tried again aftetwards. English translations may be good, but to appreciate it to its full potential you have to speak french fluently, and it's probably why it isn't in the top 20 of IMDb. This movie earns a 10 out of 10 not only because of its unique style (dialogue is 100% alexandrines), but also because of the spot on acting and because the director didn't deviate from the original play by Edmond Rostand (an absolute heart-breaking drama) in any way which is a huge achievement. Magnifique.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    beats Hollywood at its own game
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Michael Neumann
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/11/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Edmond Rostand's celebrated swordsman/poet is the ideal role for Gerard Depardieu, demanding a physical presence and a level of energy few other actors could muster. Taking its cues from the swashbuckling entertainments of Hollywood's golden years, the film may well stand the test of time to become the definitive version of the story: thrilling, romantic, literate, and larger than life in a way that not even subtitles can hide. But it isn't all swordplay and daring-do: director Jean-Paul Rappeneau and his co-writer Jean-Claude Carriere devote equal attention to the humor in Cyrano's character and to the tragedy of his unrequited love for the fair Roxanne, and Depardieu responds with a generous performance filled with bold flourishes and subtle gestures. It was a sure bet for the Best Foreign Film Oscar, but Academy voters apparently don't appreciate European features comparing so favorably to their American role models. An ill-timed and too candid interview with Depardieu, during which the actor revealed too much (for Stateside viewers) of his delinquent adolescence probably didn't do the film any favors either.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    simply a superb film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    zb95
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/7/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Just a wonderful film. So many memorable scenes but my favorite was Cyrano's sword and verbal battle with the dude who made a simple common insult of his nose which Cyrano then responded with dozens of funny and clever alternate versions he could have used instead. Just a spectacularly witty and superbly acted scene! It has to be one of the best of all time in my opinion. But the entire movie was superb top to bottom. Great lines, great costumes, great acting. The English translations appeared to be perfect -- I cannot imagine it being any better in French but I suspect it was. It deserved all the awards it got. A ten in my book!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Beautiful, Poetic, and Masterful
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    HulotderSpeiler
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/2/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Although much of the greatness of this film comes from the immortal story of the French play written hundreds of years ago, there is something special about this adaptation that sets it apart from others. It may be simply that it is French, and the French understand this play more than anyone else. It could be Depardieu's riveting performance that would make you forget that he is acting. It might be attributed to the magnificent sets and stunning cinematography, or the perfect mix of tragedy and comedy. All of those things are part of it, but the true greatness comes from the translation. Some say that it may kill the poetry to make the lines that rhyme in French rhyme in English, but in this film it is not so. Cyrano's eloquence grips you in such a way that you feel like applauding the screen. The poetic soul of the story is backed by the characters speaking in poetry. The opening scene is masterfully shot, establishing the greatest character in film or literature in one of the greatest scenes of all time. Above all, Depardiu gives a performance for the ages in a demanding role. You will see why he won the top prize for acting at Cannes
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    probably the best ending line for a period piece
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    dumsumdumfai
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/9/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Steve Martin did a commendable job in turning this classic into Roxanne - but it was too optimistic for a modern piece... and lacks that... certain.... "P" thingy. It is only through the period setting and our limited and romanticized knowledge of the past that this version can work. And no less with Depardieu's imposing figure and statue. The opening sequence is captivating enough with the atmosphere, the smoke and the candle lights and the crowded theater/bar what have you. Still you need great delivery of the lines and a top-notched translation for the non-French speaking (like me) And what a last line !!!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Cyrano - the representative of many a men
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Manoj Murali (manoj.back.in.action@gmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    There is a Cyrano Bergerac in majority of men. The man who can fight with hundred at a time, but doesn't have the courage to express his love. His complex, his fear is something which I myself have experienced in life. Apart from all this what makes Cyrano special is the happiness he finds in making his loved one happy. Even if that means letting her unite with the man she loves. As Cyrano himself says towards the end - " While I was down there in darkness, others climbed up and kissed the flower". This one line is valid not just in the life of Cyrano but many of us around. The film is filled with similar heart pleasing one liners. If ever you thought you are a loser who cant win hearts, turn on to this masterpiece. There is a beauty in being a loser. A beauty that is eternal..
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Cyrano De Bergerac
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    baloga09
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Cyrano De Bergerac was a very energetic and passionate movie. The actor that played Cyrano did such a great job. The enthusiasm and power that he put into the role was amazing. I love how Cyrano was so prideful. He had his own path and he did not care who he angered. I also enjoyed how the ending was not a happy ending. I feel the way they ended it was more believable than the way an American would of ended it, with the guy getting the girl and living happily ever after. The directer is Jean-Paul Rappeneau. He is a french film director, screenwriter, and actor. Rappeneau is known for creating the most elaborate film version of Cyrano De Bergerac. The film was one of the most expensive French films ever produced. A great idea is the idea about how people think very superficial about themselves. This idea is seen throughout the whole film. In the beginning Cyrano freaks out at a man in the theater and ends up in a sword and word battle with the guy because he makes fun of his nose. Also Cyrano feels no woman would want him just because of his nose. Even in the end when he is told that Roxanne loved whoever wrote the letters and did not care if the person was ugly, Cyrano still waited until his death was eminent to let her know he wrote the letters. Another good idea is that a man should stand up for what he believes in. Cyrano shows this constantly throughout the movie. First when he is in the bathhouse and Comte De Guiche comes to ask him a question. Cyrano could get one of his plays put on stage but he would have to join Comte De Guiche. Cyrano basically spits in his face and does not respect the man. The largest thing that stood out to me that made this movie French was the fact that it did not have a happy ending. If this were an American film Cyrano would of ended with Roxanne and Christian would not of died. But with having Christian die and Cyrano not tell Roxanne he loves her we get this interesting ending where no one ends up happy. It has a very dark Shakespearian feel to it. Another thing from the movie that was very French was that you were entertained by more words than fighting. In an American film there would of been more fighting and less word play, but in the French movie the people are more proud of being able to speak more diverse than be rich.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Great--with the heartwrenching story, funny rhyming script, and a terrific Depardieu lead
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    secondtake
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/7/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Cyrano de Bergerac (1990) This is Gerard Depardieu's shining moment in an up and down career. Some say the movie makes a blur of the subtle writing and emotional power of the original play by Edmond Rostand of the same title, written in 1897. And as much as the English version by Jose Ferrar (1950) is the acclaimed English language version, the play was originally French. And it's all in verse, including the subtitles, which in this case use the translation by Anthony Burgess (of Clockwork Orange fame). But the story, the story. It's all about the simple amazing plot (about which Rostand was convicted, on slim evidence, of stealing from a Chicago amateur writer). The year is something like 1680, in France. A man of great talent and fighting skill, a deep emotional life and poetic sensibility, and also with a gigantic nose, is in love with Roxane. This is poor Cyrano, who has everything but good looks. And Roxane happens to be in love with a very good looking young man who is a bit of a talentless fool. Cyrano, out of love for Roxane, steps in to help the fool by writing letters for him that succeed in wooing the beautiful Roxane. If this sounds like that crazy movie called "Roxane" starring Steve Martin, well, you've got it. That's the Cyrano story, and Martin's movie sort of kicked off the contemporary deluge of Cyrano movies in 1987 (three years before this one). Of course his is a comedy, and there are some changes from the play and this 1990 version, which tries even in its grandiose production to be true to the tightly written and scripted original. It's all pretty terrific. In a way, if you like Shakespeare, it's the play that holds the whole thing back a bit, lacking, oddly enough, complexity. An example is the funny but thin asides with the cake maker who wants to be a poet. There is no shortage of characters, there is a constant turning of events, and it does never quite ever slow down, but the main trick and drama of the situation is so central and gripping you end up waiting for it to find some kind of denouement or twist and surprise. And you do eventually get that, with great beauty and pathos (this is no comedy). But that's sort of all you get, in terms of narrative flow. And that's almost all you need, I have to admit. This production pulls out all the stops, and scene after scene is amazing in its set design and lighting, in its huge range of characters and gritty lovely evocation of 17th Century France. You could watch a bad play with such sets. And the photography is fluid, active, and formally terrific, too, which layers up the ongoing beauty of the filming. And Depardieu is terrific in his bloated, leading man way (I say this because he has detractors, those who have seen searing and cutting intensity in stage versions, but I have nothing to compare it to except Steve Martin). The two other main characters are actually a drag overall, and avoidably, I should think, with all the talent being lavishly expended. Roxane is more delighted than delightful, ornamentally pretty but also so stiff emotionally you wonder what all the fuss is about. And the foolish pretty boy is probably meant to be a bit shallow as a character, but it does leave his parts a little cardboard. Anyway, I overthink this. See the movie. If you don't like subtitles, see the American one from 1950. Don't think the Steve Martin one is enough. For one thing, the original ending is one of the most moving and memorable in all of cinema. For me, the Depardieu version of this last great scene is unmatched.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of the most beautiful films I have seen in my life
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    TheLittleSongbird
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I love films of all kinds, and since liking Gerard Depardieu and being familiar with Rostand's classic play, I knew it was going to be good. But I wasn't expecting it to be this brilliant, I can't think of a film recently that struck me with how beautiful and poignant it was as much as Cyrano De Bergerac did. There were three major assets that really blew me over. One was how beautifully translated and subtitled it had been, I have not seen subtitles or dialogue this lyrical or poetic in a while. Two was how Cyrano De Bergerac was made. The costume design and scenery are truly sumptuous, as is the cinematography. Gerard Depardieu's performance is truly exceptional and I don't think he has been better, though Jean De Florette comes close. Depardieu is passionate, witty and very moving. The support cast with Anne Brochet and Vincent Perez particularly notable do a fine job matching him. Cyrano De Bergerac's story is one that is timeless, and for those who haven't yet seen it, it is most likely to emotionally resonate with you like it did with me. The music is both rousing and quietly understated too. Overall, I have nothing bad to say about Cyrano De Bergerac, it is the very definition of beauty and poetry on film, complete with an exceptional lead performance. 10/10 Bethany Cox
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A sad story of why you should not let love go unspoken
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    david-sarkies
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/12/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Now this is interesting because I have a feeling that Roxanne, the American version of this film, was released first. I am not sure as to the release date of the first film for I believe it to be a 80's movie as opposed to a 90's movie. It was on recently but I think, no, I know that I threw out the television paper so I do not know. Anyway, Cyrano de Bergerac seriously romps all over Roxanne, as most French movies tend to do to their American counterparts. Cyrano de Bergerac is about the captain of the Gascony guard who has a big, no a whopping great nose, and he is very sensitive about its size. He considers himself a freak and that nobody will see past the nose to his soul. Cyrano is a poet and a great lover but he feels he can never be loved because of his physical appearance. The woman that he loves, Roxanne, is in love with another man, Christian, who is in Cyrano's battalion but Christian does not know how to be romantic so Cyrano becomes Christian's romantic side and uses his romantic words to create an intellectual depth to Christian that does not exist. Cyrano de Bergerac is a tragedy in a number of ways. There is no fulfillment in the romantic sequences. Christian is not what Roxanne wants and they can never really be together because Roxanne loves Christian's words and his looks and nothing else. She claims to love his soul, but it is a soul that says the words that she wants to hear. When Christian tries to confront her without Cyrano's help, she sees a brute that she wants nothing to do with. She does not love his soul but rather his words, the words that Cyrano speaks. The further tragic part deals with the Duke who also loves Roxanne, and wants to marry her. Instead, Roxanne marries Christian, with Cyrano's help and upon discovery, the duke sends them off to the Spanish Front where there is little hope of survival. They are married in word but it is not consummated and the duke makes sure that it is not, and never will be consummated. The greater tragedy is that of Cyrano. He holds a love for Roxanne, though it is really only attraction to her physical appearance, yet he does not speak of it to anyone. Christian learns before his death, and he is the only one that knows that Cyrano loves Roxanne. This he learns from the letters that are sent in his name. He has read the letters and soon realises that Cyrano gives Roxanne a love that he never could, but Cyrano is constantly held back by his deformity. There is constantly reference to love in spite of a deformity, but Cyrano feels that he is not for Roxanne and remains silent. He spends time with her, every Saturday, and even manages to crawl to visit her on his death bed, but it is a love that remains silent, and the only person that knows and can reveal it is dead. Roxanne was a comedy, Cyrano de Bergerac is a tragedy. There is no hope in the film and everything is spiraling down to a very bloody conclusion. Cyrano is a master swordsman, who defeats a hundred men by himself, but he cannot stave off the anger of a duke. He is able to fight the Spanish hordes, but he is taunted by a love that he feels that can never be fulfilled. He speaks only of it on his death bed, and even though is very reluctant. This is a very sad movie, nothing like the Hollywood rubbish that is splattered over all of the screens. This is a movie with depth that deals with the real emotions of people. It is not one where the couple get together and live happily in the end, but one in which pain strikes through it right until the end. It is a poetic movie, though much of it will be lost in the translation. In essence, I see Cyrano de Bergerac on the level of a modern Shakespeare for it seems to have lots of Shakespearian elements, including a very deep, poetical language -- even though it is in French. Cyrano de Bergerac is a film that has one overriding theme and that is Carpe Diem - seize the day. Though such a thing does not happen in this movie, it shows us that it is something that we should do. We cannot let our love kindle unspoken, especially when the woman that our love is focused on so dearly wants to hear. In my opinion, it is not something that should be done for I feel that we need to be tactful in regards to the woman that we speak with and shouldn't overwhelm them, but in Cyrano's case he feels that his nose makes him hideous and that Roxanne won't want anything to do with him, which is not true as you learn at the end. When it comes down to self-doubt then it should be cast away. One should be tactful, but one should not attack oneself in belief that no woman would even want him.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Perfection
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bopulie
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/11/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Merging Poetry and Cinematography in a perfect way. First time in history, and it hasn't been done or even tried again aftetwards. English translations may be good, but to appreciate it to its full potential you have to speak french fluently, and it's probably why it isn't in the top 20 of IMDb. This movie earns a 10 out of 10 not only because of its unique style (dialogue is 100% alexandrines), but also because of the spot on acting and because the director didn't deviate from the original play by Edmond Rostand (an absolute heart-breaking drama) in any way which is a huge achievement. Magnifique.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    beats Hollywood at its own game
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Michael Neumann
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/11/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Edmond Rostand's celebrated swordsman/poet is the ideal role for Gerard Depardieu, demanding a physical presence and a level of energy few other actors could muster. Taking its cues from the swashbuckling entertainments of Hollywood's golden years, the film may well stand the test of time to become the definitive version of the story: thrilling, romantic, literate, and larger than life in a way that not even subtitles can hide. But it isn't all swordplay and daring-do: director Jean-Paul Rappeneau and his co-writer Jean-Claude Carriere devote equal attention to the humor in Cyrano's character and to the tragedy of his unrequited love for the fair Roxanne, and Depardieu responds with a generous performance filled with bold flourishes and subtle gestures. It was a sure bet for the Best Foreign Film Oscar, but Academy voters apparently don't appreciate European features comparing so favorably to their American role models. An ill-timed and too candid interview with Depardieu, during which the actor revealed too much (for Stateside viewers) of his delinquent adolescence probably didn't do the film any favors either.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    simply a superb film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    zb95
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/7/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Just a wonderful film. So many memorable scenes but my favorite was Cyrano's sword and verbal battle with the dude who made a simple common insult of his nose which Cyrano then responded with dozens of funny and clever alternate versions he could have used instead. Just a spectacularly witty and superbly acted scene! It has to be one of the best of all time in my opinion. But the entire movie was superb top to bottom. Great lines, great costumes, great acting. The English translations appeared to be perfect -- I cannot imagine it being any better in French but I suspect it was. It deserved all the awards it got. A ten in my book!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Beautiful, Poetic, and Masterful
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    HulotderSpeiler
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/2/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Although much of the greatness of this film comes from the immortal story of the French play written hundreds of years ago, there is something special about this adaptation that sets it apart from others. It may be simply that it is French, and the French understand this play more than anyone else. It could be Depardieu's riveting performance that would make you forget that he is acting. It might be attributed to the magnificent sets and stunning cinematography, or the perfect mix of tragedy and comedy. All of those things are part of it, but the true greatness comes from the translation. Some say that it may kill the poetry to make the lines that rhyme in French rhyme in English, but in this film it is not so. Cyrano's eloquence grips you in such a way that you feel like applauding the screen. The poetic soul of the story is backed by the characters speaking in poetry. The opening scene is masterfully shot, establishing the greatest character in film or literature in one of the greatest scenes of all time. Above all, Depardiu gives a performance for the ages in a demanding role. You will see why he won the top prize for acting at Cannes
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    probably the best ending line for a period piece
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    dumsumdumfai
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/9/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Steve Martin did a commendable job in turning this classic into Roxanne - but it was too optimistic for a modern piece... and lacks that... certain.... "P" thingy. It is only through the period setting and our limited and romanticized knowledge of the past that this version can work. And no less with Depardieu's imposing figure and statue. The opening sequence is captivating enough with the atmosphere, the smoke and the candle lights and the crowded theater/bar what have you. Still you need great delivery of the lines and a top-notched translation for the non-French speaking (like me) And what a last line !!!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
 </reviews>
</filme>
