<filme>
 <id>
  212
 </id>
 <imdburl>
  http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0096332
 </imdburl>
 <ano>
  1988
 </ano>
 <titulo>
  A Insustent&aacute;vel Leveza do Ser
 </titulo>
 <rating>
  7.3
 </rating>
 <sinopse>
  In 1968, a Czech doctor with an active sex life meets a woman who wants monogamy, and then the Soviet invasion further disrupts their lives.
 </sinopse>
 <storyline>
  Tomas is a doctor and a lady-killer in 1960s Czechoslovakia, an apolitical man who is struck with love for the bookish country girl Tereza; his more sophisticated sometime lover Sabina eventually accepts their relationship and the two women form an electric friendship. The three are caught up in the events of the Prague Spring (1968), until the Soviet tanks crush the non-violent rebels; their illusions are shattered and their lives change forever.
 </storyline>
 <generos>
  <genero>
   Drama
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Romance
  </genero>
 </generos>
 <keywords>
  <keyword>
   soviet
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   doctor
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   waitress
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   friendship
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   invasion
  </keyword>
 </keywords>
 <diretores>
  <diretor>
   Philip Kaufman
  </diretor>
 </diretores>
 <escritores>
  <escritor>
   Milan Kundera
  </escritor>
  <escritor>
   Jean-Claude Carri&egrave;re
  </escritor>
 </escritores>
 <atores>
  <ator>
   Daniel Day-Lewis
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Juliette Binoche
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Lena Olin
  </ator>
 </atores>
 <reviews>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One view of the unbearable lightness
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    paul2001sw-1 (paul2001sw@yahoo.co.uk)
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Milan Kundera's philosophical novel 'The Unbearable Lightness of Being' was always going to be difficult to film, a story of lives lived, ordinarily, against a backdrop of politics and eroticism. Philip Kaufamn's attempt is long, has a wonderful score, chooses to have its cast speak English in eastern European accents, showcases Juliet Binoche's beauty, and I think succeeds in avoiding the heaviness, the moral weight, that the story's characters find fundamentally absent from the business of simply being alive from one moment to the next. What it doesn't quite capture is the novel's intellectual playfulness, the authorial wisdom within which the original story was set, which in the book substitutes for the enforced narrative drive of most novels. Whereas some films are best enjoyed by those who haven't seen the source material, this one might work best for those who have: otherwise, some audiences could miss the point. Nonetheless, the ending is strangely affecting and true to the original story; and Daniel Day Lewis surprisingly good as a middle class Czech philanderer.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Pretentious Rubbish With Two Redeeming Elements.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Jem Smith
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Aka My Left Testicle , aka The Unbearable Pretentiousness of a Dreadful Film. Absolutely awful . Dreadful script , comically bad acting , especially from the perpetually smug Daniel Day Lewis and his terrible mid European accent. It does though warrant 2 stars for the acres of bare flesh displayed by the equally gorgeous Lena Olin and Juliette Binoche. So don't waste 150 minutes of your life , search the net and find the 15 minutes or so of Olin and Binoche at their beautiful best. Don't waste your time on the other 135 minutes.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A lack of philosophy
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Bob Sporker
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The best thing about the novel was that the events were more meaningful because along with each event came a piece of the author's philosophy which made not only the plot seem whole but the author's main philosophical argument materialize more and more as we read on. The movie was only a documentation of the plot and because it was a movie I guess it could only "lightly" touch upon the author's philosophy. Maybe a narrator in the background could have filled us in? I watched the movie not because I enjoyed the plot but because I enjoyed reading the author's ideas about life. They weren't as evident in the movie, but I gave a 6 because the acting and cinematography were good.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not even close to what i expected
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Shr
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I actually saw the movie with a lot of expectation. The title itself was very catchy at the same time mysterious. But i have never before been this disappointed by a movie. It started out with the story of a young doctor with numerous sexual partners who falls for a meek, typical "good girl" who expects a monogamous relationship. throughout the movie what i searched for is some level of ingenuity, spontaneity or even a beautiful romance. Sorry but i didn't find any. the film itself makes no sense, mainly because there is no naturality at all, especially how he falls in love with the lady. He saw her, next moment they talk for a second, he leaves, reaches home, she shows up that night, they make out and they get married. All this in a span of 2 days or so. this applies to the whole of the movie. To conclude it was a mistake to watch this movie for me.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Too uneven and too long - but with great performances
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Bene Cumb
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Although the screenplay is based on the great and world-famous book by Milan Kundera, it was written by others (Jean-Claude Carri&egrave;re and the director Philip Kaufman) and thus lost its original touch and approach - as was pointed out by Kundera himself who withdrew from the outcome. On the other hand, fragile feelings, ponderings and internal doubts are very difficult to express on the screen - without losing the pace and uniformity of the plot. It is also pity that Prague was not / could not been used, as it is a beautiful city and gives more realism than the French places used. Depicion of the socialist/communist oppression is, however, rather perfunctory, seeming not so serious as it really was in the 1970ies within the Warsaw block when hopes of intellectuals for the so-called human-faced socialism vanished as liberal steps were diminished or repealed. The cast is, of course, brilliant, in particular the bohemian m&eacute;nage &agrave; trois members: Daniel Day-Lewis as Tomas, Juliette Binoche as Tereza and Lena Olin as Sabina - all later multiple Academy Award winners and/or nominees, and from different European countries (the movie itself is still the US one). They and some other fine European actors have provided the movie a real European atmosphere, without a Hollywood studio feeling as sometimes perceived in "older" movies. Nevertheless, The Unbearable Lightness of Being is still a movie high above average, enhancing historical facts as well. But it is hard to say whether is is recommendable to read the book before or after...
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Confessions of Dr. Zhivago - or Fanny and Alexander Solzhenitsyn
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    justincward
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Daniel Day-Lewis is a philandering Czech brain surgeon who goes on to marry naive medical receptionist -turned-photographer Juliet Binoche, but still can't stop chasing girls and still carries on with his soulmate Sabine because of their shared bowler (Derby) hat fetish. In the end, The Soviet Union's 1968 occupation of Czechoslovakia indirectly gives Daniel and Juliette's fragile relationship the boost it needed, only for tragedy to strike, in a 'Wages of Fear' kind of way. Yes, I did watch to the end. The dishy doctor's chat-up line is 'Tek off your cloze". Seems to work every time. That's about all that happens for the first few hours. We get a lot of shots of panties, then bottoms and bosoms, but still no real plot. It seems that Prague in 1968 was a seething hotbed of sexual experimentation. TULOB is a quality epic - big budget, big names, many locations, much period detail - but deadly pretentious. Daniel Day-Lewis's Tomasz is like Sam Malone from 'Cheers' with a very serious case of pathological narcissism. Juliette Binoche overacts terribly; were her character a real person everyone would constantly get very annoyed with her. Lena Olin puts in a believable turn as the exotic, possibly bisexual Sabine, who has a fling with a married man in a subplot that is completely pointless, something like her love affair. It's atmospheric, immersive, and reminiscent of a modern Dr. Zhivago - star-crossed lovers against the background of political upheaval with a tragic (and predictable) ending - but the supersoft-porn aspects are ridiculous; obviously done from a commercial imperative and nothing else. You could speculate that Juliet Binoche's wide-eyed character (raped by a Russian) symbolises the Czech republic's burgeoning yearning for freedom, but then the pseudo-intellectual police would be at your door in a flash. I knew the dog was doomed, and actually predicted the 'Tek off your cloze' line the third time - but that was half the fun. Well, I've gone on long enough, it's a shame nobody told the director Phil Kaufman after ninety minutes.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    poet-philosopher guy, kinda crazy, who just goes around having sex with women
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    song_jh
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/4/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I watched this movie on Korean TV, when I was about 16. It was dubbed into Korean, and I did not bother to try to understand it (English is my native language); actually I didn't even pay full attention to the video images, other than the sex scenes. Basically, it seemed to be about this (French?) poet-philosopher guy (Daniel Day Lewis), kinda crazy, who just goes around having sex with women. The sex scenes seemed pretty intense, with loud moans and shrieks by the women. The rest of the movie seemed boring with quaint European landscapes and historical cityscapes, the beauty of which a teenage boy shouldn't be expected to appreciate. Juliette Binoche was the guy's beautiful girlfriend or wife, who was always hurt by his womanizing but didn't divorce or break up with him (or did she in the end? I don't remember). I did not really understand the deep philosophy or message of the movie, if it had one.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Overrated mess
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    IlluSionS667
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/4/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Maybe it's because I'm not old enough to have witnessed life in the sixties myself, but nothing in this movie made any sense to me. The dialogs were strange and often nonsensical. People's behavior was often strange and the movie never gave any real insight into their motivations. And if there was any character development, it certainly was lost on me. I found it pretty impossible to connect with any of the main characters at all, and for a movie like this it seems pretty essential to be able to connect with at least its main characters. I hoped the movie would start making sense by the end, but unfortunately it never did. It was a total waste of almost 3 hours of my life...
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Bad
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mr_dark_eyed
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/3/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I watched this with an open mind. I loved the book (LOVED) and knew (read) that the movie wasn't a direct reflection of the book , which, given the nature and style of the book, makes sense. But what I didn't expect was how shallow and bad the 'adaptation' was. I thought that when a director decides to tackle such issues and to deal with such a great book, he would try harder, or at least be much deeper, and I thought such actors would not take part in something that bad. From the very beginning I was very unsatisfied. I thought I was watching a comedy. Something very American about the first part of the movie. The scene in the spa, the way Tomas was portrayed. Too cocky. A character with no 'weight' or even flesh. It's as though the director told Daniel 2 words to describe his role before they started shooting: You are a cocky womanizer. period. The way he was inspecting Tereza after she got out of the pool! I couldn't believe that it was actually happening. I was laughing, whereas I would be reading Kundera's deep thoughts about this chance encounter. about Fate. Did Tereza really have to pick her nose while waiting at Tomas' door for the first time? Is this really the way to show us how naive and simple she is? really, what kind of woman picks her nose while standing in front of a man she has a crush on (or any man)? And did she have to act like a dumb retarded person the whole time? Tomas.. I don't remember ever meeting someone like Tomas, in real life. He is so unconvincing. It's like a kids movie where characters are either black or white, so the little ones can tell who is good and who is evil. Can't a womanizer be more subtle? OK, he is handsome and we know he sleeps around and loves women, can you now make him a real human being, so we can buy the whole story? And what about the silly accents? Are they Czech? is that why they have accents? why are they talking in English then? If you want the audience to forget about the whole language issue, then make them speak in English and forget about the accents. Lets forget about the language and focus on the dialogue. But what's the point in making a British actor fake a strange accent in order to play a Czech character who speaks English with his Czech friends???? it only helped in keeping me aware all the time that these people are acting. Sabina's character was very irritating to me, while she was very intriguing in the book. The "Stop This Noise" scene was very bad. Franz was a character with no flesh or meat. Was he a weak character? why was he agreeing with her like that? In the book, we knew enough about him (and Sabina) so we could make sense of their relationship and interaction. But not here. It's as though the director relied on the fact that we know about the characters from the book and will fill in the gaps. That's what I was doing at least, relying on my knowledge of the characters to make sense of some scenes. I can go on... I think if you attempt to turn this unusual book into a film, then you should be able to use unusual ways to create an unusual film with unusual structure, as opposed to the conventional usual narrative and storytelling. It takes a brave daring filmmaker to deal with such book. Mr. Kaufmann is not. He belongs in Hollywood. This film proves one thing: if you base your lousy film on a great book, there's good chance you will get away with it, and even get praised for it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Excellent argument!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Nuno Duarte
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/6/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    from http://movieinthepark.blogspot.com/ The Unbearable Lightness of Being (1988) Prague, 1968. Tomas (Daneil Day-Lewis), a Czech surgeon who keeps a sexual relationship with Sabina (Lena Olin). At one point he goes to a spa to do an operation and meets Tereza (Juliette Binoche), who despite the contrast between them both, ends up marrying him. Tomas, sexually very active, used to variety in women, very proud and sophisticated sees his wife, very simple and somehow naive, not tolerating his polygamy. Meanwhile, the Russians invade Prague and they flee to Switzerland. The argument is based on Milan Kundera's book from 1984. I haven't read it but it sure leaves a certain willingness to do it. Not only because of those people that defend that the movie poisoned the book, but for the background. The first Czechoslovakia described, with its intellectuality and liberty, later called by Prague Spring, that disturbed the Communists from the Soviet Union and cause the invasion. Prague new identity is hammered and distrust, fear, perversion and resignation take its place. Besides that, the relationship between Tomas and the other two, as between Tereza and Sabina is very interesting. Then comes the big purpose of the movie that took charge of the title, the lightness of Tomas' life against what Tereza called hers, hardness. Anyway, the movie is directed by Philip Kaufman, mainly known for Indiana Jones's screenplays. I think this might be Daniel DL's best job, his performance as nothing to do with his last movies, as he adopts a calm but enthusiastic and genial surgeon. Meanwhile, I watched another movie, Haneke's La pianiste (2001), that I found so bad, futile and obscene that didn't think it deserved its own article. Anyway, do not watch it. Much better is The Unbearable Lightness of Being and this one I recommend. 9/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One view of the unbearable lightness
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    paul2001sw-1 (paul2001sw@yahoo.co.uk)
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Milan Kundera's philosophical novel 'The Unbearable Lightness of Being' was always going to be difficult to film, a story of lives lived, ordinarily, against a backdrop of politics and eroticism. Philip Kaufamn's attempt is long, has a wonderful score, chooses to have its cast speak English in eastern European accents, showcases Juliet Binoche's beauty, and I think succeeds in avoiding the heaviness, the moral weight, that the story's characters find fundamentally absent from the business of simply being alive from one moment to the next. What it doesn't quite capture is the novel's intellectual playfulness, the authorial wisdom within which the original story was set, which in the book substitutes for the enforced narrative drive of most novels. Whereas some films are best enjoyed by those who haven't seen the source material, this one might work best for those who have: otherwise, some audiences could miss the point. Nonetheless, the ending is strangely affecting and true to the original story; and Daniel Day Lewis surprisingly good as a middle class Czech philanderer.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Pretentious Rubbish With Two Redeeming Elements.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Jem Smith
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Aka My Left Testicle , aka The Unbearable Pretentiousness of a Dreadful Film. Absolutely awful . Dreadful script , comically bad acting , especially from the perpetually smug Daniel Day Lewis and his terrible mid European accent. It does though warrant 2 stars for the acres of bare flesh displayed by the equally gorgeous Lena Olin and Juliette Binoche. So don't waste 150 minutes of your life , search the net and find the 15 minutes or so of Olin and Binoche at their beautiful best. Don't waste your time on the other 135 minutes.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A lack of philosophy
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Bob Sporker
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The best thing about the novel was that the events were more meaningful because along with each event came a piece of the author's philosophy which made not only the plot seem whole but the author's main philosophical argument materialize more and more as we read on. The movie was only a documentation of the plot and because it was a movie I guess it could only "lightly" touch upon the author's philosophy. Maybe a narrator in the background could have filled us in? I watched the movie not because I enjoyed the plot but because I enjoyed reading the author's ideas about life. They weren't as evident in the movie, but I gave a 6 because the acting and cinematography were good.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not even close to what i expected
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Shr
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I actually saw the movie with a lot of expectation. The title itself was very catchy at the same time mysterious. But i have never before been this disappointed by a movie. It started out with the story of a young doctor with numerous sexual partners who falls for a meek, typical "good girl" who expects a monogamous relationship. throughout the movie what i searched for is some level of ingenuity, spontaneity or even a beautiful romance. Sorry but i didn't find any. the film itself makes no sense, mainly because there is no naturality at all, especially how he falls in love with the lady. He saw her, next moment they talk for a second, he leaves, reaches home, she shows up that night, they make out and they get married. All this in a span of 2 days or so. this applies to the whole of the movie. To conclude it was a mistake to watch this movie for me.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Too uneven and too long - but with great performances
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Bene Cumb
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Although the screenplay is based on the great and world-famous book by Milan Kundera, it was written by others (Jean-Claude Carri&egrave;re and the director Philip Kaufman) and thus lost its original touch and approach - as was pointed out by Kundera himself who withdrew from the outcome. On the other hand, fragile feelings, ponderings and internal doubts are very difficult to express on the screen - without losing the pace and uniformity of the plot. It is also pity that Prague was not / could not been used, as it is a beautiful city and gives more realism than the French places used. Depicion of the socialist/communist oppression is, however, rather perfunctory, seeming not so serious as it really was in the 1970ies within the Warsaw block when hopes of intellectuals for the so-called human-faced socialism vanished as liberal steps were diminished or repealed. The cast is, of course, brilliant, in particular the bohemian m&eacute;nage &agrave; trois members: Daniel Day-Lewis as Tomas, Juliette Binoche as Tereza and Lena Olin as Sabina - all later multiple Academy Award winners and/or nominees, and from different European countries (the movie itself is still the US one). They and some other fine European actors have provided the movie a real European atmosphere, without a Hollywood studio feeling as sometimes perceived in "older" movies. Nevertheless, The Unbearable Lightness of Being is still a movie high above average, enhancing historical facts as well. But it is hard to say whether is is recommendable to read the book before or after...
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Confessions of Dr. Zhivago - or Fanny and Alexander Solzhenitsyn
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    justincward
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Daniel Day-Lewis is a philandering Czech brain surgeon who goes on to marry naive medical receptionist -turned-photographer Juliet Binoche, but still can't stop chasing girls and still carries on with his soulmate Sabine because of their shared bowler (Derby) hat fetish. In the end, The Soviet Union's 1968 occupation of Czechoslovakia indirectly gives Daniel and Juliette's fragile relationship the boost it needed, only for tragedy to strike, in a 'Wages of Fear' kind of way. Yes, I did watch to the end. The dishy doctor's chat-up line is 'Tek off your cloze". Seems to work every time. That's about all that happens for the first few hours. We get a lot of shots of panties, then bottoms and bosoms, but still no real plot. It seems that Prague in 1968 was a seething hotbed of sexual experimentation. TULOB is a quality epic - big budget, big names, many locations, much period detail - but deadly pretentious. Daniel Day-Lewis's Tomasz is like Sam Malone from 'Cheers' with a very serious case of pathological narcissism. Juliette Binoche overacts terribly; were her character a real person everyone would constantly get very annoyed with her. Lena Olin puts in a believable turn as the exotic, possibly bisexual Sabine, who has a fling with a married man in a subplot that is completely pointless, something like her love affair. It's atmospheric, immersive, and reminiscent of a modern Dr. Zhivago - star-crossed lovers against the background of political upheaval with a tragic (and predictable) ending - but the supersoft-porn aspects are ridiculous; obviously done from a commercial imperative and nothing else. You could speculate that Juliet Binoche's wide-eyed character (raped by a Russian) symbolises the Czech republic's burgeoning yearning for freedom, but then the pseudo-intellectual police would be at your door in a flash. I knew the dog was doomed, and actually predicted the 'Tek off your cloze' line the third time - but that was half the fun. Well, I've gone on long enough, it's a shame nobody told the director Phil Kaufman after ninety minutes.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    poet-philosopher guy, kinda crazy, who just goes around having sex with women
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    song_jh
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/4/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I watched this movie on Korean TV, when I was about 16. It was dubbed into Korean, and I did not bother to try to understand it (English is my native language); actually I didn't even pay full attention to the video images, other than the sex scenes. Basically, it seemed to be about this (French?) poet-philosopher guy (Daniel Day Lewis), kinda crazy, who just goes around having sex with women. The sex scenes seemed pretty intense, with loud moans and shrieks by the women. The rest of the movie seemed boring with quaint European landscapes and historical cityscapes, the beauty of which a teenage boy shouldn't be expected to appreciate. Juliette Binoche was the guy's beautiful girlfriend or wife, who was always hurt by his womanizing but didn't divorce or break up with him (or did she in the end? I don't remember). I did not really understand the deep philosophy or message of the movie, if it had one.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Overrated mess
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    IlluSionS667
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/4/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Maybe it's because I'm not old enough to have witnessed life in the sixties myself, but nothing in this movie made any sense to me. The dialogs were strange and often nonsensical. People's behavior was often strange and the movie never gave any real insight into their motivations. And if there was any character development, it certainly was lost on me. I found it pretty impossible to connect with any of the main characters at all, and for a movie like this it seems pretty essential to be able to connect with at least its main characters. I hoped the movie would start making sense by the end, but unfortunately it never did. It was a total waste of almost 3 hours of my life...
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Bad
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mr_dark_eyed
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/3/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I watched this with an open mind. I loved the book (LOVED) and knew (read) that the movie wasn't a direct reflection of the book , which, given the nature and style of the book, makes sense. But what I didn't expect was how shallow and bad the 'adaptation' was. I thought that when a director decides to tackle such issues and to deal with such a great book, he would try harder, or at least be much deeper, and I thought such actors would not take part in something that bad. From the very beginning I was very unsatisfied. I thought I was watching a comedy. Something very American about the first part of the movie. The scene in the spa, the way Tomas was portrayed. Too cocky. A character with no 'weight' or even flesh. It's as though the director told Daniel 2 words to describe his role before they started shooting: You are a cocky womanizer. period. The way he was inspecting Tereza after she got out of the pool! I couldn't believe that it was actually happening. I was laughing, whereas I would be reading Kundera's deep thoughts about this chance encounter. about Fate. Did Tereza really have to pick her nose while waiting at Tomas' door for the first time? Is this really the way to show us how naive and simple she is? really, what kind of woman picks her nose while standing in front of a man she has a crush on (or any man)? And did she have to act like a dumb retarded person the whole time? Tomas.. I don't remember ever meeting someone like Tomas, in real life. He is so unconvincing. It's like a kids movie where characters are either black or white, so the little ones can tell who is good and who is evil. Can't a womanizer be more subtle? OK, he is handsome and we know he sleeps around and loves women, can you now make him a real human being, so we can buy the whole story? And what about the silly accents? Are they Czech? is that why they have accents? why are they talking in English then? If you want the audience to forget about the whole language issue, then make them speak in English and forget about the accents. Lets forget about the language and focus on the dialogue. But what's the point in making a British actor fake a strange accent in order to play a Czech character who speaks English with his Czech friends???? it only helped in keeping me aware all the time that these people are acting. Sabina's character was very irritating to me, while she was very intriguing in the book. The "Stop This Noise" scene was very bad. Franz was a character with no flesh or meat. Was he a weak character? why was he agreeing with her like that? In the book, we knew enough about him (and Sabina) so we could make sense of their relationship and interaction. But not here. It's as though the director relied on the fact that we know about the characters from the book and will fill in the gaps. That's what I was doing at least, relying on my knowledge of the characters to make sense of some scenes. I can go on... I think if you attempt to turn this unusual book into a film, then you should be able to use unusual ways to create an unusual film with unusual structure, as opposed to the conventional usual narrative and storytelling. It takes a brave daring filmmaker to deal with such book. Mr. Kaufmann is not. He belongs in Hollywood. This film proves one thing: if you base your lousy film on a great book, there's good chance you will get away with it, and even get praised for it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Excellent argument!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Nuno Duarte
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/6/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    from http://movieinthepark.blogspot.com/ The Unbearable Lightness of Being (1988) Prague, 1968. Tomas (Daneil Day-Lewis), a Czech surgeon who keeps a sexual relationship with Sabina (Lena Olin). At one point he goes to a spa to do an operation and meets Tereza (Juliette Binoche), who despite the contrast between them both, ends up marrying him. Tomas, sexually very active, used to variety in women, very proud and sophisticated sees his wife, very simple and somehow naive, not tolerating his polygamy. Meanwhile, the Russians invade Prague and they flee to Switzerland. The argument is based on Milan Kundera's book from 1984. I haven't read it but it sure leaves a certain willingness to do it. Not only because of those people that defend that the movie poisoned the book, but for the background. The first Czechoslovakia described, with its intellectuality and liberty, later called by Prague Spring, that disturbed the Communists from the Soviet Union and cause the invasion. Prague new identity is hammered and distrust, fear, perversion and resignation take its place. Besides that, the relationship between Tomas and the other two, as between Tereza and Sabina is very interesting. Then comes the big purpose of the movie that took charge of the title, the lightness of Tomas' life against what Tereza called hers, hardness. Anyway, the movie is directed by Philip Kaufman, mainly known for Indiana Jones's screenplays. I think this might be Daniel DL's best job, his performance as nothing to do with his last movies, as he adopts a calm but enthusiastic and genial surgeon. Meanwhile, I watched another movie, Haneke's La pianiste (2001), that I found so bad, futile and obscene that didn't think it deserved its own article. Anyway, do not watch it. Much better is The Unbearable Lightness of Being and this one I recommend. 9/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One view of the unbearable lightness
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    paul2001sw-1 (paul2001sw@yahoo.co.uk)
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Milan Kundera's philosophical novel 'The Unbearable Lightness of Being' was always going to be difficult to film, a story of lives lived, ordinarily, against a backdrop of politics and eroticism. Philip Kaufamn's attempt is long, has a wonderful score, chooses to have its cast speak English in eastern European accents, showcases Juliet Binoche's beauty, and I think succeeds in avoiding the heaviness, the moral weight, that the story's characters find fundamentally absent from the business of simply being alive from one moment to the next. What it doesn't quite capture is the novel's intellectual playfulness, the authorial wisdom within which the original story was set, which in the book substitutes for the enforced narrative drive of most novels. Whereas some films are best enjoyed by those who haven't seen the source material, this one might work best for those who have: otherwise, some audiences could miss the point. Nonetheless, the ending is strangely affecting and true to the original story; and Daniel Day Lewis surprisingly good as a middle class Czech philanderer.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Pretentious Rubbish With Two Redeeming Elements.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Jem Smith
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Aka My Left Testicle , aka The Unbearable Pretentiousness of a Dreadful Film. Absolutely awful . Dreadful script , comically bad acting , especially from the perpetually smug Daniel Day Lewis and his terrible mid European accent. It does though warrant 2 stars for the acres of bare flesh displayed by the equally gorgeous Lena Olin and Juliette Binoche. So don't waste 150 minutes of your life , search the net and find the 15 minutes or so of Olin and Binoche at their beautiful best. Don't waste your time on the other 135 minutes.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A lack of philosophy
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Bob Sporker
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The best thing about the novel was that the events were more meaningful because along with each event came a piece of the author's philosophy which made not only the plot seem whole but the author's main philosophical argument materialize more and more as we read on. The movie was only a documentation of the plot and because it was a movie I guess it could only "lightly" touch upon the author's philosophy. Maybe a narrator in the background could have filled us in? I watched the movie not because I enjoyed the plot but because I enjoyed reading the author's ideas about life. They weren't as evident in the movie, but I gave a 6 because the acting and cinematography were good.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not even close to what i expected
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Shr
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I actually saw the movie with a lot of expectation. The title itself was very catchy at the same time mysterious. But i have never before been this disappointed by a movie. It started out with the story of a young doctor with numerous sexual partners who falls for a meek, typical "good girl" who expects a monogamous relationship. throughout the movie what i searched for is some level of ingenuity, spontaneity or even a beautiful romance. Sorry but i didn't find any. the film itself makes no sense, mainly because there is no naturality at all, especially how he falls in love with the lady. He saw her, next moment they talk for a second, he leaves, reaches home, she shows up that night, they make out and they get married. All this in a span of 2 days or so. this applies to the whole of the movie. To conclude it was a mistake to watch this movie for me.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Too uneven and too long - but with great performances
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Bene Cumb
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Although the screenplay is based on the great and world-famous book by Milan Kundera, it was written by others (Jean-Claude Carri&egrave;re and the director Philip Kaufman) and thus lost its original touch and approach - as was pointed out by Kundera himself who withdrew from the outcome. On the other hand, fragile feelings, ponderings and internal doubts are very difficult to express on the screen - without losing the pace and uniformity of the plot. It is also pity that Prague was not / could not been used, as it is a beautiful city and gives more realism than the French places used. Depicion of the socialist/communist oppression is, however, rather perfunctory, seeming not so serious as it really was in the 1970ies within the Warsaw block when hopes of intellectuals for the so-called human-faced socialism vanished as liberal steps were diminished or repealed. The cast is, of course, brilliant, in particular the bohemian m&eacute;nage &agrave; trois members: Daniel Day-Lewis as Tomas, Juliette Binoche as Tereza and Lena Olin as Sabina - all later multiple Academy Award winners and/or nominees, and from different European countries (the movie itself is still the US one). They and some other fine European actors have provided the movie a real European atmosphere, without a Hollywood studio feeling as sometimes perceived in "older" movies. Nevertheless, The Unbearable Lightness of Being is still a movie high above average, enhancing historical facts as well. But it is hard to say whether is is recommendable to read the book before or after...
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Confessions of Dr. Zhivago - or Fanny and Alexander Solzhenitsyn
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    justincward
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Daniel Day-Lewis is a philandering Czech brain surgeon who goes on to marry naive medical receptionist -turned-photographer Juliet Binoche, but still can't stop chasing girls and still carries on with his soulmate Sabine because of their shared bowler (Derby) hat fetish. In the end, The Soviet Union's 1968 occupation of Czechoslovakia indirectly gives Daniel and Juliette's fragile relationship the boost it needed, only for tragedy to strike, in a 'Wages of Fear' kind of way. Yes, I did watch to the end. The dishy doctor's chat-up line is 'Tek off your cloze". Seems to work every time. That's about all that happens for the first few hours. We get a lot of shots of panties, then bottoms and bosoms, but still no real plot. It seems that Prague in 1968 was a seething hotbed of sexual experimentation. TULOB is a quality epic - big budget, big names, many locations, much period detail - but deadly pretentious. Daniel Day-Lewis's Tomasz is like Sam Malone from 'Cheers' with a very serious case of pathological narcissism. Juliette Binoche overacts terribly; were her character a real person everyone would constantly get very annoyed with her. Lena Olin puts in a believable turn as the exotic, possibly bisexual Sabine, who has a fling with a married man in a subplot that is completely pointless, something like her love affair. It's atmospheric, immersive, and reminiscent of a modern Dr. Zhivago - star-crossed lovers against the background of political upheaval with a tragic (and predictable) ending - but the supersoft-porn aspects are ridiculous; obviously done from a commercial imperative and nothing else. You could speculate that Juliet Binoche's wide-eyed character (raped by a Russian) symbolises the Czech republic's burgeoning yearning for freedom, but then the pseudo-intellectual police would be at your door in a flash. I knew the dog was doomed, and actually predicted the 'Tek off your cloze' line the third time - but that was half the fun. Well, I've gone on long enough, it's a shame nobody told the director Phil Kaufman after ninety minutes.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    poet-philosopher guy, kinda crazy, who just goes around having sex with women
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    song_jh
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/4/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I watched this movie on Korean TV, when I was about 16. It was dubbed into Korean, and I did not bother to try to understand it (English is my native language); actually I didn't even pay full attention to the video images, other than the sex scenes. Basically, it seemed to be about this (French?) poet-philosopher guy (Daniel Day Lewis), kinda crazy, who just goes around having sex with women. The sex scenes seemed pretty intense, with loud moans and shrieks by the women. The rest of the movie seemed boring with quaint European landscapes and historical cityscapes, the beauty of which a teenage boy shouldn't be expected to appreciate. Juliette Binoche was the guy's beautiful girlfriend or wife, who was always hurt by his womanizing but didn't divorce or break up with him (or did she in the end? I don't remember). I did not really understand the deep philosophy or message of the movie, if it had one.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Overrated mess
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    IlluSionS667
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/4/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Maybe it's because I'm not old enough to have witnessed life in the sixties myself, but nothing in this movie made any sense to me. The dialogs were strange and often nonsensical. People's behavior was often strange and the movie never gave any real insight into their motivations. And if there was any character development, it certainly was lost on me. I found it pretty impossible to connect with any of the main characters at all, and for a movie like this it seems pretty essential to be able to connect with at least its main characters. I hoped the movie would start making sense by the end, but unfortunately it never did. It was a total waste of almost 3 hours of my life...
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Bad
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mr_dark_eyed
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/3/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I watched this with an open mind. I loved the book (LOVED) and knew (read) that the movie wasn't a direct reflection of the book , which, given the nature and style of the book, makes sense. But what I didn't expect was how shallow and bad the 'adaptation' was. I thought that when a director decides to tackle such issues and to deal with such a great book, he would try harder, or at least be much deeper, and I thought such actors would not take part in something that bad. From the very beginning I was very unsatisfied. I thought I was watching a comedy. Something very American about the first part of the movie. The scene in the spa, the way Tomas was portrayed. Too cocky. A character with no 'weight' or even flesh. It's as though the director told Daniel 2 words to describe his role before they started shooting: You are a cocky womanizer. period. The way he was inspecting Tereza after she got out of the pool! I couldn't believe that it was actually happening. I was laughing, whereas I would be reading Kundera's deep thoughts about this chance encounter. about Fate. Did Tereza really have to pick her nose while waiting at Tomas' door for the first time? Is this really the way to show us how naive and simple she is? really, what kind of woman picks her nose while standing in front of a man she has a crush on (or any man)? And did she have to act like a dumb retarded person the whole time? Tomas.. I don't remember ever meeting someone like Tomas, in real life. He is so unconvincing. It's like a kids movie where characters are either black or white, so the little ones can tell who is good and who is evil. Can't a womanizer be more subtle? OK, he is handsome and we know he sleeps around and loves women, can you now make him a real human being, so we can buy the whole story? And what about the silly accents? Are they Czech? is that why they have accents? why are they talking in English then? If you want the audience to forget about the whole language issue, then make them speak in English and forget about the accents. Lets forget about the language and focus on the dialogue. But what's the point in making a British actor fake a strange accent in order to play a Czech character who speaks English with his Czech friends???? it only helped in keeping me aware all the time that these people are acting. Sabina's character was very irritating to me, while she was very intriguing in the book. The "Stop This Noise" scene was very bad. Franz was a character with no flesh or meat. Was he a weak character? why was he agreeing with her like that? In the book, we knew enough about him (and Sabina) so we could make sense of their relationship and interaction. But not here. It's as though the director relied on the fact that we know about the characters from the book and will fill in the gaps. That's what I was doing at least, relying on my knowledge of the characters to make sense of some scenes. I can go on... I think if you attempt to turn this unusual book into a film, then you should be able to use unusual ways to create an unusual film with unusual structure, as opposed to the conventional usual narrative and storytelling. It takes a brave daring filmmaker to deal with such book. Mr. Kaufmann is not. He belongs in Hollywood. This film proves one thing: if you base your lousy film on a great book, there's good chance you will get away with it, and even get praised for it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Excellent argument!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Nuno Duarte
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/6/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    from http://movieinthepark.blogspot.com/ The Unbearable Lightness of Being (1988) Prague, 1968. Tomas (Daneil Day-Lewis), a Czech surgeon who keeps a sexual relationship with Sabina (Lena Olin). At one point he goes to a spa to do an operation and meets Tereza (Juliette Binoche), who despite the contrast between them both, ends up marrying him. Tomas, sexually very active, used to variety in women, very proud and sophisticated sees his wife, very simple and somehow naive, not tolerating his polygamy. Meanwhile, the Russians invade Prague and they flee to Switzerland. The argument is based on Milan Kundera's book from 1984. I haven't read it but it sure leaves a certain willingness to do it. Not only because of those people that defend that the movie poisoned the book, but for the background. The first Czechoslovakia described, with its intellectuality and liberty, later called by Prague Spring, that disturbed the Communists from the Soviet Union and cause the invasion. Prague new identity is hammered and distrust, fear, perversion and resignation take its place. Besides that, the relationship between Tomas and the other two, as between Tereza and Sabina is very interesting. Then comes the big purpose of the movie that took charge of the title, the lightness of Tomas' life against what Tereza called hers, hardness. Anyway, the movie is directed by Philip Kaufman, mainly known for Indiana Jones's screenplays. I think this might be Daniel DL's best job, his performance as nothing to do with his last movies, as he adopts a calm but enthusiastic and genial surgeon. Meanwhile, I watched another movie, Haneke's La pianiste (2001), that I found so bad, futile and obscene that didn't think it deserved its own article. Anyway, do not watch it. Much better is The Unbearable Lightness of Being and this one I recommend. 9/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One view of the unbearable lightness
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    paul2001sw-1 (paul2001sw@yahoo.co.uk)
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Milan Kundera's philosophical novel 'The Unbearable Lightness of Being' was always going to be difficult to film, a story of lives lived, ordinarily, against a backdrop of politics and eroticism. Philip Kaufamn's attempt is long, has a wonderful score, chooses to have its cast speak English in eastern European accents, showcases Juliet Binoche's beauty, and I think succeeds in avoiding the heaviness, the moral weight, that the story's characters find fundamentally absent from the business of simply being alive from one moment to the next. What it doesn't quite capture is the novel's intellectual playfulness, the authorial wisdom within which the original story was set, which in the book substitutes for the enforced narrative drive of most novels. Whereas some films are best enjoyed by those who haven't seen the source material, this one might work best for those who have: otherwise, some audiences could miss the point. Nonetheless, the ending is strangely affecting and true to the original story; and Daniel Day Lewis surprisingly good as a middle class Czech philanderer.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Pretentious Rubbish With Two Redeeming Elements.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Jem Smith
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Aka My Left Testicle , aka The Unbearable Pretentiousness of a Dreadful Film. Absolutely awful . Dreadful script , comically bad acting , especially from the perpetually smug Daniel Day Lewis and his terrible mid European accent. It does though warrant 2 stars for the acres of bare flesh displayed by the equally gorgeous Lena Olin and Juliette Binoche. So don't waste 150 minutes of your life , search the net and find the 15 minutes or so of Olin and Binoche at their beautiful best. Don't waste your time on the other 135 minutes.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A lack of philosophy
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Bob Sporker
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The best thing about the novel was that the events were more meaningful because along with each event came a piece of the author's philosophy which made not only the plot seem whole but the author's main philosophical argument materialize more and more as we read on. The movie was only a documentation of the plot and because it was a movie I guess it could only "lightly" touch upon the author's philosophy. Maybe a narrator in the background could have filled us in? I watched the movie not because I enjoyed the plot but because I enjoyed reading the author's ideas about life. They weren't as evident in the movie, but I gave a 6 because the acting and cinematography were good.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not even close to what i expected
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Shr
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I actually saw the movie with a lot of expectation. The title itself was very catchy at the same time mysterious. But i have never before been this disappointed by a movie. It started out with the story of a young doctor with numerous sexual partners who falls for a meek, typical "good girl" who expects a monogamous relationship. throughout the movie what i searched for is some level of ingenuity, spontaneity or even a beautiful romance. Sorry but i didn't find any. the film itself makes no sense, mainly because there is no naturality at all, especially how he falls in love with the lady. He saw her, next moment they talk for a second, he leaves, reaches home, she shows up that night, they make out and they get married. All this in a span of 2 days or so. this applies to the whole of the movie. To conclude it was a mistake to watch this movie for me.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Too uneven and too long - but with great performances
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Bene Cumb
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Although the screenplay is based on the great and world-famous book by Milan Kundera, it was written by others (Jean-Claude Carri&egrave;re and the director Philip Kaufman) and thus lost its original touch and approach - as was pointed out by Kundera himself who withdrew from the outcome. On the other hand, fragile feelings, ponderings and internal doubts are very difficult to express on the screen - without losing the pace and uniformity of the plot. It is also pity that Prague was not / could not been used, as it is a beautiful city and gives more realism than the French places used. Depicion of the socialist/communist oppression is, however, rather perfunctory, seeming not so serious as it really was in the 1970ies within the Warsaw block when hopes of intellectuals for the so-called human-faced socialism vanished as liberal steps were diminished or repealed. The cast is, of course, brilliant, in particular the bohemian m&eacute;nage &agrave; trois members: Daniel Day-Lewis as Tomas, Juliette Binoche as Tereza and Lena Olin as Sabina - all later multiple Academy Award winners and/or nominees, and from different European countries (the movie itself is still the US one). They and some other fine European actors have provided the movie a real European atmosphere, without a Hollywood studio feeling as sometimes perceived in "older" movies. Nevertheless, The Unbearable Lightness of Being is still a movie high above average, enhancing historical facts as well. But it is hard to say whether is is recommendable to read the book before or after...
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Confessions of Dr. Zhivago - or Fanny and Alexander Solzhenitsyn
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    justincward
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Daniel Day-Lewis is a philandering Czech brain surgeon who goes on to marry naive medical receptionist -turned-photographer Juliet Binoche, but still can't stop chasing girls and still carries on with his soulmate Sabine because of their shared bowler (Derby) hat fetish. In the end, The Soviet Union's 1968 occupation of Czechoslovakia indirectly gives Daniel and Juliette's fragile relationship the boost it needed, only for tragedy to strike, in a 'Wages of Fear' kind of way. Yes, I did watch to the end. The dishy doctor's chat-up line is 'Tek off your cloze". Seems to work every time. That's about all that happens for the first few hours. We get a lot of shots of panties, then bottoms and bosoms, but still no real plot. It seems that Prague in 1968 was a seething hotbed of sexual experimentation. TULOB is a quality epic - big budget, big names, many locations, much period detail - but deadly pretentious. Daniel Day-Lewis's Tomasz is like Sam Malone from 'Cheers' with a very serious case of pathological narcissism. Juliette Binoche overacts terribly; were her character a real person everyone would constantly get very annoyed with her. Lena Olin puts in a believable turn as the exotic, possibly bisexual Sabine, who has a fling with a married man in a subplot that is completely pointless, something like her love affair. It's atmospheric, immersive, and reminiscent of a modern Dr. Zhivago - star-crossed lovers against the background of political upheaval with a tragic (and predictable) ending - but the supersoft-porn aspects are ridiculous; obviously done from a commercial imperative and nothing else. You could speculate that Juliet Binoche's wide-eyed character (raped by a Russian) symbolises the Czech republic's burgeoning yearning for freedom, but then the pseudo-intellectual police would be at your door in a flash. I knew the dog was doomed, and actually predicted the 'Tek off your cloze' line the third time - but that was half the fun. Well, I've gone on long enough, it's a shame nobody told the director Phil Kaufman after ninety minutes.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    poet-philosopher guy, kinda crazy, who just goes around having sex with women
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    song_jh
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/4/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I watched this movie on Korean TV, when I was about 16. It was dubbed into Korean, and I did not bother to try to understand it (English is my native language); actually I didn't even pay full attention to the video images, other than the sex scenes. Basically, it seemed to be about this (French?) poet-philosopher guy (Daniel Day Lewis), kinda crazy, who just goes around having sex with women. The sex scenes seemed pretty intense, with loud moans and shrieks by the women. The rest of the movie seemed boring with quaint European landscapes and historical cityscapes, the beauty of which a teenage boy shouldn't be expected to appreciate. Juliette Binoche was the guy's beautiful girlfriend or wife, who was always hurt by his womanizing but didn't divorce or break up with him (or did she in the end? I don't remember). I did not really understand the deep philosophy or message of the movie, if it had one.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Overrated mess
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    IlluSionS667
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/4/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Maybe it's because I'm not old enough to have witnessed life in the sixties myself, but nothing in this movie made any sense to me. The dialogs were strange and often nonsensical. People's behavior was often strange and the movie never gave any real insight into their motivations. And if there was any character development, it certainly was lost on me. I found it pretty impossible to connect with any of the main characters at all, and for a movie like this it seems pretty essential to be able to connect with at least its main characters. I hoped the movie would start making sense by the end, but unfortunately it never did. It was a total waste of almost 3 hours of my life...
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Bad
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mr_dark_eyed
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/3/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I watched this with an open mind. I loved the book (LOVED) and knew (read) that the movie wasn't a direct reflection of the book , which, given the nature and style of the book, makes sense. But what I didn't expect was how shallow and bad the 'adaptation' was. I thought that when a director decides to tackle such issues and to deal with such a great book, he would try harder, or at least be much deeper, and I thought such actors would not take part in something that bad. From the very beginning I was very unsatisfied. I thought I was watching a comedy. Something very American about the first part of the movie. The scene in the spa, the way Tomas was portrayed. Too cocky. A character with no 'weight' or even flesh. It's as though the director told Daniel 2 words to describe his role before they started shooting: You are a cocky womanizer. period. The way he was inspecting Tereza after she got out of the pool! I couldn't believe that it was actually happening. I was laughing, whereas I would be reading Kundera's deep thoughts about this chance encounter. about Fate. Did Tereza really have to pick her nose while waiting at Tomas' door for the first time? Is this really the way to show us how naive and simple she is? really, what kind of woman picks her nose while standing in front of a man she has a crush on (or any man)? And did she have to act like a dumb retarded person the whole time? Tomas.. I don't remember ever meeting someone like Tomas, in real life. He is so unconvincing. It's like a kids movie where characters are either black or white, so the little ones can tell who is good and who is evil. Can't a womanizer be more subtle? OK, he is handsome and we know he sleeps around and loves women, can you now make him a real human being, so we can buy the whole story? And what about the silly accents? Are they Czech? is that why they have accents? why are they talking in English then? If you want the audience to forget about the whole language issue, then make them speak in English and forget about the accents. Lets forget about the language and focus on the dialogue. But what's the point in making a British actor fake a strange accent in order to play a Czech character who speaks English with his Czech friends???? it only helped in keeping me aware all the time that these people are acting. Sabina's character was very irritating to me, while she was very intriguing in the book. The "Stop This Noise" scene was very bad. Franz was a character with no flesh or meat. Was he a weak character? why was he agreeing with her like that? In the book, we knew enough about him (and Sabina) so we could make sense of their relationship and interaction. But not here. It's as though the director relied on the fact that we know about the characters from the book and will fill in the gaps. That's what I was doing at least, relying on my knowledge of the characters to make sense of some scenes. I can go on... I think if you attempt to turn this unusual book into a film, then you should be able to use unusual ways to create an unusual film with unusual structure, as opposed to the conventional usual narrative and storytelling. It takes a brave daring filmmaker to deal with such book. Mr. Kaufmann is not. He belongs in Hollywood. This film proves one thing: if you base your lousy film on a great book, there's good chance you will get away with it, and even get praised for it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Excellent argument!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Nuno Duarte
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/6/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    from http://movieinthepark.blogspot.com/ The Unbearable Lightness of Being (1988) Prague, 1968. Tomas (Daneil Day-Lewis), a Czech surgeon who keeps a sexual relationship with Sabina (Lena Olin). At one point he goes to a spa to do an operation and meets Tereza (Juliette Binoche), who despite the contrast between them both, ends up marrying him. Tomas, sexually very active, used to variety in women, very proud and sophisticated sees his wife, very simple and somehow naive, not tolerating his polygamy. Meanwhile, the Russians invade Prague and they flee to Switzerland. The argument is based on Milan Kundera's book from 1984. I haven't read it but it sure leaves a certain willingness to do it. Not only because of those people that defend that the movie poisoned the book, but for the background. The first Czechoslovakia described, with its intellectuality and liberty, later called by Prague Spring, that disturbed the Communists from the Soviet Union and cause the invasion. Prague new identity is hammered and distrust, fear, perversion and resignation take its place. Besides that, the relationship between Tomas and the other two, as between Tereza and Sabina is very interesting. Then comes the big purpose of the movie that took charge of the title, the lightness of Tomas' life against what Tereza called hers, hardness. Anyway, the movie is directed by Philip Kaufman, mainly known for Indiana Jones's screenplays. I think this might be Daniel DL's best job, his performance as nothing to do with his last movies, as he adopts a calm but enthusiastic and genial surgeon. Meanwhile, I watched another movie, Haneke's La pianiste (2001), that I found so bad, futile and obscene that didn't think it deserved its own article. Anyway, do not watch it. Much better is The Unbearable Lightness of Being and this one I recommend. 9/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One view of the unbearable lightness
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    paul2001sw-1 (paul2001sw@yahoo.co.uk)
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Milan Kundera's philosophical novel 'The Unbearable Lightness of Being' was always going to be difficult to film, a story of lives lived, ordinarily, against a backdrop of politics and eroticism. Philip Kaufamn's attempt is long, has a wonderful score, chooses to have its cast speak English in eastern European accents, showcases Juliet Binoche's beauty, and I think succeeds in avoiding the heaviness, the moral weight, that the story's characters find fundamentally absent from the business of simply being alive from one moment to the next. What it doesn't quite capture is the novel's intellectual playfulness, the authorial wisdom within which the original story was set, which in the book substitutes for the enforced narrative drive of most novels. Whereas some films are best enjoyed by those who haven't seen the source material, this one might work best for those who have: otherwise, some audiences could miss the point. Nonetheless, the ending is strangely affecting and true to the original story; and Daniel Day Lewis surprisingly good as a middle class Czech philanderer.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Pretentious Rubbish With Two Redeeming Elements.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Jem Smith
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Aka My Left Testicle , aka The Unbearable Pretentiousness of a Dreadful Film. Absolutely awful . Dreadful script , comically bad acting , especially from the perpetually smug Daniel Day Lewis and his terrible mid European accent. It does though warrant 2 stars for the acres of bare flesh displayed by the equally gorgeous Lena Olin and Juliette Binoche. So don't waste 150 minutes of your life , search the net and find the 15 minutes or so of Olin and Binoche at their beautiful best. Don't waste your time on the other 135 minutes.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A lack of philosophy
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Bob Sporker
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The best thing about the novel was that the events were more meaningful because along with each event came a piece of the author's philosophy which made not only the plot seem whole but the author's main philosophical argument materialize more and more as we read on. The movie was only a documentation of the plot and because it was a movie I guess it could only "lightly" touch upon the author's philosophy. Maybe a narrator in the background could have filled us in? I watched the movie not because I enjoyed the plot but because I enjoyed reading the author's ideas about life. They weren't as evident in the movie, but I gave a 6 because the acting and cinematography were good.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not even close to what i expected
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Shr
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I actually saw the movie with a lot of expectation. The title itself was very catchy at the same time mysterious. But i have never before been this disappointed by a movie. It started out with the story of a young doctor with numerous sexual partners who falls for a meek, typical "good girl" who expects a monogamous relationship. throughout the movie what i searched for is some level of ingenuity, spontaneity or even a beautiful romance. Sorry but i didn't find any. the film itself makes no sense, mainly because there is no naturality at all, especially how he falls in love with the lady. He saw her, next moment they talk for a second, he leaves, reaches home, she shows up that night, they make out and they get married. All this in a span of 2 days or so. this applies to the whole of the movie. To conclude it was a mistake to watch this movie for me.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Too uneven and too long - but with great performances
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Bene Cumb
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Although the screenplay is based on the great and world-famous book by Milan Kundera, it was written by others (Jean-Claude Carri&egrave;re and the director Philip Kaufman) and thus lost its original touch and approach - as was pointed out by Kundera himself who withdrew from the outcome. On the other hand, fragile feelings, ponderings and internal doubts are very difficult to express on the screen - without losing the pace and uniformity of the plot. It is also pity that Prague was not / could not been used, as it is a beautiful city and gives more realism than the French places used. Depicion of the socialist/communist oppression is, however, rather perfunctory, seeming not so serious as it really was in the 1970ies within the Warsaw block when hopes of intellectuals for the so-called human-faced socialism vanished as liberal steps were diminished or repealed. The cast is, of course, brilliant, in particular the bohemian m&eacute;nage &agrave; trois members: Daniel Day-Lewis as Tomas, Juliette Binoche as Tereza and Lena Olin as Sabina - all later multiple Academy Award winners and/or nominees, and from different European countries (the movie itself is still the US one). They and some other fine European actors have provided the movie a real European atmosphere, without a Hollywood studio feeling as sometimes perceived in "older" movies. Nevertheless, The Unbearable Lightness of Being is still a movie high above average, enhancing historical facts as well. But it is hard to say whether is is recommendable to read the book before or after...
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Confessions of Dr. Zhivago - or Fanny and Alexander Solzhenitsyn
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    justincward
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Daniel Day-Lewis is a philandering Czech brain surgeon who goes on to marry naive medical receptionist -turned-photographer Juliet Binoche, but still can't stop chasing girls and still carries on with his soulmate Sabine because of their shared bowler (Derby) hat fetish. In the end, The Soviet Union's 1968 occupation of Czechoslovakia indirectly gives Daniel and Juliette's fragile relationship the boost it needed, only for tragedy to strike, in a 'Wages of Fear' kind of way. Yes, I did watch to the end. The dishy doctor's chat-up line is 'Tek off your cloze". Seems to work every time. That's about all that happens for the first few hours. We get a lot of shots of panties, then bottoms and bosoms, but still no real plot. It seems that Prague in 1968 was a seething hotbed of sexual experimentation. TULOB is a quality epic - big budget, big names, many locations, much period detail - but deadly pretentious. Daniel Day-Lewis's Tomasz is like Sam Malone from 'Cheers' with a very serious case of pathological narcissism. Juliette Binoche overacts terribly; were her character a real person everyone would constantly get very annoyed with her. Lena Olin puts in a believable turn as the exotic, possibly bisexual Sabine, who has a fling with a married man in a subplot that is completely pointless, something like her love affair. It's atmospheric, immersive, and reminiscent of a modern Dr. Zhivago - star-crossed lovers against the background of political upheaval with a tragic (and predictable) ending - but the supersoft-porn aspects are ridiculous; obviously done from a commercial imperative and nothing else. You could speculate that Juliet Binoche's wide-eyed character (raped by a Russian) symbolises the Czech republic's burgeoning yearning for freedom, but then the pseudo-intellectual police would be at your door in a flash. I knew the dog was doomed, and actually predicted the 'Tek off your cloze' line the third time - but that was half the fun. Well, I've gone on long enough, it's a shame nobody told the director Phil Kaufman after ninety minutes.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    poet-philosopher guy, kinda crazy, who just goes around having sex with women
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    song_jh
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/4/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I watched this movie on Korean TV, when I was about 16. It was dubbed into Korean, and I did not bother to try to understand it (English is my native language); actually I didn't even pay full attention to the video images, other than the sex scenes. Basically, it seemed to be about this (French?) poet-philosopher guy (Daniel Day Lewis), kinda crazy, who just goes around having sex with women. The sex scenes seemed pretty intense, with loud moans and shrieks by the women. The rest of the movie seemed boring with quaint European landscapes and historical cityscapes, the beauty of which a teenage boy shouldn't be expected to appreciate. Juliette Binoche was the guy's beautiful girlfriend or wife, who was always hurt by his womanizing but didn't divorce or break up with him (or did she in the end? I don't remember). I did not really understand the deep philosophy or message of the movie, if it had one.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Overrated mess
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    IlluSionS667
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/4/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Maybe it's because I'm not old enough to have witnessed life in the sixties myself, but nothing in this movie made any sense to me. The dialogs were strange and often nonsensical. People's behavior was often strange and the movie never gave any real insight into their motivations. And if there was any character development, it certainly was lost on me. I found it pretty impossible to connect with any of the main characters at all, and for a movie like this it seems pretty essential to be able to connect with at least its main characters. I hoped the movie would start making sense by the end, but unfortunately it never did. It was a total waste of almost 3 hours of my life...
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Bad
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mr_dark_eyed
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/3/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I watched this with an open mind. I loved the book (LOVED) and knew (read) that the movie wasn't a direct reflection of the book , which, given the nature and style of the book, makes sense. But what I didn't expect was how shallow and bad the 'adaptation' was. I thought that when a director decides to tackle such issues and to deal with such a great book, he would try harder, or at least be much deeper, and I thought such actors would not take part in something that bad. From the very beginning I was very unsatisfied. I thought I was watching a comedy. Something very American about the first part of the movie. The scene in the spa, the way Tomas was portrayed. Too cocky. A character with no 'weight' or even flesh. It's as though the director told Daniel 2 words to describe his role before they started shooting: You are a cocky womanizer. period. The way he was inspecting Tereza after she got out of the pool! I couldn't believe that it was actually happening. I was laughing, whereas I would be reading Kundera's deep thoughts about this chance encounter. about Fate. Did Tereza really have to pick her nose while waiting at Tomas' door for the first time? Is this really the way to show us how naive and simple she is? really, what kind of woman picks her nose while standing in front of a man she has a crush on (or any man)? And did she have to act like a dumb retarded person the whole time? Tomas.. I don't remember ever meeting someone like Tomas, in real life. He is so unconvincing. It's like a kids movie where characters are either black or white, so the little ones can tell who is good and who is evil. Can't a womanizer be more subtle? OK, he is handsome and we know he sleeps around and loves women, can you now make him a real human being, so we can buy the whole story? And what about the silly accents? Are they Czech? is that why they have accents? why are they talking in English then? If you want the audience to forget about the whole language issue, then make them speak in English and forget about the accents. Lets forget about the language and focus on the dialogue. But what's the point in making a British actor fake a strange accent in order to play a Czech character who speaks English with his Czech friends???? it only helped in keeping me aware all the time that these people are acting. Sabina's character was very irritating to me, while she was very intriguing in the book. The "Stop This Noise" scene was very bad. Franz was a character with no flesh or meat. Was he a weak character? why was he agreeing with her like that? In the book, we knew enough about him (and Sabina) so we could make sense of their relationship and interaction. But not here. It's as though the director relied on the fact that we know about the characters from the book and will fill in the gaps. That's what I was doing at least, relying on my knowledge of the characters to make sense of some scenes. I can go on... I think if you attempt to turn this unusual book into a film, then you should be able to use unusual ways to create an unusual film with unusual structure, as opposed to the conventional usual narrative and storytelling. It takes a brave daring filmmaker to deal with such book. Mr. Kaufmann is not. He belongs in Hollywood. This film proves one thing: if you base your lousy film on a great book, there's good chance you will get away with it, and even get praised for it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Excellent argument!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Nuno Duarte
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/6/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    from http://movieinthepark.blogspot.com/ The Unbearable Lightness of Being (1988) Prague, 1968. Tomas (Daneil Day-Lewis), a Czech surgeon who keeps a sexual relationship with Sabina (Lena Olin). At one point he goes to a spa to do an operation and meets Tereza (Juliette Binoche), who despite the contrast between them both, ends up marrying him. Tomas, sexually very active, used to variety in women, very proud and sophisticated sees his wife, very simple and somehow naive, not tolerating his polygamy. Meanwhile, the Russians invade Prague and they flee to Switzerland. The argument is based on Milan Kundera's book from 1984. I haven't read it but it sure leaves a certain willingness to do it. Not only because of those people that defend that the movie poisoned the book, but for the background. The first Czechoslovakia described, with its intellectuality and liberty, later called by Prague Spring, that disturbed the Communists from the Soviet Union and cause the invasion. Prague new identity is hammered and distrust, fear, perversion and resignation take its place. Besides that, the relationship between Tomas and the other two, as between Tereza and Sabina is very interesting. Then comes the big purpose of the movie that took charge of the title, the lightness of Tomas' life against what Tereza called hers, hardness. Anyway, the movie is directed by Philip Kaufman, mainly known for Indiana Jones's screenplays. I think this might be Daniel DL's best job, his performance as nothing to do with his last movies, as he adopts a calm but enthusiastic and genial surgeon. Meanwhile, I watched another movie, Haneke's La pianiste (2001), that I found so bad, futile and obscene that didn't think it deserved its own article. Anyway, do not watch it. Much better is The Unbearable Lightness of Being and this one I recommend. 9/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One view of the unbearable lightness
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    paul2001sw-1 (paul2001sw@yahoo.co.uk)
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Milan Kundera's philosophical novel 'The Unbearable Lightness of Being' was always going to be difficult to film, a story of lives lived, ordinarily, against a backdrop of politics and eroticism. Philip Kaufamn's attempt is long, has a wonderful score, chooses to have its cast speak English in eastern European accents, showcases Juliet Binoche's beauty, and I think succeeds in avoiding the heaviness, the moral weight, that the story's characters find fundamentally absent from the business of simply being alive from one moment to the next. What it doesn't quite capture is the novel's intellectual playfulness, the authorial wisdom within which the original story was set, which in the book substitutes for the enforced narrative drive of most novels. Whereas some films are best enjoyed by those who haven't seen the source material, this one might work best for those who have: otherwise, some audiences could miss the point. Nonetheless, the ending is strangely affecting and true to the original story; and Daniel Day Lewis surprisingly good as a middle class Czech philanderer.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Pretentious Rubbish With Two Redeeming Elements.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Jem Smith
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Aka My Left Testicle , aka The Unbearable Pretentiousness of a Dreadful Film. Absolutely awful . Dreadful script , comically bad acting , especially from the perpetually smug Daniel Day Lewis and his terrible mid European accent. It does though warrant 2 stars for the acres of bare flesh displayed by the equally gorgeous Lena Olin and Juliette Binoche. So don't waste 150 minutes of your life , search the net and find the 15 minutes or so of Olin and Binoche at their beautiful best. Don't waste your time on the other 135 minutes.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A lack of philosophy
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Bob Sporker
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The best thing about the novel was that the events were more meaningful because along with each event came a piece of the author's philosophy which made not only the plot seem whole but the author's main philosophical argument materialize more and more as we read on. The movie was only a documentation of the plot and because it was a movie I guess it could only "lightly" touch upon the author's philosophy. Maybe a narrator in the background could have filled us in? I watched the movie not because I enjoyed the plot but because I enjoyed reading the author's ideas about life. They weren't as evident in the movie, but I gave a 6 because the acting and cinematography were good.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not even close to what i expected
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Shr
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I actually saw the movie with a lot of expectation. The title itself was very catchy at the same time mysterious. But i have never before been this disappointed by a movie. It started out with the story of a young doctor with numerous sexual partners who falls for a meek, typical "good girl" who expects a monogamous relationship. throughout the movie what i searched for is some level of ingenuity, spontaneity or even a beautiful romance. Sorry but i didn't find any. the film itself makes no sense, mainly because there is no naturality at all, especially how he falls in love with the lady. He saw her, next moment they talk for a second, he leaves, reaches home, she shows up that night, they make out and they get married. All this in a span of 2 days or so. this applies to the whole of the movie. To conclude it was a mistake to watch this movie for me.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Too uneven and too long - but with great performances
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Bene Cumb
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Although the screenplay is based on the great and world-famous book by Milan Kundera, it was written by others (Jean-Claude Carri&egrave;re and the director Philip Kaufman) and thus lost its original touch and approach - as was pointed out by Kundera himself who withdrew from the outcome. On the other hand, fragile feelings, ponderings and internal doubts are very difficult to express on the screen - without losing the pace and uniformity of the plot. It is also pity that Prague was not / could not been used, as it is a beautiful city and gives more realism than the French places used. Depicion of the socialist/communist oppression is, however, rather perfunctory, seeming not so serious as it really was in the 1970ies within the Warsaw block when hopes of intellectuals for the so-called human-faced socialism vanished as liberal steps were diminished or repealed. The cast is, of course, brilliant, in particular the bohemian m&eacute;nage &agrave; trois members: Daniel Day-Lewis as Tomas, Juliette Binoche as Tereza and Lena Olin as Sabina - all later multiple Academy Award winners and/or nominees, and from different European countries (the movie itself is still the US one). They and some other fine European actors have provided the movie a real European atmosphere, without a Hollywood studio feeling as sometimes perceived in "older" movies. Nevertheless, The Unbearable Lightness of Being is still a movie high above average, enhancing historical facts as well. But it is hard to say whether is is recommendable to read the book before or after...
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Confessions of Dr. Zhivago - or Fanny and Alexander Solzhenitsyn
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    justincward
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Daniel Day-Lewis is a philandering Czech brain surgeon who goes on to marry naive medical receptionist -turned-photographer Juliet Binoche, but still can't stop chasing girls and still carries on with his soulmate Sabine because of their shared bowler (Derby) hat fetish. In the end, The Soviet Union's 1968 occupation of Czechoslovakia indirectly gives Daniel and Juliette's fragile relationship the boost it needed, only for tragedy to strike, in a 'Wages of Fear' kind of way. Yes, I did watch to the end. The dishy doctor's chat-up line is 'Tek off your cloze". Seems to work every time. That's about all that happens for the first few hours. We get a lot of shots of panties, then bottoms and bosoms, but still no real plot. It seems that Prague in 1968 was a seething hotbed of sexual experimentation. TULOB is a quality epic - big budget, big names, many locations, much period detail - but deadly pretentious. Daniel Day-Lewis's Tomasz is like Sam Malone from 'Cheers' with a very serious case of pathological narcissism. Juliette Binoche overacts terribly; were her character a real person everyone would constantly get very annoyed with her. Lena Olin puts in a believable turn as the exotic, possibly bisexual Sabine, who has a fling with a married man in a subplot that is completely pointless, something like her love affair. It's atmospheric, immersive, and reminiscent of a modern Dr. Zhivago - star-crossed lovers against the background of political upheaval with a tragic (and predictable) ending - but the supersoft-porn aspects are ridiculous; obviously done from a commercial imperative and nothing else. You could speculate that Juliet Binoche's wide-eyed character (raped by a Russian) symbolises the Czech republic's burgeoning yearning for freedom, but then the pseudo-intellectual police would be at your door in a flash. I knew the dog was doomed, and actually predicted the 'Tek off your cloze' line the third time - but that was half the fun. Well, I've gone on long enough, it's a shame nobody told the director Phil Kaufman after ninety minutes.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    poet-philosopher guy, kinda crazy, who just goes around having sex with women
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    song_jh
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/4/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I watched this movie on Korean TV, when I was about 16. It was dubbed into Korean, and I did not bother to try to understand it (English is my native language); actually I didn't even pay full attention to the video images, other than the sex scenes. Basically, it seemed to be about this (French?) poet-philosopher guy (Daniel Day Lewis), kinda crazy, who just goes around having sex with women. The sex scenes seemed pretty intense, with loud moans and shrieks by the women. The rest of the movie seemed boring with quaint European landscapes and historical cityscapes, the beauty of which a teenage boy shouldn't be expected to appreciate. Juliette Binoche was the guy's beautiful girlfriend or wife, who was always hurt by his womanizing but didn't divorce or break up with him (or did she in the end? I don't remember). I did not really understand the deep philosophy or message of the movie, if it had one.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Overrated mess
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    IlluSionS667
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/4/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Maybe it's because I'm not old enough to have witnessed life in the sixties myself, but nothing in this movie made any sense to me. The dialogs were strange and often nonsensical. People's behavior was often strange and the movie never gave any real insight into their motivations. And if there was any character development, it certainly was lost on me. I found it pretty impossible to connect with any of the main characters at all, and for a movie like this it seems pretty essential to be able to connect with at least its main characters. I hoped the movie would start making sense by the end, but unfortunately it never did. It was a total waste of almost 3 hours of my life...
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Bad
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mr_dark_eyed
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/3/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I watched this with an open mind. I loved the book (LOVED) and knew (read) that the movie wasn't a direct reflection of the book , which, given the nature and style of the book, makes sense. But what I didn't expect was how shallow and bad the 'adaptation' was. I thought that when a director decides to tackle such issues and to deal with such a great book, he would try harder, or at least be much deeper, and I thought such actors would not take part in something that bad. From the very beginning I was very unsatisfied. I thought I was watching a comedy. Something very American about the first part of the movie. The scene in the spa, the way Tomas was portrayed. Too cocky. A character with no 'weight' or even flesh. It's as though the director told Daniel 2 words to describe his role before they started shooting: You are a cocky womanizer. period. The way he was inspecting Tereza after she got out of the pool! I couldn't believe that it was actually happening. I was laughing, whereas I would be reading Kundera's deep thoughts about this chance encounter. about Fate. Did Tereza really have to pick her nose while waiting at Tomas' door for the first time? Is this really the way to show us how naive and simple she is? really, what kind of woman picks her nose while standing in front of a man she has a crush on (or any man)? And did she have to act like a dumb retarded person the whole time? Tomas.. I don't remember ever meeting someone like Tomas, in real life. He is so unconvincing. It's like a kids movie where characters are either black or white, so the little ones can tell who is good and who is evil. Can't a womanizer be more subtle? OK, he is handsome and we know he sleeps around and loves women, can you now make him a real human being, so we can buy the whole story? And what about the silly accents? Are they Czech? is that why they have accents? why are they talking in English then? If you want the audience to forget about the whole language issue, then make them speak in English and forget about the accents. Lets forget about the language and focus on the dialogue. But what's the point in making a British actor fake a strange accent in order to play a Czech character who speaks English with his Czech friends???? it only helped in keeping me aware all the time that these people are acting. Sabina's character was very irritating to me, while she was very intriguing in the book. The "Stop This Noise" scene was very bad. Franz was a character with no flesh or meat. Was he a weak character? why was he agreeing with her like that? In the book, we knew enough about him (and Sabina) so we could make sense of their relationship and interaction. But not here. It's as though the director relied on the fact that we know about the characters from the book and will fill in the gaps. That's what I was doing at least, relying on my knowledge of the characters to make sense of some scenes. I can go on... I think if you attempt to turn this unusual book into a film, then you should be able to use unusual ways to create an unusual film with unusual structure, as opposed to the conventional usual narrative and storytelling. It takes a brave daring filmmaker to deal with such book. Mr. Kaufmann is not. He belongs in Hollywood. This film proves one thing: if you base your lousy film on a great book, there's good chance you will get away with it, and even get praised for it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Excellent argument!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Nuno Duarte
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/6/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    from http://movieinthepark.blogspot.com/ The Unbearable Lightness of Being (1988) Prague, 1968. Tomas (Daneil Day-Lewis), a Czech surgeon who keeps a sexual relationship with Sabina (Lena Olin). At one point he goes to a spa to do an operation and meets Tereza (Juliette Binoche), who despite the contrast between them both, ends up marrying him. Tomas, sexually very active, used to variety in women, very proud and sophisticated sees his wife, very simple and somehow naive, not tolerating his polygamy. Meanwhile, the Russians invade Prague and they flee to Switzerland. The argument is based on Milan Kundera's book from 1984. I haven't read it but it sure leaves a certain willingness to do it. Not only because of those people that defend that the movie poisoned the book, but for the background. The first Czechoslovakia described, with its intellectuality and liberty, later called by Prague Spring, that disturbed the Communists from the Soviet Union and cause the invasion. Prague new identity is hammered and distrust, fear, perversion and resignation take its place. Besides that, the relationship between Tomas and the other two, as between Tereza and Sabina is very interesting. Then comes the big purpose of the movie that took charge of the title, the lightness of Tomas' life against what Tereza called hers, hardness. Anyway, the movie is directed by Philip Kaufman, mainly known for Indiana Jones's screenplays. I think this might be Daniel DL's best job, his performance as nothing to do with his last movies, as he adopts a calm but enthusiastic and genial surgeon. Meanwhile, I watched another movie, Haneke's La pianiste (2001), that I found so bad, futile and obscene that didn't think it deserved its own article. Anyway, do not watch it. Much better is The Unbearable Lightness of Being and this one I recommend. 9/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One view of the unbearable lightness
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    paul2001sw-1 (paul2001sw@yahoo.co.uk)
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Milan Kundera's philosophical novel 'The Unbearable Lightness of Being' was always going to be difficult to film, a story of lives lived, ordinarily, against a backdrop of politics and eroticism. Philip Kaufamn's attempt is long, has a wonderful score, chooses to have its cast speak English in eastern European accents, showcases Juliet Binoche's beauty, and I think succeeds in avoiding the heaviness, the moral weight, that the story's characters find fundamentally absent from the business of simply being alive from one moment to the next. What it doesn't quite capture is the novel's intellectual playfulness, the authorial wisdom within which the original story was set, which in the book substitutes for the enforced narrative drive of most novels. Whereas some films are best enjoyed by those who haven't seen the source material, this one might work best for those who have: otherwise, some audiences could miss the point. Nonetheless, the ending is strangely affecting and true to the original story; and Daniel Day Lewis surprisingly good as a middle class Czech philanderer.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Pretentious Rubbish With Two Redeeming Elements.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Jem Smith
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Aka My Left Testicle , aka The Unbearable Pretentiousness of a Dreadful Film. Absolutely awful . Dreadful script , comically bad acting , especially from the perpetually smug Daniel Day Lewis and his terrible mid European accent. It does though warrant 2 stars for the acres of bare flesh displayed by the equally gorgeous Lena Olin and Juliette Binoche. So don't waste 150 minutes of your life , search the net and find the 15 minutes or so of Olin and Binoche at their beautiful best. Don't waste your time on the other 135 minutes.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A lack of philosophy
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Bob Sporker
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The best thing about the novel was that the events were more meaningful because along with each event came a piece of the author's philosophy which made not only the plot seem whole but the author's main philosophical argument materialize more and more as we read on. The movie was only a documentation of the plot and because it was a movie I guess it could only "lightly" touch upon the author's philosophy. Maybe a narrator in the background could have filled us in? I watched the movie not because I enjoyed the plot but because I enjoyed reading the author's ideas about life. They weren't as evident in the movie, but I gave a 6 because the acting and cinematography were good.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not even close to what i expected
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Shr
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I actually saw the movie with a lot of expectation. The title itself was very catchy at the same time mysterious. But i have never before been this disappointed by a movie. It started out with the story of a young doctor with numerous sexual partners who falls for a meek, typical "good girl" who expects a monogamous relationship. throughout the movie what i searched for is some level of ingenuity, spontaneity or even a beautiful romance. Sorry but i didn't find any. the film itself makes no sense, mainly because there is no naturality at all, especially how he falls in love with the lady. He saw her, next moment they talk for a second, he leaves, reaches home, she shows up that night, they make out and they get married. All this in a span of 2 days or so. this applies to the whole of the movie. To conclude it was a mistake to watch this movie for me.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Too uneven and too long - but with great performances
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Bene Cumb
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Although the screenplay is based on the great and world-famous book by Milan Kundera, it was written by others (Jean-Claude Carri&egrave;re and the director Philip Kaufman) and thus lost its original touch and approach - as was pointed out by Kundera himself who withdrew from the outcome. On the other hand, fragile feelings, ponderings and internal doubts are very difficult to express on the screen - without losing the pace and uniformity of the plot. It is also pity that Prague was not / could not been used, as it is a beautiful city and gives more realism than the French places used. Depicion of the socialist/communist oppression is, however, rather perfunctory, seeming not so serious as it really was in the 1970ies within the Warsaw block when hopes of intellectuals for the so-called human-faced socialism vanished as liberal steps were diminished or repealed. The cast is, of course, brilliant, in particular the bohemian m&eacute;nage &agrave; trois members: Daniel Day-Lewis as Tomas, Juliette Binoche as Tereza and Lena Olin as Sabina - all later multiple Academy Award winners and/or nominees, and from different European countries (the movie itself is still the US one). They and some other fine European actors have provided the movie a real European atmosphere, without a Hollywood studio feeling as sometimes perceived in "older" movies. Nevertheless, The Unbearable Lightness of Being is still a movie high above average, enhancing historical facts as well. But it is hard to say whether is is recommendable to read the book before or after...
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Confessions of Dr. Zhivago - or Fanny and Alexander Solzhenitsyn
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    justincward
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Daniel Day-Lewis is a philandering Czech brain surgeon who goes on to marry naive medical receptionist -turned-photographer Juliet Binoche, but still can't stop chasing girls and still carries on with his soulmate Sabine because of their shared bowler (Derby) hat fetish. In the end, The Soviet Union's 1968 occupation of Czechoslovakia indirectly gives Daniel and Juliette's fragile relationship the boost it needed, only for tragedy to strike, in a 'Wages of Fear' kind of way. Yes, I did watch to the end. The dishy doctor's chat-up line is 'Tek off your cloze". Seems to work every time. That's about all that happens for the first few hours. We get a lot of shots of panties, then bottoms and bosoms, but still no real plot. It seems that Prague in 1968 was a seething hotbed of sexual experimentation. TULOB is a quality epic - big budget, big names, many locations, much period detail - but deadly pretentious. Daniel Day-Lewis's Tomasz is like Sam Malone from 'Cheers' with a very serious case of pathological narcissism. Juliette Binoche overacts terribly; were her character a real person everyone would constantly get very annoyed with her. Lena Olin puts in a believable turn as the exotic, possibly bisexual Sabine, who has a fling with a married man in a subplot that is completely pointless, something like her love affair. It's atmospheric, immersive, and reminiscent of a modern Dr. Zhivago - star-crossed lovers against the background of political upheaval with a tragic (and predictable) ending - but the supersoft-porn aspects are ridiculous; obviously done from a commercial imperative and nothing else. You could speculate that Juliet Binoche's wide-eyed character (raped by a Russian) symbolises the Czech republic's burgeoning yearning for freedom, but then the pseudo-intellectual police would be at your door in a flash. I knew the dog was doomed, and actually predicted the 'Tek off your cloze' line the third time - but that was half the fun. Well, I've gone on long enough, it's a shame nobody told the director Phil Kaufman after ninety minutes.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    poet-philosopher guy, kinda crazy, who just goes around having sex with women
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    song_jh
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/4/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I watched this movie on Korean TV, when I was about 16. It was dubbed into Korean, and I did not bother to try to understand it (English is my native language); actually I didn't even pay full attention to the video images, other than the sex scenes. Basically, it seemed to be about this (French?) poet-philosopher guy (Daniel Day Lewis), kinda crazy, who just goes around having sex with women. The sex scenes seemed pretty intense, with loud moans and shrieks by the women. The rest of the movie seemed boring with quaint European landscapes and historical cityscapes, the beauty of which a teenage boy shouldn't be expected to appreciate. Juliette Binoche was the guy's beautiful girlfriend or wife, who was always hurt by his womanizing but didn't divorce or break up with him (or did she in the end? I don't remember). I did not really understand the deep philosophy or message of the movie, if it had one.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Overrated mess
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    IlluSionS667
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/4/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Maybe it's because I'm not old enough to have witnessed life in the sixties myself, but nothing in this movie made any sense to me. The dialogs were strange and often nonsensical. People's behavior was often strange and the movie never gave any real insight into their motivations. And if there was any character development, it certainly was lost on me. I found it pretty impossible to connect with any of the main characters at all, and for a movie like this it seems pretty essential to be able to connect with at least its main characters. I hoped the movie would start making sense by the end, but unfortunately it never did. It was a total waste of almost 3 hours of my life...
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Bad
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mr_dark_eyed
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/3/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I watched this with an open mind. I loved the book (LOVED) and knew (read) that the movie wasn't a direct reflection of the book , which, given the nature and style of the book, makes sense. But what I didn't expect was how shallow and bad the 'adaptation' was. I thought that when a director decides to tackle such issues and to deal with such a great book, he would try harder, or at least be much deeper, and I thought such actors would not take part in something that bad. From the very beginning I was very unsatisfied. I thought I was watching a comedy. Something very American about the first part of the movie. The scene in the spa, the way Tomas was portrayed. Too cocky. A character with no 'weight' or even flesh. It's as though the director told Daniel 2 words to describe his role before they started shooting: You are a cocky womanizer. period. The way he was inspecting Tereza after she got out of the pool! I couldn't believe that it was actually happening. I was laughing, whereas I would be reading Kundera's deep thoughts about this chance encounter. about Fate. Did Tereza really have to pick her nose while waiting at Tomas' door for the first time? Is this really the way to show us how naive and simple she is? really, what kind of woman picks her nose while standing in front of a man she has a crush on (or any man)? And did she have to act like a dumb retarded person the whole time? Tomas.. I don't remember ever meeting someone like Tomas, in real life. He is so unconvincing. It's like a kids movie where characters are either black or white, so the little ones can tell who is good and who is evil. Can't a womanizer be more subtle? OK, he is handsome and we know he sleeps around and loves women, can you now make him a real human being, so we can buy the whole story? And what about the silly accents? Are they Czech? is that why they have accents? why are they talking in English then? If you want the audience to forget about the whole language issue, then make them speak in English and forget about the accents. Lets forget about the language and focus on the dialogue. But what's the point in making a British actor fake a strange accent in order to play a Czech character who speaks English with his Czech friends???? it only helped in keeping me aware all the time that these people are acting. Sabina's character was very irritating to me, while she was very intriguing in the book. The "Stop This Noise" scene was very bad. Franz was a character with no flesh or meat. Was he a weak character? why was he agreeing with her like that? In the book, we knew enough about him (and Sabina) so we could make sense of their relationship and interaction. But not here. It's as though the director relied on the fact that we know about the characters from the book and will fill in the gaps. That's what I was doing at least, relying on my knowledge of the characters to make sense of some scenes. I can go on... I think if you attempt to turn this unusual book into a film, then you should be able to use unusual ways to create an unusual film with unusual structure, as opposed to the conventional usual narrative and storytelling. It takes a brave daring filmmaker to deal with such book. Mr. Kaufmann is not. He belongs in Hollywood. This film proves one thing: if you base your lousy film on a great book, there's good chance you will get away with it, and even get praised for it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Excellent argument!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Nuno Duarte
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/6/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    from http://movieinthepark.blogspot.com/ The Unbearable Lightness of Being (1988) Prague, 1968. Tomas (Daneil Day-Lewis), a Czech surgeon who keeps a sexual relationship with Sabina (Lena Olin). At one point he goes to a spa to do an operation and meets Tereza (Juliette Binoche), who despite the contrast between them both, ends up marrying him. Tomas, sexually very active, used to variety in women, very proud and sophisticated sees his wife, very simple and somehow naive, not tolerating his polygamy. Meanwhile, the Russians invade Prague and they flee to Switzerland. The argument is based on Milan Kundera's book from 1984. I haven't read it but it sure leaves a certain willingness to do it. Not only because of those people that defend that the movie poisoned the book, but for the background. The first Czechoslovakia described, with its intellectuality and liberty, later called by Prague Spring, that disturbed the Communists from the Soviet Union and cause the invasion. Prague new identity is hammered and distrust, fear, perversion and resignation take its place. Besides that, the relationship between Tomas and the other two, as between Tereza and Sabina is very interesting. Then comes the big purpose of the movie that took charge of the title, the lightness of Tomas' life against what Tereza called hers, hardness. Anyway, the movie is directed by Philip Kaufman, mainly known for Indiana Jones's screenplays. I think this might be Daniel DL's best job, his performance as nothing to do with his last movies, as he adopts a calm but enthusiastic and genial surgeon. Meanwhile, I watched another movie, Haneke's La pianiste (2001), that I found so bad, futile and obscene that didn't think it deserved its own article. Anyway, do not watch it. Much better is The Unbearable Lightness of Being and this one I recommend. 9/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One view of the unbearable lightness
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    paul2001sw-1 (paul2001sw@yahoo.co.uk)
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Milan Kundera's philosophical novel 'The Unbearable Lightness of Being' was always going to be difficult to film, a story of lives lived, ordinarily, against a backdrop of politics and eroticism. Philip Kaufamn's attempt is long, has a wonderful score, chooses to have its cast speak English in eastern European accents, showcases Juliet Binoche's beauty, and I think succeeds in avoiding the heaviness, the moral weight, that the story's characters find fundamentally absent from the business of simply being alive from one moment to the next. What it doesn't quite capture is the novel's intellectual playfulness, the authorial wisdom within which the original story was set, which in the book substitutes for the enforced narrative drive of most novels. Whereas some films are best enjoyed by those who haven't seen the source material, this one might work best for those who have: otherwise, some audiences could miss the point. Nonetheless, the ending is strangely affecting and true to the original story; and Daniel Day Lewis surprisingly good as a middle class Czech philanderer.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Pretentious Rubbish With Two Redeeming Elements.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Jem Smith
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Aka My Left Testicle , aka The Unbearable Pretentiousness of a Dreadful Film. Absolutely awful . Dreadful script , comically bad acting , especially from the perpetually smug Daniel Day Lewis and his terrible mid European accent. It does though warrant 2 stars for the acres of bare flesh displayed by the equally gorgeous Lena Olin and Juliette Binoche. So don't waste 150 minutes of your life , search the net and find the 15 minutes or so of Olin and Binoche at their beautiful best. Don't waste your time on the other 135 minutes.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A lack of philosophy
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Bob Sporker
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The best thing about the novel was that the events were more meaningful because along with each event came a piece of the author's philosophy which made not only the plot seem whole but the author's main philosophical argument materialize more and more as we read on. The movie was only a documentation of the plot and because it was a movie I guess it could only "lightly" touch upon the author's philosophy. Maybe a narrator in the background could have filled us in? I watched the movie not because I enjoyed the plot but because I enjoyed reading the author's ideas about life. They weren't as evident in the movie, but I gave a 6 because the acting and cinematography were good.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not even close to what i expected
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Shr
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I actually saw the movie with a lot of expectation. The title itself was very catchy at the same time mysterious. But i have never before been this disappointed by a movie. It started out with the story of a young doctor with numerous sexual partners who falls for a meek, typical "good girl" who expects a monogamous relationship. throughout the movie what i searched for is some level of ingenuity, spontaneity or even a beautiful romance. Sorry but i didn't find any. the film itself makes no sense, mainly because there is no naturality at all, especially how he falls in love with the lady. He saw her, next moment they talk for a second, he leaves, reaches home, she shows up that night, they make out and they get married. All this in a span of 2 days or so. this applies to the whole of the movie. To conclude it was a mistake to watch this movie for me.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Too uneven and too long - but with great performances
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Bene Cumb
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Although the screenplay is based on the great and world-famous book by Milan Kundera, it was written by others (Jean-Claude Carri&egrave;re and the director Philip Kaufman) and thus lost its original touch and approach - as was pointed out by Kundera himself who withdrew from the outcome. On the other hand, fragile feelings, ponderings and internal doubts are very difficult to express on the screen - without losing the pace and uniformity of the plot. It is also pity that Prague was not / could not been used, as it is a beautiful city and gives more realism than the French places used. Depicion of the socialist/communist oppression is, however, rather perfunctory, seeming not so serious as it really was in the 1970ies within the Warsaw block when hopes of intellectuals for the so-called human-faced socialism vanished as liberal steps were diminished or repealed. The cast is, of course, brilliant, in particular the bohemian m&eacute;nage &agrave; trois members: Daniel Day-Lewis as Tomas, Juliette Binoche as Tereza and Lena Olin as Sabina - all later multiple Academy Award winners and/or nominees, and from different European countries (the movie itself is still the US one). They and some other fine European actors have provided the movie a real European atmosphere, without a Hollywood studio feeling as sometimes perceived in "older" movies. Nevertheless, The Unbearable Lightness of Being is still a movie high above average, enhancing historical facts as well. But it is hard to say whether is is recommendable to read the book before or after...
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Confessions of Dr. Zhivago - or Fanny and Alexander Solzhenitsyn
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    justincward
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Daniel Day-Lewis is a philandering Czech brain surgeon who goes on to marry naive medical receptionist -turned-photographer Juliet Binoche, but still can't stop chasing girls and still carries on with his soulmate Sabine because of their shared bowler (Derby) hat fetish. In the end, The Soviet Union's 1968 occupation of Czechoslovakia indirectly gives Daniel and Juliette's fragile relationship the boost it needed, only for tragedy to strike, in a 'Wages of Fear' kind of way. Yes, I did watch to the end. The dishy doctor's chat-up line is 'Tek off your cloze". Seems to work every time. That's about all that happens for the first few hours. We get a lot of shots of panties, then bottoms and bosoms, but still no real plot. It seems that Prague in 1968 was a seething hotbed of sexual experimentation. TULOB is a quality epic - big budget, big names, many locations, much period detail - but deadly pretentious. Daniel Day-Lewis's Tomasz is like Sam Malone from 'Cheers' with a very serious case of pathological narcissism. Juliette Binoche overacts terribly; were her character a real person everyone would constantly get very annoyed with her. Lena Olin puts in a believable turn as the exotic, possibly bisexual Sabine, who has a fling with a married man in a subplot that is completely pointless, something like her love affair. It's atmospheric, immersive, and reminiscent of a modern Dr. Zhivago - star-crossed lovers against the background of political upheaval with a tragic (and predictable) ending - but the supersoft-porn aspects are ridiculous; obviously done from a commercial imperative and nothing else. You could speculate that Juliet Binoche's wide-eyed character (raped by a Russian) symbolises the Czech republic's burgeoning yearning for freedom, but then the pseudo-intellectual police would be at your door in a flash. I knew the dog was doomed, and actually predicted the 'Tek off your cloze' line the third time - but that was half the fun. Well, I've gone on long enough, it's a shame nobody told the director Phil Kaufman after ninety minutes.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    poet-philosopher guy, kinda crazy, who just goes around having sex with women
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    song_jh
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/4/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I watched this movie on Korean TV, when I was about 16. It was dubbed into Korean, and I did not bother to try to understand it (English is my native language); actually I didn't even pay full attention to the video images, other than the sex scenes. Basically, it seemed to be about this (French?) poet-philosopher guy (Daniel Day Lewis), kinda crazy, who just goes around having sex with women. The sex scenes seemed pretty intense, with loud moans and shrieks by the women. The rest of the movie seemed boring with quaint European landscapes and historical cityscapes, the beauty of which a teenage boy shouldn't be expected to appreciate. Juliette Binoche was the guy's beautiful girlfriend or wife, who was always hurt by his womanizing but didn't divorce or break up with him (or did she in the end? I don't remember). I did not really understand the deep philosophy or message of the movie, if it had one.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Overrated mess
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    IlluSionS667
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/4/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Maybe it's because I'm not old enough to have witnessed life in the sixties myself, but nothing in this movie made any sense to me. The dialogs were strange and often nonsensical. People's behavior was often strange and the movie never gave any real insight into their motivations. And if there was any character development, it certainly was lost on me. I found it pretty impossible to connect with any of the main characters at all, and for a movie like this it seems pretty essential to be able to connect with at least its main characters. I hoped the movie would start making sense by the end, but unfortunately it never did. It was a total waste of almost 3 hours of my life...
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Bad
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mr_dark_eyed
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/3/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I watched this with an open mind. I loved the book (LOVED) and knew (read) that the movie wasn't a direct reflection of the book , which, given the nature and style of the book, makes sense. But what I didn't expect was how shallow and bad the 'adaptation' was. I thought that when a director decides to tackle such issues and to deal with such a great book, he would try harder, or at least be much deeper, and I thought such actors would not take part in something that bad. From the very beginning I was very unsatisfied. I thought I was watching a comedy. Something very American about the first part of the movie. The scene in the spa, the way Tomas was portrayed. Too cocky. A character with no 'weight' or even flesh. It's as though the director told Daniel 2 words to describe his role before they started shooting: You are a cocky womanizer. period. The way he was inspecting Tereza after she got out of the pool! I couldn't believe that it was actually happening. I was laughing, whereas I would be reading Kundera's deep thoughts about this chance encounter. about Fate. Did Tereza really have to pick her nose while waiting at Tomas' door for the first time? Is this really the way to show us how naive and simple she is? really, what kind of woman picks her nose while standing in front of a man she has a crush on (or any man)? And did she have to act like a dumb retarded person the whole time? Tomas.. I don't remember ever meeting someone like Tomas, in real life. He is so unconvincing. It's like a kids movie where characters are either black or white, so the little ones can tell who is good and who is evil. Can't a womanizer be more subtle? OK, he is handsome and we know he sleeps around and loves women, can you now make him a real human being, so we can buy the whole story? And what about the silly accents? Are they Czech? is that why they have accents? why are they talking in English then? If you want the audience to forget about the whole language issue, then make them speak in English and forget about the accents. Lets forget about the language and focus on the dialogue. But what's the point in making a British actor fake a strange accent in order to play a Czech character who speaks English with his Czech friends???? it only helped in keeping me aware all the time that these people are acting. Sabina's character was very irritating to me, while she was very intriguing in the book. The "Stop This Noise" scene was very bad. Franz was a character with no flesh or meat. Was he a weak character? why was he agreeing with her like that? In the book, we knew enough about him (and Sabina) so we could make sense of their relationship and interaction. But not here. It's as though the director relied on the fact that we know about the characters from the book and will fill in the gaps. That's what I was doing at least, relying on my knowledge of the characters to make sense of some scenes. I can go on... I think if you attempt to turn this unusual book into a film, then you should be able to use unusual ways to create an unusual film with unusual structure, as opposed to the conventional usual narrative and storytelling. It takes a brave daring filmmaker to deal with such book. Mr. Kaufmann is not. He belongs in Hollywood. This film proves one thing: if you base your lousy film on a great book, there's good chance you will get away with it, and even get praised for it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Excellent argument!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Nuno Duarte
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/6/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    from http://movieinthepark.blogspot.com/ The Unbearable Lightness of Being (1988) Prague, 1968. Tomas (Daneil Day-Lewis), a Czech surgeon who keeps a sexual relationship with Sabina (Lena Olin). At one point he goes to a spa to do an operation and meets Tereza (Juliette Binoche), who despite the contrast between them both, ends up marrying him. Tomas, sexually very active, used to variety in women, very proud and sophisticated sees his wife, very simple and somehow naive, not tolerating his polygamy. Meanwhile, the Russians invade Prague and they flee to Switzerland. The argument is based on Milan Kundera's book from 1984. I haven't read it but it sure leaves a certain willingness to do it. Not only because of those people that defend that the movie poisoned the book, but for the background. The first Czechoslovakia described, with its intellectuality and liberty, later called by Prague Spring, that disturbed the Communists from the Soviet Union and cause the invasion. Prague new identity is hammered and distrust, fear, perversion and resignation take its place. Besides that, the relationship between Tomas and the other two, as between Tereza and Sabina is very interesting. Then comes the big purpose of the movie that took charge of the title, the lightness of Tomas' life against what Tereza called hers, hardness. Anyway, the movie is directed by Philip Kaufman, mainly known for Indiana Jones's screenplays. I think this might be Daniel DL's best job, his performance as nothing to do with his last movies, as he adopts a calm but enthusiastic and genial surgeon. Meanwhile, I watched another movie, Haneke's La pianiste (2001), that I found so bad, futile and obscene that didn't think it deserved its own article. Anyway, do not watch it. Much better is The Unbearable Lightness of Being and this one I recommend. 9/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One view of the unbearable lightness
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    paul2001sw-1 (paul2001sw@yahoo.co.uk)
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Milan Kundera's philosophical novel 'The Unbearable Lightness of Being' was always going to be difficult to film, a story of lives lived, ordinarily, against a backdrop of politics and eroticism. Philip Kaufamn's attempt is long, has a wonderful score, chooses to have its cast speak English in eastern European accents, showcases Juliet Binoche's beauty, and I think succeeds in avoiding the heaviness, the moral weight, that the story's characters find fundamentally absent from the business of simply being alive from one moment to the next. What it doesn't quite capture is the novel's intellectual playfulness, the authorial wisdom within which the original story was set, which in the book substitutes for the enforced narrative drive of most novels. Whereas some films are best enjoyed by those who haven't seen the source material, this one might work best for those who have: otherwise, some audiences could miss the point. Nonetheless, the ending is strangely affecting and true to the original story; and Daniel Day Lewis surprisingly good as a middle class Czech philanderer.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Pretentious Rubbish With Two Redeeming Elements.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Jem Smith
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Aka My Left Testicle , aka The Unbearable Pretentiousness of a Dreadful Film. Absolutely awful . Dreadful script , comically bad acting , especially from the perpetually smug Daniel Day Lewis and his terrible mid European accent. It does though warrant 2 stars for the acres of bare flesh displayed by the equally gorgeous Lena Olin and Juliette Binoche. So don't waste 150 minutes of your life , search the net and find the 15 minutes or so of Olin and Binoche at their beautiful best. Don't waste your time on the other 135 minutes.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A lack of philosophy
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Bob Sporker
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The best thing about the novel was that the events were more meaningful because along with each event came a piece of the author's philosophy which made not only the plot seem whole but the author's main philosophical argument materialize more and more as we read on. The movie was only a documentation of the plot and because it was a movie I guess it could only "lightly" touch upon the author's philosophy. Maybe a narrator in the background could have filled us in? I watched the movie not because I enjoyed the plot but because I enjoyed reading the author's ideas about life. They weren't as evident in the movie, but I gave a 6 because the acting and cinematography were good.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not even close to what i expected
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Shr
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I actually saw the movie with a lot of expectation. The title itself was very catchy at the same time mysterious. But i have never before been this disappointed by a movie. It started out with the story of a young doctor with numerous sexual partners who falls for a meek, typical "good girl" who expects a monogamous relationship. throughout the movie what i searched for is some level of ingenuity, spontaneity or even a beautiful romance. Sorry but i didn't find any. the film itself makes no sense, mainly because there is no naturality at all, especially how he falls in love with the lady. He saw her, next moment they talk for a second, he leaves, reaches home, she shows up that night, they make out and they get married. All this in a span of 2 days or so. this applies to the whole of the movie. To conclude it was a mistake to watch this movie for me.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Too uneven and too long - but with great performances
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Bene Cumb
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Although the screenplay is based on the great and world-famous book by Milan Kundera, it was written by others (Jean-Claude Carri&egrave;re and the director Philip Kaufman) and thus lost its original touch and approach - as was pointed out by Kundera himself who withdrew from the outcome. On the other hand, fragile feelings, ponderings and internal doubts are very difficult to express on the screen - without losing the pace and uniformity of the plot. It is also pity that Prague was not / could not been used, as it is a beautiful city and gives more realism than the French places used. Depicion of the socialist/communist oppression is, however, rather perfunctory, seeming not so serious as it really was in the 1970ies within the Warsaw block when hopes of intellectuals for the so-called human-faced socialism vanished as liberal steps were diminished or repealed. The cast is, of course, brilliant, in particular the bohemian m&eacute;nage &agrave; trois members: Daniel Day-Lewis as Tomas, Juliette Binoche as Tereza and Lena Olin as Sabina - all later multiple Academy Award winners and/or nominees, and from different European countries (the movie itself is still the US one). They and some other fine European actors have provided the movie a real European atmosphere, without a Hollywood studio feeling as sometimes perceived in "older" movies. Nevertheless, The Unbearable Lightness of Being is still a movie high above average, enhancing historical facts as well. But it is hard to say whether is is recommendable to read the book before or after...
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Confessions of Dr. Zhivago - or Fanny and Alexander Solzhenitsyn
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    justincward
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Daniel Day-Lewis is a philandering Czech brain surgeon who goes on to marry naive medical receptionist -turned-photographer Juliet Binoche, but still can't stop chasing girls and still carries on with his soulmate Sabine because of their shared bowler (Derby) hat fetish. In the end, The Soviet Union's 1968 occupation of Czechoslovakia indirectly gives Daniel and Juliette's fragile relationship the boost it needed, only for tragedy to strike, in a 'Wages of Fear' kind of way. Yes, I did watch to the end. The dishy doctor's chat-up line is 'Tek off your cloze". Seems to work every time. That's about all that happens for the first few hours. We get a lot of shots of panties, then bottoms and bosoms, but still no real plot. It seems that Prague in 1968 was a seething hotbed of sexual experimentation. TULOB is a quality epic - big budget, big names, many locations, much period detail - but deadly pretentious. Daniel Day-Lewis's Tomasz is like Sam Malone from 'Cheers' with a very serious case of pathological narcissism. Juliette Binoche overacts terribly; were her character a real person everyone would constantly get very annoyed with her. Lena Olin puts in a believable turn as the exotic, possibly bisexual Sabine, who has a fling with a married man in a subplot that is completely pointless, something like her love affair. It's atmospheric, immersive, and reminiscent of a modern Dr. Zhivago - star-crossed lovers against the background of political upheaval with a tragic (and predictable) ending - but the supersoft-porn aspects are ridiculous; obviously done from a commercial imperative and nothing else. You could speculate that Juliet Binoche's wide-eyed character (raped by a Russian) symbolises the Czech republic's burgeoning yearning for freedom, but then the pseudo-intellectual police would be at your door in a flash. I knew the dog was doomed, and actually predicted the 'Tek off your cloze' line the third time - but that was half the fun. Well, I've gone on long enough, it's a shame nobody told the director Phil Kaufman after ninety minutes.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    poet-philosopher guy, kinda crazy, who just goes around having sex with women
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    song_jh
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/4/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I watched this movie on Korean TV, when I was about 16. It was dubbed into Korean, and I did not bother to try to understand it (English is my native language); actually I didn't even pay full attention to the video images, other than the sex scenes. Basically, it seemed to be about this (French?) poet-philosopher guy (Daniel Day Lewis), kinda crazy, who just goes around having sex with women. The sex scenes seemed pretty intense, with loud moans and shrieks by the women. The rest of the movie seemed boring with quaint European landscapes and historical cityscapes, the beauty of which a teenage boy shouldn't be expected to appreciate. Juliette Binoche was the guy's beautiful girlfriend or wife, who was always hurt by his womanizing but didn't divorce or break up with him (or did she in the end? I don't remember). I did not really understand the deep philosophy or message of the movie, if it had one.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Overrated mess
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    IlluSionS667
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/4/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Maybe it's because I'm not old enough to have witnessed life in the sixties myself, but nothing in this movie made any sense to me. The dialogs were strange and often nonsensical. People's behavior was often strange and the movie never gave any real insight into their motivations. And if there was any character development, it certainly was lost on me. I found it pretty impossible to connect with any of the main characters at all, and for a movie like this it seems pretty essential to be able to connect with at least its main characters. I hoped the movie would start making sense by the end, but unfortunately it never did. It was a total waste of almost 3 hours of my life...
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Bad
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mr_dark_eyed
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/3/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I watched this with an open mind. I loved the book (LOVED) and knew (read) that the movie wasn't a direct reflection of the book , which, given the nature and style of the book, makes sense. But what I didn't expect was how shallow and bad the 'adaptation' was. I thought that when a director decides to tackle such issues and to deal with such a great book, he would try harder, or at least be much deeper, and I thought such actors would not take part in something that bad. From the very beginning I was very unsatisfied. I thought I was watching a comedy. Something very American about the first part of the movie. The scene in the spa, the way Tomas was portrayed. Too cocky. A character with no 'weight' or even flesh. It's as though the director told Daniel 2 words to describe his role before they started shooting: You are a cocky womanizer. period. The way he was inspecting Tereza after she got out of the pool! I couldn't believe that it was actually happening. I was laughing, whereas I would be reading Kundera's deep thoughts about this chance encounter. about Fate. Did Tereza really have to pick her nose while waiting at Tomas' door for the first time? Is this really the way to show us how naive and simple she is? really, what kind of woman picks her nose while standing in front of a man she has a crush on (or any man)? And did she have to act like a dumb retarded person the whole time? Tomas.. I don't remember ever meeting someone like Tomas, in real life. He is so unconvincing. It's like a kids movie where characters are either black or white, so the little ones can tell who is good and who is evil. Can't a womanizer be more subtle? OK, he is handsome and we know he sleeps around and loves women, can you now make him a real human being, so we can buy the whole story? And what about the silly accents? Are they Czech? is that why they have accents? why are they talking in English then? If you want the audience to forget about the whole language issue, then make them speak in English and forget about the accents. Lets forget about the language and focus on the dialogue. But what's the point in making a British actor fake a strange accent in order to play a Czech character who speaks English with his Czech friends???? it only helped in keeping me aware all the time that these people are acting. Sabina's character was very irritating to me, while she was very intriguing in the book. The "Stop This Noise" scene was very bad. Franz was a character with no flesh or meat. Was he a weak character? why was he agreeing with her like that? In the book, we knew enough about him (and Sabina) so we could make sense of their relationship and interaction. But not here. It's as though the director relied on the fact that we know about the characters from the book and will fill in the gaps. That's what I was doing at least, relying on my knowledge of the characters to make sense of some scenes. I can go on... I think if you attempt to turn this unusual book into a film, then you should be able to use unusual ways to create an unusual film with unusual structure, as opposed to the conventional usual narrative and storytelling. It takes a brave daring filmmaker to deal with such book. Mr. Kaufmann is not. He belongs in Hollywood. This film proves one thing: if you base your lousy film on a great book, there's good chance you will get away with it, and even get praised for it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Excellent argument!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Nuno Duarte
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/6/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    from http://movieinthepark.blogspot.com/ The Unbearable Lightness of Being (1988) Prague, 1968. Tomas (Daneil Day-Lewis), a Czech surgeon who keeps a sexual relationship with Sabina (Lena Olin). At one point he goes to a spa to do an operation and meets Tereza (Juliette Binoche), who despite the contrast between them both, ends up marrying him. Tomas, sexually very active, used to variety in women, very proud and sophisticated sees his wife, very simple and somehow naive, not tolerating his polygamy. Meanwhile, the Russians invade Prague and they flee to Switzerland. The argument is based on Milan Kundera's book from 1984. I haven't read it but it sure leaves a certain willingness to do it. Not only because of those people that defend that the movie poisoned the book, but for the background. The first Czechoslovakia described, with its intellectuality and liberty, later called by Prague Spring, that disturbed the Communists from the Soviet Union and cause the invasion. Prague new identity is hammered and distrust, fear, perversion and resignation take its place. Besides that, the relationship between Tomas and the other two, as between Tereza and Sabina is very interesting. Then comes the big purpose of the movie that took charge of the title, the lightness of Tomas' life against what Tereza called hers, hardness. Anyway, the movie is directed by Philip Kaufman, mainly known for Indiana Jones's screenplays. I think this might be Daniel DL's best job, his performance as nothing to do with his last movies, as he adopts a calm but enthusiastic and genial surgeon. Meanwhile, I watched another movie, Haneke's La pianiste (2001), that I found so bad, futile and obscene that didn't think it deserved its own article. Anyway, do not watch it. Much better is The Unbearable Lightness of Being and this one I recommend. 9/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One view of the unbearable lightness
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    paul2001sw-1 (paul2001sw@yahoo.co.uk)
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Milan Kundera's philosophical novel 'The Unbearable Lightness of Being' was always going to be difficult to film, a story of lives lived, ordinarily, against a backdrop of politics and eroticism. Philip Kaufamn's attempt is long, has a wonderful score, chooses to have its cast speak English in eastern European accents, showcases Juliet Binoche's beauty, and I think succeeds in avoiding the heaviness, the moral weight, that the story's characters find fundamentally absent from the business of simply being alive from one moment to the next. What it doesn't quite capture is the novel's intellectual playfulness, the authorial wisdom within which the original story was set, which in the book substitutes for the enforced narrative drive of most novels. Whereas some films are best enjoyed by those who haven't seen the source material, this one might work best for those who have: otherwise, some audiences could miss the point. Nonetheless, the ending is strangely affecting and true to the original story; and Daniel Day Lewis surprisingly good as a middle class Czech philanderer.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Pretentious Rubbish With Two Redeeming Elements.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Jem Smith
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Aka My Left Testicle , aka The Unbearable Pretentiousness of a Dreadful Film. Absolutely awful . Dreadful script , comically bad acting , especially from the perpetually smug Daniel Day Lewis and his terrible mid European accent. It does though warrant 2 stars for the acres of bare flesh displayed by the equally gorgeous Lena Olin and Juliette Binoche. So don't waste 150 minutes of your life , search the net and find the 15 minutes or so of Olin and Binoche at their beautiful best. Don't waste your time on the other 135 minutes.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A lack of philosophy
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Bob Sporker
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The best thing about the novel was that the events were more meaningful because along with each event came a piece of the author's philosophy which made not only the plot seem whole but the author's main philosophical argument materialize more and more as we read on. The movie was only a documentation of the plot and because it was a movie I guess it could only "lightly" touch upon the author's philosophy. Maybe a narrator in the background could have filled us in? I watched the movie not because I enjoyed the plot but because I enjoyed reading the author's ideas about life. They weren't as evident in the movie, but I gave a 6 because the acting and cinematography were good.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not even close to what i expected
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Shr
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I actually saw the movie with a lot of expectation. The title itself was very catchy at the same time mysterious. But i have never before been this disappointed by a movie. It started out with the story of a young doctor with numerous sexual partners who falls for a meek, typical "good girl" who expects a monogamous relationship. throughout the movie what i searched for is some level of ingenuity, spontaneity or even a beautiful romance. Sorry but i didn't find any. the film itself makes no sense, mainly because there is no naturality at all, especially how he falls in love with the lady. He saw her, next moment they talk for a second, he leaves, reaches home, she shows up that night, they make out and they get married. All this in a span of 2 days or so. this applies to the whole of the movie. To conclude it was a mistake to watch this movie for me.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Too uneven and too long - but with great performances
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Bene Cumb
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Although the screenplay is based on the great and world-famous book by Milan Kundera, it was written by others (Jean-Claude Carri&egrave;re and the director Philip Kaufman) and thus lost its original touch and approach - as was pointed out by Kundera himself who withdrew from the outcome. On the other hand, fragile feelings, ponderings and internal doubts are very difficult to express on the screen - without losing the pace and uniformity of the plot. It is also pity that Prague was not / could not been used, as it is a beautiful city and gives more realism than the French places used. Depicion of the socialist/communist oppression is, however, rather perfunctory, seeming not so serious as it really was in the 1970ies within the Warsaw block when hopes of intellectuals for the so-called human-faced socialism vanished as liberal steps were diminished or repealed. The cast is, of course, brilliant, in particular the bohemian m&eacute;nage &agrave; trois members: Daniel Day-Lewis as Tomas, Juliette Binoche as Tereza and Lena Olin as Sabina - all later multiple Academy Award winners and/or nominees, and from different European countries (the movie itself is still the US one). They and some other fine European actors have provided the movie a real European atmosphere, without a Hollywood studio feeling as sometimes perceived in "older" movies. Nevertheless, The Unbearable Lightness of Being is still a movie high above average, enhancing historical facts as well. But it is hard to say whether is is recommendable to read the book before or after...
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Confessions of Dr. Zhivago - or Fanny and Alexander Solzhenitsyn
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    justincward
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Daniel Day-Lewis is a philandering Czech brain surgeon who goes on to marry naive medical receptionist -turned-photographer Juliet Binoche, but still can't stop chasing girls and still carries on with his soulmate Sabine because of their shared bowler (Derby) hat fetish. In the end, The Soviet Union's 1968 occupation of Czechoslovakia indirectly gives Daniel and Juliette's fragile relationship the boost it needed, only for tragedy to strike, in a 'Wages of Fear' kind of way. Yes, I did watch to the end. The dishy doctor's chat-up line is 'Tek off your cloze". Seems to work every time. That's about all that happens for the first few hours. We get a lot of shots of panties, then bottoms and bosoms, but still no real plot. It seems that Prague in 1968 was a seething hotbed of sexual experimentation. TULOB is a quality epic - big budget, big names, many locations, much period detail - but deadly pretentious. Daniel Day-Lewis's Tomasz is like Sam Malone from 'Cheers' with a very serious case of pathological narcissism. Juliette Binoche overacts terribly; were her character a real person everyone would constantly get very annoyed with her. Lena Olin puts in a believable turn as the exotic, possibly bisexual Sabine, who has a fling with a married man in a subplot that is completely pointless, something like her love affair. It's atmospheric, immersive, and reminiscent of a modern Dr. Zhivago - star-crossed lovers against the background of political upheaval with a tragic (and predictable) ending - but the supersoft-porn aspects are ridiculous; obviously done from a commercial imperative and nothing else. You could speculate that Juliet Binoche's wide-eyed character (raped by a Russian) symbolises the Czech republic's burgeoning yearning for freedom, but then the pseudo-intellectual police would be at your door in a flash. I knew the dog was doomed, and actually predicted the 'Tek off your cloze' line the third time - but that was half the fun. Well, I've gone on long enough, it's a shame nobody told the director Phil Kaufman after ninety minutes.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    poet-philosopher guy, kinda crazy, who just goes around having sex with women
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    song_jh
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/4/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I watched this movie on Korean TV, when I was about 16. It was dubbed into Korean, and I did not bother to try to understand it (English is my native language); actually I didn't even pay full attention to the video images, other than the sex scenes. Basically, it seemed to be about this (French?) poet-philosopher guy (Daniel Day Lewis), kinda crazy, who just goes around having sex with women. The sex scenes seemed pretty intense, with loud moans and shrieks by the women. The rest of the movie seemed boring with quaint European landscapes and historical cityscapes, the beauty of which a teenage boy shouldn't be expected to appreciate. Juliette Binoche was the guy's beautiful girlfriend or wife, who was always hurt by his womanizing but didn't divorce or break up with him (or did she in the end? I don't remember). I did not really understand the deep philosophy or message of the movie, if it had one.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Overrated mess
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    IlluSionS667
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/4/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Maybe it's because I'm not old enough to have witnessed life in the sixties myself, but nothing in this movie made any sense to me. The dialogs were strange and often nonsensical. People's behavior was often strange and the movie never gave any real insight into their motivations. And if there was any character development, it certainly was lost on me. I found it pretty impossible to connect with any of the main characters at all, and for a movie like this it seems pretty essential to be able to connect with at least its main characters. I hoped the movie would start making sense by the end, but unfortunately it never did. It was a total waste of almost 3 hours of my life...
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Bad
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mr_dark_eyed
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/3/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I watched this with an open mind. I loved the book (LOVED) and knew (read) that the movie wasn't a direct reflection of the book , which, given the nature and style of the book, makes sense. But what I didn't expect was how shallow and bad the 'adaptation' was. I thought that when a director decides to tackle such issues and to deal with such a great book, he would try harder, or at least be much deeper, and I thought such actors would not take part in something that bad. From the very beginning I was very unsatisfied. I thought I was watching a comedy. Something very American about the first part of the movie. The scene in the spa, the way Tomas was portrayed. Too cocky. A character with no 'weight' or even flesh. It's as though the director told Daniel 2 words to describe his role before they started shooting: You are a cocky womanizer. period. The way he was inspecting Tereza after she got out of the pool! I couldn't believe that it was actually happening. I was laughing, whereas I would be reading Kundera's deep thoughts about this chance encounter. about Fate. Did Tereza really have to pick her nose while waiting at Tomas' door for the first time? Is this really the way to show us how naive and simple she is? really, what kind of woman picks her nose while standing in front of a man she has a crush on (or any man)? And did she have to act like a dumb retarded person the whole time? Tomas.. I don't remember ever meeting someone like Tomas, in real life. He is so unconvincing. It's like a kids movie where characters are either black or white, so the little ones can tell who is good and who is evil. Can't a womanizer be more subtle? OK, he is handsome and we know he sleeps around and loves women, can you now make him a real human being, so we can buy the whole story? And what about the silly accents? Are they Czech? is that why they have accents? why are they talking in English then? If you want the audience to forget about the whole language issue, then make them speak in English and forget about the accents. Lets forget about the language and focus on the dialogue. But what's the point in making a British actor fake a strange accent in order to play a Czech character who speaks English with his Czech friends???? it only helped in keeping me aware all the time that these people are acting. Sabina's character was very irritating to me, while she was very intriguing in the book. The "Stop This Noise" scene was very bad. Franz was a character with no flesh or meat. Was he a weak character? why was he agreeing with her like that? In the book, we knew enough about him (and Sabina) so we could make sense of their relationship and interaction. But not here. It's as though the director relied on the fact that we know about the characters from the book and will fill in the gaps. That's what I was doing at least, relying on my knowledge of the characters to make sense of some scenes. I can go on... I think if you attempt to turn this unusual book into a film, then you should be able to use unusual ways to create an unusual film with unusual structure, as opposed to the conventional usual narrative and storytelling. It takes a brave daring filmmaker to deal with such book. Mr. Kaufmann is not. He belongs in Hollywood. This film proves one thing: if you base your lousy film on a great book, there's good chance you will get away with it, and even get praised for it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Excellent argument!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Nuno Duarte
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/6/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    from http://movieinthepark.blogspot.com/ The Unbearable Lightness of Being (1988) Prague, 1968. Tomas (Daneil Day-Lewis), a Czech surgeon who keeps a sexual relationship with Sabina (Lena Olin). At one point he goes to a spa to do an operation and meets Tereza (Juliette Binoche), who despite the contrast between them both, ends up marrying him. Tomas, sexually very active, used to variety in women, very proud and sophisticated sees his wife, very simple and somehow naive, not tolerating his polygamy. Meanwhile, the Russians invade Prague and they flee to Switzerland. The argument is based on Milan Kundera's book from 1984. I haven't read it but it sure leaves a certain willingness to do it. Not only because of those people that defend that the movie poisoned the book, but for the background. The first Czechoslovakia described, with its intellectuality and liberty, later called by Prague Spring, that disturbed the Communists from the Soviet Union and cause the invasion. Prague new identity is hammered and distrust, fear, perversion and resignation take its place. Besides that, the relationship between Tomas and the other two, as between Tereza and Sabina is very interesting. Then comes the big purpose of the movie that took charge of the title, the lightness of Tomas' life against what Tereza called hers, hardness. Anyway, the movie is directed by Philip Kaufman, mainly known for Indiana Jones's screenplays. I think this might be Daniel DL's best job, his performance as nothing to do with his last movies, as he adopts a calm but enthusiastic and genial surgeon. Meanwhile, I watched another movie, Haneke's La pianiste (2001), that I found so bad, futile and obscene that didn't think it deserved its own article. Anyway, do not watch it. Much better is The Unbearable Lightness of Being and this one I recommend. 9/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
 </reviews>
</filme>
