<filme>
 <id>
  213
 </id>
 <imdburl>
  http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0091867
 </imdburl>
 <ano>
  1985
 </ano>
 <titulo>
  Uma Janela para o Amor
 </titulo>
 <rating>
  7.3
 </rating>
 <sinopse>
  When Lucy Honeychurch and chaperone Charlotte Bartlett find themselves in Florence with rooms without views, fellow guests Mr Emerson and son George step in to remedy the situation. Meeting... &nbsp;&raquo;
 </sinopse>
 <storyline>
  When Lucy Honeychurch and chaperone Charlotte Bartlett find themselves in Florence with rooms without views, fellow guests Mr Emerson and son George step in to remedy the situation. Meeting the Emersons could change Lucy's life forever but, once back in England, how will her experiences in Tuscany affect her marriage plans?
 </storyline>
 <generos>
  <genero>
   Drama
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Romance
  </genero>
 </generos>
 <keywords>
  <keyword>
   florence italy
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   piano
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   chaperon
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   1900s
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   travel
  </keyword>
 </keywords>
 <diretores>
  <diretor>
   James Ivory
  </diretor>
 </diretores>
 <escritores>
  <escritor>
   E.M. Forster
  </escritor>
  <escritor>
   Ruth Prawer Jhabvala
  </escritor>
 </escritores>
 <atores>
  <ator>
   Maggie Smith
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Helena Bonham Carter
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Denholm Elliott
  </ator>
 </atores>
 <reviews>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    All the ways lead to Rome ... but Florence leads to all the ways ...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ElMaruecan82
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The remarkable thing about the Merchant-Ivory productions (in fact a solid triumvirate if we count the writer Ruth Prawer Jhabvala) is that they're generally less about plots than characters, and so real they never seem to act according to a specific screenplay, but are rather conditioned by the two main forces of the story: space and time. Indeed, over the course of time, relationships are done and undone and the coldest heart can melt like Anthony Hopkins in "The Remains of the Day". "Howard's End" was much about an estate, symbolizing the rural roots of British aristocracy, before it surrendered to business-driven modernism. Generally set at crucial periods of British history, the Merchant-Ivory productions are about people who are the products of their age while a new one is coming, and they generally use their houses as a symbolic stronghold to resist the ineluctable changes. And "A Room with a View", adapted from E.M Forster's novel of the same name, is the metaphor of the very point the story makes. Even the smallest room can open onto a large town, the sky, the infinite, like so many paths one can take from life, if he or she dares to get rid of the weight of past and conventions. A room can be made of a beds and austere furniture to welcome a young woman from a British hamlet, Lucy Honeychurch (Helena Bohnam Carter) and her restraining chaperon Charlotte (Maggie Smith), but it can offer a panoramic view of one of the most romantic towns in the world: Florence. And the first pages of this cinematic book open in Florence, in a small pension, where a group of vacationers meet. Miss Charlotte complains about the missing view in the room, to which, inviting during the following dinner a free-spirited man, Mr. Emerson (Delnhom Elliott) to proposes to switch their rooms. Emerson came with his son, and both belong to another class, up enough to afford a voyage to Italy, but whose philosophical views suggest that they embraced the turn-of-century, contrarily to the Victorian Charlotte, who refused the proposal, shocked by Emerson's lack of tact, while his reaction proves that he meant no disrespect.. She eventually accepts, convinced by other guests of the pension, Reverend Beebe (Simon Callow) and the old Allan sisters. This benign episode foreshadows the coming conflicts between the old and new order in England circa 1910, to which space and time provide crucial elements. The film is set during the Edwardian period; a sort of in-between decade where British people could nonchalantly enjoy the achievements of the more prestigious Victorian era, like a historical calm before the storm of the Great War. And being a film of dazzling imagery, the sight of these British vacationers enjoying a picnic in a Tuscan setting, savoring tea and bathing under a sepia summer sun, and a cool summer breeze, is an eloquent illustration of the quiet optimism that prevailed during that period. And this bourgeois idleness, combined with a natural setting, creates the perfect cocktail for a passionate romance, leading to the inevitable moment when the mysterious George Emerson, played by the handsome Julian Sands, gives a passionate kiss to an unchaperoned Lucy. She didn't see it coming, nor did she expect the kiss' everlasting effect, awakening the most passionate impulses. The kiss sweeps off all the conventions, the good manners that condemned Lucy to a life of rigidity, giving all its meaning to the setting in Florence, the most defining town of the Renaissance. Literally, George's kiss is Lucy's renaissance. But this is only the first act and back home; the kiss is already history after Charlotte's intervention. And when during the next scene, we meet Cecil Vyse, Daniel Day-Lewis as Lucy's future husband, a living caricature of snobbish prig with his oiled hair, rigid stature and annoying pince-nez, we're puzzled but not surprised. The film doesn't embarrass with explanations and trusts us enough to connect between the events together. So, regarding the mysterious choice of Cecyl as a husband, I guess, we should get back to the 'room with a view' metaphor. Indeed, with George, Lucy had 'a room with a view', with Cecyl, she would have thousands of rooms with no view at all. Breaking his eternally taciturn facade, George is given one opportunity to have a heart-talk with Lucy; he tells her that her marriage with Cecyl would turn her into an ornament, for the man would never be able to value her, or any woman for that matter. This is one of the outbursts of passion the film serves at the right moment to remind us that there is still a story after all, and a question: to which direction will Lucy's heart lean? And it's not just a choice between two men, but two orders, two states of mind, two ways of kissing. Roger Ebert, in one of his most enthusiastic reviews, insisted on the conflict between heart and mind, passion and intellect. I wish he had a few words about space and time as either the restraining or catalyzing elements in our lives. It's restraining when you have characters with the privilege to enjoy some escapism in a beautiful Italian landscape, but are still tied with Victorian good manners, or catalyzing, when three men, including a priest, play like children in a lake, all naked. The swimming sequence is exhilarating, and the massive male nudity never bothers, a credit to the directing and the cast' performances. Of course, as enchanting as it is, "A Room with a View" is less politically oriented than other Ivory-Merchant productions while there was more to say about socialism, feminism, weight of traditions, bourgeois insouciance, but the specific pretension of "A Room with a View" was to depict another slice of British life, from which two hearts would converge in a small point of the world, a room with a view  on the infinite, on the future, on love.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Pretty Entertaining
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gavin6942
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    When Lucy Honeychurch (Helena Bonham Carter) and chaperone Charlotte Bartlett find themselves in Florence with rooms without views, fellow guests Mr. Emerson and son George (Julian Sands) step in to remedy the situation. I watched this film knowing nothing about it because I wanted to see a Daniel Day-Lewis movie, and then I saw that Helena Bonham Carter and Julian Sands were in it. Carter was unknown to me until the 1990s, so it was a pleasant surprise to see her in such an early role. Sands is the one who steals the show, and it is a pity that it seems his career never hit the level it should. Day-Lewis is always good, though he plays a rather secondary role here. It would be hard to compare this to any of his other great performances, because certainly they overshadow this one.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    beauty crumbs
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Vincentiu
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    in this case, important is the taste. clear, delicate, special. like spring air. because , portrait of a society, charming love story, full of drops of lovely humor, creation of an extraordinary cast, adaptation of lovely novel, it is a kind of sentimental jewel - small, hided, admirable. a film like a state of soul. or slice of holiday because each viewer is part of it. because the joy of performance, the Italian images, the crumbs of Victorian manner to understand reality, the roots of a special revolution, the masks and the bath scene, Maggy Smith in one of her adorable roles, all is part of a seductive circle. a film like an open window.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    beautiful scenery...PC feminism in 1905
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    filmtherapy
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/3/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    An 18 or so year old girl Lucy Honeychurch and her chaperon Charlotte a middle aged spinster cousin go on a trip to Florence. There in a pension they encounter Mr Emerson and his son George. Mr. Emerson trades rooms with the women so that they might have rooms with views. George falls in love with Lucy and steals a kiss from her. Her chaperon sees this happen and returns Lucy at once to England. By chance Mr. Emerson and George rent a cottage near the Honeychurch's house... by this time Lucy is engaged to someone else. However true love wins out. I didn't care for the women's lib part of it (also the exaggerated era prudishness is cartoonish)....Lucy has spunk and George is the perfect milquetoast husband...."I want a wife who speaks her mind thinks on her own blah blah blah...." This turns it into a typical modern PC chick flick....no wonder it was popular. That was the "plot" and raison d'etre of the film other reviewers are looking for. I did like the beautiful scenery and wonderfully recreated world of the Edwardian era. It is a pretty movie to watch. OK watch
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    It's kind of like "Jane Eyre"....really.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    planktonrules
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/3/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The film is a story about manners--very, very, very proper and stuffy British manners during the Edwardian era. As a result of convention, Lucy (Carter) and George (Sands) are kept apart. Partway through watching "A Room With a View", I realized that, believe it or not, the underlying theme is the same as you'll find in "Jane Eyre"....seriously. Both concern social conventions and morality versus happiness and romantic passion. In the case of Jane, her love (Mr. Rochester) was not technically able to marry her and so she ran off--and lived, for a time, with a man in training to be a missionary and his family. The missionary had no passion at all for Jane but proposed--a marriage of convenience and intellect. Should she choose this good man or live with a man already married (Rochester)--albeit, his marriage was clearly a fraud perpetrated on him. Likewise, in "A Room With a View", Helena Bonham Carter's character must choose between a more worldly (and rather non-religious) Julian Sands or the incredibly stodgy and respectable fianc&eacute; (Daniel Day-Lewis). Either a marriage of predictability and convention or a marriage with passion, and, perhaps, irrespectability are her apparent choices. Now I am NOT complaining that the themes are the same...after all, "Jane Eyre" is one of my very favorite books (and is MUCH better than the movie versions). Some things to look for in this film--the gorgeous views of Florence, the lovely score and the funny (but very explicit) skinny-dipping scene. Clever and enjoyable...but also perhaps a bit slow due to its commentary about manners.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Edwardian Eyeful
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    AZINDN
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I will gush over this film because it is worthy of praise and a standing ovation. A Room With A View is likely one of the most perfect films to grace screens in decades. The E.M. Forrester story produced and directed by the team of Ivory and Merchant brings the tale of Miss Lucy Honeychurch (Helena Bonham-Carter) to life in perfect Edwardian splendor. Wonderful locations of the Florence cathedral, Palazzo Vecchio, sculpture by Donatello, and an assortment of rolling landscapes are stunning visual fodder for this comic tale of Apolonian vs. Dionesian parlor manners. Exquisite young Bonham-Carter's casting as the virginal heiress is thwarted by her traveling companion, the venerable Dame Maggie Smith as her meddling biddy chaperon, Aunt Charlotte, with Dame Judy Dench as a proto-Jackie Collins author, Elenore Lavish, Daniel Day-Lewis as the prissy snobbish Cecil Vyse, and, a gorgeous, naked Julian Sands as socialist George Emerson comprises a most outstanding casting achievement. The excellent soundtrack offering of Dame Kiri Te Kaniwa's rendition of "O Mio Caro" takes your breath away as are the bits of wonderful piano solos that Lucy produces throughout the film. The cinematography is most wonderful with scenic panoramas of the far off Florence or Lucy sauntering through a field of poppies and wildflowers to receive the kiss to curl your toes from George Emerson, well, can romantic love get any better? This video is required for collectors of films of Julian Sands and Daniel Day-Lewis, however, its real value is as one of the finest of the Merchant Ivory magic touch in film making.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Take A Back Room to A Room With A View **1/2
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    edwagreen
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    You don't need much room to view this disappointing 1985 film. The problem is that with the exception of Maggie Smith, who gives new meaning to spinsterhood, the characters are unbelievable in this brooding Merchant-Ivory piece set in the Victorian era. Daniel Day-Lewis comes off as a fop or dandy; even though he is engaged to Helena Bonham Carter here. She finds true love in Italy and it follows her back home in England. The film often drags The scene with the naked men was funny but the result was highly predictable. The men in particular are really off the wall in this film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Beautiful film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Wayne Malin (wwaayynnee51@hotmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/10/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    In the early 1900s young Lucy Honeychurch (Helena Bonham Carter) is on vacation in Italy. There they meet young, free-wheeling George Emerson (Julian Sands). Lucy and George fall in love but she backs off being afraid. Back in England she agrees to marry self-righteous obnoxious Cecil Vyes (Daniel Day-Lewis) because he's a "safe" choice. Then George (by chance) moves near her...and sparks start to fly. This is a costume drama and, like most of them, this is slow-moving and deliberately paced but I was never bored. The script is sharp, the movie looks beautiful and the cast is full of established English actors who know how to play their roles to the hilt. The only not so good acting was by Rupert Graves, Sands and Carter--but they were all very young when they did this so they were still learning. The only bad acting is by Daniel Day-Lewis. He plays his character so ridiculously obvious that he's just annoying. It's good that he has a small role. Also you probably think this is stuffy and dull...but there is a sequence when Graves, Sands and Simon Callow all go skinny-dipping! And yes--you see everything but it's all so innocent and fun that it's hard to be shocked. I saw it in a theatre and nobody was even remotely bothered. I'd say this is a costume drama for people who don't like costume dramas! Well worth seeing. I give it a 10!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Nearly perfect film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    avgjoedc
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/9/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I say its nearly perfect, but I really cant fault it for anything. The performances are uniformly exquisite, the visuals/scenery are magnificent, the script follows the classic novel - but keeps the humor, irony, and pathos open to a modern audience. It is the most accessible and most enjoyable of the Merchant & Ivory translations of classic works - and really elevates the magic of the original EM Forster novel. While the leads keep the story going, the smaller roles constantly keep you amused. The aged sisters, the carefree brother, the nervous mother, the vicar, the bold authoress, etc all provoke a smile. And the last 3 minutes are simply delightful.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A room with a view.....but I couldn't see much else
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    thomvic
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/5/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I suspected this movie was going to be a great drama with a good love story from what I read on the back of the DVD. Hmmmm well not really. For one thing, Helena Bonham Carter's character wasn't very sympathetic and it felt more like she was complaining or making snard remarks at everyone half the time. The whole Florence scenes felt more like they were trying to praise Italy for being a romantic place rather than giving it a real backing as a place of memory for Lucy Honeychurch and George. They had one fling when it could have happened anywhere. What's more, this feels like it could have done better in the theatre as a play and I'm not sure if there ever was one. This is definitely more dialogue driven than plot driven. Charlotte's character (Maggie Smith) feels more like Lucy's actual mother than her cousin and sometimes I had to remind myself she was her cousin than her mother. Performances were pretty good though I thought the characters weren't particularly interesting and also because the plot went at too quick of a pace to really make you absorb the emotions of the characters. Yes I know it is also meant to be a comedy as well but I didn't really find anything really funny. Though Daniel Day Lewis as Cecil was played to perfection and made for a very dorky character. Don't have too much expectations with this. It is fun and silly but in the end more of a play that doesn't really make you remember much.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    All the ways lead to Rome ... but Florence leads to all the ways ...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ElMaruecan82
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The remarkable thing about the Merchant-Ivory productions (in fact a solid triumvirate if we count the writer Ruth Prawer Jhabvala) is that they're generally less about plots than characters, and so real they never seem to act according to a specific screenplay, but are rather conditioned by the two main forces of the story: space and time. Indeed, over the course of time, relationships are done and undone and the coldest heart can melt like Anthony Hopkins in "The Remains of the Day". "Howard's End" was much about an estate, symbolizing the rural roots of British aristocracy, before it surrendered to business-driven modernism. Generally set at crucial periods of British history, the Merchant-Ivory productions are about people who are the products of their age while a new one is coming, and they generally use their houses as a symbolic stronghold to resist the ineluctable changes. And "A Room with a View", adapted from E.M Forster's novel of the same name, is the metaphor of the very point the story makes. Even the smallest room can open onto a large town, the sky, the infinite, like so many paths one can take from life, if he or she dares to get rid of the weight of past and conventions. A room can be made of a beds and austere furniture to welcome a young woman from a British hamlet, Lucy Honeychurch (Helena Bohnam Carter) and her restraining chaperon Charlotte (Maggie Smith), but it can offer a panoramic view of one of the most romantic towns in the world: Florence. And the first pages of this cinematic book open in Florence, in a small pension, where a group of vacationers meet. Miss Charlotte complains about the missing view in the room, to which, inviting during the following dinner a free-spirited man, Mr. Emerson (Delnhom Elliott) to proposes to switch their rooms. Emerson came with his son, and both belong to another class, up enough to afford a voyage to Italy, but whose philosophical views suggest that they embraced the turn-of-century, contrarily to the Victorian Charlotte, who refused the proposal, shocked by Emerson's lack of tact, while his reaction proves that he meant no disrespect.. She eventually accepts, convinced by other guests of the pension, Reverend Beebe (Simon Callow) and the old Allan sisters. This benign episode foreshadows the coming conflicts between the old and new order in England circa 1910, to which space and time provide crucial elements. The film is set during the Edwardian period; a sort of in-between decade where British people could nonchalantly enjoy the achievements of the more prestigious Victorian era, like a historical calm before the storm of the Great War. And being a film of dazzling imagery, the sight of these British vacationers enjoying a picnic in a Tuscan setting, savoring tea and bathing under a sepia summer sun, and a cool summer breeze, is an eloquent illustration of the quiet optimism that prevailed during that period. And this bourgeois idleness, combined with a natural setting, creates the perfect cocktail for a passionate romance, leading to the inevitable moment when the mysterious George Emerson, played by the handsome Julian Sands, gives a passionate kiss to an unchaperoned Lucy. She didn't see it coming, nor did she expect the kiss' everlasting effect, awakening the most passionate impulses. The kiss sweeps off all the conventions, the good manners that condemned Lucy to a life of rigidity, giving all its meaning to the setting in Florence, the most defining town of the Renaissance. Literally, George's kiss is Lucy's renaissance. But this is only the first act and back home; the kiss is already history after Charlotte's intervention. And when during the next scene, we meet Cecil Vyse, Daniel Day-Lewis as Lucy's future husband, a living caricature of snobbish prig with his oiled hair, rigid stature and annoying pince-nez, we're puzzled but not surprised. The film doesn't embarrass with explanations and trusts us enough to connect between the events together. So, regarding the mysterious choice of Cecyl as a husband, I guess, we should get back to the 'room with a view' metaphor. Indeed, with George, Lucy had 'a room with a view', with Cecyl, she would have thousands of rooms with no view at all. Breaking his eternally taciturn facade, George is given one opportunity to have a heart-talk with Lucy; he tells her that her marriage with Cecyl would turn her into an ornament, for the man would never be able to value her, or any woman for that matter. This is one of the outbursts of passion the film serves at the right moment to remind us that there is still a story after all, and a question: to which direction will Lucy's heart lean? And it's not just a choice between two men, but two orders, two states of mind, two ways of kissing. Roger Ebert, in one of his most enthusiastic reviews, insisted on the conflict between heart and mind, passion and intellect. I wish he had a few words about space and time as either the restraining or catalyzing elements in our lives. It's restraining when you have characters with the privilege to enjoy some escapism in a beautiful Italian landscape, but are still tied with Victorian good manners, or catalyzing, when three men, including a priest, play like children in a lake, all naked. The swimming sequence is exhilarating, and the massive male nudity never bothers, a credit to the directing and the cast' performances. Of course, as enchanting as it is, "A Room with a View" is less politically oriented than other Ivory-Merchant productions while there was more to say about socialism, feminism, weight of traditions, bourgeois insouciance, but the specific pretension of "A Room with a View" was to depict another slice of British life, from which two hearts would converge in a small point of the world, a room with a view  on the infinite, on the future, on love.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Pretty Entertaining
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gavin6942
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    When Lucy Honeychurch (Helena Bonham Carter) and chaperone Charlotte Bartlett find themselves in Florence with rooms without views, fellow guests Mr. Emerson and son George (Julian Sands) step in to remedy the situation. I watched this film knowing nothing about it because I wanted to see a Daniel Day-Lewis movie, and then I saw that Helena Bonham Carter and Julian Sands were in it. Carter was unknown to me until the 1990s, so it was a pleasant surprise to see her in such an early role. Sands is the one who steals the show, and it is a pity that it seems his career never hit the level it should. Day-Lewis is always good, though he plays a rather secondary role here. It would be hard to compare this to any of his other great performances, because certainly they overshadow this one.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    beauty crumbs
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Vincentiu
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    in this case, important is the taste. clear, delicate, special. like spring air. because , portrait of a society, charming love story, full of drops of lovely humor, creation of an extraordinary cast, adaptation of lovely novel, it is a kind of sentimental jewel - small, hided, admirable. a film like a state of soul. or slice of holiday because each viewer is part of it. because the joy of performance, the Italian images, the crumbs of Victorian manner to understand reality, the roots of a special revolution, the masks and the bath scene, Maggy Smith in one of her adorable roles, all is part of a seductive circle. a film like an open window.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    beautiful scenery...PC feminism in 1905
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    filmtherapy
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/3/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    An 18 or so year old girl Lucy Honeychurch and her chaperon Charlotte a middle aged spinster cousin go on a trip to Florence. There in a pension they encounter Mr Emerson and his son George. Mr. Emerson trades rooms with the women so that they might have rooms with views. George falls in love with Lucy and steals a kiss from her. Her chaperon sees this happen and returns Lucy at once to England. By chance Mr. Emerson and George rent a cottage near the Honeychurch's house... by this time Lucy is engaged to someone else. However true love wins out. I didn't care for the women's lib part of it (also the exaggerated era prudishness is cartoonish)....Lucy has spunk and George is the perfect milquetoast husband...."I want a wife who speaks her mind thinks on her own blah blah blah...." This turns it into a typical modern PC chick flick....no wonder it was popular. That was the "plot" and raison d'etre of the film other reviewers are looking for. I did like the beautiful scenery and wonderfully recreated world of the Edwardian era. It is a pretty movie to watch. OK watch
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    It's kind of like "Jane Eyre"....really.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    planktonrules
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/3/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The film is a story about manners--very, very, very proper and stuffy British manners during the Edwardian era. As a result of convention, Lucy (Carter) and George (Sands) are kept apart. Partway through watching "A Room With a View", I realized that, believe it or not, the underlying theme is the same as you'll find in "Jane Eyre"....seriously. Both concern social conventions and morality versus happiness and romantic passion. In the case of Jane, her love (Mr. Rochester) was not technically able to marry her and so she ran off--and lived, for a time, with a man in training to be a missionary and his family. The missionary had no passion at all for Jane but proposed--a marriage of convenience and intellect. Should she choose this good man or live with a man already married (Rochester)--albeit, his marriage was clearly a fraud perpetrated on him. Likewise, in "A Room With a View", Helena Bonham Carter's character must choose between a more worldly (and rather non-religious) Julian Sands or the incredibly stodgy and respectable fianc&eacute; (Daniel Day-Lewis). Either a marriage of predictability and convention or a marriage with passion, and, perhaps, irrespectability are her apparent choices. Now I am NOT complaining that the themes are the same...after all, "Jane Eyre" is one of my very favorite books (and is MUCH better than the movie versions). Some things to look for in this film--the gorgeous views of Florence, the lovely score and the funny (but very explicit) skinny-dipping scene. Clever and enjoyable...but also perhaps a bit slow due to its commentary about manners.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Edwardian Eyeful
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    AZINDN
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I will gush over this film because it is worthy of praise and a standing ovation. A Room With A View is likely one of the most perfect films to grace screens in decades. The E.M. Forrester story produced and directed by the team of Ivory and Merchant brings the tale of Miss Lucy Honeychurch (Helena Bonham-Carter) to life in perfect Edwardian splendor. Wonderful locations of the Florence cathedral, Palazzo Vecchio, sculpture by Donatello, and an assortment of rolling landscapes are stunning visual fodder for this comic tale of Apolonian vs. Dionesian parlor manners. Exquisite young Bonham-Carter's casting as the virginal heiress is thwarted by her traveling companion, the venerable Dame Maggie Smith as her meddling biddy chaperon, Aunt Charlotte, with Dame Judy Dench as a proto-Jackie Collins author, Elenore Lavish, Daniel Day-Lewis as the prissy snobbish Cecil Vyse, and, a gorgeous, naked Julian Sands as socialist George Emerson comprises a most outstanding casting achievement. The excellent soundtrack offering of Dame Kiri Te Kaniwa's rendition of "O Mio Caro" takes your breath away as are the bits of wonderful piano solos that Lucy produces throughout the film. The cinematography is most wonderful with scenic panoramas of the far off Florence or Lucy sauntering through a field of poppies and wildflowers to receive the kiss to curl your toes from George Emerson, well, can romantic love get any better? This video is required for collectors of films of Julian Sands and Daniel Day-Lewis, however, its real value is as one of the finest of the Merchant Ivory magic touch in film making.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Take A Back Room to A Room With A View **1/2
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    edwagreen
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    You don't need much room to view this disappointing 1985 film. The problem is that with the exception of Maggie Smith, who gives new meaning to spinsterhood, the characters are unbelievable in this brooding Merchant-Ivory piece set in the Victorian era. Daniel Day-Lewis comes off as a fop or dandy; even though he is engaged to Helena Bonham Carter here. She finds true love in Italy and it follows her back home in England. The film often drags The scene with the naked men was funny but the result was highly predictable. The men in particular are really off the wall in this film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Beautiful film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Wayne Malin (wwaayynnee51@hotmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/10/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    In the early 1900s young Lucy Honeychurch (Helena Bonham Carter) is on vacation in Italy. There they meet young, free-wheeling George Emerson (Julian Sands). Lucy and George fall in love but she backs off being afraid. Back in England she agrees to marry self-righteous obnoxious Cecil Vyes (Daniel Day-Lewis) because he's a "safe" choice. Then George (by chance) moves near her...and sparks start to fly. This is a costume drama and, like most of them, this is slow-moving and deliberately paced but I was never bored. The script is sharp, the movie looks beautiful and the cast is full of established English actors who know how to play their roles to the hilt. The only not so good acting was by Rupert Graves, Sands and Carter--but they were all very young when they did this so they were still learning. The only bad acting is by Daniel Day-Lewis. He plays his character so ridiculously obvious that he's just annoying. It's good that he has a small role. Also you probably think this is stuffy and dull...but there is a sequence when Graves, Sands and Simon Callow all go skinny-dipping! And yes--you see everything but it's all so innocent and fun that it's hard to be shocked. I saw it in a theatre and nobody was even remotely bothered. I'd say this is a costume drama for people who don't like costume dramas! Well worth seeing. I give it a 10!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Nearly perfect film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    avgjoedc
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/9/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I say its nearly perfect, but I really cant fault it for anything. The performances are uniformly exquisite, the visuals/scenery are magnificent, the script follows the classic novel - but keeps the humor, irony, and pathos open to a modern audience. It is the most accessible and most enjoyable of the Merchant & Ivory translations of classic works - and really elevates the magic of the original EM Forster novel. While the leads keep the story going, the smaller roles constantly keep you amused. The aged sisters, the carefree brother, the nervous mother, the vicar, the bold authoress, etc all provoke a smile. And the last 3 minutes are simply delightful.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A room with a view.....but I couldn't see much else
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    thomvic
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/5/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I suspected this movie was going to be a great drama with a good love story from what I read on the back of the DVD. Hmmmm well not really. For one thing, Helena Bonham Carter's character wasn't very sympathetic and it felt more like she was complaining or making snard remarks at everyone half the time. The whole Florence scenes felt more like they were trying to praise Italy for being a romantic place rather than giving it a real backing as a place of memory for Lucy Honeychurch and George. They had one fling when it could have happened anywhere. What's more, this feels like it could have done better in the theatre as a play and I'm not sure if there ever was one. This is definitely more dialogue driven than plot driven. Charlotte's character (Maggie Smith) feels more like Lucy's actual mother than her cousin and sometimes I had to remind myself she was her cousin than her mother. Performances were pretty good though I thought the characters weren't particularly interesting and also because the plot went at too quick of a pace to really make you absorb the emotions of the characters. Yes I know it is also meant to be a comedy as well but I didn't really find anything really funny. Though Daniel Day Lewis as Cecil was played to perfection and made for a very dorky character. Don't have too much expectations with this. It is fun and silly but in the end more of a play that doesn't really make you remember much.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    All the ways lead to Rome ... but Florence leads to all the ways ...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ElMaruecan82
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The remarkable thing about the Merchant-Ivory productions (in fact a solid triumvirate if we count the writer Ruth Prawer Jhabvala) is that they're generally less about plots than characters, and so real they never seem to act according to a specific screenplay, but are rather conditioned by the two main forces of the story: space and time. Indeed, over the course of time, relationships are done and undone and the coldest heart can melt like Anthony Hopkins in "The Remains of the Day". "Howard's End" was much about an estate, symbolizing the rural roots of British aristocracy, before it surrendered to business-driven modernism. Generally set at crucial periods of British history, the Merchant-Ivory productions are about people who are the products of their age while a new one is coming, and they generally use their houses as a symbolic stronghold to resist the ineluctable changes. And "A Room with a View", adapted from E.M Forster's novel of the same name, is the metaphor of the very point the story makes. Even the smallest room can open onto a large town, the sky, the infinite, like so many paths one can take from life, if he or she dares to get rid of the weight of past and conventions. A room can be made of a beds and austere furniture to welcome a young woman from a British hamlet, Lucy Honeychurch (Helena Bohnam Carter) and her restraining chaperon Charlotte (Maggie Smith), but it can offer a panoramic view of one of the most romantic towns in the world: Florence. And the first pages of this cinematic book open in Florence, in a small pension, where a group of vacationers meet. Miss Charlotte complains about the missing view in the room, to which, inviting during the following dinner a free-spirited man, Mr. Emerson (Delnhom Elliott) to proposes to switch their rooms. Emerson came with his son, and both belong to another class, up enough to afford a voyage to Italy, but whose philosophical views suggest that they embraced the turn-of-century, contrarily to the Victorian Charlotte, who refused the proposal, shocked by Emerson's lack of tact, while his reaction proves that he meant no disrespect.. She eventually accepts, convinced by other guests of the pension, Reverend Beebe (Simon Callow) and the old Allan sisters. This benign episode foreshadows the coming conflicts between the old and new order in England circa 1910, to which space and time provide crucial elements. The film is set during the Edwardian period; a sort of in-between decade where British people could nonchalantly enjoy the achievements of the more prestigious Victorian era, like a historical calm before the storm of the Great War. And being a film of dazzling imagery, the sight of these British vacationers enjoying a picnic in a Tuscan setting, savoring tea and bathing under a sepia summer sun, and a cool summer breeze, is an eloquent illustration of the quiet optimism that prevailed during that period. And this bourgeois idleness, combined with a natural setting, creates the perfect cocktail for a passionate romance, leading to the inevitable moment when the mysterious George Emerson, played by the handsome Julian Sands, gives a passionate kiss to an unchaperoned Lucy. She didn't see it coming, nor did she expect the kiss' everlasting effect, awakening the most passionate impulses. The kiss sweeps off all the conventions, the good manners that condemned Lucy to a life of rigidity, giving all its meaning to the setting in Florence, the most defining town of the Renaissance. Literally, George's kiss is Lucy's renaissance. But this is only the first act and back home; the kiss is already history after Charlotte's intervention. And when during the next scene, we meet Cecil Vyse, Daniel Day-Lewis as Lucy's future husband, a living caricature of snobbish prig with his oiled hair, rigid stature and annoying pince-nez, we're puzzled but not surprised. The film doesn't embarrass with explanations and trusts us enough to connect between the events together. So, regarding the mysterious choice of Cecyl as a husband, I guess, we should get back to the 'room with a view' metaphor. Indeed, with George, Lucy had 'a room with a view', with Cecyl, she would have thousands of rooms with no view at all. Breaking his eternally taciturn facade, George is given one opportunity to have a heart-talk with Lucy; he tells her that her marriage with Cecyl would turn her into an ornament, for the man would never be able to value her, or any woman for that matter. This is one of the outbursts of passion the film serves at the right moment to remind us that there is still a story after all, and a question: to which direction will Lucy's heart lean? And it's not just a choice between two men, but two orders, two states of mind, two ways of kissing. Roger Ebert, in one of his most enthusiastic reviews, insisted on the conflict between heart and mind, passion and intellect. I wish he had a few words about space and time as either the restraining or catalyzing elements in our lives. It's restraining when you have characters with the privilege to enjoy some escapism in a beautiful Italian landscape, but are still tied with Victorian good manners, or catalyzing, when three men, including a priest, play like children in a lake, all naked. The swimming sequence is exhilarating, and the massive male nudity never bothers, a credit to the directing and the cast' performances. Of course, as enchanting as it is, "A Room with a View" is less politically oriented than other Ivory-Merchant productions while there was more to say about socialism, feminism, weight of traditions, bourgeois insouciance, but the specific pretension of "A Room with a View" was to depict another slice of British life, from which two hearts would converge in a small point of the world, a room with a view  on the infinite, on the future, on love.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Pretty Entertaining
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gavin6942
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    When Lucy Honeychurch (Helena Bonham Carter) and chaperone Charlotte Bartlett find themselves in Florence with rooms without views, fellow guests Mr. Emerson and son George (Julian Sands) step in to remedy the situation. I watched this film knowing nothing about it because I wanted to see a Daniel Day-Lewis movie, and then I saw that Helena Bonham Carter and Julian Sands were in it. Carter was unknown to me until the 1990s, so it was a pleasant surprise to see her in such an early role. Sands is the one who steals the show, and it is a pity that it seems his career never hit the level it should. Day-Lewis is always good, though he plays a rather secondary role here. It would be hard to compare this to any of his other great performances, because certainly they overshadow this one.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    beauty crumbs
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Vincentiu
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    in this case, important is the taste. clear, delicate, special. like spring air. because , portrait of a society, charming love story, full of drops of lovely humor, creation of an extraordinary cast, adaptation of lovely novel, it is a kind of sentimental jewel - small, hided, admirable. a film like a state of soul. or slice of holiday because each viewer is part of it. because the joy of performance, the Italian images, the crumbs of Victorian manner to understand reality, the roots of a special revolution, the masks and the bath scene, Maggy Smith in one of her adorable roles, all is part of a seductive circle. a film like an open window.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    beautiful scenery...PC feminism in 1905
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    filmtherapy
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/3/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    An 18 or so year old girl Lucy Honeychurch and her chaperon Charlotte a middle aged spinster cousin go on a trip to Florence. There in a pension they encounter Mr Emerson and his son George. Mr. Emerson trades rooms with the women so that they might have rooms with views. George falls in love with Lucy and steals a kiss from her. Her chaperon sees this happen and returns Lucy at once to England. By chance Mr. Emerson and George rent a cottage near the Honeychurch's house... by this time Lucy is engaged to someone else. However true love wins out. I didn't care for the women's lib part of it (also the exaggerated era prudishness is cartoonish)....Lucy has spunk and George is the perfect milquetoast husband...."I want a wife who speaks her mind thinks on her own blah blah blah...." This turns it into a typical modern PC chick flick....no wonder it was popular. That was the "plot" and raison d'etre of the film other reviewers are looking for. I did like the beautiful scenery and wonderfully recreated world of the Edwardian era. It is a pretty movie to watch. OK watch
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    It's kind of like "Jane Eyre"....really.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    planktonrules
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/3/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The film is a story about manners--very, very, very proper and stuffy British manners during the Edwardian era. As a result of convention, Lucy (Carter) and George (Sands) are kept apart. Partway through watching "A Room With a View", I realized that, believe it or not, the underlying theme is the same as you'll find in "Jane Eyre"....seriously. Both concern social conventions and morality versus happiness and romantic passion. In the case of Jane, her love (Mr. Rochester) was not technically able to marry her and so she ran off--and lived, for a time, with a man in training to be a missionary and his family. The missionary had no passion at all for Jane but proposed--a marriage of convenience and intellect. Should she choose this good man or live with a man already married (Rochester)--albeit, his marriage was clearly a fraud perpetrated on him. Likewise, in "A Room With a View", Helena Bonham Carter's character must choose between a more worldly (and rather non-religious) Julian Sands or the incredibly stodgy and respectable fianc&eacute; (Daniel Day-Lewis). Either a marriage of predictability and convention or a marriage with passion, and, perhaps, irrespectability are her apparent choices. Now I am NOT complaining that the themes are the same...after all, "Jane Eyre" is one of my very favorite books (and is MUCH better than the movie versions). Some things to look for in this film--the gorgeous views of Florence, the lovely score and the funny (but very explicit) skinny-dipping scene. Clever and enjoyable...but also perhaps a bit slow due to its commentary about manners.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Edwardian Eyeful
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    AZINDN
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I will gush over this film because it is worthy of praise and a standing ovation. A Room With A View is likely one of the most perfect films to grace screens in decades. The E.M. Forrester story produced and directed by the team of Ivory and Merchant brings the tale of Miss Lucy Honeychurch (Helena Bonham-Carter) to life in perfect Edwardian splendor. Wonderful locations of the Florence cathedral, Palazzo Vecchio, sculpture by Donatello, and an assortment of rolling landscapes are stunning visual fodder for this comic tale of Apolonian vs. Dionesian parlor manners. Exquisite young Bonham-Carter's casting as the virginal heiress is thwarted by her traveling companion, the venerable Dame Maggie Smith as her meddling biddy chaperon, Aunt Charlotte, with Dame Judy Dench as a proto-Jackie Collins author, Elenore Lavish, Daniel Day-Lewis as the prissy snobbish Cecil Vyse, and, a gorgeous, naked Julian Sands as socialist George Emerson comprises a most outstanding casting achievement. The excellent soundtrack offering of Dame Kiri Te Kaniwa's rendition of "O Mio Caro" takes your breath away as are the bits of wonderful piano solos that Lucy produces throughout the film. The cinematography is most wonderful with scenic panoramas of the far off Florence or Lucy sauntering through a field of poppies and wildflowers to receive the kiss to curl your toes from George Emerson, well, can romantic love get any better? This video is required for collectors of films of Julian Sands and Daniel Day-Lewis, however, its real value is as one of the finest of the Merchant Ivory magic touch in film making.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Take A Back Room to A Room With A View **1/2
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    edwagreen
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    You don't need much room to view this disappointing 1985 film. The problem is that with the exception of Maggie Smith, who gives new meaning to spinsterhood, the characters are unbelievable in this brooding Merchant-Ivory piece set in the Victorian era. Daniel Day-Lewis comes off as a fop or dandy; even though he is engaged to Helena Bonham Carter here. She finds true love in Italy and it follows her back home in England. The film often drags The scene with the naked men was funny but the result was highly predictable. The men in particular are really off the wall in this film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Beautiful film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Wayne Malin (wwaayynnee51@hotmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/10/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    In the early 1900s young Lucy Honeychurch (Helena Bonham Carter) is on vacation in Italy. There they meet young, free-wheeling George Emerson (Julian Sands). Lucy and George fall in love but she backs off being afraid. Back in England she agrees to marry self-righteous obnoxious Cecil Vyes (Daniel Day-Lewis) because he's a "safe" choice. Then George (by chance) moves near her...and sparks start to fly. This is a costume drama and, like most of them, this is slow-moving and deliberately paced but I was never bored. The script is sharp, the movie looks beautiful and the cast is full of established English actors who know how to play their roles to the hilt. The only not so good acting was by Rupert Graves, Sands and Carter--but they were all very young when they did this so they were still learning. The only bad acting is by Daniel Day-Lewis. He plays his character so ridiculously obvious that he's just annoying. It's good that he has a small role. Also you probably think this is stuffy and dull...but there is a sequence when Graves, Sands and Simon Callow all go skinny-dipping! And yes--you see everything but it's all so innocent and fun that it's hard to be shocked. I saw it in a theatre and nobody was even remotely bothered. I'd say this is a costume drama for people who don't like costume dramas! Well worth seeing. I give it a 10!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Nearly perfect film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    avgjoedc
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/9/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I say its nearly perfect, but I really cant fault it for anything. The performances are uniformly exquisite, the visuals/scenery are magnificent, the script follows the classic novel - but keeps the humor, irony, and pathos open to a modern audience. It is the most accessible and most enjoyable of the Merchant & Ivory translations of classic works - and really elevates the magic of the original EM Forster novel. While the leads keep the story going, the smaller roles constantly keep you amused. The aged sisters, the carefree brother, the nervous mother, the vicar, the bold authoress, etc all provoke a smile. And the last 3 minutes are simply delightful.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A room with a view.....but I couldn't see much else
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    thomvic
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/5/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I suspected this movie was going to be a great drama with a good love story from what I read on the back of the DVD. Hmmmm well not really. For one thing, Helena Bonham Carter's character wasn't very sympathetic and it felt more like she was complaining or making snard remarks at everyone half the time. The whole Florence scenes felt more like they were trying to praise Italy for being a romantic place rather than giving it a real backing as a place of memory for Lucy Honeychurch and George. They had one fling when it could have happened anywhere. What's more, this feels like it could have done better in the theatre as a play and I'm not sure if there ever was one. This is definitely more dialogue driven than plot driven. Charlotte's character (Maggie Smith) feels more like Lucy's actual mother than her cousin and sometimes I had to remind myself she was her cousin than her mother. Performances were pretty good though I thought the characters weren't particularly interesting and also because the plot went at too quick of a pace to really make you absorb the emotions of the characters. Yes I know it is also meant to be a comedy as well but I didn't really find anything really funny. Though Daniel Day Lewis as Cecil was played to perfection and made for a very dorky character. Don't have too much expectations with this. It is fun and silly but in the end more of a play that doesn't really make you remember much.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    All the ways lead to Rome ... but Florence leads to all the ways ...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ElMaruecan82
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The remarkable thing about the Merchant-Ivory productions (in fact a solid triumvirate if we count the writer Ruth Prawer Jhabvala) is that they're generally less about plots than characters, and so real they never seem to act according to a specific screenplay, but are rather conditioned by the two main forces of the story: space and time. Indeed, over the course of time, relationships are done and undone and the coldest heart can melt like Anthony Hopkins in "The Remains of the Day". "Howard's End" was much about an estate, symbolizing the rural roots of British aristocracy, before it surrendered to business-driven modernism. Generally set at crucial periods of British history, the Merchant-Ivory productions are about people who are the products of their age while a new one is coming, and they generally use their houses as a symbolic stronghold to resist the ineluctable changes. And "A Room with a View", adapted from E.M Forster's novel of the same name, is the metaphor of the very point the story makes. Even the smallest room can open onto a large town, the sky, the infinite, like so many paths one can take from life, if he or she dares to get rid of the weight of past and conventions. A room can be made of a beds and austere furniture to welcome a young woman from a British hamlet, Lucy Honeychurch (Helena Bohnam Carter) and her restraining chaperon Charlotte (Maggie Smith), but it can offer a panoramic view of one of the most romantic towns in the world: Florence. And the first pages of this cinematic book open in Florence, in a small pension, where a group of vacationers meet. Miss Charlotte complains about the missing view in the room, to which, inviting during the following dinner a free-spirited man, Mr. Emerson (Delnhom Elliott) to proposes to switch their rooms. Emerson came with his son, and both belong to another class, up enough to afford a voyage to Italy, but whose philosophical views suggest that they embraced the turn-of-century, contrarily to the Victorian Charlotte, who refused the proposal, shocked by Emerson's lack of tact, while his reaction proves that he meant no disrespect.. She eventually accepts, convinced by other guests of the pension, Reverend Beebe (Simon Callow) and the old Allan sisters. This benign episode foreshadows the coming conflicts between the old and new order in England circa 1910, to which space and time provide crucial elements. The film is set during the Edwardian period; a sort of in-between decade where British people could nonchalantly enjoy the achievements of the more prestigious Victorian era, like a historical calm before the storm of the Great War. And being a film of dazzling imagery, the sight of these British vacationers enjoying a picnic in a Tuscan setting, savoring tea and bathing under a sepia summer sun, and a cool summer breeze, is an eloquent illustration of the quiet optimism that prevailed during that period. And this bourgeois idleness, combined with a natural setting, creates the perfect cocktail for a passionate romance, leading to the inevitable moment when the mysterious George Emerson, played by the handsome Julian Sands, gives a passionate kiss to an unchaperoned Lucy. She didn't see it coming, nor did she expect the kiss' everlasting effect, awakening the most passionate impulses. The kiss sweeps off all the conventions, the good manners that condemned Lucy to a life of rigidity, giving all its meaning to the setting in Florence, the most defining town of the Renaissance. Literally, George's kiss is Lucy's renaissance. But this is only the first act and back home; the kiss is already history after Charlotte's intervention. And when during the next scene, we meet Cecil Vyse, Daniel Day-Lewis as Lucy's future husband, a living caricature of snobbish prig with his oiled hair, rigid stature and annoying pince-nez, we're puzzled but not surprised. The film doesn't embarrass with explanations and trusts us enough to connect between the events together. So, regarding the mysterious choice of Cecyl as a husband, I guess, we should get back to the 'room with a view' metaphor. Indeed, with George, Lucy had 'a room with a view', with Cecyl, she would have thousands of rooms with no view at all. Breaking his eternally taciturn facade, George is given one opportunity to have a heart-talk with Lucy; he tells her that her marriage with Cecyl would turn her into an ornament, for the man would never be able to value her, or any woman for that matter. This is one of the outbursts of passion the film serves at the right moment to remind us that there is still a story after all, and a question: to which direction will Lucy's heart lean? And it's not just a choice between two men, but two orders, two states of mind, two ways of kissing. Roger Ebert, in one of his most enthusiastic reviews, insisted on the conflict between heart and mind, passion and intellect. I wish he had a few words about space and time as either the restraining or catalyzing elements in our lives. It's restraining when you have characters with the privilege to enjoy some escapism in a beautiful Italian landscape, but are still tied with Victorian good manners, or catalyzing, when three men, including a priest, play like children in a lake, all naked. The swimming sequence is exhilarating, and the massive male nudity never bothers, a credit to the directing and the cast' performances. Of course, as enchanting as it is, "A Room with a View" is less politically oriented than other Ivory-Merchant productions while there was more to say about socialism, feminism, weight of traditions, bourgeois insouciance, but the specific pretension of "A Room with a View" was to depict another slice of British life, from which two hearts would converge in a small point of the world, a room with a view  on the infinite, on the future, on love.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Pretty Entertaining
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gavin6942
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    When Lucy Honeychurch (Helena Bonham Carter) and chaperone Charlotte Bartlett find themselves in Florence with rooms without views, fellow guests Mr. Emerson and son George (Julian Sands) step in to remedy the situation. I watched this film knowing nothing about it because I wanted to see a Daniel Day-Lewis movie, and then I saw that Helena Bonham Carter and Julian Sands were in it. Carter was unknown to me until the 1990s, so it was a pleasant surprise to see her in such an early role. Sands is the one who steals the show, and it is a pity that it seems his career never hit the level it should. Day-Lewis is always good, though he plays a rather secondary role here. It would be hard to compare this to any of his other great performances, because certainly they overshadow this one.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    beauty crumbs
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Vincentiu
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    in this case, important is the taste. clear, delicate, special. like spring air. because , portrait of a society, charming love story, full of drops of lovely humor, creation of an extraordinary cast, adaptation of lovely novel, it is a kind of sentimental jewel - small, hided, admirable. a film like a state of soul. or slice of holiday because each viewer is part of it. because the joy of performance, the Italian images, the crumbs of Victorian manner to understand reality, the roots of a special revolution, the masks and the bath scene, Maggy Smith in one of her adorable roles, all is part of a seductive circle. a film like an open window.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    beautiful scenery...PC feminism in 1905
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    filmtherapy
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/3/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    An 18 or so year old girl Lucy Honeychurch and her chaperon Charlotte a middle aged spinster cousin go on a trip to Florence. There in a pension they encounter Mr Emerson and his son George. Mr. Emerson trades rooms with the women so that they might have rooms with views. George falls in love with Lucy and steals a kiss from her. Her chaperon sees this happen and returns Lucy at once to England. By chance Mr. Emerson and George rent a cottage near the Honeychurch's house... by this time Lucy is engaged to someone else. However true love wins out. I didn't care for the women's lib part of it (also the exaggerated era prudishness is cartoonish)....Lucy has spunk and George is the perfect milquetoast husband...."I want a wife who speaks her mind thinks on her own blah blah blah...." This turns it into a typical modern PC chick flick....no wonder it was popular. That was the "plot" and raison d'etre of the film other reviewers are looking for. I did like the beautiful scenery and wonderfully recreated world of the Edwardian era. It is a pretty movie to watch. OK watch
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    It's kind of like "Jane Eyre"....really.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    planktonrules
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/3/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The film is a story about manners--very, very, very proper and stuffy British manners during the Edwardian era. As a result of convention, Lucy (Carter) and George (Sands) are kept apart. Partway through watching "A Room With a View", I realized that, believe it or not, the underlying theme is the same as you'll find in "Jane Eyre"....seriously. Both concern social conventions and morality versus happiness and romantic passion. In the case of Jane, her love (Mr. Rochester) was not technically able to marry her and so she ran off--and lived, for a time, with a man in training to be a missionary and his family. The missionary had no passion at all for Jane but proposed--a marriage of convenience and intellect. Should she choose this good man or live with a man already married (Rochester)--albeit, his marriage was clearly a fraud perpetrated on him. Likewise, in "A Room With a View", Helena Bonham Carter's character must choose between a more worldly (and rather non-religious) Julian Sands or the incredibly stodgy and respectable fianc&eacute; (Daniel Day-Lewis). Either a marriage of predictability and convention or a marriage with passion, and, perhaps, irrespectability are her apparent choices. Now I am NOT complaining that the themes are the same...after all, "Jane Eyre" is one of my very favorite books (and is MUCH better than the movie versions). Some things to look for in this film--the gorgeous views of Florence, the lovely score and the funny (but very explicit) skinny-dipping scene. Clever and enjoyable...but also perhaps a bit slow due to its commentary about manners.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Edwardian Eyeful
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    AZINDN
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I will gush over this film because it is worthy of praise and a standing ovation. A Room With A View is likely one of the most perfect films to grace screens in decades. The E.M. Forrester story produced and directed by the team of Ivory and Merchant brings the tale of Miss Lucy Honeychurch (Helena Bonham-Carter) to life in perfect Edwardian splendor. Wonderful locations of the Florence cathedral, Palazzo Vecchio, sculpture by Donatello, and an assortment of rolling landscapes are stunning visual fodder for this comic tale of Apolonian vs. Dionesian parlor manners. Exquisite young Bonham-Carter's casting as the virginal heiress is thwarted by her traveling companion, the venerable Dame Maggie Smith as her meddling biddy chaperon, Aunt Charlotte, with Dame Judy Dench as a proto-Jackie Collins author, Elenore Lavish, Daniel Day-Lewis as the prissy snobbish Cecil Vyse, and, a gorgeous, naked Julian Sands as socialist George Emerson comprises a most outstanding casting achievement. The excellent soundtrack offering of Dame Kiri Te Kaniwa's rendition of "O Mio Caro" takes your breath away as are the bits of wonderful piano solos that Lucy produces throughout the film. The cinematography is most wonderful with scenic panoramas of the far off Florence or Lucy sauntering through a field of poppies and wildflowers to receive the kiss to curl your toes from George Emerson, well, can romantic love get any better? This video is required for collectors of films of Julian Sands and Daniel Day-Lewis, however, its real value is as one of the finest of the Merchant Ivory magic touch in film making.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Take A Back Room to A Room With A View **1/2
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    edwagreen
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    You don't need much room to view this disappointing 1985 film. The problem is that with the exception of Maggie Smith, who gives new meaning to spinsterhood, the characters are unbelievable in this brooding Merchant-Ivory piece set in the Victorian era. Daniel Day-Lewis comes off as a fop or dandy; even though he is engaged to Helena Bonham Carter here. She finds true love in Italy and it follows her back home in England. The film often drags The scene with the naked men was funny but the result was highly predictable. The men in particular are really off the wall in this film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Beautiful film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Wayne Malin (wwaayynnee51@hotmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/10/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    In the early 1900s young Lucy Honeychurch (Helena Bonham Carter) is on vacation in Italy. There they meet young, free-wheeling George Emerson (Julian Sands). Lucy and George fall in love but she backs off being afraid. Back in England she agrees to marry self-righteous obnoxious Cecil Vyes (Daniel Day-Lewis) because he's a "safe" choice. Then George (by chance) moves near her...and sparks start to fly. This is a costume drama and, like most of them, this is slow-moving and deliberately paced but I was never bored. The script is sharp, the movie looks beautiful and the cast is full of established English actors who know how to play their roles to the hilt. The only not so good acting was by Rupert Graves, Sands and Carter--but they were all very young when they did this so they were still learning. The only bad acting is by Daniel Day-Lewis. He plays his character so ridiculously obvious that he's just annoying. It's good that he has a small role. Also you probably think this is stuffy and dull...but there is a sequence when Graves, Sands and Simon Callow all go skinny-dipping! And yes--you see everything but it's all so innocent and fun that it's hard to be shocked. I saw it in a theatre and nobody was even remotely bothered. I'd say this is a costume drama for people who don't like costume dramas! Well worth seeing. I give it a 10!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Nearly perfect film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    avgjoedc
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/9/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I say its nearly perfect, but I really cant fault it for anything. The performances are uniformly exquisite, the visuals/scenery are magnificent, the script follows the classic novel - but keeps the humor, irony, and pathos open to a modern audience. It is the most accessible and most enjoyable of the Merchant & Ivory translations of classic works - and really elevates the magic of the original EM Forster novel. While the leads keep the story going, the smaller roles constantly keep you amused. The aged sisters, the carefree brother, the nervous mother, the vicar, the bold authoress, etc all provoke a smile. And the last 3 minutes are simply delightful.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A room with a view.....but I couldn't see much else
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    thomvic
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/5/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I suspected this movie was going to be a great drama with a good love story from what I read on the back of the DVD. Hmmmm well not really. For one thing, Helena Bonham Carter's character wasn't very sympathetic and it felt more like she was complaining or making snard remarks at everyone half the time. The whole Florence scenes felt more like they were trying to praise Italy for being a romantic place rather than giving it a real backing as a place of memory for Lucy Honeychurch and George. They had one fling when it could have happened anywhere. What's more, this feels like it could have done better in the theatre as a play and I'm not sure if there ever was one. This is definitely more dialogue driven than plot driven. Charlotte's character (Maggie Smith) feels more like Lucy's actual mother than her cousin and sometimes I had to remind myself she was her cousin than her mother. Performances were pretty good though I thought the characters weren't particularly interesting and also because the plot went at too quick of a pace to really make you absorb the emotions of the characters. Yes I know it is also meant to be a comedy as well but I didn't really find anything really funny. Though Daniel Day Lewis as Cecil was played to perfection and made for a very dorky character. Don't have too much expectations with this. It is fun and silly but in the end more of a play that doesn't really make you remember much.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    All the ways lead to Rome ... but Florence leads to all the ways ...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ElMaruecan82
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The remarkable thing about the Merchant-Ivory productions (in fact a solid triumvirate if we count the writer Ruth Prawer Jhabvala) is that they're generally less about plots than characters, and so real they never seem to act according to a specific screenplay, but are rather conditioned by the two main forces of the story: space and time. Indeed, over the course of time, relationships are done and undone and the coldest heart can melt like Anthony Hopkins in "The Remains of the Day". "Howard's End" was much about an estate, symbolizing the rural roots of British aristocracy, before it surrendered to business-driven modernism. Generally set at crucial periods of British history, the Merchant-Ivory productions are about people who are the products of their age while a new one is coming, and they generally use their houses as a symbolic stronghold to resist the ineluctable changes. And "A Room with a View", adapted from E.M Forster's novel of the same name, is the metaphor of the very point the story makes. Even the smallest room can open onto a large town, the sky, the infinite, like so many paths one can take from life, if he or she dares to get rid of the weight of past and conventions. A room can be made of a beds and austere furniture to welcome a young woman from a British hamlet, Lucy Honeychurch (Helena Bohnam Carter) and her restraining chaperon Charlotte (Maggie Smith), but it can offer a panoramic view of one of the most romantic towns in the world: Florence. And the first pages of this cinematic book open in Florence, in a small pension, where a group of vacationers meet. Miss Charlotte complains about the missing view in the room, to which, inviting during the following dinner a free-spirited man, Mr. Emerson (Delnhom Elliott) to proposes to switch their rooms. Emerson came with his son, and both belong to another class, up enough to afford a voyage to Italy, but whose philosophical views suggest that they embraced the turn-of-century, contrarily to the Victorian Charlotte, who refused the proposal, shocked by Emerson's lack of tact, while his reaction proves that he meant no disrespect.. She eventually accepts, convinced by other guests of the pension, Reverend Beebe (Simon Callow) and the old Allan sisters. This benign episode foreshadows the coming conflicts between the old and new order in England circa 1910, to which space and time provide crucial elements. The film is set during the Edwardian period; a sort of in-between decade where British people could nonchalantly enjoy the achievements of the more prestigious Victorian era, like a historical calm before the storm of the Great War. And being a film of dazzling imagery, the sight of these British vacationers enjoying a picnic in a Tuscan setting, savoring tea and bathing under a sepia summer sun, and a cool summer breeze, is an eloquent illustration of the quiet optimism that prevailed during that period. And this bourgeois idleness, combined with a natural setting, creates the perfect cocktail for a passionate romance, leading to the inevitable moment when the mysterious George Emerson, played by the handsome Julian Sands, gives a passionate kiss to an unchaperoned Lucy. She didn't see it coming, nor did she expect the kiss' everlasting effect, awakening the most passionate impulses. The kiss sweeps off all the conventions, the good manners that condemned Lucy to a life of rigidity, giving all its meaning to the setting in Florence, the most defining town of the Renaissance. Literally, George's kiss is Lucy's renaissance. But this is only the first act and back home; the kiss is already history after Charlotte's intervention. And when during the next scene, we meet Cecil Vyse, Daniel Day-Lewis as Lucy's future husband, a living caricature of snobbish prig with his oiled hair, rigid stature and annoying pince-nez, we're puzzled but not surprised. The film doesn't embarrass with explanations and trusts us enough to connect between the events together. So, regarding the mysterious choice of Cecyl as a husband, I guess, we should get back to the 'room with a view' metaphor. Indeed, with George, Lucy had 'a room with a view', with Cecyl, she would have thousands of rooms with no view at all. Breaking his eternally taciturn facade, George is given one opportunity to have a heart-talk with Lucy; he tells her that her marriage with Cecyl would turn her into an ornament, for the man would never be able to value her, or any woman for that matter. This is one of the outbursts of passion the film serves at the right moment to remind us that there is still a story after all, and a question: to which direction will Lucy's heart lean? And it's not just a choice between two men, but two orders, two states of mind, two ways of kissing. Roger Ebert, in one of his most enthusiastic reviews, insisted on the conflict between heart and mind, passion and intellect. I wish he had a few words about space and time as either the restraining or catalyzing elements in our lives. It's restraining when you have characters with the privilege to enjoy some escapism in a beautiful Italian landscape, but are still tied with Victorian good manners, or catalyzing, when three men, including a priest, play like children in a lake, all naked. The swimming sequence is exhilarating, and the massive male nudity never bothers, a credit to the directing and the cast' performances. Of course, as enchanting as it is, "A Room with a View" is less politically oriented than other Ivory-Merchant productions while there was more to say about socialism, feminism, weight of traditions, bourgeois insouciance, but the specific pretension of "A Room with a View" was to depict another slice of British life, from which two hearts would converge in a small point of the world, a room with a view  on the infinite, on the future, on love.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Pretty Entertaining
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gavin6942
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    When Lucy Honeychurch (Helena Bonham Carter) and chaperone Charlotte Bartlett find themselves in Florence with rooms without views, fellow guests Mr. Emerson and son George (Julian Sands) step in to remedy the situation. I watched this film knowing nothing about it because I wanted to see a Daniel Day-Lewis movie, and then I saw that Helena Bonham Carter and Julian Sands were in it. Carter was unknown to me until the 1990s, so it was a pleasant surprise to see her in such an early role. Sands is the one who steals the show, and it is a pity that it seems his career never hit the level it should. Day-Lewis is always good, though he plays a rather secondary role here. It would be hard to compare this to any of his other great performances, because certainly they overshadow this one.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    beauty crumbs
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Vincentiu
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    in this case, important is the taste. clear, delicate, special. like spring air. because , portrait of a society, charming love story, full of drops of lovely humor, creation of an extraordinary cast, adaptation of lovely novel, it is a kind of sentimental jewel - small, hided, admirable. a film like a state of soul. or slice of holiday because each viewer is part of it. because the joy of performance, the Italian images, the crumbs of Victorian manner to understand reality, the roots of a special revolution, the masks and the bath scene, Maggy Smith in one of her adorable roles, all is part of a seductive circle. a film like an open window.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    beautiful scenery...PC feminism in 1905
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    filmtherapy
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/3/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    An 18 or so year old girl Lucy Honeychurch and her chaperon Charlotte a middle aged spinster cousin go on a trip to Florence. There in a pension they encounter Mr Emerson and his son George. Mr. Emerson trades rooms with the women so that they might have rooms with views. George falls in love with Lucy and steals a kiss from her. Her chaperon sees this happen and returns Lucy at once to England. By chance Mr. Emerson and George rent a cottage near the Honeychurch's house... by this time Lucy is engaged to someone else. However true love wins out. I didn't care for the women's lib part of it (also the exaggerated era prudishness is cartoonish)....Lucy has spunk and George is the perfect milquetoast husband...."I want a wife who speaks her mind thinks on her own blah blah blah...." This turns it into a typical modern PC chick flick....no wonder it was popular. That was the "plot" and raison d'etre of the film other reviewers are looking for. I did like the beautiful scenery and wonderfully recreated world of the Edwardian era. It is a pretty movie to watch. OK watch
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    It's kind of like "Jane Eyre"....really.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    planktonrules
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/3/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The film is a story about manners--very, very, very proper and stuffy British manners during the Edwardian era. As a result of convention, Lucy (Carter) and George (Sands) are kept apart. Partway through watching "A Room With a View", I realized that, believe it or not, the underlying theme is the same as you'll find in "Jane Eyre"....seriously. Both concern social conventions and morality versus happiness and romantic passion. In the case of Jane, her love (Mr. Rochester) was not technically able to marry her and so she ran off--and lived, for a time, with a man in training to be a missionary and his family. The missionary had no passion at all for Jane but proposed--a marriage of convenience and intellect. Should she choose this good man or live with a man already married (Rochester)--albeit, his marriage was clearly a fraud perpetrated on him. Likewise, in "A Room With a View", Helena Bonham Carter's character must choose between a more worldly (and rather non-religious) Julian Sands or the incredibly stodgy and respectable fianc&eacute; (Daniel Day-Lewis). Either a marriage of predictability and convention or a marriage with passion, and, perhaps, irrespectability are her apparent choices. Now I am NOT complaining that the themes are the same...after all, "Jane Eyre" is one of my very favorite books (and is MUCH better than the movie versions). Some things to look for in this film--the gorgeous views of Florence, the lovely score and the funny (but very explicit) skinny-dipping scene. Clever and enjoyable...but also perhaps a bit slow due to its commentary about manners.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Edwardian Eyeful
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    AZINDN
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I will gush over this film because it is worthy of praise and a standing ovation. A Room With A View is likely one of the most perfect films to grace screens in decades. The E.M. Forrester story produced and directed by the team of Ivory and Merchant brings the tale of Miss Lucy Honeychurch (Helena Bonham-Carter) to life in perfect Edwardian splendor. Wonderful locations of the Florence cathedral, Palazzo Vecchio, sculpture by Donatello, and an assortment of rolling landscapes are stunning visual fodder for this comic tale of Apolonian vs. Dionesian parlor manners. Exquisite young Bonham-Carter's casting as the virginal heiress is thwarted by her traveling companion, the venerable Dame Maggie Smith as her meddling biddy chaperon, Aunt Charlotte, with Dame Judy Dench as a proto-Jackie Collins author, Elenore Lavish, Daniel Day-Lewis as the prissy snobbish Cecil Vyse, and, a gorgeous, naked Julian Sands as socialist George Emerson comprises a most outstanding casting achievement. The excellent soundtrack offering of Dame Kiri Te Kaniwa's rendition of "O Mio Caro" takes your breath away as are the bits of wonderful piano solos that Lucy produces throughout the film. The cinematography is most wonderful with scenic panoramas of the far off Florence or Lucy sauntering through a field of poppies and wildflowers to receive the kiss to curl your toes from George Emerson, well, can romantic love get any better? This video is required for collectors of films of Julian Sands and Daniel Day-Lewis, however, its real value is as one of the finest of the Merchant Ivory magic touch in film making.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Take A Back Room to A Room With A View **1/2
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    edwagreen
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    You don't need much room to view this disappointing 1985 film. The problem is that with the exception of Maggie Smith, who gives new meaning to spinsterhood, the characters are unbelievable in this brooding Merchant-Ivory piece set in the Victorian era. Daniel Day-Lewis comes off as a fop or dandy; even though he is engaged to Helena Bonham Carter here. She finds true love in Italy and it follows her back home in England. The film often drags The scene with the naked men was funny but the result was highly predictable. The men in particular are really off the wall in this film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Beautiful film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Wayne Malin (wwaayynnee51@hotmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/10/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    In the early 1900s young Lucy Honeychurch (Helena Bonham Carter) is on vacation in Italy. There they meet young, free-wheeling George Emerson (Julian Sands). Lucy and George fall in love but she backs off being afraid. Back in England she agrees to marry self-righteous obnoxious Cecil Vyes (Daniel Day-Lewis) because he's a "safe" choice. Then George (by chance) moves near her...and sparks start to fly. This is a costume drama and, like most of them, this is slow-moving and deliberately paced but I was never bored. The script is sharp, the movie looks beautiful and the cast is full of established English actors who know how to play their roles to the hilt. The only not so good acting was by Rupert Graves, Sands and Carter--but they were all very young when they did this so they were still learning. The only bad acting is by Daniel Day-Lewis. He plays his character so ridiculously obvious that he's just annoying. It's good that he has a small role. Also you probably think this is stuffy and dull...but there is a sequence when Graves, Sands and Simon Callow all go skinny-dipping! And yes--you see everything but it's all so innocent and fun that it's hard to be shocked. I saw it in a theatre and nobody was even remotely bothered. I'd say this is a costume drama for people who don't like costume dramas! Well worth seeing. I give it a 10!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Nearly perfect film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    avgjoedc
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/9/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I say its nearly perfect, but I really cant fault it for anything. The performances are uniformly exquisite, the visuals/scenery are magnificent, the script follows the classic novel - but keeps the humor, irony, and pathos open to a modern audience. It is the most accessible and most enjoyable of the Merchant & Ivory translations of classic works - and really elevates the magic of the original EM Forster novel. While the leads keep the story going, the smaller roles constantly keep you amused. The aged sisters, the carefree brother, the nervous mother, the vicar, the bold authoress, etc all provoke a smile. And the last 3 minutes are simply delightful.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A room with a view.....but I couldn't see much else
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    thomvic
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/5/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I suspected this movie was going to be a great drama with a good love story from what I read on the back of the DVD. Hmmmm well not really. For one thing, Helena Bonham Carter's character wasn't very sympathetic and it felt more like she was complaining or making snard remarks at everyone half the time. The whole Florence scenes felt more like they were trying to praise Italy for being a romantic place rather than giving it a real backing as a place of memory for Lucy Honeychurch and George. They had one fling when it could have happened anywhere. What's more, this feels like it could have done better in the theatre as a play and I'm not sure if there ever was one. This is definitely more dialogue driven than plot driven. Charlotte's character (Maggie Smith) feels more like Lucy's actual mother than her cousin and sometimes I had to remind myself she was her cousin than her mother. Performances were pretty good though I thought the characters weren't particularly interesting and also because the plot went at too quick of a pace to really make you absorb the emotions of the characters. Yes I know it is also meant to be a comedy as well but I didn't really find anything really funny. Though Daniel Day Lewis as Cecil was played to perfection and made for a very dorky character. Don't have too much expectations with this. It is fun and silly but in the end more of a play that doesn't really make you remember much.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    All the ways lead to Rome ... but Florence leads to all the ways ...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ElMaruecan82
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The remarkable thing about the Merchant-Ivory productions (in fact a solid triumvirate if we count the writer Ruth Prawer Jhabvala) is that they're generally less about plots than characters, and so real they never seem to act according to a specific screenplay, but are rather conditioned by the two main forces of the story: space and time. Indeed, over the course of time, relationships are done and undone and the coldest heart can melt like Anthony Hopkins in "The Remains of the Day". "Howard's End" was much about an estate, symbolizing the rural roots of British aristocracy, before it surrendered to business-driven modernism. Generally set at crucial periods of British history, the Merchant-Ivory productions are about people who are the products of their age while a new one is coming, and they generally use their houses as a symbolic stronghold to resist the ineluctable changes. And "A Room with a View", adapted from E.M Forster's novel of the same name, is the metaphor of the very point the story makes. Even the smallest room can open onto a large town, the sky, the infinite, like so many paths one can take from life, if he or she dares to get rid of the weight of past and conventions. A room can be made of a beds and austere furniture to welcome a young woman from a British hamlet, Lucy Honeychurch (Helena Bohnam Carter) and her restraining chaperon Charlotte (Maggie Smith), but it can offer a panoramic view of one of the most romantic towns in the world: Florence. And the first pages of this cinematic book open in Florence, in a small pension, where a group of vacationers meet. Miss Charlotte complains about the missing view in the room, to which, inviting during the following dinner a free-spirited man, Mr. Emerson (Delnhom Elliott) to proposes to switch their rooms. Emerson came with his son, and both belong to another class, up enough to afford a voyage to Italy, but whose philosophical views suggest that they embraced the turn-of-century, contrarily to the Victorian Charlotte, who refused the proposal, shocked by Emerson's lack of tact, while his reaction proves that he meant no disrespect.. She eventually accepts, convinced by other guests of the pension, Reverend Beebe (Simon Callow) and the old Allan sisters. This benign episode foreshadows the coming conflicts between the old and new order in England circa 1910, to which space and time provide crucial elements. The film is set during the Edwardian period; a sort of in-between decade where British people could nonchalantly enjoy the achievements of the more prestigious Victorian era, like a historical calm before the storm of the Great War. And being a film of dazzling imagery, the sight of these British vacationers enjoying a picnic in a Tuscan setting, savoring tea and bathing under a sepia summer sun, and a cool summer breeze, is an eloquent illustration of the quiet optimism that prevailed during that period. And this bourgeois idleness, combined with a natural setting, creates the perfect cocktail for a passionate romance, leading to the inevitable moment when the mysterious George Emerson, played by the handsome Julian Sands, gives a passionate kiss to an unchaperoned Lucy. She didn't see it coming, nor did she expect the kiss' everlasting effect, awakening the most passionate impulses. The kiss sweeps off all the conventions, the good manners that condemned Lucy to a life of rigidity, giving all its meaning to the setting in Florence, the most defining town of the Renaissance. Literally, George's kiss is Lucy's renaissance. But this is only the first act and back home; the kiss is already history after Charlotte's intervention. And when during the next scene, we meet Cecil Vyse, Daniel Day-Lewis as Lucy's future husband, a living caricature of snobbish prig with his oiled hair, rigid stature and annoying pince-nez, we're puzzled but not surprised. The film doesn't embarrass with explanations and trusts us enough to connect between the events together. So, regarding the mysterious choice of Cecyl as a husband, I guess, we should get back to the 'room with a view' metaphor. Indeed, with George, Lucy had 'a room with a view', with Cecyl, she would have thousands of rooms with no view at all. Breaking his eternally taciturn facade, George is given one opportunity to have a heart-talk with Lucy; he tells her that her marriage with Cecyl would turn her into an ornament, for the man would never be able to value her, or any woman for that matter. This is one of the outbursts of passion the film serves at the right moment to remind us that there is still a story after all, and a question: to which direction will Lucy's heart lean? And it's not just a choice between two men, but two orders, two states of mind, two ways of kissing. Roger Ebert, in one of his most enthusiastic reviews, insisted on the conflict between heart and mind, passion and intellect. I wish he had a few words about space and time as either the restraining or catalyzing elements in our lives. It's restraining when you have characters with the privilege to enjoy some escapism in a beautiful Italian landscape, but are still tied with Victorian good manners, or catalyzing, when three men, including a priest, play like children in a lake, all naked. The swimming sequence is exhilarating, and the massive male nudity never bothers, a credit to the directing and the cast' performances. Of course, as enchanting as it is, "A Room with a View" is less politically oriented than other Ivory-Merchant productions while there was more to say about socialism, feminism, weight of traditions, bourgeois insouciance, but the specific pretension of "A Room with a View" was to depict another slice of British life, from which two hearts would converge in a small point of the world, a room with a view  on the infinite, on the future, on love.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Pretty Entertaining
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gavin6942
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    When Lucy Honeychurch (Helena Bonham Carter) and chaperone Charlotte Bartlett find themselves in Florence with rooms without views, fellow guests Mr. Emerson and son George (Julian Sands) step in to remedy the situation. I watched this film knowing nothing about it because I wanted to see a Daniel Day-Lewis movie, and then I saw that Helena Bonham Carter and Julian Sands were in it. Carter was unknown to me until the 1990s, so it was a pleasant surprise to see her in such an early role. Sands is the one who steals the show, and it is a pity that it seems his career never hit the level it should. Day-Lewis is always good, though he plays a rather secondary role here. It would be hard to compare this to any of his other great performances, because certainly they overshadow this one.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    beauty crumbs
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Vincentiu
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    in this case, important is the taste. clear, delicate, special. like spring air. because , portrait of a society, charming love story, full of drops of lovely humor, creation of an extraordinary cast, adaptation of lovely novel, it is a kind of sentimental jewel - small, hided, admirable. a film like a state of soul. or slice of holiday because each viewer is part of it. because the joy of performance, the Italian images, the crumbs of Victorian manner to understand reality, the roots of a special revolution, the masks and the bath scene, Maggy Smith in one of her adorable roles, all is part of a seductive circle. a film like an open window.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    beautiful scenery...PC feminism in 1905
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    filmtherapy
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/3/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    An 18 or so year old girl Lucy Honeychurch and her chaperon Charlotte a middle aged spinster cousin go on a trip to Florence. There in a pension they encounter Mr Emerson and his son George. Mr. Emerson trades rooms with the women so that they might have rooms with views. George falls in love with Lucy and steals a kiss from her. Her chaperon sees this happen and returns Lucy at once to England. By chance Mr. Emerson and George rent a cottage near the Honeychurch's house... by this time Lucy is engaged to someone else. However true love wins out. I didn't care for the women's lib part of it (also the exaggerated era prudishness is cartoonish)....Lucy has spunk and George is the perfect milquetoast husband...."I want a wife who speaks her mind thinks on her own blah blah blah...." This turns it into a typical modern PC chick flick....no wonder it was popular. That was the "plot" and raison d'etre of the film other reviewers are looking for. I did like the beautiful scenery and wonderfully recreated world of the Edwardian era. It is a pretty movie to watch. OK watch
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    It's kind of like "Jane Eyre"....really.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    planktonrules
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/3/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The film is a story about manners--very, very, very proper and stuffy British manners during the Edwardian era. As a result of convention, Lucy (Carter) and George (Sands) are kept apart. Partway through watching "A Room With a View", I realized that, believe it or not, the underlying theme is the same as you'll find in "Jane Eyre"....seriously. Both concern social conventions and morality versus happiness and romantic passion. In the case of Jane, her love (Mr. Rochester) was not technically able to marry her and so she ran off--and lived, for a time, with a man in training to be a missionary and his family. The missionary had no passion at all for Jane but proposed--a marriage of convenience and intellect. Should she choose this good man or live with a man already married (Rochester)--albeit, his marriage was clearly a fraud perpetrated on him. Likewise, in "A Room With a View", Helena Bonham Carter's character must choose between a more worldly (and rather non-religious) Julian Sands or the incredibly stodgy and respectable fianc&eacute; (Daniel Day-Lewis). Either a marriage of predictability and convention or a marriage with passion, and, perhaps, irrespectability are her apparent choices. Now I am NOT complaining that the themes are the same...after all, "Jane Eyre" is one of my very favorite books (and is MUCH better than the movie versions). Some things to look for in this film--the gorgeous views of Florence, the lovely score and the funny (but very explicit) skinny-dipping scene. Clever and enjoyable...but also perhaps a bit slow due to its commentary about manners.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Edwardian Eyeful
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    AZINDN
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I will gush over this film because it is worthy of praise and a standing ovation. A Room With A View is likely one of the most perfect films to grace screens in decades. The E.M. Forrester story produced and directed by the team of Ivory and Merchant brings the tale of Miss Lucy Honeychurch (Helena Bonham-Carter) to life in perfect Edwardian splendor. Wonderful locations of the Florence cathedral, Palazzo Vecchio, sculpture by Donatello, and an assortment of rolling landscapes are stunning visual fodder for this comic tale of Apolonian vs. Dionesian parlor manners. Exquisite young Bonham-Carter's casting as the virginal heiress is thwarted by her traveling companion, the venerable Dame Maggie Smith as her meddling biddy chaperon, Aunt Charlotte, with Dame Judy Dench as a proto-Jackie Collins author, Elenore Lavish, Daniel Day-Lewis as the prissy snobbish Cecil Vyse, and, a gorgeous, naked Julian Sands as socialist George Emerson comprises a most outstanding casting achievement. The excellent soundtrack offering of Dame Kiri Te Kaniwa's rendition of "O Mio Caro" takes your breath away as are the bits of wonderful piano solos that Lucy produces throughout the film. The cinematography is most wonderful with scenic panoramas of the far off Florence or Lucy sauntering through a field of poppies and wildflowers to receive the kiss to curl your toes from George Emerson, well, can romantic love get any better? This video is required for collectors of films of Julian Sands and Daniel Day-Lewis, however, its real value is as one of the finest of the Merchant Ivory magic touch in film making.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Take A Back Room to A Room With A View **1/2
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    edwagreen
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    You don't need much room to view this disappointing 1985 film. The problem is that with the exception of Maggie Smith, who gives new meaning to spinsterhood, the characters are unbelievable in this brooding Merchant-Ivory piece set in the Victorian era. Daniel Day-Lewis comes off as a fop or dandy; even though he is engaged to Helena Bonham Carter here. She finds true love in Italy and it follows her back home in England. The film often drags The scene with the naked men was funny but the result was highly predictable. The men in particular are really off the wall in this film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Beautiful film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Wayne Malin (wwaayynnee51@hotmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/10/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    In the early 1900s young Lucy Honeychurch (Helena Bonham Carter) is on vacation in Italy. There they meet young, free-wheeling George Emerson (Julian Sands). Lucy and George fall in love but she backs off being afraid. Back in England she agrees to marry self-righteous obnoxious Cecil Vyes (Daniel Day-Lewis) because he's a "safe" choice. Then George (by chance) moves near her...and sparks start to fly. This is a costume drama and, like most of them, this is slow-moving and deliberately paced but I was never bored. The script is sharp, the movie looks beautiful and the cast is full of established English actors who know how to play their roles to the hilt. The only not so good acting was by Rupert Graves, Sands and Carter--but they were all very young when they did this so they were still learning. The only bad acting is by Daniel Day-Lewis. He plays his character so ridiculously obvious that he's just annoying. It's good that he has a small role. Also you probably think this is stuffy and dull...but there is a sequence when Graves, Sands and Simon Callow all go skinny-dipping! And yes--you see everything but it's all so innocent and fun that it's hard to be shocked. I saw it in a theatre and nobody was even remotely bothered. I'd say this is a costume drama for people who don't like costume dramas! Well worth seeing. I give it a 10!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Nearly perfect film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    avgjoedc
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/9/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I say its nearly perfect, but I really cant fault it for anything. The performances are uniformly exquisite, the visuals/scenery are magnificent, the script follows the classic novel - but keeps the humor, irony, and pathos open to a modern audience. It is the most accessible and most enjoyable of the Merchant & Ivory translations of classic works - and really elevates the magic of the original EM Forster novel. While the leads keep the story going, the smaller roles constantly keep you amused. The aged sisters, the carefree brother, the nervous mother, the vicar, the bold authoress, etc all provoke a smile. And the last 3 minutes are simply delightful.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A room with a view.....but I couldn't see much else
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    thomvic
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/5/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I suspected this movie was going to be a great drama with a good love story from what I read on the back of the DVD. Hmmmm well not really. For one thing, Helena Bonham Carter's character wasn't very sympathetic and it felt more like she was complaining or making snard remarks at everyone half the time. The whole Florence scenes felt more like they were trying to praise Italy for being a romantic place rather than giving it a real backing as a place of memory for Lucy Honeychurch and George. They had one fling when it could have happened anywhere. What's more, this feels like it could have done better in the theatre as a play and I'm not sure if there ever was one. This is definitely more dialogue driven than plot driven. Charlotte's character (Maggie Smith) feels more like Lucy's actual mother than her cousin and sometimes I had to remind myself she was her cousin than her mother. Performances were pretty good though I thought the characters weren't particularly interesting and also because the plot went at too quick of a pace to really make you absorb the emotions of the characters. Yes I know it is also meant to be a comedy as well but I didn't really find anything really funny. Though Daniel Day Lewis as Cecil was played to perfection and made for a very dorky character. Don't have too much expectations with this. It is fun and silly but in the end more of a play that doesn't really make you remember much.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    All the ways lead to Rome ... but Florence leads to all the ways ...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ElMaruecan82
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The remarkable thing about the Merchant-Ivory productions (in fact a solid triumvirate if we count the writer Ruth Prawer Jhabvala) is that they're generally less about plots than characters, and so real they never seem to act according to a specific screenplay, but are rather conditioned by the two main forces of the story: space and time. Indeed, over the course of time, relationships are done and undone and the coldest heart can melt like Anthony Hopkins in "The Remains of the Day". "Howard's End" was much about an estate, symbolizing the rural roots of British aristocracy, before it surrendered to business-driven modernism. Generally set at crucial periods of British history, the Merchant-Ivory productions are about people who are the products of their age while a new one is coming, and they generally use their houses as a symbolic stronghold to resist the ineluctable changes. And "A Room with a View", adapted from E.M Forster's novel of the same name, is the metaphor of the very point the story makes. Even the smallest room can open onto a large town, the sky, the infinite, like so many paths one can take from life, if he or she dares to get rid of the weight of past and conventions. A room can be made of a beds and austere furniture to welcome a young woman from a British hamlet, Lucy Honeychurch (Helena Bohnam Carter) and her restraining chaperon Charlotte (Maggie Smith), but it can offer a panoramic view of one of the most romantic towns in the world: Florence. And the first pages of this cinematic book open in Florence, in a small pension, where a group of vacationers meet. Miss Charlotte complains about the missing view in the room, to which, inviting during the following dinner a free-spirited man, Mr. Emerson (Delnhom Elliott) to proposes to switch their rooms. Emerson came with his son, and both belong to another class, up enough to afford a voyage to Italy, but whose philosophical views suggest that they embraced the turn-of-century, contrarily to the Victorian Charlotte, who refused the proposal, shocked by Emerson's lack of tact, while his reaction proves that he meant no disrespect.. She eventually accepts, convinced by other guests of the pension, Reverend Beebe (Simon Callow) and the old Allan sisters. This benign episode foreshadows the coming conflicts between the old and new order in England circa 1910, to which space and time provide crucial elements. The film is set during the Edwardian period; a sort of in-between decade where British people could nonchalantly enjoy the achievements of the more prestigious Victorian era, like a historical calm before the storm of the Great War. And being a film of dazzling imagery, the sight of these British vacationers enjoying a picnic in a Tuscan setting, savoring tea and bathing under a sepia summer sun, and a cool summer breeze, is an eloquent illustration of the quiet optimism that prevailed during that period. And this bourgeois idleness, combined with a natural setting, creates the perfect cocktail for a passionate romance, leading to the inevitable moment when the mysterious George Emerson, played by the handsome Julian Sands, gives a passionate kiss to an unchaperoned Lucy. She didn't see it coming, nor did she expect the kiss' everlasting effect, awakening the most passionate impulses. The kiss sweeps off all the conventions, the good manners that condemned Lucy to a life of rigidity, giving all its meaning to the setting in Florence, the most defining town of the Renaissance. Literally, George's kiss is Lucy's renaissance. But this is only the first act and back home; the kiss is already history after Charlotte's intervention. And when during the next scene, we meet Cecil Vyse, Daniel Day-Lewis as Lucy's future husband, a living caricature of snobbish prig with his oiled hair, rigid stature and annoying pince-nez, we're puzzled but not surprised. The film doesn't embarrass with explanations and trusts us enough to connect between the events together. So, regarding the mysterious choice of Cecyl as a husband, I guess, we should get back to the 'room with a view' metaphor. Indeed, with George, Lucy had 'a room with a view', with Cecyl, she would have thousands of rooms with no view at all. Breaking his eternally taciturn facade, George is given one opportunity to have a heart-talk with Lucy; he tells her that her marriage with Cecyl would turn her into an ornament, for the man would never be able to value her, or any woman for that matter. This is one of the outbursts of passion the film serves at the right moment to remind us that there is still a story after all, and a question: to which direction will Lucy's heart lean? And it's not just a choice between two men, but two orders, two states of mind, two ways of kissing. Roger Ebert, in one of his most enthusiastic reviews, insisted on the conflict between heart and mind, passion and intellect. I wish he had a few words about space and time as either the restraining or catalyzing elements in our lives. It's restraining when you have characters with the privilege to enjoy some escapism in a beautiful Italian landscape, but are still tied with Victorian good manners, or catalyzing, when three men, including a priest, play like children in a lake, all naked. The swimming sequence is exhilarating, and the massive male nudity never bothers, a credit to the directing and the cast' performances. Of course, as enchanting as it is, "A Room with a View" is less politically oriented than other Ivory-Merchant productions while there was more to say about socialism, feminism, weight of traditions, bourgeois insouciance, but the specific pretension of "A Room with a View" was to depict another slice of British life, from which two hearts would converge in a small point of the world, a room with a view  on the infinite, on the future, on love.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Pretty Entertaining
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gavin6942
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    When Lucy Honeychurch (Helena Bonham Carter) and chaperone Charlotte Bartlett find themselves in Florence with rooms without views, fellow guests Mr. Emerson and son George (Julian Sands) step in to remedy the situation. I watched this film knowing nothing about it because I wanted to see a Daniel Day-Lewis movie, and then I saw that Helena Bonham Carter and Julian Sands were in it. Carter was unknown to me until the 1990s, so it was a pleasant surprise to see her in such an early role. Sands is the one who steals the show, and it is a pity that it seems his career never hit the level it should. Day-Lewis is always good, though he plays a rather secondary role here. It would be hard to compare this to any of his other great performances, because certainly they overshadow this one.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    beauty crumbs
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Vincentiu
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    in this case, important is the taste. clear, delicate, special. like spring air. because , portrait of a society, charming love story, full of drops of lovely humor, creation of an extraordinary cast, adaptation of lovely novel, it is a kind of sentimental jewel - small, hided, admirable. a film like a state of soul. or slice of holiday because each viewer is part of it. because the joy of performance, the Italian images, the crumbs of Victorian manner to understand reality, the roots of a special revolution, the masks and the bath scene, Maggy Smith in one of her adorable roles, all is part of a seductive circle. a film like an open window.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    beautiful scenery...PC feminism in 1905
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    filmtherapy
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/3/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    An 18 or so year old girl Lucy Honeychurch and her chaperon Charlotte a middle aged spinster cousin go on a trip to Florence. There in a pension they encounter Mr Emerson and his son George. Mr. Emerson trades rooms with the women so that they might have rooms with views. George falls in love with Lucy and steals a kiss from her. Her chaperon sees this happen and returns Lucy at once to England. By chance Mr. Emerson and George rent a cottage near the Honeychurch's house... by this time Lucy is engaged to someone else. However true love wins out. I didn't care for the women's lib part of it (also the exaggerated era prudishness is cartoonish)....Lucy has spunk and George is the perfect milquetoast husband...."I want a wife who speaks her mind thinks on her own blah blah blah...." This turns it into a typical modern PC chick flick....no wonder it was popular. That was the "plot" and raison d'etre of the film other reviewers are looking for. I did like the beautiful scenery and wonderfully recreated world of the Edwardian era. It is a pretty movie to watch. OK watch
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    It's kind of like "Jane Eyre"....really.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    planktonrules
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/3/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The film is a story about manners--very, very, very proper and stuffy British manners during the Edwardian era. As a result of convention, Lucy (Carter) and George (Sands) are kept apart. Partway through watching "A Room With a View", I realized that, believe it or not, the underlying theme is the same as you'll find in "Jane Eyre"....seriously. Both concern social conventions and morality versus happiness and romantic passion. In the case of Jane, her love (Mr. Rochester) was not technically able to marry her and so she ran off--and lived, for a time, with a man in training to be a missionary and his family. The missionary had no passion at all for Jane but proposed--a marriage of convenience and intellect. Should she choose this good man or live with a man already married (Rochester)--albeit, his marriage was clearly a fraud perpetrated on him. Likewise, in "A Room With a View", Helena Bonham Carter's character must choose between a more worldly (and rather non-religious) Julian Sands or the incredibly stodgy and respectable fianc&eacute; (Daniel Day-Lewis). Either a marriage of predictability and convention or a marriage with passion, and, perhaps, irrespectability are her apparent choices. Now I am NOT complaining that the themes are the same...after all, "Jane Eyre" is one of my very favorite books (and is MUCH better than the movie versions). Some things to look for in this film--the gorgeous views of Florence, the lovely score and the funny (but very explicit) skinny-dipping scene. Clever and enjoyable...but also perhaps a bit slow due to its commentary about manners.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Edwardian Eyeful
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    AZINDN
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I will gush over this film because it is worthy of praise and a standing ovation. A Room With A View is likely one of the most perfect films to grace screens in decades. The E.M. Forrester story produced and directed by the team of Ivory and Merchant brings the tale of Miss Lucy Honeychurch (Helena Bonham-Carter) to life in perfect Edwardian splendor. Wonderful locations of the Florence cathedral, Palazzo Vecchio, sculpture by Donatello, and an assortment of rolling landscapes are stunning visual fodder for this comic tale of Apolonian vs. Dionesian parlor manners. Exquisite young Bonham-Carter's casting as the virginal heiress is thwarted by her traveling companion, the venerable Dame Maggie Smith as her meddling biddy chaperon, Aunt Charlotte, with Dame Judy Dench as a proto-Jackie Collins author, Elenore Lavish, Daniel Day-Lewis as the prissy snobbish Cecil Vyse, and, a gorgeous, naked Julian Sands as socialist George Emerson comprises a most outstanding casting achievement. The excellent soundtrack offering of Dame Kiri Te Kaniwa's rendition of "O Mio Caro" takes your breath away as are the bits of wonderful piano solos that Lucy produces throughout the film. The cinematography is most wonderful with scenic panoramas of the far off Florence or Lucy sauntering through a field of poppies and wildflowers to receive the kiss to curl your toes from George Emerson, well, can romantic love get any better? This video is required for collectors of films of Julian Sands and Daniel Day-Lewis, however, its real value is as one of the finest of the Merchant Ivory magic touch in film making.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Take A Back Room to A Room With A View **1/2
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    edwagreen
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    You don't need much room to view this disappointing 1985 film. The problem is that with the exception of Maggie Smith, who gives new meaning to spinsterhood, the characters are unbelievable in this brooding Merchant-Ivory piece set in the Victorian era. Daniel Day-Lewis comes off as a fop or dandy; even though he is engaged to Helena Bonham Carter here. She finds true love in Italy and it follows her back home in England. The film often drags The scene with the naked men was funny but the result was highly predictable. The men in particular are really off the wall in this film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Beautiful film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Wayne Malin (wwaayynnee51@hotmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/10/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    In the early 1900s young Lucy Honeychurch (Helena Bonham Carter) is on vacation in Italy. There they meet young, free-wheeling George Emerson (Julian Sands). Lucy and George fall in love but she backs off being afraid. Back in England she agrees to marry self-righteous obnoxious Cecil Vyes (Daniel Day-Lewis) because he's a "safe" choice. Then George (by chance) moves near her...and sparks start to fly. This is a costume drama and, like most of them, this is slow-moving and deliberately paced but I was never bored. The script is sharp, the movie looks beautiful and the cast is full of established English actors who know how to play their roles to the hilt. The only not so good acting was by Rupert Graves, Sands and Carter--but they were all very young when they did this so they were still learning. The only bad acting is by Daniel Day-Lewis. He plays his character so ridiculously obvious that he's just annoying. It's good that he has a small role. Also you probably think this is stuffy and dull...but there is a sequence when Graves, Sands and Simon Callow all go skinny-dipping! And yes--you see everything but it's all so innocent and fun that it's hard to be shocked. I saw it in a theatre and nobody was even remotely bothered. I'd say this is a costume drama for people who don't like costume dramas! Well worth seeing. I give it a 10!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Nearly perfect film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    avgjoedc
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/9/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I say its nearly perfect, but I really cant fault it for anything. The performances are uniformly exquisite, the visuals/scenery are magnificent, the script follows the classic novel - but keeps the humor, irony, and pathos open to a modern audience. It is the most accessible and most enjoyable of the Merchant & Ivory translations of classic works - and really elevates the magic of the original EM Forster novel. While the leads keep the story going, the smaller roles constantly keep you amused. The aged sisters, the carefree brother, the nervous mother, the vicar, the bold authoress, etc all provoke a smile. And the last 3 minutes are simply delightful.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A room with a view.....but I couldn't see much else
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    thomvic
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/5/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I suspected this movie was going to be a great drama with a good love story from what I read on the back of the DVD. Hmmmm well not really. For one thing, Helena Bonham Carter's character wasn't very sympathetic and it felt more like she was complaining or making snard remarks at everyone half the time. The whole Florence scenes felt more like they were trying to praise Italy for being a romantic place rather than giving it a real backing as a place of memory for Lucy Honeychurch and George. They had one fling when it could have happened anywhere. What's more, this feels like it could have done better in the theatre as a play and I'm not sure if there ever was one. This is definitely more dialogue driven than plot driven. Charlotte's character (Maggie Smith) feels more like Lucy's actual mother than her cousin and sometimes I had to remind myself she was her cousin than her mother. Performances were pretty good though I thought the characters weren't particularly interesting and also because the plot went at too quick of a pace to really make you absorb the emotions of the characters. Yes I know it is also meant to be a comedy as well but I didn't really find anything really funny. Though Daniel Day Lewis as Cecil was played to perfection and made for a very dorky character. Don't have too much expectations with this. It is fun and silly but in the end more of a play that doesn't really make you remember much.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    All the ways lead to Rome ... but Florence leads to all the ways ...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ElMaruecan82
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The remarkable thing about the Merchant-Ivory productions (in fact a solid triumvirate if we count the writer Ruth Prawer Jhabvala) is that they're generally less about plots than characters, and so real they never seem to act according to a specific screenplay, but are rather conditioned by the two main forces of the story: space and time. Indeed, over the course of time, relationships are done and undone and the coldest heart can melt like Anthony Hopkins in "The Remains of the Day". "Howard's End" was much about an estate, symbolizing the rural roots of British aristocracy, before it surrendered to business-driven modernism. Generally set at crucial periods of British history, the Merchant-Ivory productions are about people who are the products of their age while a new one is coming, and they generally use their houses as a symbolic stronghold to resist the ineluctable changes. And "A Room with a View", adapted from E.M Forster's novel of the same name, is the metaphor of the very point the story makes. Even the smallest room can open onto a large town, the sky, the infinite, like so many paths one can take from life, if he or she dares to get rid of the weight of past and conventions. A room can be made of a beds and austere furniture to welcome a young woman from a British hamlet, Lucy Honeychurch (Helena Bohnam Carter) and her restraining chaperon Charlotte (Maggie Smith), but it can offer a panoramic view of one of the most romantic towns in the world: Florence. And the first pages of this cinematic book open in Florence, in a small pension, where a group of vacationers meet. Miss Charlotte complains about the missing view in the room, to which, inviting during the following dinner a free-spirited man, Mr. Emerson (Delnhom Elliott) to proposes to switch their rooms. Emerson came with his son, and both belong to another class, up enough to afford a voyage to Italy, but whose philosophical views suggest that they embraced the turn-of-century, contrarily to the Victorian Charlotte, who refused the proposal, shocked by Emerson's lack of tact, while his reaction proves that he meant no disrespect.. She eventually accepts, convinced by other guests of the pension, Reverend Beebe (Simon Callow) and the old Allan sisters. This benign episode foreshadows the coming conflicts between the old and new order in England circa 1910, to which space and time provide crucial elements. The film is set during the Edwardian period; a sort of in-between decade where British people could nonchalantly enjoy the achievements of the more prestigious Victorian era, like a historical calm before the storm of the Great War. And being a film of dazzling imagery, the sight of these British vacationers enjoying a picnic in a Tuscan setting, savoring tea and bathing under a sepia summer sun, and a cool summer breeze, is an eloquent illustration of the quiet optimism that prevailed during that period. And this bourgeois idleness, combined with a natural setting, creates the perfect cocktail for a passionate romance, leading to the inevitable moment when the mysterious George Emerson, played by the handsome Julian Sands, gives a passionate kiss to an unchaperoned Lucy. She didn't see it coming, nor did she expect the kiss' everlasting effect, awakening the most passionate impulses. The kiss sweeps off all the conventions, the good manners that condemned Lucy to a life of rigidity, giving all its meaning to the setting in Florence, the most defining town of the Renaissance. Literally, George's kiss is Lucy's renaissance. But this is only the first act and back home; the kiss is already history after Charlotte's intervention. And when during the next scene, we meet Cecil Vyse, Daniel Day-Lewis as Lucy's future husband, a living caricature of snobbish prig with his oiled hair, rigid stature and annoying pince-nez, we're puzzled but not surprised. The film doesn't embarrass with explanations and trusts us enough to connect between the events together. So, regarding the mysterious choice of Cecyl as a husband, I guess, we should get back to the 'room with a view' metaphor. Indeed, with George, Lucy had 'a room with a view', with Cecyl, she would have thousands of rooms with no view at all. Breaking his eternally taciturn facade, George is given one opportunity to have a heart-talk with Lucy; he tells her that her marriage with Cecyl would turn her into an ornament, for the man would never be able to value her, or any woman for that matter. This is one of the outbursts of passion the film serves at the right moment to remind us that there is still a story after all, and a question: to which direction will Lucy's heart lean? And it's not just a choice between two men, but two orders, two states of mind, two ways of kissing. Roger Ebert, in one of his most enthusiastic reviews, insisted on the conflict between heart and mind, passion and intellect. I wish he had a few words about space and time as either the restraining or catalyzing elements in our lives. It's restraining when you have characters with the privilege to enjoy some escapism in a beautiful Italian landscape, but are still tied with Victorian good manners, or catalyzing, when three men, including a priest, play like children in a lake, all naked. The swimming sequence is exhilarating, and the massive male nudity never bothers, a credit to the directing and the cast' performances. Of course, as enchanting as it is, "A Room with a View" is less politically oriented than other Ivory-Merchant productions while there was more to say about socialism, feminism, weight of traditions, bourgeois insouciance, but the specific pretension of "A Room with a View" was to depict another slice of British life, from which two hearts would converge in a small point of the world, a room with a view  on the infinite, on the future, on love.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Pretty Entertaining
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gavin6942
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    When Lucy Honeychurch (Helena Bonham Carter) and chaperone Charlotte Bartlett find themselves in Florence with rooms without views, fellow guests Mr. Emerson and son George (Julian Sands) step in to remedy the situation. I watched this film knowing nothing about it because I wanted to see a Daniel Day-Lewis movie, and then I saw that Helena Bonham Carter and Julian Sands were in it. Carter was unknown to me until the 1990s, so it was a pleasant surprise to see her in such an early role. Sands is the one who steals the show, and it is a pity that it seems his career never hit the level it should. Day-Lewis is always good, though he plays a rather secondary role here. It would be hard to compare this to any of his other great performances, because certainly they overshadow this one.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    beauty crumbs
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Vincentiu
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    in this case, important is the taste. clear, delicate, special. like spring air. because , portrait of a society, charming love story, full of drops of lovely humor, creation of an extraordinary cast, adaptation of lovely novel, it is a kind of sentimental jewel - small, hided, admirable. a film like a state of soul. or slice of holiday because each viewer is part of it. because the joy of performance, the Italian images, the crumbs of Victorian manner to understand reality, the roots of a special revolution, the masks and the bath scene, Maggy Smith in one of her adorable roles, all is part of a seductive circle. a film like an open window.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    beautiful scenery...PC feminism in 1905
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    filmtherapy
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/3/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    An 18 or so year old girl Lucy Honeychurch and her chaperon Charlotte a middle aged spinster cousin go on a trip to Florence. There in a pension they encounter Mr Emerson and his son George. Mr. Emerson trades rooms with the women so that they might have rooms with views. George falls in love with Lucy and steals a kiss from her. Her chaperon sees this happen and returns Lucy at once to England. By chance Mr. Emerson and George rent a cottage near the Honeychurch's house... by this time Lucy is engaged to someone else. However true love wins out. I didn't care for the women's lib part of it (also the exaggerated era prudishness is cartoonish)....Lucy has spunk and George is the perfect milquetoast husband...."I want a wife who speaks her mind thinks on her own blah blah blah...." This turns it into a typical modern PC chick flick....no wonder it was popular. That was the "plot" and raison d'etre of the film other reviewers are looking for. I did like the beautiful scenery and wonderfully recreated world of the Edwardian era. It is a pretty movie to watch. OK watch
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    It's kind of like "Jane Eyre"....really.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    planktonrules
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/3/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The film is a story about manners--very, very, very proper and stuffy British manners during the Edwardian era. As a result of convention, Lucy (Carter) and George (Sands) are kept apart. Partway through watching "A Room With a View", I realized that, believe it or not, the underlying theme is the same as you'll find in "Jane Eyre"....seriously. Both concern social conventions and morality versus happiness and romantic passion. In the case of Jane, her love (Mr. Rochester) was not technically able to marry her and so she ran off--and lived, for a time, with a man in training to be a missionary and his family. The missionary had no passion at all for Jane but proposed--a marriage of convenience and intellect. Should she choose this good man or live with a man already married (Rochester)--albeit, his marriage was clearly a fraud perpetrated on him. Likewise, in "A Room With a View", Helena Bonham Carter's character must choose between a more worldly (and rather non-religious) Julian Sands or the incredibly stodgy and respectable fianc&eacute; (Daniel Day-Lewis). Either a marriage of predictability and convention or a marriage with passion, and, perhaps, irrespectability are her apparent choices. Now I am NOT complaining that the themes are the same...after all, "Jane Eyre" is one of my very favorite books (and is MUCH better than the movie versions). Some things to look for in this film--the gorgeous views of Florence, the lovely score and the funny (but very explicit) skinny-dipping scene. Clever and enjoyable...but also perhaps a bit slow due to its commentary about manners.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Edwardian Eyeful
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    AZINDN
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I will gush over this film because it is worthy of praise and a standing ovation. A Room With A View is likely one of the most perfect films to grace screens in decades. The E.M. Forrester story produced and directed by the team of Ivory and Merchant brings the tale of Miss Lucy Honeychurch (Helena Bonham-Carter) to life in perfect Edwardian splendor. Wonderful locations of the Florence cathedral, Palazzo Vecchio, sculpture by Donatello, and an assortment of rolling landscapes are stunning visual fodder for this comic tale of Apolonian vs. Dionesian parlor manners. Exquisite young Bonham-Carter's casting as the virginal heiress is thwarted by her traveling companion, the venerable Dame Maggie Smith as her meddling biddy chaperon, Aunt Charlotte, with Dame Judy Dench as a proto-Jackie Collins author, Elenore Lavish, Daniel Day-Lewis as the prissy snobbish Cecil Vyse, and, a gorgeous, naked Julian Sands as socialist George Emerson comprises a most outstanding casting achievement. The excellent soundtrack offering of Dame Kiri Te Kaniwa's rendition of "O Mio Caro" takes your breath away as are the bits of wonderful piano solos that Lucy produces throughout the film. The cinematography is most wonderful with scenic panoramas of the far off Florence or Lucy sauntering through a field of poppies and wildflowers to receive the kiss to curl your toes from George Emerson, well, can romantic love get any better? This video is required for collectors of films of Julian Sands and Daniel Day-Lewis, however, its real value is as one of the finest of the Merchant Ivory magic touch in film making.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Take A Back Room to A Room With A View **1/2
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    edwagreen
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    You don't need much room to view this disappointing 1985 film. The problem is that with the exception of Maggie Smith, who gives new meaning to spinsterhood, the characters are unbelievable in this brooding Merchant-Ivory piece set in the Victorian era. Daniel Day-Lewis comes off as a fop or dandy; even though he is engaged to Helena Bonham Carter here. She finds true love in Italy and it follows her back home in England. The film often drags The scene with the naked men was funny but the result was highly predictable. The men in particular are really off the wall in this film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Beautiful film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Wayne Malin (wwaayynnee51@hotmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/10/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    In the early 1900s young Lucy Honeychurch (Helena Bonham Carter) is on vacation in Italy. There they meet young, free-wheeling George Emerson (Julian Sands). Lucy and George fall in love but she backs off being afraid. Back in England she agrees to marry self-righteous obnoxious Cecil Vyes (Daniel Day-Lewis) because he's a "safe" choice. Then George (by chance) moves near her...and sparks start to fly. This is a costume drama and, like most of them, this is slow-moving and deliberately paced but I was never bored. The script is sharp, the movie looks beautiful and the cast is full of established English actors who know how to play their roles to the hilt. The only not so good acting was by Rupert Graves, Sands and Carter--but they were all very young when they did this so they were still learning. The only bad acting is by Daniel Day-Lewis. He plays his character so ridiculously obvious that he's just annoying. It's good that he has a small role. Also you probably think this is stuffy and dull...but there is a sequence when Graves, Sands and Simon Callow all go skinny-dipping! And yes--you see everything but it's all so innocent and fun that it's hard to be shocked. I saw it in a theatre and nobody was even remotely bothered. I'd say this is a costume drama for people who don't like costume dramas! Well worth seeing. I give it a 10!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Nearly perfect film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    avgjoedc
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/9/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I say its nearly perfect, but I really cant fault it for anything. The performances are uniformly exquisite, the visuals/scenery are magnificent, the script follows the classic novel - but keeps the humor, irony, and pathos open to a modern audience. It is the most accessible and most enjoyable of the Merchant & Ivory translations of classic works - and really elevates the magic of the original EM Forster novel. While the leads keep the story going, the smaller roles constantly keep you amused. The aged sisters, the carefree brother, the nervous mother, the vicar, the bold authoress, etc all provoke a smile. And the last 3 minutes are simply delightful.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A room with a view.....but I couldn't see much else
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    thomvic
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/5/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I suspected this movie was going to be a great drama with a good love story from what I read on the back of the DVD. Hmmmm well not really. For one thing, Helena Bonham Carter's character wasn't very sympathetic and it felt more like she was complaining or making snard remarks at everyone half the time. The whole Florence scenes felt more like they were trying to praise Italy for being a romantic place rather than giving it a real backing as a place of memory for Lucy Honeychurch and George. They had one fling when it could have happened anywhere. What's more, this feels like it could have done better in the theatre as a play and I'm not sure if there ever was one. This is definitely more dialogue driven than plot driven. Charlotte's character (Maggie Smith) feels more like Lucy's actual mother than her cousin and sometimes I had to remind myself she was her cousin than her mother. Performances were pretty good though I thought the characters weren't particularly interesting and also because the plot went at too quick of a pace to really make you absorb the emotions of the characters. Yes I know it is also meant to be a comedy as well but I didn't really find anything really funny. Though Daniel Day Lewis as Cecil was played to perfection and made for a very dorky character. Don't have too much expectations with this. It is fun and silly but in the end more of a play that doesn't really make you remember much.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    All the ways lead to Rome ... but Florence leads to all the ways ...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ElMaruecan82
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The remarkable thing about the Merchant-Ivory productions (in fact a solid triumvirate if we count the writer Ruth Prawer Jhabvala) is that they're generally less about plots than characters, and so real they never seem to act according to a specific screenplay, but are rather conditioned by the two main forces of the story: space and time. Indeed, over the course of time, relationships are done and undone and the coldest heart can melt like Anthony Hopkins in "The Remains of the Day". "Howard's End" was much about an estate, symbolizing the rural roots of British aristocracy, before it surrendered to business-driven modernism. Generally set at crucial periods of British history, the Merchant-Ivory productions are about people who are the products of their age while a new one is coming, and they generally use their houses as a symbolic stronghold to resist the ineluctable changes. And "A Room with a View", adapted from E.M Forster's novel of the same name, is the metaphor of the very point the story makes. Even the smallest room can open onto a large town, the sky, the infinite, like so many paths one can take from life, if he or she dares to get rid of the weight of past and conventions. A room can be made of a beds and austere furniture to welcome a young woman from a British hamlet, Lucy Honeychurch (Helena Bohnam Carter) and her restraining chaperon Charlotte (Maggie Smith), but it can offer a panoramic view of one of the most romantic towns in the world: Florence. And the first pages of this cinematic book open in Florence, in a small pension, where a group of vacationers meet. Miss Charlotte complains about the missing view in the room, to which, inviting during the following dinner a free-spirited man, Mr. Emerson (Delnhom Elliott) to proposes to switch their rooms. Emerson came with his son, and both belong to another class, up enough to afford a voyage to Italy, but whose philosophical views suggest that they embraced the turn-of-century, contrarily to the Victorian Charlotte, who refused the proposal, shocked by Emerson's lack of tact, while his reaction proves that he meant no disrespect.. She eventually accepts, convinced by other guests of the pension, Reverend Beebe (Simon Callow) and the old Allan sisters. This benign episode foreshadows the coming conflicts between the old and new order in England circa 1910, to which space and time provide crucial elements. The film is set during the Edwardian period; a sort of in-between decade where British people could nonchalantly enjoy the achievements of the more prestigious Victorian era, like a historical calm before the storm of the Great War. And being a film of dazzling imagery, the sight of these British vacationers enjoying a picnic in a Tuscan setting, savoring tea and bathing under a sepia summer sun, and a cool summer breeze, is an eloquent illustration of the quiet optimism that prevailed during that period. And this bourgeois idleness, combined with a natural setting, creates the perfect cocktail for a passionate romance, leading to the inevitable moment when the mysterious George Emerson, played by the handsome Julian Sands, gives a passionate kiss to an unchaperoned Lucy. She didn't see it coming, nor did she expect the kiss' everlasting effect, awakening the most passionate impulses. The kiss sweeps off all the conventions, the good manners that condemned Lucy to a life of rigidity, giving all its meaning to the setting in Florence, the most defining town of the Renaissance. Literally, George's kiss is Lucy's renaissance. But this is only the first act and back home; the kiss is already history after Charlotte's intervention. And when during the next scene, we meet Cecil Vyse, Daniel Day-Lewis as Lucy's future husband, a living caricature of snobbish prig with his oiled hair, rigid stature and annoying pince-nez, we're puzzled but not surprised. The film doesn't embarrass with explanations and trusts us enough to connect between the events together. So, regarding the mysterious choice of Cecyl as a husband, I guess, we should get back to the 'room with a view' metaphor. Indeed, with George, Lucy had 'a room with a view', with Cecyl, she would have thousands of rooms with no view at all. Breaking his eternally taciturn facade, George is given one opportunity to have a heart-talk with Lucy; he tells her that her marriage with Cecyl would turn her into an ornament, for the man would never be able to value her, or any woman for that matter. This is one of the outbursts of passion the film serves at the right moment to remind us that there is still a story after all, and a question: to which direction will Lucy's heart lean? And it's not just a choice between two men, but two orders, two states of mind, two ways of kissing. Roger Ebert, in one of his most enthusiastic reviews, insisted on the conflict between heart and mind, passion and intellect. I wish he had a few words about space and time as either the restraining or catalyzing elements in our lives. It's restraining when you have characters with the privilege to enjoy some escapism in a beautiful Italian landscape, but are still tied with Victorian good manners, or catalyzing, when three men, including a priest, play like children in a lake, all naked. The swimming sequence is exhilarating, and the massive male nudity never bothers, a credit to the directing and the cast' performances. Of course, as enchanting as it is, "A Room with a View" is less politically oriented than other Ivory-Merchant productions while there was more to say about socialism, feminism, weight of traditions, bourgeois insouciance, but the specific pretension of "A Room with a View" was to depict another slice of British life, from which two hearts would converge in a small point of the world, a room with a view  on the infinite, on the future, on love.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Pretty Entertaining
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gavin6942
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    When Lucy Honeychurch (Helena Bonham Carter) and chaperone Charlotte Bartlett find themselves in Florence with rooms without views, fellow guests Mr. Emerson and son George (Julian Sands) step in to remedy the situation. I watched this film knowing nothing about it because I wanted to see a Daniel Day-Lewis movie, and then I saw that Helena Bonham Carter and Julian Sands were in it. Carter was unknown to me until the 1990s, so it was a pleasant surprise to see her in such an early role. Sands is the one who steals the show, and it is a pity that it seems his career never hit the level it should. Day-Lewis is always good, though he plays a rather secondary role here. It would be hard to compare this to any of his other great performances, because certainly they overshadow this one.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    beauty crumbs
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Vincentiu
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    in this case, important is the taste. clear, delicate, special. like spring air. because , portrait of a society, charming love story, full of drops of lovely humor, creation of an extraordinary cast, adaptation of lovely novel, it is a kind of sentimental jewel - small, hided, admirable. a film like a state of soul. or slice of holiday because each viewer is part of it. because the joy of performance, the Italian images, the crumbs of Victorian manner to understand reality, the roots of a special revolution, the masks and the bath scene, Maggy Smith in one of her adorable roles, all is part of a seductive circle. a film like an open window.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    beautiful scenery...PC feminism in 1905
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    filmtherapy
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/3/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    An 18 or so year old girl Lucy Honeychurch and her chaperon Charlotte a middle aged spinster cousin go on a trip to Florence. There in a pension they encounter Mr Emerson and his son George. Mr. Emerson trades rooms with the women so that they might have rooms with views. George falls in love with Lucy and steals a kiss from her. Her chaperon sees this happen and returns Lucy at once to England. By chance Mr. Emerson and George rent a cottage near the Honeychurch's house... by this time Lucy is engaged to someone else. However true love wins out. I didn't care for the women's lib part of it (also the exaggerated era prudishness is cartoonish)....Lucy has spunk and George is the perfect milquetoast husband...."I want a wife who speaks her mind thinks on her own blah blah blah...." This turns it into a typical modern PC chick flick....no wonder it was popular. That was the "plot" and raison d'etre of the film other reviewers are looking for. I did like the beautiful scenery and wonderfully recreated world of the Edwardian era. It is a pretty movie to watch. OK watch
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    It's kind of like "Jane Eyre"....really.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    planktonrules
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/3/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The film is a story about manners--very, very, very proper and stuffy British manners during the Edwardian era. As a result of convention, Lucy (Carter) and George (Sands) are kept apart. Partway through watching "A Room With a View", I realized that, believe it or not, the underlying theme is the same as you'll find in "Jane Eyre"....seriously. Both concern social conventions and morality versus happiness and romantic passion. In the case of Jane, her love (Mr. Rochester) was not technically able to marry her and so she ran off--and lived, for a time, with a man in training to be a missionary and his family. The missionary had no passion at all for Jane but proposed--a marriage of convenience and intellect. Should she choose this good man or live with a man already married (Rochester)--albeit, his marriage was clearly a fraud perpetrated on him. Likewise, in "A Room With a View", Helena Bonham Carter's character must choose between a more worldly (and rather non-religious) Julian Sands or the incredibly stodgy and respectable fianc&eacute; (Daniel Day-Lewis). Either a marriage of predictability and convention or a marriage with passion, and, perhaps, irrespectability are her apparent choices. Now I am NOT complaining that the themes are the same...after all, "Jane Eyre" is one of my very favorite books (and is MUCH better than the movie versions). Some things to look for in this film--the gorgeous views of Florence, the lovely score and the funny (but very explicit) skinny-dipping scene. Clever and enjoyable...but also perhaps a bit slow due to its commentary about manners.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Edwardian Eyeful
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    AZINDN
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I will gush over this film because it is worthy of praise and a standing ovation. A Room With A View is likely one of the most perfect films to grace screens in decades. The E.M. Forrester story produced and directed by the team of Ivory and Merchant brings the tale of Miss Lucy Honeychurch (Helena Bonham-Carter) to life in perfect Edwardian splendor. Wonderful locations of the Florence cathedral, Palazzo Vecchio, sculpture by Donatello, and an assortment of rolling landscapes are stunning visual fodder for this comic tale of Apolonian vs. Dionesian parlor manners. Exquisite young Bonham-Carter's casting as the virginal heiress is thwarted by her traveling companion, the venerable Dame Maggie Smith as her meddling biddy chaperon, Aunt Charlotte, with Dame Judy Dench as a proto-Jackie Collins author, Elenore Lavish, Daniel Day-Lewis as the prissy snobbish Cecil Vyse, and, a gorgeous, naked Julian Sands as socialist George Emerson comprises a most outstanding casting achievement. The excellent soundtrack offering of Dame Kiri Te Kaniwa's rendition of "O Mio Caro" takes your breath away as are the bits of wonderful piano solos that Lucy produces throughout the film. The cinematography is most wonderful with scenic panoramas of the far off Florence or Lucy sauntering through a field of poppies and wildflowers to receive the kiss to curl your toes from George Emerson, well, can romantic love get any better? This video is required for collectors of films of Julian Sands and Daniel Day-Lewis, however, its real value is as one of the finest of the Merchant Ivory magic touch in film making.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Take A Back Room to A Room With A View **1/2
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    edwagreen
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    You don't need much room to view this disappointing 1985 film. The problem is that with the exception of Maggie Smith, who gives new meaning to spinsterhood, the characters are unbelievable in this brooding Merchant-Ivory piece set in the Victorian era. Daniel Day-Lewis comes off as a fop or dandy; even though he is engaged to Helena Bonham Carter here. She finds true love in Italy and it follows her back home in England. The film often drags The scene with the naked men was funny but the result was highly predictable. The men in particular are really off the wall in this film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Beautiful film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Wayne Malin (wwaayynnee51@hotmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/10/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    In the early 1900s young Lucy Honeychurch (Helena Bonham Carter) is on vacation in Italy. There they meet young, free-wheeling George Emerson (Julian Sands). Lucy and George fall in love but she backs off being afraid. Back in England she agrees to marry self-righteous obnoxious Cecil Vyes (Daniel Day-Lewis) because he's a "safe" choice. Then George (by chance) moves near her...and sparks start to fly. This is a costume drama and, like most of them, this is slow-moving and deliberately paced but I was never bored. The script is sharp, the movie looks beautiful and the cast is full of established English actors who know how to play their roles to the hilt. The only not so good acting was by Rupert Graves, Sands and Carter--but they were all very young when they did this so they were still learning. The only bad acting is by Daniel Day-Lewis. He plays his character so ridiculously obvious that he's just annoying. It's good that he has a small role. Also you probably think this is stuffy and dull...but there is a sequence when Graves, Sands and Simon Callow all go skinny-dipping! And yes--you see everything but it's all so innocent and fun that it's hard to be shocked. I saw it in a theatre and nobody was even remotely bothered. I'd say this is a costume drama for people who don't like costume dramas! Well worth seeing. I give it a 10!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Nearly perfect film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    avgjoedc
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/9/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I say its nearly perfect, but I really cant fault it for anything. The performances are uniformly exquisite, the visuals/scenery are magnificent, the script follows the classic novel - but keeps the humor, irony, and pathos open to a modern audience. It is the most accessible and most enjoyable of the Merchant & Ivory translations of classic works - and really elevates the magic of the original EM Forster novel. While the leads keep the story going, the smaller roles constantly keep you amused. The aged sisters, the carefree brother, the nervous mother, the vicar, the bold authoress, etc all provoke a smile. And the last 3 minutes are simply delightful.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A room with a view.....but I couldn't see much else
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    thomvic
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/5/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I suspected this movie was going to be a great drama with a good love story from what I read on the back of the DVD. Hmmmm well not really. For one thing, Helena Bonham Carter's character wasn't very sympathetic and it felt more like she was complaining or making snard remarks at everyone half the time. The whole Florence scenes felt more like they were trying to praise Italy for being a romantic place rather than giving it a real backing as a place of memory for Lucy Honeychurch and George. They had one fling when it could have happened anywhere. What's more, this feels like it could have done better in the theatre as a play and I'm not sure if there ever was one. This is definitely more dialogue driven than plot driven. Charlotte's character (Maggie Smith) feels more like Lucy's actual mother than her cousin and sometimes I had to remind myself she was her cousin than her mother. Performances were pretty good though I thought the characters weren't particularly interesting and also because the plot went at too quick of a pace to really make you absorb the emotions of the characters. Yes I know it is also meant to be a comedy as well but I didn't really find anything really funny. Though Daniel Day Lewis as Cecil was played to perfection and made for a very dorky character. Don't have too much expectations with this. It is fun and silly but in the end more of a play that doesn't really make you remember much.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
 </reviews>
</filme>
