<filme>
 <id>
  229
 </id>
 <imdburl>
  http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0088170
 </imdburl>
 <ano>
  1984
 </ano>
 <titulo>
  Jornada nas Estrelas III - &Agrave; Procura de Spock
 </titulo>
 <rating>
  6.5
 </rating>
 <sinopse>
  Admiral Kirk and his bridge crew risk their careers stealing the decommissioned Enterprise to return to the restricted Genesis planet to recover Spock's body.
 </sinopse>
 <storyline>
  Following Kirk's encounter with Khan that left the Enterprise severely damaged and Spock dead, they return to Starfleet so that Enterprise could be repaired. Kirk's hoping to go back to the newly-created Genesis planet where he laid Spock to rest. But upon arriving, he is told that the Enterprise will not be repaired and that Genesis has become a delicate matter and until it is resolved, no one is allowed to go there or talk about it. McCoy is also acting strangely and is later detained when he starts talking about Genesis. Kirk is visited by Spock's father Sarek, who tells him that he betrayed Spock because being placed on Genesis was not what he would have wanted. He tells Kirk he is supposed to bring Spock's body along with his soul or katra as the Vulcans call it which he passes onto someone, and bring it to Vulcan for the final rites. Sarek assumes Kirk would have it but he does not. Kirk then thinks that Spock may have passed it someone else and realizes McCoy is the one who has...
 </storyline>
 <generos>
  <genero>
   Action
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Adventure
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Sci-Fi
  </genero>
 </generos>
 <keywords>
  <keyword>
   klingon
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   planet
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   vulcan
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   admiral
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   soul
  </keyword>
 </keywords>
 <diretores>
  <diretor>
   Leonard Nimoy
  </diretor>
 </diretores>
 <escritores>
  <escritor>
   Gene Roddenberry
  </escritor>
  <escritor>
   Harve Bennett
  </escritor>
 </escritores>
 <atores>
  <ator>
   William Shatner
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Leonard Nimoy
  </ator>
  <ator>
   DeForest Kelley
  </ator>
 </atores>
 <reviews>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Figures They'd Save Spock
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    wfjohnston14
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Star Trek III: The Search for Spock is a good film that follows right after the second film. This film, directed by Leonard Nimoy, is a nice film to add to the Star Trek Franchise. The Enterprise crew risks their careers as they take the decommissioned Enterprise to search for Spock's body. They find that Spock's body is missing and go searching for it and find a Vulcan boy instead who looks like Spock. Also, they intercept a Klingon ship at the planet too that puts one of the members of the Enterprise in danger and losing their life. What happened to Spock? Will the Enterprise survive against the Klingon? And what will happen to Kirk? This film is a good film, it has problems, but it is a very good film that is very entertaining and brings back Spock. When Spock's body landed on the planet that was being powered by Genesis, his body regenerated and that's why they found him as a boy. The one problem though is that the planet is regenerating too fast and is soon falling apart and Spock too is aging rapidly. He then is himself, but with no memory, so when they take the Klingon ship back to Vulcan, he and McCoy mind meld and Spock is better. Spock gave McCoy his memory right before he died. The crew member that dies is Kirk's son and he gets very emotional and later to save the crew, destroys the ship and they escape using the Klingon ship. This film is a nice addition and puts things back to where they used to be, everyone alright and ready to go on new adventures. A job well done Nimoy. Me: B
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not quite stronger, but a lot better than the original
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gavin-thelordofthefu-48-460297
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    While Star Trek III may not be as strong or as epic as the Wrath of Khan, it is however a lot better than the original in some ways. The story is fine aside from a few over-the-top moments and mediocre dialog; the script is decent it helped explain the Enterprise group's attempt to find Spock, who died in the end of Star Trek II and the pacing moves along very nicely. The scenery is great and the visuals are terrific. The acting is still solid and aside from William Shatner and Leonard Nimoy, Christopher Lloyd is so enjoyable as Kruge. The music score from James Horner is rousing and the action sequences are thrilling. Overall, not strong, but an enjoyable entry to the franchise even though I'm not a Trekkie.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Standing Proof That Odd Numbered Treks Aren't Always Bad
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Jacob Jefferson (jjgooner@yahoo.co.uk)
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Star Trek III: The Search for Spock *** (out of 4) 102 mins/ PG Cast: William Shatner, Leonard Nimoy, DeForest Kelley, James Doohan, George Takei, Robin Curts, Merritt Butrick, Christopher Lloyd Director: Leonard Nimoy Plot: Admiral Kirk is forced to steal the Enterprise ship and return to planet Genesis to find Spock's lifeless body. JJ's Verdict: Anyone who says all odd numbered Star Trek films are bad is totally wrong. In fact I even prefer The Search for Spock to the superior (so the majority says) Wrath of Khan. Following on from its predecessor, the film constantly references to events from it. While doing this it uses great footage and piles on Kirk's emotional baggage from Spock's 'death' scene. I put death in commas because as the film suggests and his actor's name in the cast list, Spock isn't actually dead. He mind-melted with Kelley's Dr. McCoy and left his body on Genesis. This film follows Kirk and his crew in their recovery of the body and their fight to stop the evil Klingons form inhabiting the planet. This revelation that Spock isn't dead, although fine as a plot element, sort of takes away the effect the final scene of Wrath of Khan has on you. The Search for Spock actually has a much clearer plot than the previous films and although it might be a tiny bit predictable at times, at least it is easier to follow than past Star Trek ventures. The way the film weaves between three groups of people (Kirk and his crew, The Klingons and Saavik and David) keeps the film very interesting and engaging throughout and almost makes it feel like an ensemble piece. The film has both improved special effects and space battles and the acting is very good throughout. William Shatner leads the front-line once again and also tops his performance from Star Trek II. And Christopher Lloyd's Klingon, despite not looking very convincing, plays it pretty scary. The scene in which Kirk and the crew steal The Enterprise is highly amusing and is great tongue-in-cheek humour. Leonard Nimoy, although consistently good as Spock, really finds his speciality in directing. His direction of all the actors really makes you care about their characters and he achieves something that, yet again, the previous two films couldn't do; he kept the audience interested. The film ends on a fitting high note and makes you feel very satisfied. And although Kirk seems to think so, I haven't had enough of this film and wish every Trek could be like this.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Decent Star Trek Movie,But Dosen't Live Up To Wrath Of Khan,
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Dillon Harris
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Star Trek 3: The Search For Spock is a pretty good movie with a decent storyline but a very strong cast.It's definitely not the worst in the Star Trek film series,but it's not the best either.It doesn't live up to it's predecessor,Star Trek 2: The Wrath Of Khan,but it's still a lot better than Star Trek: The Motion Picture.The Search For Spock still has a lot of great action sequences and although it's missing Leonard Nimoy for most of the movie,it's still delivers very strong performances from the other cast members,William Shatner is as good as ever in this movie as Cpatain James T. Kirk.While I feel huge Star Trek fans will be disappointed with the Search For Spockk,they will still get a good kick out of him and wont be entirely unimpressed. Captain Kirk (William Shatner) heads off with his crew on the Enterprise to the Genesis planet to save Spock (Leonard Nimoy,who also directs),who may still be alive.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "Turn death into a fighting chance to live."
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Al_The_Strange
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    With the rip-roaring success of The Wrath of Khan, the studios greenlit the third classic Trek film with Spock himself as the director. The problem is, with the way the last film ended, Spock couldn't be in the actual film. It was only natural that the next step in the series was to bring Spock back; hence, the search. The Search for Spock starts off a bit brooding, but quickly taps into the right adventurous spirit as the Enterprise crew becomes renegades and gives the Federation a hilarious slip. From then on, with bad run-ins with Klingons, the stakes are raised very high, and the struggle becomes quite epic. A few scenes stand out as being fairly epic and jaw-dropping. It is an entertaining thrill ride overall. My only beef with the film is that it still feels very small-scale. A lot of it might be because pitting the Enterprise crew against one small greedy band of Klingon rogues, led by a rather flat one-dimensional villain, just doesn't compare to everything we've already seen in The Wrath of Khan. Let's face it, Khan was too good of a villain, and nothing Captain Kruge does can outstage that. Not even the constant raising of the stakes, and confrontations with death, are able to elevate the film above and beyond the limited confines of its own plot. Despite those quibbles, the film still does the best it can to one-up most things, and still deliver the best story it can. The classic Trek crew remains a fun, endearing, and well-rounded group of characters, and their adventure follows a solid plot structure. Themes of rebirth, initially introduced in the last film, are reinforced here. This film boasts solid, steady photography and editing. Acting is not bad: William Shatner, Leonard Nimoy, DeForest Kelley, and the other classic Trek cast members reprise their roles with good nuance, and with a little more tongue-in-cheek attitude. Christopher Lloyd plays the villain quite memorably, even if the character is a two-bit scumbag. This production has some really good-looking sets, props, costumes, and special effects. The music score has more of the same from the last film, and that's not bad. On its own, this film is fun and satisfying, but understanding its story may rely pretty heavily on seeing The Wrath of Khan first. As such, it's best recommended as an immediate follow-up. 4/5 (Entertainment: Very Good | Story: Pretty Good | Film: Very Good)
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I'm still searching for answers
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ironhorse_iv
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie didn't answer much. Search for Spock has some aspect of the Star Trek theme, but it is very poorly handled. Still, not bad for Leonard Nimoy's first directed film. This one isn't as bad as the other odd numbered installments, especially if you factor in the fact that it ties what happen in the events of the previous Star Trek movie 'Wrath of Khan' so well. If you are a first time viewer of this movie, I wouldn't watch this movie until you watch Wrath of Khan first. It's very important to watch that movie before this. Yes, Star Trek III: The Search for Spock came after that movie, and being after such a masterpiece, people going to look at it being worst compare to that film. No, Star Trek film can live up to that film. Still the movie has some OK action scenes and interesting story. The movie starts out with recaps of the last few minutes of Wrath of Khan and then the movie officially begins. A spy has deliver some information about the Genesis program that Klingon commander Kruge (Christopher Lloyd) needs to hear. It seems like Genesis does, what Nintendo don't. What I meant by that is that Genesis has create life on a planet. The Klingons see this as a weapon to have. The Klingons were always Russian allegory in these films. So hearing this, must have been the same feeling when the Soviets heard about the Atom Bomb. Still, I cannot get over the fact that Christopher Lloyd is playing a Klingon, here. I was expecting him to shout "Great Scott!" or something. His character is quite stupid and silly at times. Just watch the killer plant scene, you can't help laughing at him. He's just not that menacing enough and not epic to the likes of Khan. Well, the Klingons are not the only ones hearing voices, but Dr. McCoy (De Forest Kelly) is talking all crazy about a certain Vulcan name Spock and that Captain Kirk (William Shatner) and the crew should go to Genesis to search for him. Now it's a quest between the crew of the Enterprise to rescue Spock before the Klingons get a hold of the planet. This movie suffers from the typical middle child syndrome of being a 2nd movie in a trilogy's story arc. Star Trek III: The Search For Spock is the second chapter of what is called by some fans "the Star Trek Trilogy", yes it is the third film of the series, but it's the second act in what is indeed a three parter. The first act is in Wrath of Khan, concerning its events leading up to somebody's death. The second act is in Search for Spock where somebody soul and body have to be re united and the third is in Voyage Home where somebody fully regains himself. My biggest problem with Start Trek 3 is that I feel it takes away from the impact of 2. The whole idea of life and death at the end of the 2nd one regarding a death of a character and the birth of a new planet is breath taking. Then this movie has Genesis's kind of break that apart! Breaking apart is a theme here. This film shows that Kirk ends up losing so much more than a friend. He sacrifices his ship, loses a family member and hope. The scene where Kirk is forced to relive his friend's death when he does the mind meld is a wonderful scene. The problem is when you look at how strong, 2 is with its story and themes and how this one causes those scenes to be all for nothing. It's disappointing. I think the worst idea is bringing back a character back after such a heroic death. The needs of the many outweigh the needs of the few. Captain Kirk's friend is noted to say for the reasons and justifying about his sacrifice. I believe that if you kill a character, then that character should stays dead. It does no favors for somebody to kill a character, only to bring them back in a later movie. Its movies like this, that started the 'resurrection of Jesus' concept of bringing dead characters back to live. A good example is Ellen Ripley who dies in Alien 3 only to be given an awful new spin in Alien Resurrection. It's like Nimoy woke up and realize how much money he can make, if he brings back a beloved character back to life. At less, this character got a good story on how he came back, so I can't complain too loudly. Still, it makes you wonders if Genesis was aging faster and faster; how come Kirk's friend didn't aged out as well. Wouldn't he die again by old age? Also how comes, nobody else aged on the planet if Genesis does that to life forms? Wouldn't they also grow older as long as they stay on the planet? The science is baffling. Also what's baffling is how Kristie Alley regenerated to Robin Curtis. It's seem like Alley didn't want to return, so the character was rewritten as a new character as Savvik. I find the Pon-Farr scene, stupid as hell. And where was David Marcus's mother, Carol? It would've been interesting to have her in Saavik's place down on Genesis and it would make more sense. The movie's over all is that it's works to a level, but compare to others. It's not that awesome. Still, it's worth the watch, so check it out. So start trekking.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Needs of the many do indeed outweigh the needs of the few with this film!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    illbebackreviews
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    As a countdown to 'Star Trek: Into Darkness', I decided to watch every single Star Trek movie for the first time. After the brilliant second film, I was excited to watch this one despite not being sure of what to expect. I had heard a lot of criticism about this movie calling it a cheap business trick. 'Star Trek III: The Search for Spock' basically follows the story of Admiral Kirk who has a tough time getting over the loss of his Vulcan friend, Spock. When Bones begins to act strangely, acting as if he is Spock, Kirk begins to realize, with the help of Spock's father, that maybe Spock can be brought back to life if his body and his mind (in this case Bones) are re-united and a spell cast to re-join the two however Klingon Commander, Kruge, played by Christopher Llyod turns out to be the only obstacle as he is in pursuit for the secrets to Genesis. There were quite a few things I really liked about this movie. Much like Star Trek II, I really liked the villain here played brilliantly by Christopher Llyod, who honestly feels the scene stealer in this film. I do love much of the story and I do not believe that this feels like a cash grab, unlike movies such as the Star Wars prequels which were made entirely for merchandising rights and not for story. The story was handled well and it wasn't anything like Spock never died but much more deep. Also the adventure that this movie has is great and I loved all the movie until the last half hour where much of the film becomes rather silly and could easily have been cut down or it could've been directed much better than it was. **SPOILERS AHEAD*** Of course, I am referring to when Kirk attempts to lure Kruge back to the now destructing Genesis and the two fight. Obviously, this fight looks terrible. I am not after any choreographed fight sequence that goes on neither is the fight the big mistake here. It is how this fight ends and Kruge is killed in an extremely silly and childish manner, with Kirk remarking "I have had enough of you!" This is literally the end of the majority of the story until the film truly needs to wrap up. **END OF SPOILERS** Now the film does need a good 20 minutes to truly wrap up and it does get slow and the greatness of the most of the rest of the film truly drops for me here. I am sick of people bashing the multiple endings to 'The Lord of the Rings: The Return of the King' stating that the endings were too many and too long. In that case, people do not realize that the Lord of the Rings is ranked 'Massive' on a scale. It needs those endings to wrap up a 12 hour trilogy...This film doesn't need 20 minutes to wrap up. This ending could've been 10 minutes and would've been perfect or the last 10 minutes or so could've been cut and as a cliffhanger, be added into the beginning of the next Star Trek film and I'm guessing it would work, considering the movie ends with 'The adventure continues...' The special effects were truly sloppy in this movie and such moments like when the Enterprise is destroyed and Genesis is being destroyed certainly do look bad. The acting is mostly good by the crew and was quite a pity to see a re-cast for Saavik...I truly loved the one from Star Trek II and yet, despite this new one being good, the Saavik from Wrath of Khan was superior. In the end, I can say that 'Star Trek III: The Search for Spock' is a good movie and would be considerably better had that 20 minute ending to a 1 hr 45 minute movie not got in the way. That being said, this movie is still fun and has considerable entertainment and displays such adventurous quality to a fun Sci Fi movie and a rather good and worthy addition to Star Trek.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Good Search It Is
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Michael_Elliott
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Star Trek III: The Search for Spock (1984) *** (out of 4) After the events in the previous film, Kirk (William Shatner) risks his career by stealing the Enterprise to go to a restricted planet in hopes of finding Spock's body who they feel might be alive. Along the way they run into a Klingon leader (Christopher Lloyd) who wants to kill them all. STAR TREK III: THE SEARCH OF SPOCK probably shouldn't have worked since if you've seen the second film then you know what happens to Spock. In order for this "trick" to work the producers and writers really needed to come up with something good and thankfully they did that. I won't ruin what this trick is in "the search for Spock" but I thought it was a rather smart move and it helped make the film a lot more believable. Leonard Nimoy steps into the director's chair here and it's obvious he's very comfortable there as he delivers a good looking film with a good pace and of course the main people back in action. Once again we've got Shatner turning in a good performance as Spock and there's no question that he helps keep the film moving. I don't care what you want to say about the guy but there's no question that he owned this role and could play it in his sleep. Regulars like DeForrest Kelley, James Doohan and George Takei are also good in their roles. It seems a lot of people are split on Lloyd but I thought he was pretty good here. I liked seeing him under all the make-up and thought he did a good job even if the role itself wasn't the greatest. The special effects here are certainly a step up from the previous movie and I'd also say that battle sequences are much better directed. Overall this film doesn't quite reach the levels as the second but it's certainly a worthy sequel.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Spock returns.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bluesman-20
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Star Trek III was one of my favourite Trek movies. The Story gets as emotional and personal as it can be. The Enterprise returns to Spacedock battle scarred and looking her age The Events of the movie follow by rapidly. The planet caused by the Genesis explosion has become a scandal. It is a forbidden subject and off limits to everyone. Dr.McCoy is suffering from something and Spock's Father Sarek comes to Kirk demanding the return of Spock's body and his Katra. Kirk learns Spock placed his soul his spirit inside McCoy. And McCoy is slowly being driven insane, Not only that his life itself is in danger. Meanwhile Kirk's Son and Lt. Saavick go to the planet and Discover Spock is alive and growing older with the planet. The planet itself is dying and so is Spock. The Klingons discover the Geneisis project and want it for a super weapon. This leads to a dramatic climax in which Kirk and Crew Steal the Enterprise go to the planet and Fight the Klingons only to destroy the Enterprise in a effort to save Spock. It gets more personal as Kirk discovers the Klingon's have killed his son. Angered Kirk goes to war to save what is left of the things that matter to him. To me the key scene here is the death of the U.S.S Enterprise. Kirk's true love,He destroys it to save his best friends. That to me speaks of the love this band of brothers have for one another. Under rated for sure. But just as great as the others in the series.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The best yet...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Leofwine_draca
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I enjoyed STAR TREK III: THE SEARCH FOR SPOCK a lot better than the overrated previous instalment, which was way too derivative of the original TV show (with its 'villain of the week' format) and did absolutely nothing for me. Let's face it, such story lines have been done time and again, and it takes something special to make a film stand out from the rest. Thankfully, THE SEARCH FOR SPOCK has that something special to it. Leonard Nimoy steps in as director and does a confident, assured job; even better, the quest storyline is heartfelt, emotionally wrought, and unexpected. The crew are all on top form, giving it their all and staying true to their characters throughout, and the Klingons make great, theatrical enemies, particularly Christopher Lloyd's OTT head bad guy. At the end of the day, I watch these films as somebody with an interest in the sci-fi genre rather than as a Trekkie, and so far this has been my favourite. I look forward to checking out part four!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Figures They'd Save Spock
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    wfjohnston14
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Star Trek III: The Search for Spock is a good film that follows right after the second film. This film, directed by Leonard Nimoy, is a nice film to add to the Star Trek Franchise. The Enterprise crew risks their careers as they take the decommissioned Enterprise to search for Spock's body. They find that Spock's body is missing and go searching for it and find a Vulcan boy instead who looks like Spock. Also, they intercept a Klingon ship at the planet too that puts one of the members of the Enterprise in danger and losing their life. What happened to Spock? Will the Enterprise survive against the Klingon? And what will happen to Kirk? This film is a good film, it has problems, but it is a very good film that is very entertaining and brings back Spock. When Spock's body landed on the planet that was being powered by Genesis, his body regenerated and that's why they found him as a boy. The one problem though is that the planet is regenerating too fast and is soon falling apart and Spock too is aging rapidly. He then is himself, but with no memory, so when they take the Klingon ship back to Vulcan, he and McCoy mind meld and Spock is better. Spock gave McCoy his memory right before he died. The crew member that dies is Kirk's son and he gets very emotional and later to save the crew, destroys the ship and they escape using the Klingon ship. This film is a nice addition and puts things back to where they used to be, everyone alright and ready to go on new adventures. A job well done Nimoy. Me: B
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not quite stronger, but a lot better than the original
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gavin-thelordofthefu-48-460297
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    While Star Trek III may not be as strong or as epic as the Wrath of Khan, it is however a lot better than the original in some ways. The story is fine aside from a few over-the-top moments and mediocre dialog; the script is decent it helped explain the Enterprise group's attempt to find Spock, who died in the end of Star Trek II and the pacing moves along very nicely. The scenery is great and the visuals are terrific. The acting is still solid and aside from William Shatner and Leonard Nimoy, Christopher Lloyd is so enjoyable as Kruge. The music score from James Horner is rousing and the action sequences are thrilling. Overall, not strong, but an enjoyable entry to the franchise even though I'm not a Trekkie.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Standing Proof That Odd Numbered Treks Aren't Always Bad
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Jacob Jefferson (jjgooner@yahoo.co.uk)
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Star Trek III: The Search for Spock *** (out of 4) 102 mins/ PG Cast: William Shatner, Leonard Nimoy, DeForest Kelley, James Doohan, George Takei, Robin Curts, Merritt Butrick, Christopher Lloyd Director: Leonard Nimoy Plot: Admiral Kirk is forced to steal the Enterprise ship and return to planet Genesis to find Spock's lifeless body. JJ's Verdict: Anyone who says all odd numbered Star Trek films are bad is totally wrong. In fact I even prefer The Search for Spock to the superior (so the majority says) Wrath of Khan. Following on from its predecessor, the film constantly references to events from it. While doing this it uses great footage and piles on Kirk's emotional baggage from Spock's 'death' scene. I put death in commas because as the film suggests and his actor's name in the cast list, Spock isn't actually dead. He mind-melted with Kelley's Dr. McCoy and left his body on Genesis. This film follows Kirk and his crew in their recovery of the body and their fight to stop the evil Klingons form inhabiting the planet. This revelation that Spock isn't dead, although fine as a plot element, sort of takes away the effect the final scene of Wrath of Khan has on you. The Search for Spock actually has a much clearer plot than the previous films and although it might be a tiny bit predictable at times, at least it is easier to follow than past Star Trek ventures. The way the film weaves between three groups of people (Kirk and his crew, The Klingons and Saavik and David) keeps the film very interesting and engaging throughout and almost makes it feel like an ensemble piece. The film has both improved special effects and space battles and the acting is very good throughout. William Shatner leads the front-line once again and also tops his performance from Star Trek II. And Christopher Lloyd's Klingon, despite not looking very convincing, plays it pretty scary. The scene in which Kirk and the crew steal The Enterprise is highly amusing and is great tongue-in-cheek humour. Leonard Nimoy, although consistently good as Spock, really finds his speciality in directing. His direction of all the actors really makes you care about their characters and he achieves something that, yet again, the previous two films couldn't do; he kept the audience interested. The film ends on a fitting high note and makes you feel very satisfied. And although Kirk seems to think so, I haven't had enough of this film and wish every Trek could be like this.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Decent Star Trek Movie,But Dosen't Live Up To Wrath Of Khan,
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Dillon Harris
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Star Trek 3: The Search For Spock is a pretty good movie with a decent storyline but a very strong cast.It's definitely not the worst in the Star Trek film series,but it's not the best either.It doesn't live up to it's predecessor,Star Trek 2: The Wrath Of Khan,but it's still a lot better than Star Trek: The Motion Picture.The Search For Spock still has a lot of great action sequences and although it's missing Leonard Nimoy for most of the movie,it's still delivers very strong performances from the other cast members,William Shatner is as good as ever in this movie as Cpatain James T. Kirk.While I feel huge Star Trek fans will be disappointed with the Search For Spockk,they will still get a good kick out of him and wont be entirely unimpressed. Captain Kirk (William Shatner) heads off with his crew on the Enterprise to the Genesis planet to save Spock (Leonard Nimoy,who also directs),who may still be alive.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "Turn death into a fighting chance to live."
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Al_The_Strange
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    With the rip-roaring success of The Wrath of Khan, the studios greenlit the third classic Trek film with Spock himself as the director. The problem is, with the way the last film ended, Spock couldn't be in the actual film. It was only natural that the next step in the series was to bring Spock back; hence, the search. The Search for Spock starts off a bit brooding, but quickly taps into the right adventurous spirit as the Enterprise crew becomes renegades and gives the Federation a hilarious slip. From then on, with bad run-ins with Klingons, the stakes are raised very high, and the struggle becomes quite epic. A few scenes stand out as being fairly epic and jaw-dropping. It is an entertaining thrill ride overall. My only beef with the film is that it still feels very small-scale. A lot of it might be because pitting the Enterprise crew against one small greedy band of Klingon rogues, led by a rather flat one-dimensional villain, just doesn't compare to everything we've already seen in The Wrath of Khan. Let's face it, Khan was too good of a villain, and nothing Captain Kruge does can outstage that. Not even the constant raising of the stakes, and confrontations with death, are able to elevate the film above and beyond the limited confines of its own plot. Despite those quibbles, the film still does the best it can to one-up most things, and still deliver the best story it can. The classic Trek crew remains a fun, endearing, and well-rounded group of characters, and their adventure follows a solid plot structure. Themes of rebirth, initially introduced in the last film, are reinforced here. This film boasts solid, steady photography and editing. Acting is not bad: William Shatner, Leonard Nimoy, DeForest Kelley, and the other classic Trek cast members reprise their roles with good nuance, and with a little more tongue-in-cheek attitude. Christopher Lloyd plays the villain quite memorably, even if the character is a two-bit scumbag. This production has some really good-looking sets, props, costumes, and special effects. The music score has more of the same from the last film, and that's not bad. On its own, this film is fun and satisfying, but understanding its story may rely pretty heavily on seeing The Wrath of Khan first. As such, it's best recommended as an immediate follow-up. 4/5 (Entertainment: Very Good | Story: Pretty Good | Film: Very Good)
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I'm still searching for answers
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ironhorse_iv
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie didn't answer much. Search for Spock has some aspect of the Star Trek theme, but it is very poorly handled. Still, not bad for Leonard Nimoy's first directed film. This one isn't as bad as the other odd numbered installments, especially if you factor in the fact that it ties what happen in the events of the previous Star Trek movie 'Wrath of Khan' so well. If you are a first time viewer of this movie, I wouldn't watch this movie until you watch Wrath of Khan first. It's very important to watch that movie before this. Yes, Star Trek III: The Search for Spock came after that movie, and being after such a masterpiece, people going to look at it being worst compare to that film. No, Star Trek film can live up to that film. Still the movie has some OK action scenes and interesting story. The movie starts out with recaps of the last few minutes of Wrath of Khan and then the movie officially begins. A spy has deliver some information about the Genesis program that Klingon commander Kruge (Christopher Lloyd) needs to hear. It seems like Genesis does, what Nintendo don't. What I meant by that is that Genesis has create life on a planet. The Klingons see this as a weapon to have. The Klingons were always Russian allegory in these films. So hearing this, must have been the same feeling when the Soviets heard about the Atom Bomb. Still, I cannot get over the fact that Christopher Lloyd is playing a Klingon, here. I was expecting him to shout "Great Scott!" or something. His character is quite stupid and silly at times. Just watch the killer plant scene, you can't help laughing at him. He's just not that menacing enough and not epic to the likes of Khan. Well, the Klingons are not the only ones hearing voices, but Dr. McCoy (De Forest Kelly) is talking all crazy about a certain Vulcan name Spock and that Captain Kirk (William Shatner) and the crew should go to Genesis to search for him. Now it's a quest between the crew of the Enterprise to rescue Spock before the Klingons get a hold of the planet. This movie suffers from the typical middle child syndrome of being a 2nd movie in a trilogy's story arc. Star Trek III: The Search For Spock is the second chapter of what is called by some fans "the Star Trek Trilogy", yes it is the third film of the series, but it's the second act in what is indeed a three parter. The first act is in Wrath of Khan, concerning its events leading up to somebody's death. The second act is in Search for Spock where somebody soul and body have to be re united and the third is in Voyage Home where somebody fully regains himself. My biggest problem with Start Trek 3 is that I feel it takes away from the impact of 2. The whole idea of life and death at the end of the 2nd one regarding a death of a character and the birth of a new planet is breath taking. Then this movie has Genesis's kind of break that apart! Breaking apart is a theme here. This film shows that Kirk ends up losing so much more than a friend. He sacrifices his ship, loses a family member and hope. The scene where Kirk is forced to relive his friend's death when he does the mind meld is a wonderful scene. The problem is when you look at how strong, 2 is with its story and themes and how this one causes those scenes to be all for nothing. It's disappointing. I think the worst idea is bringing back a character back after such a heroic death. The needs of the many outweigh the needs of the few. Captain Kirk's friend is noted to say for the reasons and justifying about his sacrifice. I believe that if you kill a character, then that character should stays dead. It does no favors for somebody to kill a character, only to bring them back in a later movie. Its movies like this, that started the 'resurrection of Jesus' concept of bringing dead characters back to live. A good example is Ellen Ripley who dies in Alien 3 only to be given an awful new spin in Alien Resurrection. It's like Nimoy woke up and realize how much money he can make, if he brings back a beloved character back to life. At less, this character got a good story on how he came back, so I can't complain too loudly. Still, it makes you wonders if Genesis was aging faster and faster; how come Kirk's friend didn't aged out as well. Wouldn't he die again by old age? Also how comes, nobody else aged on the planet if Genesis does that to life forms? Wouldn't they also grow older as long as they stay on the planet? The science is baffling. Also what's baffling is how Kristie Alley regenerated to Robin Curtis. It's seem like Alley didn't want to return, so the character was rewritten as a new character as Savvik. I find the Pon-Farr scene, stupid as hell. And where was David Marcus's mother, Carol? It would've been interesting to have her in Saavik's place down on Genesis and it would make more sense. The movie's over all is that it's works to a level, but compare to others. It's not that awesome. Still, it's worth the watch, so check it out. So start trekking.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Needs of the many do indeed outweigh the needs of the few with this film!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    illbebackreviews
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    As a countdown to 'Star Trek: Into Darkness', I decided to watch every single Star Trek movie for the first time. After the brilliant second film, I was excited to watch this one despite not being sure of what to expect. I had heard a lot of criticism about this movie calling it a cheap business trick. 'Star Trek III: The Search for Spock' basically follows the story of Admiral Kirk who has a tough time getting over the loss of his Vulcan friend, Spock. When Bones begins to act strangely, acting as if he is Spock, Kirk begins to realize, with the help of Spock's father, that maybe Spock can be brought back to life if his body and his mind (in this case Bones) are re-united and a spell cast to re-join the two however Klingon Commander, Kruge, played by Christopher Llyod turns out to be the only obstacle as he is in pursuit for the secrets to Genesis. There were quite a few things I really liked about this movie. Much like Star Trek II, I really liked the villain here played brilliantly by Christopher Llyod, who honestly feels the scene stealer in this film. I do love much of the story and I do not believe that this feels like a cash grab, unlike movies such as the Star Wars prequels which were made entirely for merchandising rights and not for story. The story was handled well and it wasn't anything like Spock never died but much more deep. Also the adventure that this movie has is great and I loved all the movie until the last half hour where much of the film becomes rather silly and could easily have been cut down or it could've been directed much better than it was. **SPOILERS AHEAD*** Of course, I am referring to when Kirk attempts to lure Kruge back to the now destructing Genesis and the two fight. Obviously, this fight looks terrible. I am not after any choreographed fight sequence that goes on neither is the fight the big mistake here. It is how this fight ends and Kruge is killed in an extremely silly and childish manner, with Kirk remarking "I have had enough of you!" This is literally the end of the majority of the story until the film truly needs to wrap up. **END OF SPOILERS** Now the film does need a good 20 minutes to truly wrap up and it does get slow and the greatness of the most of the rest of the film truly drops for me here. I am sick of people bashing the multiple endings to 'The Lord of the Rings: The Return of the King' stating that the endings were too many and too long. In that case, people do not realize that the Lord of the Rings is ranked 'Massive' on a scale. It needs those endings to wrap up a 12 hour trilogy...This film doesn't need 20 minutes to wrap up. This ending could've been 10 minutes and would've been perfect or the last 10 minutes or so could've been cut and as a cliffhanger, be added into the beginning of the next Star Trek film and I'm guessing it would work, considering the movie ends with 'The adventure continues...' The special effects were truly sloppy in this movie and such moments like when the Enterprise is destroyed and Genesis is being destroyed certainly do look bad. The acting is mostly good by the crew and was quite a pity to see a re-cast for Saavik...I truly loved the one from Star Trek II and yet, despite this new one being good, the Saavik from Wrath of Khan was superior. In the end, I can say that 'Star Trek III: The Search for Spock' is a good movie and would be considerably better had that 20 minute ending to a 1 hr 45 minute movie not got in the way. That being said, this movie is still fun and has considerable entertainment and displays such adventurous quality to a fun Sci Fi movie and a rather good and worthy addition to Star Trek.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Good Search It Is
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Michael_Elliott
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Star Trek III: The Search for Spock (1984) *** (out of 4) After the events in the previous film, Kirk (William Shatner) risks his career by stealing the Enterprise to go to a restricted planet in hopes of finding Spock's body who they feel might be alive. Along the way they run into a Klingon leader (Christopher Lloyd) who wants to kill them all. STAR TREK III: THE SEARCH OF SPOCK probably shouldn't have worked since if you've seen the second film then you know what happens to Spock. In order for this "trick" to work the producers and writers really needed to come up with something good and thankfully they did that. I won't ruin what this trick is in "the search for Spock" but I thought it was a rather smart move and it helped make the film a lot more believable. Leonard Nimoy steps into the director's chair here and it's obvious he's very comfortable there as he delivers a good looking film with a good pace and of course the main people back in action. Once again we've got Shatner turning in a good performance as Spock and there's no question that he helps keep the film moving. I don't care what you want to say about the guy but there's no question that he owned this role and could play it in his sleep. Regulars like DeForrest Kelley, James Doohan and George Takei are also good in their roles. It seems a lot of people are split on Lloyd but I thought he was pretty good here. I liked seeing him under all the make-up and thought he did a good job even if the role itself wasn't the greatest. The special effects here are certainly a step up from the previous movie and I'd also say that battle sequences are much better directed. Overall this film doesn't quite reach the levels as the second but it's certainly a worthy sequel.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Spock returns.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bluesman-20
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Star Trek III was one of my favourite Trek movies. The Story gets as emotional and personal as it can be. The Enterprise returns to Spacedock battle scarred and looking her age The Events of the movie follow by rapidly. The planet caused by the Genesis explosion has become a scandal. It is a forbidden subject and off limits to everyone. Dr.McCoy is suffering from something and Spock's Father Sarek comes to Kirk demanding the return of Spock's body and his Katra. Kirk learns Spock placed his soul his spirit inside McCoy. And McCoy is slowly being driven insane, Not only that his life itself is in danger. Meanwhile Kirk's Son and Lt. Saavick go to the planet and Discover Spock is alive and growing older with the planet. The planet itself is dying and so is Spock. The Klingons discover the Geneisis project and want it for a super weapon. This leads to a dramatic climax in which Kirk and Crew Steal the Enterprise go to the planet and Fight the Klingons only to destroy the Enterprise in a effort to save Spock. It gets more personal as Kirk discovers the Klingon's have killed his son. Angered Kirk goes to war to save what is left of the things that matter to him. To me the key scene here is the death of the U.S.S Enterprise. Kirk's true love,He destroys it to save his best friends. That to me speaks of the love this band of brothers have for one another. Under rated for sure. But just as great as the others in the series.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The best yet...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Leofwine_draca
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I enjoyed STAR TREK III: THE SEARCH FOR SPOCK a lot better than the overrated previous instalment, which was way too derivative of the original TV show (with its 'villain of the week' format) and did absolutely nothing for me. Let's face it, such story lines have been done time and again, and it takes something special to make a film stand out from the rest. Thankfully, THE SEARCH FOR SPOCK has that something special to it. Leonard Nimoy steps in as director and does a confident, assured job; even better, the quest storyline is heartfelt, emotionally wrought, and unexpected. The crew are all on top form, giving it their all and staying true to their characters throughout, and the Klingons make great, theatrical enemies, particularly Christopher Lloyd's OTT head bad guy. At the end of the day, I watch these films as somebody with an interest in the sci-fi genre rather than as a Trekkie, and so far this has been my favourite. I look forward to checking out part four!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Figures They'd Save Spock
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    wfjohnston14
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Star Trek III: The Search for Spock is a good film that follows right after the second film. This film, directed by Leonard Nimoy, is a nice film to add to the Star Trek Franchise. The Enterprise crew risks their careers as they take the decommissioned Enterprise to search for Spock's body. They find that Spock's body is missing and go searching for it and find a Vulcan boy instead who looks like Spock. Also, they intercept a Klingon ship at the planet too that puts one of the members of the Enterprise in danger and losing their life. What happened to Spock? Will the Enterprise survive against the Klingon? And what will happen to Kirk? This film is a good film, it has problems, but it is a very good film that is very entertaining and brings back Spock. When Spock's body landed on the planet that was being powered by Genesis, his body regenerated and that's why they found him as a boy. The one problem though is that the planet is regenerating too fast and is soon falling apart and Spock too is aging rapidly. He then is himself, but with no memory, so when they take the Klingon ship back to Vulcan, he and McCoy mind meld and Spock is better. Spock gave McCoy his memory right before he died. The crew member that dies is Kirk's son and he gets very emotional and later to save the crew, destroys the ship and they escape using the Klingon ship. This film is a nice addition and puts things back to where they used to be, everyone alright and ready to go on new adventures. A job well done Nimoy. Me: B
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not quite stronger, but a lot better than the original
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gavin-thelordofthefu-48-460297
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    While Star Trek III may not be as strong or as epic as the Wrath of Khan, it is however a lot better than the original in some ways. The story is fine aside from a few over-the-top moments and mediocre dialog; the script is decent it helped explain the Enterprise group's attempt to find Spock, who died in the end of Star Trek II and the pacing moves along very nicely. The scenery is great and the visuals are terrific. The acting is still solid and aside from William Shatner and Leonard Nimoy, Christopher Lloyd is so enjoyable as Kruge. The music score from James Horner is rousing and the action sequences are thrilling. Overall, not strong, but an enjoyable entry to the franchise even though I'm not a Trekkie.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Standing Proof That Odd Numbered Treks Aren't Always Bad
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Jacob Jefferson (jjgooner@yahoo.co.uk)
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Star Trek III: The Search for Spock *** (out of 4) 102 mins/ PG Cast: William Shatner, Leonard Nimoy, DeForest Kelley, James Doohan, George Takei, Robin Curts, Merritt Butrick, Christopher Lloyd Director: Leonard Nimoy Plot: Admiral Kirk is forced to steal the Enterprise ship and return to planet Genesis to find Spock's lifeless body. JJ's Verdict: Anyone who says all odd numbered Star Trek films are bad is totally wrong. In fact I even prefer The Search for Spock to the superior (so the majority says) Wrath of Khan. Following on from its predecessor, the film constantly references to events from it. While doing this it uses great footage and piles on Kirk's emotional baggage from Spock's 'death' scene. I put death in commas because as the film suggests and his actor's name in the cast list, Spock isn't actually dead. He mind-melted with Kelley's Dr. McCoy and left his body on Genesis. This film follows Kirk and his crew in their recovery of the body and their fight to stop the evil Klingons form inhabiting the planet. This revelation that Spock isn't dead, although fine as a plot element, sort of takes away the effect the final scene of Wrath of Khan has on you. The Search for Spock actually has a much clearer plot than the previous films and although it might be a tiny bit predictable at times, at least it is easier to follow than past Star Trek ventures. The way the film weaves between three groups of people (Kirk and his crew, The Klingons and Saavik and David) keeps the film very interesting and engaging throughout and almost makes it feel like an ensemble piece. The film has both improved special effects and space battles and the acting is very good throughout. William Shatner leads the front-line once again and also tops his performance from Star Trek II. And Christopher Lloyd's Klingon, despite not looking very convincing, plays it pretty scary. The scene in which Kirk and the crew steal The Enterprise is highly amusing and is great tongue-in-cheek humour. Leonard Nimoy, although consistently good as Spock, really finds his speciality in directing. His direction of all the actors really makes you care about their characters and he achieves something that, yet again, the previous two films couldn't do; he kept the audience interested. The film ends on a fitting high note and makes you feel very satisfied. And although Kirk seems to think so, I haven't had enough of this film and wish every Trek could be like this.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Decent Star Trek Movie,But Dosen't Live Up To Wrath Of Khan,
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Dillon Harris
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Star Trek 3: The Search For Spock is a pretty good movie with a decent storyline but a very strong cast.It's definitely not the worst in the Star Trek film series,but it's not the best either.It doesn't live up to it's predecessor,Star Trek 2: The Wrath Of Khan,but it's still a lot better than Star Trek: The Motion Picture.The Search For Spock still has a lot of great action sequences and although it's missing Leonard Nimoy for most of the movie,it's still delivers very strong performances from the other cast members,William Shatner is as good as ever in this movie as Cpatain James T. Kirk.While I feel huge Star Trek fans will be disappointed with the Search For Spockk,they will still get a good kick out of him and wont be entirely unimpressed. Captain Kirk (William Shatner) heads off with his crew on the Enterprise to the Genesis planet to save Spock (Leonard Nimoy,who also directs),who may still be alive.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "Turn death into a fighting chance to live."
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Al_The_Strange
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    With the rip-roaring success of The Wrath of Khan, the studios greenlit the third classic Trek film with Spock himself as the director. The problem is, with the way the last film ended, Spock couldn't be in the actual film. It was only natural that the next step in the series was to bring Spock back; hence, the search. The Search for Spock starts off a bit brooding, but quickly taps into the right adventurous spirit as the Enterprise crew becomes renegades and gives the Federation a hilarious slip. From then on, with bad run-ins with Klingons, the stakes are raised very high, and the struggle becomes quite epic. A few scenes stand out as being fairly epic and jaw-dropping. It is an entertaining thrill ride overall. My only beef with the film is that it still feels very small-scale. A lot of it might be because pitting the Enterprise crew against one small greedy band of Klingon rogues, led by a rather flat one-dimensional villain, just doesn't compare to everything we've already seen in The Wrath of Khan. Let's face it, Khan was too good of a villain, and nothing Captain Kruge does can outstage that. Not even the constant raising of the stakes, and confrontations with death, are able to elevate the film above and beyond the limited confines of its own plot. Despite those quibbles, the film still does the best it can to one-up most things, and still deliver the best story it can. The classic Trek crew remains a fun, endearing, and well-rounded group of characters, and their adventure follows a solid plot structure. Themes of rebirth, initially introduced in the last film, are reinforced here. This film boasts solid, steady photography and editing. Acting is not bad: William Shatner, Leonard Nimoy, DeForest Kelley, and the other classic Trek cast members reprise their roles with good nuance, and with a little more tongue-in-cheek attitude. Christopher Lloyd plays the villain quite memorably, even if the character is a two-bit scumbag. This production has some really good-looking sets, props, costumes, and special effects. The music score has more of the same from the last film, and that's not bad. On its own, this film is fun and satisfying, but understanding its story may rely pretty heavily on seeing The Wrath of Khan first. As such, it's best recommended as an immediate follow-up. 4/5 (Entertainment: Very Good | Story: Pretty Good | Film: Very Good)
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I'm still searching for answers
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ironhorse_iv
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie didn't answer much. Search for Spock has some aspect of the Star Trek theme, but it is very poorly handled. Still, not bad for Leonard Nimoy's first directed film. This one isn't as bad as the other odd numbered installments, especially if you factor in the fact that it ties what happen in the events of the previous Star Trek movie 'Wrath of Khan' so well. If you are a first time viewer of this movie, I wouldn't watch this movie until you watch Wrath of Khan first. It's very important to watch that movie before this. Yes, Star Trek III: The Search for Spock came after that movie, and being after such a masterpiece, people going to look at it being worst compare to that film. No, Star Trek film can live up to that film. Still the movie has some OK action scenes and interesting story. The movie starts out with recaps of the last few minutes of Wrath of Khan and then the movie officially begins. A spy has deliver some information about the Genesis program that Klingon commander Kruge (Christopher Lloyd) needs to hear. It seems like Genesis does, what Nintendo don't. What I meant by that is that Genesis has create life on a planet. The Klingons see this as a weapon to have. The Klingons were always Russian allegory in these films. So hearing this, must have been the same feeling when the Soviets heard about the Atom Bomb. Still, I cannot get over the fact that Christopher Lloyd is playing a Klingon, here. I was expecting him to shout "Great Scott!" or something. His character is quite stupid and silly at times. Just watch the killer plant scene, you can't help laughing at him. He's just not that menacing enough and not epic to the likes of Khan. Well, the Klingons are not the only ones hearing voices, but Dr. McCoy (De Forest Kelly) is talking all crazy about a certain Vulcan name Spock and that Captain Kirk (William Shatner) and the crew should go to Genesis to search for him. Now it's a quest between the crew of the Enterprise to rescue Spock before the Klingons get a hold of the planet. This movie suffers from the typical middle child syndrome of being a 2nd movie in a trilogy's story arc. Star Trek III: The Search For Spock is the second chapter of what is called by some fans "the Star Trek Trilogy", yes it is the third film of the series, but it's the second act in what is indeed a three parter. The first act is in Wrath of Khan, concerning its events leading up to somebody's death. The second act is in Search for Spock where somebody soul and body have to be re united and the third is in Voyage Home where somebody fully regains himself. My biggest problem with Start Trek 3 is that I feel it takes away from the impact of 2. The whole idea of life and death at the end of the 2nd one regarding a death of a character and the birth of a new planet is breath taking. Then this movie has Genesis's kind of break that apart! Breaking apart is a theme here. This film shows that Kirk ends up losing so much more than a friend. He sacrifices his ship, loses a family member and hope. The scene where Kirk is forced to relive his friend's death when he does the mind meld is a wonderful scene. The problem is when you look at how strong, 2 is with its story and themes and how this one causes those scenes to be all for nothing. It's disappointing. I think the worst idea is bringing back a character back after such a heroic death. The needs of the many outweigh the needs of the few. Captain Kirk's friend is noted to say for the reasons and justifying about his sacrifice. I believe that if you kill a character, then that character should stays dead. It does no favors for somebody to kill a character, only to bring them back in a later movie. Its movies like this, that started the 'resurrection of Jesus' concept of bringing dead characters back to live. A good example is Ellen Ripley who dies in Alien 3 only to be given an awful new spin in Alien Resurrection. It's like Nimoy woke up and realize how much money he can make, if he brings back a beloved character back to life. At less, this character got a good story on how he came back, so I can't complain too loudly. Still, it makes you wonders if Genesis was aging faster and faster; how come Kirk's friend didn't aged out as well. Wouldn't he die again by old age? Also how comes, nobody else aged on the planet if Genesis does that to life forms? Wouldn't they also grow older as long as they stay on the planet? The science is baffling. Also what's baffling is how Kristie Alley regenerated to Robin Curtis. It's seem like Alley didn't want to return, so the character was rewritten as a new character as Savvik. I find the Pon-Farr scene, stupid as hell. And where was David Marcus's mother, Carol? It would've been interesting to have her in Saavik's place down on Genesis and it would make more sense. The movie's over all is that it's works to a level, but compare to others. It's not that awesome. Still, it's worth the watch, so check it out. So start trekking.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Needs of the many do indeed outweigh the needs of the few with this film!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    illbebackreviews
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    As a countdown to 'Star Trek: Into Darkness', I decided to watch every single Star Trek movie for the first time. After the brilliant second film, I was excited to watch this one despite not being sure of what to expect. I had heard a lot of criticism about this movie calling it a cheap business trick. 'Star Trek III: The Search for Spock' basically follows the story of Admiral Kirk who has a tough time getting over the loss of his Vulcan friend, Spock. When Bones begins to act strangely, acting as if he is Spock, Kirk begins to realize, with the help of Spock's father, that maybe Spock can be brought back to life if his body and his mind (in this case Bones) are re-united and a spell cast to re-join the two however Klingon Commander, Kruge, played by Christopher Llyod turns out to be the only obstacle as he is in pursuit for the secrets to Genesis. There were quite a few things I really liked about this movie. Much like Star Trek II, I really liked the villain here played brilliantly by Christopher Llyod, who honestly feels the scene stealer in this film. I do love much of the story and I do not believe that this feels like a cash grab, unlike movies such as the Star Wars prequels which were made entirely for merchandising rights and not for story. The story was handled well and it wasn't anything like Spock never died but much more deep. Also the adventure that this movie has is great and I loved all the movie until the last half hour where much of the film becomes rather silly and could easily have been cut down or it could've been directed much better than it was. **SPOILERS AHEAD*** Of course, I am referring to when Kirk attempts to lure Kruge back to the now destructing Genesis and the two fight. Obviously, this fight looks terrible. I am not after any choreographed fight sequence that goes on neither is the fight the big mistake here. It is how this fight ends and Kruge is killed in an extremely silly and childish manner, with Kirk remarking "I have had enough of you!" This is literally the end of the majority of the story until the film truly needs to wrap up. **END OF SPOILERS** Now the film does need a good 20 minutes to truly wrap up and it does get slow and the greatness of the most of the rest of the film truly drops for me here. I am sick of people bashing the multiple endings to 'The Lord of the Rings: The Return of the King' stating that the endings were too many and too long. In that case, people do not realize that the Lord of the Rings is ranked 'Massive' on a scale. It needs those endings to wrap up a 12 hour trilogy...This film doesn't need 20 minutes to wrap up. This ending could've been 10 minutes and would've been perfect or the last 10 minutes or so could've been cut and as a cliffhanger, be added into the beginning of the next Star Trek film and I'm guessing it would work, considering the movie ends with 'The adventure continues...' The special effects were truly sloppy in this movie and such moments like when the Enterprise is destroyed and Genesis is being destroyed certainly do look bad. The acting is mostly good by the crew and was quite a pity to see a re-cast for Saavik...I truly loved the one from Star Trek II and yet, despite this new one being good, the Saavik from Wrath of Khan was superior. In the end, I can say that 'Star Trek III: The Search for Spock' is a good movie and would be considerably better had that 20 minute ending to a 1 hr 45 minute movie not got in the way. That being said, this movie is still fun and has considerable entertainment and displays such adventurous quality to a fun Sci Fi movie and a rather good and worthy addition to Star Trek.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Good Search It Is
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Michael_Elliott
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Star Trek III: The Search for Spock (1984) *** (out of 4) After the events in the previous film, Kirk (William Shatner) risks his career by stealing the Enterprise to go to a restricted planet in hopes of finding Spock's body who they feel might be alive. Along the way they run into a Klingon leader (Christopher Lloyd) who wants to kill them all. STAR TREK III: THE SEARCH OF SPOCK probably shouldn't have worked since if you've seen the second film then you know what happens to Spock. In order for this "trick" to work the producers and writers really needed to come up with something good and thankfully they did that. I won't ruin what this trick is in "the search for Spock" but I thought it was a rather smart move and it helped make the film a lot more believable. Leonard Nimoy steps into the director's chair here and it's obvious he's very comfortable there as he delivers a good looking film with a good pace and of course the main people back in action. Once again we've got Shatner turning in a good performance as Spock and there's no question that he helps keep the film moving. I don't care what you want to say about the guy but there's no question that he owned this role and could play it in his sleep. Regulars like DeForrest Kelley, James Doohan and George Takei are also good in their roles. It seems a lot of people are split on Lloyd but I thought he was pretty good here. I liked seeing him under all the make-up and thought he did a good job even if the role itself wasn't the greatest. The special effects here are certainly a step up from the previous movie and I'd also say that battle sequences are much better directed. Overall this film doesn't quite reach the levels as the second but it's certainly a worthy sequel.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Spock returns.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bluesman-20
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Star Trek III was one of my favourite Trek movies. The Story gets as emotional and personal as it can be. The Enterprise returns to Spacedock battle scarred and looking her age The Events of the movie follow by rapidly. The planet caused by the Genesis explosion has become a scandal. It is a forbidden subject and off limits to everyone. Dr.McCoy is suffering from something and Spock's Father Sarek comes to Kirk demanding the return of Spock's body and his Katra. Kirk learns Spock placed his soul his spirit inside McCoy. And McCoy is slowly being driven insane, Not only that his life itself is in danger. Meanwhile Kirk's Son and Lt. Saavick go to the planet and Discover Spock is alive and growing older with the planet. The planet itself is dying and so is Spock. The Klingons discover the Geneisis project and want it for a super weapon. This leads to a dramatic climax in which Kirk and Crew Steal the Enterprise go to the planet and Fight the Klingons only to destroy the Enterprise in a effort to save Spock. It gets more personal as Kirk discovers the Klingon's have killed his son. Angered Kirk goes to war to save what is left of the things that matter to him. To me the key scene here is the death of the U.S.S Enterprise. Kirk's true love,He destroys it to save his best friends. That to me speaks of the love this band of brothers have for one another. Under rated for sure. But just as great as the others in the series.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The best yet...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Leofwine_draca
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I enjoyed STAR TREK III: THE SEARCH FOR SPOCK a lot better than the overrated previous instalment, which was way too derivative of the original TV show (with its 'villain of the week' format) and did absolutely nothing for me. Let's face it, such story lines have been done time and again, and it takes something special to make a film stand out from the rest. Thankfully, THE SEARCH FOR SPOCK has that something special to it. Leonard Nimoy steps in as director and does a confident, assured job; even better, the quest storyline is heartfelt, emotionally wrought, and unexpected. The crew are all on top form, giving it their all and staying true to their characters throughout, and the Klingons make great, theatrical enemies, particularly Christopher Lloyd's OTT head bad guy. At the end of the day, I watch these films as somebody with an interest in the sci-fi genre rather than as a Trekkie, and so far this has been my favourite. I look forward to checking out part four!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Figures They'd Save Spock
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    wfjohnston14
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Star Trek III: The Search for Spock is a good film that follows right after the second film. This film, directed by Leonard Nimoy, is a nice film to add to the Star Trek Franchise. The Enterprise crew risks their careers as they take the decommissioned Enterprise to search for Spock's body. They find that Spock's body is missing and go searching for it and find a Vulcan boy instead who looks like Spock. Also, they intercept a Klingon ship at the planet too that puts one of the members of the Enterprise in danger and losing their life. What happened to Spock? Will the Enterprise survive against the Klingon? And what will happen to Kirk? This film is a good film, it has problems, but it is a very good film that is very entertaining and brings back Spock. When Spock's body landed on the planet that was being powered by Genesis, his body regenerated and that's why they found him as a boy. The one problem though is that the planet is regenerating too fast and is soon falling apart and Spock too is aging rapidly. He then is himself, but with no memory, so when they take the Klingon ship back to Vulcan, he and McCoy mind meld and Spock is better. Spock gave McCoy his memory right before he died. The crew member that dies is Kirk's son and he gets very emotional and later to save the crew, destroys the ship and they escape using the Klingon ship. This film is a nice addition and puts things back to where they used to be, everyone alright and ready to go on new adventures. A job well done Nimoy. Me: B
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not quite stronger, but a lot better than the original
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gavin-thelordofthefu-48-460297
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    While Star Trek III may not be as strong or as epic as the Wrath of Khan, it is however a lot better than the original in some ways. The story is fine aside from a few over-the-top moments and mediocre dialog; the script is decent it helped explain the Enterprise group's attempt to find Spock, who died in the end of Star Trek II and the pacing moves along very nicely. The scenery is great and the visuals are terrific. The acting is still solid and aside from William Shatner and Leonard Nimoy, Christopher Lloyd is so enjoyable as Kruge. The music score from James Horner is rousing and the action sequences are thrilling. Overall, not strong, but an enjoyable entry to the franchise even though I'm not a Trekkie.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Standing Proof That Odd Numbered Treks Aren't Always Bad
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Jacob Jefferson (jjgooner@yahoo.co.uk)
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Star Trek III: The Search for Spock *** (out of 4) 102 mins/ PG Cast: William Shatner, Leonard Nimoy, DeForest Kelley, James Doohan, George Takei, Robin Curts, Merritt Butrick, Christopher Lloyd Director: Leonard Nimoy Plot: Admiral Kirk is forced to steal the Enterprise ship and return to planet Genesis to find Spock's lifeless body. JJ's Verdict: Anyone who says all odd numbered Star Trek films are bad is totally wrong. In fact I even prefer The Search for Spock to the superior (so the majority says) Wrath of Khan. Following on from its predecessor, the film constantly references to events from it. While doing this it uses great footage and piles on Kirk's emotional baggage from Spock's 'death' scene. I put death in commas because as the film suggests and his actor's name in the cast list, Spock isn't actually dead. He mind-melted with Kelley's Dr. McCoy and left his body on Genesis. This film follows Kirk and his crew in their recovery of the body and their fight to stop the evil Klingons form inhabiting the planet. This revelation that Spock isn't dead, although fine as a plot element, sort of takes away the effect the final scene of Wrath of Khan has on you. The Search for Spock actually has a much clearer plot than the previous films and although it might be a tiny bit predictable at times, at least it is easier to follow than past Star Trek ventures. The way the film weaves between three groups of people (Kirk and his crew, The Klingons and Saavik and David) keeps the film very interesting and engaging throughout and almost makes it feel like an ensemble piece. The film has both improved special effects and space battles and the acting is very good throughout. William Shatner leads the front-line once again and also tops his performance from Star Trek II. And Christopher Lloyd's Klingon, despite not looking very convincing, plays it pretty scary. The scene in which Kirk and the crew steal The Enterprise is highly amusing and is great tongue-in-cheek humour. Leonard Nimoy, although consistently good as Spock, really finds his speciality in directing. His direction of all the actors really makes you care about their characters and he achieves something that, yet again, the previous two films couldn't do; he kept the audience interested. The film ends on a fitting high note and makes you feel very satisfied. And although Kirk seems to think so, I haven't had enough of this film and wish every Trek could be like this.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Decent Star Trek Movie,But Dosen't Live Up To Wrath Of Khan,
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Dillon Harris
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Star Trek 3: The Search For Spock is a pretty good movie with a decent storyline but a very strong cast.It's definitely not the worst in the Star Trek film series,but it's not the best either.It doesn't live up to it's predecessor,Star Trek 2: The Wrath Of Khan,but it's still a lot better than Star Trek: The Motion Picture.The Search For Spock still has a lot of great action sequences and although it's missing Leonard Nimoy for most of the movie,it's still delivers very strong performances from the other cast members,William Shatner is as good as ever in this movie as Cpatain James T. Kirk.While I feel huge Star Trek fans will be disappointed with the Search For Spockk,they will still get a good kick out of him and wont be entirely unimpressed. Captain Kirk (William Shatner) heads off with his crew on the Enterprise to the Genesis planet to save Spock (Leonard Nimoy,who also directs),who may still be alive.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "Turn death into a fighting chance to live."
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Al_The_Strange
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    With the rip-roaring success of The Wrath of Khan, the studios greenlit the third classic Trek film with Spock himself as the director. The problem is, with the way the last film ended, Spock couldn't be in the actual film. It was only natural that the next step in the series was to bring Spock back; hence, the search. The Search for Spock starts off a bit brooding, but quickly taps into the right adventurous spirit as the Enterprise crew becomes renegades and gives the Federation a hilarious slip. From then on, with bad run-ins with Klingons, the stakes are raised very high, and the struggle becomes quite epic. A few scenes stand out as being fairly epic and jaw-dropping. It is an entertaining thrill ride overall. My only beef with the film is that it still feels very small-scale. A lot of it might be because pitting the Enterprise crew against one small greedy band of Klingon rogues, led by a rather flat one-dimensional villain, just doesn't compare to everything we've already seen in The Wrath of Khan. Let's face it, Khan was too good of a villain, and nothing Captain Kruge does can outstage that. Not even the constant raising of the stakes, and confrontations with death, are able to elevate the film above and beyond the limited confines of its own plot. Despite those quibbles, the film still does the best it can to one-up most things, and still deliver the best story it can. The classic Trek crew remains a fun, endearing, and well-rounded group of characters, and their adventure follows a solid plot structure. Themes of rebirth, initially introduced in the last film, are reinforced here. This film boasts solid, steady photography and editing. Acting is not bad: William Shatner, Leonard Nimoy, DeForest Kelley, and the other classic Trek cast members reprise their roles with good nuance, and with a little more tongue-in-cheek attitude. Christopher Lloyd plays the villain quite memorably, even if the character is a two-bit scumbag. This production has some really good-looking sets, props, costumes, and special effects. The music score has more of the same from the last film, and that's not bad. On its own, this film is fun and satisfying, but understanding its story may rely pretty heavily on seeing The Wrath of Khan first. As such, it's best recommended as an immediate follow-up. 4/5 (Entertainment: Very Good | Story: Pretty Good | Film: Very Good)
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I'm still searching for answers
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ironhorse_iv
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie didn't answer much. Search for Spock has some aspect of the Star Trek theme, but it is very poorly handled. Still, not bad for Leonard Nimoy's first directed film. This one isn't as bad as the other odd numbered installments, especially if you factor in the fact that it ties what happen in the events of the previous Star Trek movie 'Wrath of Khan' so well. If you are a first time viewer of this movie, I wouldn't watch this movie until you watch Wrath of Khan first. It's very important to watch that movie before this. Yes, Star Trek III: The Search for Spock came after that movie, and being after such a masterpiece, people going to look at it being worst compare to that film. No, Star Trek film can live up to that film. Still the movie has some OK action scenes and interesting story. The movie starts out with recaps of the last few minutes of Wrath of Khan and then the movie officially begins. A spy has deliver some information about the Genesis program that Klingon commander Kruge (Christopher Lloyd) needs to hear. It seems like Genesis does, what Nintendo don't. What I meant by that is that Genesis has create life on a planet. The Klingons see this as a weapon to have. The Klingons were always Russian allegory in these films. So hearing this, must have been the same feeling when the Soviets heard about the Atom Bomb. Still, I cannot get over the fact that Christopher Lloyd is playing a Klingon, here. I was expecting him to shout "Great Scott!" or something. His character is quite stupid and silly at times. Just watch the killer plant scene, you can't help laughing at him. He's just not that menacing enough and not epic to the likes of Khan. Well, the Klingons are not the only ones hearing voices, but Dr. McCoy (De Forest Kelly) is talking all crazy about a certain Vulcan name Spock and that Captain Kirk (William Shatner) and the crew should go to Genesis to search for him. Now it's a quest between the crew of the Enterprise to rescue Spock before the Klingons get a hold of the planet. This movie suffers from the typical middle child syndrome of being a 2nd movie in a trilogy's story arc. Star Trek III: The Search For Spock is the second chapter of what is called by some fans "the Star Trek Trilogy", yes it is the third film of the series, but it's the second act in what is indeed a three parter. The first act is in Wrath of Khan, concerning its events leading up to somebody's death. The second act is in Search for Spock where somebody soul and body have to be re united and the third is in Voyage Home where somebody fully regains himself. My biggest problem with Start Trek 3 is that I feel it takes away from the impact of 2. The whole idea of life and death at the end of the 2nd one regarding a death of a character and the birth of a new planet is breath taking. Then this movie has Genesis's kind of break that apart! Breaking apart is a theme here. This film shows that Kirk ends up losing so much more than a friend. He sacrifices his ship, loses a family member and hope. The scene where Kirk is forced to relive his friend's death when he does the mind meld is a wonderful scene. The problem is when you look at how strong, 2 is with its story and themes and how this one causes those scenes to be all for nothing. It's disappointing. I think the worst idea is bringing back a character back after such a heroic death. The needs of the many outweigh the needs of the few. Captain Kirk's friend is noted to say for the reasons and justifying about his sacrifice. I believe that if you kill a character, then that character should stays dead. It does no favors for somebody to kill a character, only to bring them back in a later movie. Its movies like this, that started the 'resurrection of Jesus' concept of bringing dead characters back to live. A good example is Ellen Ripley who dies in Alien 3 only to be given an awful new spin in Alien Resurrection. It's like Nimoy woke up and realize how much money he can make, if he brings back a beloved character back to life. At less, this character got a good story on how he came back, so I can't complain too loudly. Still, it makes you wonders if Genesis was aging faster and faster; how come Kirk's friend didn't aged out as well. Wouldn't he die again by old age? Also how comes, nobody else aged on the planet if Genesis does that to life forms? Wouldn't they also grow older as long as they stay on the planet? The science is baffling. Also what's baffling is how Kristie Alley regenerated to Robin Curtis. It's seem like Alley didn't want to return, so the character was rewritten as a new character as Savvik. I find the Pon-Farr scene, stupid as hell. And where was David Marcus's mother, Carol? It would've been interesting to have her in Saavik's place down on Genesis and it would make more sense. The movie's over all is that it's works to a level, but compare to others. It's not that awesome. Still, it's worth the watch, so check it out. So start trekking.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Needs of the many do indeed outweigh the needs of the few with this film!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    illbebackreviews
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    As a countdown to 'Star Trek: Into Darkness', I decided to watch every single Star Trek movie for the first time. After the brilliant second film, I was excited to watch this one despite not being sure of what to expect. I had heard a lot of criticism about this movie calling it a cheap business trick. 'Star Trek III: The Search for Spock' basically follows the story of Admiral Kirk who has a tough time getting over the loss of his Vulcan friend, Spock. When Bones begins to act strangely, acting as if he is Spock, Kirk begins to realize, with the help of Spock's father, that maybe Spock can be brought back to life if his body and his mind (in this case Bones) are re-united and a spell cast to re-join the two however Klingon Commander, Kruge, played by Christopher Llyod turns out to be the only obstacle as he is in pursuit for the secrets to Genesis. There were quite a few things I really liked about this movie. Much like Star Trek II, I really liked the villain here played brilliantly by Christopher Llyod, who honestly feels the scene stealer in this film. I do love much of the story and I do not believe that this feels like a cash grab, unlike movies such as the Star Wars prequels which were made entirely for merchandising rights and not for story. The story was handled well and it wasn't anything like Spock never died but much more deep. Also the adventure that this movie has is great and I loved all the movie until the last half hour where much of the film becomes rather silly and could easily have been cut down or it could've been directed much better than it was. **SPOILERS AHEAD*** Of course, I am referring to when Kirk attempts to lure Kruge back to the now destructing Genesis and the two fight. Obviously, this fight looks terrible. I am not after any choreographed fight sequence that goes on neither is the fight the big mistake here. It is how this fight ends and Kruge is killed in an extremely silly and childish manner, with Kirk remarking "I have had enough of you!" This is literally the end of the majority of the story until the film truly needs to wrap up. **END OF SPOILERS** Now the film does need a good 20 minutes to truly wrap up and it does get slow and the greatness of the most of the rest of the film truly drops for me here. I am sick of people bashing the multiple endings to 'The Lord of the Rings: The Return of the King' stating that the endings were too many and too long. In that case, people do not realize that the Lord of the Rings is ranked 'Massive' on a scale. It needs those endings to wrap up a 12 hour trilogy...This film doesn't need 20 minutes to wrap up. This ending could've been 10 minutes and would've been perfect or the last 10 minutes or so could've been cut and as a cliffhanger, be added into the beginning of the next Star Trek film and I'm guessing it would work, considering the movie ends with 'The adventure continues...' The special effects were truly sloppy in this movie and such moments like when the Enterprise is destroyed and Genesis is being destroyed certainly do look bad. The acting is mostly good by the crew and was quite a pity to see a re-cast for Saavik...I truly loved the one from Star Trek II and yet, despite this new one being good, the Saavik from Wrath of Khan was superior. In the end, I can say that 'Star Trek III: The Search for Spock' is a good movie and would be considerably better had that 20 minute ending to a 1 hr 45 minute movie not got in the way. That being said, this movie is still fun and has considerable entertainment and displays such adventurous quality to a fun Sci Fi movie and a rather good and worthy addition to Star Trek.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Good Search It Is
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Michael_Elliott
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Star Trek III: The Search for Spock (1984) *** (out of 4) After the events in the previous film, Kirk (William Shatner) risks his career by stealing the Enterprise to go to a restricted planet in hopes of finding Spock's body who they feel might be alive. Along the way they run into a Klingon leader (Christopher Lloyd) who wants to kill them all. STAR TREK III: THE SEARCH OF SPOCK probably shouldn't have worked since if you've seen the second film then you know what happens to Spock. In order for this "trick" to work the producers and writers really needed to come up with something good and thankfully they did that. I won't ruin what this trick is in "the search for Spock" but I thought it was a rather smart move and it helped make the film a lot more believable. Leonard Nimoy steps into the director's chair here and it's obvious he's very comfortable there as he delivers a good looking film with a good pace and of course the main people back in action. Once again we've got Shatner turning in a good performance as Spock and there's no question that he helps keep the film moving. I don't care what you want to say about the guy but there's no question that he owned this role and could play it in his sleep. Regulars like DeForrest Kelley, James Doohan and George Takei are also good in their roles. It seems a lot of people are split on Lloyd but I thought he was pretty good here. I liked seeing him under all the make-up and thought he did a good job even if the role itself wasn't the greatest. The special effects here are certainly a step up from the previous movie and I'd also say that battle sequences are much better directed. Overall this film doesn't quite reach the levels as the second but it's certainly a worthy sequel.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Spock returns.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bluesman-20
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Star Trek III was one of my favourite Trek movies. The Story gets as emotional and personal as it can be. The Enterprise returns to Spacedock battle scarred and looking her age The Events of the movie follow by rapidly. The planet caused by the Genesis explosion has become a scandal. It is a forbidden subject and off limits to everyone. Dr.McCoy is suffering from something and Spock's Father Sarek comes to Kirk demanding the return of Spock's body and his Katra. Kirk learns Spock placed his soul his spirit inside McCoy. And McCoy is slowly being driven insane, Not only that his life itself is in danger. Meanwhile Kirk's Son and Lt. Saavick go to the planet and Discover Spock is alive and growing older with the planet. The planet itself is dying and so is Spock. The Klingons discover the Geneisis project and want it for a super weapon. This leads to a dramatic climax in which Kirk and Crew Steal the Enterprise go to the planet and Fight the Klingons only to destroy the Enterprise in a effort to save Spock. It gets more personal as Kirk discovers the Klingon's have killed his son. Angered Kirk goes to war to save what is left of the things that matter to him. To me the key scene here is the death of the U.S.S Enterprise. Kirk's true love,He destroys it to save his best friends. That to me speaks of the love this band of brothers have for one another. Under rated for sure. But just as great as the others in the series.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The best yet...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Leofwine_draca
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I enjoyed STAR TREK III: THE SEARCH FOR SPOCK a lot better than the overrated previous instalment, which was way too derivative of the original TV show (with its 'villain of the week' format) and did absolutely nothing for me. Let's face it, such story lines have been done time and again, and it takes something special to make a film stand out from the rest. Thankfully, THE SEARCH FOR SPOCK has that something special to it. Leonard Nimoy steps in as director and does a confident, assured job; even better, the quest storyline is heartfelt, emotionally wrought, and unexpected. The crew are all on top form, giving it their all and staying true to their characters throughout, and the Klingons make great, theatrical enemies, particularly Christopher Lloyd's OTT head bad guy. At the end of the day, I watch these films as somebody with an interest in the sci-fi genre rather than as a Trekkie, and so far this has been my favourite. I look forward to checking out part four!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Figures They'd Save Spock
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    wfjohnston14
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Star Trek III: The Search for Spock is a good film that follows right after the second film. This film, directed by Leonard Nimoy, is a nice film to add to the Star Trek Franchise. The Enterprise crew risks their careers as they take the decommissioned Enterprise to search for Spock's body. They find that Spock's body is missing and go searching for it and find a Vulcan boy instead who looks like Spock. Also, they intercept a Klingon ship at the planet too that puts one of the members of the Enterprise in danger and losing their life. What happened to Spock? Will the Enterprise survive against the Klingon? And what will happen to Kirk? This film is a good film, it has problems, but it is a very good film that is very entertaining and brings back Spock. When Spock's body landed on the planet that was being powered by Genesis, his body regenerated and that's why they found him as a boy. The one problem though is that the planet is regenerating too fast and is soon falling apart and Spock too is aging rapidly. He then is himself, but with no memory, so when they take the Klingon ship back to Vulcan, he and McCoy mind meld and Spock is better. Spock gave McCoy his memory right before he died. The crew member that dies is Kirk's son and he gets very emotional and later to save the crew, destroys the ship and they escape using the Klingon ship. This film is a nice addition and puts things back to where they used to be, everyone alright and ready to go on new adventures. A job well done Nimoy. Me: B
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not quite stronger, but a lot better than the original
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gavin-thelordofthefu-48-460297
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    While Star Trek III may not be as strong or as epic as the Wrath of Khan, it is however a lot better than the original in some ways. The story is fine aside from a few over-the-top moments and mediocre dialog; the script is decent it helped explain the Enterprise group's attempt to find Spock, who died in the end of Star Trek II and the pacing moves along very nicely. The scenery is great and the visuals are terrific. The acting is still solid and aside from William Shatner and Leonard Nimoy, Christopher Lloyd is so enjoyable as Kruge. The music score from James Horner is rousing and the action sequences are thrilling. Overall, not strong, but an enjoyable entry to the franchise even though I'm not a Trekkie.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Standing Proof That Odd Numbered Treks Aren't Always Bad
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Jacob Jefferson (jjgooner@yahoo.co.uk)
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Star Trek III: The Search for Spock *** (out of 4) 102 mins/ PG Cast: William Shatner, Leonard Nimoy, DeForest Kelley, James Doohan, George Takei, Robin Curts, Merritt Butrick, Christopher Lloyd Director: Leonard Nimoy Plot: Admiral Kirk is forced to steal the Enterprise ship and return to planet Genesis to find Spock's lifeless body. JJ's Verdict: Anyone who says all odd numbered Star Trek films are bad is totally wrong. In fact I even prefer The Search for Spock to the superior (so the majority says) Wrath of Khan. Following on from its predecessor, the film constantly references to events from it. While doing this it uses great footage and piles on Kirk's emotional baggage from Spock's 'death' scene. I put death in commas because as the film suggests and his actor's name in the cast list, Spock isn't actually dead. He mind-melted with Kelley's Dr. McCoy and left his body on Genesis. This film follows Kirk and his crew in their recovery of the body and their fight to stop the evil Klingons form inhabiting the planet. This revelation that Spock isn't dead, although fine as a plot element, sort of takes away the effect the final scene of Wrath of Khan has on you. The Search for Spock actually has a much clearer plot than the previous films and although it might be a tiny bit predictable at times, at least it is easier to follow than past Star Trek ventures. The way the film weaves between three groups of people (Kirk and his crew, The Klingons and Saavik and David) keeps the film very interesting and engaging throughout and almost makes it feel like an ensemble piece. The film has both improved special effects and space battles and the acting is very good throughout. William Shatner leads the front-line once again and also tops his performance from Star Trek II. And Christopher Lloyd's Klingon, despite not looking very convincing, plays it pretty scary. The scene in which Kirk and the crew steal The Enterprise is highly amusing and is great tongue-in-cheek humour. Leonard Nimoy, although consistently good as Spock, really finds his speciality in directing. His direction of all the actors really makes you care about their characters and he achieves something that, yet again, the previous two films couldn't do; he kept the audience interested. The film ends on a fitting high note and makes you feel very satisfied. And although Kirk seems to think so, I haven't had enough of this film and wish every Trek could be like this.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Decent Star Trek Movie,But Dosen't Live Up To Wrath Of Khan,
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Dillon Harris
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Star Trek 3: The Search For Spock is a pretty good movie with a decent storyline but a very strong cast.It's definitely not the worst in the Star Trek film series,but it's not the best either.It doesn't live up to it's predecessor,Star Trek 2: The Wrath Of Khan,but it's still a lot better than Star Trek: The Motion Picture.The Search For Spock still has a lot of great action sequences and although it's missing Leonard Nimoy for most of the movie,it's still delivers very strong performances from the other cast members,William Shatner is as good as ever in this movie as Cpatain James T. Kirk.While I feel huge Star Trek fans will be disappointed with the Search For Spockk,they will still get a good kick out of him and wont be entirely unimpressed. Captain Kirk (William Shatner) heads off with his crew on the Enterprise to the Genesis planet to save Spock (Leonard Nimoy,who also directs),who may still be alive.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "Turn death into a fighting chance to live."
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Al_The_Strange
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    With the rip-roaring success of The Wrath of Khan, the studios greenlit the third classic Trek film with Spock himself as the director. The problem is, with the way the last film ended, Spock couldn't be in the actual film. It was only natural that the next step in the series was to bring Spock back; hence, the search. The Search for Spock starts off a bit brooding, but quickly taps into the right adventurous spirit as the Enterprise crew becomes renegades and gives the Federation a hilarious slip. From then on, with bad run-ins with Klingons, the stakes are raised very high, and the struggle becomes quite epic. A few scenes stand out as being fairly epic and jaw-dropping. It is an entertaining thrill ride overall. My only beef with the film is that it still feels very small-scale. A lot of it might be because pitting the Enterprise crew against one small greedy band of Klingon rogues, led by a rather flat one-dimensional villain, just doesn't compare to everything we've already seen in The Wrath of Khan. Let's face it, Khan was too good of a villain, and nothing Captain Kruge does can outstage that. Not even the constant raising of the stakes, and confrontations with death, are able to elevate the film above and beyond the limited confines of its own plot. Despite those quibbles, the film still does the best it can to one-up most things, and still deliver the best story it can. The classic Trek crew remains a fun, endearing, and well-rounded group of characters, and their adventure follows a solid plot structure. Themes of rebirth, initially introduced in the last film, are reinforced here. This film boasts solid, steady photography and editing. Acting is not bad: William Shatner, Leonard Nimoy, DeForest Kelley, and the other classic Trek cast members reprise their roles with good nuance, and with a little more tongue-in-cheek attitude. Christopher Lloyd plays the villain quite memorably, even if the character is a two-bit scumbag. This production has some really good-looking sets, props, costumes, and special effects. The music score has more of the same from the last film, and that's not bad. On its own, this film is fun and satisfying, but understanding its story may rely pretty heavily on seeing The Wrath of Khan first. As such, it's best recommended as an immediate follow-up. 4/5 (Entertainment: Very Good | Story: Pretty Good | Film: Very Good)
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I'm still searching for answers
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ironhorse_iv
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie didn't answer much. Search for Spock has some aspect of the Star Trek theme, but it is very poorly handled. Still, not bad for Leonard Nimoy's first directed film. This one isn't as bad as the other odd numbered installments, especially if you factor in the fact that it ties what happen in the events of the previous Star Trek movie 'Wrath of Khan' so well. If you are a first time viewer of this movie, I wouldn't watch this movie until you watch Wrath of Khan first. It's very important to watch that movie before this. Yes, Star Trek III: The Search for Spock came after that movie, and being after such a masterpiece, people going to look at it being worst compare to that film. No, Star Trek film can live up to that film. Still the movie has some OK action scenes and interesting story. The movie starts out with recaps of the last few minutes of Wrath of Khan and then the movie officially begins. A spy has deliver some information about the Genesis program that Klingon commander Kruge (Christopher Lloyd) needs to hear. It seems like Genesis does, what Nintendo don't. What I meant by that is that Genesis has create life on a planet. The Klingons see this as a weapon to have. The Klingons were always Russian allegory in these films. So hearing this, must have been the same feeling when the Soviets heard about the Atom Bomb. Still, I cannot get over the fact that Christopher Lloyd is playing a Klingon, here. I was expecting him to shout "Great Scott!" or something. His character is quite stupid and silly at times. Just watch the killer plant scene, you can't help laughing at him. He's just not that menacing enough and not epic to the likes of Khan. Well, the Klingons are not the only ones hearing voices, but Dr. McCoy (De Forest Kelly) is talking all crazy about a certain Vulcan name Spock and that Captain Kirk (William Shatner) and the crew should go to Genesis to search for him. Now it's a quest between the crew of the Enterprise to rescue Spock before the Klingons get a hold of the planet. This movie suffers from the typical middle child syndrome of being a 2nd movie in a trilogy's story arc. Star Trek III: The Search For Spock is the second chapter of what is called by some fans "the Star Trek Trilogy", yes it is the third film of the series, but it's the second act in what is indeed a three parter. The first act is in Wrath of Khan, concerning its events leading up to somebody's death. The second act is in Search for Spock where somebody soul and body have to be re united and the third is in Voyage Home where somebody fully regains himself. My biggest problem with Start Trek 3 is that I feel it takes away from the impact of 2. The whole idea of life and death at the end of the 2nd one regarding a death of a character and the birth of a new planet is breath taking. Then this movie has Genesis's kind of break that apart! Breaking apart is a theme here. This film shows that Kirk ends up losing so much more than a friend. He sacrifices his ship, loses a family member and hope. The scene where Kirk is forced to relive his friend's death when he does the mind meld is a wonderful scene. The problem is when you look at how strong, 2 is with its story and themes and how this one causes those scenes to be all for nothing. It's disappointing. I think the worst idea is bringing back a character back after such a heroic death. The needs of the many outweigh the needs of the few. Captain Kirk's friend is noted to say for the reasons and justifying about his sacrifice. I believe that if you kill a character, then that character should stays dead. It does no favors for somebody to kill a character, only to bring them back in a later movie. Its movies like this, that started the 'resurrection of Jesus' concept of bringing dead characters back to live. A good example is Ellen Ripley who dies in Alien 3 only to be given an awful new spin in Alien Resurrection. It's like Nimoy woke up and realize how much money he can make, if he brings back a beloved character back to life. At less, this character got a good story on how he came back, so I can't complain too loudly. Still, it makes you wonders if Genesis was aging faster and faster; how come Kirk's friend didn't aged out as well. Wouldn't he die again by old age? Also how comes, nobody else aged on the planet if Genesis does that to life forms? Wouldn't they also grow older as long as they stay on the planet? The science is baffling. Also what's baffling is how Kristie Alley regenerated to Robin Curtis. It's seem like Alley didn't want to return, so the character was rewritten as a new character as Savvik. I find the Pon-Farr scene, stupid as hell. And where was David Marcus's mother, Carol? It would've been interesting to have her in Saavik's place down on Genesis and it would make more sense. The movie's over all is that it's works to a level, but compare to others. It's not that awesome. Still, it's worth the watch, so check it out. So start trekking.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Needs of the many do indeed outweigh the needs of the few with this film!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    illbebackreviews
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    As a countdown to 'Star Trek: Into Darkness', I decided to watch every single Star Trek movie for the first time. After the brilliant second film, I was excited to watch this one despite not being sure of what to expect. I had heard a lot of criticism about this movie calling it a cheap business trick. 'Star Trek III: The Search for Spock' basically follows the story of Admiral Kirk who has a tough time getting over the loss of his Vulcan friend, Spock. When Bones begins to act strangely, acting as if he is Spock, Kirk begins to realize, with the help of Spock's father, that maybe Spock can be brought back to life if his body and his mind (in this case Bones) are re-united and a spell cast to re-join the two however Klingon Commander, Kruge, played by Christopher Llyod turns out to be the only obstacle as he is in pursuit for the secrets to Genesis. There were quite a few things I really liked about this movie. Much like Star Trek II, I really liked the villain here played brilliantly by Christopher Llyod, who honestly feels the scene stealer in this film. I do love much of the story and I do not believe that this feels like a cash grab, unlike movies such as the Star Wars prequels which were made entirely for merchandising rights and not for story. The story was handled well and it wasn't anything like Spock never died but much more deep. Also the adventure that this movie has is great and I loved all the movie until the last half hour where much of the film becomes rather silly and could easily have been cut down or it could've been directed much better than it was. **SPOILERS AHEAD*** Of course, I am referring to when Kirk attempts to lure Kruge back to the now destructing Genesis and the two fight. Obviously, this fight looks terrible. I am not after any choreographed fight sequence that goes on neither is the fight the big mistake here. It is how this fight ends and Kruge is killed in an extremely silly and childish manner, with Kirk remarking "I have had enough of you!" This is literally the end of the majority of the story until the film truly needs to wrap up. **END OF SPOILERS** Now the film does need a good 20 minutes to truly wrap up and it does get slow and the greatness of the most of the rest of the film truly drops for me here. I am sick of people bashing the multiple endings to 'The Lord of the Rings: The Return of the King' stating that the endings were too many and too long. In that case, people do not realize that the Lord of the Rings is ranked 'Massive' on a scale. It needs those endings to wrap up a 12 hour trilogy...This film doesn't need 20 minutes to wrap up. This ending could've been 10 minutes and would've been perfect or the last 10 minutes or so could've been cut and as a cliffhanger, be added into the beginning of the next Star Trek film and I'm guessing it would work, considering the movie ends with 'The adventure continues...' The special effects were truly sloppy in this movie and such moments like when the Enterprise is destroyed and Genesis is being destroyed certainly do look bad. The acting is mostly good by the crew and was quite a pity to see a re-cast for Saavik...I truly loved the one from Star Trek II and yet, despite this new one being good, the Saavik from Wrath of Khan was superior. In the end, I can say that 'Star Trek III: The Search for Spock' is a good movie and would be considerably better had that 20 minute ending to a 1 hr 45 minute movie not got in the way. That being said, this movie is still fun and has considerable entertainment and displays such adventurous quality to a fun Sci Fi movie and a rather good and worthy addition to Star Trek.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Good Search It Is
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Michael_Elliott
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Star Trek III: The Search for Spock (1984) *** (out of 4) After the events in the previous film, Kirk (William Shatner) risks his career by stealing the Enterprise to go to a restricted planet in hopes of finding Spock's body who they feel might be alive. Along the way they run into a Klingon leader (Christopher Lloyd) who wants to kill them all. STAR TREK III: THE SEARCH OF SPOCK probably shouldn't have worked since if you've seen the second film then you know what happens to Spock. In order for this "trick" to work the producers and writers really needed to come up with something good and thankfully they did that. I won't ruin what this trick is in "the search for Spock" but I thought it was a rather smart move and it helped make the film a lot more believable. Leonard Nimoy steps into the director's chair here and it's obvious he's very comfortable there as he delivers a good looking film with a good pace and of course the main people back in action. Once again we've got Shatner turning in a good performance as Spock and there's no question that he helps keep the film moving. I don't care what you want to say about the guy but there's no question that he owned this role and could play it in his sleep. Regulars like DeForrest Kelley, James Doohan and George Takei are also good in their roles. It seems a lot of people are split on Lloyd but I thought he was pretty good here. I liked seeing him under all the make-up and thought he did a good job even if the role itself wasn't the greatest. The special effects here are certainly a step up from the previous movie and I'd also say that battle sequences are much better directed. Overall this film doesn't quite reach the levels as the second but it's certainly a worthy sequel.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Spock returns.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bluesman-20
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Star Trek III was one of my favourite Trek movies. The Story gets as emotional and personal as it can be. The Enterprise returns to Spacedock battle scarred and looking her age The Events of the movie follow by rapidly. The planet caused by the Genesis explosion has become a scandal. It is a forbidden subject and off limits to everyone. Dr.McCoy is suffering from something and Spock's Father Sarek comes to Kirk demanding the return of Spock's body and his Katra. Kirk learns Spock placed his soul his spirit inside McCoy. And McCoy is slowly being driven insane, Not only that his life itself is in danger. Meanwhile Kirk's Son and Lt. Saavick go to the planet and Discover Spock is alive and growing older with the planet. The planet itself is dying and so is Spock. The Klingons discover the Geneisis project and want it for a super weapon. This leads to a dramatic climax in which Kirk and Crew Steal the Enterprise go to the planet and Fight the Klingons only to destroy the Enterprise in a effort to save Spock. It gets more personal as Kirk discovers the Klingon's have killed his son. Angered Kirk goes to war to save what is left of the things that matter to him. To me the key scene here is the death of the U.S.S Enterprise. Kirk's true love,He destroys it to save his best friends. That to me speaks of the love this band of brothers have for one another. Under rated for sure. But just as great as the others in the series.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The best yet...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Leofwine_draca
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I enjoyed STAR TREK III: THE SEARCH FOR SPOCK a lot better than the overrated previous instalment, which was way too derivative of the original TV show (with its 'villain of the week' format) and did absolutely nothing for me. Let's face it, such story lines have been done time and again, and it takes something special to make a film stand out from the rest. Thankfully, THE SEARCH FOR SPOCK has that something special to it. Leonard Nimoy steps in as director and does a confident, assured job; even better, the quest storyline is heartfelt, emotionally wrought, and unexpected. The crew are all on top form, giving it their all and staying true to their characters throughout, and the Klingons make great, theatrical enemies, particularly Christopher Lloyd's OTT head bad guy. At the end of the day, I watch these films as somebody with an interest in the sci-fi genre rather than as a Trekkie, and so far this has been my favourite. I look forward to checking out part four!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Figures They'd Save Spock
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    wfjohnston14
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Star Trek III: The Search for Spock is a good film that follows right after the second film. This film, directed by Leonard Nimoy, is a nice film to add to the Star Trek Franchise. The Enterprise crew risks their careers as they take the decommissioned Enterprise to search for Spock's body. They find that Spock's body is missing and go searching for it and find a Vulcan boy instead who looks like Spock. Also, they intercept a Klingon ship at the planet too that puts one of the members of the Enterprise in danger and losing their life. What happened to Spock? Will the Enterprise survive against the Klingon? And what will happen to Kirk? This film is a good film, it has problems, but it is a very good film that is very entertaining and brings back Spock. When Spock's body landed on the planet that was being powered by Genesis, his body regenerated and that's why they found him as a boy. The one problem though is that the planet is regenerating too fast and is soon falling apart and Spock too is aging rapidly. He then is himself, but with no memory, so when they take the Klingon ship back to Vulcan, he and McCoy mind meld and Spock is better. Spock gave McCoy his memory right before he died. The crew member that dies is Kirk's son and he gets very emotional and later to save the crew, destroys the ship and they escape using the Klingon ship. This film is a nice addition and puts things back to where they used to be, everyone alright and ready to go on new adventures. A job well done Nimoy. Me: B
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not quite stronger, but a lot better than the original
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gavin-thelordofthefu-48-460297
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    While Star Trek III may not be as strong or as epic as the Wrath of Khan, it is however a lot better than the original in some ways. The story is fine aside from a few over-the-top moments and mediocre dialog; the script is decent it helped explain the Enterprise group's attempt to find Spock, who died in the end of Star Trek II and the pacing moves along very nicely. The scenery is great and the visuals are terrific. The acting is still solid and aside from William Shatner and Leonard Nimoy, Christopher Lloyd is so enjoyable as Kruge. The music score from James Horner is rousing and the action sequences are thrilling. Overall, not strong, but an enjoyable entry to the franchise even though I'm not a Trekkie.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Standing Proof That Odd Numbered Treks Aren't Always Bad
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Jacob Jefferson (jjgooner@yahoo.co.uk)
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Star Trek III: The Search for Spock *** (out of 4) 102 mins/ PG Cast: William Shatner, Leonard Nimoy, DeForest Kelley, James Doohan, George Takei, Robin Curts, Merritt Butrick, Christopher Lloyd Director: Leonard Nimoy Plot: Admiral Kirk is forced to steal the Enterprise ship and return to planet Genesis to find Spock's lifeless body. JJ's Verdict: Anyone who says all odd numbered Star Trek films are bad is totally wrong. In fact I even prefer The Search for Spock to the superior (so the majority says) Wrath of Khan. Following on from its predecessor, the film constantly references to events from it. While doing this it uses great footage and piles on Kirk's emotional baggage from Spock's 'death' scene. I put death in commas because as the film suggests and his actor's name in the cast list, Spock isn't actually dead. He mind-melted with Kelley's Dr. McCoy and left his body on Genesis. This film follows Kirk and his crew in their recovery of the body and their fight to stop the evil Klingons form inhabiting the planet. This revelation that Spock isn't dead, although fine as a plot element, sort of takes away the effect the final scene of Wrath of Khan has on you. The Search for Spock actually has a much clearer plot than the previous films and although it might be a tiny bit predictable at times, at least it is easier to follow than past Star Trek ventures. The way the film weaves between three groups of people (Kirk and his crew, The Klingons and Saavik and David) keeps the film very interesting and engaging throughout and almost makes it feel like an ensemble piece. The film has both improved special effects and space battles and the acting is very good throughout. William Shatner leads the front-line once again and also tops his performance from Star Trek II. And Christopher Lloyd's Klingon, despite not looking very convincing, plays it pretty scary. The scene in which Kirk and the crew steal The Enterprise is highly amusing and is great tongue-in-cheek humour. Leonard Nimoy, although consistently good as Spock, really finds his speciality in directing. His direction of all the actors really makes you care about their characters and he achieves something that, yet again, the previous two films couldn't do; he kept the audience interested. The film ends on a fitting high note and makes you feel very satisfied. And although Kirk seems to think so, I haven't had enough of this film and wish every Trek could be like this.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Decent Star Trek Movie,But Dosen't Live Up To Wrath Of Khan,
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Dillon Harris
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Star Trek 3: The Search For Spock is a pretty good movie with a decent storyline but a very strong cast.It's definitely not the worst in the Star Trek film series,but it's not the best either.It doesn't live up to it's predecessor,Star Trek 2: The Wrath Of Khan,but it's still a lot better than Star Trek: The Motion Picture.The Search For Spock still has a lot of great action sequences and although it's missing Leonard Nimoy for most of the movie,it's still delivers very strong performances from the other cast members,William Shatner is as good as ever in this movie as Cpatain James T. Kirk.While I feel huge Star Trek fans will be disappointed with the Search For Spockk,they will still get a good kick out of him and wont be entirely unimpressed. Captain Kirk (William Shatner) heads off with his crew on the Enterprise to the Genesis planet to save Spock (Leonard Nimoy,who also directs),who may still be alive.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "Turn death into a fighting chance to live."
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Al_The_Strange
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    With the rip-roaring success of The Wrath of Khan, the studios greenlit the third classic Trek film with Spock himself as the director. The problem is, with the way the last film ended, Spock couldn't be in the actual film. It was only natural that the next step in the series was to bring Spock back; hence, the search. The Search for Spock starts off a bit brooding, but quickly taps into the right adventurous spirit as the Enterprise crew becomes renegades and gives the Federation a hilarious slip. From then on, with bad run-ins with Klingons, the stakes are raised very high, and the struggle becomes quite epic. A few scenes stand out as being fairly epic and jaw-dropping. It is an entertaining thrill ride overall. My only beef with the film is that it still feels very small-scale. A lot of it might be because pitting the Enterprise crew against one small greedy band of Klingon rogues, led by a rather flat one-dimensional villain, just doesn't compare to everything we've already seen in The Wrath of Khan. Let's face it, Khan was too good of a villain, and nothing Captain Kruge does can outstage that. Not even the constant raising of the stakes, and confrontations with death, are able to elevate the film above and beyond the limited confines of its own plot. Despite those quibbles, the film still does the best it can to one-up most things, and still deliver the best story it can. The classic Trek crew remains a fun, endearing, and well-rounded group of characters, and their adventure follows a solid plot structure. Themes of rebirth, initially introduced in the last film, are reinforced here. This film boasts solid, steady photography and editing. Acting is not bad: William Shatner, Leonard Nimoy, DeForest Kelley, and the other classic Trek cast members reprise their roles with good nuance, and with a little more tongue-in-cheek attitude. Christopher Lloyd plays the villain quite memorably, even if the character is a two-bit scumbag. This production has some really good-looking sets, props, costumes, and special effects. The music score has more of the same from the last film, and that's not bad. On its own, this film is fun and satisfying, but understanding its story may rely pretty heavily on seeing The Wrath of Khan first. As such, it's best recommended as an immediate follow-up. 4/5 (Entertainment: Very Good | Story: Pretty Good | Film: Very Good)
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I'm still searching for answers
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ironhorse_iv
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie didn't answer much. Search for Spock has some aspect of the Star Trek theme, but it is very poorly handled. Still, not bad for Leonard Nimoy's first directed film. This one isn't as bad as the other odd numbered installments, especially if you factor in the fact that it ties what happen in the events of the previous Star Trek movie 'Wrath of Khan' so well. If you are a first time viewer of this movie, I wouldn't watch this movie until you watch Wrath of Khan first. It's very important to watch that movie before this. Yes, Star Trek III: The Search for Spock came after that movie, and being after such a masterpiece, people going to look at it being worst compare to that film. No, Star Trek film can live up to that film. Still the movie has some OK action scenes and interesting story. The movie starts out with recaps of the last few minutes of Wrath of Khan and then the movie officially begins. A spy has deliver some information about the Genesis program that Klingon commander Kruge (Christopher Lloyd) needs to hear. It seems like Genesis does, what Nintendo don't. What I meant by that is that Genesis has create life on a planet. The Klingons see this as a weapon to have. The Klingons were always Russian allegory in these films. So hearing this, must have been the same feeling when the Soviets heard about the Atom Bomb. Still, I cannot get over the fact that Christopher Lloyd is playing a Klingon, here. I was expecting him to shout "Great Scott!" or something. His character is quite stupid and silly at times. Just watch the killer plant scene, you can't help laughing at him. He's just not that menacing enough and not epic to the likes of Khan. Well, the Klingons are not the only ones hearing voices, but Dr. McCoy (De Forest Kelly) is talking all crazy about a certain Vulcan name Spock and that Captain Kirk (William Shatner) and the crew should go to Genesis to search for him. Now it's a quest between the crew of the Enterprise to rescue Spock before the Klingons get a hold of the planet. This movie suffers from the typical middle child syndrome of being a 2nd movie in a trilogy's story arc. Star Trek III: The Search For Spock is the second chapter of what is called by some fans "the Star Trek Trilogy", yes it is the third film of the series, but it's the second act in what is indeed a three parter. The first act is in Wrath of Khan, concerning its events leading up to somebody's death. The second act is in Search for Spock where somebody soul and body have to be re united and the third is in Voyage Home where somebody fully regains himself. My biggest problem with Start Trek 3 is that I feel it takes away from the impact of 2. The whole idea of life and death at the end of the 2nd one regarding a death of a character and the birth of a new planet is breath taking. Then this movie has Genesis's kind of break that apart! Breaking apart is a theme here. This film shows that Kirk ends up losing so much more than a friend. He sacrifices his ship, loses a family member and hope. The scene where Kirk is forced to relive his friend's death when he does the mind meld is a wonderful scene. The problem is when you look at how strong, 2 is with its story and themes and how this one causes those scenes to be all for nothing. It's disappointing. I think the worst idea is bringing back a character back after such a heroic death. The needs of the many outweigh the needs of the few. Captain Kirk's friend is noted to say for the reasons and justifying about his sacrifice. I believe that if you kill a character, then that character should stays dead. It does no favors for somebody to kill a character, only to bring them back in a later movie. Its movies like this, that started the 'resurrection of Jesus' concept of bringing dead characters back to live. A good example is Ellen Ripley who dies in Alien 3 only to be given an awful new spin in Alien Resurrection. It's like Nimoy woke up and realize how much money he can make, if he brings back a beloved character back to life. At less, this character got a good story on how he came back, so I can't complain too loudly. Still, it makes you wonders if Genesis was aging faster and faster; how come Kirk's friend didn't aged out as well. Wouldn't he die again by old age? Also how comes, nobody else aged on the planet if Genesis does that to life forms? Wouldn't they also grow older as long as they stay on the planet? The science is baffling. Also what's baffling is how Kristie Alley regenerated to Robin Curtis. It's seem like Alley didn't want to return, so the character was rewritten as a new character as Savvik. I find the Pon-Farr scene, stupid as hell. And where was David Marcus's mother, Carol? It would've been interesting to have her in Saavik's place down on Genesis and it would make more sense. The movie's over all is that it's works to a level, but compare to others. It's not that awesome. Still, it's worth the watch, so check it out. So start trekking.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Needs of the many do indeed outweigh the needs of the few with this film!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    illbebackreviews
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    As a countdown to 'Star Trek: Into Darkness', I decided to watch every single Star Trek movie for the first time. After the brilliant second film, I was excited to watch this one despite not being sure of what to expect. I had heard a lot of criticism about this movie calling it a cheap business trick. 'Star Trek III: The Search for Spock' basically follows the story of Admiral Kirk who has a tough time getting over the loss of his Vulcan friend, Spock. When Bones begins to act strangely, acting as if he is Spock, Kirk begins to realize, with the help of Spock's father, that maybe Spock can be brought back to life if his body and his mind (in this case Bones) are re-united and a spell cast to re-join the two however Klingon Commander, Kruge, played by Christopher Llyod turns out to be the only obstacle as he is in pursuit for the secrets to Genesis. There were quite a few things I really liked about this movie. Much like Star Trek II, I really liked the villain here played brilliantly by Christopher Llyod, who honestly feels the scene stealer in this film. I do love much of the story and I do not believe that this feels like a cash grab, unlike movies such as the Star Wars prequels which were made entirely for merchandising rights and not for story. The story was handled well and it wasn't anything like Spock never died but much more deep. Also the adventure that this movie has is great and I loved all the movie until the last half hour where much of the film becomes rather silly and could easily have been cut down or it could've been directed much better than it was. **SPOILERS AHEAD*** Of course, I am referring to when Kirk attempts to lure Kruge back to the now destructing Genesis and the two fight. Obviously, this fight looks terrible. I am not after any choreographed fight sequence that goes on neither is the fight the big mistake here. It is how this fight ends and Kruge is killed in an extremely silly and childish manner, with Kirk remarking "I have had enough of you!" This is literally the end of the majority of the story until the film truly needs to wrap up. **END OF SPOILERS** Now the film does need a good 20 minutes to truly wrap up and it does get slow and the greatness of the most of the rest of the film truly drops for me here. I am sick of people bashing the multiple endings to 'The Lord of the Rings: The Return of the King' stating that the endings were too many and too long. In that case, people do not realize that the Lord of the Rings is ranked 'Massive' on a scale. It needs those endings to wrap up a 12 hour trilogy...This film doesn't need 20 minutes to wrap up. This ending could've been 10 minutes and would've been perfect or the last 10 minutes or so could've been cut and as a cliffhanger, be added into the beginning of the next Star Trek film and I'm guessing it would work, considering the movie ends with 'The adventure continues...' The special effects were truly sloppy in this movie and such moments like when the Enterprise is destroyed and Genesis is being destroyed certainly do look bad. The acting is mostly good by the crew and was quite a pity to see a re-cast for Saavik...I truly loved the one from Star Trek II and yet, despite this new one being good, the Saavik from Wrath of Khan was superior. In the end, I can say that 'Star Trek III: The Search for Spock' is a good movie and would be considerably better had that 20 minute ending to a 1 hr 45 minute movie not got in the way. That being said, this movie is still fun and has considerable entertainment and displays such adventurous quality to a fun Sci Fi movie and a rather good and worthy addition to Star Trek.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Good Search It Is
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Michael_Elliott
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Star Trek III: The Search for Spock (1984) *** (out of 4) After the events in the previous film, Kirk (William Shatner) risks his career by stealing the Enterprise to go to a restricted planet in hopes of finding Spock's body who they feel might be alive. Along the way they run into a Klingon leader (Christopher Lloyd) who wants to kill them all. STAR TREK III: THE SEARCH OF SPOCK probably shouldn't have worked since if you've seen the second film then you know what happens to Spock. In order for this "trick" to work the producers and writers really needed to come up with something good and thankfully they did that. I won't ruin what this trick is in "the search for Spock" but I thought it was a rather smart move and it helped make the film a lot more believable. Leonard Nimoy steps into the director's chair here and it's obvious he's very comfortable there as he delivers a good looking film with a good pace and of course the main people back in action. Once again we've got Shatner turning in a good performance as Spock and there's no question that he helps keep the film moving. I don't care what you want to say about the guy but there's no question that he owned this role and could play it in his sleep. Regulars like DeForrest Kelley, James Doohan and George Takei are also good in their roles. It seems a lot of people are split on Lloyd but I thought he was pretty good here. I liked seeing him under all the make-up and thought he did a good job even if the role itself wasn't the greatest. The special effects here are certainly a step up from the previous movie and I'd also say that battle sequences are much better directed. Overall this film doesn't quite reach the levels as the second but it's certainly a worthy sequel.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Spock returns.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bluesman-20
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Star Trek III was one of my favourite Trek movies. The Story gets as emotional and personal as it can be. The Enterprise returns to Spacedock battle scarred and looking her age The Events of the movie follow by rapidly. The planet caused by the Genesis explosion has become a scandal. It is a forbidden subject and off limits to everyone. Dr.McCoy is suffering from something and Spock's Father Sarek comes to Kirk demanding the return of Spock's body and his Katra. Kirk learns Spock placed his soul his spirit inside McCoy. And McCoy is slowly being driven insane, Not only that his life itself is in danger. Meanwhile Kirk's Son and Lt. Saavick go to the planet and Discover Spock is alive and growing older with the planet. The planet itself is dying and so is Spock. The Klingons discover the Geneisis project and want it for a super weapon. This leads to a dramatic climax in which Kirk and Crew Steal the Enterprise go to the planet and Fight the Klingons only to destroy the Enterprise in a effort to save Spock. It gets more personal as Kirk discovers the Klingon's have killed his son. Angered Kirk goes to war to save what is left of the things that matter to him. To me the key scene here is the death of the U.S.S Enterprise. Kirk's true love,He destroys it to save his best friends. That to me speaks of the love this band of brothers have for one another. Under rated for sure. But just as great as the others in the series.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The best yet...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Leofwine_draca
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I enjoyed STAR TREK III: THE SEARCH FOR SPOCK a lot better than the overrated previous instalment, which was way too derivative of the original TV show (with its 'villain of the week' format) and did absolutely nothing for me. Let's face it, such story lines have been done time and again, and it takes something special to make a film stand out from the rest. Thankfully, THE SEARCH FOR SPOCK has that something special to it. Leonard Nimoy steps in as director and does a confident, assured job; even better, the quest storyline is heartfelt, emotionally wrought, and unexpected. The crew are all on top form, giving it their all and staying true to their characters throughout, and the Klingons make great, theatrical enemies, particularly Christopher Lloyd's OTT head bad guy. At the end of the day, I watch these films as somebody with an interest in the sci-fi genre rather than as a Trekkie, and so far this has been my favourite. I look forward to checking out part four!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Figures They'd Save Spock
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    wfjohnston14
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Star Trek III: The Search for Spock is a good film that follows right after the second film. This film, directed by Leonard Nimoy, is a nice film to add to the Star Trek Franchise. The Enterprise crew risks their careers as they take the decommissioned Enterprise to search for Spock's body. They find that Spock's body is missing and go searching for it and find a Vulcan boy instead who looks like Spock. Also, they intercept a Klingon ship at the planet too that puts one of the members of the Enterprise in danger and losing their life. What happened to Spock? Will the Enterprise survive against the Klingon? And what will happen to Kirk? This film is a good film, it has problems, but it is a very good film that is very entertaining and brings back Spock. When Spock's body landed on the planet that was being powered by Genesis, his body regenerated and that's why they found him as a boy. The one problem though is that the planet is regenerating too fast and is soon falling apart and Spock too is aging rapidly. He then is himself, but with no memory, so when they take the Klingon ship back to Vulcan, he and McCoy mind meld and Spock is better. Spock gave McCoy his memory right before he died. The crew member that dies is Kirk's son and he gets very emotional and later to save the crew, destroys the ship and they escape using the Klingon ship. This film is a nice addition and puts things back to where they used to be, everyone alright and ready to go on new adventures. A job well done Nimoy. Me: B
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not quite stronger, but a lot better than the original
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gavin-thelordofthefu-48-460297
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    While Star Trek III may not be as strong or as epic as the Wrath of Khan, it is however a lot better than the original in some ways. The story is fine aside from a few over-the-top moments and mediocre dialog; the script is decent it helped explain the Enterprise group's attempt to find Spock, who died in the end of Star Trek II and the pacing moves along very nicely. The scenery is great and the visuals are terrific. The acting is still solid and aside from William Shatner and Leonard Nimoy, Christopher Lloyd is so enjoyable as Kruge. The music score from James Horner is rousing and the action sequences are thrilling. Overall, not strong, but an enjoyable entry to the franchise even though I'm not a Trekkie.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Standing Proof That Odd Numbered Treks Aren't Always Bad
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Jacob Jefferson (jjgooner@yahoo.co.uk)
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Star Trek III: The Search for Spock *** (out of 4) 102 mins/ PG Cast: William Shatner, Leonard Nimoy, DeForest Kelley, James Doohan, George Takei, Robin Curts, Merritt Butrick, Christopher Lloyd Director: Leonard Nimoy Plot: Admiral Kirk is forced to steal the Enterprise ship and return to planet Genesis to find Spock's lifeless body. JJ's Verdict: Anyone who says all odd numbered Star Trek films are bad is totally wrong. In fact I even prefer The Search for Spock to the superior (so the majority says) Wrath of Khan. Following on from its predecessor, the film constantly references to events from it. While doing this it uses great footage and piles on Kirk's emotional baggage from Spock's 'death' scene. I put death in commas because as the film suggests and his actor's name in the cast list, Spock isn't actually dead. He mind-melted with Kelley's Dr. McCoy and left his body on Genesis. This film follows Kirk and his crew in their recovery of the body and their fight to stop the evil Klingons form inhabiting the planet. This revelation that Spock isn't dead, although fine as a plot element, sort of takes away the effect the final scene of Wrath of Khan has on you. The Search for Spock actually has a much clearer plot than the previous films and although it might be a tiny bit predictable at times, at least it is easier to follow than past Star Trek ventures. The way the film weaves between three groups of people (Kirk and his crew, The Klingons and Saavik and David) keeps the film very interesting and engaging throughout and almost makes it feel like an ensemble piece. The film has both improved special effects and space battles and the acting is very good throughout. William Shatner leads the front-line once again and also tops his performance from Star Trek II. And Christopher Lloyd's Klingon, despite not looking very convincing, plays it pretty scary. The scene in which Kirk and the crew steal The Enterprise is highly amusing and is great tongue-in-cheek humour. Leonard Nimoy, although consistently good as Spock, really finds his speciality in directing. His direction of all the actors really makes you care about their characters and he achieves something that, yet again, the previous two films couldn't do; he kept the audience interested. The film ends on a fitting high note and makes you feel very satisfied. And although Kirk seems to think so, I haven't had enough of this film and wish every Trek could be like this.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Decent Star Trek Movie,But Dosen't Live Up To Wrath Of Khan,
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Dillon Harris
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Star Trek 3: The Search For Spock is a pretty good movie with a decent storyline but a very strong cast.It's definitely not the worst in the Star Trek film series,but it's not the best either.It doesn't live up to it's predecessor,Star Trek 2: The Wrath Of Khan,but it's still a lot better than Star Trek: The Motion Picture.The Search For Spock still has a lot of great action sequences and although it's missing Leonard Nimoy for most of the movie,it's still delivers very strong performances from the other cast members,William Shatner is as good as ever in this movie as Cpatain James T. Kirk.While I feel huge Star Trek fans will be disappointed with the Search For Spockk,they will still get a good kick out of him and wont be entirely unimpressed. Captain Kirk (William Shatner) heads off with his crew on the Enterprise to the Genesis planet to save Spock (Leonard Nimoy,who also directs),who may still be alive.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "Turn death into a fighting chance to live."
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Al_The_Strange
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    With the rip-roaring success of The Wrath of Khan, the studios greenlit the third classic Trek film with Spock himself as the director. The problem is, with the way the last film ended, Spock couldn't be in the actual film. It was only natural that the next step in the series was to bring Spock back; hence, the search. The Search for Spock starts off a bit brooding, but quickly taps into the right adventurous spirit as the Enterprise crew becomes renegades and gives the Federation a hilarious slip. From then on, with bad run-ins with Klingons, the stakes are raised very high, and the struggle becomes quite epic. A few scenes stand out as being fairly epic and jaw-dropping. It is an entertaining thrill ride overall. My only beef with the film is that it still feels very small-scale. A lot of it might be because pitting the Enterprise crew against one small greedy band of Klingon rogues, led by a rather flat one-dimensional villain, just doesn't compare to everything we've already seen in The Wrath of Khan. Let's face it, Khan was too good of a villain, and nothing Captain Kruge does can outstage that. Not even the constant raising of the stakes, and confrontations with death, are able to elevate the film above and beyond the limited confines of its own plot. Despite those quibbles, the film still does the best it can to one-up most things, and still deliver the best story it can. The classic Trek crew remains a fun, endearing, and well-rounded group of characters, and their adventure follows a solid plot structure. Themes of rebirth, initially introduced in the last film, are reinforced here. This film boasts solid, steady photography and editing. Acting is not bad: William Shatner, Leonard Nimoy, DeForest Kelley, and the other classic Trek cast members reprise their roles with good nuance, and with a little more tongue-in-cheek attitude. Christopher Lloyd plays the villain quite memorably, even if the character is a two-bit scumbag. This production has some really good-looking sets, props, costumes, and special effects. The music score has more of the same from the last film, and that's not bad. On its own, this film is fun and satisfying, but understanding its story may rely pretty heavily on seeing The Wrath of Khan first. As such, it's best recommended as an immediate follow-up. 4/5 (Entertainment: Very Good | Story: Pretty Good | Film: Very Good)
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I'm still searching for answers
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ironhorse_iv
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie didn't answer much. Search for Spock has some aspect of the Star Trek theme, but it is very poorly handled. Still, not bad for Leonard Nimoy's first directed film. This one isn't as bad as the other odd numbered installments, especially if you factor in the fact that it ties what happen in the events of the previous Star Trek movie 'Wrath of Khan' so well. If you are a first time viewer of this movie, I wouldn't watch this movie until you watch Wrath of Khan first. It's very important to watch that movie before this. Yes, Star Trek III: The Search for Spock came after that movie, and being after such a masterpiece, people going to look at it being worst compare to that film. No, Star Trek film can live up to that film. Still the movie has some OK action scenes and interesting story. The movie starts out with recaps of the last few minutes of Wrath of Khan and then the movie officially begins. A spy has deliver some information about the Genesis program that Klingon commander Kruge (Christopher Lloyd) needs to hear. It seems like Genesis does, what Nintendo don't. What I meant by that is that Genesis has create life on a planet. The Klingons see this as a weapon to have. The Klingons were always Russian allegory in these films. So hearing this, must have been the same feeling when the Soviets heard about the Atom Bomb. Still, I cannot get over the fact that Christopher Lloyd is playing a Klingon, here. I was expecting him to shout "Great Scott!" or something. His character is quite stupid and silly at times. Just watch the killer plant scene, you can't help laughing at him. He's just not that menacing enough and not epic to the likes of Khan. Well, the Klingons are not the only ones hearing voices, but Dr. McCoy (De Forest Kelly) is talking all crazy about a certain Vulcan name Spock and that Captain Kirk (William Shatner) and the crew should go to Genesis to search for him. Now it's a quest between the crew of the Enterprise to rescue Spock before the Klingons get a hold of the planet. This movie suffers from the typical middle child syndrome of being a 2nd movie in a trilogy's story arc. Star Trek III: The Search For Spock is the second chapter of what is called by some fans "the Star Trek Trilogy", yes it is the third film of the series, but it's the second act in what is indeed a three parter. The first act is in Wrath of Khan, concerning its events leading up to somebody's death. The second act is in Search for Spock where somebody soul and body have to be re united and the third is in Voyage Home where somebody fully regains himself. My biggest problem with Start Trek 3 is that I feel it takes away from the impact of 2. The whole idea of life and death at the end of the 2nd one regarding a death of a character and the birth of a new planet is breath taking. Then this movie has Genesis's kind of break that apart! Breaking apart is a theme here. This film shows that Kirk ends up losing so much more than a friend. He sacrifices his ship, loses a family member and hope. The scene where Kirk is forced to relive his friend's death when he does the mind meld is a wonderful scene. The problem is when you look at how strong, 2 is with its story and themes and how this one causes those scenes to be all for nothing. It's disappointing. I think the worst idea is bringing back a character back after such a heroic death. The needs of the many outweigh the needs of the few. Captain Kirk's friend is noted to say for the reasons and justifying about his sacrifice. I believe that if you kill a character, then that character should stays dead. It does no favors for somebody to kill a character, only to bring them back in a later movie. Its movies like this, that started the 'resurrection of Jesus' concept of bringing dead characters back to live. A good example is Ellen Ripley who dies in Alien 3 only to be given an awful new spin in Alien Resurrection. It's like Nimoy woke up and realize how much money he can make, if he brings back a beloved character back to life. At less, this character got a good story on how he came back, so I can't complain too loudly. Still, it makes you wonders if Genesis was aging faster and faster; how come Kirk's friend didn't aged out as well. Wouldn't he die again by old age? Also how comes, nobody else aged on the planet if Genesis does that to life forms? Wouldn't they also grow older as long as they stay on the planet? The science is baffling. Also what's baffling is how Kristie Alley regenerated to Robin Curtis. It's seem like Alley didn't want to return, so the character was rewritten as a new character as Savvik. I find the Pon-Farr scene, stupid as hell. And where was David Marcus's mother, Carol? It would've been interesting to have her in Saavik's place down on Genesis and it would make more sense. The movie's over all is that it's works to a level, but compare to others. It's not that awesome. Still, it's worth the watch, so check it out. So start trekking.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Needs of the many do indeed outweigh the needs of the few with this film!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    illbebackreviews
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    As a countdown to 'Star Trek: Into Darkness', I decided to watch every single Star Trek movie for the first time. After the brilliant second film, I was excited to watch this one despite not being sure of what to expect. I had heard a lot of criticism about this movie calling it a cheap business trick. 'Star Trek III: The Search for Spock' basically follows the story of Admiral Kirk who has a tough time getting over the loss of his Vulcan friend, Spock. When Bones begins to act strangely, acting as if he is Spock, Kirk begins to realize, with the help of Spock's father, that maybe Spock can be brought back to life if his body and his mind (in this case Bones) are re-united and a spell cast to re-join the two however Klingon Commander, Kruge, played by Christopher Llyod turns out to be the only obstacle as he is in pursuit for the secrets to Genesis. There were quite a few things I really liked about this movie. Much like Star Trek II, I really liked the villain here played brilliantly by Christopher Llyod, who honestly feels the scene stealer in this film. I do love much of the story and I do not believe that this feels like a cash grab, unlike movies such as the Star Wars prequels which were made entirely for merchandising rights and not for story. The story was handled well and it wasn't anything like Spock never died but much more deep. Also the adventure that this movie has is great and I loved all the movie until the last half hour where much of the film becomes rather silly and could easily have been cut down or it could've been directed much better than it was. **SPOILERS AHEAD*** Of course, I am referring to when Kirk attempts to lure Kruge back to the now destructing Genesis and the two fight. Obviously, this fight looks terrible. I am not after any choreographed fight sequence that goes on neither is the fight the big mistake here. It is how this fight ends and Kruge is killed in an extremely silly and childish manner, with Kirk remarking "I have had enough of you!" This is literally the end of the majority of the story until the film truly needs to wrap up. **END OF SPOILERS** Now the film does need a good 20 minutes to truly wrap up and it does get slow and the greatness of the most of the rest of the film truly drops for me here. I am sick of people bashing the multiple endings to 'The Lord of the Rings: The Return of the King' stating that the endings were too many and too long. In that case, people do not realize that the Lord of the Rings is ranked 'Massive' on a scale. It needs those endings to wrap up a 12 hour trilogy...This film doesn't need 20 minutes to wrap up. This ending could've been 10 minutes and would've been perfect or the last 10 minutes or so could've been cut and as a cliffhanger, be added into the beginning of the next Star Trek film and I'm guessing it would work, considering the movie ends with 'The adventure continues...' The special effects were truly sloppy in this movie and such moments like when the Enterprise is destroyed and Genesis is being destroyed certainly do look bad. The acting is mostly good by the crew and was quite a pity to see a re-cast for Saavik...I truly loved the one from Star Trek II and yet, despite this new one being good, the Saavik from Wrath of Khan was superior. In the end, I can say that 'Star Trek III: The Search for Spock' is a good movie and would be considerably better had that 20 minute ending to a 1 hr 45 minute movie not got in the way. That being said, this movie is still fun and has considerable entertainment and displays such adventurous quality to a fun Sci Fi movie and a rather good and worthy addition to Star Trek.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Good Search It Is
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Michael_Elliott
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Star Trek III: The Search for Spock (1984) *** (out of 4) After the events in the previous film, Kirk (William Shatner) risks his career by stealing the Enterprise to go to a restricted planet in hopes of finding Spock's body who they feel might be alive. Along the way they run into a Klingon leader (Christopher Lloyd) who wants to kill them all. STAR TREK III: THE SEARCH OF SPOCK probably shouldn't have worked since if you've seen the second film then you know what happens to Spock. In order for this "trick" to work the producers and writers really needed to come up with something good and thankfully they did that. I won't ruin what this trick is in "the search for Spock" but I thought it was a rather smart move and it helped make the film a lot more believable. Leonard Nimoy steps into the director's chair here and it's obvious he's very comfortable there as he delivers a good looking film with a good pace and of course the main people back in action. Once again we've got Shatner turning in a good performance as Spock and there's no question that he helps keep the film moving. I don't care what you want to say about the guy but there's no question that he owned this role and could play it in his sleep. Regulars like DeForrest Kelley, James Doohan and George Takei are also good in their roles. It seems a lot of people are split on Lloyd but I thought he was pretty good here. I liked seeing him under all the make-up and thought he did a good job even if the role itself wasn't the greatest. The special effects here are certainly a step up from the previous movie and I'd also say that battle sequences are much better directed. Overall this film doesn't quite reach the levels as the second but it's certainly a worthy sequel.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Spock returns.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bluesman-20
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Star Trek III was one of my favourite Trek movies. The Story gets as emotional and personal as it can be. The Enterprise returns to Spacedock battle scarred and looking her age The Events of the movie follow by rapidly. The planet caused by the Genesis explosion has become a scandal. It is a forbidden subject and off limits to everyone. Dr.McCoy is suffering from something and Spock's Father Sarek comes to Kirk demanding the return of Spock's body and his Katra. Kirk learns Spock placed his soul his spirit inside McCoy. And McCoy is slowly being driven insane, Not only that his life itself is in danger. Meanwhile Kirk's Son and Lt. Saavick go to the planet and Discover Spock is alive and growing older with the planet. The planet itself is dying and so is Spock. The Klingons discover the Geneisis project and want it for a super weapon. This leads to a dramatic climax in which Kirk and Crew Steal the Enterprise go to the planet and Fight the Klingons only to destroy the Enterprise in a effort to save Spock. It gets more personal as Kirk discovers the Klingon's have killed his son. Angered Kirk goes to war to save what is left of the things that matter to him. To me the key scene here is the death of the U.S.S Enterprise. Kirk's true love,He destroys it to save his best friends. That to me speaks of the love this band of brothers have for one another. Under rated for sure. But just as great as the others in the series.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The best yet...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Leofwine_draca
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I enjoyed STAR TREK III: THE SEARCH FOR SPOCK a lot better than the overrated previous instalment, which was way too derivative of the original TV show (with its 'villain of the week' format) and did absolutely nothing for me. Let's face it, such story lines have been done time and again, and it takes something special to make a film stand out from the rest. Thankfully, THE SEARCH FOR SPOCK has that something special to it. Leonard Nimoy steps in as director and does a confident, assured job; even better, the quest storyline is heartfelt, emotionally wrought, and unexpected. The crew are all on top form, giving it their all and staying true to their characters throughout, and the Klingons make great, theatrical enemies, particularly Christopher Lloyd's OTT head bad guy. At the end of the day, I watch these films as somebody with an interest in the sci-fi genre rather than as a Trekkie, and so far this has been my favourite. I look forward to checking out part four!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Figures They'd Save Spock
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    wfjohnston14
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Star Trek III: The Search for Spock is a good film that follows right after the second film. This film, directed by Leonard Nimoy, is a nice film to add to the Star Trek Franchise. The Enterprise crew risks their careers as they take the decommissioned Enterprise to search for Spock's body. They find that Spock's body is missing and go searching for it and find a Vulcan boy instead who looks like Spock. Also, they intercept a Klingon ship at the planet too that puts one of the members of the Enterprise in danger and losing their life. What happened to Spock? Will the Enterprise survive against the Klingon? And what will happen to Kirk? This film is a good film, it has problems, but it is a very good film that is very entertaining and brings back Spock. When Spock's body landed on the planet that was being powered by Genesis, his body regenerated and that's why they found him as a boy. The one problem though is that the planet is regenerating too fast and is soon falling apart and Spock too is aging rapidly. He then is himself, but with no memory, so when they take the Klingon ship back to Vulcan, he and McCoy mind meld and Spock is better. Spock gave McCoy his memory right before he died. The crew member that dies is Kirk's son and he gets very emotional and later to save the crew, destroys the ship and they escape using the Klingon ship. This film is a nice addition and puts things back to where they used to be, everyone alright and ready to go on new adventures. A job well done Nimoy. Me: B
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not quite stronger, but a lot better than the original
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gavin-thelordofthefu-48-460297
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    While Star Trek III may not be as strong or as epic as the Wrath of Khan, it is however a lot better than the original in some ways. The story is fine aside from a few over-the-top moments and mediocre dialog; the script is decent it helped explain the Enterprise group's attempt to find Spock, who died in the end of Star Trek II and the pacing moves along very nicely. The scenery is great and the visuals are terrific. The acting is still solid and aside from William Shatner and Leonard Nimoy, Christopher Lloyd is so enjoyable as Kruge. The music score from James Horner is rousing and the action sequences are thrilling. Overall, not strong, but an enjoyable entry to the franchise even though I'm not a Trekkie.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Standing Proof That Odd Numbered Treks Aren't Always Bad
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Jacob Jefferson (jjgooner@yahoo.co.uk)
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Star Trek III: The Search for Spock *** (out of 4) 102 mins/ PG Cast: William Shatner, Leonard Nimoy, DeForest Kelley, James Doohan, George Takei, Robin Curts, Merritt Butrick, Christopher Lloyd Director: Leonard Nimoy Plot: Admiral Kirk is forced to steal the Enterprise ship and return to planet Genesis to find Spock's lifeless body. JJ's Verdict: Anyone who says all odd numbered Star Trek films are bad is totally wrong. In fact I even prefer The Search for Spock to the superior (so the majority says) Wrath of Khan. Following on from its predecessor, the film constantly references to events from it. While doing this it uses great footage and piles on Kirk's emotional baggage from Spock's 'death' scene. I put death in commas because as the film suggests and his actor's name in the cast list, Spock isn't actually dead. He mind-melted with Kelley's Dr. McCoy and left his body on Genesis. This film follows Kirk and his crew in their recovery of the body and their fight to stop the evil Klingons form inhabiting the planet. This revelation that Spock isn't dead, although fine as a plot element, sort of takes away the effect the final scene of Wrath of Khan has on you. The Search for Spock actually has a much clearer plot than the previous films and although it might be a tiny bit predictable at times, at least it is easier to follow than past Star Trek ventures. The way the film weaves between three groups of people (Kirk and his crew, The Klingons and Saavik and David) keeps the film very interesting and engaging throughout and almost makes it feel like an ensemble piece. The film has both improved special effects and space battles and the acting is very good throughout. William Shatner leads the front-line once again and also tops his performance from Star Trek II. And Christopher Lloyd's Klingon, despite not looking very convincing, plays it pretty scary. The scene in which Kirk and the crew steal The Enterprise is highly amusing and is great tongue-in-cheek humour. Leonard Nimoy, although consistently good as Spock, really finds his speciality in directing. His direction of all the actors really makes you care about their characters and he achieves something that, yet again, the previous two films couldn't do; he kept the audience interested. The film ends on a fitting high note and makes you feel very satisfied. And although Kirk seems to think so, I haven't had enough of this film and wish every Trek could be like this.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Decent Star Trek Movie,But Dosen't Live Up To Wrath Of Khan,
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Dillon Harris
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Star Trek 3: The Search For Spock is a pretty good movie with a decent storyline but a very strong cast.It's definitely not the worst in the Star Trek film series,but it's not the best either.It doesn't live up to it's predecessor,Star Trek 2: The Wrath Of Khan,but it's still a lot better than Star Trek: The Motion Picture.The Search For Spock still has a lot of great action sequences and although it's missing Leonard Nimoy for most of the movie,it's still delivers very strong performances from the other cast members,William Shatner is as good as ever in this movie as Cpatain James T. Kirk.While I feel huge Star Trek fans will be disappointed with the Search For Spockk,they will still get a good kick out of him and wont be entirely unimpressed. Captain Kirk (William Shatner) heads off with his crew on the Enterprise to the Genesis planet to save Spock (Leonard Nimoy,who also directs),who may still be alive.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "Turn death into a fighting chance to live."
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Al_The_Strange
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    With the rip-roaring success of The Wrath of Khan, the studios greenlit the third classic Trek film with Spock himself as the director. The problem is, with the way the last film ended, Spock couldn't be in the actual film. It was only natural that the next step in the series was to bring Spock back; hence, the search. The Search for Spock starts off a bit brooding, but quickly taps into the right adventurous spirit as the Enterprise crew becomes renegades and gives the Federation a hilarious slip. From then on, with bad run-ins with Klingons, the stakes are raised very high, and the struggle becomes quite epic. A few scenes stand out as being fairly epic and jaw-dropping. It is an entertaining thrill ride overall. My only beef with the film is that it still feels very small-scale. A lot of it might be because pitting the Enterprise crew against one small greedy band of Klingon rogues, led by a rather flat one-dimensional villain, just doesn't compare to everything we've already seen in The Wrath of Khan. Let's face it, Khan was too good of a villain, and nothing Captain Kruge does can outstage that. Not even the constant raising of the stakes, and confrontations with death, are able to elevate the film above and beyond the limited confines of its own plot. Despite those quibbles, the film still does the best it can to one-up most things, and still deliver the best story it can. The classic Trek crew remains a fun, endearing, and well-rounded group of characters, and their adventure follows a solid plot structure. Themes of rebirth, initially introduced in the last film, are reinforced here. This film boasts solid, steady photography and editing. Acting is not bad: William Shatner, Leonard Nimoy, DeForest Kelley, and the other classic Trek cast members reprise their roles with good nuance, and with a little more tongue-in-cheek attitude. Christopher Lloyd plays the villain quite memorably, even if the character is a two-bit scumbag. This production has some really good-looking sets, props, costumes, and special effects. The music score has more of the same from the last film, and that's not bad. On its own, this film is fun and satisfying, but understanding its story may rely pretty heavily on seeing The Wrath of Khan first. As such, it's best recommended as an immediate follow-up. 4/5 (Entertainment: Very Good | Story: Pretty Good | Film: Very Good)
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I'm still searching for answers
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ironhorse_iv
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie didn't answer much. Search for Spock has some aspect of the Star Trek theme, but it is very poorly handled. Still, not bad for Leonard Nimoy's first directed film. This one isn't as bad as the other odd numbered installments, especially if you factor in the fact that it ties what happen in the events of the previous Star Trek movie 'Wrath of Khan' so well. If you are a first time viewer of this movie, I wouldn't watch this movie until you watch Wrath of Khan first. It's very important to watch that movie before this. Yes, Star Trek III: The Search for Spock came after that movie, and being after such a masterpiece, people going to look at it being worst compare to that film. No, Star Trek film can live up to that film. Still the movie has some OK action scenes and interesting story. The movie starts out with recaps of the last few minutes of Wrath of Khan and then the movie officially begins. A spy has deliver some information about the Genesis program that Klingon commander Kruge (Christopher Lloyd) needs to hear. It seems like Genesis does, what Nintendo don't. What I meant by that is that Genesis has create life on a planet. The Klingons see this as a weapon to have. The Klingons were always Russian allegory in these films. So hearing this, must have been the same feeling when the Soviets heard about the Atom Bomb. Still, I cannot get over the fact that Christopher Lloyd is playing a Klingon, here. I was expecting him to shout "Great Scott!" or something. His character is quite stupid and silly at times. Just watch the killer plant scene, you can't help laughing at him. He's just not that menacing enough and not epic to the likes of Khan. Well, the Klingons are not the only ones hearing voices, but Dr. McCoy (De Forest Kelly) is talking all crazy about a certain Vulcan name Spock and that Captain Kirk (William Shatner) and the crew should go to Genesis to search for him. Now it's a quest between the crew of the Enterprise to rescue Spock before the Klingons get a hold of the planet. This movie suffers from the typical middle child syndrome of being a 2nd movie in a trilogy's story arc. Star Trek III: The Search For Spock is the second chapter of what is called by some fans "the Star Trek Trilogy", yes it is the third film of the series, but it's the second act in what is indeed a three parter. The first act is in Wrath of Khan, concerning its events leading up to somebody's death. The second act is in Search for Spock where somebody soul and body have to be re united and the third is in Voyage Home where somebody fully regains himself. My biggest problem with Start Trek 3 is that I feel it takes away from the impact of 2. The whole idea of life and death at the end of the 2nd one regarding a death of a character and the birth of a new planet is breath taking. Then this movie has Genesis's kind of break that apart! Breaking apart is a theme here. This film shows that Kirk ends up losing so much more than a friend. He sacrifices his ship, loses a family member and hope. The scene where Kirk is forced to relive his friend's death when he does the mind meld is a wonderful scene. The problem is when you look at how strong, 2 is with its story and themes and how this one causes those scenes to be all for nothing. It's disappointing. I think the worst idea is bringing back a character back after such a heroic death. The needs of the many outweigh the needs of the few. Captain Kirk's friend is noted to say for the reasons and justifying about his sacrifice. I believe that if you kill a character, then that character should stays dead. It does no favors for somebody to kill a character, only to bring them back in a later movie. Its movies like this, that started the 'resurrection of Jesus' concept of bringing dead characters back to live. A good example is Ellen Ripley who dies in Alien 3 only to be given an awful new spin in Alien Resurrection. It's like Nimoy woke up and realize how much money he can make, if he brings back a beloved character back to life. At less, this character got a good story on how he came back, so I can't complain too loudly. Still, it makes you wonders if Genesis was aging faster and faster; how come Kirk's friend didn't aged out as well. Wouldn't he die again by old age? Also how comes, nobody else aged on the planet if Genesis does that to life forms? Wouldn't they also grow older as long as they stay on the planet? The science is baffling. Also what's baffling is how Kristie Alley regenerated to Robin Curtis. It's seem like Alley didn't want to return, so the character was rewritten as a new character as Savvik. I find the Pon-Farr scene, stupid as hell. And where was David Marcus's mother, Carol? It would've been interesting to have her in Saavik's place down on Genesis and it would make more sense. The movie's over all is that it's works to a level, but compare to others. It's not that awesome. Still, it's worth the watch, so check it out. So start trekking.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Needs of the many do indeed outweigh the needs of the few with this film!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    illbebackreviews
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    As a countdown to 'Star Trek: Into Darkness', I decided to watch every single Star Trek movie for the first time. After the brilliant second film, I was excited to watch this one despite not being sure of what to expect. I had heard a lot of criticism about this movie calling it a cheap business trick. 'Star Trek III: The Search for Spock' basically follows the story of Admiral Kirk who has a tough time getting over the loss of his Vulcan friend, Spock. When Bones begins to act strangely, acting as if he is Spock, Kirk begins to realize, with the help of Spock's father, that maybe Spock can be brought back to life if his body and his mind (in this case Bones) are re-united and a spell cast to re-join the two however Klingon Commander, Kruge, played by Christopher Llyod turns out to be the only obstacle as he is in pursuit for the secrets to Genesis. There were quite a few things I really liked about this movie. Much like Star Trek II, I really liked the villain here played brilliantly by Christopher Llyod, who honestly feels the scene stealer in this film. I do love much of the story and I do not believe that this feels like a cash grab, unlike movies such as the Star Wars prequels which were made entirely for merchandising rights and not for story. The story was handled well and it wasn't anything like Spock never died but much more deep. Also the adventure that this movie has is great and I loved all the movie until the last half hour where much of the film becomes rather silly and could easily have been cut down or it could've been directed much better than it was. **SPOILERS AHEAD*** Of course, I am referring to when Kirk attempts to lure Kruge back to the now destructing Genesis and the two fight. Obviously, this fight looks terrible. I am not after any choreographed fight sequence that goes on neither is the fight the big mistake here. It is how this fight ends and Kruge is killed in an extremely silly and childish manner, with Kirk remarking "I have had enough of you!" This is literally the end of the majority of the story until the film truly needs to wrap up. **END OF SPOILERS** Now the film does need a good 20 minutes to truly wrap up and it does get slow and the greatness of the most of the rest of the film truly drops for me here. I am sick of people bashing the multiple endings to 'The Lord of the Rings: The Return of the King' stating that the endings were too many and too long. In that case, people do not realize that the Lord of the Rings is ranked 'Massive' on a scale. It needs those endings to wrap up a 12 hour trilogy...This film doesn't need 20 minutes to wrap up. This ending could've been 10 minutes and would've been perfect or the last 10 minutes or so could've been cut and as a cliffhanger, be added into the beginning of the next Star Trek film and I'm guessing it would work, considering the movie ends with 'The adventure continues...' The special effects were truly sloppy in this movie and such moments like when the Enterprise is destroyed and Genesis is being destroyed certainly do look bad. The acting is mostly good by the crew and was quite a pity to see a re-cast for Saavik...I truly loved the one from Star Trek II and yet, despite this new one being good, the Saavik from Wrath of Khan was superior. In the end, I can say that 'Star Trek III: The Search for Spock' is a good movie and would be considerably better had that 20 minute ending to a 1 hr 45 minute movie not got in the way. That being said, this movie is still fun and has considerable entertainment and displays such adventurous quality to a fun Sci Fi movie and a rather good and worthy addition to Star Trek.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Good Search It Is
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Michael_Elliott
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Star Trek III: The Search for Spock (1984) *** (out of 4) After the events in the previous film, Kirk (William Shatner) risks his career by stealing the Enterprise to go to a restricted planet in hopes of finding Spock's body who they feel might be alive. Along the way they run into a Klingon leader (Christopher Lloyd) who wants to kill them all. STAR TREK III: THE SEARCH OF SPOCK probably shouldn't have worked since if you've seen the second film then you know what happens to Spock. In order for this "trick" to work the producers and writers really needed to come up with something good and thankfully they did that. I won't ruin what this trick is in "the search for Spock" but I thought it was a rather smart move and it helped make the film a lot more believable. Leonard Nimoy steps into the director's chair here and it's obvious he's very comfortable there as he delivers a good looking film with a good pace and of course the main people back in action. Once again we've got Shatner turning in a good performance as Spock and there's no question that he helps keep the film moving. I don't care what you want to say about the guy but there's no question that he owned this role and could play it in his sleep. Regulars like DeForrest Kelley, James Doohan and George Takei are also good in their roles. It seems a lot of people are split on Lloyd but I thought he was pretty good here. I liked seeing him under all the make-up and thought he did a good job even if the role itself wasn't the greatest. The special effects here are certainly a step up from the previous movie and I'd also say that battle sequences are much better directed. Overall this film doesn't quite reach the levels as the second but it's certainly a worthy sequel.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Spock returns.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bluesman-20
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Star Trek III was one of my favourite Trek movies. The Story gets as emotional and personal as it can be. The Enterprise returns to Spacedock battle scarred and looking her age The Events of the movie follow by rapidly. The planet caused by the Genesis explosion has become a scandal. It is a forbidden subject and off limits to everyone. Dr.McCoy is suffering from something and Spock's Father Sarek comes to Kirk demanding the return of Spock's body and his Katra. Kirk learns Spock placed his soul his spirit inside McCoy. And McCoy is slowly being driven insane, Not only that his life itself is in danger. Meanwhile Kirk's Son and Lt. Saavick go to the planet and Discover Spock is alive and growing older with the planet. The planet itself is dying and so is Spock. The Klingons discover the Geneisis project and want it for a super weapon. This leads to a dramatic climax in which Kirk and Crew Steal the Enterprise go to the planet and Fight the Klingons only to destroy the Enterprise in a effort to save Spock. It gets more personal as Kirk discovers the Klingon's have killed his son. Angered Kirk goes to war to save what is left of the things that matter to him. To me the key scene here is the death of the U.S.S Enterprise. Kirk's true love,He destroys it to save his best friends. That to me speaks of the love this band of brothers have for one another. Under rated for sure. But just as great as the others in the series.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The best yet...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Leofwine_draca
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I enjoyed STAR TREK III: THE SEARCH FOR SPOCK a lot better than the overrated previous instalment, which was way too derivative of the original TV show (with its 'villain of the week' format) and did absolutely nothing for me. Let's face it, such story lines have been done time and again, and it takes something special to make a film stand out from the rest. Thankfully, THE SEARCH FOR SPOCK has that something special to it. Leonard Nimoy steps in as director and does a confident, assured job; even better, the quest storyline is heartfelt, emotionally wrought, and unexpected. The crew are all on top form, giving it their all and staying true to their characters throughout, and the Klingons make great, theatrical enemies, particularly Christopher Lloyd's OTT head bad guy. At the end of the day, I watch these films as somebody with an interest in the sci-fi genre rather than as a Trekkie, and so far this has been my favourite. I look forward to checking out part four!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Figures They'd Save Spock
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    wfjohnston14
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Star Trek III: The Search for Spock is a good film that follows right after the second film. This film, directed by Leonard Nimoy, is a nice film to add to the Star Trek Franchise. The Enterprise crew risks their careers as they take the decommissioned Enterprise to search for Spock's body. They find that Spock's body is missing and go searching for it and find a Vulcan boy instead who looks like Spock. Also, they intercept a Klingon ship at the planet too that puts one of the members of the Enterprise in danger and losing their life. What happened to Spock? Will the Enterprise survive against the Klingon? And what will happen to Kirk? This film is a good film, it has problems, but it is a very good film that is very entertaining and brings back Spock. When Spock's body landed on the planet that was being powered by Genesis, his body regenerated and that's why they found him as a boy. The one problem though is that the planet is regenerating too fast and is soon falling apart and Spock too is aging rapidly. He then is himself, but with no memory, so when they take the Klingon ship back to Vulcan, he and McCoy mind meld and Spock is better. Spock gave McCoy his memory right before he died. The crew member that dies is Kirk's son and he gets very emotional and later to save the crew, destroys the ship and they escape using the Klingon ship. This film is a nice addition and puts things back to where they used to be, everyone alright and ready to go on new adventures. A job well done Nimoy. Me: B
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not quite stronger, but a lot better than the original
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gavin-thelordofthefu-48-460297
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    While Star Trek III may not be as strong or as epic as the Wrath of Khan, it is however a lot better than the original in some ways. The story is fine aside from a few over-the-top moments and mediocre dialog; the script is decent it helped explain the Enterprise group's attempt to find Spock, who died in the end of Star Trek II and the pacing moves along very nicely. The scenery is great and the visuals are terrific. The acting is still solid and aside from William Shatner and Leonard Nimoy, Christopher Lloyd is so enjoyable as Kruge. The music score from James Horner is rousing and the action sequences are thrilling. Overall, not strong, but an enjoyable entry to the franchise even though I'm not a Trekkie.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Standing Proof That Odd Numbered Treks Aren't Always Bad
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Jacob Jefferson (jjgooner@yahoo.co.uk)
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Star Trek III: The Search for Spock *** (out of 4) 102 mins/ PG Cast: William Shatner, Leonard Nimoy, DeForest Kelley, James Doohan, George Takei, Robin Curts, Merritt Butrick, Christopher Lloyd Director: Leonard Nimoy Plot: Admiral Kirk is forced to steal the Enterprise ship and return to planet Genesis to find Spock's lifeless body. JJ's Verdict: Anyone who says all odd numbered Star Trek films are bad is totally wrong. In fact I even prefer The Search for Spock to the superior (so the majority says) Wrath of Khan. Following on from its predecessor, the film constantly references to events from it. While doing this it uses great footage and piles on Kirk's emotional baggage from Spock's 'death' scene. I put death in commas because as the film suggests and his actor's name in the cast list, Spock isn't actually dead. He mind-melted with Kelley's Dr. McCoy and left his body on Genesis. This film follows Kirk and his crew in their recovery of the body and their fight to stop the evil Klingons form inhabiting the planet. This revelation that Spock isn't dead, although fine as a plot element, sort of takes away the effect the final scene of Wrath of Khan has on you. The Search for Spock actually has a much clearer plot than the previous films and although it might be a tiny bit predictable at times, at least it is easier to follow than past Star Trek ventures. The way the film weaves between three groups of people (Kirk and his crew, The Klingons and Saavik and David) keeps the film very interesting and engaging throughout and almost makes it feel like an ensemble piece. The film has both improved special effects and space battles and the acting is very good throughout. William Shatner leads the front-line once again and also tops his performance from Star Trek II. And Christopher Lloyd's Klingon, despite not looking very convincing, plays it pretty scary. The scene in which Kirk and the crew steal The Enterprise is highly amusing and is great tongue-in-cheek humour. Leonard Nimoy, although consistently good as Spock, really finds his speciality in directing. His direction of all the actors really makes you care about their characters and he achieves something that, yet again, the previous two films couldn't do; he kept the audience interested. The film ends on a fitting high note and makes you feel very satisfied. And although Kirk seems to think so, I haven't had enough of this film and wish every Trek could be like this.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Decent Star Trek Movie,But Dosen't Live Up To Wrath Of Khan,
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Dillon Harris
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Star Trek 3: The Search For Spock is a pretty good movie with a decent storyline but a very strong cast.It's definitely not the worst in the Star Trek film series,but it's not the best either.It doesn't live up to it's predecessor,Star Trek 2: The Wrath Of Khan,but it's still a lot better than Star Trek: The Motion Picture.The Search For Spock still has a lot of great action sequences and although it's missing Leonard Nimoy for most of the movie,it's still delivers very strong performances from the other cast members,William Shatner is as good as ever in this movie as Cpatain James T. Kirk.While I feel huge Star Trek fans will be disappointed with the Search For Spockk,they will still get a good kick out of him and wont be entirely unimpressed. Captain Kirk (William Shatner) heads off with his crew on the Enterprise to the Genesis planet to save Spock (Leonard Nimoy,who also directs),who may still be alive.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "Turn death into a fighting chance to live."
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Al_The_Strange
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    With the rip-roaring success of The Wrath of Khan, the studios greenlit the third classic Trek film with Spock himself as the director. The problem is, with the way the last film ended, Spock couldn't be in the actual film. It was only natural that the next step in the series was to bring Spock back; hence, the search. The Search for Spock starts off a bit brooding, but quickly taps into the right adventurous spirit as the Enterprise crew becomes renegades and gives the Federation a hilarious slip. From then on, with bad run-ins with Klingons, the stakes are raised very high, and the struggle becomes quite epic. A few scenes stand out as being fairly epic and jaw-dropping. It is an entertaining thrill ride overall. My only beef with the film is that it still feels very small-scale. A lot of it might be because pitting the Enterprise crew against one small greedy band of Klingon rogues, led by a rather flat one-dimensional villain, just doesn't compare to everything we've already seen in The Wrath of Khan. Let's face it, Khan was too good of a villain, and nothing Captain Kruge does can outstage that. Not even the constant raising of the stakes, and confrontations with death, are able to elevate the film above and beyond the limited confines of its own plot. Despite those quibbles, the film still does the best it can to one-up most things, and still deliver the best story it can. The classic Trek crew remains a fun, endearing, and well-rounded group of characters, and their adventure follows a solid plot structure. Themes of rebirth, initially introduced in the last film, are reinforced here. This film boasts solid, steady photography and editing. Acting is not bad: William Shatner, Leonard Nimoy, DeForest Kelley, and the other classic Trek cast members reprise their roles with good nuance, and with a little more tongue-in-cheek attitude. Christopher Lloyd plays the villain quite memorably, even if the character is a two-bit scumbag. This production has some really good-looking sets, props, costumes, and special effects. The music score has more of the same from the last film, and that's not bad. On its own, this film is fun and satisfying, but understanding its story may rely pretty heavily on seeing The Wrath of Khan first. As such, it's best recommended as an immediate follow-up. 4/5 (Entertainment: Very Good | Story: Pretty Good | Film: Very Good)
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I'm still searching for answers
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ironhorse_iv
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie didn't answer much. Search for Spock has some aspect of the Star Trek theme, but it is very poorly handled. Still, not bad for Leonard Nimoy's first directed film. This one isn't as bad as the other odd numbered installments, especially if you factor in the fact that it ties what happen in the events of the previous Star Trek movie 'Wrath of Khan' so well. If you are a first time viewer of this movie, I wouldn't watch this movie until you watch Wrath of Khan first. It's very important to watch that movie before this. Yes, Star Trek III: The Search for Spock came after that movie, and being after such a masterpiece, people going to look at it being worst compare to that film. No, Star Trek film can live up to that film. Still the movie has some OK action scenes and interesting story. The movie starts out with recaps of the last few minutes of Wrath of Khan and then the movie officially begins. A spy has deliver some information about the Genesis program that Klingon commander Kruge (Christopher Lloyd) needs to hear. It seems like Genesis does, what Nintendo don't. What I meant by that is that Genesis has create life on a planet. The Klingons see this as a weapon to have. The Klingons were always Russian allegory in these films. So hearing this, must have been the same feeling when the Soviets heard about the Atom Bomb. Still, I cannot get over the fact that Christopher Lloyd is playing a Klingon, here. I was expecting him to shout "Great Scott!" or something. His character is quite stupid and silly at times. Just watch the killer plant scene, you can't help laughing at him. He's just not that menacing enough and not epic to the likes of Khan. Well, the Klingons are not the only ones hearing voices, but Dr. McCoy (De Forest Kelly) is talking all crazy about a certain Vulcan name Spock and that Captain Kirk (William Shatner) and the crew should go to Genesis to search for him. Now it's a quest between the crew of the Enterprise to rescue Spock before the Klingons get a hold of the planet. This movie suffers from the typical middle child syndrome of being a 2nd movie in a trilogy's story arc. Star Trek III: The Search For Spock is the second chapter of what is called by some fans "the Star Trek Trilogy", yes it is the third film of the series, but it's the second act in what is indeed a three parter. The first act is in Wrath of Khan, concerning its events leading up to somebody's death. The second act is in Search for Spock where somebody soul and body have to be re united and the third is in Voyage Home where somebody fully regains himself. My biggest problem with Start Trek 3 is that I feel it takes away from the impact of 2. The whole idea of life and death at the end of the 2nd one regarding a death of a character and the birth of a new planet is breath taking. Then this movie has Genesis's kind of break that apart! Breaking apart is a theme here. This film shows that Kirk ends up losing so much more than a friend. He sacrifices his ship, loses a family member and hope. The scene where Kirk is forced to relive his friend's death when he does the mind meld is a wonderful scene. The problem is when you look at how strong, 2 is with its story and themes and how this one causes those scenes to be all for nothing. It's disappointing. I think the worst idea is bringing back a character back after such a heroic death. The needs of the many outweigh the needs of the few. Captain Kirk's friend is noted to say for the reasons and justifying about his sacrifice. I believe that if you kill a character, then that character should stays dead. It does no favors for somebody to kill a character, only to bring them back in a later movie. Its movies like this, that started the 'resurrection of Jesus' concept of bringing dead characters back to live. A good example is Ellen Ripley who dies in Alien 3 only to be given an awful new spin in Alien Resurrection. It's like Nimoy woke up and realize how much money he can make, if he brings back a beloved character back to life. At less, this character got a good story on how he came back, so I can't complain too loudly. Still, it makes you wonders if Genesis was aging faster and faster; how come Kirk's friend didn't aged out as well. Wouldn't he die again by old age? Also how comes, nobody else aged on the planet if Genesis does that to life forms? Wouldn't they also grow older as long as they stay on the planet? The science is baffling. Also what's baffling is how Kristie Alley regenerated to Robin Curtis. It's seem like Alley didn't want to return, so the character was rewritten as a new character as Savvik. I find the Pon-Farr scene, stupid as hell. And where was David Marcus's mother, Carol? It would've been interesting to have her in Saavik's place down on Genesis and it would make more sense. The movie's over all is that it's works to a level, but compare to others. It's not that awesome. Still, it's worth the watch, so check it out. So start trekking.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Needs of the many do indeed outweigh the needs of the few with this film!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    illbebackreviews
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    As a countdown to 'Star Trek: Into Darkness', I decided to watch every single Star Trek movie for the first time. After the brilliant second film, I was excited to watch this one despite not being sure of what to expect. I had heard a lot of criticism about this movie calling it a cheap business trick. 'Star Trek III: The Search for Spock' basically follows the story of Admiral Kirk who has a tough time getting over the loss of his Vulcan friend, Spock. When Bones begins to act strangely, acting as if he is Spock, Kirk begins to realize, with the help of Spock's father, that maybe Spock can be brought back to life if his body and his mind (in this case Bones) are re-united and a spell cast to re-join the two however Klingon Commander, Kruge, played by Christopher Llyod turns out to be the only obstacle as he is in pursuit for the secrets to Genesis. There were quite a few things I really liked about this movie. Much like Star Trek II, I really liked the villain here played brilliantly by Christopher Llyod, who honestly feels the scene stealer in this film. I do love much of the story and I do not believe that this feels like a cash grab, unlike movies such as the Star Wars prequels which were made entirely for merchandising rights and not for story. The story was handled well and it wasn't anything like Spock never died but much more deep. Also the adventure that this movie has is great and I loved all the movie until the last half hour where much of the film becomes rather silly and could easily have been cut down or it could've been directed much better than it was. **SPOILERS AHEAD*** Of course, I am referring to when Kirk attempts to lure Kruge back to the now destructing Genesis and the two fight. Obviously, this fight looks terrible. I am not after any choreographed fight sequence that goes on neither is the fight the big mistake here. It is how this fight ends and Kruge is killed in an extremely silly and childish manner, with Kirk remarking "I have had enough of you!" This is literally the end of the majority of the story until the film truly needs to wrap up. **END OF SPOILERS** Now the film does need a good 20 minutes to truly wrap up and it does get slow and the greatness of the most of the rest of the film truly drops for me here. I am sick of people bashing the multiple endings to 'The Lord of the Rings: The Return of the King' stating that the endings were too many and too long. In that case, people do not realize that the Lord of the Rings is ranked 'Massive' on a scale. It needs those endings to wrap up a 12 hour trilogy...This film doesn't need 20 minutes to wrap up. This ending could've been 10 minutes and would've been perfect or the last 10 minutes or so could've been cut and as a cliffhanger, be added into the beginning of the next Star Trek film and I'm guessing it would work, considering the movie ends with 'The adventure continues...' The special effects were truly sloppy in this movie and such moments like when the Enterprise is destroyed and Genesis is being destroyed certainly do look bad. The acting is mostly good by the crew and was quite a pity to see a re-cast for Saavik...I truly loved the one from Star Trek II and yet, despite this new one being good, the Saavik from Wrath of Khan was superior. In the end, I can say that 'Star Trek III: The Search for Spock' is a good movie and would be considerably better had that 20 minute ending to a 1 hr 45 minute movie not got in the way. That being said, this movie is still fun and has considerable entertainment and displays such adventurous quality to a fun Sci Fi movie and a rather good and worthy addition to Star Trek.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Good Search It Is
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Michael_Elliott
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Star Trek III: The Search for Spock (1984) *** (out of 4) After the events in the previous film, Kirk (William Shatner) risks his career by stealing the Enterprise to go to a restricted planet in hopes of finding Spock's body who they feel might be alive. Along the way they run into a Klingon leader (Christopher Lloyd) who wants to kill them all. STAR TREK III: THE SEARCH OF SPOCK probably shouldn't have worked since if you've seen the second film then you know what happens to Spock. In order for this "trick" to work the producers and writers really needed to come up with something good and thankfully they did that. I won't ruin what this trick is in "the search for Spock" but I thought it was a rather smart move and it helped make the film a lot more believable. Leonard Nimoy steps into the director's chair here and it's obvious he's very comfortable there as he delivers a good looking film with a good pace and of course the main people back in action. Once again we've got Shatner turning in a good performance as Spock and there's no question that he helps keep the film moving. I don't care what you want to say about the guy but there's no question that he owned this role and could play it in his sleep. Regulars like DeForrest Kelley, James Doohan and George Takei are also good in their roles. It seems a lot of people are split on Lloyd but I thought he was pretty good here. I liked seeing him under all the make-up and thought he did a good job even if the role itself wasn't the greatest. The special effects here are certainly a step up from the previous movie and I'd also say that battle sequences are much better directed. Overall this film doesn't quite reach the levels as the second but it's certainly a worthy sequel.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Spock returns.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bluesman-20
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Star Trek III was one of my favourite Trek movies. The Story gets as emotional and personal as it can be. The Enterprise returns to Spacedock battle scarred and looking her age The Events of the movie follow by rapidly. The planet caused by the Genesis explosion has become a scandal. It is a forbidden subject and off limits to everyone. Dr.McCoy is suffering from something and Spock's Father Sarek comes to Kirk demanding the return of Spock's body and his Katra. Kirk learns Spock placed his soul his spirit inside McCoy. And McCoy is slowly being driven insane, Not only that his life itself is in danger. Meanwhile Kirk's Son and Lt. Saavick go to the planet and Discover Spock is alive and growing older with the planet. The planet itself is dying and so is Spock. The Klingons discover the Geneisis project and want it for a super weapon. This leads to a dramatic climax in which Kirk and Crew Steal the Enterprise go to the planet and Fight the Klingons only to destroy the Enterprise in a effort to save Spock. It gets more personal as Kirk discovers the Klingon's have killed his son. Angered Kirk goes to war to save what is left of the things that matter to him. To me the key scene here is the death of the U.S.S Enterprise. Kirk's true love,He destroys it to save his best friends. That to me speaks of the love this band of brothers have for one another. Under rated for sure. But just as great as the others in the series.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The best yet...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Leofwine_draca
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I enjoyed STAR TREK III: THE SEARCH FOR SPOCK a lot better than the overrated previous instalment, which was way too derivative of the original TV show (with its 'villain of the week' format) and did absolutely nothing for me. Let's face it, such story lines have been done time and again, and it takes something special to make a film stand out from the rest. Thankfully, THE SEARCH FOR SPOCK has that something special to it. Leonard Nimoy steps in as director and does a confident, assured job; even better, the quest storyline is heartfelt, emotionally wrought, and unexpected. The crew are all on top form, giving it their all and staying true to their characters throughout, and the Klingons make great, theatrical enemies, particularly Christopher Lloyd's OTT head bad guy. At the end of the day, I watch these films as somebody with an interest in the sci-fi genre rather than as a Trekkie, and so far this has been my favourite. I look forward to checking out part four!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Figures They'd Save Spock
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    wfjohnston14
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Star Trek III: The Search for Spock is a good film that follows right after the second film. This film, directed by Leonard Nimoy, is a nice film to add to the Star Trek Franchise. The Enterprise crew risks their careers as they take the decommissioned Enterprise to search for Spock's body. They find that Spock's body is missing and go searching for it and find a Vulcan boy instead who looks like Spock. Also, they intercept a Klingon ship at the planet too that puts one of the members of the Enterprise in danger and losing their life. What happened to Spock? Will the Enterprise survive against the Klingon? And what will happen to Kirk? This film is a good film, it has problems, but it is a very good film that is very entertaining and brings back Spock. When Spock's body landed on the planet that was being powered by Genesis, his body regenerated and that's why they found him as a boy. The one problem though is that the planet is regenerating too fast and is soon falling apart and Spock too is aging rapidly. He then is himself, but with no memory, so when they take the Klingon ship back to Vulcan, he and McCoy mind meld and Spock is better. Spock gave McCoy his memory right before he died. The crew member that dies is Kirk's son and he gets very emotional and later to save the crew, destroys the ship and they escape using the Klingon ship. This film is a nice addition and puts things back to where they used to be, everyone alright and ready to go on new adventures. A job well done Nimoy. Me: B
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not quite stronger, but a lot better than the original
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gavin-thelordofthefu-48-460297
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    While Star Trek III may not be as strong or as epic as the Wrath of Khan, it is however a lot better than the original in some ways. The story is fine aside from a few over-the-top moments and mediocre dialog; the script is decent it helped explain the Enterprise group's attempt to find Spock, who died in the end of Star Trek II and the pacing moves along very nicely. The scenery is great and the visuals are terrific. The acting is still solid and aside from William Shatner and Leonard Nimoy, Christopher Lloyd is so enjoyable as Kruge. The music score from James Horner is rousing and the action sequences are thrilling. Overall, not strong, but an enjoyable entry to the franchise even though I'm not a Trekkie.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Standing Proof That Odd Numbered Treks Aren't Always Bad
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Jacob Jefferson (jjgooner@yahoo.co.uk)
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Star Trek III: The Search for Spock *** (out of 4) 102 mins/ PG Cast: William Shatner, Leonard Nimoy, DeForest Kelley, James Doohan, George Takei, Robin Curts, Merritt Butrick, Christopher Lloyd Director: Leonard Nimoy Plot: Admiral Kirk is forced to steal the Enterprise ship and return to planet Genesis to find Spock's lifeless body. JJ's Verdict: Anyone who says all odd numbered Star Trek films are bad is totally wrong. In fact I even prefer The Search for Spock to the superior (so the majority says) Wrath of Khan. Following on from its predecessor, the film constantly references to events from it. While doing this it uses great footage and piles on Kirk's emotional baggage from Spock's 'death' scene. I put death in commas because as the film suggests and his actor's name in the cast list, Spock isn't actually dead. He mind-melted with Kelley's Dr. McCoy and left his body on Genesis. This film follows Kirk and his crew in their recovery of the body and their fight to stop the evil Klingons form inhabiting the planet. This revelation that Spock isn't dead, although fine as a plot element, sort of takes away the effect the final scene of Wrath of Khan has on you. The Search for Spock actually has a much clearer plot than the previous films and although it might be a tiny bit predictable at times, at least it is easier to follow than past Star Trek ventures. The way the film weaves between three groups of people (Kirk and his crew, The Klingons and Saavik and David) keeps the film very interesting and engaging throughout and almost makes it feel like an ensemble piece. The film has both improved special effects and space battles and the acting is very good throughout. William Shatner leads the front-line once again and also tops his performance from Star Trek II. And Christopher Lloyd's Klingon, despite not looking very convincing, plays it pretty scary. The scene in which Kirk and the crew steal The Enterprise is highly amusing and is great tongue-in-cheek humour. Leonard Nimoy, although consistently good as Spock, really finds his speciality in directing. His direction of all the actors really makes you care about their characters and he achieves something that, yet again, the previous two films couldn't do; he kept the audience interested. The film ends on a fitting high note and makes you feel very satisfied. And although Kirk seems to think so, I haven't had enough of this film and wish every Trek could be like this.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Decent Star Trek Movie,But Dosen't Live Up To Wrath Of Khan,
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Dillon Harris
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Star Trek 3: The Search For Spock is a pretty good movie with a decent storyline but a very strong cast.It's definitely not the worst in the Star Trek film series,but it's not the best either.It doesn't live up to it's predecessor,Star Trek 2: The Wrath Of Khan,but it's still a lot better than Star Trek: The Motion Picture.The Search For Spock still has a lot of great action sequences and although it's missing Leonard Nimoy for most of the movie,it's still delivers very strong performances from the other cast members,William Shatner is as good as ever in this movie as Cpatain James T. Kirk.While I feel huge Star Trek fans will be disappointed with the Search For Spockk,they will still get a good kick out of him and wont be entirely unimpressed. Captain Kirk (William Shatner) heads off with his crew on the Enterprise to the Genesis planet to save Spock (Leonard Nimoy,who also directs),who may still be alive.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "Turn death into a fighting chance to live."
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Al_The_Strange
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    With the rip-roaring success of The Wrath of Khan, the studios greenlit the third classic Trek film with Spock himself as the director. The problem is, with the way the last film ended, Spock couldn't be in the actual film. It was only natural that the next step in the series was to bring Spock back; hence, the search. The Search for Spock starts off a bit brooding, but quickly taps into the right adventurous spirit as the Enterprise crew becomes renegades and gives the Federation a hilarious slip. From then on, with bad run-ins with Klingons, the stakes are raised very high, and the struggle becomes quite epic. A few scenes stand out as being fairly epic and jaw-dropping. It is an entertaining thrill ride overall. My only beef with the film is that it still feels very small-scale. A lot of it might be because pitting the Enterprise crew against one small greedy band of Klingon rogues, led by a rather flat one-dimensional villain, just doesn't compare to everything we've already seen in The Wrath of Khan. Let's face it, Khan was too good of a villain, and nothing Captain Kruge does can outstage that. Not even the constant raising of the stakes, and confrontations with death, are able to elevate the film above and beyond the limited confines of its own plot. Despite those quibbles, the film still does the best it can to one-up most things, and still deliver the best story it can. The classic Trek crew remains a fun, endearing, and well-rounded group of characters, and their adventure follows a solid plot structure. Themes of rebirth, initially introduced in the last film, are reinforced here. This film boasts solid, steady photography and editing. Acting is not bad: William Shatner, Leonard Nimoy, DeForest Kelley, and the other classic Trek cast members reprise their roles with good nuance, and with a little more tongue-in-cheek attitude. Christopher Lloyd plays the villain quite memorably, even if the character is a two-bit scumbag. This production has some really good-looking sets, props, costumes, and special effects. The music score has more of the same from the last film, and that's not bad. On its own, this film is fun and satisfying, but understanding its story may rely pretty heavily on seeing The Wrath of Khan first. As such, it's best recommended as an immediate follow-up. 4/5 (Entertainment: Very Good | Story: Pretty Good | Film: Very Good)
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I'm still searching for answers
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ironhorse_iv
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie didn't answer much. Search for Spock has some aspect of the Star Trek theme, but it is very poorly handled. Still, not bad for Leonard Nimoy's first directed film. This one isn't as bad as the other odd numbered installments, especially if you factor in the fact that it ties what happen in the events of the previous Star Trek movie 'Wrath of Khan' so well. If you are a first time viewer of this movie, I wouldn't watch this movie until you watch Wrath of Khan first. It's very important to watch that movie before this. Yes, Star Trek III: The Search for Spock came after that movie, and being after such a masterpiece, people going to look at it being worst compare to that film. No, Star Trek film can live up to that film. Still the movie has some OK action scenes and interesting story. The movie starts out with recaps of the last few minutes of Wrath of Khan and then the movie officially begins. A spy has deliver some information about the Genesis program that Klingon commander Kruge (Christopher Lloyd) needs to hear. It seems like Genesis does, what Nintendo don't. What I meant by that is that Genesis has create life on a planet. The Klingons see this as a weapon to have. The Klingons were always Russian allegory in these films. So hearing this, must have been the same feeling when the Soviets heard about the Atom Bomb. Still, I cannot get over the fact that Christopher Lloyd is playing a Klingon, here. I was expecting him to shout "Great Scott!" or something. His character is quite stupid and silly at times. Just watch the killer plant scene, you can't help laughing at him. He's just not that menacing enough and not epic to the likes of Khan. Well, the Klingons are not the only ones hearing voices, but Dr. McCoy (De Forest Kelly) is talking all crazy about a certain Vulcan name Spock and that Captain Kirk (William Shatner) and the crew should go to Genesis to search for him. Now it's a quest between the crew of the Enterprise to rescue Spock before the Klingons get a hold of the planet. This movie suffers from the typical middle child syndrome of being a 2nd movie in a trilogy's story arc. Star Trek III: The Search For Spock is the second chapter of what is called by some fans "the Star Trek Trilogy", yes it is the third film of the series, but it's the second act in what is indeed a three parter. The first act is in Wrath of Khan, concerning its events leading up to somebody's death. The second act is in Search for Spock where somebody soul and body have to be re united and the third is in Voyage Home where somebody fully regains himself. My biggest problem with Start Trek 3 is that I feel it takes away from the impact of 2. The whole idea of life and death at the end of the 2nd one regarding a death of a character and the birth of a new planet is breath taking. Then this movie has Genesis's kind of break that apart! Breaking apart is a theme here. This film shows that Kirk ends up losing so much more than a friend. He sacrifices his ship, loses a family member and hope. The scene where Kirk is forced to relive his friend's death when he does the mind meld is a wonderful scene. The problem is when you look at how strong, 2 is with its story and themes and how this one causes those scenes to be all for nothing. It's disappointing. I think the worst idea is bringing back a character back after such a heroic death. The needs of the many outweigh the needs of the few. Captain Kirk's friend is noted to say for the reasons and justifying about his sacrifice. I believe that if you kill a character, then that character should stays dead. It does no favors for somebody to kill a character, only to bring them back in a later movie. Its movies like this, that started the 'resurrection of Jesus' concept of bringing dead characters back to live. A good example is Ellen Ripley who dies in Alien 3 only to be given an awful new spin in Alien Resurrection. It's like Nimoy woke up and realize how much money he can make, if he brings back a beloved character back to life. At less, this character got a good story on how he came back, so I can't complain too loudly. Still, it makes you wonders if Genesis was aging faster and faster; how come Kirk's friend didn't aged out as well. Wouldn't he die again by old age? Also how comes, nobody else aged on the planet if Genesis does that to life forms? Wouldn't they also grow older as long as they stay on the planet? The science is baffling. Also what's baffling is how Kristie Alley regenerated to Robin Curtis. It's seem like Alley didn't want to return, so the character was rewritten as a new character as Savvik. I find the Pon-Farr scene, stupid as hell. And where was David Marcus's mother, Carol? It would've been interesting to have her in Saavik's place down on Genesis and it would make more sense. The movie's over all is that it's works to a level, but compare to others. It's not that awesome. Still, it's worth the watch, so check it out. So start trekking.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Needs of the many do indeed outweigh the needs of the few with this film!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    illbebackreviews
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    As a countdown to 'Star Trek: Into Darkness', I decided to watch every single Star Trek movie for the first time. After the brilliant second film, I was excited to watch this one despite not being sure of what to expect. I had heard a lot of criticism about this movie calling it a cheap business trick. 'Star Trek III: The Search for Spock' basically follows the story of Admiral Kirk who has a tough time getting over the loss of his Vulcan friend, Spock. When Bones begins to act strangely, acting as if he is Spock, Kirk begins to realize, with the help of Spock's father, that maybe Spock can be brought back to life if his body and his mind (in this case Bones) are re-united and a spell cast to re-join the two however Klingon Commander, Kruge, played by Christopher Llyod turns out to be the only obstacle as he is in pursuit for the secrets to Genesis. There were quite a few things I really liked about this movie. Much like Star Trek II, I really liked the villain here played brilliantly by Christopher Llyod, who honestly feels the scene stealer in this film. I do love much of the story and I do not believe that this feels like a cash grab, unlike movies such as the Star Wars prequels which were made entirely for merchandising rights and not for story. The story was handled well and it wasn't anything like Spock never died but much more deep. Also the adventure that this movie has is great and I loved all the movie until the last half hour where much of the film becomes rather silly and could easily have been cut down or it could've been directed much better than it was. **SPOILERS AHEAD*** Of course, I am referring to when Kirk attempts to lure Kruge back to the now destructing Genesis and the two fight. Obviously, this fight looks terrible. I am not after any choreographed fight sequence that goes on neither is the fight the big mistake here. It is how this fight ends and Kruge is killed in an extremely silly and childish manner, with Kirk remarking "I have had enough of you!" This is literally the end of the majority of the story until the film truly needs to wrap up. **END OF SPOILERS** Now the film does need a good 20 minutes to truly wrap up and it does get slow and the greatness of the most of the rest of the film truly drops for me here. I am sick of people bashing the multiple endings to 'The Lord of the Rings: The Return of the King' stating that the endings were too many and too long. In that case, people do not realize that the Lord of the Rings is ranked 'Massive' on a scale. It needs those endings to wrap up a 12 hour trilogy...This film doesn't need 20 minutes to wrap up. This ending could've been 10 minutes and would've been perfect or the last 10 minutes or so could've been cut and as a cliffhanger, be added into the beginning of the next Star Trek film and I'm guessing it would work, considering the movie ends with 'The adventure continues...' The special effects were truly sloppy in this movie and such moments like when the Enterprise is destroyed and Genesis is being destroyed certainly do look bad. The acting is mostly good by the crew and was quite a pity to see a re-cast for Saavik...I truly loved the one from Star Trek II and yet, despite this new one being good, the Saavik from Wrath of Khan was superior. In the end, I can say that 'Star Trek III: The Search for Spock' is a good movie and would be considerably better had that 20 minute ending to a 1 hr 45 minute movie not got in the way. That being said, this movie is still fun and has considerable entertainment and displays such adventurous quality to a fun Sci Fi movie and a rather good and worthy addition to Star Trek.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Good Search It Is
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Michael_Elliott
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Star Trek III: The Search for Spock (1984) *** (out of 4) After the events in the previous film, Kirk (William Shatner) risks his career by stealing the Enterprise to go to a restricted planet in hopes of finding Spock's body who they feel might be alive. Along the way they run into a Klingon leader (Christopher Lloyd) who wants to kill them all. STAR TREK III: THE SEARCH OF SPOCK probably shouldn't have worked since if you've seen the second film then you know what happens to Spock. In order for this "trick" to work the producers and writers really needed to come up with something good and thankfully they did that. I won't ruin what this trick is in "the search for Spock" but I thought it was a rather smart move and it helped make the film a lot more believable. Leonard Nimoy steps into the director's chair here and it's obvious he's very comfortable there as he delivers a good looking film with a good pace and of course the main people back in action. Once again we've got Shatner turning in a good performance as Spock and there's no question that he helps keep the film moving. I don't care what you want to say about the guy but there's no question that he owned this role and could play it in his sleep. Regulars like DeForrest Kelley, James Doohan and George Takei are also good in their roles. It seems a lot of people are split on Lloyd but I thought he was pretty good here. I liked seeing him under all the make-up and thought he did a good job even if the role itself wasn't the greatest. The special effects here are certainly a step up from the previous movie and I'd also say that battle sequences are much better directed. Overall this film doesn't quite reach the levels as the second but it's certainly a worthy sequel.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Spock returns.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bluesman-20
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Star Trek III was one of my favourite Trek movies. The Story gets as emotional and personal as it can be. The Enterprise returns to Spacedock battle scarred and looking her age The Events of the movie follow by rapidly. The planet caused by the Genesis explosion has become a scandal. It is a forbidden subject and off limits to everyone. Dr.McCoy is suffering from something and Spock's Father Sarek comes to Kirk demanding the return of Spock's body and his Katra. Kirk learns Spock placed his soul his spirit inside McCoy. And McCoy is slowly being driven insane, Not only that his life itself is in danger. Meanwhile Kirk's Son and Lt. Saavick go to the planet and Discover Spock is alive and growing older with the planet. The planet itself is dying and so is Spock. The Klingons discover the Geneisis project and want it for a super weapon. This leads to a dramatic climax in which Kirk and Crew Steal the Enterprise go to the planet and Fight the Klingons only to destroy the Enterprise in a effort to save Spock. It gets more personal as Kirk discovers the Klingon's have killed his son. Angered Kirk goes to war to save what is left of the things that matter to him. To me the key scene here is the death of the U.S.S Enterprise. Kirk's true love,He destroys it to save his best friends. That to me speaks of the love this band of brothers have for one another. Under rated for sure. But just as great as the others in the series.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The best yet...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Leofwine_draca
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I enjoyed STAR TREK III: THE SEARCH FOR SPOCK a lot better than the overrated previous instalment, which was way too derivative of the original TV show (with its 'villain of the week' format) and did absolutely nothing for me. Let's face it, such story lines have been done time and again, and it takes something special to make a film stand out from the rest. Thankfully, THE SEARCH FOR SPOCK has that something special to it. Leonard Nimoy steps in as director and does a confident, assured job; even better, the quest storyline is heartfelt, emotionally wrought, and unexpected. The crew are all on top form, giving it their all and staying true to their characters throughout, and the Klingons make great, theatrical enemies, particularly Christopher Lloyd's OTT head bad guy. At the end of the day, I watch these films as somebody with an interest in the sci-fi genre rather than as a Trekkie, and so far this has been my favourite. I look forward to checking out part four!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
 </reviews>
</filme>
