<filme>
 <id>
  230
 </id>
 <imdburl>
  http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0092007
 </imdburl>
 <ano>
  1986
 </ano>
 <titulo>
  Jornada nas Estrelas IV - A Volta para Casa
 </titulo>
 <rating>
  7.2
 </rating>
 <sinopse>
  To save Earth from an alien probe, Admiral Kirk and his fugitive crew go back in time to 20th century Earth to retrieve the only beings who can communicate with it, humpback whales.
 </sinopse>
 <storyline>
  James Kirk who after rescuing Mr. Spock and bringing him to Vulcan where he is fully restored, is now the most hated man in the universe, because he disobeyed his superiors and killed a Klingon crew and took their ship. After three months on Vulcan, Kirk decides to return to Earth to face the consequences of his actions along with his crew who aided him. Also accompanying them is Mr. Spock, who is still trying to understand his human side. What they don't know is that an alien probe approaches Earth and is emitting a signal that nullifies all power systems. And it is now vaporizing the planet's oceans covering the planet in a cloud that covers the earth cutting them off from the sun - the planet's main source of energy. The President of the Federation sends a transmission telling everyone about what is happening and to stay away from earth. Kirk upon hearing it, checks out the probe's transmission and Spock postulates that the alien is not hostile merely unaware that it's ...
 </storyline>
 <generos>
  <genero>
   Adventure
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Comedy
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Sci-Fi
  </genero>
 </generos>
 <keywords>
  <keyword>
   whale
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   probe
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   humpback whales
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   23rd century
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   klingon
  </keyword>
 </keywords>
 <diretores>
  <diretor>
   Leonard Nimoy
  </diretor>
 </diretores>
 <escritores>
  <escritor>
   Gene Roddenberry
  </escritor>
  <escritor>
   Leonard Nimoy
  </escritor>
 </escritores>
 <atores>
  <ator>
   William Shatner
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Leonard Nimoy
  </ator>
  <ator>
   DeForest Kelley
  </ator>
 </atores>
 <reviews>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Standard, but a bit better than Search for Spock
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gavin-thelordofthefu-48-460297
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    While the original had it's flaws, I thought it was a decent enough film, but the The Wrath of Khan was a much better film with a compelling story while The Search for Spock is pretty good aside from it's other-the-top moments. Star Trek IV: The Voyage Home isn't as excellent as the second, but it's marginally better than Search for Spock. The story isn't exactly perfect, but it was OK with it's fine moments and while most of the humor is nice, some of them are pretty feeble. Aside from those flaws, everything else holds up. The scenery is nice to look at especially New York City, the special effects are solid, the writing is clever, and the music score from Leonard Rosenman is rousing. The cast is still as charming as ever along with a nice appearance from Catherine Hicks (who would later play Andy's mother in Child's Play). William Shatner, Leonard Nimoy and others did a fine job with their performances. Overall, not solid, but a bit better than Search for Spock. That's all I have to say.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The best Star Trek movie yet
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Leofwine_draca
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    STAR TREK IV: THE VOYAGE HOME was, for me, the most entertaining of the Star Trek movies so far, purely because it feels like an episode of the original series blown up to movie length. The time travel plot is an ingenious excuse for Kirk and co to have some fish-out-of-water fun, and fun it certainly is! This is a notably lighter film than the previous instalments and there's plenty of workable comedy to see it through. The cast feel more relaxed than before and there's a holiday atmosphere to the whole thing. Shatner is even charming on occasion while Kelley and Nimoy make the most of their comic bonding. The film also has a more modern, less dated feel than the previous outings. It's worth noting that the new TV Show, STAR TREK: THE NEXT GENERATION, was starting around this time, which may have influenced things, so the special effects are better and there's more originality in the alien races who provide window dressing. Yes, the film has a political message to convey - it's all about saving the planet and protecting the whales - but it's done so in a matter-of-fact way that refuses to preach to the viewer. The focus, instead, is on having a good time, with the result that the audience does too.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The best one so far
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mutty-mcflea
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A big improvement on the previous three dullards, 'The Voyage Home' rounds off the story arc kicked off in 'The Wrath of Khan' and finally brings the series to life. Although it drags in places and suffers from a few (raise eyebrow) illogical ideas (wouldn't people walk right into the cloaked Klingon ship sitting in the middle of a park?), the movie is an engaging romp that ups the comedy element without getting silly. The breezy dialogue lets the regular cast have fun as their characters try to fit in 300 years into their past, and Leonard Nimoy's direction is far less static than in 'Star Trek III'. It's not the best instalment but it does point the franchise in the right direction.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    My favourite Star Trek big-screen adventure
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    IndustriousAngel
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    There's a special place in my heart for Enterprise-Travels-Back-In-Time stories, and "The Voyage Home" is up there with the best of them (like City on the Edge of Forever). The film makes ample use of fish-out-of-water gags, but never gets a mere parody. It's the funniest ST movie by far: Spock's ears and generally trying to blend in, Checkov checking out the nuclear-powered carrier, Scotty trying to communicate with a stone-age computer, Bones experiencing a 20th century hospital ... The film is far from perfect - plot holes abound, starting with the silly premise (the probe destroying earth by communication), and the environmental "message" is written in overlarge letters, but still a very entertaining and endearing film, endlessly rewatchable!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Strangely Watchable
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Jacob Jefferson (jjgooner@yahoo.co.uk)
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Star Trek IV: The Voyage Home *** (out of 4) 119 mins/ PG Cast: William Shatner, Leonard Nimoy, DeForest Kelley, James Doohan, George Takei, Walter Koenig, Nichelle Nichols, Catherine Hicks, Mark Lenard Director: Leonard Nimoy Plot: Admiral James Kirk and his crew are forced to travel back in time to 1986 to retrieve two hunchback whales that are the only beings that can communicate with an Alien Probe, which is on the brink of turning Earth extinct. JJ's Verdict: Star Trek IV: The Voyage Home is almost not a Star Trek movie. It has a completely different tone, setting and plot to its three predecessors. This is, in fact, a very good thing. Its originality and utter bizarreness are its defining qualities. The film opens well with use of footage from parts 2 and 3 and introduces newcomers to the plot very well. As Kirk and his crew are returning back to Earth, the planet becomes under attack from an Alien probe, which is searching for signs of whale call. However, whales have been extinct since the 21st century so Kirk is forced to time-travel back to the 1980's to find the species and take them back to the 23rd century. Here hilarity ensues as the crew tries to get used to eating pizza, swearing and 'dark age' medicine. Although at times this does feel very, very silly, it can be welcoming at times as most of the film is very, very funny. Leonard Nimoy shows once again he can direct well, but his character, Spock is sidelined to an emotionless bore. Shatner and his crew put in good performances once again and Catherine Hicks is very good as Kirk's love interest/ whale expert, Gillian. The film also ends very well with huge triumph and feel-goodness. Due to this really being a comedy it can be annoying that the film is full of clich&eacute;s and coincidences that usually annoy viewers, but this is a Star Trek for not only Star Trek fans but all movie fans.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Star Trek film even the non-Star Trek fans can enjoy
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bravesfan35
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Sure this film isn't like the 3 previous films but that's what makes it so interesting. Instead of spending the entire movie in space, we get to see Kirk and the crew on Earth back in the 1980's and watch them try to adjust to the way things were back then (example: Kirk had to sell his antique glasses that McCoy had bought him for his birthday in order to get money). The film also takes the step of adding a lot of comedy to it. From Spock experimenting with "colorful metaphors" to Scotty learning how to use a non-voice activated computer, the film is a treasure to watch. Also stars Catherine Hicks (from 7th Heaven) as the intelligent but stubborn Gillian Taylor. Wonder whatever happened with her character after she got assigned to a science vessel. We'll never know.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Plain and Simple,Not Something You'd Expect From Star Trek,
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Dillon Harris
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Star Trek 4: The Voyage Home is a very enjoyable movie with a simple storyline and,like there always is in Star Trek,a brilliant cast.It's certainly not the best Star Trek movie,and it's definitely the least exciting,there isn't an awful lot of spaceships and aliens in this movie,but it did feel like we got some time to really know these characters in a much less serious scenario.What I liked the best about this movie was that they fit a lot of comedy in it,Star Trek dosen't try to be funny a lot of the time,but this movie showed they do have a sense of humor.Fans of Star Trek won't be getting a big action-packed science fiction movie,but they will get a sweet and funny story,and you'll probably surprised with how much you enjoy it Kirk and his crew boldly go back in time in search of the only thing that can save Earth in the distant future,humpback whales.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Star Trek IV
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    wfjohnston14
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This was the funniest film as this one had good humor throughout the film. The crew now heads to the present day and that's the big thing that gives the film its humor, them in such a different environment as their clothes, behaviors, and weapons are strange to Earth. It was not the best idea for a film with its plot and story involving the whales, but it is carried by the wonderful script. The film is filled with memorable moments of Spock punching a guy or asking how to get a nuclear vessel which is insane. The films are still popular and hopefully will still be as good as it may be nearing its final voyage home.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "Admiral, we have found the nuclear wessel. And Admiral...it's the Enterprise!"
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Al_The_Strange
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    In Star Trek II, the Enterprise crew confronted Khan at a great expense. In Star Trek III, they confronted Klingons in a frantic bid to bring back Spock, at great expense. So naturally, in the fourth film of the classic Trek saga, with the Enterprise crew hanging around planet Vulcan in a captured Klingon Bird of Prey, they had to find their way back home. This film turns the voyage home into an adventure all on its own. The film starts off pretty straight-faced, immediately tossing the Federation and Earth into peril to prompt the Enterprise crew to deal with it. The crew's solution - to travel back and time and save the whales - proves to be utterly ridiculous, but the film plays with so much tongue-in-cheek humor that it becomes a comedy classic. There are a few visually impressive moments, as the Klingon Bird of Prey skirts along Earth's oceans, but most of the fun in this film is the lighthearted fish-out-of-water comedy. What could be more hilarious than watching 24th century space explorers slumming around 20th century San Francisco, struggling against a seemingly-primitive society to solve high-tech problems? Some of the funniest and most endearing jokes include seeing Chekov roaming with with his Russian accent, asking where the "nuclear wessels" are. It's always a blast to watch Spock trying to get the hang of cursing, and ultimately using his nerve pinch on an annoying punk. And one of my favorite scenes is Scotty visiting an industrial plant, trying to use a 20th century computer by speaking to it. The comedy makes the film entertaining throughout, but there's still enough problems and peril to make it roll evenly and effectively. It's a little derivative, but still a well-structured plot with quality characters. The film gets a little pushy with the whole "save the whales" theme, but it fits in the light and fluffy context of the overall picture. The film looks good, with solid photography and editing. Acting is still great from the classic Trek cast: William Shatner, Leonard Nimoy, DeForest Kelley, and the rest get even amounts of screen time to express their tongue-in-cheek humor with phenomenal results. Writing is quite witty. This production has some fine-looking sets, props, costumes, locales, and special effects. Music is really boisterous and happy-sounding, but strangely catchy. 4.5/5 (Entertainment: Very Good | Story: Good | Film: Very Good)
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Brilliantly Accessible & Entertaining
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Helio Copter
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/9/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is not the best Star Trek film. But it is the most fun, the most accessible to general audiences, and really much more than just a novelty or comedy. The plot is brilliant in multiple ways. The most obvious is the irresistible humor that arises naturally from the circumstances that the characters find themselves in. This is always the best type of humor, not forced or contrived. Of course, there is also a strong conservation/preservation message, which is inspiringly though-provoking (in the best tradition of Star Trek). Thirdly, this film wraps up the continuous story-arc begun in Stark Trek II & III, finding closure for the characters and answering some of the questions left by the previous installment. As far as other specific things, Catherine Hicks does a great job in her role as a biologist, and it is nice to see all of the crew members getting some genuine screen time of their own (i.e. not just Kirk/Spock/McCoy). The one particular problem is that there are a few moments when things get a little too lighthearted, to the point of being disposably unbelievable. But that can be forgiven, because on the whole, Star Trek IV manages to be a wonderfully engaging, universal film that a wide audience can appreciate, without sacrificing its soul in the process.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Standard, but a bit better than Search for Spock
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gavin-thelordofthefu-48-460297
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    While the original had it's flaws, I thought it was a decent enough film, but the The Wrath of Khan was a much better film with a compelling story while The Search for Spock is pretty good aside from it's other-the-top moments. Star Trek IV: The Voyage Home isn't as excellent as the second, but it's marginally better than Search for Spock. The story isn't exactly perfect, but it was OK with it's fine moments and while most of the humor is nice, some of them are pretty feeble. Aside from those flaws, everything else holds up. The scenery is nice to look at especially New York City, the special effects are solid, the writing is clever, and the music score from Leonard Rosenman is rousing. The cast is still as charming as ever along with a nice appearance from Catherine Hicks (who would later play Andy's mother in Child's Play). William Shatner, Leonard Nimoy and others did a fine job with their performances. Overall, not solid, but a bit better than Search for Spock. That's all I have to say.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The best Star Trek movie yet
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Leofwine_draca
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    STAR TREK IV: THE VOYAGE HOME was, for me, the most entertaining of the Star Trek movies so far, purely because it feels like an episode of the original series blown up to movie length. The time travel plot is an ingenious excuse for Kirk and co to have some fish-out-of-water fun, and fun it certainly is! This is a notably lighter film than the previous instalments and there's plenty of workable comedy to see it through. The cast feel more relaxed than before and there's a holiday atmosphere to the whole thing. Shatner is even charming on occasion while Kelley and Nimoy make the most of their comic bonding. The film also has a more modern, less dated feel than the previous outings. It's worth noting that the new TV Show, STAR TREK: THE NEXT GENERATION, was starting around this time, which may have influenced things, so the special effects are better and there's more originality in the alien races who provide window dressing. Yes, the film has a political message to convey - it's all about saving the planet and protecting the whales - but it's done so in a matter-of-fact way that refuses to preach to the viewer. The focus, instead, is on having a good time, with the result that the audience does too.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The best one so far
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mutty-mcflea
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A big improvement on the previous three dullards, 'The Voyage Home' rounds off the story arc kicked off in 'The Wrath of Khan' and finally brings the series to life. Although it drags in places and suffers from a few (raise eyebrow) illogical ideas (wouldn't people walk right into the cloaked Klingon ship sitting in the middle of a park?), the movie is an engaging romp that ups the comedy element without getting silly. The breezy dialogue lets the regular cast have fun as their characters try to fit in 300 years into their past, and Leonard Nimoy's direction is far less static than in 'Star Trek III'. It's not the best instalment but it does point the franchise in the right direction.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    My favourite Star Trek big-screen adventure
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    IndustriousAngel
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    There's a special place in my heart for Enterprise-Travels-Back-In-Time stories, and "The Voyage Home" is up there with the best of them (like City on the Edge of Forever). The film makes ample use of fish-out-of-water gags, but never gets a mere parody. It's the funniest ST movie by far: Spock's ears and generally trying to blend in, Checkov checking out the nuclear-powered carrier, Scotty trying to communicate with a stone-age computer, Bones experiencing a 20th century hospital ... The film is far from perfect - plot holes abound, starting with the silly premise (the probe destroying earth by communication), and the environmental "message" is written in overlarge letters, but still a very entertaining and endearing film, endlessly rewatchable!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Strangely Watchable
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Jacob Jefferson (jjgooner@yahoo.co.uk)
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Star Trek IV: The Voyage Home *** (out of 4) 119 mins/ PG Cast: William Shatner, Leonard Nimoy, DeForest Kelley, James Doohan, George Takei, Walter Koenig, Nichelle Nichols, Catherine Hicks, Mark Lenard Director: Leonard Nimoy Plot: Admiral James Kirk and his crew are forced to travel back in time to 1986 to retrieve two hunchback whales that are the only beings that can communicate with an Alien Probe, which is on the brink of turning Earth extinct. JJ's Verdict: Star Trek IV: The Voyage Home is almost not a Star Trek movie. It has a completely different tone, setting and plot to its three predecessors. This is, in fact, a very good thing. Its originality and utter bizarreness are its defining qualities. The film opens well with use of footage from parts 2 and 3 and introduces newcomers to the plot very well. As Kirk and his crew are returning back to Earth, the planet becomes under attack from an Alien probe, which is searching for signs of whale call. However, whales have been extinct since the 21st century so Kirk is forced to time-travel back to the 1980's to find the species and take them back to the 23rd century. Here hilarity ensues as the crew tries to get used to eating pizza, swearing and 'dark age' medicine. Although at times this does feel very, very silly, it can be welcoming at times as most of the film is very, very funny. Leonard Nimoy shows once again he can direct well, but his character, Spock is sidelined to an emotionless bore. Shatner and his crew put in good performances once again and Catherine Hicks is very good as Kirk's love interest/ whale expert, Gillian. The film also ends very well with huge triumph and feel-goodness. Due to this really being a comedy it can be annoying that the film is full of clich&eacute;s and coincidences that usually annoy viewers, but this is a Star Trek for not only Star Trek fans but all movie fans.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Star Trek film even the non-Star Trek fans can enjoy
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bravesfan35
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Sure this film isn't like the 3 previous films but that's what makes it so interesting. Instead of spending the entire movie in space, we get to see Kirk and the crew on Earth back in the 1980's and watch them try to adjust to the way things were back then (example: Kirk had to sell his antique glasses that McCoy had bought him for his birthday in order to get money). The film also takes the step of adding a lot of comedy to it. From Spock experimenting with "colorful metaphors" to Scotty learning how to use a non-voice activated computer, the film is a treasure to watch. Also stars Catherine Hicks (from 7th Heaven) as the intelligent but stubborn Gillian Taylor. Wonder whatever happened with her character after she got assigned to a science vessel. We'll never know.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Plain and Simple,Not Something You'd Expect From Star Trek,
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Dillon Harris
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Star Trek 4: The Voyage Home is a very enjoyable movie with a simple storyline and,like there always is in Star Trek,a brilliant cast.It's certainly not the best Star Trek movie,and it's definitely the least exciting,there isn't an awful lot of spaceships and aliens in this movie,but it did feel like we got some time to really know these characters in a much less serious scenario.What I liked the best about this movie was that they fit a lot of comedy in it,Star Trek dosen't try to be funny a lot of the time,but this movie showed they do have a sense of humor.Fans of Star Trek won't be getting a big action-packed science fiction movie,but they will get a sweet and funny story,and you'll probably surprised with how much you enjoy it Kirk and his crew boldly go back in time in search of the only thing that can save Earth in the distant future,humpback whales.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Star Trek IV
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    wfjohnston14
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This was the funniest film as this one had good humor throughout the film. The crew now heads to the present day and that's the big thing that gives the film its humor, them in such a different environment as their clothes, behaviors, and weapons are strange to Earth. It was not the best idea for a film with its plot and story involving the whales, but it is carried by the wonderful script. The film is filled with memorable moments of Spock punching a guy or asking how to get a nuclear vessel which is insane. The films are still popular and hopefully will still be as good as it may be nearing its final voyage home.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "Admiral, we have found the nuclear wessel. And Admiral...it's the Enterprise!"
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Al_The_Strange
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    In Star Trek II, the Enterprise crew confronted Khan at a great expense. In Star Trek III, they confronted Klingons in a frantic bid to bring back Spock, at great expense. So naturally, in the fourth film of the classic Trek saga, with the Enterprise crew hanging around planet Vulcan in a captured Klingon Bird of Prey, they had to find their way back home. This film turns the voyage home into an adventure all on its own. The film starts off pretty straight-faced, immediately tossing the Federation and Earth into peril to prompt the Enterprise crew to deal with it. The crew's solution - to travel back and time and save the whales - proves to be utterly ridiculous, but the film plays with so much tongue-in-cheek humor that it becomes a comedy classic. There are a few visually impressive moments, as the Klingon Bird of Prey skirts along Earth's oceans, but most of the fun in this film is the lighthearted fish-out-of-water comedy. What could be more hilarious than watching 24th century space explorers slumming around 20th century San Francisco, struggling against a seemingly-primitive society to solve high-tech problems? Some of the funniest and most endearing jokes include seeing Chekov roaming with with his Russian accent, asking where the "nuclear wessels" are. It's always a blast to watch Spock trying to get the hang of cursing, and ultimately using his nerve pinch on an annoying punk. And one of my favorite scenes is Scotty visiting an industrial plant, trying to use a 20th century computer by speaking to it. The comedy makes the film entertaining throughout, but there's still enough problems and peril to make it roll evenly and effectively. It's a little derivative, but still a well-structured plot with quality characters. The film gets a little pushy with the whole "save the whales" theme, but it fits in the light and fluffy context of the overall picture. The film looks good, with solid photography and editing. Acting is still great from the classic Trek cast: William Shatner, Leonard Nimoy, DeForest Kelley, and the rest get even amounts of screen time to express their tongue-in-cheek humor with phenomenal results. Writing is quite witty. This production has some fine-looking sets, props, costumes, locales, and special effects. Music is really boisterous and happy-sounding, but strangely catchy. 4.5/5 (Entertainment: Very Good | Story: Good | Film: Very Good)
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Brilliantly Accessible & Entertaining
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Helio Copter
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/9/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is not the best Star Trek film. But it is the most fun, the most accessible to general audiences, and really much more than just a novelty or comedy. The plot is brilliant in multiple ways. The most obvious is the irresistible humor that arises naturally from the circumstances that the characters find themselves in. This is always the best type of humor, not forced or contrived. Of course, there is also a strong conservation/preservation message, which is inspiringly though-provoking (in the best tradition of Star Trek). Thirdly, this film wraps up the continuous story-arc begun in Stark Trek II & III, finding closure for the characters and answering some of the questions left by the previous installment. As far as other specific things, Catherine Hicks does a great job in her role as a biologist, and it is nice to see all of the crew members getting some genuine screen time of their own (i.e. not just Kirk/Spock/McCoy). The one particular problem is that there are a few moments when things get a little too lighthearted, to the point of being disposably unbelievable. But that can be forgiven, because on the whole, Star Trek IV manages to be a wonderfully engaging, universal film that a wide audience can appreciate, without sacrificing its soul in the process.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Standard, but a bit better than Search for Spock
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gavin-thelordofthefu-48-460297
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    While the original had it's flaws, I thought it was a decent enough film, but the The Wrath of Khan was a much better film with a compelling story while The Search for Spock is pretty good aside from it's other-the-top moments. Star Trek IV: The Voyage Home isn't as excellent as the second, but it's marginally better than Search for Spock. The story isn't exactly perfect, but it was OK with it's fine moments and while most of the humor is nice, some of them are pretty feeble. Aside from those flaws, everything else holds up. The scenery is nice to look at especially New York City, the special effects are solid, the writing is clever, and the music score from Leonard Rosenman is rousing. The cast is still as charming as ever along with a nice appearance from Catherine Hicks (who would later play Andy's mother in Child's Play). William Shatner, Leonard Nimoy and others did a fine job with their performances. Overall, not solid, but a bit better than Search for Spock. That's all I have to say.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The best Star Trek movie yet
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Leofwine_draca
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    STAR TREK IV: THE VOYAGE HOME was, for me, the most entertaining of the Star Trek movies so far, purely because it feels like an episode of the original series blown up to movie length. The time travel plot is an ingenious excuse for Kirk and co to have some fish-out-of-water fun, and fun it certainly is! This is a notably lighter film than the previous instalments and there's plenty of workable comedy to see it through. The cast feel more relaxed than before and there's a holiday atmosphere to the whole thing. Shatner is even charming on occasion while Kelley and Nimoy make the most of their comic bonding. The film also has a more modern, less dated feel than the previous outings. It's worth noting that the new TV Show, STAR TREK: THE NEXT GENERATION, was starting around this time, which may have influenced things, so the special effects are better and there's more originality in the alien races who provide window dressing. Yes, the film has a political message to convey - it's all about saving the planet and protecting the whales - but it's done so in a matter-of-fact way that refuses to preach to the viewer. The focus, instead, is on having a good time, with the result that the audience does too.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The best one so far
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mutty-mcflea
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A big improvement on the previous three dullards, 'The Voyage Home' rounds off the story arc kicked off in 'The Wrath of Khan' and finally brings the series to life. Although it drags in places and suffers from a few (raise eyebrow) illogical ideas (wouldn't people walk right into the cloaked Klingon ship sitting in the middle of a park?), the movie is an engaging romp that ups the comedy element without getting silly. The breezy dialogue lets the regular cast have fun as their characters try to fit in 300 years into their past, and Leonard Nimoy's direction is far less static than in 'Star Trek III'. It's not the best instalment but it does point the franchise in the right direction.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    My favourite Star Trek big-screen adventure
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    IndustriousAngel
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    There's a special place in my heart for Enterprise-Travels-Back-In-Time stories, and "The Voyage Home" is up there with the best of them (like City on the Edge of Forever). The film makes ample use of fish-out-of-water gags, but never gets a mere parody. It's the funniest ST movie by far: Spock's ears and generally trying to blend in, Checkov checking out the nuclear-powered carrier, Scotty trying to communicate with a stone-age computer, Bones experiencing a 20th century hospital ... The film is far from perfect - plot holes abound, starting with the silly premise (the probe destroying earth by communication), and the environmental "message" is written in overlarge letters, but still a very entertaining and endearing film, endlessly rewatchable!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Strangely Watchable
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Jacob Jefferson (jjgooner@yahoo.co.uk)
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Star Trek IV: The Voyage Home *** (out of 4) 119 mins/ PG Cast: William Shatner, Leonard Nimoy, DeForest Kelley, James Doohan, George Takei, Walter Koenig, Nichelle Nichols, Catherine Hicks, Mark Lenard Director: Leonard Nimoy Plot: Admiral James Kirk and his crew are forced to travel back in time to 1986 to retrieve two hunchback whales that are the only beings that can communicate with an Alien Probe, which is on the brink of turning Earth extinct. JJ's Verdict: Star Trek IV: The Voyage Home is almost not a Star Trek movie. It has a completely different tone, setting and plot to its three predecessors. This is, in fact, a very good thing. Its originality and utter bizarreness are its defining qualities. The film opens well with use of footage from parts 2 and 3 and introduces newcomers to the plot very well. As Kirk and his crew are returning back to Earth, the planet becomes under attack from an Alien probe, which is searching for signs of whale call. However, whales have been extinct since the 21st century so Kirk is forced to time-travel back to the 1980's to find the species and take them back to the 23rd century. Here hilarity ensues as the crew tries to get used to eating pizza, swearing and 'dark age' medicine. Although at times this does feel very, very silly, it can be welcoming at times as most of the film is very, very funny. Leonard Nimoy shows once again he can direct well, but his character, Spock is sidelined to an emotionless bore. Shatner and his crew put in good performances once again and Catherine Hicks is very good as Kirk's love interest/ whale expert, Gillian. The film also ends very well with huge triumph and feel-goodness. Due to this really being a comedy it can be annoying that the film is full of clich&eacute;s and coincidences that usually annoy viewers, but this is a Star Trek for not only Star Trek fans but all movie fans.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Star Trek film even the non-Star Trek fans can enjoy
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bravesfan35
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Sure this film isn't like the 3 previous films but that's what makes it so interesting. Instead of spending the entire movie in space, we get to see Kirk and the crew on Earth back in the 1980's and watch them try to adjust to the way things were back then (example: Kirk had to sell his antique glasses that McCoy had bought him for his birthday in order to get money). The film also takes the step of adding a lot of comedy to it. From Spock experimenting with "colorful metaphors" to Scotty learning how to use a non-voice activated computer, the film is a treasure to watch. Also stars Catherine Hicks (from 7th Heaven) as the intelligent but stubborn Gillian Taylor. Wonder whatever happened with her character after she got assigned to a science vessel. We'll never know.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Plain and Simple,Not Something You'd Expect From Star Trek,
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Dillon Harris
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Star Trek 4: The Voyage Home is a very enjoyable movie with a simple storyline and,like there always is in Star Trek,a brilliant cast.It's certainly not the best Star Trek movie,and it's definitely the least exciting,there isn't an awful lot of spaceships and aliens in this movie,but it did feel like we got some time to really know these characters in a much less serious scenario.What I liked the best about this movie was that they fit a lot of comedy in it,Star Trek dosen't try to be funny a lot of the time,but this movie showed they do have a sense of humor.Fans of Star Trek won't be getting a big action-packed science fiction movie,but they will get a sweet and funny story,and you'll probably surprised with how much you enjoy it Kirk and his crew boldly go back in time in search of the only thing that can save Earth in the distant future,humpback whales.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Star Trek IV
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    wfjohnston14
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This was the funniest film as this one had good humor throughout the film. The crew now heads to the present day and that's the big thing that gives the film its humor, them in such a different environment as their clothes, behaviors, and weapons are strange to Earth. It was not the best idea for a film with its plot and story involving the whales, but it is carried by the wonderful script. The film is filled with memorable moments of Spock punching a guy or asking how to get a nuclear vessel which is insane. The films are still popular and hopefully will still be as good as it may be nearing its final voyage home.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "Admiral, we have found the nuclear wessel. And Admiral...it's the Enterprise!"
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Al_The_Strange
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    In Star Trek II, the Enterprise crew confronted Khan at a great expense. In Star Trek III, they confronted Klingons in a frantic bid to bring back Spock, at great expense. So naturally, in the fourth film of the classic Trek saga, with the Enterprise crew hanging around planet Vulcan in a captured Klingon Bird of Prey, they had to find their way back home. This film turns the voyage home into an adventure all on its own. The film starts off pretty straight-faced, immediately tossing the Federation and Earth into peril to prompt the Enterprise crew to deal with it. The crew's solution - to travel back and time and save the whales - proves to be utterly ridiculous, but the film plays with so much tongue-in-cheek humor that it becomes a comedy classic. There are a few visually impressive moments, as the Klingon Bird of Prey skirts along Earth's oceans, but most of the fun in this film is the lighthearted fish-out-of-water comedy. What could be more hilarious than watching 24th century space explorers slumming around 20th century San Francisco, struggling against a seemingly-primitive society to solve high-tech problems? Some of the funniest and most endearing jokes include seeing Chekov roaming with with his Russian accent, asking where the "nuclear wessels" are. It's always a blast to watch Spock trying to get the hang of cursing, and ultimately using his nerve pinch on an annoying punk. And one of my favorite scenes is Scotty visiting an industrial plant, trying to use a 20th century computer by speaking to it. The comedy makes the film entertaining throughout, but there's still enough problems and peril to make it roll evenly and effectively. It's a little derivative, but still a well-structured plot with quality characters. The film gets a little pushy with the whole "save the whales" theme, but it fits in the light and fluffy context of the overall picture. The film looks good, with solid photography and editing. Acting is still great from the classic Trek cast: William Shatner, Leonard Nimoy, DeForest Kelley, and the rest get even amounts of screen time to express their tongue-in-cheek humor with phenomenal results. Writing is quite witty. This production has some fine-looking sets, props, costumes, locales, and special effects. Music is really boisterous and happy-sounding, but strangely catchy. 4.5/5 (Entertainment: Very Good | Story: Good | Film: Very Good)
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Brilliantly Accessible & Entertaining
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Helio Copter
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/9/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is not the best Star Trek film. But it is the most fun, the most accessible to general audiences, and really much more than just a novelty or comedy. The plot is brilliant in multiple ways. The most obvious is the irresistible humor that arises naturally from the circumstances that the characters find themselves in. This is always the best type of humor, not forced or contrived. Of course, there is also a strong conservation/preservation message, which is inspiringly though-provoking (in the best tradition of Star Trek). Thirdly, this film wraps up the continuous story-arc begun in Stark Trek II & III, finding closure for the characters and answering some of the questions left by the previous installment. As far as other specific things, Catherine Hicks does a great job in her role as a biologist, and it is nice to see all of the crew members getting some genuine screen time of their own (i.e. not just Kirk/Spock/McCoy). The one particular problem is that there are a few moments when things get a little too lighthearted, to the point of being disposably unbelievable. But that can be forgiven, because on the whole, Star Trek IV manages to be a wonderfully engaging, universal film that a wide audience can appreciate, without sacrificing its soul in the process.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Standard, but a bit better than Search for Spock
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gavin-thelordofthefu-48-460297
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    While the original had it's flaws, I thought it was a decent enough film, but the The Wrath of Khan was a much better film with a compelling story while The Search for Spock is pretty good aside from it's other-the-top moments. Star Trek IV: The Voyage Home isn't as excellent as the second, but it's marginally better than Search for Spock. The story isn't exactly perfect, but it was OK with it's fine moments and while most of the humor is nice, some of them are pretty feeble. Aside from those flaws, everything else holds up. The scenery is nice to look at especially New York City, the special effects are solid, the writing is clever, and the music score from Leonard Rosenman is rousing. The cast is still as charming as ever along with a nice appearance from Catherine Hicks (who would later play Andy's mother in Child's Play). William Shatner, Leonard Nimoy and others did a fine job with their performances. Overall, not solid, but a bit better than Search for Spock. That's all I have to say.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The best Star Trek movie yet
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Leofwine_draca
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    STAR TREK IV: THE VOYAGE HOME was, for me, the most entertaining of the Star Trek movies so far, purely because it feels like an episode of the original series blown up to movie length. The time travel plot is an ingenious excuse for Kirk and co to have some fish-out-of-water fun, and fun it certainly is! This is a notably lighter film than the previous instalments and there's plenty of workable comedy to see it through. The cast feel more relaxed than before and there's a holiday atmosphere to the whole thing. Shatner is even charming on occasion while Kelley and Nimoy make the most of their comic bonding. The film also has a more modern, less dated feel than the previous outings. It's worth noting that the new TV Show, STAR TREK: THE NEXT GENERATION, was starting around this time, which may have influenced things, so the special effects are better and there's more originality in the alien races who provide window dressing. Yes, the film has a political message to convey - it's all about saving the planet and protecting the whales - but it's done so in a matter-of-fact way that refuses to preach to the viewer. The focus, instead, is on having a good time, with the result that the audience does too.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The best one so far
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mutty-mcflea
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A big improvement on the previous three dullards, 'The Voyage Home' rounds off the story arc kicked off in 'The Wrath of Khan' and finally brings the series to life. Although it drags in places and suffers from a few (raise eyebrow) illogical ideas (wouldn't people walk right into the cloaked Klingon ship sitting in the middle of a park?), the movie is an engaging romp that ups the comedy element without getting silly. The breezy dialogue lets the regular cast have fun as their characters try to fit in 300 years into their past, and Leonard Nimoy's direction is far less static than in 'Star Trek III'. It's not the best instalment but it does point the franchise in the right direction.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    My favourite Star Trek big-screen adventure
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    IndustriousAngel
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    There's a special place in my heart for Enterprise-Travels-Back-In-Time stories, and "The Voyage Home" is up there with the best of them (like City on the Edge of Forever). The film makes ample use of fish-out-of-water gags, but never gets a mere parody. It's the funniest ST movie by far: Spock's ears and generally trying to blend in, Checkov checking out the nuclear-powered carrier, Scotty trying to communicate with a stone-age computer, Bones experiencing a 20th century hospital ... The film is far from perfect - plot holes abound, starting with the silly premise (the probe destroying earth by communication), and the environmental "message" is written in overlarge letters, but still a very entertaining and endearing film, endlessly rewatchable!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Strangely Watchable
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Jacob Jefferson (jjgooner@yahoo.co.uk)
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Star Trek IV: The Voyage Home *** (out of 4) 119 mins/ PG Cast: William Shatner, Leonard Nimoy, DeForest Kelley, James Doohan, George Takei, Walter Koenig, Nichelle Nichols, Catherine Hicks, Mark Lenard Director: Leonard Nimoy Plot: Admiral James Kirk and his crew are forced to travel back in time to 1986 to retrieve two hunchback whales that are the only beings that can communicate with an Alien Probe, which is on the brink of turning Earth extinct. JJ's Verdict: Star Trek IV: The Voyage Home is almost not a Star Trek movie. It has a completely different tone, setting and plot to its three predecessors. This is, in fact, a very good thing. Its originality and utter bizarreness are its defining qualities. The film opens well with use of footage from parts 2 and 3 and introduces newcomers to the plot very well. As Kirk and his crew are returning back to Earth, the planet becomes under attack from an Alien probe, which is searching for signs of whale call. However, whales have been extinct since the 21st century so Kirk is forced to time-travel back to the 1980's to find the species and take them back to the 23rd century. Here hilarity ensues as the crew tries to get used to eating pizza, swearing and 'dark age' medicine. Although at times this does feel very, very silly, it can be welcoming at times as most of the film is very, very funny. Leonard Nimoy shows once again he can direct well, but his character, Spock is sidelined to an emotionless bore. Shatner and his crew put in good performances once again and Catherine Hicks is very good as Kirk's love interest/ whale expert, Gillian. The film also ends very well with huge triumph and feel-goodness. Due to this really being a comedy it can be annoying that the film is full of clich&eacute;s and coincidences that usually annoy viewers, but this is a Star Trek for not only Star Trek fans but all movie fans.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Star Trek film even the non-Star Trek fans can enjoy
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bravesfan35
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Sure this film isn't like the 3 previous films but that's what makes it so interesting. Instead of spending the entire movie in space, we get to see Kirk and the crew on Earth back in the 1980's and watch them try to adjust to the way things were back then (example: Kirk had to sell his antique glasses that McCoy had bought him for his birthday in order to get money). The film also takes the step of adding a lot of comedy to it. From Spock experimenting with "colorful metaphors" to Scotty learning how to use a non-voice activated computer, the film is a treasure to watch. Also stars Catherine Hicks (from 7th Heaven) as the intelligent but stubborn Gillian Taylor. Wonder whatever happened with her character after she got assigned to a science vessel. We'll never know.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Plain and Simple,Not Something You'd Expect From Star Trek,
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Dillon Harris
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Star Trek 4: The Voyage Home is a very enjoyable movie with a simple storyline and,like there always is in Star Trek,a brilliant cast.It's certainly not the best Star Trek movie,and it's definitely the least exciting,there isn't an awful lot of spaceships and aliens in this movie,but it did feel like we got some time to really know these characters in a much less serious scenario.What I liked the best about this movie was that they fit a lot of comedy in it,Star Trek dosen't try to be funny a lot of the time,but this movie showed they do have a sense of humor.Fans of Star Trek won't be getting a big action-packed science fiction movie,but they will get a sweet and funny story,and you'll probably surprised with how much you enjoy it Kirk and his crew boldly go back in time in search of the only thing that can save Earth in the distant future,humpback whales.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Star Trek IV
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    wfjohnston14
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This was the funniest film as this one had good humor throughout the film. The crew now heads to the present day and that's the big thing that gives the film its humor, them in such a different environment as their clothes, behaviors, and weapons are strange to Earth. It was not the best idea for a film with its plot and story involving the whales, but it is carried by the wonderful script. The film is filled with memorable moments of Spock punching a guy or asking how to get a nuclear vessel which is insane. The films are still popular and hopefully will still be as good as it may be nearing its final voyage home.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "Admiral, we have found the nuclear wessel. And Admiral...it's the Enterprise!"
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Al_The_Strange
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    In Star Trek II, the Enterprise crew confronted Khan at a great expense. In Star Trek III, they confronted Klingons in a frantic bid to bring back Spock, at great expense. So naturally, in the fourth film of the classic Trek saga, with the Enterprise crew hanging around planet Vulcan in a captured Klingon Bird of Prey, they had to find their way back home. This film turns the voyage home into an adventure all on its own. The film starts off pretty straight-faced, immediately tossing the Federation and Earth into peril to prompt the Enterprise crew to deal with it. The crew's solution - to travel back and time and save the whales - proves to be utterly ridiculous, but the film plays with so much tongue-in-cheek humor that it becomes a comedy classic. There are a few visually impressive moments, as the Klingon Bird of Prey skirts along Earth's oceans, but most of the fun in this film is the lighthearted fish-out-of-water comedy. What could be more hilarious than watching 24th century space explorers slumming around 20th century San Francisco, struggling against a seemingly-primitive society to solve high-tech problems? Some of the funniest and most endearing jokes include seeing Chekov roaming with with his Russian accent, asking where the "nuclear wessels" are. It's always a blast to watch Spock trying to get the hang of cursing, and ultimately using his nerve pinch on an annoying punk. And one of my favorite scenes is Scotty visiting an industrial plant, trying to use a 20th century computer by speaking to it. The comedy makes the film entertaining throughout, but there's still enough problems and peril to make it roll evenly and effectively. It's a little derivative, but still a well-structured plot with quality characters. The film gets a little pushy with the whole "save the whales" theme, but it fits in the light and fluffy context of the overall picture. The film looks good, with solid photography and editing. Acting is still great from the classic Trek cast: William Shatner, Leonard Nimoy, DeForest Kelley, and the rest get even amounts of screen time to express their tongue-in-cheek humor with phenomenal results. Writing is quite witty. This production has some fine-looking sets, props, costumes, locales, and special effects. Music is really boisterous and happy-sounding, but strangely catchy. 4.5/5 (Entertainment: Very Good | Story: Good | Film: Very Good)
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Brilliantly Accessible & Entertaining
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Helio Copter
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/9/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is not the best Star Trek film. But it is the most fun, the most accessible to general audiences, and really much more than just a novelty or comedy. The plot is brilliant in multiple ways. The most obvious is the irresistible humor that arises naturally from the circumstances that the characters find themselves in. This is always the best type of humor, not forced or contrived. Of course, there is also a strong conservation/preservation message, which is inspiringly though-provoking (in the best tradition of Star Trek). Thirdly, this film wraps up the continuous story-arc begun in Stark Trek II & III, finding closure for the characters and answering some of the questions left by the previous installment. As far as other specific things, Catherine Hicks does a great job in her role as a biologist, and it is nice to see all of the crew members getting some genuine screen time of their own (i.e. not just Kirk/Spock/McCoy). The one particular problem is that there are a few moments when things get a little too lighthearted, to the point of being disposably unbelievable. But that can be forgiven, because on the whole, Star Trek IV manages to be a wonderfully engaging, universal film that a wide audience can appreciate, without sacrificing its soul in the process.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Standard, but a bit better than Search for Spock
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gavin-thelordofthefu-48-460297
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    While the original had it's flaws, I thought it was a decent enough film, but the The Wrath of Khan was a much better film with a compelling story while The Search for Spock is pretty good aside from it's other-the-top moments. Star Trek IV: The Voyage Home isn't as excellent as the second, but it's marginally better than Search for Spock. The story isn't exactly perfect, but it was OK with it's fine moments and while most of the humor is nice, some of them are pretty feeble. Aside from those flaws, everything else holds up. The scenery is nice to look at especially New York City, the special effects are solid, the writing is clever, and the music score from Leonard Rosenman is rousing. The cast is still as charming as ever along with a nice appearance from Catherine Hicks (who would later play Andy's mother in Child's Play). William Shatner, Leonard Nimoy and others did a fine job with their performances. Overall, not solid, but a bit better than Search for Spock. That's all I have to say.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The best Star Trek movie yet
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Leofwine_draca
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    STAR TREK IV: THE VOYAGE HOME was, for me, the most entertaining of the Star Trek movies so far, purely because it feels like an episode of the original series blown up to movie length. The time travel plot is an ingenious excuse for Kirk and co to have some fish-out-of-water fun, and fun it certainly is! This is a notably lighter film than the previous instalments and there's plenty of workable comedy to see it through. The cast feel more relaxed than before and there's a holiday atmosphere to the whole thing. Shatner is even charming on occasion while Kelley and Nimoy make the most of their comic bonding. The film also has a more modern, less dated feel than the previous outings. It's worth noting that the new TV Show, STAR TREK: THE NEXT GENERATION, was starting around this time, which may have influenced things, so the special effects are better and there's more originality in the alien races who provide window dressing. Yes, the film has a political message to convey - it's all about saving the planet and protecting the whales - but it's done so in a matter-of-fact way that refuses to preach to the viewer. The focus, instead, is on having a good time, with the result that the audience does too.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The best one so far
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mutty-mcflea
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A big improvement on the previous three dullards, 'The Voyage Home' rounds off the story arc kicked off in 'The Wrath of Khan' and finally brings the series to life. Although it drags in places and suffers from a few (raise eyebrow) illogical ideas (wouldn't people walk right into the cloaked Klingon ship sitting in the middle of a park?), the movie is an engaging romp that ups the comedy element without getting silly. The breezy dialogue lets the regular cast have fun as their characters try to fit in 300 years into their past, and Leonard Nimoy's direction is far less static than in 'Star Trek III'. It's not the best instalment but it does point the franchise in the right direction.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    My favourite Star Trek big-screen adventure
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    IndustriousAngel
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    There's a special place in my heart for Enterprise-Travels-Back-In-Time stories, and "The Voyage Home" is up there with the best of them (like City on the Edge of Forever). The film makes ample use of fish-out-of-water gags, but never gets a mere parody. It's the funniest ST movie by far: Spock's ears and generally trying to blend in, Checkov checking out the nuclear-powered carrier, Scotty trying to communicate with a stone-age computer, Bones experiencing a 20th century hospital ... The film is far from perfect - plot holes abound, starting with the silly premise (the probe destroying earth by communication), and the environmental "message" is written in overlarge letters, but still a very entertaining and endearing film, endlessly rewatchable!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Strangely Watchable
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Jacob Jefferson (jjgooner@yahoo.co.uk)
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Star Trek IV: The Voyage Home *** (out of 4) 119 mins/ PG Cast: William Shatner, Leonard Nimoy, DeForest Kelley, James Doohan, George Takei, Walter Koenig, Nichelle Nichols, Catherine Hicks, Mark Lenard Director: Leonard Nimoy Plot: Admiral James Kirk and his crew are forced to travel back in time to 1986 to retrieve two hunchback whales that are the only beings that can communicate with an Alien Probe, which is on the brink of turning Earth extinct. JJ's Verdict: Star Trek IV: The Voyage Home is almost not a Star Trek movie. It has a completely different tone, setting and plot to its three predecessors. This is, in fact, a very good thing. Its originality and utter bizarreness are its defining qualities. The film opens well with use of footage from parts 2 and 3 and introduces newcomers to the plot very well. As Kirk and his crew are returning back to Earth, the planet becomes under attack from an Alien probe, which is searching for signs of whale call. However, whales have been extinct since the 21st century so Kirk is forced to time-travel back to the 1980's to find the species and take them back to the 23rd century. Here hilarity ensues as the crew tries to get used to eating pizza, swearing and 'dark age' medicine. Although at times this does feel very, very silly, it can be welcoming at times as most of the film is very, very funny. Leonard Nimoy shows once again he can direct well, but his character, Spock is sidelined to an emotionless bore. Shatner and his crew put in good performances once again and Catherine Hicks is very good as Kirk's love interest/ whale expert, Gillian. The film also ends very well with huge triumph and feel-goodness. Due to this really being a comedy it can be annoying that the film is full of clich&eacute;s and coincidences that usually annoy viewers, but this is a Star Trek for not only Star Trek fans but all movie fans.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Star Trek film even the non-Star Trek fans can enjoy
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bravesfan35
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Sure this film isn't like the 3 previous films but that's what makes it so interesting. Instead of spending the entire movie in space, we get to see Kirk and the crew on Earth back in the 1980's and watch them try to adjust to the way things were back then (example: Kirk had to sell his antique glasses that McCoy had bought him for his birthday in order to get money). The film also takes the step of adding a lot of comedy to it. From Spock experimenting with "colorful metaphors" to Scotty learning how to use a non-voice activated computer, the film is a treasure to watch. Also stars Catherine Hicks (from 7th Heaven) as the intelligent but stubborn Gillian Taylor. Wonder whatever happened with her character after she got assigned to a science vessel. We'll never know.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Plain and Simple,Not Something You'd Expect From Star Trek,
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Dillon Harris
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Star Trek 4: The Voyage Home is a very enjoyable movie with a simple storyline and,like there always is in Star Trek,a brilliant cast.It's certainly not the best Star Trek movie,and it's definitely the least exciting,there isn't an awful lot of spaceships and aliens in this movie,but it did feel like we got some time to really know these characters in a much less serious scenario.What I liked the best about this movie was that they fit a lot of comedy in it,Star Trek dosen't try to be funny a lot of the time,but this movie showed they do have a sense of humor.Fans of Star Trek won't be getting a big action-packed science fiction movie,but they will get a sweet and funny story,and you'll probably surprised with how much you enjoy it Kirk and his crew boldly go back in time in search of the only thing that can save Earth in the distant future,humpback whales.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Star Trek IV
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    wfjohnston14
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This was the funniest film as this one had good humor throughout the film. The crew now heads to the present day and that's the big thing that gives the film its humor, them in such a different environment as their clothes, behaviors, and weapons are strange to Earth. It was not the best idea for a film with its plot and story involving the whales, but it is carried by the wonderful script. The film is filled with memorable moments of Spock punching a guy or asking how to get a nuclear vessel which is insane. The films are still popular and hopefully will still be as good as it may be nearing its final voyage home.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "Admiral, we have found the nuclear wessel. And Admiral...it's the Enterprise!"
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Al_The_Strange
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    In Star Trek II, the Enterprise crew confronted Khan at a great expense. In Star Trek III, they confronted Klingons in a frantic bid to bring back Spock, at great expense. So naturally, in the fourth film of the classic Trek saga, with the Enterprise crew hanging around planet Vulcan in a captured Klingon Bird of Prey, they had to find their way back home. This film turns the voyage home into an adventure all on its own. The film starts off pretty straight-faced, immediately tossing the Federation and Earth into peril to prompt the Enterprise crew to deal with it. The crew's solution - to travel back and time and save the whales - proves to be utterly ridiculous, but the film plays with so much tongue-in-cheek humor that it becomes a comedy classic. There are a few visually impressive moments, as the Klingon Bird of Prey skirts along Earth's oceans, but most of the fun in this film is the lighthearted fish-out-of-water comedy. What could be more hilarious than watching 24th century space explorers slumming around 20th century San Francisco, struggling against a seemingly-primitive society to solve high-tech problems? Some of the funniest and most endearing jokes include seeing Chekov roaming with with his Russian accent, asking where the "nuclear wessels" are. It's always a blast to watch Spock trying to get the hang of cursing, and ultimately using his nerve pinch on an annoying punk. And one of my favorite scenes is Scotty visiting an industrial plant, trying to use a 20th century computer by speaking to it. The comedy makes the film entertaining throughout, but there's still enough problems and peril to make it roll evenly and effectively. It's a little derivative, but still a well-structured plot with quality characters. The film gets a little pushy with the whole "save the whales" theme, but it fits in the light and fluffy context of the overall picture. The film looks good, with solid photography and editing. Acting is still great from the classic Trek cast: William Shatner, Leonard Nimoy, DeForest Kelley, and the rest get even amounts of screen time to express their tongue-in-cheek humor with phenomenal results. Writing is quite witty. This production has some fine-looking sets, props, costumes, locales, and special effects. Music is really boisterous and happy-sounding, but strangely catchy. 4.5/5 (Entertainment: Very Good | Story: Good | Film: Very Good)
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Brilliantly Accessible & Entertaining
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Helio Copter
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/9/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is not the best Star Trek film. But it is the most fun, the most accessible to general audiences, and really much more than just a novelty or comedy. The plot is brilliant in multiple ways. The most obvious is the irresistible humor that arises naturally from the circumstances that the characters find themselves in. This is always the best type of humor, not forced or contrived. Of course, there is also a strong conservation/preservation message, which is inspiringly though-provoking (in the best tradition of Star Trek). Thirdly, this film wraps up the continuous story-arc begun in Stark Trek II & III, finding closure for the characters and answering some of the questions left by the previous installment. As far as other specific things, Catherine Hicks does a great job in her role as a biologist, and it is nice to see all of the crew members getting some genuine screen time of their own (i.e. not just Kirk/Spock/McCoy). The one particular problem is that there are a few moments when things get a little too lighthearted, to the point of being disposably unbelievable. But that can be forgiven, because on the whole, Star Trek IV manages to be a wonderfully engaging, universal film that a wide audience can appreciate, without sacrificing its soul in the process.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Standard, but a bit better than Search for Spock
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gavin-thelordofthefu-48-460297
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    While the original had it's flaws, I thought it was a decent enough film, but the The Wrath of Khan was a much better film with a compelling story while The Search for Spock is pretty good aside from it's other-the-top moments. Star Trek IV: The Voyage Home isn't as excellent as the second, but it's marginally better than Search for Spock. The story isn't exactly perfect, but it was OK with it's fine moments and while most of the humor is nice, some of them are pretty feeble. Aside from those flaws, everything else holds up. The scenery is nice to look at especially New York City, the special effects are solid, the writing is clever, and the music score from Leonard Rosenman is rousing. The cast is still as charming as ever along with a nice appearance from Catherine Hicks (who would later play Andy's mother in Child's Play). William Shatner, Leonard Nimoy and others did a fine job with their performances. Overall, not solid, but a bit better than Search for Spock. That's all I have to say.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The best Star Trek movie yet
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Leofwine_draca
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    STAR TREK IV: THE VOYAGE HOME was, for me, the most entertaining of the Star Trek movies so far, purely because it feels like an episode of the original series blown up to movie length. The time travel plot is an ingenious excuse for Kirk and co to have some fish-out-of-water fun, and fun it certainly is! This is a notably lighter film than the previous instalments and there's plenty of workable comedy to see it through. The cast feel more relaxed than before and there's a holiday atmosphere to the whole thing. Shatner is even charming on occasion while Kelley and Nimoy make the most of their comic bonding. The film also has a more modern, less dated feel than the previous outings. It's worth noting that the new TV Show, STAR TREK: THE NEXT GENERATION, was starting around this time, which may have influenced things, so the special effects are better and there's more originality in the alien races who provide window dressing. Yes, the film has a political message to convey - it's all about saving the planet and protecting the whales - but it's done so in a matter-of-fact way that refuses to preach to the viewer. The focus, instead, is on having a good time, with the result that the audience does too.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The best one so far
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mutty-mcflea
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A big improvement on the previous three dullards, 'The Voyage Home' rounds off the story arc kicked off in 'The Wrath of Khan' and finally brings the series to life. Although it drags in places and suffers from a few (raise eyebrow) illogical ideas (wouldn't people walk right into the cloaked Klingon ship sitting in the middle of a park?), the movie is an engaging romp that ups the comedy element without getting silly. The breezy dialogue lets the regular cast have fun as their characters try to fit in 300 years into their past, and Leonard Nimoy's direction is far less static than in 'Star Trek III'. It's not the best instalment but it does point the franchise in the right direction.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    My favourite Star Trek big-screen adventure
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    IndustriousAngel
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    There's a special place in my heart for Enterprise-Travels-Back-In-Time stories, and "The Voyage Home" is up there with the best of them (like City on the Edge of Forever). The film makes ample use of fish-out-of-water gags, but never gets a mere parody. It's the funniest ST movie by far: Spock's ears and generally trying to blend in, Checkov checking out the nuclear-powered carrier, Scotty trying to communicate with a stone-age computer, Bones experiencing a 20th century hospital ... The film is far from perfect - plot holes abound, starting with the silly premise (the probe destroying earth by communication), and the environmental "message" is written in overlarge letters, but still a very entertaining and endearing film, endlessly rewatchable!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Strangely Watchable
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Jacob Jefferson (jjgooner@yahoo.co.uk)
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Star Trek IV: The Voyage Home *** (out of 4) 119 mins/ PG Cast: William Shatner, Leonard Nimoy, DeForest Kelley, James Doohan, George Takei, Walter Koenig, Nichelle Nichols, Catherine Hicks, Mark Lenard Director: Leonard Nimoy Plot: Admiral James Kirk and his crew are forced to travel back in time to 1986 to retrieve two hunchback whales that are the only beings that can communicate with an Alien Probe, which is on the brink of turning Earth extinct. JJ's Verdict: Star Trek IV: The Voyage Home is almost not a Star Trek movie. It has a completely different tone, setting and plot to its three predecessors. This is, in fact, a very good thing. Its originality and utter bizarreness are its defining qualities. The film opens well with use of footage from parts 2 and 3 and introduces newcomers to the plot very well. As Kirk and his crew are returning back to Earth, the planet becomes under attack from an Alien probe, which is searching for signs of whale call. However, whales have been extinct since the 21st century so Kirk is forced to time-travel back to the 1980's to find the species and take them back to the 23rd century. Here hilarity ensues as the crew tries to get used to eating pizza, swearing and 'dark age' medicine. Although at times this does feel very, very silly, it can be welcoming at times as most of the film is very, very funny. Leonard Nimoy shows once again he can direct well, but his character, Spock is sidelined to an emotionless bore. Shatner and his crew put in good performances once again and Catherine Hicks is very good as Kirk's love interest/ whale expert, Gillian. The film also ends very well with huge triumph and feel-goodness. Due to this really being a comedy it can be annoying that the film is full of clich&eacute;s and coincidences that usually annoy viewers, but this is a Star Trek for not only Star Trek fans but all movie fans.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Star Trek film even the non-Star Trek fans can enjoy
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bravesfan35
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Sure this film isn't like the 3 previous films but that's what makes it so interesting. Instead of spending the entire movie in space, we get to see Kirk and the crew on Earth back in the 1980's and watch them try to adjust to the way things were back then (example: Kirk had to sell his antique glasses that McCoy had bought him for his birthday in order to get money). The film also takes the step of adding a lot of comedy to it. From Spock experimenting with "colorful metaphors" to Scotty learning how to use a non-voice activated computer, the film is a treasure to watch. Also stars Catherine Hicks (from 7th Heaven) as the intelligent but stubborn Gillian Taylor. Wonder whatever happened with her character after she got assigned to a science vessel. We'll never know.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Plain and Simple,Not Something You'd Expect From Star Trek,
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Dillon Harris
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Star Trek 4: The Voyage Home is a very enjoyable movie with a simple storyline and,like there always is in Star Trek,a brilliant cast.It's certainly not the best Star Trek movie,and it's definitely the least exciting,there isn't an awful lot of spaceships and aliens in this movie,but it did feel like we got some time to really know these characters in a much less serious scenario.What I liked the best about this movie was that they fit a lot of comedy in it,Star Trek dosen't try to be funny a lot of the time,but this movie showed they do have a sense of humor.Fans of Star Trek won't be getting a big action-packed science fiction movie,but they will get a sweet and funny story,and you'll probably surprised with how much you enjoy it Kirk and his crew boldly go back in time in search of the only thing that can save Earth in the distant future,humpback whales.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Star Trek IV
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    wfjohnston14
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This was the funniest film as this one had good humor throughout the film. The crew now heads to the present day and that's the big thing that gives the film its humor, them in such a different environment as their clothes, behaviors, and weapons are strange to Earth. It was not the best idea for a film with its plot and story involving the whales, but it is carried by the wonderful script. The film is filled with memorable moments of Spock punching a guy or asking how to get a nuclear vessel which is insane. The films are still popular and hopefully will still be as good as it may be nearing its final voyage home.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "Admiral, we have found the nuclear wessel. And Admiral...it's the Enterprise!"
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Al_The_Strange
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    In Star Trek II, the Enterprise crew confronted Khan at a great expense. In Star Trek III, they confronted Klingons in a frantic bid to bring back Spock, at great expense. So naturally, in the fourth film of the classic Trek saga, with the Enterprise crew hanging around planet Vulcan in a captured Klingon Bird of Prey, they had to find their way back home. This film turns the voyage home into an adventure all on its own. The film starts off pretty straight-faced, immediately tossing the Federation and Earth into peril to prompt the Enterprise crew to deal with it. The crew's solution - to travel back and time and save the whales - proves to be utterly ridiculous, but the film plays with so much tongue-in-cheek humor that it becomes a comedy classic. There are a few visually impressive moments, as the Klingon Bird of Prey skirts along Earth's oceans, but most of the fun in this film is the lighthearted fish-out-of-water comedy. What could be more hilarious than watching 24th century space explorers slumming around 20th century San Francisco, struggling against a seemingly-primitive society to solve high-tech problems? Some of the funniest and most endearing jokes include seeing Chekov roaming with with his Russian accent, asking where the "nuclear wessels" are. It's always a blast to watch Spock trying to get the hang of cursing, and ultimately using his nerve pinch on an annoying punk. And one of my favorite scenes is Scotty visiting an industrial plant, trying to use a 20th century computer by speaking to it. The comedy makes the film entertaining throughout, but there's still enough problems and peril to make it roll evenly and effectively. It's a little derivative, but still a well-structured plot with quality characters. The film gets a little pushy with the whole "save the whales" theme, but it fits in the light and fluffy context of the overall picture. The film looks good, with solid photography and editing. Acting is still great from the classic Trek cast: William Shatner, Leonard Nimoy, DeForest Kelley, and the rest get even amounts of screen time to express their tongue-in-cheek humor with phenomenal results. Writing is quite witty. This production has some fine-looking sets, props, costumes, locales, and special effects. Music is really boisterous and happy-sounding, but strangely catchy. 4.5/5 (Entertainment: Very Good | Story: Good | Film: Very Good)
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Brilliantly Accessible & Entertaining
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Helio Copter
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/9/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is not the best Star Trek film. But it is the most fun, the most accessible to general audiences, and really much more than just a novelty or comedy. The plot is brilliant in multiple ways. The most obvious is the irresistible humor that arises naturally from the circumstances that the characters find themselves in. This is always the best type of humor, not forced or contrived. Of course, there is also a strong conservation/preservation message, which is inspiringly though-provoking (in the best tradition of Star Trek). Thirdly, this film wraps up the continuous story-arc begun in Stark Trek II & III, finding closure for the characters and answering some of the questions left by the previous installment. As far as other specific things, Catherine Hicks does a great job in her role as a biologist, and it is nice to see all of the crew members getting some genuine screen time of their own (i.e. not just Kirk/Spock/McCoy). The one particular problem is that there are a few moments when things get a little too lighthearted, to the point of being disposably unbelievable. But that can be forgiven, because on the whole, Star Trek IV manages to be a wonderfully engaging, universal film that a wide audience can appreciate, without sacrificing its soul in the process.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Standard, but a bit better than Search for Spock
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gavin-thelordofthefu-48-460297
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    While the original had it's flaws, I thought it was a decent enough film, but the The Wrath of Khan was a much better film with a compelling story while The Search for Spock is pretty good aside from it's other-the-top moments. Star Trek IV: The Voyage Home isn't as excellent as the second, but it's marginally better than Search for Spock. The story isn't exactly perfect, but it was OK with it's fine moments and while most of the humor is nice, some of them are pretty feeble. Aside from those flaws, everything else holds up. The scenery is nice to look at especially New York City, the special effects are solid, the writing is clever, and the music score from Leonard Rosenman is rousing. The cast is still as charming as ever along with a nice appearance from Catherine Hicks (who would later play Andy's mother in Child's Play). William Shatner, Leonard Nimoy and others did a fine job with their performances. Overall, not solid, but a bit better than Search for Spock. That's all I have to say.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The best Star Trek movie yet
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Leofwine_draca
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    STAR TREK IV: THE VOYAGE HOME was, for me, the most entertaining of the Star Trek movies so far, purely because it feels like an episode of the original series blown up to movie length. The time travel plot is an ingenious excuse for Kirk and co to have some fish-out-of-water fun, and fun it certainly is! This is a notably lighter film than the previous instalments and there's plenty of workable comedy to see it through. The cast feel more relaxed than before and there's a holiday atmosphere to the whole thing. Shatner is even charming on occasion while Kelley and Nimoy make the most of their comic bonding. The film also has a more modern, less dated feel than the previous outings. It's worth noting that the new TV Show, STAR TREK: THE NEXT GENERATION, was starting around this time, which may have influenced things, so the special effects are better and there's more originality in the alien races who provide window dressing. Yes, the film has a political message to convey - it's all about saving the planet and protecting the whales - but it's done so in a matter-of-fact way that refuses to preach to the viewer. The focus, instead, is on having a good time, with the result that the audience does too.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The best one so far
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mutty-mcflea
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A big improvement on the previous three dullards, 'The Voyage Home' rounds off the story arc kicked off in 'The Wrath of Khan' and finally brings the series to life. Although it drags in places and suffers from a few (raise eyebrow) illogical ideas (wouldn't people walk right into the cloaked Klingon ship sitting in the middle of a park?), the movie is an engaging romp that ups the comedy element without getting silly. The breezy dialogue lets the regular cast have fun as their characters try to fit in 300 years into their past, and Leonard Nimoy's direction is far less static than in 'Star Trek III'. It's not the best instalment but it does point the franchise in the right direction.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    My favourite Star Trek big-screen adventure
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    IndustriousAngel
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    There's a special place in my heart for Enterprise-Travels-Back-In-Time stories, and "The Voyage Home" is up there with the best of them (like City on the Edge of Forever). The film makes ample use of fish-out-of-water gags, but never gets a mere parody. It's the funniest ST movie by far: Spock's ears and generally trying to blend in, Checkov checking out the nuclear-powered carrier, Scotty trying to communicate with a stone-age computer, Bones experiencing a 20th century hospital ... The film is far from perfect - plot holes abound, starting with the silly premise (the probe destroying earth by communication), and the environmental "message" is written in overlarge letters, but still a very entertaining and endearing film, endlessly rewatchable!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Strangely Watchable
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Jacob Jefferson (jjgooner@yahoo.co.uk)
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Star Trek IV: The Voyage Home *** (out of 4) 119 mins/ PG Cast: William Shatner, Leonard Nimoy, DeForest Kelley, James Doohan, George Takei, Walter Koenig, Nichelle Nichols, Catherine Hicks, Mark Lenard Director: Leonard Nimoy Plot: Admiral James Kirk and his crew are forced to travel back in time to 1986 to retrieve two hunchback whales that are the only beings that can communicate with an Alien Probe, which is on the brink of turning Earth extinct. JJ's Verdict: Star Trek IV: The Voyage Home is almost not a Star Trek movie. It has a completely different tone, setting and plot to its three predecessors. This is, in fact, a very good thing. Its originality and utter bizarreness are its defining qualities. The film opens well with use of footage from parts 2 and 3 and introduces newcomers to the plot very well. As Kirk and his crew are returning back to Earth, the planet becomes under attack from an Alien probe, which is searching for signs of whale call. However, whales have been extinct since the 21st century so Kirk is forced to time-travel back to the 1980's to find the species and take them back to the 23rd century. Here hilarity ensues as the crew tries to get used to eating pizza, swearing and 'dark age' medicine. Although at times this does feel very, very silly, it can be welcoming at times as most of the film is very, very funny. Leonard Nimoy shows once again he can direct well, but his character, Spock is sidelined to an emotionless bore. Shatner and his crew put in good performances once again and Catherine Hicks is very good as Kirk's love interest/ whale expert, Gillian. The film also ends very well with huge triumph and feel-goodness. Due to this really being a comedy it can be annoying that the film is full of clich&eacute;s and coincidences that usually annoy viewers, but this is a Star Trek for not only Star Trek fans but all movie fans.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Star Trek film even the non-Star Trek fans can enjoy
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bravesfan35
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Sure this film isn't like the 3 previous films but that's what makes it so interesting. Instead of spending the entire movie in space, we get to see Kirk and the crew on Earth back in the 1980's and watch them try to adjust to the way things were back then (example: Kirk had to sell his antique glasses that McCoy had bought him for his birthday in order to get money). The film also takes the step of adding a lot of comedy to it. From Spock experimenting with "colorful metaphors" to Scotty learning how to use a non-voice activated computer, the film is a treasure to watch. Also stars Catherine Hicks (from 7th Heaven) as the intelligent but stubborn Gillian Taylor. Wonder whatever happened with her character after she got assigned to a science vessel. We'll never know.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Plain and Simple,Not Something You'd Expect From Star Trek,
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Dillon Harris
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Star Trek 4: The Voyage Home is a very enjoyable movie with a simple storyline and,like there always is in Star Trek,a brilliant cast.It's certainly not the best Star Trek movie,and it's definitely the least exciting,there isn't an awful lot of spaceships and aliens in this movie,but it did feel like we got some time to really know these characters in a much less serious scenario.What I liked the best about this movie was that they fit a lot of comedy in it,Star Trek dosen't try to be funny a lot of the time,but this movie showed they do have a sense of humor.Fans of Star Trek won't be getting a big action-packed science fiction movie,but they will get a sweet and funny story,and you'll probably surprised with how much you enjoy it Kirk and his crew boldly go back in time in search of the only thing that can save Earth in the distant future,humpback whales.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Star Trek IV
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    wfjohnston14
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This was the funniest film as this one had good humor throughout the film. The crew now heads to the present day and that's the big thing that gives the film its humor, them in such a different environment as their clothes, behaviors, and weapons are strange to Earth. It was not the best idea for a film with its plot and story involving the whales, but it is carried by the wonderful script. The film is filled with memorable moments of Spock punching a guy or asking how to get a nuclear vessel which is insane. The films are still popular and hopefully will still be as good as it may be nearing its final voyage home.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "Admiral, we have found the nuclear wessel. And Admiral...it's the Enterprise!"
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Al_The_Strange
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    In Star Trek II, the Enterprise crew confronted Khan at a great expense. In Star Trek III, they confronted Klingons in a frantic bid to bring back Spock, at great expense. So naturally, in the fourth film of the classic Trek saga, with the Enterprise crew hanging around planet Vulcan in a captured Klingon Bird of Prey, they had to find their way back home. This film turns the voyage home into an adventure all on its own. The film starts off pretty straight-faced, immediately tossing the Federation and Earth into peril to prompt the Enterprise crew to deal with it. The crew's solution - to travel back and time and save the whales - proves to be utterly ridiculous, but the film plays with so much tongue-in-cheek humor that it becomes a comedy classic. There are a few visually impressive moments, as the Klingon Bird of Prey skirts along Earth's oceans, but most of the fun in this film is the lighthearted fish-out-of-water comedy. What could be more hilarious than watching 24th century space explorers slumming around 20th century San Francisco, struggling against a seemingly-primitive society to solve high-tech problems? Some of the funniest and most endearing jokes include seeing Chekov roaming with with his Russian accent, asking where the "nuclear wessels" are. It's always a blast to watch Spock trying to get the hang of cursing, and ultimately using his nerve pinch on an annoying punk. And one of my favorite scenes is Scotty visiting an industrial plant, trying to use a 20th century computer by speaking to it. The comedy makes the film entertaining throughout, but there's still enough problems and peril to make it roll evenly and effectively. It's a little derivative, but still a well-structured plot with quality characters. The film gets a little pushy with the whole "save the whales" theme, but it fits in the light and fluffy context of the overall picture. The film looks good, with solid photography and editing. Acting is still great from the classic Trek cast: William Shatner, Leonard Nimoy, DeForest Kelley, and the rest get even amounts of screen time to express their tongue-in-cheek humor with phenomenal results. Writing is quite witty. This production has some fine-looking sets, props, costumes, locales, and special effects. Music is really boisterous and happy-sounding, but strangely catchy. 4.5/5 (Entertainment: Very Good | Story: Good | Film: Very Good)
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Brilliantly Accessible & Entertaining
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Helio Copter
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/9/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is not the best Star Trek film. But it is the most fun, the most accessible to general audiences, and really much more than just a novelty or comedy. The plot is brilliant in multiple ways. The most obvious is the irresistible humor that arises naturally from the circumstances that the characters find themselves in. This is always the best type of humor, not forced or contrived. Of course, there is also a strong conservation/preservation message, which is inspiringly though-provoking (in the best tradition of Star Trek). Thirdly, this film wraps up the continuous story-arc begun in Stark Trek II & III, finding closure for the characters and answering some of the questions left by the previous installment. As far as other specific things, Catherine Hicks does a great job in her role as a biologist, and it is nice to see all of the crew members getting some genuine screen time of their own (i.e. not just Kirk/Spock/McCoy). The one particular problem is that there are a few moments when things get a little too lighthearted, to the point of being disposably unbelievable. But that can be forgiven, because on the whole, Star Trek IV manages to be a wonderfully engaging, universal film that a wide audience can appreciate, without sacrificing its soul in the process.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Standard, but a bit better than Search for Spock
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gavin-thelordofthefu-48-460297
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    While the original had it's flaws, I thought it was a decent enough film, but the The Wrath of Khan was a much better film with a compelling story while The Search for Spock is pretty good aside from it's other-the-top moments. Star Trek IV: The Voyage Home isn't as excellent as the second, but it's marginally better than Search for Spock. The story isn't exactly perfect, but it was OK with it's fine moments and while most of the humor is nice, some of them are pretty feeble. Aside from those flaws, everything else holds up. The scenery is nice to look at especially New York City, the special effects are solid, the writing is clever, and the music score from Leonard Rosenman is rousing. The cast is still as charming as ever along with a nice appearance from Catherine Hicks (who would later play Andy's mother in Child's Play). William Shatner, Leonard Nimoy and others did a fine job with their performances. Overall, not solid, but a bit better than Search for Spock. That's all I have to say.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The best Star Trek movie yet
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Leofwine_draca
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    STAR TREK IV: THE VOYAGE HOME was, for me, the most entertaining of the Star Trek movies so far, purely because it feels like an episode of the original series blown up to movie length. The time travel plot is an ingenious excuse for Kirk and co to have some fish-out-of-water fun, and fun it certainly is! This is a notably lighter film than the previous instalments and there's plenty of workable comedy to see it through. The cast feel more relaxed than before and there's a holiday atmosphere to the whole thing. Shatner is even charming on occasion while Kelley and Nimoy make the most of their comic bonding. The film also has a more modern, less dated feel than the previous outings. It's worth noting that the new TV Show, STAR TREK: THE NEXT GENERATION, was starting around this time, which may have influenced things, so the special effects are better and there's more originality in the alien races who provide window dressing. Yes, the film has a political message to convey - it's all about saving the planet and protecting the whales - but it's done so in a matter-of-fact way that refuses to preach to the viewer. The focus, instead, is on having a good time, with the result that the audience does too.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The best one so far
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mutty-mcflea
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A big improvement on the previous three dullards, 'The Voyage Home' rounds off the story arc kicked off in 'The Wrath of Khan' and finally brings the series to life. Although it drags in places and suffers from a few (raise eyebrow) illogical ideas (wouldn't people walk right into the cloaked Klingon ship sitting in the middle of a park?), the movie is an engaging romp that ups the comedy element without getting silly. The breezy dialogue lets the regular cast have fun as their characters try to fit in 300 years into their past, and Leonard Nimoy's direction is far less static than in 'Star Trek III'. It's not the best instalment but it does point the franchise in the right direction.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    My favourite Star Trek big-screen adventure
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    IndustriousAngel
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    There's a special place in my heart for Enterprise-Travels-Back-In-Time stories, and "The Voyage Home" is up there with the best of them (like City on the Edge of Forever). The film makes ample use of fish-out-of-water gags, but never gets a mere parody. It's the funniest ST movie by far: Spock's ears and generally trying to blend in, Checkov checking out the nuclear-powered carrier, Scotty trying to communicate with a stone-age computer, Bones experiencing a 20th century hospital ... The film is far from perfect - plot holes abound, starting with the silly premise (the probe destroying earth by communication), and the environmental "message" is written in overlarge letters, but still a very entertaining and endearing film, endlessly rewatchable!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Strangely Watchable
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Jacob Jefferson (jjgooner@yahoo.co.uk)
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Star Trek IV: The Voyage Home *** (out of 4) 119 mins/ PG Cast: William Shatner, Leonard Nimoy, DeForest Kelley, James Doohan, George Takei, Walter Koenig, Nichelle Nichols, Catherine Hicks, Mark Lenard Director: Leonard Nimoy Plot: Admiral James Kirk and his crew are forced to travel back in time to 1986 to retrieve two hunchback whales that are the only beings that can communicate with an Alien Probe, which is on the brink of turning Earth extinct. JJ's Verdict: Star Trek IV: The Voyage Home is almost not a Star Trek movie. It has a completely different tone, setting and plot to its three predecessors. This is, in fact, a very good thing. Its originality and utter bizarreness are its defining qualities. The film opens well with use of footage from parts 2 and 3 and introduces newcomers to the plot very well. As Kirk and his crew are returning back to Earth, the planet becomes under attack from an Alien probe, which is searching for signs of whale call. However, whales have been extinct since the 21st century so Kirk is forced to time-travel back to the 1980's to find the species and take them back to the 23rd century. Here hilarity ensues as the crew tries to get used to eating pizza, swearing and 'dark age' medicine. Although at times this does feel very, very silly, it can be welcoming at times as most of the film is very, very funny. Leonard Nimoy shows once again he can direct well, but his character, Spock is sidelined to an emotionless bore. Shatner and his crew put in good performances once again and Catherine Hicks is very good as Kirk's love interest/ whale expert, Gillian. The film also ends very well with huge triumph and feel-goodness. Due to this really being a comedy it can be annoying that the film is full of clich&eacute;s and coincidences that usually annoy viewers, but this is a Star Trek for not only Star Trek fans but all movie fans.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Star Trek film even the non-Star Trek fans can enjoy
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bravesfan35
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Sure this film isn't like the 3 previous films but that's what makes it so interesting. Instead of spending the entire movie in space, we get to see Kirk and the crew on Earth back in the 1980's and watch them try to adjust to the way things were back then (example: Kirk had to sell his antique glasses that McCoy had bought him for his birthday in order to get money). The film also takes the step of adding a lot of comedy to it. From Spock experimenting with "colorful metaphors" to Scotty learning how to use a non-voice activated computer, the film is a treasure to watch. Also stars Catherine Hicks (from 7th Heaven) as the intelligent but stubborn Gillian Taylor. Wonder whatever happened with her character after she got assigned to a science vessel. We'll never know.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Plain and Simple,Not Something You'd Expect From Star Trek,
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Dillon Harris
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Star Trek 4: The Voyage Home is a very enjoyable movie with a simple storyline and,like there always is in Star Trek,a brilliant cast.It's certainly not the best Star Trek movie,and it's definitely the least exciting,there isn't an awful lot of spaceships and aliens in this movie,but it did feel like we got some time to really know these characters in a much less serious scenario.What I liked the best about this movie was that they fit a lot of comedy in it,Star Trek dosen't try to be funny a lot of the time,but this movie showed they do have a sense of humor.Fans of Star Trek won't be getting a big action-packed science fiction movie,but they will get a sweet and funny story,and you'll probably surprised with how much you enjoy it Kirk and his crew boldly go back in time in search of the only thing that can save Earth in the distant future,humpback whales.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Star Trek IV
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    wfjohnston14
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This was the funniest film as this one had good humor throughout the film. The crew now heads to the present day and that's the big thing that gives the film its humor, them in such a different environment as their clothes, behaviors, and weapons are strange to Earth. It was not the best idea for a film with its plot and story involving the whales, but it is carried by the wonderful script. The film is filled with memorable moments of Spock punching a guy or asking how to get a nuclear vessel which is insane. The films are still popular and hopefully will still be as good as it may be nearing its final voyage home.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "Admiral, we have found the nuclear wessel. And Admiral...it's the Enterprise!"
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Al_The_Strange
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    In Star Trek II, the Enterprise crew confronted Khan at a great expense. In Star Trek III, they confronted Klingons in a frantic bid to bring back Spock, at great expense. So naturally, in the fourth film of the classic Trek saga, with the Enterprise crew hanging around planet Vulcan in a captured Klingon Bird of Prey, they had to find their way back home. This film turns the voyage home into an adventure all on its own. The film starts off pretty straight-faced, immediately tossing the Federation and Earth into peril to prompt the Enterprise crew to deal with it. The crew's solution - to travel back and time and save the whales - proves to be utterly ridiculous, but the film plays with so much tongue-in-cheek humor that it becomes a comedy classic. There are a few visually impressive moments, as the Klingon Bird of Prey skirts along Earth's oceans, but most of the fun in this film is the lighthearted fish-out-of-water comedy. What could be more hilarious than watching 24th century space explorers slumming around 20th century San Francisco, struggling against a seemingly-primitive society to solve high-tech problems? Some of the funniest and most endearing jokes include seeing Chekov roaming with with his Russian accent, asking where the "nuclear wessels" are. It's always a blast to watch Spock trying to get the hang of cursing, and ultimately using his nerve pinch on an annoying punk. And one of my favorite scenes is Scotty visiting an industrial plant, trying to use a 20th century computer by speaking to it. The comedy makes the film entertaining throughout, but there's still enough problems and peril to make it roll evenly and effectively. It's a little derivative, but still a well-structured plot with quality characters. The film gets a little pushy with the whole "save the whales" theme, but it fits in the light and fluffy context of the overall picture. The film looks good, with solid photography and editing. Acting is still great from the classic Trek cast: William Shatner, Leonard Nimoy, DeForest Kelley, and the rest get even amounts of screen time to express their tongue-in-cheek humor with phenomenal results. Writing is quite witty. This production has some fine-looking sets, props, costumes, locales, and special effects. Music is really boisterous and happy-sounding, but strangely catchy. 4.5/5 (Entertainment: Very Good | Story: Good | Film: Very Good)
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Brilliantly Accessible & Entertaining
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Helio Copter
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/9/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is not the best Star Trek film. But it is the most fun, the most accessible to general audiences, and really much more than just a novelty or comedy. The plot is brilliant in multiple ways. The most obvious is the irresistible humor that arises naturally from the circumstances that the characters find themselves in. This is always the best type of humor, not forced or contrived. Of course, there is also a strong conservation/preservation message, which is inspiringly though-provoking (in the best tradition of Star Trek). Thirdly, this film wraps up the continuous story-arc begun in Stark Trek II & III, finding closure for the characters and answering some of the questions left by the previous installment. As far as other specific things, Catherine Hicks does a great job in her role as a biologist, and it is nice to see all of the crew members getting some genuine screen time of their own (i.e. not just Kirk/Spock/McCoy). The one particular problem is that there are a few moments when things get a little too lighthearted, to the point of being disposably unbelievable. But that can be forgiven, because on the whole, Star Trek IV manages to be a wonderfully engaging, universal film that a wide audience can appreciate, without sacrificing its soul in the process.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Standard, but a bit better than Search for Spock
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gavin-thelordofthefu-48-460297
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    While the original had it's flaws, I thought it was a decent enough film, but the The Wrath of Khan was a much better film with a compelling story while The Search for Spock is pretty good aside from it's other-the-top moments. Star Trek IV: The Voyage Home isn't as excellent as the second, but it's marginally better than Search for Spock. The story isn't exactly perfect, but it was OK with it's fine moments and while most of the humor is nice, some of them are pretty feeble. Aside from those flaws, everything else holds up. The scenery is nice to look at especially New York City, the special effects are solid, the writing is clever, and the music score from Leonard Rosenman is rousing. The cast is still as charming as ever along with a nice appearance from Catherine Hicks (who would later play Andy's mother in Child's Play). William Shatner, Leonard Nimoy and others did a fine job with their performances. Overall, not solid, but a bit better than Search for Spock. That's all I have to say.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The best Star Trek movie yet
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Leofwine_draca
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    STAR TREK IV: THE VOYAGE HOME was, for me, the most entertaining of the Star Trek movies so far, purely because it feels like an episode of the original series blown up to movie length. The time travel plot is an ingenious excuse for Kirk and co to have some fish-out-of-water fun, and fun it certainly is! This is a notably lighter film than the previous instalments and there's plenty of workable comedy to see it through. The cast feel more relaxed than before and there's a holiday atmosphere to the whole thing. Shatner is even charming on occasion while Kelley and Nimoy make the most of their comic bonding. The film also has a more modern, less dated feel than the previous outings. It's worth noting that the new TV Show, STAR TREK: THE NEXT GENERATION, was starting around this time, which may have influenced things, so the special effects are better and there's more originality in the alien races who provide window dressing. Yes, the film has a political message to convey - it's all about saving the planet and protecting the whales - but it's done so in a matter-of-fact way that refuses to preach to the viewer. The focus, instead, is on having a good time, with the result that the audience does too.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The best one so far
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mutty-mcflea
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A big improvement on the previous three dullards, 'The Voyage Home' rounds off the story arc kicked off in 'The Wrath of Khan' and finally brings the series to life. Although it drags in places and suffers from a few (raise eyebrow) illogical ideas (wouldn't people walk right into the cloaked Klingon ship sitting in the middle of a park?), the movie is an engaging romp that ups the comedy element without getting silly. The breezy dialogue lets the regular cast have fun as their characters try to fit in 300 years into their past, and Leonard Nimoy's direction is far less static than in 'Star Trek III'. It's not the best instalment but it does point the franchise in the right direction.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    My favourite Star Trek big-screen adventure
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    IndustriousAngel
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    There's a special place in my heart for Enterprise-Travels-Back-In-Time stories, and "The Voyage Home" is up there with the best of them (like City on the Edge of Forever). The film makes ample use of fish-out-of-water gags, but never gets a mere parody. It's the funniest ST movie by far: Spock's ears and generally trying to blend in, Checkov checking out the nuclear-powered carrier, Scotty trying to communicate with a stone-age computer, Bones experiencing a 20th century hospital ... The film is far from perfect - plot holes abound, starting with the silly premise (the probe destroying earth by communication), and the environmental "message" is written in overlarge letters, but still a very entertaining and endearing film, endlessly rewatchable!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Strangely Watchable
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Jacob Jefferson (jjgooner@yahoo.co.uk)
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Star Trek IV: The Voyage Home *** (out of 4) 119 mins/ PG Cast: William Shatner, Leonard Nimoy, DeForest Kelley, James Doohan, George Takei, Walter Koenig, Nichelle Nichols, Catherine Hicks, Mark Lenard Director: Leonard Nimoy Plot: Admiral James Kirk and his crew are forced to travel back in time to 1986 to retrieve two hunchback whales that are the only beings that can communicate with an Alien Probe, which is on the brink of turning Earth extinct. JJ's Verdict: Star Trek IV: The Voyage Home is almost not a Star Trek movie. It has a completely different tone, setting and plot to its three predecessors. This is, in fact, a very good thing. Its originality and utter bizarreness are its defining qualities. The film opens well with use of footage from parts 2 and 3 and introduces newcomers to the plot very well. As Kirk and his crew are returning back to Earth, the planet becomes under attack from an Alien probe, which is searching for signs of whale call. However, whales have been extinct since the 21st century so Kirk is forced to time-travel back to the 1980's to find the species and take them back to the 23rd century. Here hilarity ensues as the crew tries to get used to eating pizza, swearing and 'dark age' medicine. Although at times this does feel very, very silly, it can be welcoming at times as most of the film is very, very funny. Leonard Nimoy shows once again he can direct well, but his character, Spock is sidelined to an emotionless bore. Shatner and his crew put in good performances once again and Catherine Hicks is very good as Kirk's love interest/ whale expert, Gillian. The film also ends very well with huge triumph and feel-goodness. Due to this really being a comedy it can be annoying that the film is full of clich&eacute;s and coincidences that usually annoy viewers, but this is a Star Trek for not only Star Trek fans but all movie fans.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Star Trek film even the non-Star Trek fans can enjoy
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bravesfan35
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Sure this film isn't like the 3 previous films but that's what makes it so interesting. Instead of spending the entire movie in space, we get to see Kirk and the crew on Earth back in the 1980's and watch them try to adjust to the way things were back then (example: Kirk had to sell his antique glasses that McCoy had bought him for his birthday in order to get money). The film also takes the step of adding a lot of comedy to it. From Spock experimenting with "colorful metaphors" to Scotty learning how to use a non-voice activated computer, the film is a treasure to watch. Also stars Catherine Hicks (from 7th Heaven) as the intelligent but stubborn Gillian Taylor. Wonder whatever happened with her character after she got assigned to a science vessel. We'll never know.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Plain and Simple,Not Something You'd Expect From Star Trek,
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Dillon Harris
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Star Trek 4: The Voyage Home is a very enjoyable movie with a simple storyline and,like there always is in Star Trek,a brilliant cast.It's certainly not the best Star Trek movie,and it's definitely the least exciting,there isn't an awful lot of spaceships and aliens in this movie,but it did feel like we got some time to really know these characters in a much less serious scenario.What I liked the best about this movie was that they fit a lot of comedy in it,Star Trek dosen't try to be funny a lot of the time,but this movie showed they do have a sense of humor.Fans of Star Trek won't be getting a big action-packed science fiction movie,but they will get a sweet and funny story,and you'll probably surprised with how much you enjoy it Kirk and his crew boldly go back in time in search of the only thing that can save Earth in the distant future,humpback whales.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Star Trek IV
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    wfjohnston14
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This was the funniest film as this one had good humor throughout the film. The crew now heads to the present day and that's the big thing that gives the film its humor, them in such a different environment as their clothes, behaviors, and weapons are strange to Earth. It was not the best idea for a film with its plot and story involving the whales, but it is carried by the wonderful script. The film is filled with memorable moments of Spock punching a guy or asking how to get a nuclear vessel which is insane. The films are still popular and hopefully will still be as good as it may be nearing its final voyage home.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "Admiral, we have found the nuclear wessel. And Admiral...it's the Enterprise!"
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Al_The_Strange
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    In Star Trek II, the Enterprise crew confronted Khan at a great expense. In Star Trek III, they confronted Klingons in a frantic bid to bring back Spock, at great expense. So naturally, in the fourth film of the classic Trek saga, with the Enterprise crew hanging around planet Vulcan in a captured Klingon Bird of Prey, they had to find their way back home. This film turns the voyage home into an adventure all on its own. The film starts off pretty straight-faced, immediately tossing the Federation and Earth into peril to prompt the Enterprise crew to deal with it. The crew's solution - to travel back and time and save the whales - proves to be utterly ridiculous, but the film plays with so much tongue-in-cheek humor that it becomes a comedy classic. There are a few visually impressive moments, as the Klingon Bird of Prey skirts along Earth's oceans, but most of the fun in this film is the lighthearted fish-out-of-water comedy. What could be more hilarious than watching 24th century space explorers slumming around 20th century San Francisco, struggling against a seemingly-primitive society to solve high-tech problems? Some of the funniest and most endearing jokes include seeing Chekov roaming with with his Russian accent, asking where the "nuclear wessels" are. It's always a blast to watch Spock trying to get the hang of cursing, and ultimately using his nerve pinch on an annoying punk. And one of my favorite scenes is Scotty visiting an industrial plant, trying to use a 20th century computer by speaking to it. The comedy makes the film entertaining throughout, but there's still enough problems and peril to make it roll evenly and effectively. It's a little derivative, but still a well-structured plot with quality characters. The film gets a little pushy with the whole "save the whales" theme, but it fits in the light and fluffy context of the overall picture. The film looks good, with solid photography and editing. Acting is still great from the classic Trek cast: William Shatner, Leonard Nimoy, DeForest Kelley, and the rest get even amounts of screen time to express their tongue-in-cheek humor with phenomenal results. Writing is quite witty. This production has some fine-looking sets, props, costumes, locales, and special effects. Music is really boisterous and happy-sounding, but strangely catchy. 4.5/5 (Entertainment: Very Good | Story: Good | Film: Very Good)
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Brilliantly Accessible & Entertaining
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Helio Copter
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/9/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is not the best Star Trek film. But it is the most fun, the most accessible to general audiences, and really much more than just a novelty or comedy. The plot is brilliant in multiple ways. The most obvious is the irresistible humor that arises naturally from the circumstances that the characters find themselves in. This is always the best type of humor, not forced or contrived. Of course, there is also a strong conservation/preservation message, which is inspiringly though-provoking (in the best tradition of Star Trek). Thirdly, this film wraps up the continuous story-arc begun in Stark Trek II & III, finding closure for the characters and answering some of the questions left by the previous installment. As far as other specific things, Catherine Hicks does a great job in her role as a biologist, and it is nice to see all of the crew members getting some genuine screen time of their own (i.e. not just Kirk/Spock/McCoy). The one particular problem is that there are a few moments when things get a little too lighthearted, to the point of being disposably unbelievable. But that can be forgiven, because on the whole, Star Trek IV manages to be a wonderfully engaging, universal film that a wide audience can appreciate, without sacrificing its soul in the process.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Standard, but a bit better than Search for Spock
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gavin-thelordofthefu-48-460297
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    While the original had it's flaws, I thought it was a decent enough film, but the The Wrath of Khan was a much better film with a compelling story while The Search for Spock is pretty good aside from it's other-the-top moments. Star Trek IV: The Voyage Home isn't as excellent as the second, but it's marginally better than Search for Spock. The story isn't exactly perfect, but it was OK with it's fine moments and while most of the humor is nice, some of them are pretty feeble. Aside from those flaws, everything else holds up. The scenery is nice to look at especially New York City, the special effects are solid, the writing is clever, and the music score from Leonard Rosenman is rousing. The cast is still as charming as ever along with a nice appearance from Catherine Hicks (who would later play Andy's mother in Child's Play). William Shatner, Leonard Nimoy and others did a fine job with their performances. Overall, not solid, but a bit better than Search for Spock. That's all I have to say.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The best Star Trek movie yet
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Leofwine_draca
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    STAR TREK IV: THE VOYAGE HOME was, for me, the most entertaining of the Star Trek movies so far, purely because it feels like an episode of the original series blown up to movie length. The time travel plot is an ingenious excuse for Kirk and co to have some fish-out-of-water fun, and fun it certainly is! This is a notably lighter film than the previous instalments and there's plenty of workable comedy to see it through. The cast feel more relaxed than before and there's a holiday atmosphere to the whole thing. Shatner is even charming on occasion while Kelley and Nimoy make the most of their comic bonding. The film also has a more modern, less dated feel than the previous outings. It's worth noting that the new TV Show, STAR TREK: THE NEXT GENERATION, was starting around this time, which may have influenced things, so the special effects are better and there's more originality in the alien races who provide window dressing. Yes, the film has a political message to convey - it's all about saving the planet and protecting the whales - but it's done so in a matter-of-fact way that refuses to preach to the viewer. The focus, instead, is on having a good time, with the result that the audience does too.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The best one so far
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mutty-mcflea
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A big improvement on the previous three dullards, 'The Voyage Home' rounds off the story arc kicked off in 'The Wrath of Khan' and finally brings the series to life. Although it drags in places and suffers from a few (raise eyebrow) illogical ideas (wouldn't people walk right into the cloaked Klingon ship sitting in the middle of a park?), the movie is an engaging romp that ups the comedy element without getting silly. The breezy dialogue lets the regular cast have fun as their characters try to fit in 300 years into their past, and Leonard Nimoy's direction is far less static than in 'Star Trek III'. It's not the best instalment but it does point the franchise in the right direction.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    My favourite Star Trek big-screen adventure
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    IndustriousAngel
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    There's a special place in my heart for Enterprise-Travels-Back-In-Time stories, and "The Voyage Home" is up there with the best of them (like City on the Edge of Forever). The film makes ample use of fish-out-of-water gags, but never gets a mere parody. It's the funniest ST movie by far: Spock's ears and generally trying to blend in, Checkov checking out the nuclear-powered carrier, Scotty trying to communicate with a stone-age computer, Bones experiencing a 20th century hospital ... The film is far from perfect - plot holes abound, starting with the silly premise (the probe destroying earth by communication), and the environmental "message" is written in overlarge letters, but still a very entertaining and endearing film, endlessly rewatchable!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Strangely Watchable
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Jacob Jefferson (jjgooner@yahoo.co.uk)
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Star Trek IV: The Voyage Home *** (out of 4) 119 mins/ PG Cast: William Shatner, Leonard Nimoy, DeForest Kelley, James Doohan, George Takei, Walter Koenig, Nichelle Nichols, Catherine Hicks, Mark Lenard Director: Leonard Nimoy Plot: Admiral James Kirk and his crew are forced to travel back in time to 1986 to retrieve two hunchback whales that are the only beings that can communicate with an Alien Probe, which is on the brink of turning Earth extinct. JJ's Verdict: Star Trek IV: The Voyage Home is almost not a Star Trek movie. It has a completely different tone, setting and plot to its three predecessors. This is, in fact, a very good thing. Its originality and utter bizarreness are its defining qualities. The film opens well with use of footage from parts 2 and 3 and introduces newcomers to the plot very well. As Kirk and his crew are returning back to Earth, the planet becomes under attack from an Alien probe, which is searching for signs of whale call. However, whales have been extinct since the 21st century so Kirk is forced to time-travel back to the 1980's to find the species and take them back to the 23rd century. Here hilarity ensues as the crew tries to get used to eating pizza, swearing and 'dark age' medicine. Although at times this does feel very, very silly, it can be welcoming at times as most of the film is very, very funny. Leonard Nimoy shows once again he can direct well, but his character, Spock is sidelined to an emotionless bore. Shatner and his crew put in good performances once again and Catherine Hicks is very good as Kirk's love interest/ whale expert, Gillian. The film also ends very well with huge triumph and feel-goodness. Due to this really being a comedy it can be annoying that the film is full of clich&eacute;s and coincidences that usually annoy viewers, but this is a Star Trek for not only Star Trek fans but all movie fans.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Star Trek film even the non-Star Trek fans can enjoy
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bravesfan35
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Sure this film isn't like the 3 previous films but that's what makes it so interesting. Instead of spending the entire movie in space, we get to see Kirk and the crew on Earth back in the 1980's and watch them try to adjust to the way things were back then (example: Kirk had to sell his antique glasses that McCoy had bought him for his birthday in order to get money). The film also takes the step of adding a lot of comedy to it. From Spock experimenting with "colorful metaphors" to Scotty learning how to use a non-voice activated computer, the film is a treasure to watch. Also stars Catherine Hicks (from 7th Heaven) as the intelligent but stubborn Gillian Taylor. Wonder whatever happened with her character after she got assigned to a science vessel. We'll never know.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Plain and Simple,Not Something You'd Expect From Star Trek,
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Dillon Harris
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Star Trek 4: The Voyage Home is a very enjoyable movie with a simple storyline and,like there always is in Star Trek,a brilliant cast.It's certainly not the best Star Trek movie,and it's definitely the least exciting,there isn't an awful lot of spaceships and aliens in this movie,but it did feel like we got some time to really know these characters in a much less serious scenario.What I liked the best about this movie was that they fit a lot of comedy in it,Star Trek dosen't try to be funny a lot of the time,but this movie showed they do have a sense of humor.Fans of Star Trek won't be getting a big action-packed science fiction movie,but they will get a sweet and funny story,and you'll probably surprised with how much you enjoy it Kirk and his crew boldly go back in time in search of the only thing that can save Earth in the distant future,humpback whales.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Star Trek IV
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    wfjohnston14
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This was the funniest film as this one had good humor throughout the film. The crew now heads to the present day and that's the big thing that gives the film its humor, them in such a different environment as their clothes, behaviors, and weapons are strange to Earth. It was not the best idea for a film with its plot and story involving the whales, but it is carried by the wonderful script. The film is filled with memorable moments of Spock punching a guy or asking how to get a nuclear vessel which is insane. The films are still popular and hopefully will still be as good as it may be nearing its final voyage home.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "Admiral, we have found the nuclear wessel. And Admiral...it's the Enterprise!"
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Al_The_Strange
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    In Star Trek II, the Enterprise crew confronted Khan at a great expense. In Star Trek III, they confronted Klingons in a frantic bid to bring back Spock, at great expense. So naturally, in the fourth film of the classic Trek saga, with the Enterprise crew hanging around planet Vulcan in a captured Klingon Bird of Prey, they had to find their way back home. This film turns the voyage home into an adventure all on its own. The film starts off pretty straight-faced, immediately tossing the Federation and Earth into peril to prompt the Enterprise crew to deal with it. The crew's solution - to travel back and time and save the whales - proves to be utterly ridiculous, but the film plays with so much tongue-in-cheek humor that it becomes a comedy classic. There are a few visually impressive moments, as the Klingon Bird of Prey skirts along Earth's oceans, but most of the fun in this film is the lighthearted fish-out-of-water comedy. What could be more hilarious than watching 24th century space explorers slumming around 20th century San Francisco, struggling against a seemingly-primitive society to solve high-tech problems? Some of the funniest and most endearing jokes include seeing Chekov roaming with with his Russian accent, asking where the "nuclear wessels" are. It's always a blast to watch Spock trying to get the hang of cursing, and ultimately using his nerve pinch on an annoying punk. And one of my favorite scenes is Scotty visiting an industrial plant, trying to use a 20th century computer by speaking to it. The comedy makes the film entertaining throughout, but there's still enough problems and peril to make it roll evenly and effectively. It's a little derivative, but still a well-structured plot with quality characters. The film gets a little pushy with the whole "save the whales" theme, but it fits in the light and fluffy context of the overall picture. The film looks good, with solid photography and editing. Acting is still great from the classic Trek cast: William Shatner, Leonard Nimoy, DeForest Kelley, and the rest get even amounts of screen time to express their tongue-in-cheek humor with phenomenal results. Writing is quite witty. This production has some fine-looking sets, props, costumes, locales, and special effects. Music is really boisterous and happy-sounding, but strangely catchy. 4.5/5 (Entertainment: Very Good | Story: Good | Film: Very Good)
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Brilliantly Accessible & Entertaining
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Helio Copter
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/9/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is not the best Star Trek film. But it is the most fun, the most accessible to general audiences, and really much more than just a novelty or comedy. The plot is brilliant in multiple ways. The most obvious is the irresistible humor that arises naturally from the circumstances that the characters find themselves in. This is always the best type of humor, not forced or contrived. Of course, there is also a strong conservation/preservation message, which is inspiringly though-provoking (in the best tradition of Star Trek). Thirdly, this film wraps up the continuous story-arc begun in Stark Trek II & III, finding closure for the characters and answering some of the questions left by the previous installment. As far as other specific things, Catherine Hicks does a great job in her role as a biologist, and it is nice to see all of the crew members getting some genuine screen time of their own (i.e. not just Kirk/Spock/McCoy). The one particular problem is that there are a few moments when things get a little too lighthearted, to the point of being disposably unbelievable. But that can be forgiven, because on the whole, Star Trek IV manages to be a wonderfully engaging, universal film that a wide audience can appreciate, without sacrificing its soul in the process.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
 </reviews>
</filme>
