<filme>
 <id>
  233
 </id>
 <imdburl>
  http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0105690
 </imdburl>
 <ano>
  1992
 </ano>
 <titulo>
  A For&ccedil;a em Alerta
 </titulo>
 <rating>
  6.3
 </rating>
 <sinopse>
  A former SEAL, now cook, is the only person who can stop a gang of terrorists when they seize control of a US Navy battleship.
 </sinopse>
 <storyline>
  The battleship Missouri is about to be decomissioned. Casey Ryback is Captain Adam's personal cook. And Ryback is always butting heads with the ship's XO Commander Krill but the Captain always intercedes. One day, after the President visits the Missouri, which is also the Captain's birthday, the Captain learns that a helicopter has been cleared to land on the ship by Commander Krill, which he was not informed of. When questioned Krill tells the Captain that it's a surprise for his birthday, the Captain then allows it. Later after another one of their scuffles, Krill has Ryback locked in the freezer. During the party, the rock band reveals themselves to be mercenaries, led by William Stranix, a CIA operative, who is in league with Krill to unload all of the ship's nuclear warheads. They lock up all of the crew and make preparations to remove the warheads. And Krill remembers Ryback, Stranix sends two of his men to take care of Ryback, only thing is that Ryback took care of them. Upon ...
 </storyline>
 <generos>
  <genero>
   Action
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Thriller
  </genero>
 </generos>
 <keywords>
  <keyword>
   cook
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   terrorist
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   battleship
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   party
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   warhead
  </keyword>
 </keywords>
 <diretores>
  <diretor>
   Andrew Davis
  </diretor>
 </diretores>
 <escritores>
  <escritor>
   J.F. Lawton
  </escritor>
 </escritores>
 <atores>
  <ator>
   Steven Seagal
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Gary Busey
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Tommy Lee Jones
  </ator>
 </atores>
 <reviews>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Great action flick
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    sfcat
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I'm really surprised to see such a low average. In my mind, it's Steven Segal's best film, and it's an excellent action movie. It moves at a great pace, the plot is not too trite or unoriginal, especially for the time, and most of it was believable. It's a great popcorn movie! In short, Steven Segal is the captains friend For some reason he's working as ship's cook Something he's good at, but he's been demoted- I don't recall if we ever found out explicitly why, there's some talk of him getting in trouble, but I don't think they tell us the detail. A surprise party goes wrong, so there's a pretty girl involved when everything goes to heck.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Awesome action flick.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Scott LeBrun (Hey_Sweden)
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Let me just join the chorus here in saying that "Under Siege" is definitely the best film of Steven Seagals' career. It benefits from the presence of a genre pro as director, Andrew Davis. He'd previously directed Seagal in "Above the Law", and he shows how well he can handle large scale action and shooting in confined locations. Another plus is more colourful villains than usual, extremely well played by Tommy Lee Jones and Gary Busey; they're both endlessly amusing. Playboy Playmate Erika Eleniak adds appreciable eye candy, and the film also has that irresistible over the top brutality that characterized Seagals' early films. Seagal plays Casey Ryback, a cook aboard the U.S.S. Missouri who must save the day when mercenaries, led by Jones and assisted by disgruntled officer Busey, touch down on the battleship under the guise of a blues band. They quickly take over, but Busey conveniently forgets about Seagal, who's able to slip away and start taking measures to stop the bad guys' plans. Ryback isn't entirely on his own, though, acquiring some companions (including Eleniak, who plays a centerfold hired to jump out of a birthday cake) along the way. Of course, as prepared as these bad guys are, they're no match for this particular cook. Slick as hell, this ass kicking film is consistently fun, perfect popcorn fare with a great pace and a sense of humour about itself. Seagal looks loose and relaxed here; even though he's never been much of an actor, he's always proved quite watchable (at least in his earlier efforts). Busey is a standout among the villains; at one point, he's actually dressed in drag. A *ton* of familiar faces play supporting and small parts: Colm Meaney, Patrick O'Neal, Andy Romano, Nick Mancuso, Troy Evans, Glenn Morshower, Bernie Casey, Raymond Cruz, Duane Davis, George Cheung, Sandy Ward, Michael Des Barres, Dennis Lipscomb, and Dale Dye. There's enough explosions and gunfire to maintain ones' attention, as well as one marvelous and memorable comeuppance for one of the baddies. With a stirring score by Gary Chang as accompaniment, this is rock solid escapism from start to finish, and it's too bad that this level of quality in a Seagal flick wouldn't recur after this. Nine out of 10.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    So this somehow found its way into cinemas
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mutty-mcflea
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Transferring the plot of 'Die Hard' to a battleship more faithfully than most screenwriters adapt novels, 'Pretty Woman' hack J.F. Lawton gives Steven Seagal a cinematic vehicle that's just as bad as all his straight-to-video dreck. Unlike 'Die Hard', this thing is devoid of tension, style and wit, preferring instead to make a lot of noise through various soporific action sequences. Once Seagal's character has finally been let out of that fridge he never worries, never fails, never has to improvise and is consequently never interesting, while sidekick Erika Eleniak stops being engaging as soon as she puts her clothes on and starts asking questions like 'What are they saying?' and 'What's that?' and 'What IS that?' Meanwhile Tommy Lee Jones hams it up to no effect, Andrew Davis's direction is desperately flat and every one-liner gets its very own tumbleweed. Rubbish.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Seagel at his best this film is a high tech laugh and pack of thrills .
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    julesdil
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Lets say this was a good seagel film a thriller and action its very cool in ways . The film was described as die hard on a battle ship no its not die hard is a bad boring film but this is very entertaining .This has thrills , and laughs lots of action which is bad getting killed so its a classic this is simple different 90s action that is very inventive if you want to watch go ahead its an seagal film everyone knows seagal hes just awesome .8.0 out of 10.0 / entertaining film / it does lack brilliance and brill acting although seagal is the highlighlight its still very underrated and great . 15 certificate clearly underrated this is a brutal action film the seagal action ids always brutal . should be 18 for strong brutal action violence , threat and language and some sexual scenes . 7 0ut of 10 for violence can be very bad to viewers . total explitict content 10 out of 100 so it gets little explitict content .
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Lively and Fun
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    leonlouisricci
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is Steven Seagal's most popular film among fans and critics. Although he made some others that are just as good. Above the Law (1988), Out for Justice (1991), and Under Siege 2 (1995). These three are not as slick and audience friendly and have more gritty violence and raw characters. But this movie could be called his most fun. It has a light hearted tone and there is a lot played for laughs by the co-stars and there is much attention given to the ship itself. It is a lively affair with enough ingredients to give everyone a good time, even non-fans of the action star. Overall it is an inoffensive action flick with some big budget gimmicks and fun villains, some very good cinematography, and high powered sound. If you liked this one check out those others for even more entertainment from the whispering martial arts expert.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Die Hard on a battleship!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Tweekums
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/9/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    After being decommissioned in Hawaii the USS Missouri; a colossal battleship is taking its last journey and it won't be plain sailing! To celebrate the captain's fiftieth birthday the Executive Officer, Cmdr. Krill, has arranged a surprise party which is to involve having a band, some caterers and Jordan Tate AKA Miss July 1989 flown in by helicopter. The only problem is that with the exception of Miss Tate none of them is who they seem to be; they, along with Krill, intend to seize the ship along with its tomahawk nuclear missiles. The group is led by former CIA operative William Stranix who was understandably upset when the Agency decided he was no longer required and tried to kill him. When their plan swings into action most of the crew are quickly captured or killed; one exception is Casey Ryback, the chef. Krill has him under marine guard in the galley but he isn't captive for long. Ryback isn't an ordinary cook; he is a former Navy Seal and he is trained for just this sort of problem! Ryback soon finds an ally Jordan Tate! The two of them work to thwart Krill's plans and prevent a nuclear strike against Honolulu! This is a solid action thriller; probably Steven Seagal's best film; certainly the best one I've seen. He plays Ryback and does a pretty good job in the role managing to hold his own against Tommy Lee Jones and Gary Busey who play Stranix and Krill; they are both delightfully over the top villains at one point Busey dons a dress complete with a chest that makes Erika Eleniak, who plays Jordan Tate look small! At first I thought her appearance was just eye-candy and her emerging from a giant cake showing her breasts seemed to confirm this fear; thankfully when she puts some clothes on she made a good character not necessarily believable but fun to watch. The story was pretty good and the action is great without getting too gruesome; there are shootings, knife-fights and explosions to keep things exciting and not too much time is wasted on unnecessary exposition.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Seagal's Best
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Film Flare
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/5/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Well, this film is the height of Seagal's career. The best film he has ever done.....fact! Playing Casey Ryback, the ship's cook, Seagal brings a level of charm, charisma and action man can-do attitude to this film. Aided, of course by beautifully OTT villains, played by the unholy trinity of Tommy Lee Jones, Gary 'Insane in the membrane' Busey and Colm 'DS9' Meaney, they all chew the scenery until their mouths are full. Gary Busey especially excels as the charmless and dangerous Commander Krill (Busey in drag is a scene that highlights his frame of mind). The director, Andrew Davis (who also directed Nico) directs this film with flair and style and commands a not terrible cast to perform well with a run of the mill script. The story is a simple, terrorist highjacking narrative but it is elevated with a cheeky humour, nice little one liners and characters fleshed out a little bit more than you would have expected from a film of this type. Once again, the martial arts and gunfights are well done, there is a knife fight towards the end of the film which is just good and there is no shortage of explosions, creative deaths and gunfire to keep the crowd from noticing a number of plot holes. All in all, a good film. Not even a good film compared to the other Steven Seagal films listed here, it is actually a good film if you're in the mood for, and can tolerate, mindless action.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Best Seagal Film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Marvin Larson
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/3/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Under Siege" packs nonstop action and suspense into two quick hours, and is quite entertaining. Violent and not particularly literary but worthy entry in action genre and realized in &uml;Die hard&uml; style. Wooden Seagal plays the violent Casey Ryback, he cleans up the battleship by means of punches, kicks, bounds and leaps, martial arts skills with fights certainly is slick. The Aikido expert Seagal saves the day in this exciting movie which he also co-produced .In the film appear many secondary roles played by prestigious actors as Patrick O'Neal,Colm Meany, Damian Chapa, Raymond Cruz , Bernie Casey, Nick Mancuso and several others. This elaborately produced action film with two-fisted Seagal is just another action film full of struggles ,thrills, noise and lots of violence. Steven Seagal as almost always, plays a stalwart and lone fighter, BUT, he delivers the goods in his own style full of usual violence and fights with snapping wrists and flying bodies. Unfortunately, these days, a much heftier Seagal does mostly low budget and direct to video garbage , such as &uml;Half past dead&uml;, &uml;The foreigner&uml; and its sequel, &uml;Shadow man &uml;, &uml;Flight of fury&uml;, &uml;Urban justice&uml; and many others.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Terrific Entertainer!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    nama chakravorty
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    'Under Siege' is A Terrific Entertainer, with everything working for it. Tight-Script, Gripping Direction & Fantastic Performances, make 'Under Siege' a must see. 'Under Siege' Synopsis: A former SEAL, now cook, is the only person who can stop a gang of terrorists when they seize control of a US Navy battleship. 'Under Siege' is entertaining & exciting from start to end. It never loses its pace. J. F. Lawton's Screenplay is top-notch. Andrew Davis's Direction is Gripping. Cinematography & Editing are good. Action-Sequences/Stunts are fabulous. Performance-Wise: Steven Seagal delivers a heroic performance. Tommy Lee Jones & Gary Busey are simply Fantastic as the repulsive villains. They both are the real scene-stealer's! Erika Eleniak looks wow & does reasonably well. Others lend support. On the whole, 'Under Siege' is a terrific film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Best of Steven Seagal
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ebiros2
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/11/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie was made when Steven Seagal was at his prime. A group of terrorists highjacks the USS Missouri, and making demands on the US government. It's up to the lowly cook (Steven Seagal) to save the day. This is one of the best movie Steven Seagal made. It's also probably the only big budget movie he's starred in. The best actor in this movie probably is the battleship itself. All the exciting action scenes relates to the workings of this ship. The firing of the Tomahawk missile, and the 16 inch guns. The team of Seagal, Eleniak, and Busey, and Jones were spot on for the act. They chose the right backdrop for the movie. Being inside a battleship makes for many opportunity for good action scenes.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Great action flick
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    sfcat
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I'm really surprised to see such a low average. In my mind, it's Steven Segal's best film, and it's an excellent action movie. It moves at a great pace, the plot is not too trite or unoriginal, especially for the time, and most of it was believable. It's a great popcorn movie! In short, Steven Segal is the captains friend For some reason he's working as ship's cook Something he's good at, but he's been demoted- I don't recall if we ever found out explicitly why, there's some talk of him getting in trouble, but I don't think they tell us the detail. A surprise party goes wrong, so there's a pretty girl involved when everything goes to heck.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Awesome action flick.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Scott LeBrun (Hey_Sweden)
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Let me just join the chorus here in saying that "Under Siege" is definitely the best film of Steven Seagals' career. It benefits from the presence of a genre pro as director, Andrew Davis. He'd previously directed Seagal in "Above the Law", and he shows how well he can handle large scale action and shooting in confined locations. Another plus is more colourful villains than usual, extremely well played by Tommy Lee Jones and Gary Busey; they're both endlessly amusing. Playboy Playmate Erika Eleniak adds appreciable eye candy, and the film also has that irresistible over the top brutality that characterized Seagals' early films. Seagal plays Casey Ryback, a cook aboard the U.S.S. Missouri who must save the day when mercenaries, led by Jones and assisted by disgruntled officer Busey, touch down on the battleship under the guise of a blues band. They quickly take over, but Busey conveniently forgets about Seagal, who's able to slip away and start taking measures to stop the bad guys' plans. Ryback isn't entirely on his own, though, acquiring some companions (including Eleniak, who plays a centerfold hired to jump out of a birthday cake) along the way. Of course, as prepared as these bad guys are, they're no match for this particular cook. Slick as hell, this ass kicking film is consistently fun, perfect popcorn fare with a great pace and a sense of humour about itself. Seagal looks loose and relaxed here; even though he's never been much of an actor, he's always proved quite watchable (at least in his earlier efforts). Busey is a standout among the villains; at one point, he's actually dressed in drag. A *ton* of familiar faces play supporting and small parts: Colm Meaney, Patrick O'Neal, Andy Romano, Nick Mancuso, Troy Evans, Glenn Morshower, Bernie Casey, Raymond Cruz, Duane Davis, George Cheung, Sandy Ward, Michael Des Barres, Dennis Lipscomb, and Dale Dye. There's enough explosions and gunfire to maintain ones' attention, as well as one marvelous and memorable comeuppance for one of the baddies. With a stirring score by Gary Chang as accompaniment, this is rock solid escapism from start to finish, and it's too bad that this level of quality in a Seagal flick wouldn't recur after this. Nine out of 10.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    So this somehow found its way into cinemas
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mutty-mcflea
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Transferring the plot of 'Die Hard' to a battleship more faithfully than most screenwriters adapt novels, 'Pretty Woman' hack J.F. Lawton gives Steven Seagal a cinematic vehicle that's just as bad as all his straight-to-video dreck. Unlike 'Die Hard', this thing is devoid of tension, style and wit, preferring instead to make a lot of noise through various soporific action sequences. Once Seagal's character has finally been let out of that fridge he never worries, never fails, never has to improvise and is consequently never interesting, while sidekick Erika Eleniak stops being engaging as soon as she puts her clothes on and starts asking questions like 'What are they saying?' and 'What's that?' and 'What IS that?' Meanwhile Tommy Lee Jones hams it up to no effect, Andrew Davis's direction is desperately flat and every one-liner gets its very own tumbleweed. Rubbish.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Seagel at his best this film is a high tech laugh and pack of thrills .
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    julesdil
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Lets say this was a good seagel film a thriller and action its very cool in ways . The film was described as die hard on a battle ship no its not die hard is a bad boring film but this is very entertaining .This has thrills , and laughs lots of action which is bad getting killed so its a classic this is simple different 90s action that is very inventive if you want to watch go ahead its an seagal film everyone knows seagal hes just awesome .8.0 out of 10.0 / entertaining film / it does lack brilliance and brill acting although seagal is the highlighlight its still very underrated and great . 15 certificate clearly underrated this is a brutal action film the seagal action ids always brutal . should be 18 for strong brutal action violence , threat and language and some sexual scenes . 7 0ut of 10 for violence can be very bad to viewers . total explitict content 10 out of 100 so it gets little explitict content .
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Lively and Fun
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    leonlouisricci
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is Steven Seagal's most popular film among fans and critics. Although he made some others that are just as good. Above the Law (1988), Out for Justice (1991), and Under Siege 2 (1995). These three are not as slick and audience friendly and have more gritty violence and raw characters. But this movie could be called his most fun. It has a light hearted tone and there is a lot played for laughs by the co-stars and there is much attention given to the ship itself. It is a lively affair with enough ingredients to give everyone a good time, even non-fans of the action star. Overall it is an inoffensive action flick with some big budget gimmicks and fun villains, some very good cinematography, and high powered sound. If you liked this one check out those others for even more entertainment from the whispering martial arts expert.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Die Hard on a battleship!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Tweekums
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/9/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    After being decommissioned in Hawaii the USS Missouri; a colossal battleship is taking its last journey and it won't be plain sailing! To celebrate the captain's fiftieth birthday the Executive Officer, Cmdr. Krill, has arranged a surprise party which is to involve having a band, some caterers and Jordan Tate AKA Miss July 1989 flown in by helicopter. The only problem is that with the exception of Miss Tate none of them is who they seem to be; they, along with Krill, intend to seize the ship along with its tomahawk nuclear missiles. The group is led by former CIA operative William Stranix who was understandably upset when the Agency decided he was no longer required and tried to kill him. When their plan swings into action most of the crew are quickly captured or killed; one exception is Casey Ryback, the chef. Krill has him under marine guard in the galley but he isn't captive for long. Ryback isn't an ordinary cook; he is a former Navy Seal and he is trained for just this sort of problem! Ryback soon finds an ally Jordan Tate! The two of them work to thwart Krill's plans and prevent a nuclear strike against Honolulu! This is a solid action thriller; probably Steven Seagal's best film; certainly the best one I've seen. He plays Ryback and does a pretty good job in the role managing to hold his own against Tommy Lee Jones and Gary Busey who play Stranix and Krill; they are both delightfully over the top villains at one point Busey dons a dress complete with a chest that makes Erika Eleniak, who plays Jordan Tate look small! At first I thought her appearance was just eye-candy and her emerging from a giant cake showing her breasts seemed to confirm this fear; thankfully when she puts some clothes on she made a good character not necessarily believable but fun to watch. The story was pretty good and the action is great without getting too gruesome; there are shootings, knife-fights and explosions to keep things exciting and not too much time is wasted on unnecessary exposition.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Seagal's Best
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Film Flare
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/5/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Well, this film is the height of Seagal's career. The best film he has ever done.....fact! Playing Casey Ryback, the ship's cook, Seagal brings a level of charm, charisma and action man can-do attitude to this film. Aided, of course by beautifully OTT villains, played by the unholy trinity of Tommy Lee Jones, Gary 'Insane in the membrane' Busey and Colm 'DS9' Meaney, they all chew the scenery until their mouths are full. Gary Busey especially excels as the charmless and dangerous Commander Krill (Busey in drag is a scene that highlights his frame of mind). The director, Andrew Davis (who also directed Nico) directs this film with flair and style and commands a not terrible cast to perform well with a run of the mill script. The story is a simple, terrorist highjacking narrative but it is elevated with a cheeky humour, nice little one liners and characters fleshed out a little bit more than you would have expected from a film of this type. Once again, the martial arts and gunfights are well done, there is a knife fight towards the end of the film which is just good and there is no shortage of explosions, creative deaths and gunfire to keep the crowd from noticing a number of plot holes. All in all, a good film. Not even a good film compared to the other Steven Seagal films listed here, it is actually a good film if you're in the mood for, and can tolerate, mindless action.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Best Seagal Film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Marvin Larson
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/3/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Under Siege" packs nonstop action and suspense into two quick hours, and is quite entertaining. Violent and not particularly literary but worthy entry in action genre and realized in &uml;Die hard&uml; style. Wooden Seagal plays the violent Casey Ryback, he cleans up the battleship by means of punches, kicks, bounds and leaps, martial arts skills with fights certainly is slick. The Aikido expert Seagal saves the day in this exciting movie which he also co-produced .In the film appear many secondary roles played by prestigious actors as Patrick O'Neal,Colm Meany, Damian Chapa, Raymond Cruz , Bernie Casey, Nick Mancuso and several others. This elaborately produced action film with two-fisted Seagal is just another action film full of struggles ,thrills, noise and lots of violence. Steven Seagal as almost always, plays a stalwart and lone fighter, BUT, he delivers the goods in his own style full of usual violence and fights with snapping wrists and flying bodies. Unfortunately, these days, a much heftier Seagal does mostly low budget and direct to video garbage , such as &uml;Half past dead&uml;, &uml;The foreigner&uml; and its sequel, &uml;Shadow man &uml;, &uml;Flight of fury&uml;, &uml;Urban justice&uml; and many others.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Terrific Entertainer!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    nama chakravorty
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    'Under Siege' is A Terrific Entertainer, with everything working for it. Tight-Script, Gripping Direction & Fantastic Performances, make 'Under Siege' a must see. 'Under Siege' Synopsis: A former SEAL, now cook, is the only person who can stop a gang of terrorists when they seize control of a US Navy battleship. 'Under Siege' is entertaining & exciting from start to end. It never loses its pace. J. F. Lawton's Screenplay is top-notch. Andrew Davis's Direction is Gripping. Cinematography & Editing are good. Action-Sequences/Stunts are fabulous. Performance-Wise: Steven Seagal delivers a heroic performance. Tommy Lee Jones & Gary Busey are simply Fantastic as the repulsive villains. They both are the real scene-stealer's! Erika Eleniak looks wow & does reasonably well. Others lend support. On the whole, 'Under Siege' is a terrific film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Best of Steven Seagal
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ebiros2
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/11/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie was made when Steven Seagal was at his prime. A group of terrorists highjacks the USS Missouri, and making demands on the US government. It's up to the lowly cook (Steven Seagal) to save the day. This is one of the best movie Steven Seagal made. It's also probably the only big budget movie he's starred in. The best actor in this movie probably is the battleship itself. All the exciting action scenes relates to the workings of this ship. The firing of the Tomahawk missile, and the 16 inch guns. The team of Seagal, Eleniak, and Busey, and Jones were spot on for the act. They chose the right backdrop for the movie. Being inside a battleship makes for many opportunity for good action scenes.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Great action flick
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    sfcat
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I'm really surprised to see such a low average. In my mind, it's Steven Segal's best film, and it's an excellent action movie. It moves at a great pace, the plot is not too trite or unoriginal, especially for the time, and most of it was believable. It's a great popcorn movie! In short, Steven Segal is the captains friend For some reason he's working as ship's cook Something he's good at, but he's been demoted- I don't recall if we ever found out explicitly why, there's some talk of him getting in trouble, but I don't think they tell us the detail. A surprise party goes wrong, so there's a pretty girl involved when everything goes to heck.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Awesome action flick.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Scott LeBrun (Hey_Sweden)
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Let me just join the chorus here in saying that "Under Siege" is definitely the best film of Steven Seagals' career. It benefits from the presence of a genre pro as director, Andrew Davis. He'd previously directed Seagal in "Above the Law", and he shows how well he can handle large scale action and shooting in confined locations. Another plus is more colourful villains than usual, extremely well played by Tommy Lee Jones and Gary Busey; they're both endlessly amusing. Playboy Playmate Erika Eleniak adds appreciable eye candy, and the film also has that irresistible over the top brutality that characterized Seagals' early films. Seagal plays Casey Ryback, a cook aboard the U.S.S. Missouri who must save the day when mercenaries, led by Jones and assisted by disgruntled officer Busey, touch down on the battleship under the guise of a blues band. They quickly take over, but Busey conveniently forgets about Seagal, who's able to slip away and start taking measures to stop the bad guys' plans. Ryback isn't entirely on his own, though, acquiring some companions (including Eleniak, who plays a centerfold hired to jump out of a birthday cake) along the way. Of course, as prepared as these bad guys are, they're no match for this particular cook. Slick as hell, this ass kicking film is consistently fun, perfect popcorn fare with a great pace and a sense of humour about itself. Seagal looks loose and relaxed here; even though he's never been much of an actor, he's always proved quite watchable (at least in his earlier efforts). Busey is a standout among the villains; at one point, he's actually dressed in drag. A *ton* of familiar faces play supporting and small parts: Colm Meaney, Patrick O'Neal, Andy Romano, Nick Mancuso, Troy Evans, Glenn Morshower, Bernie Casey, Raymond Cruz, Duane Davis, George Cheung, Sandy Ward, Michael Des Barres, Dennis Lipscomb, and Dale Dye. There's enough explosions and gunfire to maintain ones' attention, as well as one marvelous and memorable comeuppance for one of the baddies. With a stirring score by Gary Chang as accompaniment, this is rock solid escapism from start to finish, and it's too bad that this level of quality in a Seagal flick wouldn't recur after this. Nine out of 10.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    So this somehow found its way into cinemas
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mutty-mcflea
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Transferring the plot of 'Die Hard' to a battleship more faithfully than most screenwriters adapt novels, 'Pretty Woman' hack J.F. Lawton gives Steven Seagal a cinematic vehicle that's just as bad as all his straight-to-video dreck. Unlike 'Die Hard', this thing is devoid of tension, style and wit, preferring instead to make a lot of noise through various soporific action sequences. Once Seagal's character has finally been let out of that fridge he never worries, never fails, never has to improvise and is consequently never interesting, while sidekick Erika Eleniak stops being engaging as soon as she puts her clothes on and starts asking questions like 'What are they saying?' and 'What's that?' and 'What IS that?' Meanwhile Tommy Lee Jones hams it up to no effect, Andrew Davis's direction is desperately flat and every one-liner gets its very own tumbleweed. Rubbish.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Seagel at his best this film is a high tech laugh and pack of thrills .
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    julesdil
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Lets say this was a good seagel film a thriller and action its very cool in ways . The film was described as die hard on a battle ship no its not die hard is a bad boring film but this is very entertaining .This has thrills , and laughs lots of action which is bad getting killed so its a classic this is simple different 90s action that is very inventive if you want to watch go ahead its an seagal film everyone knows seagal hes just awesome .8.0 out of 10.0 / entertaining film / it does lack brilliance and brill acting although seagal is the highlighlight its still very underrated and great . 15 certificate clearly underrated this is a brutal action film the seagal action ids always brutal . should be 18 for strong brutal action violence , threat and language and some sexual scenes . 7 0ut of 10 for violence can be very bad to viewers . total explitict content 10 out of 100 so it gets little explitict content .
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Lively and Fun
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    leonlouisricci
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is Steven Seagal's most popular film among fans and critics. Although he made some others that are just as good. Above the Law (1988), Out for Justice (1991), and Under Siege 2 (1995). These three are not as slick and audience friendly and have more gritty violence and raw characters. But this movie could be called his most fun. It has a light hearted tone and there is a lot played for laughs by the co-stars and there is much attention given to the ship itself. It is a lively affair with enough ingredients to give everyone a good time, even non-fans of the action star. Overall it is an inoffensive action flick with some big budget gimmicks and fun villains, some very good cinematography, and high powered sound. If you liked this one check out those others for even more entertainment from the whispering martial arts expert.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Die Hard on a battleship!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Tweekums
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/9/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    After being decommissioned in Hawaii the USS Missouri; a colossal battleship is taking its last journey and it won't be plain sailing! To celebrate the captain's fiftieth birthday the Executive Officer, Cmdr. Krill, has arranged a surprise party which is to involve having a band, some caterers and Jordan Tate AKA Miss July 1989 flown in by helicopter. The only problem is that with the exception of Miss Tate none of them is who they seem to be; they, along with Krill, intend to seize the ship along with its tomahawk nuclear missiles. The group is led by former CIA operative William Stranix who was understandably upset when the Agency decided he was no longer required and tried to kill him. When their plan swings into action most of the crew are quickly captured or killed; one exception is Casey Ryback, the chef. Krill has him under marine guard in the galley but he isn't captive for long. Ryback isn't an ordinary cook; he is a former Navy Seal and he is trained for just this sort of problem! Ryback soon finds an ally Jordan Tate! The two of them work to thwart Krill's plans and prevent a nuclear strike against Honolulu! This is a solid action thriller; probably Steven Seagal's best film; certainly the best one I've seen. He plays Ryback and does a pretty good job in the role managing to hold his own against Tommy Lee Jones and Gary Busey who play Stranix and Krill; they are both delightfully over the top villains at one point Busey dons a dress complete with a chest that makes Erika Eleniak, who plays Jordan Tate look small! At first I thought her appearance was just eye-candy and her emerging from a giant cake showing her breasts seemed to confirm this fear; thankfully when she puts some clothes on she made a good character not necessarily believable but fun to watch. The story was pretty good and the action is great without getting too gruesome; there are shootings, knife-fights and explosions to keep things exciting and not too much time is wasted on unnecessary exposition.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Seagal's Best
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Film Flare
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/5/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Well, this film is the height of Seagal's career. The best film he has ever done.....fact! Playing Casey Ryback, the ship's cook, Seagal brings a level of charm, charisma and action man can-do attitude to this film. Aided, of course by beautifully OTT villains, played by the unholy trinity of Tommy Lee Jones, Gary 'Insane in the membrane' Busey and Colm 'DS9' Meaney, they all chew the scenery until their mouths are full. Gary Busey especially excels as the charmless and dangerous Commander Krill (Busey in drag is a scene that highlights his frame of mind). The director, Andrew Davis (who also directed Nico) directs this film with flair and style and commands a not terrible cast to perform well with a run of the mill script. The story is a simple, terrorist highjacking narrative but it is elevated with a cheeky humour, nice little one liners and characters fleshed out a little bit more than you would have expected from a film of this type. Once again, the martial arts and gunfights are well done, there is a knife fight towards the end of the film which is just good and there is no shortage of explosions, creative deaths and gunfire to keep the crowd from noticing a number of plot holes. All in all, a good film. Not even a good film compared to the other Steven Seagal films listed here, it is actually a good film if you're in the mood for, and can tolerate, mindless action.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Best Seagal Film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Marvin Larson
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/3/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Under Siege" packs nonstop action and suspense into two quick hours, and is quite entertaining. Violent and not particularly literary but worthy entry in action genre and realized in &uml;Die hard&uml; style. Wooden Seagal plays the violent Casey Ryback, he cleans up the battleship by means of punches, kicks, bounds and leaps, martial arts skills with fights certainly is slick. The Aikido expert Seagal saves the day in this exciting movie which he also co-produced .In the film appear many secondary roles played by prestigious actors as Patrick O'Neal,Colm Meany, Damian Chapa, Raymond Cruz , Bernie Casey, Nick Mancuso and several others. This elaborately produced action film with two-fisted Seagal is just another action film full of struggles ,thrills, noise and lots of violence. Steven Seagal as almost always, plays a stalwart and lone fighter, BUT, he delivers the goods in his own style full of usual violence and fights with snapping wrists and flying bodies. Unfortunately, these days, a much heftier Seagal does mostly low budget and direct to video garbage , such as &uml;Half past dead&uml;, &uml;The foreigner&uml; and its sequel, &uml;Shadow man &uml;, &uml;Flight of fury&uml;, &uml;Urban justice&uml; and many others.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Terrific Entertainer!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    nama chakravorty
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    'Under Siege' is A Terrific Entertainer, with everything working for it. Tight-Script, Gripping Direction & Fantastic Performances, make 'Under Siege' a must see. 'Under Siege' Synopsis: A former SEAL, now cook, is the only person who can stop a gang of terrorists when they seize control of a US Navy battleship. 'Under Siege' is entertaining & exciting from start to end. It never loses its pace. J. F. Lawton's Screenplay is top-notch. Andrew Davis's Direction is Gripping. Cinematography & Editing are good. Action-Sequences/Stunts are fabulous. Performance-Wise: Steven Seagal delivers a heroic performance. Tommy Lee Jones & Gary Busey are simply Fantastic as the repulsive villains. They both are the real scene-stealer's! Erika Eleniak looks wow & does reasonably well. Others lend support. On the whole, 'Under Siege' is a terrific film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Best of Steven Seagal
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ebiros2
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/11/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie was made when Steven Seagal was at his prime. A group of terrorists highjacks the USS Missouri, and making demands on the US government. It's up to the lowly cook (Steven Seagal) to save the day. This is one of the best movie Steven Seagal made. It's also probably the only big budget movie he's starred in. The best actor in this movie probably is the battleship itself. All the exciting action scenes relates to the workings of this ship. The firing of the Tomahawk missile, and the 16 inch guns. The team of Seagal, Eleniak, and Busey, and Jones were spot on for the act. They chose the right backdrop for the movie. Being inside a battleship makes for many opportunity for good action scenes.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Great action flick
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    sfcat
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I'm really surprised to see such a low average. In my mind, it's Steven Segal's best film, and it's an excellent action movie. It moves at a great pace, the plot is not too trite or unoriginal, especially for the time, and most of it was believable. It's a great popcorn movie! In short, Steven Segal is the captains friend For some reason he's working as ship's cook Something he's good at, but he's been demoted- I don't recall if we ever found out explicitly why, there's some talk of him getting in trouble, but I don't think they tell us the detail. A surprise party goes wrong, so there's a pretty girl involved when everything goes to heck.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Awesome action flick.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Scott LeBrun (Hey_Sweden)
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Let me just join the chorus here in saying that "Under Siege" is definitely the best film of Steven Seagals' career. It benefits from the presence of a genre pro as director, Andrew Davis. He'd previously directed Seagal in "Above the Law", and he shows how well he can handle large scale action and shooting in confined locations. Another plus is more colourful villains than usual, extremely well played by Tommy Lee Jones and Gary Busey; they're both endlessly amusing. Playboy Playmate Erika Eleniak adds appreciable eye candy, and the film also has that irresistible over the top brutality that characterized Seagals' early films. Seagal plays Casey Ryback, a cook aboard the U.S.S. Missouri who must save the day when mercenaries, led by Jones and assisted by disgruntled officer Busey, touch down on the battleship under the guise of a blues band. They quickly take over, but Busey conveniently forgets about Seagal, who's able to slip away and start taking measures to stop the bad guys' plans. Ryback isn't entirely on his own, though, acquiring some companions (including Eleniak, who plays a centerfold hired to jump out of a birthday cake) along the way. Of course, as prepared as these bad guys are, they're no match for this particular cook. Slick as hell, this ass kicking film is consistently fun, perfect popcorn fare with a great pace and a sense of humour about itself. Seagal looks loose and relaxed here; even though he's never been much of an actor, he's always proved quite watchable (at least in his earlier efforts). Busey is a standout among the villains; at one point, he's actually dressed in drag. A *ton* of familiar faces play supporting and small parts: Colm Meaney, Patrick O'Neal, Andy Romano, Nick Mancuso, Troy Evans, Glenn Morshower, Bernie Casey, Raymond Cruz, Duane Davis, George Cheung, Sandy Ward, Michael Des Barres, Dennis Lipscomb, and Dale Dye. There's enough explosions and gunfire to maintain ones' attention, as well as one marvelous and memorable comeuppance for one of the baddies. With a stirring score by Gary Chang as accompaniment, this is rock solid escapism from start to finish, and it's too bad that this level of quality in a Seagal flick wouldn't recur after this. Nine out of 10.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    So this somehow found its way into cinemas
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mutty-mcflea
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Transferring the plot of 'Die Hard' to a battleship more faithfully than most screenwriters adapt novels, 'Pretty Woman' hack J.F. Lawton gives Steven Seagal a cinematic vehicle that's just as bad as all his straight-to-video dreck. Unlike 'Die Hard', this thing is devoid of tension, style and wit, preferring instead to make a lot of noise through various soporific action sequences. Once Seagal's character has finally been let out of that fridge he never worries, never fails, never has to improvise and is consequently never interesting, while sidekick Erika Eleniak stops being engaging as soon as she puts her clothes on and starts asking questions like 'What are they saying?' and 'What's that?' and 'What IS that?' Meanwhile Tommy Lee Jones hams it up to no effect, Andrew Davis's direction is desperately flat and every one-liner gets its very own tumbleweed. Rubbish.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Seagel at his best this film is a high tech laugh and pack of thrills .
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    julesdil
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Lets say this was a good seagel film a thriller and action its very cool in ways . The film was described as die hard on a battle ship no its not die hard is a bad boring film but this is very entertaining .This has thrills , and laughs lots of action which is bad getting killed so its a classic this is simple different 90s action that is very inventive if you want to watch go ahead its an seagal film everyone knows seagal hes just awesome .8.0 out of 10.0 / entertaining film / it does lack brilliance and brill acting although seagal is the highlighlight its still very underrated and great . 15 certificate clearly underrated this is a brutal action film the seagal action ids always brutal . should be 18 for strong brutal action violence , threat and language and some sexual scenes . 7 0ut of 10 for violence can be very bad to viewers . total explitict content 10 out of 100 so it gets little explitict content .
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Lively and Fun
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    leonlouisricci
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is Steven Seagal's most popular film among fans and critics. Although he made some others that are just as good. Above the Law (1988), Out for Justice (1991), and Under Siege 2 (1995). These three are not as slick and audience friendly and have more gritty violence and raw characters. But this movie could be called his most fun. It has a light hearted tone and there is a lot played for laughs by the co-stars and there is much attention given to the ship itself. It is a lively affair with enough ingredients to give everyone a good time, even non-fans of the action star. Overall it is an inoffensive action flick with some big budget gimmicks and fun villains, some very good cinematography, and high powered sound. If you liked this one check out those others for even more entertainment from the whispering martial arts expert.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Die Hard on a battleship!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Tweekums
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/9/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    After being decommissioned in Hawaii the USS Missouri; a colossal battleship is taking its last journey and it won't be plain sailing! To celebrate the captain's fiftieth birthday the Executive Officer, Cmdr. Krill, has arranged a surprise party which is to involve having a band, some caterers and Jordan Tate AKA Miss July 1989 flown in by helicopter. The only problem is that with the exception of Miss Tate none of them is who they seem to be; they, along with Krill, intend to seize the ship along with its tomahawk nuclear missiles. The group is led by former CIA operative William Stranix who was understandably upset when the Agency decided he was no longer required and tried to kill him. When their plan swings into action most of the crew are quickly captured or killed; one exception is Casey Ryback, the chef. Krill has him under marine guard in the galley but he isn't captive for long. Ryback isn't an ordinary cook; he is a former Navy Seal and he is trained for just this sort of problem! Ryback soon finds an ally Jordan Tate! The two of them work to thwart Krill's plans and prevent a nuclear strike against Honolulu! This is a solid action thriller; probably Steven Seagal's best film; certainly the best one I've seen. He plays Ryback and does a pretty good job in the role managing to hold his own against Tommy Lee Jones and Gary Busey who play Stranix and Krill; they are both delightfully over the top villains at one point Busey dons a dress complete with a chest that makes Erika Eleniak, who plays Jordan Tate look small! At first I thought her appearance was just eye-candy and her emerging from a giant cake showing her breasts seemed to confirm this fear; thankfully when she puts some clothes on she made a good character not necessarily believable but fun to watch. The story was pretty good and the action is great without getting too gruesome; there are shootings, knife-fights and explosions to keep things exciting and not too much time is wasted on unnecessary exposition.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Seagal's Best
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Film Flare
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/5/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Well, this film is the height of Seagal's career. The best film he has ever done.....fact! Playing Casey Ryback, the ship's cook, Seagal brings a level of charm, charisma and action man can-do attitude to this film. Aided, of course by beautifully OTT villains, played by the unholy trinity of Tommy Lee Jones, Gary 'Insane in the membrane' Busey and Colm 'DS9' Meaney, they all chew the scenery until their mouths are full. Gary Busey especially excels as the charmless and dangerous Commander Krill (Busey in drag is a scene that highlights his frame of mind). The director, Andrew Davis (who also directed Nico) directs this film with flair and style and commands a not terrible cast to perform well with a run of the mill script. The story is a simple, terrorist highjacking narrative but it is elevated with a cheeky humour, nice little one liners and characters fleshed out a little bit more than you would have expected from a film of this type. Once again, the martial arts and gunfights are well done, there is a knife fight towards the end of the film which is just good and there is no shortage of explosions, creative deaths and gunfire to keep the crowd from noticing a number of plot holes. All in all, a good film. Not even a good film compared to the other Steven Seagal films listed here, it is actually a good film if you're in the mood for, and can tolerate, mindless action.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Best Seagal Film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Marvin Larson
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/3/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Under Siege" packs nonstop action and suspense into two quick hours, and is quite entertaining. Violent and not particularly literary but worthy entry in action genre and realized in &uml;Die hard&uml; style. Wooden Seagal plays the violent Casey Ryback, he cleans up the battleship by means of punches, kicks, bounds and leaps, martial arts skills with fights certainly is slick. The Aikido expert Seagal saves the day in this exciting movie which he also co-produced .In the film appear many secondary roles played by prestigious actors as Patrick O'Neal,Colm Meany, Damian Chapa, Raymond Cruz , Bernie Casey, Nick Mancuso and several others. This elaborately produced action film with two-fisted Seagal is just another action film full of struggles ,thrills, noise and lots of violence. Steven Seagal as almost always, plays a stalwart and lone fighter, BUT, he delivers the goods in his own style full of usual violence and fights with snapping wrists and flying bodies. Unfortunately, these days, a much heftier Seagal does mostly low budget and direct to video garbage , such as &uml;Half past dead&uml;, &uml;The foreigner&uml; and its sequel, &uml;Shadow man &uml;, &uml;Flight of fury&uml;, &uml;Urban justice&uml; and many others.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Terrific Entertainer!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    nama chakravorty
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    'Under Siege' is A Terrific Entertainer, with everything working for it. Tight-Script, Gripping Direction & Fantastic Performances, make 'Under Siege' a must see. 'Under Siege' Synopsis: A former SEAL, now cook, is the only person who can stop a gang of terrorists when they seize control of a US Navy battleship. 'Under Siege' is entertaining & exciting from start to end. It never loses its pace. J. F. Lawton's Screenplay is top-notch. Andrew Davis's Direction is Gripping. Cinematography & Editing are good. Action-Sequences/Stunts are fabulous. Performance-Wise: Steven Seagal delivers a heroic performance. Tommy Lee Jones & Gary Busey are simply Fantastic as the repulsive villains. They both are the real scene-stealer's! Erika Eleniak looks wow & does reasonably well. Others lend support. On the whole, 'Under Siege' is a terrific film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Best of Steven Seagal
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ebiros2
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/11/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie was made when Steven Seagal was at his prime. A group of terrorists highjacks the USS Missouri, and making demands on the US government. It's up to the lowly cook (Steven Seagal) to save the day. This is one of the best movie Steven Seagal made. It's also probably the only big budget movie he's starred in. The best actor in this movie probably is the battleship itself. All the exciting action scenes relates to the workings of this ship. The firing of the Tomahawk missile, and the 16 inch guns. The team of Seagal, Eleniak, and Busey, and Jones were spot on for the act. They chose the right backdrop for the movie. Being inside a battleship makes for many opportunity for good action scenes.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Great action flick
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    sfcat
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I'm really surprised to see such a low average. In my mind, it's Steven Segal's best film, and it's an excellent action movie. It moves at a great pace, the plot is not too trite or unoriginal, especially for the time, and most of it was believable. It's a great popcorn movie! In short, Steven Segal is the captains friend For some reason he's working as ship's cook Something he's good at, but he's been demoted- I don't recall if we ever found out explicitly why, there's some talk of him getting in trouble, but I don't think they tell us the detail. A surprise party goes wrong, so there's a pretty girl involved when everything goes to heck.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Awesome action flick.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Scott LeBrun (Hey_Sweden)
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Let me just join the chorus here in saying that "Under Siege" is definitely the best film of Steven Seagals' career. It benefits from the presence of a genre pro as director, Andrew Davis. He'd previously directed Seagal in "Above the Law", and he shows how well he can handle large scale action and shooting in confined locations. Another plus is more colourful villains than usual, extremely well played by Tommy Lee Jones and Gary Busey; they're both endlessly amusing. Playboy Playmate Erika Eleniak adds appreciable eye candy, and the film also has that irresistible over the top brutality that characterized Seagals' early films. Seagal plays Casey Ryback, a cook aboard the U.S.S. Missouri who must save the day when mercenaries, led by Jones and assisted by disgruntled officer Busey, touch down on the battleship under the guise of a blues band. They quickly take over, but Busey conveniently forgets about Seagal, who's able to slip away and start taking measures to stop the bad guys' plans. Ryback isn't entirely on his own, though, acquiring some companions (including Eleniak, who plays a centerfold hired to jump out of a birthday cake) along the way. Of course, as prepared as these bad guys are, they're no match for this particular cook. Slick as hell, this ass kicking film is consistently fun, perfect popcorn fare with a great pace and a sense of humour about itself. Seagal looks loose and relaxed here; even though he's never been much of an actor, he's always proved quite watchable (at least in his earlier efforts). Busey is a standout among the villains; at one point, he's actually dressed in drag. A *ton* of familiar faces play supporting and small parts: Colm Meaney, Patrick O'Neal, Andy Romano, Nick Mancuso, Troy Evans, Glenn Morshower, Bernie Casey, Raymond Cruz, Duane Davis, George Cheung, Sandy Ward, Michael Des Barres, Dennis Lipscomb, and Dale Dye. There's enough explosions and gunfire to maintain ones' attention, as well as one marvelous and memorable comeuppance for one of the baddies. With a stirring score by Gary Chang as accompaniment, this is rock solid escapism from start to finish, and it's too bad that this level of quality in a Seagal flick wouldn't recur after this. Nine out of 10.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    So this somehow found its way into cinemas
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mutty-mcflea
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Transferring the plot of 'Die Hard' to a battleship more faithfully than most screenwriters adapt novels, 'Pretty Woman' hack J.F. Lawton gives Steven Seagal a cinematic vehicle that's just as bad as all his straight-to-video dreck. Unlike 'Die Hard', this thing is devoid of tension, style and wit, preferring instead to make a lot of noise through various soporific action sequences. Once Seagal's character has finally been let out of that fridge he never worries, never fails, never has to improvise and is consequently never interesting, while sidekick Erika Eleniak stops being engaging as soon as she puts her clothes on and starts asking questions like 'What are they saying?' and 'What's that?' and 'What IS that?' Meanwhile Tommy Lee Jones hams it up to no effect, Andrew Davis's direction is desperately flat and every one-liner gets its very own tumbleweed. Rubbish.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Seagel at his best this film is a high tech laugh and pack of thrills .
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    julesdil
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Lets say this was a good seagel film a thriller and action its very cool in ways . The film was described as die hard on a battle ship no its not die hard is a bad boring film but this is very entertaining .This has thrills , and laughs lots of action which is bad getting killed so its a classic this is simple different 90s action that is very inventive if you want to watch go ahead its an seagal film everyone knows seagal hes just awesome .8.0 out of 10.0 / entertaining film / it does lack brilliance and brill acting although seagal is the highlighlight its still very underrated and great . 15 certificate clearly underrated this is a brutal action film the seagal action ids always brutal . should be 18 for strong brutal action violence , threat and language and some sexual scenes . 7 0ut of 10 for violence can be very bad to viewers . total explitict content 10 out of 100 so it gets little explitict content .
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Lively and Fun
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    leonlouisricci
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is Steven Seagal's most popular film among fans and critics. Although he made some others that are just as good. Above the Law (1988), Out for Justice (1991), and Under Siege 2 (1995). These three are not as slick and audience friendly and have more gritty violence and raw characters. But this movie could be called his most fun. It has a light hearted tone and there is a lot played for laughs by the co-stars and there is much attention given to the ship itself. It is a lively affair with enough ingredients to give everyone a good time, even non-fans of the action star. Overall it is an inoffensive action flick with some big budget gimmicks and fun villains, some very good cinematography, and high powered sound. If you liked this one check out those others for even more entertainment from the whispering martial arts expert.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Die Hard on a battleship!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Tweekums
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/9/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    After being decommissioned in Hawaii the USS Missouri; a colossal battleship is taking its last journey and it won't be plain sailing! To celebrate the captain's fiftieth birthday the Executive Officer, Cmdr. Krill, has arranged a surprise party which is to involve having a band, some caterers and Jordan Tate AKA Miss July 1989 flown in by helicopter. The only problem is that with the exception of Miss Tate none of them is who they seem to be; they, along with Krill, intend to seize the ship along with its tomahawk nuclear missiles. The group is led by former CIA operative William Stranix who was understandably upset when the Agency decided he was no longer required and tried to kill him. When their plan swings into action most of the crew are quickly captured or killed; one exception is Casey Ryback, the chef. Krill has him under marine guard in the galley but he isn't captive for long. Ryback isn't an ordinary cook; he is a former Navy Seal and he is trained for just this sort of problem! Ryback soon finds an ally Jordan Tate! The two of them work to thwart Krill's plans and prevent a nuclear strike against Honolulu! This is a solid action thriller; probably Steven Seagal's best film; certainly the best one I've seen. He plays Ryback and does a pretty good job in the role managing to hold his own against Tommy Lee Jones and Gary Busey who play Stranix and Krill; they are both delightfully over the top villains at one point Busey dons a dress complete with a chest that makes Erika Eleniak, who plays Jordan Tate look small! At first I thought her appearance was just eye-candy and her emerging from a giant cake showing her breasts seemed to confirm this fear; thankfully when she puts some clothes on she made a good character not necessarily believable but fun to watch. The story was pretty good and the action is great without getting too gruesome; there are shootings, knife-fights and explosions to keep things exciting and not too much time is wasted on unnecessary exposition.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Seagal's Best
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Film Flare
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/5/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Well, this film is the height of Seagal's career. The best film he has ever done.....fact! Playing Casey Ryback, the ship's cook, Seagal brings a level of charm, charisma and action man can-do attitude to this film. Aided, of course by beautifully OTT villains, played by the unholy trinity of Tommy Lee Jones, Gary 'Insane in the membrane' Busey and Colm 'DS9' Meaney, they all chew the scenery until their mouths are full. Gary Busey especially excels as the charmless and dangerous Commander Krill (Busey in drag is a scene that highlights his frame of mind). The director, Andrew Davis (who also directed Nico) directs this film with flair and style and commands a not terrible cast to perform well with a run of the mill script. The story is a simple, terrorist highjacking narrative but it is elevated with a cheeky humour, nice little one liners and characters fleshed out a little bit more than you would have expected from a film of this type. Once again, the martial arts and gunfights are well done, there is a knife fight towards the end of the film which is just good and there is no shortage of explosions, creative deaths and gunfire to keep the crowd from noticing a number of plot holes. All in all, a good film. Not even a good film compared to the other Steven Seagal films listed here, it is actually a good film if you're in the mood for, and can tolerate, mindless action.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Best Seagal Film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Marvin Larson
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/3/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Under Siege" packs nonstop action and suspense into two quick hours, and is quite entertaining. Violent and not particularly literary but worthy entry in action genre and realized in &uml;Die hard&uml; style. Wooden Seagal plays the violent Casey Ryback, he cleans up the battleship by means of punches, kicks, bounds and leaps, martial arts skills with fights certainly is slick. The Aikido expert Seagal saves the day in this exciting movie which he also co-produced .In the film appear many secondary roles played by prestigious actors as Patrick O'Neal,Colm Meany, Damian Chapa, Raymond Cruz , Bernie Casey, Nick Mancuso and several others. This elaborately produced action film with two-fisted Seagal is just another action film full of struggles ,thrills, noise and lots of violence. Steven Seagal as almost always, plays a stalwart and lone fighter, BUT, he delivers the goods in his own style full of usual violence and fights with snapping wrists and flying bodies. Unfortunately, these days, a much heftier Seagal does mostly low budget and direct to video garbage , such as &uml;Half past dead&uml;, &uml;The foreigner&uml; and its sequel, &uml;Shadow man &uml;, &uml;Flight of fury&uml;, &uml;Urban justice&uml; and many others.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Terrific Entertainer!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    nama chakravorty
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    'Under Siege' is A Terrific Entertainer, with everything working for it. Tight-Script, Gripping Direction & Fantastic Performances, make 'Under Siege' a must see. 'Under Siege' Synopsis: A former SEAL, now cook, is the only person who can stop a gang of terrorists when they seize control of a US Navy battleship. 'Under Siege' is entertaining & exciting from start to end. It never loses its pace. J. F. Lawton's Screenplay is top-notch. Andrew Davis's Direction is Gripping. Cinematography & Editing are good. Action-Sequences/Stunts are fabulous. Performance-Wise: Steven Seagal delivers a heroic performance. Tommy Lee Jones & Gary Busey are simply Fantastic as the repulsive villains. They both are the real scene-stealer's! Erika Eleniak looks wow & does reasonably well. Others lend support. On the whole, 'Under Siege' is a terrific film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Best of Steven Seagal
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ebiros2
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/11/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie was made when Steven Seagal was at his prime. A group of terrorists highjacks the USS Missouri, and making demands on the US government. It's up to the lowly cook (Steven Seagal) to save the day. This is one of the best movie Steven Seagal made. It's also probably the only big budget movie he's starred in. The best actor in this movie probably is the battleship itself. All the exciting action scenes relates to the workings of this ship. The firing of the Tomahawk missile, and the 16 inch guns. The team of Seagal, Eleniak, and Busey, and Jones were spot on for the act. They chose the right backdrop for the movie. Being inside a battleship makes for many opportunity for good action scenes.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Great action flick
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    sfcat
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I'm really surprised to see such a low average. In my mind, it's Steven Segal's best film, and it's an excellent action movie. It moves at a great pace, the plot is not too trite or unoriginal, especially for the time, and most of it was believable. It's a great popcorn movie! In short, Steven Segal is the captains friend For some reason he's working as ship's cook Something he's good at, but he's been demoted- I don't recall if we ever found out explicitly why, there's some talk of him getting in trouble, but I don't think they tell us the detail. A surprise party goes wrong, so there's a pretty girl involved when everything goes to heck.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Awesome action flick.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Scott LeBrun (Hey_Sweden)
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Let me just join the chorus here in saying that "Under Siege" is definitely the best film of Steven Seagals' career. It benefits from the presence of a genre pro as director, Andrew Davis. He'd previously directed Seagal in "Above the Law", and he shows how well he can handle large scale action and shooting in confined locations. Another plus is more colourful villains than usual, extremely well played by Tommy Lee Jones and Gary Busey; they're both endlessly amusing. Playboy Playmate Erika Eleniak adds appreciable eye candy, and the film also has that irresistible over the top brutality that characterized Seagals' early films. Seagal plays Casey Ryback, a cook aboard the U.S.S. Missouri who must save the day when mercenaries, led by Jones and assisted by disgruntled officer Busey, touch down on the battleship under the guise of a blues band. They quickly take over, but Busey conveniently forgets about Seagal, who's able to slip away and start taking measures to stop the bad guys' plans. Ryback isn't entirely on his own, though, acquiring some companions (including Eleniak, who plays a centerfold hired to jump out of a birthday cake) along the way. Of course, as prepared as these bad guys are, they're no match for this particular cook. Slick as hell, this ass kicking film is consistently fun, perfect popcorn fare with a great pace and a sense of humour about itself. Seagal looks loose and relaxed here; even though he's never been much of an actor, he's always proved quite watchable (at least in his earlier efforts). Busey is a standout among the villains; at one point, he's actually dressed in drag. A *ton* of familiar faces play supporting and small parts: Colm Meaney, Patrick O'Neal, Andy Romano, Nick Mancuso, Troy Evans, Glenn Morshower, Bernie Casey, Raymond Cruz, Duane Davis, George Cheung, Sandy Ward, Michael Des Barres, Dennis Lipscomb, and Dale Dye. There's enough explosions and gunfire to maintain ones' attention, as well as one marvelous and memorable comeuppance for one of the baddies. With a stirring score by Gary Chang as accompaniment, this is rock solid escapism from start to finish, and it's too bad that this level of quality in a Seagal flick wouldn't recur after this. Nine out of 10.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    So this somehow found its way into cinemas
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mutty-mcflea
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Transferring the plot of 'Die Hard' to a battleship more faithfully than most screenwriters adapt novels, 'Pretty Woman' hack J.F. Lawton gives Steven Seagal a cinematic vehicle that's just as bad as all his straight-to-video dreck. Unlike 'Die Hard', this thing is devoid of tension, style and wit, preferring instead to make a lot of noise through various soporific action sequences. Once Seagal's character has finally been let out of that fridge he never worries, never fails, never has to improvise and is consequently never interesting, while sidekick Erika Eleniak stops being engaging as soon as she puts her clothes on and starts asking questions like 'What are they saying?' and 'What's that?' and 'What IS that?' Meanwhile Tommy Lee Jones hams it up to no effect, Andrew Davis's direction is desperately flat and every one-liner gets its very own tumbleweed. Rubbish.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Seagel at his best this film is a high tech laugh and pack of thrills .
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    julesdil
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Lets say this was a good seagel film a thriller and action its very cool in ways . The film was described as die hard on a battle ship no its not die hard is a bad boring film but this is very entertaining .This has thrills , and laughs lots of action which is bad getting killed so its a classic this is simple different 90s action that is very inventive if you want to watch go ahead its an seagal film everyone knows seagal hes just awesome .8.0 out of 10.0 / entertaining film / it does lack brilliance and brill acting although seagal is the highlighlight its still very underrated and great . 15 certificate clearly underrated this is a brutal action film the seagal action ids always brutal . should be 18 for strong brutal action violence , threat and language and some sexual scenes . 7 0ut of 10 for violence can be very bad to viewers . total explitict content 10 out of 100 so it gets little explitict content .
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Lively and Fun
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    leonlouisricci
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is Steven Seagal's most popular film among fans and critics. Although he made some others that are just as good. Above the Law (1988), Out for Justice (1991), and Under Siege 2 (1995). These three are not as slick and audience friendly and have more gritty violence and raw characters. But this movie could be called his most fun. It has a light hearted tone and there is a lot played for laughs by the co-stars and there is much attention given to the ship itself. It is a lively affair with enough ingredients to give everyone a good time, even non-fans of the action star. Overall it is an inoffensive action flick with some big budget gimmicks and fun villains, some very good cinematography, and high powered sound. If you liked this one check out those others for even more entertainment from the whispering martial arts expert.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Die Hard on a battleship!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Tweekums
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/9/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    After being decommissioned in Hawaii the USS Missouri; a colossal battleship is taking its last journey and it won't be plain sailing! To celebrate the captain's fiftieth birthday the Executive Officer, Cmdr. Krill, has arranged a surprise party which is to involve having a band, some caterers and Jordan Tate AKA Miss July 1989 flown in by helicopter. The only problem is that with the exception of Miss Tate none of them is who they seem to be; they, along with Krill, intend to seize the ship along with its tomahawk nuclear missiles. The group is led by former CIA operative William Stranix who was understandably upset when the Agency decided he was no longer required and tried to kill him. When their plan swings into action most of the crew are quickly captured or killed; one exception is Casey Ryback, the chef. Krill has him under marine guard in the galley but he isn't captive for long. Ryback isn't an ordinary cook; he is a former Navy Seal and he is trained for just this sort of problem! Ryback soon finds an ally Jordan Tate! The two of them work to thwart Krill's plans and prevent a nuclear strike against Honolulu! This is a solid action thriller; probably Steven Seagal's best film; certainly the best one I've seen. He plays Ryback and does a pretty good job in the role managing to hold his own against Tommy Lee Jones and Gary Busey who play Stranix and Krill; they are both delightfully over the top villains at one point Busey dons a dress complete with a chest that makes Erika Eleniak, who plays Jordan Tate look small! At first I thought her appearance was just eye-candy and her emerging from a giant cake showing her breasts seemed to confirm this fear; thankfully when she puts some clothes on she made a good character not necessarily believable but fun to watch. The story was pretty good and the action is great without getting too gruesome; there are shootings, knife-fights and explosions to keep things exciting and not too much time is wasted on unnecessary exposition.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Seagal's Best
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Film Flare
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/5/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Well, this film is the height of Seagal's career. The best film he has ever done.....fact! Playing Casey Ryback, the ship's cook, Seagal brings a level of charm, charisma and action man can-do attitude to this film. Aided, of course by beautifully OTT villains, played by the unholy trinity of Tommy Lee Jones, Gary 'Insane in the membrane' Busey and Colm 'DS9' Meaney, they all chew the scenery until their mouths are full. Gary Busey especially excels as the charmless and dangerous Commander Krill (Busey in drag is a scene that highlights his frame of mind). The director, Andrew Davis (who also directed Nico) directs this film with flair and style and commands a not terrible cast to perform well with a run of the mill script. The story is a simple, terrorist highjacking narrative but it is elevated with a cheeky humour, nice little one liners and characters fleshed out a little bit more than you would have expected from a film of this type. Once again, the martial arts and gunfights are well done, there is a knife fight towards the end of the film which is just good and there is no shortage of explosions, creative deaths and gunfire to keep the crowd from noticing a number of plot holes. All in all, a good film. Not even a good film compared to the other Steven Seagal films listed here, it is actually a good film if you're in the mood for, and can tolerate, mindless action.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Best Seagal Film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Marvin Larson
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/3/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Under Siege" packs nonstop action and suspense into two quick hours, and is quite entertaining. Violent and not particularly literary but worthy entry in action genre and realized in &uml;Die hard&uml; style. Wooden Seagal plays the violent Casey Ryback, he cleans up the battleship by means of punches, kicks, bounds and leaps, martial arts skills with fights certainly is slick. The Aikido expert Seagal saves the day in this exciting movie which he also co-produced .In the film appear many secondary roles played by prestigious actors as Patrick O'Neal,Colm Meany, Damian Chapa, Raymond Cruz , Bernie Casey, Nick Mancuso and several others. This elaborately produced action film with two-fisted Seagal is just another action film full of struggles ,thrills, noise and lots of violence. Steven Seagal as almost always, plays a stalwart and lone fighter, BUT, he delivers the goods in his own style full of usual violence and fights with snapping wrists and flying bodies. Unfortunately, these days, a much heftier Seagal does mostly low budget and direct to video garbage , such as &uml;Half past dead&uml;, &uml;The foreigner&uml; and its sequel, &uml;Shadow man &uml;, &uml;Flight of fury&uml;, &uml;Urban justice&uml; and many others.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Terrific Entertainer!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    nama chakravorty
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    'Under Siege' is A Terrific Entertainer, with everything working for it. Tight-Script, Gripping Direction & Fantastic Performances, make 'Under Siege' a must see. 'Under Siege' Synopsis: A former SEAL, now cook, is the only person who can stop a gang of terrorists when they seize control of a US Navy battleship. 'Under Siege' is entertaining & exciting from start to end. It never loses its pace. J. F. Lawton's Screenplay is top-notch. Andrew Davis's Direction is Gripping. Cinematography & Editing are good. Action-Sequences/Stunts are fabulous. Performance-Wise: Steven Seagal delivers a heroic performance. Tommy Lee Jones & Gary Busey are simply Fantastic as the repulsive villains. They both are the real scene-stealer's! Erika Eleniak looks wow & does reasonably well. Others lend support. On the whole, 'Under Siege' is a terrific film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Best of Steven Seagal
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ebiros2
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/11/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie was made when Steven Seagal was at his prime. A group of terrorists highjacks the USS Missouri, and making demands on the US government. It's up to the lowly cook (Steven Seagal) to save the day. This is one of the best movie Steven Seagal made. It's also probably the only big budget movie he's starred in. The best actor in this movie probably is the battleship itself. All the exciting action scenes relates to the workings of this ship. The firing of the Tomahawk missile, and the 16 inch guns. The team of Seagal, Eleniak, and Busey, and Jones were spot on for the act. They chose the right backdrop for the movie. Being inside a battleship makes for many opportunity for good action scenes.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Great action flick
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    sfcat
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I'm really surprised to see such a low average. In my mind, it's Steven Segal's best film, and it's an excellent action movie. It moves at a great pace, the plot is not too trite or unoriginal, especially for the time, and most of it was believable. It's a great popcorn movie! In short, Steven Segal is the captains friend For some reason he's working as ship's cook Something he's good at, but he's been demoted- I don't recall if we ever found out explicitly why, there's some talk of him getting in trouble, but I don't think they tell us the detail. A surprise party goes wrong, so there's a pretty girl involved when everything goes to heck.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Awesome action flick.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Scott LeBrun (Hey_Sweden)
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Let me just join the chorus here in saying that "Under Siege" is definitely the best film of Steven Seagals' career. It benefits from the presence of a genre pro as director, Andrew Davis. He'd previously directed Seagal in "Above the Law", and he shows how well he can handle large scale action and shooting in confined locations. Another plus is more colourful villains than usual, extremely well played by Tommy Lee Jones and Gary Busey; they're both endlessly amusing. Playboy Playmate Erika Eleniak adds appreciable eye candy, and the film also has that irresistible over the top brutality that characterized Seagals' early films. Seagal plays Casey Ryback, a cook aboard the U.S.S. Missouri who must save the day when mercenaries, led by Jones and assisted by disgruntled officer Busey, touch down on the battleship under the guise of a blues band. They quickly take over, but Busey conveniently forgets about Seagal, who's able to slip away and start taking measures to stop the bad guys' plans. Ryback isn't entirely on his own, though, acquiring some companions (including Eleniak, who plays a centerfold hired to jump out of a birthday cake) along the way. Of course, as prepared as these bad guys are, they're no match for this particular cook. Slick as hell, this ass kicking film is consistently fun, perfect popcorn fare with a great pace and a sense of humour about itself. Seagal looks loose and relaxed here; even though he's never been much of an actor, he's always proved quite watchable (at least in his earlier efforts). Busey is a standout among the villains; at one point, he's actually dressed in drag. A *ton* of familiar faces play supporting and small parts: Colm Meaney, Patrick O'Neal, Andy Romano, Nick Mancuso, Troy Evans, Glenn Morshower, Bernie Casey, Raymond Cruz, Duane Davis, George Cheung, Sandy Ward, Michael Des Barres, Dennis Lipscomb, and Dale Dye. There's enough explosions and gunfire to maintain ones' attention, as well as one marvelous and memorable comeuppance for one of the baddies. With a stirring score by Gary Chang as accompaniment, this is rock solid escapism from start to finish, and it's too bad that this level of quality in a Seagal flick wouldn't recur after this. Nine out of 10.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    So this somehow found its way into cinemas
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mutty-mcflea
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Transferring the plot of 'Die Hard' to a battleship more faithfully than most screenwriters adapt novels, 'Pretty Woman' hack J.F. Lawton gives Steven Seagal a cinematic vehicle that's just as bad as all his straight-to-video dreck. Unlike 'Die Hard', this thing is devoid of tension, style and wit, preferring instead to make a lot of noise through various soporific action sequences. Once Seagal's character has finally been let out of that fridge he never worries, never fails, never has to improvise and is consequently never interesting, while sidekick Erika Eleniak stops being engaging as soon as she puts her clothes on and starts asking questions like 'What are they saying?' and 'What's that?' and 'What IS that?' Meanwhile Tommy Lee Jones hams it up to no effect, Andrew Davis's direction is desperately flat and every one-liner gets its very own tumbleweed. Rubbish.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Seagel at his best this film is a high tech laugh and pack of thrills .
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    julesdil
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Lets say this was a good seagel film a thriller and action its very cool in ways . The film was described as die hard on a battle ship no its not die hard is a bad boring film but this is very entertaining .This has thrills , and laughs lots of action which is bad getting killed so its a classic this is simple different 90s action that is very inventive if you want to watch go ahead its an seagal film everyone knows seagal hes just awesome .8.0 out of 10.0 / entertaining film / it does lack brilliance and brill acting although seagal is the highlighlight its still very underrated and great . 15 certificate clearly underrated this is a brutal action film the seagal action ids always brutal . should be 18 for strong brutal action violence , threat and language and some sexual scenes . 7 0ut of 10 for violence can be very bad to viewers . total explitict content 10 out of 100 so it gets little explitict content .
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Lively and Fun
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    leonlouisricci
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is Steven Seagal's most popular film among fans and critics. Although he made some others that are just as good. Above the Law (1988), Out for Justice (1991), and Under Siege 2 (1995). These three are not as slick and audience friendly and have more gritty violence and raw characters. But this movie could be called his most fun. It has a light hearted tone and there is a lot played for laughs by the co-stars and there is much attention given to the ship itself. It is a lively affair with enough ingredients to give everyone a good time, even non-fans of the action star. Overall it is an inoffensive action flick with some big budget gimmicks and fun villains, some very good cinematography, and high powered sound. If you liked this one check out those others for even more entertainment from the whispering martial arts expert.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Die Hard on a battleship!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Tweekums
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/9/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    After being decommissioned in Hawaii the USS Missouri; a colossal battleship is taking its last journey and it won't be plain sailing! To celebrate the captain's fiftieth birthday the Executive Officer, Cmdr. Krill, has arranged a surprise party which is to involve having a band, some caterers and Jordan Tate AKA Miss July 1989 flown in by helicopter. The only problem is that with the exception of Miss Tate none of them is who they seem to be; they, along with Krill, intend to seize the ship along with its tomahawk nuclear missiles. The group is led by former CIA operative William Stranix who was understandably upset when the Agency decided he was no longer required and tried to kill him. When their plan swings into action most of the crew are quickly captured or killed; one exception is Casey Ryback, the chef. Krill has him under marine guard in the galley but he isn't captive for long. Ryback isn't an ordinary cook; he is a former Navy Seal and he is trained for just this sort of problem! Ryback soon finds an ally Jordan Tate! The two of them work to thwart Krill's plans and prevent a nuclear strike against Honolulu! This is a solid action thriller; probably Steven Seagal's best film; certainly the best one I've seen. He plays Ryback and does a pretty good job in the role managing to hold his own against Tommy Lee Jones and Gary Busey who play Stranix and Krill; they are both delightfully over the top villains at one point Busey dons a dress complete with a chest that makes Erika Eleniak, who plays Jordan Tate look small! At first I thought her appearance was just eye-candy and her emerging from a giant cake showing her breasts seemed to confirm this fear; thankfully when she puts some clothes on she made a good character not necessarily believable but fun to watch. The story was pretty good and the action is great without getting too gruesome; there are shootings, knife-fights and explosions to keep things exciting and not too much time is wasted on unnecessary exposition.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Seagal's Best
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Film Flare
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/5/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Well, this film is the height of Seagal's career. The best film he has ever done.....fact! Playing Casey Ryback, the ship's cook, Seagal brings a level of charm, charisma and action man can-do attitude to this film. Aided, of course by beautifully OTT villains, played by the unholy trinity of Tommy Lee Jones, Gary 'Insane in the membrane' Busey and Colm 'DS9' Meaney, they all chew the scenery until their mouths are full. Gary Busey especially excels as the charmless and dangerous Commander Krill (Busey in drag is a scene that highlights his frame of mind). The director, Andrew Davis (who also directed Nico) directs this film with flair and style and commands a not terrible cast to perform well with a run of the mill script. The story is a simple, terrorist highjacking narrative but it is elevated with a cheeky humour, nice little one liners and characters fleshed out a little bit more than you would have expected from a film of this type. Once again, the martial arts and gunfights are well done, there is a knife fight towards the end of the film which is just good and there is no shortage of explosions, creative deaths and gunfire to keep the crowd from noticing a number of plot holes. All in all, a good film. Not even a good film compared to the other Steven Seagal films listed here, it is actually a good film if you're in the mood for, and can tolerate, mindless action.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Best Seagal Film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Marvin Larson
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/3/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Under Siege" packs nonstop action and suspense into two quick hours, and is quite entertaining. Violent and not particularly literary but worthy entry in action genre and realized in &uml;Die hard&uml; style. Wooden Seagal plays the violent Casey Ryback, he cleans up the battleship by means of punches, kicks, bounds and leaps, martial arts skills with fights certainly is slick. The Aikido expert Seagal saves the day in this exciting movie which he also co-produced .In the film appear many secondary roles played by prestigious actors as Patrick O'Neal,Colm Meany, Damian Chapa, Raymond Cruz , Bernie Casey, Nick Mancuso and several others. This elaborately produced action film with two-fisted Seagal is just another action film full of struggles ,thrills, noise and lots of violence. Steven Seagal as almost always, plays a stalwart and lone fighter, BUT, he delivers the goods in his own style full of usual violence and fights with snapping wrists and flying bodies. Unfortunately, these days, a much heftier Seagal does mostly low budget and direct to video garbage , such as &uml;Half past dead&uml;, &uml;The foreigner&uml; and its sequel, &uml;Shadow man &uml;, &uml;Flight of fury&uml;, &uml;Urban justice&uml; and many others.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Terrific Entertainer!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    nama chakravorty
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    'Under Siege' is A Terrific Entertainer, with everything working for it. Tight-Script, Gripping Direction & Fantastic Performances, make 'Under Siege' a must see. 'Under Siege' Synopsis: A former SEAL, now cook, is the only person who can stop a gang of terrorists when they seize control of a US Navy battleship. 'Under Siege' is entertaining & exciting from start to end. It never loses its pace. J. F. Lawton's Screenplay is top-notch. Andrew Davis's Direction is Gripping. Cinematography & Editing are good. Action-Sequences/Stunts are fabulous. Performance-Wise: Steven Seagal delivers a heroic performance. Tommy Lee Jones & Gary Busey are simply Fantastic as the repulsive villains. They both are the real scene-stealer's! Erika Eleniak looks wow & does reasonably well. Others lend support. On the whole, 'Under Siege' is a terrific film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Best of Steven Seagal
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ebiros2
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/11/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie was made when Steven Seagal was at his prime. A group of terrorists highjacks the USS Missouri, and making demands on the US government. It's up to the lowly cook (Steven Seagal) to save the day. This is one of the best movie Steven Seagal made. It's also probably the only big budget movie he's starred in. The best actor in this movie probably is the battleship itself. All the exciting action scenes relates to the workings of this ship. The firing of the Tomahawk missile, and the 16 inch guns. The team of Seagal, Eleniak, and Busey, and Jones were spot on for the act. They chose the right backdrop for the movie. Being inside a battleship makes for many opportunity for good action scenes.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Great action flick
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    sfcat
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I'm really surprised to see such a low average. In my mind, it's Steven Segal's best film, and it's an excellent action movie. It moves at a great pace, the plot is not too trite or unoriginal, especially for the time, and most of it was believable. It's a great popcorn movie! In short, Steven Segal is the captains friend For some reason he's working as ship's cook Something he's good at, but he's been demoted- I don't recall if we ever found out explicitly why, there's some talk of him getting in trouble, but I don't think they tell us the detail. A surprise party goes wrong, so there's a pretty girl involved when everything goes to heck.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Awesome action flick.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Scott LeBrun (Hey_Sweden)
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Let me just join the chorus here in saying that "Under Siege" is definitely the best film of Steven Seagals' career. It benefits from the presence of a genre pro as director, Andrew Davis. He'd previously directed Seagal in "Above the Law", and he shows how well he can handle large scale action and shooting in confined locations. Another plus is more colourful villains than usual, extremely well played by Tommy Lee Jones and Gary Busey; they're both endlessly amusing. Playboy Playmate Erika Eleniak adds appreciable eye candy, and the film also has that irresistible over the top brutality that characterized Seagals' early films. Seagal plays Casey Ryback, a cook aboard the U.S.S. Missouri who must save the day when mercenaries, led by Jones and assisted by disgruntled officer Busey, touch down on the battleship under the guise of a blues band. They quickly take over, but Busey conveniently forgets about Seagal, who's able to slip away and start taking measures to stop the bad guys' plans. Ryback isn't entirely on his own, though, acquiring some companions (including Eleniak, who plays a centerfold hired to jump out of a birthday cake) along the way. Of course, as prepared as these bad guys are, they're no match for this particular cook. Slick as hell, this ass kicking film is consistently fun, perfect popcorn fare with a great pace and a sense of humour about itself. Seagal looks loose and relaxed here; even though he's never been much of an actor, he's always proved quite watchable (at least in his earlier efforts). Busey is a standout among the villains; at one point, he's actually dressed in drag. A *ton* of familiar faces play supporting and small parts: Colm Meaney, Patrick O'Neal, Andy Romano, Nick Mancuso, Troy Evans, Glenn Morshower, Bernie Casey, Raymond Cruz, Duane Davis, George Cheung, Sandy Ward, Michael Des Barres, Dennis Lipscomb, and Dale Dye. There's enough explosions and gunfire to maintain ones' attention, as well as one marvelous and memorable comeuppance for one of the baddies. With a stirring score by Gary Chang as accompaniment, this is rock solid escapism from start to finish, and it's too bad that this level of quality in a Seagal flick wouldn't recur after this. Nine out of 10.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    So this somehow found its way into cinemas
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mutty-mcflea
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Transferring the plot of 'Die Hard' to a battleship more faithfully than most screenwriters adapt novels, 'Pretty Woman' hack J.F. Lawton gives Steven Seagal a cinematic vehicle that's just as bad as all his straight-to-video dreck. Unlike 'Die Hard', this thing is devoid of tension, style and wit, preferring instead to make a lot of noise through various soporific action sequences. Once Seagal's character has finally been let out of that fridge he never worries, never fails, never has to improvise and is consequently never interesting, while sidekick Erika Eleniak stops being engaging as soon as she puts her clothes on and starts asking questions like 'What are they saying?' and 'What's that?' and 'What IS that?' Meanwhile Tommy Lee Jones hams it up to no effect, Andrew Davis's direction is desperately flat and every one-liner gets its very own tumbleweed. Rubbish.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Seagel at his best this film is a high tech laugh and pack of thrills .
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    julesdil
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Lets say this was a good seagel film a thriller and action its very cool in ways . The film was described as die hard on a battle ship no its not die hard is a bad boring film but this is very entertaining .This has thrills , and laughs lots of action which is bad getting killed so its a classic this is simple different 90s action that is very inventive if you want to watch go ahead its an seagal film everyone knows seagal hes just awesome .8.0 out of 10.0 / entertaining film / it does lack brilliance and brill acting although seagal is the highlighlight its still very underrated and great . 15 certificate clearly underrated this is a brutal action film the seagal action ids always brutal . should be 18 for strong brutal action violence , threat and language and some sexual scenes . 7 0ut of 10 for violence can be very bad to viewers . total explitict content 10 out of 100 so it gets little explitict content .
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Lively and Fun
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    leonlouisricci
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is Steven Seagal's most popular film among fans and critics. Although he made some others that are just as good. Above the Law (1988), Out for Justice (1991), and Under Siege 2 (1995). These three are not as slick and audience friendly and have more gritty violence and raw characters. But this movie could be called his most fun. It has a light hearted tone and there is a lot played for laughs by the co-stars and there is much attention given to the ship itself. It is a lively affair with enough ingredients to give everyone a good time, even non-fans of the action star. Overall it is an inoffensive action flick with some big budget gimmicks and fun villains, some very good cinematography, and high powered sound. If you liked this one check out those others for even more entertainment from the whispering martial arts expert.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Die Hard on a battleship!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Tweekums
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/9/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    After being decommissioned in Hawaii the USS Missouri; a colossal battleship is taking its last journey and it won't be plain sailing! To celebrate the captain's fiftieth birthday the Executive Officer, Cmdr. Krill, has arranged a surprise party which is to involve having a band, some caterers and Jordan Tate AKA Miss July 1989 flown in by helicopter. The only problem is that with the exception of Miss Tate none of them is who they seem to be; they, along with Krill, intend to seize the ship along with its tomahawk nuclear missiles. The group is led by former CIA operative William Stranix who was understandably upset when the Agency decided he was no longer required and tried to kill him. When their plan swings into action most of the crew are quickly captured or killed; one exception is Casey Ryback, the chef. Krill has him under marine guard in the galley but he isn't captive for long. Ryback isn't an ordinary cook; he is a former Navy Seal and he is trained for just this sort of problem! Ryback soon finds an ally Jordan Tate! The two of them work to thwart Krill's plans and prevent a nuclear strike against Honolulu! This is a solid action thriller; probably Steven Seagal's best film; certainly the best one I've seen. He plays Ryback and does a pretty good job in the role managing to hold his own against Tommy Lee Jones and Gary Busey who play Stranix and Krill; they are both delightfully over the top villains at one point Busey dons a dress complete with a chest that makes Erika Eleniak, who plays Jordan Tate look small! At first I thought her appearance was just eye-candy and her emerging from a giant cake showing her breasts seemed to confirm this fear; thankfully when she puts some clothes on she made a good character not necessarily believable but fun to watch. The story was pretty good and the action is great without getting too gruesome; there are shootings, knife-fights and explosions to keep things exciting and not too much time is wasted on unnecessary exposition.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Seagal's Best
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Film Flare
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/5/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Well, this film is the height of Seagal's career. The best film he has ever done.....fact! Playing Casey Ryback, the ship's cook, Seagal brings a level of charm, charisma and action man can-do attitude to this film. Aided, of course by beautifully OTT villains, played by the unholy trinity of Tommy Lee Jones, Gary 'Insane in the membrane' Busey and Colm 'DS9' Meaney, they all chew the scenery until their mouths are full. Gary Busey especially excels as the charmless and dangerous Commander Krill (Busey in drag is a scene that highlights his frame of mind). The director, Andrew Davis (who also directed Nico) directs this film with flair and style and commands a not terrible cast to perform well with a run of the mill script. The story is a simple, terrorist highjacking narrative but it is elevated with a cheeky humour, nice little one liners and characters fleshed out a little bit more than you would have expected from a film of this type. Once again, the martial arts and gunfights are well done, there is a knife fight towards the end of the film which is just good and there is no shortage of explosions, creative deaths and gunfire to keep the crowd from noticing a number of plot holes. All in all, a good film. Not even a good film compared to the other Steven Seagal films listed here, it is actually a good film if you're in the mood for, and can tolerate, mindless action.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Best Seagal Film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Marvin Larson
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/3/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Under Siege" packs nonstop action and suspense into two quick hours, and is quite entertaining. Violent and not particularly literary but worthy entry in action genre and realized in &uml;Die hard&uml; style. Wooden Seagal plays the violent Casey Ryback, he cleans up the battleship by means of punches, kicks, bounds and leaps, martial arts skills with fights certainly is slick. The Aikido expert Seagal saves the day in this exciting movie which he also co-produced .In the film appear many secondary roles played by prestigious actors as Patrick O'Neal,Colm Meany, Damian Chapa, Raymond Cruz , Bernie Casey, Nick Mancuso and several others. This elaborately produced action film with two-fisted Seagal is just another action film full of struggles ,thrills, noise and lots of violence. Steven Seagal as almost always, plays a stalwart and lone fighter, BUT, he delivers the goods in his own style full of usual violence and fights with snapping wrists and flying bodies. Unfortunately, these days, a much heftier Seagal does mostly low budget and direct to video garbage , such as &uml;Half past dead&uml;, &uml;The foreigner&uml; and its sequel, &uml;Shadow man &uml;, &uml;Flight of fury&uml;, &uml;Urban justice&uml; and many others.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Terrific Entertainer!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    nama chakravorty
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    'Under Siege' is A Terrific Entertainer, with everything working for it. Tight-Script, Gripping Direction & Fantastic Performances, make 'Under Siege' a must see. 'Under Siege' Synopsis: A former SEAL, now cook, is the only person who can stop a gang of terrorists when they seize control of a US Navy battleship. 'Under Siege' is entertaining & exciting from start to end. It never loses its pace. J. F. Lawton's Screenplay is top-notch. Andrew Davis's Direction is Gripping. Cinematography & Editing are good. Action-Sequences/Stunts are fabulous. Performance-Wise: Steven Seagal delivers a heroic performance. Tommy Lee Jones & Gary Busey are simply Fantastic as the repulsive villains. They both are the real scene-stealer's! Erika Eleniak looks wow & does reasonably well. Others lend support. On the whole, 'Under Siege' is a terrific film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Best of Steven Seagal
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ebiros2
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/11/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie was made when Steven Seagal was at his prime. A group of terrorists highjacks the USS Missouri, and making demands on the US government. It's up to the lowly cook (Steven Seagal) to save the day. This is one of the best movie Steven Seagal made. It's also probably the only big budget movie he's starred in. The best actor in this movie probably is the battleship itself. All the exciting action scenes relates to the workings of this ship. The firing of the Tomahawk missile, and the 16 inch guns. The team of Seagal, Eleniak, and Busey, and Jones were spot on for the act. They chose the right backdrop for the movie. Being inside a battleship makes for many opportunity for good action scenes.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Great action flick
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    sfcat
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I'm really surprised to see such a low average. In my mind, it's Steven Segal's best film, and it's an excellent action movie. It moves at a great pace, the plot is not too trite or unoriginal, especially for the time, and most of it was believable. It's a great popcorn movie! In short, Steven Segal is the captains friend For some reason he's working as ship's cook Something he's good at, but he's been demoted- I don't recall if we ever found out explicitly why, there's some talk of him getting in trouble, but I don't think they tell us the detail. A surprise party goes wrong, so there's a pretty girl involved when everything goes to heck.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Awesome action flick.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Scott LeBrun (Hey_Sweden)
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Let me just join the chorus here in saying that "Under Siege" is definitely the best film of Steven Seagals' career. It benefits from the presence of a genre pro as director, Andrew Davis. He'd previously directed Seagal in "Above the Law", and he shows how well he can handle large scale action and shooting in confined locations. Another plus is more colourful villains than usual, extremely well played by Tommy Lee Jones and Gary Busey; they're both endlessly amusing. Playboy Playmate Erika Eleniak adds appreciable eye candy, and the film also has that irresistible over the top brutality that characterized Seagals' early films. Seagal plays Casey Ryback, a cook aboard the U.S.S. Missouri who must save the day when mercenaries, led by Jones and assisted by disgruntled officer Busey, touch down on the battleship under the guise of a blues band. They quickly take over, but Busey conveniently forgets about Seagal, who's able to slip away and start taking measures to stop the bad guys' plans. Ryback isn't entirely on his own, though, acquiring some companions (including Eleniak, who plays a centerfold hired to jump out of a birthday cake) along the way. Of course, as prepared as these bad guys are, they're no match for this particular cook. Slick as hell, this ass kicking film is consistently fun, perfect popcorn fare with a great pace and a sense of humour about itself. Seagal looks loose and relaxed here; even though he's never been much of an actor, he's always proved quite watchable (at least in his earlier efforts). Busey is a standout among the villains; at one point, he's actually dressed in drag. A *ton* of familiar faces play supporting and small parts: Colm Meaney, Patrick O'Neal, Andy Romano, Nick Mancuso, Troy Evans, Glenn Morshower, Bernie Casey, Raymond Cruz, Duane Davis, George Cheung, Sandy Ward, Michael Des Barres, Dennis Lipscomb, and Dale Dye. There's enough explosions and gunfire to maintain ones' attention, as well as one marvelous and memorable comeuppance for one of the baddies. With a stirring score by Gary Chang as accompaniment, this is rock solid escapism from start to finish, and it's too bad that this level of quality in a Seagal flick wouldn't recur after this. Nine out of 10.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    So this somehow found its way into cinemas
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mutty-mcflea
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Transferring the plot of 'Die Hard' to a battleship more faithfully than most screenwriters adapt novels, 'Pretty Woman' hack J.F. Lawton gives Steven Seagal a cinematic vehicle that's just as bad as all his straight-to-video dreck. Unlike 'Die Hard', this thing is devoid of tension, style and wit, preferring instead to make a lot of noise through various soporific action sequences. Once Seagal's character has finally been let out of that fridge he never worries, never fails, never has to improvise and is consequently never interesting, while sidekick Erika Eleniak stops being engaging as soon as she puts her clothes on and starts asking questions like 'What are they saying?' and 'What's that?' and 'What IS that?' Meanwhile Tommy Lee Jones hams it up to no effect, Andrew Davis's direction is desperately flat and every one-liner gets its very own tumbleweed. Rubbish.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Seagel at his best this film is a high tech laugh and pack of thrills .
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    julesdil
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Lets say this was a good seagel film a thriller and action its very cool in ways . The film was described as die hard on a battle ship no its not die hard is a bad boring film but this is very entertaining .This has thrills , and laughs lots of action which is bad getting killed so its a classic this is simple different 90s action that is very inventive if you want to watch go ahead its an seagal film everyone knows seagal hes just awesome .8.0 out of 10.0 / entertaining film / it does lack brilliance and brill acting although seagal is the highlighlight its still very underrated and great . 15 certificate clearly underrated this is a brutal action film the seagal action ids always brutal . should be 18 for strong brutal action violence , threat and language and some sexual scenes . 7 0ut of 10 for violence can be very bad to viewers . total explitict content 10 out of 100 so it gets little explitict content .
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Lively and Fun
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    leonlouisricci
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is Steven Seagal's most popular film among fans and critics. Although he made some others that are just as good. Above the Law (1988), Out for Justice (1991), and Under Siege 2 (1995). These three are not as slick and audience friendly and have more gritty violence and raw characters. But this movie could be called his most fun. It has a light hearted tone and there is a lot played for laughs by the co-stars and there is much attention given to the ship itself. It is a lively affair with enough ingredients to give everyone a good time, even non-fans of the action star. Overall it is an inoffensive action flick with some big budget gimmicks and fun villains, some very good cinematography, and high powered sound. If you liked this one check out those others for even more entertainment from the whispering martial arts expert.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Die Hard on a battleship!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Tweekums
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/9/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    After being decommissioned in Hawaii the USS Missouri; a colossal battleship is taking its last journey and it won't be plain sailing! To celebrate the captain's fiftieth birthday the Executive Officer, Cmdr. Krill, has arranged a surprise party which is to involve having a band, some caterers and Jordan Tate AKA Miss July 1989 flown in by helicopter. The only problem is that with the exception of Miss Tate none of them is who they seem to be; they, along with Krill, intend to seize the ship along with its tomahawk nuclear missiles. The group is led by former CIA operative William Stranix who was understandably upset when the Agency decided he was no longer required and tried to kill him. When their plan swings into action most of the crew are quickly captured or killed; one exception is Casey Ryback, the chef. Krill has him under marine guard in the galley but he isn't captive for long. Ryback isn't an ordinary cook; he is a former Navy Seal and he is trained for just this sort of problem! Ryback soon finds an ally Jordan Tate! The two of them work to thwart Krill's plans and prevent a nuclear strike against Honolulu! This is a solid action thriller; probably Steven Seagal's best film; certainly the best one I've seen. He plays Ryback and does a pretty good job in the role managing to hold his own against Tommy Lee Jones and Gary Busey who play Stranix and Krill; they are both delightfully over the top villains at one point Busey dons a dress complete with a chest that makes Erika Eleniak, who plays Jordan Tate look small! At first I thought her appearance was just eye-candy and her emerging from a giant cake showing her breasts seemed to confirm this fear; thankfully when she puts some clothes on she made a good character not necessarily believable but fun to watch. The story was pretty good and the action is great without getting too gruesome; there are shootings, knife-fights and explosions to keep things exciting and not too much time is wasted on unnecessary exposition.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Seagal's Best
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Film Flare
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/5/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Well, this film is the height of Seagal's career. The best film he has ever done.....fact! Playing Casey Ryback, the ship's cook, Seagal brings a level of charm, charisma and action man can-do attitude to this film. Aided, of course by beautifully OTT villains, played by the unholy trinity of Tommy Lee Jones, Gary 'Insane in the membrane' Busey and Colm 'DS9' Meaney, they all chew the scenery until their mouths are full. Gary Busey especially excels as the charmless and dangerous Commander Krill (Busey in drag is a scene that highlights his frame of mind). The director, Andrew Davis (who also directed Nico) directs this film with flair and style and commands a not terrible cast to perform well with a run of the mill script. The story is a simple, terrorist highjacking narrative but it is elevated with a cheeky humour, nice little one liners and characters fleshed out a little bit more than you would have expected from a film of this type. Once again, the martial arts and gunfights are well done, there is a knife fight towards the end of the film which is just good and there is no shortage of explosions, creative deaths and gunfire to keep the crowd from noticing a number of plot holes. All in all, a good film. Not even a good film compared to the other Steven Seagal films listed here, it is actually a good film if you're in the mood for, and can tolerate, mindless action.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Best Seagal Film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Marvin Larson
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/3/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Under Siege" packs nonstop action and suspense into two quick hours, and is quite entertaining. Violent and not particularly literary but worthy entry in action genre and realized in &uml;Die hard&uml; style. Wooden Seagal plays the violent Casey Ryback, he cleans up the battleship by means of punches, kicks, bounds and leaps, martial arts skills with fights certainly is slick. The Aikido expert Seagal saves the day in this exciting movie which he also co-produced .In the film appear many secondary roles played by prestigious actors as Patrick O'Neal,Colm Meany, Damian Chapa, Raymond Cruz , Bernie Casey, Nick Mancuso and several others. This elaborately produced action film with two-fisted Seagal is just another action film full of struggles ,thrills, noise and lots of violence. Steven Seagal as almost always, plays a stalwart and lone fighter, BUT, he delivers the goods in his own style full of usual violence and fights with snapping wrists and flying bodies. Unfortunately, these days, a much heftier Seagal does mostly low budget and direct to video garbage , such as &uml;Half past dead&uml;, &uml;The foreigner&uml; and its sequel, &uml;Shadow man &uml;, &uml;Flight of fury&uml;, &uml;Urban justice&uml; and many others.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Terrific Entertainer!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    nama chakravorty
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    'Under Siege' is A Terrific Entertainer, with everything working for it. Tight-Script, Gripping Direction & Fantastic Performances, make 'Under Siege' a must see. 'Under Siege' Synopsis: A former SEAL, now cook, is the only person who can stop a gang of terrorists when they seize control of a US Navy battleship. 'Under Siege' is entertaining & exciting from start to end. It never loses its pace. J. F. Lawton's Screenplay is top-notch. Andrew Davis's Direction is Gripping. Cinematography & Editing are good. Action-Sequences/Stunts are fabulous. Performance-Wise: Steven Seagal delivers a heroic performance. Tommy Lee Jones & Gary Busey are simply Fantastic as the repulsive villains. They both are the real scene-stealer's! Erika Eleniak looks wow & does reasonably well. Others lend support. On the whole, 'Under Siege' is a terrific film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Best of Steven Seagal
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ebiros2
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/11/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie was made when Steven Seagal was at his prime. A group of terrorists highjacks the USS Missouri, and making demands on the US government. It's up to the lowly cook (Steven Seagal) to save the day. This is one of the best movie Steven Seagal made. It's also probably the only big budget movie he's starred in. The best actor in this movie probably is the battleship itself. All the exciting action scenes relates to the workings of this ship. The firing of the Tomahawk missile, and the 16 inch guns. The team of Seagal, Eleniak, and Busey, and Jones were spot on for the act. They chose the right backdrop for the movie. Being inside a battleship makes for many opportunity for good action scenes.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Great action flick
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    sfcat
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I'm really surprised to see such a low average. In my mind, it's Steven Segal's best film, and it's an excellent action movie. It moves at a great pace, the plot is not too trite or unoriginal, especially for the time, and most of it was believable. It's a great popcorn movie! In short, Steven Segal is the captains friend For some reason he's working as ship's cook Something he's good at, but he's been demoted- I don't recall if we ever found out explicitly why, there's some talk of him getting in trouble, but I don't think they tell us the detail. A surprise party goes wrong, so there's a pretty girl involved when everything goes to heck.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Awesome action flick.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Scott LeBrun (Hey_Sweden)
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Let me just join the chorus here in saying that "Under Siege" is definitely the best film of Steven Seagals' career. It benefits from the presence of a genre pro as director, Andrew Davis. He'd previously directed Seagal in "Above the Law", and he shows how well he can handle large scale action and shooting in confined locations. Another plus is more colourful villains than usual, extremely well played by Tommy Lee Jones and Gary Busey; they're both endlessly amusing. Playboy Playmate Erika Eleniak adds appreciable eye candy, and the film also has that irresistible over the top brutality that characterized Seagals' early films. Seagal plays Casey Ryback, a cook aboard the U.S.S. Missouri who must save the day when mercenaries, led by Jones and assisted by disgruntled officer Busey, touch down on the battleship under the guise of a blues band. They quickly take over, but Busey conveniently forgets about Seagal, who's able to slip away and start taking measures to stop the bad guys' plans. Ryback isn't entirely on his own, though, acquiring some companions (including Eleniak, who plays a centerfold hired to jump out of a birthday cake) along the way. Of course, as prepared as these bad guys are, they're no match for this particular cook. Slick as hell, this ass kicking film is consistently fun, perfect popcorn fare with a great pace and a sense of humour about itself. Seagal looks loose and relaxed here; even though he's never been much of an actor, he's always proved quite watchable (at least in his earlier efforts). Busey is a standout among the villains; at one point, he's actually dressed in drag. A *ton* of familiar faces play supporting and small parts: Colm Meaney, Patrick O'Neal, Andy Romano, Nick Mancuso, Troy Evans, Glenn Morshower, Bernie Casey, Raymond Cruz, Duane Davis, George Cheung, Sandy Ward, Michael Des Barres, Dennis Lipscomb, and Dale Dye. There's enough explosions and gunfire to maintain ones' attention, as well as one marvelous and memorable comeuppance for one of the baddies. With a stirring score by Gary Chang as accompaniment, this is rock solid escapism from start to finish, and it's too bad that this level of quality in a Seagal flick wouldn't recur after this. Nine out of 10.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    So this somehow found its way into cinemas
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mutty-mcflea
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Transferring the plot of 'Die Hard' to a battleship more faithfully than most screenwriters adapt novels, 'Pretty Woman' hack J.F. Lawton gives Steven Seagal a cinematic vehicle that's just as bad as all his straight-to-video dreck. Unlike 'Die Hard', this thing is devoid of tension, style and wit, preferring instead to make a lot of noise through various soporific action sequences. Once Seagal's character has finally been let out of that fridge he never worries, never fails, never has to improvise and is consequently never interesting, while sidekick Erika Eleniak stops being engaging as soon as she puts her clothes on and starts asking questions like 'What are they saying?' and 'What's that?' and 'What IS that?' Meanwhile Tommy Lee Jones hams it up to no effect, Andrew Davis's direction is desperately flat and every one-liner gets its very own tumbleweed. Rubbish.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Seagel at his best this film is a high tech laugh and pack of thrills .
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    julesdil
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Lets say this was a good seagel film a thriller and action its very cool in ways . The film was described as die hard on a battle ship no its not die hard is a bad boring film but this is very entertaining .This has thrills , and laughs lots of action which is bad getting killed so its a classic this is simple different 90s action that is very inventive if you want to watch go ahead its an seagal film everyone knows seagal hes just awesome .8.0 out of 10.0 / entertaining film / it does lack brilliance and brill acting although seagal is the highlighlight its still very underrated and great . 15 certificate clearly underrated this is a brutal action film the seagal action ids always brutal . should be 18 for strong brutal action violence , threat and language and some sexual scenes . 7 0ut of 10 for violence can be very bad to viewers . total explitict content 10 out of 100 so it gets little explitict content .
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Lively and Fun
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    leonlouisricci
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is Steven Seagal's most popular film among fans and critics. Although he made some others that are just as good. Above the Law (1988), Out for Justice (1991), and Under Siege 2 (1995). These three are not as slick and audience friendly and have more gritty violence and raw characters. But this movie could be called his most fun. It has a light hearted tone and there is a lot played for laughs by the co-stars and there is much attention given to the ship itself. It is a lively affair with enough ingredients to give everyone a good time, even non-fans of the action star. Overall it is an inoffensive action flick with some big budget gimmicks and fun villains, some very good cinematography, and high powered sound. If you liked this one check out those others for even more entertainment from the whispering martial arts expert.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Die Hard on a battleship!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Tweekums
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/9/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    After being decommissioned in Hawaii the USS Missouri; a colossal battleship is taking its last journey and it won't be plain sailing! To celebrate the captain's fiftieth birthday the Executive Officer, Cmdr. Krill, has arranged a surprise party which is to involve having a band, some caterers and Jordan Tate AKA Miss July 1989 flown in by helicopter. The only problem is that with the exception of Miss Tate none of them is who they seem to be; they, along with Krill, intend to seize the ship along with its tomahawk nuclear missiles. The group is led by former CIA operative William Stranix who was understandably upset when the Agency decided he was no longer required and tried to kill him. When their plan swings into action most of the crew are quickly captured or killed; one exception is Casey Ryback, the chef. Krill has him under marine guard in the galley but he isn't captive for long. Ryback isn't an ordinary cook; he is a former Navy Seal and he is trained for just this sort of problem! Ryback soon finds an ally Jordan Tate! The two of them work to thwart Krill's plans and prevent a nuclear strike against Honolulu! This is a solid action thriller; probably Steven Seagal's best film; certainly the best one I've seen. He plays Ryback and does a pretty good job in the role managing to hold his own against Tommy Lee Jones and Gary Busey who play Stranix and Krill; they are both delightfully over the top villains at one point Busey dons a dress complete with a chest that makes Erika Eleniak, who plays Jordan Tate look small! At first I thought her appearance was just eye-candy and her emerging from a giant cake showing her breasts seemed to confirm this fear; thankfully when she puts some clothes on she made a good character not necessarily believable but fun to watch. The story was pretty good and the action is great without getting too gruesome; there are shootings, knife-fights and explosions to keep things exciting and not too much time is wasted on unnecessary exposition.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Seagal's Best
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Film Flare
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/5/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Well, this film is the height of Seagal's career. The best film he has ever done.....fact! Playing Casey Ryback, the ship's cook, Seagal brings a level of charm, charisma and action man can-do attitude to this film. Aided, of course by beautifully OTT villains, played by the unholy trinity of Tommy Lee Jones, Gary 'Insane in the membrane' Busey and Colm 'DS9' Meaney, they all chew the scenery until their mouths are full. Gary Busey especially excels as the charmless and dangerous Commander Krill (Busey in drag is a scene that highlights his frame of mind). The director, Andrew Davis (who also directed Nico) directs this film with flair and style and commands a not terrible cast to perform well with a run of the mill script. The story is a simple, terrorist highjacking narrative but it is elevated with a cheeky humour, nice little one liners and characters fleshed out a little bit more than you would have expected from a film of this type. Once again, the martial arts and gunfights are well done, there is a knife fight towards the end of the film which is just good and there is no shortage of explosions, creative deaths and gunfire to keep the crowd from noticing a number of plot holes. All in all, a good film. Not even a good film compared to the other Steven Seagal films listed here, it is actually a good film if you're in the mood for, and can tolerate, mindless action.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Best Seagal Film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Marvin Larson
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/3/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Under Siege" packs nonstop action and suspense into two quick hours, and is quite entertaining. Violent and not particularly literary but worthy entry in action genre and realized in &uml;Die hard&uml; style. Wooden Seagal plays the violent Casey Ryback, he cleans up the battleship by means of punches, kicks, bounds and leaps, martial arts skills with fights certainly is slick. The Aikido expert Seagal saves the day in this exciting movie which he also co-produced .In the film appear many secondary roles played by prestigious actors as Patrick O'Neal,Colm Meany, Damian Chapa, Raymond Cruz , Bernie Casey, Nick Mancuso and several others. This elaborately produced action film with two-fisted Seagal is just another action film full of struggles ,thrills, noise and lots of violence. Steven Seagal as almost always, plays a stalwart and lone fighter, BUT, he delivers the goods in his own style full of usual violence and fights with snapping wrists and flying bodies. Unfortunately, these days, a much heftier Seagal does mostly low budget and direct to video garbage , such as &uml;Half past dead&uml;, &uml;The foreigner&uml; and its sequel, &uml;Shadow man &uml;, &uml;Flight of fury&uml;, &uml;Urban justice&uml; and many others.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Terrific Entertainer!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    nama chakravorty
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    'Under Siege' is A Terrific Entertainer, with everything working for it. Tight-Script, Gripping Direction & Fantastic Performances, make 'Under Siege' a must see. 'Under Siege' Synopsis: A former SEAL, now cook, is the only person who can stop a gang of terrorists when they seize control of a US Navy battleship. 'Under Siege' is entertaining & exciting from start to end. It never loses its pace. J. F. Lawton's Screenplay is top-notch. Andrew Davis's Direction is Gripping. Cinematography & Editing are good. Action-Sequences/Stunts are fabulous. Performance-Wise: Steven Seagal delivers a heroic performance. Tommy Lee Jones & Gary Busey are simply Fantastic as the repulsive villains. They both are the real scene-stealer's! Erika Eleniak looks wow & does reasonably well. Others lend support. On the whole, 'Under Siege' is a terrific film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Best of Steven Seagal
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ebiros2
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/11/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie was made when Steven Seagal was at his prime. A group of terrorists highjacks the USS Missouri, and making demands on the US government. It's up to the lowly cook (Steven Seagal) to save the day. This is one of the best movie Steven Seagal made. It's also probably the only big budget movie he's starred in. The best actor in this movie probably is the battleship itself. All the exciting action scenes relates to the workings of this ship. The firing of the Tomahawk missile, and the 16 inch guns. The team of Seagal, Eleniak, and Busey, and Jones were spot on for the act. They chose the right backdrop for the movie. Being inside a battleship makes for many opportunity for good action scenes.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
 </reviews>
</filme>
