<filme>
 <id>
  235
 </id>
 <imdburl>
  http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0116996
 </imdburl>
 <ano>
  1996
 </ano>
 <titulo>
  Marte Ataca!
 </titulo>
 <rating>
  6.3
 </rating>
 <sinopse>
  The Earth is invaded by Martians with irresistible weapons and a cruel sense of humor.
 </sinopse>
 <storyline>
  It is a normal day for everyone, until the President of the United States announces Martians have been spotted circling Earth. The Martians land and a meeting is arranged, but not everything goes to plan, and the Martians seem to have other plans for Earth. Are they just misunderstood beings or do they really want to destroy all of humanity?
 </storyline>
 <generos>
  <genero>
   Comedy
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Sci-Fi
  </genero>
 </generos>
 <keywords>
  <keyword>
   martian
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   general
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   weapon
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   alien
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   scientist
  </keyword>
 </keywords>
 <diretores>
  <diretor>
   Tim Burton
  </diretor>
 </diretores>
 <escritores>
  <escritor>
   Len Brown
  </escritor>
  <escritor>
   Woody Gelman
  </escritor>
 </escritores>
 <atores>
  <ator>
   Jack Nicholson
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Pierce Brosnan
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Sarah Jessica Parker
  </ator>
 </atores>
 <reviews>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Sci-Fi Satire With A Hidden Agenda
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Dalbert Pringle
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    *Possible Spoilers!* "We come in peace!" Mars Attacks was a totally "cool" way for director Tim Burton to annihilate such despicable big-name actors as Jack Nicholson, Danny DeVito, Jack Black, Sarah Jesica Parker, Glenn Close, Michael J. Fox and Martin Short (Phew! What a list of all-star casualties, eh!?) - And have a helluva lot of fun dong it. I only wish that Burton had also managed to have that annoying flake, Annette Bening, gunned down and vaporized, as well. Hideous-looking alien-bastards from Mars (vicious, cruel, and deceptive), toting insta-fry ray guns, land on Earth, and after hoodwinking the gullible public into thinking that this is a visit of friendship, commence with a horrific attack of mass-destruction, blowing up everything in site to smithereens. Can nothing save Earth from these ugly, bubble-headed, little creeps and their nasty, sadistic destructiveness?? Well, little do these menacing Martian-midgets know that we have discovered our very own secret weapon against them that's even more devastating than all of the nuclear weapons in the world. Yes. Indeed. And, who would've ever thought that Grandma Norris's "Slim Whitman" records would actually serve as our only defense against the Martians and inevitably save the day? I found this Sci-Fi/Comedy/Action film from 1996 to be a really uncharacteristic picture from Tim Burton. Presented as a tribute to 1950's UFO movies, Mars Attacks (with its awesome visual effects) delivers a kooky blend of twisted humor and ultra-violence that, when it works (which is about two-thirds of the time), is guaranteed to put a smile on the face of any fan of B-Movie schlock. P.S. - Yes, I do agree that, when it came to bad taste, Burton certainly did push the limits when he had the Martians perform their head-transplanting job, using Poppy, the cute, little, bug-eyed chihuahua, in their awful experiment.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Good, if a bit overfull
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    pwoodstock23
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Mars Attacks! Is an engaging, funny science fiction film directed by Tim Burton about an alien invasion of Earth from Mars (as the title suggests). Thousands of Flying Saucers appear around Earth, claiming peaceful intentions. Surprising virtually no one, they open fire within 48 hours. The film then follows the president and his immediate inner circle, a few American families, an entrepreneur, a few casino employees and a few others as the deal with this. As you can probably tell, this movie is somewhat bloated character-wise. The movie spends 40 minutes introducing it's many many characters. Many of them go on to serve absolutely no importance (see: Jack Nicholson opening a casino, only for it to blow up, a subplot serving only to give him a second role, or Danny DeVito, who shows up briefly early in the movie, and later comes back only to yell at a few people, plead for his life, and die), but the sheer number of characters keeps it from becoming boring, even when the martians are blowing stuff up for quite a few minutes on end. Director Tim Burton brings his namesake creative imagery here, making the movie's Martians very memorable. For example, when one martian shakes the president's hand, his hand comes of with a long tail, which then impales the president and then extends into the flag of their country, as he falls over onto the war room table, with plenty of miniature UFOs. Oh yeah, spoilers. (pretty much everyone dies) The movie's comedy also keeps it interesting, culminating in a hilarious ending of extreme dues ex machinma played for laughs that is absolutely memorable. Overall, it is a funny, quirky movie that pays tribute to the sci-fi movies of the 50s, both in content and feel, which probably could have cut out a character or two (or maybe three)
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not the satire it wants to be.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Sergeant_Tibbs
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Tim Burton's Mars Attacks! is a homage to 1950s sci-fi that fits in with the ensemble disaster films of the 1990s. I've always been a big fan of Tim Burton, his Big Fish was my first taste of what cinema could be, but even though this film was during the peak of his power, it's still a big let down. It has an insanely huge cast of talent with Jack Nicholson (in two roles), Glenn Close, Natalie Portman, Annette Bening, Michael J. Fox, Danny DeVito, Rod Steiger and many more, all given stock desires and conflicts with none particularly focused on and few resolved. The cast was why I watched it as well as the fact that it's on my watchlist from university in regards to music in film so it was worth watching in some regard but despite my low expectations it was still quite a disappointment. The first half is significantly better than the eye-rolling second, even though not much plot development is made. It's spent slowly setting up all the characters and humanity's reaction to martians. It's quite amusing at times, but never laugh out loud, feeling like it's completely comprised of the quirky side characters of Burton's other films and lacking the protagonist to root for. It's all pretty half decent for what it is, but unfortunately it has horrible and flat special effects which it relies on more than anything. Maybe it was the best of its kind at the time (though Independence Day in the same year was far superior), this is very primitive and most of the time it doesn't look like it belongs in the film's reality. Even some of the non-CGI effects are very poor. Perhaps this was more than Burton could handle or producers intervened, but it doesn't work and he should've tried for a stop motion or puppet effect. It does have some good elements. Danny Elfman's creative score is the biggest part of the homage to the 1950s sci-fi and that music plays a big theme in the story. While the score features the theremin prominently as the alien's signature sound, calling back to The Day The Earth Stood Still, it is the in film pseudo-country music that defeats the aliens. This suggests the idea, regarding pop culture, of what is now considered ordinary, the eeriness of the theremin over the country. However, contrivances in the script are very bothersome and ruin most of its execution. There's little sense of escalation from the first half to the second. It's the cringeworthy comedic and hokey moments in the second half that completely ruin the film and quickly wears out its welcome becoming one awful gag after the other that's doesn't feel like the satire it wants to be. A very weak effort for Burton. 4/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Ridiculous attack, poor film making from Tim Burton
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    aldri-feb
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I used to love watching this movie when I was a kid. I felt the Martians character was creepy and somehow really fun, I watched it over and over again but never got bored. But after about 15 years and watching it again yesterday, my point of view about 'Mars Attacks!' suddenly change. This is a type of movie that gives different impression if you watched it in 1990s and nowadays. May be in 1996 or few years after, 'Mars Attacks!' is still fine and exceptional for viewers but it's boring and silly when viewers watch these days. In other words, this movie gets old for young generation. The storyline itself is more like B-movie. It has no heart and chemistry between their entire casts. I have no idea what was Tim Burton purpose by directing this poor movie. It's one of his worst movie I've ever seen, even worse than 'Dark Shadows'. The only thing that could save this movie is their casts. They didn't act remarkably though but it's fun to see star like Jack Nicholson, Glenn Close, Annette Benning, Pierce Brosnan, Danny De Vito and Michael J. Fox in a movie. And don't forget, it also had young artists that becomes popular these days like Natalie Portman, Jack Black and Sarah Jessica Parker. Overall, 'Mars Attacks!' is not a film that audience would enjoy nowadays, the more years you watch it, the more you dislike this movie. It's different with classic movie like 'Godfather', 'Star Wars' or 'Jurassic Park' that never gets old and everyone could still enjoy even for future generation.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Relax . . . It's Not Supposed To Be High Art!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    capteagen
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I used the summary I did because I get the feeling reading other reviews that people were expecting SFX like those of "Independence Day" or "Alien(s)," etc., and were disappointed in not finding them here. In truth, I believe producer/director Tim Burton and the older cast members in particular knew exactly what they were doing. They directed the film at a general audience to be sure, but also targeted a segment of older viewers like me; the Baby Boomers who came of age at the height of the Cold War and the threat of nuclear annihilation, and/or accidental contamination by nuclear fallout or waste wherein the consequences included things as harmless as "Blinky" the three-eyed fish of The Simpson's fame, to atomic mutations on steroids such as the giant ants in the 50s thriller, "Them." I am the quintessential member of that target audience; I'm 57 years old, male, and grew-up on a diet of Saturday afternoon and "late, late show" television that often included a healthy (or unhealthy depending upon one's views) dose of 1950s SciFi "classics," such as "Earth vs. The Flying Saucers", "War of the Worlds", "The Day The Earth Stood Still", the aforementioned "Them", "I Married A Monster From Outer Space", "The Thing From Another World", and others. Those were the high quality films; those with good scripts, good acting (e.g. Michael Rennie, Patricia Neal, etc.), and enjoyable, if not exactly believable, story lines. Then there were those of much lower quality, e.g. "Zontar, Thing From Venus", "Beast With A Million Eyes", "The Crawling Eye" (known in the UK as "The Trollenberg Terror"), and others. The thing is, at the time people of my generation loved them all, regardless of quality. They were escapist fun, period; and sometimes the cheesier they were, e.g. "Plan Nine From Outer Space," the better. One suspects that Tim Burton, two years younger than me, wasted a lot of Saturday afternoon watching such fare. We know Steven Spielberg did because he said so! Regardless, what Burton and the cast have done is that they created a very tongue-in-cheek and very campy homage to the entire 1950s SciFi genre. I don't want to be a spoiler but suffice it to say that there are sly, and some not so sly, allusions to much of the finest in 1950s schlock. I don't think this next observation will spoil anything, but perhaps one of the most significant, and I believe heartfelt, references to yesteryear is the appearance of the Martian "flying saucers." They clearly are meant to honor the work of the late Ray Harryhausen, the master of stop-action photography. Ray died only last month (May 7, 2013) at the age of 92, but his work as director, cinematographer, and special effects coordinator in such films as "Clash of the Titans", "Jason and the Argonauts", "It Came from Beneath the Sea", and "Earth vs. the Flying Saucers" just to name few, was considered to be the high tech leading edge of SFX in its time. Before the advent of today's computer generated wonders, Ray was a true wizard and even though computer generated graphics are used here, Burton's crew made the saucers look like the work of stop-action photography, which had to be something of a labor of love. In any event, while it may not be the be all and end all of film making, the movie nonetheless accomplishes it's goal of sort of taking us back to a somewhat simpler time, and doing it with equal parts humor and loving attention to cheesy detail.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Ahhhhhhhhh! Mars Attacks!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tbills2
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Okaaaay, aaaand 50,000 points is awarded to Mars Attacks!, for having the awesomest cast of A-list actors in all of movie history! DING * DING * DING * DING * DING * DING * DING Congratulations, Mars Attacks! Here now to claim their prize on the behalf of the filmmakers, please give a warm, Earthly welcome to the Martian Ambassador, from Mars! ACK! ACK! ACK! ACK! Wait, no! Audience, watch out! Get out of here, quick! Ahhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhh! Let's work our way through these top stars, shall we - Jack Nicholson is the coolest actor in Hollywood. Natalie Portman is the starlet of her generation. Glenn Close possesses such a prominent prestige. Annette Bening is peppy and very fine. The smart and sleek Pierce Brosnan who is oh so dashing. The greatly adored Michael J. Fox. America's Sweetheart, Sarah Jessica Parker. Danny DeVito, don't count him out. The strong and sexy Pam Grier. The endearingly hilarious Martin Short, who is so endearingly hilarious. The largely exuberant Jack Black. The rambunctiously sweet Christina Applegate. The greatest man in Vegas, Tom Jones. And the greatest football running-back, Jim Brown. Not too shabby, and you might even recognize a few more familiar faces. Let's work our way through their performances, shall we - Nicholson is purely Jack, 'nough said. Natalie Portman is too good. Close can overact with the best of 'em. Bening is endlessly appealing as a free spirit. Mr. Brosnan insists on pleasing. Michael J. Fox is really good at summoning his inner jerk. Sarah J. is too intelligent to act so witless. DeVito is noticeable even among the biggest stars. Pam Grier is openly big-hearted as she strengthens her legacy as an actress. Marty Short bares a comical confidence. Jack Black has a lot to give and seems preparing for fame. Christina Applegate is briefly buoyant. Tom Jones should stick to singing. And Jim Brown is actually pretty darn decent, he steals the spotlight. Mars Attacks! has good effects, considerable entertainment value, and it is pieced together nicely. Tim Burton loves to take every opportunity to delve into the dark arts, but his talents are best served on the lighter side, case in point, this and Edward Scissorhands.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    You kind of know where Tim Burton was going with it.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Jonny 99
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Tim Burton used his star power to assemble one of the highest power casts you'll see in a mid 90's film. Unfortunately, he doesn't give them that much to do. "Mars Attacks" much like "The Informant!" plays like a joke that doesn't provoke laughter as much as it does a sense of knowing where Burton was going with the film. Basically, he tries to lampoon the 1950's creature feature film particularly "The Day the Earth Stood Still" but an underlying Burton-ian meanspiritness and tendency toward strong violence sucks much of the fun out of the film. The writers provide only a modest amount of fun from which to take leaving Burton to rely on CGI red-spangled speedos on the Martians and the stuntcasting - including Tom Jones wasted by simply playing himself - to push the movie along. Burton cross the spoof line in a few spots and instead simply lifts ideas from much better films particularly Rod Steiger's General Decker a copy of George C Scott General Turgidson from "Dr. Stangelove." The plagiarism serves not as homage but as a sign that you could be watching a much better film. In short, better parody of the same material exists elsewhere.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A pretty good black comedy with Martians and a beautiful ensemble of characters
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Augusta Melbourne
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This stylistic feature of black comedy has put quite a mark on reflecting and perhaps parodying America's attitudes towards culture and materialism. The fact that the design of the UFOs and Martians were less shoddy and more of what we think of them means that it helps to look at these in terms of our assumptions. A great ensemble of character with their own time to shine, the comedy is affectionate as well as outrageous. It's not meant to be predictable, it's the fact that the characters should have seen this one coming. Also, this parody of clich&eacute;s and laughable scenes of science fiction from 1950's B movies should be more recognised. The glitzy costumes and visual flair isn't there just to look at.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of Tim Burton's best.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Alex Holland
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Tim Burton, has done many movies in his career but his funniest film to date is "Mars Attacks". The film is a love letter/spoof of the 50's era of sci-fi B movies,(which viewed today would be laughable). The plot is pretty paper thin but too be honest it's a Tim Burton movie. A group of cruel and tasteless aliens decide to destroy the earth for shits and giggles. While the army and a gong ho general want to nuke the aliens, the president and his peace loving professor want earth and mars to coincide but the aliens don't really care as they enjoy defacing famous landmarks and killing innocent people. The genius of Mars Attacks is that it's a comedy,while most alien invasion films are serious and depressing, Mars Attacks makes fun of the fact that it's a bad movie and does it perfectly. The cast is really second to none,Jack Nicholson is great as both the President and as sleezy alcholic casino owner Art Land. Other cast members include, Glenn Close as a bitchy first lady,Pierce Brosnan as a professor for the white house that wants to analyze and have peace with the martians,Danny Devito as a rude gambler, and even a young Jack Black as a redneck soldier. Mars Attacks is a very smart and funny movie because it doesn't takes itself seriously. I know Tim Burton never talks about this movie, but I think that he should be proud of one of the funniest spoofs ever made.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    ACK ACK ACK (Translated) "Do Not Run We Are Your Friends"
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    leonlouisricci
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    There is just one scene after another that is a colorful, bizarre, twisted and unique Tim Burton vision of life, here, and on Mars. The movie never lets up and is based on the equally colorful and beautifully bent trading cards put out by Topps in 1962 painted by the great Pulp artist Norm Saunders. The film is a faithful adaptation and includes most of the card images all presented in sharp primary colors and given a respectful representation. This is a top notch Black Comedy that is funny, violent, and irreverent. It is favorably factitious and an amazing adventure with a lurid and gross artistic quality associated with the Director's style and in-sensibilities. The stellar cast is not necessary but all seem to be having a lot of fun. The visuals are the star and the script is less impressive, but the overall effect is cutting edge cinema that has an appeal for the slightly off key karma of the underground but marketed for the main stream. The film's detractors are left with not much to complain about (but they do) except the movie's brazen belief that it is a design of the different for the norm. But for them it is ridiculed and unappreciated.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Sci-Fi Satire With A Hidden Agenda
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Dalbert Pringle
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    *Possible Spoilers!* "We come in peace!" Mars Attacks was a totally "cool" way for director Tim Burton to annihilate such despicable big-name actors as Jack Nicholson, Danny DeVito, Jack Black, Sarah Jesica Parker, Glenn Close, Michael J. Fox and Martin Short (Phew! What a list of all-star casualties, eh!?) - And have a helluva lot of fun dong it. I only wish that Burton had also managed to have that annoying flake, Annette Bening, gunned down and vaporized, as well. Hideous-looking alien-bastards from Mars (vicious, cruel, and deceptive), toting insta-fry ray guns, land on Earth, and after hoodwinking the gullible public into thinking that this is a visit of friendship, commence with a horrific attack of mass-destruction, blowing up everything in site to smithereens. Can nothing save Earth from these ugly, bubble-headed, little creeps and their nasty, sadistic destructiveness?? Well, little do these menacing Martian-midgets know that we have discovered our very own secret weapon against them that's even more devastating than all of the nuclear weapons in the world. Yes. Indeed. And, who would've ever thought that Grandma Norris's "Slim Whitman" records would actually serve as our only defense against the Martians and inevitably save the day? I found this Sci-Fi/Comedy/Action film from 1996 to be a really uncharacteristic picture from Tim Burton. Presented as a tribute to 1950's UFO movies, Mars Attacks (with its awesome visual effects) delivers a kooky blend of twisted humor and ultra-violence that, when it works (which is about two-thirds of the time), is guaranteed to put a smile on the face of any fan of B-Movie schlock. P.S. - Yes, I do agree that, when it came to bad taste, Burton certainly did push the limits when he had the Martians perform their head-transplanting job, using Poppy, the cute, little, bug-eyed chihuahua, in their awful experiment.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Good, if a bit overfull
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    pwoodstock23
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Mars Attacks! Is an engaging, funny science fiction film directed by Tim Burton about an alien invasion of Earth from Mars (as the title suggests). Thousands of Flying Saucers appear around Earth, claiming peaceful intentions. Surprising virtually no one, they open fire within 48 hours. The film then follows the president and his immediate inner circle, a few American families, an entrepreneur, a few casino employees and a few others as the deal with this. As you can probably tell, this movie is somewhat bloated character-wise. The movie spends 40 minutes introducing it's many many characters. Many of them go on to serve absolutely no importance (see: Jack Nicholson opening a casino, only for it to blow up, a subplot serving only to give him a second role, or Danny DeVito, who shows up briefly early in the movie, and later comes back only to yell at a few people, plead for his life, and die), but the sheer number of characters keeps it from becoming boring, even when the martians are blowing stuff up for quite a few minutes on end. Director Tim Burton brings his namesake creative imagery here, making the movie's Martians very memorable. For example, when one martian shakes the president's hand, his hand comes of with a long tail, which then impales the president and then extends into the flag of their country, as he falls over onto the war room table, with plenty of miniature UFOs. Oh yeah, spoilers. (pretty much everyone dies) The movie's comedy also keeps it interesting, culminating in a hilarious ending of extreme dues ex machinma played for laughs that is absolutely memorable. Overall, it is a funny, quirky movie that pays tribute to the sci-fi movies of the 50s, both in content and feel, which probably could have cut out a character or two (or maybe three)
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not the satire it wants to be.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Sergeant_Tibbs
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Tim Burton's Mars Attacks! is a homage to 1950s sci-fi that fits in with the ensemble disaster films of the 1990s. I've always been a big fan of Tim Burton, his Big Fish was my first taste of what cinema could be, but even though this film was during the peak of his power, it's still a big let down. It has an insanely huge cast of talent with Jack Nicholson (in two roles), Glenn Close, Natalie Portman, Annette Bening, Michael J. Fox, Danny DeVito, Rod Steiger and many more, all given stock desires and conflicts with none particularly focused on and few resolved. The cast was why I watched it as well as the fact that it's on my watchlist from university in regards to music in film so it was worth watching in some regard but despite my low expectations it was still quite a disappointment. The first half is significantly better than the eye-rolling second, even though not much plot development is made. It's spent slowly setting up all the characters and humanity's reaction to martians. It's quite amusing at times, but never laugh out loud, feeling like it's completely comprised of the quirky side characters of Burton's other films and lacking the protagonist to root for. It's all pretty half decent for what it is, but unfortunately it has horrible and flat special effects which it relies on more than anything. Maybe it was the best of its kind at the time (though Independence Day in the same year was far superior), this is very primitive and most of the time it doesn't look like it belongs in the film's reality. Even some of the non-CGI effects are very poor. Perhaps this was more than Burton could handle or producers intervened, but it doesn't work and he should've tried for a stop motion or puppet effect. It does have some good elements. Danny Elfman's creative score is the biggest part of the homage to the 1950s sci-fi and that music plays a big theme in the story. While the score features the theremin prominently as the alien's signature sound, calling back to The Day The Earth Stood Still, it is the in film pseudo-country music that defeats the aliens. This suggests the idea, regarding pop culture, of what is now considered ordinary, the eeriness of the theremin over the country. However, contrivances in the script are very bothersome and ruin most of its execution. There's little sense of escalation from the first half to the second. It's the cringeworthy comedic and hokey moments in the second half that completely ruin the film and quickly wears out its welcome becoming one awful gag after the other that's doesn't feel like the satire it wants to be. A very weak effort for Burton. 4/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Ridiculous attack, poor film making from Tim Burton
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    aldri-feb
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I used to love watching this movie when I was a kid. I felt the Martians character was creepy and somehow really fun, I watched it over and over again but never got bored. But after about 15 years and watching it again yesterday, my point of view about 'Mars Attacks!' suddenly change. This is a type of movie that gives different impression if you watched it in 1990s and nowadays. May be in 1996 or few years after, 'Mars Attacks!' is still fine and exceptional for viewers but it's boring and silly when viewers watch these days. In other words, this movie gets old for young generation. The storyline itself is more like B-movie. It has no heart and chemistry between their entire casts. I have no idea what was Tim Burton purpose by directing this poor movie. It's one of his worst movie I've ever seen, even worse than 'Dark Shadows'. The only thing that could save this movie is their casts. They didn't act remarkably though but it's fun to see star like Jack Nicholson, Glenn Close, Annette Benning, Pierce Brosnan, Danny De Vito and Michael J. Fox in a movie. And don't forget, it also had young artists that becomes popular these days like Natalie Portman, Jack Black and Sarah Jessica Parker. Overall, 'Mars Attacks!' is not a film that audience would enjoy nowadays, the more years you watch it, the more you dislike this movie. It's different with classic movie like 'Godfather', 'Star Wars' or 'Jurassic Park' that never gets old and everyone could still enjoy even for future generation.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Relax . . . It's Not Supposed To Be High Art!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    capteagen
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I used the summary I did because I get the feeling reading other reviews that people were expecting SFX like those of "Independence Day" or "Alien(s)," etc., and were disappointed in not finding them here. In truth, I believe producer/director Tim Burton and the older cast members in particular knew exactly what they were doing. They directed the film at a general audience to be sure, but also targeted a segment of older viewers like me; the Baby Boomers who came of age at the height of the Cold War and the threat of nuclear annihilation, and/or accidental contamination by nuclear fallout or waste wherein the consequences included things as harmless as "Blinky" the three-eyed fish of The Simpson's fame, to atomic mutations on steroids such as the giant ants in the 50s thriller, "Them." I am the quintessential member of that target audience; I'm 57 years old, male, and grew-up on a diet of Saturday afternoon and "late, late show" television that often included a healthy (or unhealthy depending upon one's views) dose of 1950s SciFi "classics," such as "Earth vs. The Flying Saucers", "War of the Worlds", "The Day The Earth Stood Still", the aforementioned "Them", "I Married A Monster From Outer Space", "The Thing From Another World", and others. Those were the high quality films; those with good scripts, good acting (e.g. Michael Rennie, Patricia Neal, etc.), and enjoyable, if not exactly believable, story lines. Then there were those of much lower quality, e.g. "Zontar, Thing From Venus", "Beast With A Million Eyes", "The Crawling Eye" (known in the UK as "The Trollenberg Terror"), and others. The thing is, at the time people of my generation loved them all, regardless of quality. They were escapist fun, period; and sometimes the cheesier they were, e.g. "Plan Nine From Outer Space," the better. One suspects that Tim Burton, two years younger than me, wasted a lot of Saturday afternoon watching such fare. We know Steven Spielberg did because he said so! Regardless, what Burton and the cast have done is that they created a very tongue-in-cheek and very campy homage to the entire 1950s SciFi genre. I don't want to be a spoiler but suffice it to say that there are sly, and some not so sly, allusions to much of the finest in 1950s schlock. I don't think this next observation will spoil anything, but perhaps one of the most significant, and I believe heartfelt, references to yesteryear is the appearance of the Martian "flying saucers." They clearly are meant to honor the work of the late Ray Harryhausen, the master of stop-action photography. Ray died only last month (May 7, 2013) at the age of 92, but his work as director, cinematographer, and special effects coordinator in such films as "Clash of the Titans", "Jason and the Argonauts", "It Came from Beneath the Sea", and "Earth vs. the Flying Saucers" just to name few, was considered to be the high tech leading edge of SFX in its time. Before the advent of today's computer generated wonders, Ray was a true wizard and even though computer generated graphics are used here, Burton's crew made the saucers look like the work of stop-action photography, which had to be something of a labor of love. In any event, while it may not be the be all and end all of film making, the movie nonetheless accomplishes it's goal of sort of taking us back to a somewhat simpler time, and doing it with equal parts humor and loving attention to cheesy detail.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Ahhhhhhhhh! Mars Attacks!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tbills2
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Okaaaay, aaaand 50,000 points is awarded to Mars Attacks!, for having the awesomest cast of A-list actors in all of movie history! DING * DING * DING * DING * DING * DING * DING Congratulations, Mars Attacks! Here now to claim their prize on the behalf of the filmmakers, please give a warm, Earthly welcome to the Martian Ambassador, from Mars! ACK! ACK! ACK! ACK! Wait, no! Audience, watch out! Get out of here, quick! Ahhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhh! Let's work our way through these top stars, shall we - Jack Nicholson is the coolest actor in Hollywood. Natalie Portman is the starlet of her generation. Glenn Close possesses such a prominent prestige. Annette Bening is peppy and very fine. The smart and sleek Pierce Brosnan who is oh so dashing. The greatly adored Michael J. Fox. America's Sweetheart, Sarah Jessica Parker. Danny DeVito, don't count him out. The strong and sexy Pam Grier. The endearingly hilarious Martin Short, who is so endearingly hilarious. The largely exuberant Jack Black. The rambunctiously sweet Christina Applegate. The greatest man in Vegas, Tom Jones. And the greatest football running-back, Jim Brown. Not too shabby, and you might even recognize a few more familiar faces. Let's work our way through their performances, shall we - Nicholson is purely Jack, 'nough said. Natalie Portman is too good. Close can overact with the best of 'em. Bening is endlessly appealing as a free spirit. Mr. Brosnan insists on pleasing. Michael J. Fox is really good at summoning his inner jerk. Sarah J. is too intelligent to act so witless. DeVito is noticeable even among the biggest stars. Pam Grier is openly big-hearted as she strengthens her legacy as an actress. Marty Short bares a comical confidence. Jack Black has a lot to give and seems preparing for fame. Christina Applegate is briefly buoyant. Tom Jones should stick to singing. And Jim Brown is actually pretty darn decent, he steals the spotlight. Mars Attacks! has good effects, considerable entertainment value, and it is pieced together nicely. Tim Burton loves to take every opportunity to delve into the dark arts, but his talents are best served on the lighter side, case in point, this and Edward Scissorhands.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    You kind of know where Tim Burton was going with it.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Jonny 99
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Tim Burton used his star power to assemble one of the highest power casts you'll see in a mid 90's film. Unfortunately, he doesn't give them that much to do. "Mars Attacks" much like "The Informant!" plays like a joke that doesn't provoke laughter as much as it does a sense of knowing where Burton was going with the film. Basically, he tries to lampoon the 1950's creature feature film particularly "The Day the Earth Stood Still" but an underlying Burton-ian meanspiritness and tendency toward strong violence sucks much of the fun out of the film. The writers provide only a modest amount of fun from which to take leaving Burton to rely on CGI red-spangled speedos on the Martians and the stuntcasting - including Tom Jones wasted by simply playing himself - to push the movie along. Burton cross the spoof line in a few spots and instead simply lifts ideas from much better films particularly Rod Steiger's General Decker a copy of George C Scott General Turgidson from "Dr. Stangelove." The plagiarism serves not as homage but as a sign that you could be watching a much better film. In short, better parody of the same material exists elsewhere.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A pretty good black comedy with Martians and a beautiful ensemble of characters
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Augusta Melbourne
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This stylistic feature of black comedy has put quite a mark on reflecting and perhaps parodying America's attitudes towards culture and materialism. The fact that the design of the UFOs and Martians were less shoddy and more of what we think of them means that it helps to look at these in terms of our assumptions. A great ensemble of character with their own time to shine, the comedy is affectionate as well as outrageous. It's not meant to be predictable, it's the fact that the characters should have seen this one coming. Also, this parody of clich&eacute;s and laughable scenes of science fiction from 1950's B movies should be more recognised. The glitzy costumes and visual flair isn't there just to look at.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of Tim Burton's best.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Alex Holland
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Tim Burton, has done many movies in his career but his funniest film to date is "Mars Attacks". The film is a love letter/spoof of the 50's era of sci-fi B movies,(which viewed today would be laughable). The plot is pretty paper thin but too be honest it's a Tim Burton movie. A group of cruel and tasteless aliens decide to destroy the earth for shits and giggles. While the army and a gong ho general want to nuke the aliens, the president and his peace loving professor want earth and mars to coincide but the aliens don't really care as they enjoy defacing famous landmarks and killing innocent people. The genius of Mars Attacks is that it's a comedy,while most alien invasion films are serious and depressing, Mars Attacks makes fun of the fact that it's a bad movie and does it perfectly. The cast is really second to none,Jack Nicholson is great as both the President and as sleezy alcholic casino owner Art Land. Other cast members include, Glenn Close as a bitchy first lady,Pierce Brosnan as a professor for the white house that wants to analyze and have peace with the martians,Danny Devito as a rude gambler, and even a young Jack Black as a redneck soldier. Mars Attacks is a very smart and funny movie because it doesn't takes itself seriously. I know Tim Burton never talks about this movie, but I think that he should be proud of one of the funniest spoofs ever made.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    ACK ACK ACK (Translated) "Do Not Run We Are Your Friends"
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    leonlouisricci
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    There is just one scene after another that is a colorful, bizarre, twisted and unique Tim Burton vision of life, here, and on Mars. The movie never lets up and is based on the equally colorful and beautifully bent trading cards put out by Topps in 1962 painted by the great Pulp artist Norm Saunders. The film is a faithful adaptation and includes most of the card images all presented in sharp primary colors and given a respectful representation. This is a top notch Black Comedy that is funny, violent, and irreverent. It is favorably factitious and an amazing adventure with a lurid and gross artistic quality associated with the Director's style and in-sensibilities. The stellar cast is not necessary but all seem to be having a lot of fun. The visuals are the star and the script is less impressive, but the overall effect is cutting edge cinema that has an appeal for the slightly off key karma of the underground but marketed for the main stream. The film's detractors are left with not much to complain about (but they do) except the movie's brazen belief that it is a design of the different for the norm. But for them it is ridiculed and unappreciated.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Sci-Fi Satire With A Hidden Agenda
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Dalbert Pringle
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    *Possible Spoilers!* "We come in peace!" Mars Attacks was a totally "cool" way for director Tim Burton to annihilate such despicable big-name actors as Jack Nicholson, Danny DeVito, Jack Black, Sarah Jesica Parker, Glenn Close, Michael J. Fox and Martin Short (Phew! What a list of all-star casualties, eh!?) - And have a helluva lot of fun dong it. I only wish that Burton had also managed to have that annoying flake, Annette Bening, gunned down and vaporized, as well. Hideous-looking alien-bastards from Mars (vicious, cruel, and deceptive), toting insta-fry ray guns, land on Earth, and after hoodwinking the gullible public into thinking that this is a visit of friendship, commence with a horrific attack of mass-destruction, blowing up everything in site to smithereens. Can nothing save Earth from these ugly, bubble-headed, little creeps and their nasty, sadistic destructiveness?? Well, little do these menacing Martian-midgets know that we have discovered our very own secret weapon against them that's even more devastating than all of the nuclear weapons in the world. Yes. Indeed. And, who would've ever thought that Grandma Norris's "Slim Whitman" records would actually serve as our only defense against the Martians and inevitably save the day? I found this Sci-Fi/Comedy/Action film from 1996 to be a really uncharacteristic picture from Tim Burton. Presented as a tribute to 1950's UFO movies, Mars Attacks (with its awesome visual effects) delivers a kooky blend of twisted humor and ultra-violence that, when it works (which is about two-thirds of the time), is guaranteed to put a smile on the face of any fan of B-Movie schlock. P.S. - Yes, I do agree that, when it came to bad taste, Burton certainly did push the limits when he had the Martians perform their head-transplanting job, using Poppy, the cute, little, bug-eyed chihuahua, in their awful experiment.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Good, if a bit overfull
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    pwoodstock23
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Mars Attacks! Is an engaging, funny science fiction film directed by Tim Burton about an alien invasion of Earth from Mars (as the title suggests). Thousands of Flying Saucers appear around Earth, claiming peaceful intentions. Surprising virtually no one, they open fire within 48 hours. The film then follows the president and his immediate inner circle, a few American families, an entrepreneur, a few casino employees and a few others as the deal with this. As you can probably tell, this movie is somewhat bloated character-wise. The movie spends 40 minutes introducing it's many many characters. Many of them go on to serve absolutely no importance (see: Jack Nicholson opening a casino, only for it to blow up, a subplot serving only to give him a second role, or Danny DeVito, who shows up briefly early in the movie, and later comes back only to yell at a few people, plead for his life, and die), but the sheer number of characters keeps it from becoming boring, even when the martians are blowing stuff up for quite a few minutes on end. Director Tim Burton brings his namesake creative imagery here, making the movie's Martians very memorable. For example, when one martian shakes the president's hand, his hand comes of with a long tail, which then impales the president and then extends into the flag of their country, as he falls over onto the war room table, with plenty of miniature UFOs. Oh yeah, spoilers. (pretty much everyone dies) The movie's comedy also keeps it interesting, culminating in a hilarious ending of extreme dues ex machinma played for laughs that is absolutely memorable. Overall, it is a funny, quirky movie that pays tribute to the sci-fi movies of the 50s, both in content and feel, which probably could have cut out a character or two (or maybe three)
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not the satire it wants to be.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Sergeant_Tibbs
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Tim Burton's Mars Attacks! is a homage to 1950s sci-fi that fits in with the ensemble disaster films of the 1990s. I've always been a big fan of Tim Burton, his Big Fish was my first taste of what cinema could be, but even though this film was during the peak of his power, it's still a big let down. It has an insanely huge cast of talent with Jack Nicholson (in two roles), Glenn Close, Natalie Portman, Annette Bening, Michael J. Fox, Danny DeVito, Rod Steiger and many more, all given stock desires and conflicts with none particularly focused on and few resolved. The cast was why I watched it as well as the fact that it's on my watchlist from university in regards to music in film so it was worth watching in some regard but despite my low expectations it was still quite a disappointment. The first half is significantly better than the eye-rolling second, even though not much plot development is made. It's spent slowly setting up all the characters and humanity's reaction to martians. It's quite amusing at times, but never laugh out loud, feeling like it's completely comprised of the quirky side characters of Burton's other films and lacking the protagonist to root for. It's all pretty half decent for what it is, but unfortunately it has horrible and flat special effects which it relies on more than anything. Maybe it was the best of its kind at the time (though Independence Day in the same year was far superior), this is very primitive and most of the time it doesn't look like it belongs in the film's reality. Even some of the non-CGI effects are very poor. Perhaps this was more than Burton could handle or producers intervened, but it doesn't work and he should've tried for a stop motion or puppet effect. It does have some good elements. Danny Elfman's creative score is the biggest part of the homage to the 1950s sci-fi and that music plays a big theme in the story. While the score features the theremin prominently as the alien's signature sound, calling back to The Day The Earth Stood Still, it is the in film pseudo-country music that defeats the aliens. This suggests the idea, regarding pop culture, of what is now considered ordinary, the eeriness of the theremin over the country. However, contrivances in the script are very bothersome and ruin most of its execution. There's little sense of escalation from the first half to the second. It's the cringeworthy comedic and hokey moments in the second half that completely ruin the film and quickly wears out its welcome becoming one awful gag after the other that's doesn't feel like the satire it wants to be. A very weak effort for Burton. 4/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Ridiculous attack, poor film making from Tim Burton
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    aldri-feb
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I used to love watching this movie when I was a kid. I felt the Martians character was creepy and somehow really fun, I watched it over and over again but never got bored. But after about 15 years and watching it again yesterday, my point of view about 'Mars Attacks!' suddenly change. This is a type of movie that gives different impression if you watched it in 1990s and nowadays. May be in 1996 or few years after, 'Mars Attacks!' is still fine and exceptional for viewers but it's boring and silly when viewers watch these days. In other words, this movie gets old for young generation. The storyline itself is more like B-movie. It has no heart and chemistry between their entire casts. I have no idea what was Tim Burton purpose by directing this poor movie. It's one of his worst movie I've ever seen, even worse than 'Dark Shadows'. The only thing that could save this movie is their casts. They didn't act remarkably though but it's fun to see star like Jack Nicholson, Glenn Close, Annette Benning, Pierce Brosnan, Danny De Vito and Michael J. Fox in a movie. And don't forget, it also had young artists that becomes popular these days like Natalie Portman, Jack Black and Sarah Jessica Parker. Overall, 'Mars Attacks!' is not a film that audience would enjoy nowadays, the more years you watch it, the more you dislike this movie. It's different with classic movie like 'Godfather', 'Star Wars' or 'Jurassic Park' that never gets old and everyone could still enjoy even for future generation.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Relax . . . It's Not Supposed To Be High Art!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    capteagen
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I used the summary I did because I get the feeling reading other reviews that people were expecting SFX like those of "Independence Day" or "Alien(s)," etc., and were disappointed in not finding them here. In truth, I believe producer/director Tim Burton and the older cast members in particular knew exactly what they were doing. They directed the film at a general audience to be sure, but also targeted a segment of older viewers like me; the Baby Boomers who came of age at the height of the Cold War and the threat of nuclear annihilation, and/or accidental contamination by nuclear fallout or waste wherein the consequences included things as harmless as "Blinky" the three-eyed fish of The Simpson's fame, to atomic mutations on steroids such as the giant ants in the 50s thriller, "Them." I am the quintessential member of that target audience; I'm 57 years old, male, and grew-up on a diet of Saturday afternoon and "late, late show" television that often included a healthy (or unhealthy depending upon one's views) dose of 1950s SciFi "classics," such as "Earth vs. The Flying Saucers", "War of the Worlds", "The Day The Earth Stood Still", the aforementioned "Them", "I Married A Monster From Outer Space", "The Thing From Another World", and others. Those were the high quality films; those with good scripts, good acting (e.g. Michael Rennie, Patricia Neal, etc.), and enjoyable, if not exactly believable, story lines. Then there were those of much lower quality, e.g. "Zontar, Thing From Venus", "Beast With A Million Eyes", "The Crawling Eye" (known in the UK as "The Trollenberg Terror"), and others. The thing is, at the time people of my generation loved them all, regardless of quality. They were escapist fun, period; and sometimes the cheesier they were, e.g. "Plan Nine From Outer Space," the better. One suspects that Tim Burton, two years younger than me, wasted a lot of Saturday afternoon watching such fare. We know Steven Spielberg did because he said so! Regardless, what Burton and the cast have done is that they created a very tongue-in-cheek and very campy homage to the entire 1950s SciFi genre. I don't want to be a spoiler but suffice it to say that there are sly, and some not so sly, allusions to much of the finest in 1950s schlock. I don't think this next observation will spoil anything, but perhaps one of the most significant, and I believe heartfelt, references to yesteryear is the appearance of the Martian "flying saucers." They clearly are meant to honor the work of the late Ray Harryhausen, the master of stop-action photography. Ray died only last month (May 7, 2013) at the age of 92, but his work as director, cinematographer, and special effects coordinator in such films as "Clash of the Titans", "Jason and the Argonauts", "It Came from Beneath the Sea", and "Earth vs. the Flying Saucers" just to name few, was considered to be the high tech leading edge of SFX in its time. Before the advent of today's computer generated wonders, Ray was a true wizard and even though computer generated graphics are used here, Burton's crew made the saucers look like the work of stop-action photography, which had to be something of a labor of love. In any event, while it may not be the be all and end all of film making, the movie nonetheless accomplishes it's goal of sort of taking us back to a somewhat simpler time, and doing it with equal parts humor and loving attention to cheesy detail.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Ahhhhhhhhh! Mars Attacks!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tbills2
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Okaaaay, aaaand 50,000 points is awarded to Mars Attacks!, for having the awesomest cast of A-list actors in all of movie history! DING * DING * DING * DING * DING * DING * DING Congratulations, Mars Attacks! Here now to claim their prize on the behalf of the filmmakers, please give a warm, Earthly welcome to the Martian Ambassador, from Mars! ACK! ACK! ACK! ACK! Wait, no! Audience, watch out! Get out of here, quick! Ahhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhh! Let's work our way through these top stars, shall we - Jack Nicholson is the coolest actor in Hollywood. Natalie Portman is the starlet of her generation. Glenn Close possesses such a prominent prestige. Annette Bening is peppy and very fine. The smart and sleek Pierce Brosnan who is oh so dashing. The greatly adored Michael J. Fox. America's Sweetheart, Sarah Jessica Parker. Danny DeVito, don't count him out. The strong and sexy Pam Grier. The endearingly hilarious Martin Short, who is so endearingly hilarious. The largely exuberant Jack Black. The rambunctiously sweet Christina Applegate. The greatest man in Vegas, Tom Jones. And the greatest football running-back, Jim Brown. Not too shabby, and you might even recognize a few more familiar faces. Let's work our way through their performances, shall we - Nicholson is purely Jack, 'nough said. Natalie Portman is too good. Close can overact with the best of 'em. Bening is endlessly appealing as a free spirit. Mr. Brosnan insists on pleasing. Michael J. Fox is really good at summoning his inner jerk. Sarah J. is too intelligent to act so witless. DeVito is noticeable even among the biggest stars. Pam Grier is openly big-hearted as she strengthens her legacy as an actress. Marty Short bares a comical confidence. Jack Black has a lot to give and seems preparing for fame. Christina Applegate is briefly buoyant. Tom Jones should stick to singing. And Jim Brown is actually pretty darn decent, he steals the spotlight. Mars Attacks! has good effects, considerable entertainment value, and it is pieced together nicely. Tim Burton loves to take every opportunity to delve into the dark arts, but his talents are best served on the lighter side, case in point, this and Edward Scissorhands.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    You kind of know where Tim Burton was going with it.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Jonny 99
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Tim Burton used his star power to assemble one of the highest power casts you'll see in a mid 90's film. Unfortunately, he doesn't give them that much to do. "Mars Attacks" much like "The Informant!" plays like a joke that doesn't provoke laughter as much as it does a sense of knowing where Burton was going with the film. Basically, he tries to lampoon the 1950's creature feature film particularly "The Day the Earth Stood Still" but an underlying Burton-ian meanspiritness and tendency toward strong violence sucks much of the fun out of the film. The writers provide only a modest amount of fun from which to take leaving Burton to rely on CGI red-spangled speedos on the Martians and the stuntcasting - including Tom Jones wasted by simply playing himself - to push the movie along. Burton cross the spoof line in a few spots and instead simply lifts ideas from much better films particularly Rod Steiger's General Decker a copy of George C Scott General Turgidson from "Dr. Stangelove." The plagiarism serves not as homage but as a sign that you could be watching a much better film. In short, better parody of the same material exists elsewhere.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A pretty good black comedy with Martians and a beautiful ensemble of characters
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Augusta Melbourne
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This stylistic feature of black comedy has put quite a mark on reflecting and perhaps parodying America's attitudes towards culture and materialism. The fact that the design of the UFOs and Martians were less shoddy and more of what we think of them means that it helps to look at these in terms of our assumptions. A great ensemble of character with their own time to shine, the comedy is affectionate as well as outrageous. It's not meant to be predictable, it's the fact that the characters should have seen this one coming. Also, this parody of clich&eacute;s and laughable scenes of science fiction from 1950's B movies should be more recognised. The glitzy costumes and visual flair isn't there just to look at.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of Tim Burton's best.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Alex Holland
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Tim Burton, has done many movies in his career but his funniest film to date is "Mars Attacks". The film is a love letter/spoof of the 50's era of sci-fi B movies,(which viewed today would be laughable). The plot is pretty paper thin but too be honest it's a Tim Burton movie. A group of cruel and tasteless aliens decide to destroy the earth for shits and giggles. While the army and a gong ho general want to nuke the aliens, the president and his peace loving professor want earth and mars to coincide but the aliens don't really care as they enjoy defacing famous landmarks and killing innocent people. The genius of Mars Attacks is that it's a comedy,while most alien invasion films are serious and depressing, Mars Attacks makes fun of the fact that it's a bad movie and does it perfectly. The cast is really second to none,Jack Nicholson is great as both the President and as sleezy alcholic casino owner Art Land. Other cast members include, Glenn Close as a bitchy first lady,Pierce Brosnan as a professor for the white house that wants to analyze and have peace with the martians,Danny Devito as a rude gambler, and even a young Jack Black as a redneck soldier. Mars Attacks is a very smart and funny movie because it doesn't takes itself seriously. I know Tim Burton never talks about this movie, but I think that he should be proud of one of the funniest spoofs ever made.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    ACK ACK ACK (Translated) "Do Not Run We Are Your Friends"
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    leonlouisricci
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    There is just one scene after another that is a colorful, bizarre, twisted and unique Tim Burton vision of life, here, and on Mars. The movie never lets up and is based on the equally colorful and beautifully bent trading cards put out by Topps in 1962 painted by the great Pulp artist Norm Saunders. The film is a faithful adaptation and includes most of the card images all presented in sharp primary colors and given a respectful representation. This is a top notch Black Comedy that is funny, violent, and irreverent. It is favorably factitious and an amazing adventure with a lurid and gross artistic quality associated with the Director's style and in-sensibilities. The stellar cast is not necessary but all seem to be having a lot of fun. The visuals are the star and the script is less impressive, but the overall effect is cutting edge cinema that has an appeal for the slightly off key karma of the underground but marketed for the main stream. The film's detractors are left with not much to complain about (but they do) except the movie's brazen belief that it is a design of the different for the norm. But for them it is ridiculed and unappreciated.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Sci-Fi Satire With A Hidden Agenda
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Dalbert Pringle
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    *Possible Spoilers!* "We come in peace!" Mars Attacks was a totally "cool" way for director Tim Burton to annihilate such despicable big-name actors as Jack Nicholson, Danny DeVito, Jack Black, Sarah Jesica Parker, Glenn Close, Michael J. Fox and Martin Short (Phew! What a list of all-star casualties, eh!?) - And have a helluva lot of fun dong it. I only wish that Burton had also managed to have that annoying flake, Annette Bening, gunned down and vaporized, as well. Hideous-looking alien-bastards from Mars (vicious, cruel, and deceptive), toting insta-fry ray guns, land on Earth, and after hoodwinking the gullible public into thinking that this is a visit of friendship, commence with a horrific attack of mass-destruction, blowing up everything in site to smithereens. Can nothing save Earth from these ugly, bubble-headed, little creeps and their nasty, sadistic destructiveness?? Well, little do these menacing Martian-midgets know that we have discovered our very own secret weapon against them that's even more devastating than all of the nuclear weapons in the world. Yes. Indeed. And, who would've ever thought that Grandma Norris's "Slim Whitman" records would actually serve as our only defense against the Martians and inevitably save the day? I found this Sci-Fi/Comedy/Action film from 1996 to be a really uncharacteristic picture from Tim Burton. Presented as a tribute to 1950's UFO movies, Mars Attacks (with its awesome visual effects) delivers a kooky blend of twisted humor and ultra-violence that, when it works (which is about two-thirds of the time), is guaranteed to put a smile on the face of any fan of B-Movie schlock. P.S. - Yes, I do agree that, when it came to bad taste, Burton certainly did push the limits when he had the Martians perform their head-transplanting job, using Poppy, the cute, little, bug-eyed chihuahua, in their awful experiment.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Good, if a bit overfull
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    pwoodstock23
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Mars Attacks! Is an engaging, funny science fiction film directed by Tim Burton about an alien invasion of Earth from Mars (as the title suggests). Thousands of Flying Saucers appear around Earth, claiming peaceful intentions. Surprising virtually no one, they open fire within 48 hours. The film then follows the president and his immediate inner circle, a few American families, an entrepreneur, a few casino employees and a few others as the deal with this. As you can probably tell, this movie is somewhat bloated character-wise. The movie spends 40 minutes introducing it's many many characters. Many of them go on to serve absolutely no importance (see: Jack Nicholson opening a casino, only for it to blow up, a subplot serving only to give him a second role, or Danny DeVito, who shows up briefly early in the movie, and later comes back only to yell at a few people, plead for his life, and die), but the sheer number of characters keeps it from becoming boring, even when the martians are blowing stuff up for quite a few minutes on end. Director Tim Burton brings his namesake creative imagery here, making the movie's Martians very memorable. For example, when one martian shakes the president's hand, his hand comes of with a long tail, which then impales the president and then extends into the flag of their country, as he falls over onto the war room table, with plenty of miniature UFOs. Oh yeah, spoilers. (pretty much everyone dies) The movie's comedy also keeps it interesting, culminating in a hilarious ending of extreme dues ex machinma played for laughs that is absolutely memorable. Overall, it is a funny, quirky movie that pays tribute to the sci-fi movies of the 50s, both in content and feel, which probably could have cut out a character or two (or maybe three)
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not the satire it wants to be.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Sergeant_Tibbs
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Tim Burton's Mars Attacks! is a homage to 1950s sci-fi that fits in with the ensemble disaster films of the 1990s. I've always been a big fan of Tim Burton, his Big Fish was my first taste of what cinema could be, but even though this film was during the peak of his power, it's still a big let down. It has an insanely huge cast of talent with Jack Nicholson (in two roles), Glenn Close, Natalie Portman, Annette Bening, Michael J. Fox, Danny DeVito, Rod Steiger and many more, all given stock desires and conflicts with none particularly focused on and few resolved. The cast was why I watched it as well as the fact that it's on my watchlist from university in regards to music in film so it was worth watching in some regard but despite my low expectations it was still quite a disappointment. The first half is significantly better than the eye-rolling second, even though not much plot development is made. It's spent slowly setting up all the characters and humanity's reaction to martians. It's quite amusing at times, but never laugh out loud, feeling like it's completely comprised of the quirky side characters of Burton's other films and lacking the protagonist to root for. It's all pretty half decent for what it is, but unfortunately it has horrible and flat special effects which it relies on more than anything. Maybe it was the best of its kind at the time (though Independence Day in the same year was far superior), this is very primitive and most of the time it doesn't look like it belongs in the film's reality. Even some of the non-CGI effects are very poor. Perhaps this was more than Burton could handle or producers intervened, but it doesn't work and he should've tried for a stop motion or puppet effect. It does have some good elements. Danny Elfman's creative score is the biggest part of the homage to the 1950s sci-fi and that music plays a big theme in the story. While the score features the theremin prominently as the alien's signature sound, calling back to The Day The Earth Stood Still, it is the in film pseudo-country music that defeats the aliens. This suggests the idea, regarding pop culture, of what is now considered ordinary, the eeriness of the theremin over the country. However, contrivances in the script are very bothersome and ruin most of its execution. There's little sense of escalation from the first half to the second. It's the cringeworthy comedic and hokey moments in the second half that completely ruin the film and quickly wears out its welcome becoming one awful gag after the other that's doesn't feel like the satire it wants to be. A very weak effort for Burton. 4/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Ridiculous attack, poor film making from Tim Burton
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    aldri-feb
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I used to love watching this movie when I was a kid. I felt the Martians character was creepy and somehow really fun, I watched it over and over again but never got bored. But after about 15 years and watching it again yesterday, my point of view about 'Mars Attacks!' suddenly change. This is a type of movie that gives different impression if you watched it in 1990s and nowadays. May be in 1996 or few years after, 'Mars Attacks!' is still fine and exceptional for viewers but it's boring and silly when viewers watch these days. In other words, this movie gets old for young generation. The storyline itself is more like B-movie. It has no heart and chemistry between their entire casts. I have no idea what was Tim Burton purpose by directing this poor movie. It's one of his worst movie I've ever seen, even worse than 'Dark Shadows'. The only thing that could save this movie is their casts. They didn't act remarkably though but it's fun to see star like Jack Nicholson, Glenn Close, Annette Benning, Pierce Brosnan, Danny De Vito and Michael J. Fox in a movie. And don't forget, it also had young artists that becomes popular these days like Natalie Portman, Jack Black and Sarah Jessica Parker. Overall, 'Mars Attacks!' is not a film that audience would enjoy nowadays, the more years you watch it, the more you dislike this movie. It's different with classic movie like 'Godfather', 'Star Wars' or 'Jurassic Park' that never gets old and everyone could still enjoy even for future generation.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Relax . . . It's Not Supposed To Be High Art!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    capteagen
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I used the summary I did because I get the feeling reading other reviews that people were expecting SFX like those of "Independence Day" or "Alien(s)," etc., and were disappointed in not finding them here. In truth, I believe producer/director Tim Burton and the older cast members in particular knew exactly what they were doing. They directed the film at a general audience to be sure, but also targeted a segment of older viewers like me; the Baby Boomers who came of age at the height of the Cold War and the threat of nuclear annihilation, and/or accidental contamination by nuclear fallout or waste wherein the consequences included things as harmless as "Blinky" the three-eyed fish of The Simpson's fame, to atomic mutations on steroids such as the giant ants in the 50s thriller, "Them." I am the quintessential member of that target audience; I'm 57 years old, male, and grew-up on a diet of Saturday afternoon and "late, late show" television that often included a healthy (or unhealthy depending upon one's views) dose of 1950s SciFi "classics," such as "Earth vs. The Flying Saucers", "War of the Worlds", "The Day The Earth Stood Still", the aforementioned "Them", "I Married A Monster From Outer Space", "The Thing From Another World", and others. Those were the high quality films; those with good scripts, good acting (e.g. Michael Rennie, Patricia Neal, etc.), and enjoyable, if not exactly believable, story lines. Then there were those of much lower quality, e.g. "Zontar, Thing From Venus", "Beast With A Million Eyes", "The Crawling Eye" (known in the UK as "The Trollenberg Terror"), and others. The thing is, at the time people of my generation loved them all, regardless of quality. They were escapist fun, period; and sometimes the cheesier they were, e.g. "Plan Nine From Outer Space," the better. One suspects that Tim Burton, two years younger than me, wasted a lot of Saturday afternoon watching such fare. We know Steven Spielberg did because he said so! Regardless, what Burton and the cast have done is that they created a very tongue-in-cheek and very campy homage to the entire 1950s SciFi genre. I don't want to be a spoiler but suffice it to say that there are sly, and some not so sly, allusions to much of the finest in 1950s schlock. I don't think this next observation will spoil anything, but perhaps one of the most significant, and I believe heartfelt, references to yesteryear is the appearance of the Martian "flying saucers." They clearly are meant to honor the work of the late Ray Harryhausen, the master of stop-action photography. Ray died only last month (May 7, 2013) at the age of 92, but his work as director, cinematographer, and special effects coordinator in such films as "Clash of the Titans", "Jason and the Argonauts", "It Came from Beneath the Sea", and "Earth vs. the Flying Saucers" just to name few, was considered to be the high tech leading edge of SFX in its time. Before the advent of today's computer generated wonders, Ray was a true wizard and even though computer generated graphics are used here, Burton's crew made the saucers look like the work of stop-action photography, which had to be something of a labor of love. In any event, while it may not be the be all and end all of film making, the movie nonetheless accomplishes it's goal of sort of taking us back to a somewhat simpler time, and doing it with equal parts humor and loving attention to cheesy detail.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Ahhhhhhhhh! Mars Attacks!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tbills2
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Okaaaay, aaaand 50,000 points is awarded to Mars Attacks!, for having the awesomest cast of A-list actors in all of movie history! DING * DING * DING * DING * DING * DING * DING Congratulations, Mars Attacks! Here now to claim their prize on the behalf of the filmmakers, please give a warm, Earthly welcome to the Martian Ambassador, from Mars! ACK! ACK! ACK! ACK! Wait, no! Audience, watch out! Get out of here, quick! Ahhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhh! Let's work our way through these top stars, shall we - Jack Nicholson is the coolest actor in Hollywood. Natalie Portman is the starlet of her generation. Glenn Close possesses such a prominent prestige. Annette Bening is peppy and very fine. The smart and sleek Pierce Brosnan who is oh so dashing. The greatly adored Michael J. Fox. America's Sweetheart, Sarah Jessica Parker. Danny DeVito, don't count him out. The strong and sexy Pam Grier. The endearingly hilarious Martin Short, who is so endearingly hilarious. The largely exuberant Jack Black. The rambunctiously sweet Christina Applegate. The greatest man in Vegas, Tom Jones. And the greatest football running-back, Jim Brown. Not too shabby, and you might even recognize a few more familiar faces. Let's work our way through their performances, shall we - Nicholson is purely Jack, 'nough said. Natalie Portman is too good. Close can overact with the best of 'em. Bening is endlessly appealing as a free spirit. Mr. Brosnan insists on pleasing. Michael J. Fox is really good at summoning his inner jerk. Sarah J. is too intelligent to act so witless. DeVito is noticeable even among the biggest stars. Pam Grier is openly big-hearted as she strengthens her legacy as an actress. Marty Short bares a comical confidence. Jack Black has a lot to give and seems preparing for fame. Christina Applegate is briefly buoyant. Tom Jones should stick to singing. And Jim Brown is actually pretty darn decent, he steals the spotlight. Mars Attacks! has good effects, considerable entertainment value, and it is pieced together nicely. Tim Burton loves to take every opportunity to delve into the dark arts, but his talents are best served on the lighter side, case in point, this and Edward Scissorhands.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    You kind of know where Tim Burton was going with it.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Jonny 99
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Tim Burton used his star power to assemble one of the highest power casts you'll see in a mid 90's film. Unfortunately, he doesn't give them that much to do. "Mars Attacks" much like "The Informant!" plays like a joke that doesn't provoke laughter as much as it does a sense of knowing where Burton was going with the film. Basically, he tries to lampoon the 1950's creature feature film particularly "The Day the Earth Stood Still" but an underlying Burton-ian meanspiritness and tendency toward strong violence sucks much of the fun out of the film. The writers provide only a modest amount of fun from which to take leaving Burton to rely on CGI red-spangled speedos on the Martians and the stuntcasting - including Tom Jones wasted by simply playing himself - to push the movie along. Burton cross the spoof line in a few spots and instead simply lifts ideas from much better films particularly Rod Steiger's General Decker a copy of George C Scott General Turgidson from "Dr. Stangelove." The plagiarism serves not as homage but as a sign that you could be watching a much better film. In short, better parody of the same material exists elsewhere.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A pretty good black comedy with Martians and a beautiful ensemble of characters
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Augusta Melbourne
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This stylistic feature of black comedy has put quite a mark on reflecting and perhaps parodying America's attitudes towards culture and materialism. The fact that the design of the UFOs and Martians were less shoddy and more of what we think of them means that it helps to look at these in terms of our assumptions. A great ensemble of character with their own time to shine, the comedy is affectionate as well as outrageous. It's not meant to be predictable, it's the fact that the characters should have seen this one coming. Also, this parody of clich&eacute;s and laughable scenes of science fiction from 1950's B movies should be more recognised. The glitzy costumes and visual flair isn't there just to look at.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of Tim Burton's best.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Alex Holland
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Tim Burton, has done many movies in his career but his funniest film to date is "Mars Attacks". The film is a love letter/spoof of the 50's era of sci-fi B movies,(which viewed today would be laughable). The plot is pretty paper thin but too be honest it's a Tim Burton movie. A group of cruel and tasteless aliens decide to destroy the earth for shits and giggles. While the army and a gong ho general want to nuke the aliens, the president and his peace loving professor want earth and mars to coincide but the aliens don't really care as they enjoy defacing famous landmarks and killing innocent people. The genius of Mars Attacks is that it's a comedy,while most alien invasion films are serious and depressing, Mars Attacks makes fun of the fact that it's a bad movie and does it perfectly. The cast is really second to none,Jack Nicholson is great as both the President and as sleezy alcholic casino owner Art Land. Other cast members include, Glenn Close as a bitchy first lady,Pierce Brosnan as a professor for the white house that wants to analyze and have peace with the martians,Danny Devito as a rude gambler, and even a young Jack Black as a redneck soldier. Mars Attacks is a very smart and funny movie because it doesn't takes itself seriously. I know Tim Burton never talks about this movie, but I think that he should be proud of one of the funniest spoofs ever made.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    ACK ACK ACK (Translated) "Do Not Run We Are Your Friends"
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    leonlouisricci
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    There is just one scene after another that is a colorful, bizarre, twisted and unique Tim Burton vision of life, here, and on Mars. The movie never lets up and is based on the equally colorful and beautifully bent trading cards put out by Topps in 1962 painted by the great Pulp artist Norm Saunders. The film is a faithful adaptation and includes most of the card images all presented in sharp primary colors and given a respectful representation. This is a top notch Black Comedy that is funny, violent, and irreverent. It is favorably factitious and an amazing adventure with a lurid and gross artistic quality associated with the Director's style and in-sensibilities. The stellar cast is not necessary but all seem to be having a lot of fun. The visuals are the star and the script is less impressive, but the overall effect is cutting edge cinema that has an appeal for the slightly off key karma of the underground but marketed for the main stream. The film's detractors are left with not much to complain about (but they do) except the movie's brazen belief that it is a design of the different for the norm. But for them it is ridiculed and unappreciated.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Sci-Fi Satire With A Hidden Agenda
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Dalbert Pringle
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    *Possible Spoilers!* "We come in peace!" Mars Attacks was a totally "cool" way for director Tim Burton to annihilate such despicable big-name actors as Jack Nicholson, Danny DeVito, Jack Black, Sarah Jesica Parker, Glenn Close, Michael J. Fox and Martin Short (Phew! What a list of all-star casualties, eh!?) - And have a helluva lot of fun dong it. I only wish that Burton had also managed to have that annoying flake, Annette Bening, gunned down and vaporized, as well. Hideous-looking alien-bastards from Mars (vicious, cruel, and deceptive), toting insta-fry ray guns, land on Earth, and after hoodwinking the gullible public into thinking that this is a visit of friendship, commence with a horrific attack of mass-destruction, blowing up everything in site to smithereens. Can nothing save Earth from these ugly, bubble-headed, little creeps and their nasty, sadistic destructiveness?? Well, little do these menacing Martian-midgets know that we have discovered our very own secret weapon against them that's even more devastating than all of the nuclear weapons in the world. Yes. Indeed. And, who would've ever thought that Grandma Norris's "Slim Whitman" records would actually serve as our only defense against the Martians and inevitably save the day? I found this Sci-Fi/Comedy/Action film from 1996 to be a really uncharacteristic picture from Tim Burton. Presented as a tribute to 1950's UFO movies, Mars Attacks (with its awesome visual effects) delivers a kooky blend of twisted humor and ultra-violence that, when it works (which is about two-thirds of the time), is guaranteed to put a smile on the face of any fan of B-Movie schlock. P.S. - Yes, I do agree that, when it came to bad taste, Burton certainly did push the limits when he had the Martians perform their head-transplanting job, using Poppy, the cute, little, bug-eyed chihuahua, in their awful experiment.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Good, if a bit overfull
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    pwoodstock23
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Mars Attacks! Is an engaging, funny science fiction film directed by Tim Burton about an alien invasion of Earth from Mars (as the title suggests). Thousands of Flying Saucers appear around Earth, claiming peaceful intentions. Surprising virtually no one, they open fire within 48 hours. The film then follows the president and his immediate inner circle, a few American families, an entrepreneur, a few casino employees and a few others as the deal with this. As you can probably tell, this movie is somewhat bloated character-wise. The movie spends 40 minutes introducing it's many many characters. Many of them go on to serve absolutely no importance (see: Jack Nicholson opening a casino, only for it to blow up, a subplot serving only to give him a second role, or Danny DeVito, who shows up briefly early in the movie, and later comes back only to yell at a few people, plead for his life, and die), but the sheer number of characters keeps it from becoming boring, even when the martians are blowing stuff up for quite a few minutes on end. Director Tim Burton brings his namesake creative imagery here, making the movie's Martians very memorable. For example, when one martian shakes the president's hand, his hand comes of with a long tail, which then impales the president and then extends into the flag of their country, as he falls over onto the war room table, with plenty of miniature UFOs. Oh yeah, spoilers. (pretty much everyone dies) The movie's comedy also keeps it interesting, culminating in a hilarious ending of extreme dues ex machinma played for laughs that is absolutely memorable. Overall, it is a funny, quirky movie that pays tribute to the sci-fi movies of the 50s, both in content and feel, which probably could have cut out a character or two (or maybe three)
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not the satire it wants to be.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Sergeant_Tibbs
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Tim Burton's Mars Attacks! is a homage to 1950s sci-fi that fits in with the ensemble disaster films of the 1990s. I've always been a big fan of Tim Burton, his Big Fish was my first taste of what cinema could be, but even though this film was during the peak of his power, it's still a big let down. It has an insanely huge cast of talent with Jack Nicholson (in two roles), Glenn Close, Natalie Portman, Annette Bening, Michael J. Fox, Danny DeVito, Rod Steiger and many more, all given stock desires and conflicts with none particularly focused on and few resolved. The cast was why I watched it as well as the fact that it's on my watchlist from university in regards to music in film so it was worth watching in some regard but despite my low expectations it was still quite a disappointment. The first half is significantly better than the eye-rolling second, even though not much plot development is made. It's spent slowly setting up all the characters and humanity's reaction to martians. It's quite amusing at times, but never laugh out loud, feeling like it's completely comprised of the quirky side characters of Burton's other films and lacking the protagonist to root for. It's all pretty half decent for what it is, but unfortunately it has horrible and flat special effects which it relies on more than anything. Maybe it was the best of its kind at the time (though Independence Day in the same year was far superior), this is very primitive and most of the time it doesn't look like it belongs in the film's reality. Even some of the non-CGI effects are very poor. Perhaps this was more than Burton could handle or producers intervened, but it doesn't work and he should've tried for a stop motion or puppet effect. It does have some good elements. Danny Elfman's creative score is the biggest part of the homage to the 1950s sci-fi and that music plays a big theme in the story. While the score features the theremin prominently as the alien's signature sound, calling back to The Day The Earth Stood Still, it is the in film pseudo-country music that defeats the aliens. This suggests the idea, regarding pop culture, of what is now considered ordinary, the eeriness of the theremin over the country. However, contrivances in the script are very bothersome and ruin most of its execution. There's little sense of escalation from the first half to the second. It's the cringeworthy comedic and hokey moments in the second half that completely ruin the film and quickly wears out its welcome becoming one awful gag after the other that's doesn't feel like the satire it wants to be. A very weak effort for Burton. 4/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Ridiculous attack, poor film making from Tim Burton
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    aldri-feb
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I used to love watching this movie when I was a kid. I felt the Martians character was creepy and somehow really fun, I watched it over and over again but never got bored. But after about 15 years and watching it again yesterday, my point of view about 'Mars Attacks!' suddenly change. This is a type of movie that gives different impression if you watched it in 1990s and nowadays. May be in 1996 or few years after, 'Mars Attacks!' is still fine and exceptional for viewers but it's boring and silly when viewers watch these days. In other words, this movie gets old for young generation. The storyline itself is more like B-movie. It has no heart and chemistry between their entire casts. I have no idea what was Tim Burton purpose by directing this poor movie. It's one of his worst movie I've ever seen, even worse than 'Dark Shadows'. The only thing that could save this movie is their casts. They didn't act remarkably though but it's fun to see star like Jack Nicholson, Glenn Close, Annette Benning, Pierce Brosnan, Danny De Vito and Michael J. Fox in a movie. And don't forget, it also had young artists that becomes popular these days like Natalie Portman, Jack Black and Sarah Jessica Parker. Overall, 'Mars Attacks!' is not a film that audience would enjoy nowadays, the more years you watch it, the more you dislike this movie. It's different with classic movie like 'Godfather', 'Star Wars' or 'Jurassic Park' that never gets old and everyone could still enjoy even for future generation.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Relax . . . It's Not Supposed To Be High Art!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    capteagen
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I used the summary I did because I get the feeling reading other reviews that people were expecting SFX like those of "Independence Day" or "Alien(s)," etc., and were disappointed in not finding them here. In truth, I believe producer/director Tim Burton and the older cast members in particular knew exactly what they were doing. They directed the film at a general audience to be sure, but also targeted a segment of older viewers like me; the Baby Boomers who came of age at the height of the Cold War and the threat of nuclear annihilation, and/or accidental contamination by nuclear fallout or waste wherein the consequences included things as harmless as "Blinky" the three-eyed fish of The Simpson's fame, to atomic mutations on steroids such as the giant ants in the 50s thriller, "Them." I am the quintessential member of that target audience; I'm 57 years old, male, and grew-up on a diet of Saturday afternoon and "late, late show" television that often included a healthy (or unhealthy depending upon one's views) dose of 1950s SciFi "classics," such as "Earth vs. The Flying Saucers", "War of the Worlds", "The Day The Earth Stood Still", the aforementioned "Them", "I Married A Monster From Outer Space", "The Thing From Another World", and others. Those were the high quality films; those with good scripts, good acting (e.g. Michael Rennie, Patricia Neal, etc.), and enjoyable, if not exactly believable, story lines. Then there were those of much lower quality, e.g. "Zontar, Thing From Venus", "Beast With A Million Eyes", "The Crawling Eye" (known in the UK as "The Trollenberg Terror"), and others. The thing is, at the time people of my generation loved them all, regardless of quality. They were escapist fun, period; and sometimes the cheesier they were, e.g. "Plan Nine From Outer Space," the better. One suspects that Tim Burton, two years younger than me, wasted a lot of Saturday afternoon watching such fare. We know Steven Spielberg did because he said so! Regardless, what Burton and the cast have done is that they created a very tongue-in-cheek and very campy homage to the entire 1950s SciFi genre. I don't want to be a spoiler but suffice it to say that there are sly, and some not so sly, allusions to much of the finest in 1950s schlock. I don't think this next observation will spoil anything, but perhaps one of the most significant, and I believe heartfelt, references to yesteryear is the appearance of the Martian "flying saucers." They clearly are meant to honor the work of the late Ray Harryhausen, the master of stop-action photography. Ray died only last month (May 7, 2013) at the age of 92, but his work as director, cinematographer, and special effects coordinator in such films as "Clash of the Titans", "Jason and the Argonauts", "It Came from Beneath the Sea", and "Earth vs. the Flying Saucers" just to name few, was considered to be the high tech leading edge of SFX in its time. Before the advent of today's computer generated wonders, Ray was a true wizard and even though computer generated graphics are used here, Burton's crew made the saucers look like the work of stop-action photography, which had to be something of a labor of love. In any event, while it may not be the be all and end all of film making, the movie nonetheless accomplishes it's goal of sort of taking us back to a somewhat simpler time, and doing it with equal parts humor and loving attention to cheesy detail.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Ahhhhhhhhh! Mars Attacks!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tbills2
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Okaaaay, aaaand 50,000 points is awarded to Mars Attacks!, for having the awesomest cast of A-list actors in all of movie history! DING * DING * DING * DING * DING * DING * DING Congratulations, Mars Attacks! Here now to claim their prize on the behalf of the filmmakers, please give a warm, Earthly welcome to the Martian Ambassador, from Mars! ACK! ACK! ACK! ACK! Wait, no! Audience, watch out! Get out of here, quick! Ahhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhh! Let's work our way through these top stars, shall we - Jack Nicholson is the coolest actor in Hollywood. Natalie Portman is the starlet of her generation. Glenn Close possesses such a prominent prestige. Annette Bening is peppy and very fine. The smart and sleek Pierce Brosnan who is oh so dashing. The greatly adored Michael J. Fox. America's Sweetheart, Sarah Jessica Parker. Danny DeVito, don't count him out. The strong and sexy Pam Grier. The endearingly hilarious Martin Short, who is so endearingly hilarious. The largely exuberant Jack Black. The rambunctiously sweet Christina Applegate. The greatest man in Vegas, Tom Jones. And the greatest football running-back, Jim Brown. Not too shabby, and you might even recognize a few more familiar faces. Let's work our way through their performances, shall we - Nicholson is purely Jack, 'nough said. Natalie Portman is too good. Close can overact with the best of 'em. Bening is endlessly appealing as a free spirit. Mr. Brosnan insists on pleasing. Michael J. Fox is really good at summoning his inner jerk. Sarah J. is too intelligent to act so witless. DeVito is noticeable even among the biggest stars. Pam Grier is openly big-hearted as she strengthens her legacy as an actress. Marty Short bares a comical confidence. Jack Black has a lot to give and seems preparing for fame. Christina Applegate is briefly buoyant. Tom Jones should stick to singing. And Jim Brown is actually pretty darn decent, he steals the spotlight. Mars Attacks! has good effects, considerable entertainment value, and it is pieced together nicely. Tim Burton loves to take every opportunity to delve into the dark arts, but his talents are best served on the lighter side, case in point, this and Edward Scissorhands.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    You kind of know where Tim Burton was going with it.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Jonny 99
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Tim Burton used his star power to assemble one of the highest power casts you'll see in a mid 90's film. Unfortunately, he doesn't give them that much to do. "Mars Attacks" much like "The Informant!" plays like a joke that doesn't provoke laughter as much as it does a sense of knowing where Burton was going with the film. Basically, he tries to lampoon the 1950's creature feature film particularly "The Day the Earth Stood Still" but an underlying Burton-ian meanspiritness and tendency toward strong violence sucks much of the fun out of the film. The writers provide only a modest amount of fun from which to take leaving Burton to rely on CGI red-spangled speedos on the Martians and the stuntcasting - including Tom Jones wasted by simply playing himself - to push the movie along. Burton cross the spoof line in a few spots and instead simply lifts ideas from much better films particularly Rod Steiger's General Decker a copy of George C Scott General Turgidson from "Dr. Stangelove." The plagiarism serves not as homage but as a sign that you could be watching a much better film. In short, better parody of the same material exists elsewhere.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A pretty good black comedy with Martians and a beautiful ensemble of characters
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Augusta Melbourne
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This stylistic feature of black comedy has put quite a mark on reflecting and perhaps parodying America's attitudes towards culture and materialism. The fact that the design of the UFOs and Martians were less shoddy and more of what we think of them means that it helps to look at these in terms of our assumptions. A great ensemble of character with their own time to shine, the comedy is affectionate as well as outrageous. It's not meant to be predictable, it's the fact that the characters should have seen this one coming. Also, this parody of clich&eacute;s and laughable scenes of science fiction from 1950's B movies should be more recognised. The glitzy costumes and visual flair isn't there just to look at.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of Tim Burton's best.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Alex Holland
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Tim Burton, has done many movies in his career but his funniest film to date is "Mars Attacks". The film is a love letter/spoof of the 50's era of sci-fi B movies,(which viewed today would be laughable). The plot is pretty paper thin but too be honest it's a Tim Burton movie. A group of cruel and tasteless aliens decide to destroy the earth for shits and giggles. While the army and a gong ho general want to nuke the aliens, the president and his peace loving professor want earth and mars to coincide but the aliens don't really care as they enjoy defacing famous landmarks and killing innocent people. The genius of Mars Attacks is that it's a comedy,while most alien invasion films are serious and depressing, Mars Attacks makes fun of the fact that it's a bad movie and does it perfectly. The cast is really second to none,Jack Nicholson is great as both the President and as sleezy alcholic casino owner Art Land. Other cast members include, Glenn Close as a bitchy first lady,Pierce Brosnan as a professor for the white house that wants to analyze and have peace with the martians,Danny Devito as a rude gambler, and even a young Jack Black as a redneck soldier. Mars Attacks is a very smart and funny movie because it doesn't takes itself seriously. I know Tim Burton never talks about this movie, but I think that he should be proud of one of the funniest spoofs ever made.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    ACK ACK ACK (Translated) "Do Not Run We Are Your Friends"
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    leonlouisricci
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    There is just one scene after another that is a colorful, bizarre, twisted and unique Tim Burton vision of life, here, and on Mars. The movie never lets up and is based on the equally colorful and beautifully bent trading cards put out by Topps in 1962 painted by the great Pulp artist Norm Saunders. The film is a faithful adaptation and includes most of the card images all presented in sharp primary colors and given a respectful representation. This is a top notch Black Comedy that is funny, violent, and irreverent. It is favorably factitious and an amazing adventure with a lurid and gross artistic quality associated with the Director's style and in-sensibilities. The stellar cast is not necessary but all seem to be having a lot of fun. The visuals are the star and the script is less impressive, but the overall effect is cutting edge cinema that has an appeal for the slightly off key karma of the underground but marketed for the main stream. The film's detractors are left with not much to complain about (but they do) except the movie's brazen belief that it is a design of the different for the norm. But for them it is ridiculed and unappreciated.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Sci-Fi Satire With A Hidden Agenda
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Dalbert Pringle
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    *Possible Spoilers!* "We come in peace!" Mars Attacks was a totally "cool" way for director Tim Burton to annihilate such despicable big-name actors as Jack Nicholson, Danny DeVito, Jack Black, Sarah Jesica Parker, Glenn Close, Michael J. Fox and Martin Short (Phew! What a list of all-star casualties, eh!?) - And have a helluva lot of fun dong it. I only wish that Burton had also managed to have that annoying flake, Annette Bening, gunned down and vaporized, as well. Hideous-looking alien-bastards from Mars (vicious, cruel, and deceptive), toting insta-fry ray guns, land on Earth, and after hoodwinking the gullible public into thinking that this is a visit of friendship, commence with a horrific attack of mass-destruction, blowing up everything in site to smithereens. Can nothing save Earth from these ugly, bubble-headed, little creeps and their nasty, sadistic destructiveness?? Well, little do these menacing Martian-midgets know that we have discovered our very own secret weapon against them that's even more devastating than all of the nuclear weapons in the world. Yes. Indeed. And, who would've ever thought that Grandma Norris's "Slim Whitman" records would actually serve as our only defense against the Martians and inevitably save the day? I found this Sci-Fi/Comedy/Action film from 1996 to be a really uncharacteristic picture from Tim Burton. Presented as a tribute to 1950's UFO movies, Mars Attacks (with its awesome visual effects) delivers a kooky blend of twisted humor and ultra-violence that, when it works (which is about two-thirds of the time), is guaranteed to put a smile on the face of any fan of B-Movie schlock. P.S. - Yes, I do agree that, when it came to bad taste, Burton certainly did push the limits when he had the Martians perform their head-transplanting job, using Poppy, the cute, little, bug-eyed chihuahua, in their awful experiment.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Good, if a bit overfull
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    pwoodstock23
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Mars Attacks! Is an engaging, funny science fiction film directed by Tim Burton about an alien invasion of Earth from Mars (as the title suggests). Thousands of Flying Saucers appear around Earth, claiming peaceful intentions. Surprising virtually no one, they open fire within 48 hours. The film then follows the president and his immediate inner circle, a few American families, an entrepreneur, a few casino employees and a few others as the deal with this. As you can probably tell, this movie is somewhat bloated character-wise. The movie spends 40 minutes introducing it's many many characters. Many of them go on to serve absolutely no importance (see: Jack Nicholson opening a casino, only for it to blow up, a subplot serving only to give him a second role, or Danny DeVito, who shows up briefly early in the movie, and later comes back only to yell at a few people, plead for his life, and die), but the sheer number of characters keeps it from becoming boring, even when the martians are blowing stuff up for quite a few minutes on end. Director Tim Burton brings his namesake creative imagery here, making the movie's Martians very memorable. For example, when one martian shakes the president's hand, his hand comes of with a long tail, which then impales the president and then extends into the flag of their country, as he falls over onto the war room table, with plenty of miniature UFOs. Oh yeah, spoilers. (pretty much everyone dies) The movie's comedy also keeps it interesting, culminating in a hilarious ending of extreme dues ex machinma played for laughs that is absolutely memorable. Overall, it is a funny, quirky movie that pays tribute to the sci-fi movies of the 50s, both in content and feel, which probably could have cut out a character or two (or maybe three)
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not the satire it wants to be.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Sergeant_Tibbs
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Tim Burton's Mars Attacks! is a homage to 1950s sci-fi that fits in with the ensemble disaster films of the 1990s. I've always been a big fan of Tim Burton, his Big Fish was my first taste of what cinema could be, but even though this film was during the peak of his power, it's still a big let down. It has an insanely huge cast of talent with Jack Nicholson (in two roles), Glenn Close, Natalie Portman, Annette Bening, Michael J. Fox, Danny DeVito, Rod Steiger and many more, all given stock desires and conflicts with none particularly focused on and few resolved. The cast was why I watched it as well as the fact that it's on my watchlist from university in regards to music in film so it was worth watching in some regard but despite my low expectations it was still quite a disappointment. The first half is significantly better than the eye-rolling second, even though not much plot development is made. It's spent slowly setting up all the characters and humanity's reaction to martians. It's quite amusing at times, but never laugh out loud, feeling like it's completely comprised of the quirky side characters of Burton's other films and lacking the protagonist to root for. It's all pretty half decent for what it is, but unfortunately it has horrible and flat special effects which it relies on more than anything. Maybe it was the best of its kind at the time (though Independence Day in the same year was far superior), this is very primitive and most of the time it doesn't look like it belongs in the film's reality. Even some of the non-CGI effects are very poor. Perhaps this was more than Burton could handle or producers intervened, but it doesn't work and he should've tried for a stop motion or puppet effect. It does have some good elements. Danny Elfman's creative score is the biggest part of the homage to the 1950s sci-fi and that music plays a big theme in the story. While the score features the theremin prominently as the alien's signature sound, calling back to The Day The Earth Stood Still, it is the in film pseudo-country music that defeats the aliens. This suggests the idea, regarding pop culture, of what is now considered ordinary, the eeriness of the theremin over the country. However, contrivances in the script are very bothersome and ruin most of its execution. There's little sense of escalation from the first half to the second. It's the cringeworthy comedic and hokey moments in the second half that completely ruin the film and quickly wears out its welcome becoming one awful gag after the other that's doesn't feel like the satire it wants to be. A very weak effort for Burton. 4/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Ridiculous attack, poor film making from Tim Burton
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    aldri-feb
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I used to love watching this movie when I was a kid. I felt the Martians character was creepy and somehow really fun, I watched it over and over again but never got bored. But after about 15 years and watching it again yesterday, my point of view about 'Mars Attacks!' suddenly change. This is a type of movie that gives different impression if you watched it in 1990s and nowadays. May be in 1996 or few years after, 'Mars Attacks!' is still fine and exceptional for viewers but it's boring and silly when viewers watch these days. In other words, this movie gets old for young generation. The storyline itself is more like B-movie. It has no heart and chemistry between their entire casts. I have no idea what was Tim Burton purpose by directing this poor movie. It's one of his worst movie I've ever seen, even worse than 'Dark Shadows'. The only thing that could save this movie is their casts. They didn't act remarkably though but it's fun to see star like Jack Nicholson, Glenn Close, Annette Benning, Pierce Brosnan, Danny De Vito and Michael J. Fox in a movie. And don't forget, it also had young artists that becomes popular these days like Natalie Portman, Jack Black and Sarah Jessica Parker. Overall, 'Mars Attacks!' is not a film that audience would enjoy nowadays, the more years you watch it, the more you dislike this movie. It's different with classic movie like 'Godfather', 'Star Wars' or 'Jurassic Park' that never gets old and everyone could still enjoy even for future generation.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Relax . . . It's Not Supposed To Be High Art!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    capteagen
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I used the summary I did because I get the feeling reading other reviews that people were expecting SFX like those of "Independence Day" or "Alien(s)," etc., and were disappointed in not finding them here. In truth, I believe producer/director Tim Burton and the older cast members in particular knew exactly what they were doing. They directed the film at a general audience to be sure, but also targeted a segment of older viewers like me; the Baby Boomers who came of age at the height of the Cold War and the threat of nuclear annihilation, and/or accidental contamination by nuclear fallout or waste wherein the consequences included things as harmless as "Blinky" the three-eyed fish of The Simpson's fame, to atomic mutations on steroids such as the giant ants in the 50s thriller, "Them." I am the quintessential member of that target audience; I'm 57 years old, male, and grew-up on a diet of Saturday afternoon and "late, late show" television that often included a healthy (or unhealthy depending upon one's views) dose of 1950s SciFi "classics," such as "Earth vs. The Flying Saucers", "War of the Worlds", "The Day The Earth Stood Still", the aforementioned "Them", "I Married A Monster From Outer Space", "The Thing From Another World", and others. Those were the high quality films; those with good scripts, good acting (e.g. Michael Rennie, Patricia Neal, etc.), and enjoyable, if not exactly believable, story lines. Then there were those of much lower quality, e.g. "Zontar, Thing From Venus", "Beast With A Million Eyes", "The Crawling Eye" (known in the UK as "The Trollenberg Terror"), and others. The thing is, at the time people of my generation loved them all, regardless of quality. They were escapist fun, period; and sometimes the cheesier they were, e.g. "Plan Nine From Outer Space," the better. One suspects that Tim Burton, two years younger than me, wasted a lot of Saturday afternoon watching such fare. We know Steven Spielberg did because he said so! Regardless, what Burton and the cast have done is that they created a very tongue-in-cheek and very campy homage to the entire 1950s SciFi genre. I don't want to be a spoiler but suffice it to say that there are sly, and some not so sly, allusions to much of the finest in 1950s schlock. I don't think this next observation will spoil anything, but perhaps one of the most significant, and I believe heartfelt, references to yesteryear is the appearance of the Martian "flying saucers." They clearly are meant to honor the work of the late Ray Harryhausen, the master of stop-action photography. Ray died only last month (May 7, 2013) at the age of 92, but his work as director, cinematographer, and special effects coordinator in such films as "Clash of the Titans", "Jason and the Argonauts", "It Came from Beneath the Sea", and "Earth vs. the Flying Saucers" just to name few, was considered to be the high tech leading edge of SFX in its time. Before the advent of today's computer generated wonders, Ray was a true wizard and even though computer generated graphics are used here, Burton's crew made the saucers look like the work of stop-action photography, which had to be something of a labor of love. In any event, while it may not be the be all and end all of film making, the movie nonetheless accomplishes it's goal of sort of taking us back to a somewhat simpler time, and doing it with equal parts humor and loving attention to cheesy detail.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Ahhhhhhhhh! Mars Attacks!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tbills2
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Okaaaay, aaaand 50,000 points is awarded to Mars Attacks!, for having the awesomest cast of A-list actors in all of movie history! DING * DING * DING * DING * DING * DING * DING Congratulations, Mars Attacks! Here now to claim their prize on the behalf of the filmmakers, please give a warm, Earthly welcome to the Martian Ambassador, from Mars! ACK! ACK! ACK! ACK! Wait, no! Audience, watch out! Get out of here, quick! Ahhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhh! Let's work our way through these top stars, shall we - Jack Nicholson is the coolest actor in Hollywood. Natalie Portman is the starlet of her generation. Glenn Close possesses such a prominent prestige. Annette Bening is peppy and very fine. The smart and sleek Pierce Brosnan who is oh so dashing. The greatly adored Michael J. Fox. America's Sweetheart, Sarah Jessica Parker. Danny DeVito, don't count him out. The strong and sexy Pam Grier. The endearingly hilarious Martin Short, who is so endearingly hilarious. The largely exuberant Jack Black. The rambunctiously sweet Christina Applegate. The greatest man in Vegas, Tom Jones. And the greatest football running-back, Jim Brown. Not too shabby, and you might even recognize a few more familiar faces. Let's work our way through their performances, shall we - Nicholson is purely Jack, 'nough said. Natalie Portman is too good. Close can overact with the best of 'em. Bening is endlessly appealing as a free spirit. Mr. Brosnan insists on pleasing. Michael J. Fox is really good at summoning his inner jerk. Sarah J. is too intelligent to act so witless. DeVito is noticeable even among the biggest stars. Pam Grier is openly big-hearted as she strengthens her legacy as an actress. Marty Short bares a comical confidence. Jack Black has a lot to give and seems preparing for fame. Christina Applegate is briefly buoyant. Tom Jones should stick to singing. And Jim Brown is actually pretty darn decent, he steals the spotlight. Mars Attacks! has good effects, considerable entertainment value, and it is pieced together nicely. Tim Burton loves to take every opportunity to delve into the dark arts, but his talents are best served on the lighter side, case in point, this and Edward Scissorhands.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    You kind of know where Tim Burton was going with it.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Jonny 99
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Tim Burton used his star power to assemble one of the highest power casts you'll see in a mid 90's film. Unfortunately, he doesn't give them that much to do. "Mars Attacks" much like "The Informant!" plays like a joke that doesn't provoke laughter as much as it does a sense of knowing where Burton was going with the film. Basically, he tries to lampoon the 1950's creature feature film particularly "The Day the Earth Stood Still" but an underlying Burton-ian meanspiritness and tendency toward strong violence sucks much of the fun out of the film. The writers provide only a modest amount of fun from which to take leaving Burton to rely on CGI red-spangled speedos on the Martians and the stuntcasting - including Tom Jones wasted by simply playing himself - to push the movie along. Burton cross the spoof line in a few spots and instead simply lifts ideas from much better films particularly Rod Steiger's General Decker a copy of George C Scott General Turgidson from "Dr. Stangelove." The plagiarism serves not as homage but as a sign that you could be watching a much better film. In short, better parody of the same material exists elsewhere.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A pretty good black comedy with Martians and a beautiful ensemble of characters
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Augusta Melbourne
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This stylistic feature of black comedy has put quite a mark on reflecting and perhaps parodying America's attitudes towards culture and materialism. The fact that the design of the UFOs and Martians were less shoddy and more of what we think of them means that it helps to look at these in terms of our assumptions. A great ensemble of character with their own time to shine, the comedy is affectionate as well as outrageous. It's not meant to be predictable, it's the fact that the characters should have seen this one coming. Also, this parody of clich&eacute;s and laughable scenes of science fiction from 1950's B movies should be more recognised. The glitzy costumes and visual flair isn't there just to look at.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of Tim Burton's best.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Alex Holland
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Tim Burton, has done many movies in his career but his funniest film to date is "Mars Attacks". The film is a love letter/spoof of the 50's era of sci-fi B movies,(which viewed today would be laughable). The plot is pretty paper thin but too be honest it's a Tim Burton movie. A group of cruel and tasteless aliens decide to destroy the earth for shits and giggles. While the army and a gong ho general want to nuke the aliens, the president and his peace loving professor want earth and mars to coincide but the aliens don't really care as they enjoy defacing famous landmarks and killing innocent people. The genius of Mars Attacks is that it's a comedy,while most alien invasion films are serious and depressing, Mars Attacks makes fun of the fact that it's a bad movie and does it perfectly. The cast is really second to none,Jack Nicholson is great as both the President and as sleezy alcholic casino owner Art Land. Other cast members include, Glenn Close as a bitchy first lady,Pierce Brosnan as a professor for the white house that wants to analyze and have peace with the martians,Danny Devito as a rude gambler, and even a young Jack Black as a redneck soldier. Mars Attacks is a very smart and funny movie because it doesn't takes itself seriously. I know Tim Burton never talks about this movie, but I think that he should be proud of one of the funniest spoofs ever made.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    ACK ACK ACK (Translated) "Do Not Run We Are Your Friends"
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    leonlouisricci
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    There is just one scene after another that is a colorful, bizarre, twisted and unique Tim Burton vision of life, here, and on Mars. The movie never lets up and is based on the equally colorful and beautifully bent trading cards put out by Topps in 1962 painted by the great Pulp artist Norm Saunders. The film is a faithful adaptation and includes most of the card images all presented in sharp primary colors and given a respectful representation. This is a top notch Black Comedy that is funny, violent, and irreverent. It is favorably factitious and an amazing adventure with a lurid and gross artistic quality associated with the Director's style and in-sensibilities. The stellar cast is not necessary but all seem to be having a lot of fun. The visuals are the star and the script is less impressive, but the overall effect is cutting edge cinema that has an appeal for the slightly off key karma of the underground but marketed for the main stream. The film's detractors are left with not much to complain about (but they do) except the movie's brazen belief that it is a design of the different for the norm. But for them it is ridiculed and unappreciated.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Sci-Fi Satire With A Hidden Agenda
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Dalbert Pringle
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    *Possible Spoilers!* "We come in peace!" Mars Attacks was a totally "cool" way for director Tim Burton to annihilate such despicable big-name actors as Jack Nicholson, Danny DeVito, Jack Black, Sarah Jesica Parker, Glenn Close, Michael J. Fox and Martin Short (Phew! What a list of all-star casualties, eh!?) - And have a helluva lot of fun dong it. I only wish that Burton had also managed to have that annoying flake, Annette Bening, gunned down and vaporized, as well. Hideous-looking alien-bastards from Mars (vicious, cruel, and deceptive), toting insta-fry ray guns, land on Earth, and after hoodwinking the gullible public into thinking that this is a visit of friendship, commence with a horrific attack of mass-destruction, blowing up everything in site to smithereens. Can nothing save Earth from these ugly, bubble-headed, little creeps and their nasty, sadistic destructiveness?? Well, little do these menacing Martian-midgets know that we have discovered our very own secret weapon against them that's even more devastating than all of the nuclear weapons in the world. Yes. Indeed. And, who would've ever thought that Grandma Norris's "Slim Whitman" records would actually serve as our only defense against the Martians and inevitably save the day? I found this Sci-Fi/Comedy/Action film from 1996 to be a really uncharacteristic picture from Tim Burton. Presented as a tribute to 1950's UFO movies, Mars Attacks (with its awesome visual effects) delivers a kooky blend of twisted humor and ultra-violence that, when it works (which is about two-thirds of the time), is guaranteed to put a smile on the face of any fan of B-Movie schlock. P.S. - Yes, I do agree that, when it came to bad taste, Burton certainly did push the limits when he had the Martians perform their head-transplanting job, using Poppy, the cute, little, bug-eyed chihuahua, in their awful experiment.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Good, if a bit overfull
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    pwoodstock23
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Mars Attacks! Is an engaging, funny science fiction film directed by Tim Burton about an alien invasion of Earth from Mars (as the title suggests). Thousands of Flying Saucers appear around Earth, claiming peaceful intentions. Surprising virtually no one, they open fire within 48 hours. The film then follows the president and his immediate inner circle, a few American families, an entrepreneur, a few casino employees and a few others as the deal with this. As you can probably tell, this movie is somewhat bloated character-wise. The movie spends 40 minutes introducing it's many many characters. Many of them go on to serve absolutely no importance (see: Jack Nicholson opening a casino, only for it to blow up, a subplot serving only to give him a second role, or Danny DeVito, who shows up briefly early in the movie, and later comes back only to yell at a few people, plead for his life, and die), but the sheer number of characters keeps it from becoming boring, even when the martians are blowing stuff up for quite a few minutes on end. Director Tim Burton brings his namesake creative imagery here, making the movie's Martians very memorable. For example, when one martian shakes the president's hand, his hand comes of with a long tail, which then impales the president and then extends into the flag of their country, as he falls over onto the war room table, with plenty of miniature UFOs. Oh yeah, spoilers. (pretty much everyone dies) The movie's comedy also keeps it interesting, culminating in a hilarious ending of extreme dues ex machinma played for laughs that is absolutely memorable. Overall, it is a funny, quirky movie that pays tribute to the sci-fi movies of the 50s, both in content and feel, which probably could have cut out a character or two (or maybe three)
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not the satire it wants to be.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Sergeant_Tibbs
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Tim Burton's Mars Attacks! is a homage to 1950s sci-fi that fits in with the ensemble disaster films of the 1990s. I've always been a big fan of Tim Burton, his Big Fish was my first taste of what cinema could be, but even though this film was during the peak of his power, it's still a big let down. It has an insanely huge cast of talent with Jack Nicholson (in two roles), Glenn Close, Natalie Portman, Annette Bening, Michael J. Fox, Danny DeVito, Rod Steiger and many more, all given stock desires and conflicts with none particularly focused on and few resolved. The cast was why I watched it as well as the fact that it's on my watchlist from university in regards to music in film so it was worth watching in some regard but despite my low expectations it was still quite a disappointment. The first half is significantly better than the eye-rolling second, even though not much plot development is made. It's spent slowly setting up all the characters and humanity's reaction to martians. It's quite amusing at times, but never laugh out loud, feeling like it's completely comprised of the quirky side characters of Burton's other films and lacking the protagonist to root for. It's all pretty half decent for what it is, but unfortunately it has horrible and flat special effects which it relies on more than anything. Maybe it was the best of its kind at the time (though Independence Day in the same year was far superior), this is very primitive and most of the time it doesn't look like it belongs in the film's reality. Even some of the non-CGI effects are very poor. Perhaps this was more than Burton could handle or producers intervened, but it doesn't work and he should've tried for a stop motion or puppet effect. It does have some good elements. Danny Elfman's creative score is the biggest part of the homage to the 1950s sci-fi and that music plays a big theme in the story. While the score features the theremin prominently as the alien's signature sound, calling back to The Day The Earth Stood Still, it is the in film pseudo-country music that defeats the aliens. This suggests the idea, regarding pop culture, of what is now considered ordinary, the eeriness of the theremin over the country. However, contrivances in the script are very bothersome and ruin most of its execution. There's little sense of escalation from the first half to the second. It's the cringeworthy comedic and hokey moments in the second half that completely ruin the film and quickly wears out its welcome becoming one awful gag after the other that's doesn't feel like the satire it wants to be. A very weak effort for Burton. 4/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Ridiculous attack, poor film making from Tim Burton
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    aldri-feb
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I used to love watching this movie when I was a kid. I felt the Martians character was creepy and somehow really fun, I watched it over and over again but never got bored. But after about 15 years and watching it again yesterday, my point of view about 'Mars Attacks!' suddenly change. This is a type of movie that gives different impression if you watched it in 1990s and nowadays. May be in 1996 or few years after, 'Mars Attacks!' is still fine and exceptional for viewers but it's boring and silly when viewers watch these days. In other words, this movie gets old for young generation. The storyline itself is more like B-movie. It has no heart and chemistry between their entire casts. I have no idea what was Tim Burton purpose by directing this poor movie. It's one of his worst movie I've ever seen, even worse than 'Dark Shadows'. The only thing that could save this movie is their casts. They didn't act remarkably though but it's fun to see star like Jack Nicholson, Glenn Close, Annette Benning, Pierce Brosnan, Danny De Vito and Michael J. Fox in a movie. And don't forget, it also had young artists that becomes popular these days like Natalie Portman, Jack Black and Sarah Jessica Parker. Overall, 'Mars Attacks!' is not a film that audience would enjoy nowadays, the more years you watch it, the more you dislike this movie. It's different with classic movie like 'Godfather', 'Star Wars' or 'Jurassic Park' that never gets old and everyone could still enjoy even for future generation.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Relax . . . It's Not Supposed To Be High Art!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    capteagen
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I used the summary I did because I get the feeling reading other reviews that people were expecting SFX like those of "Independence Day" or "Alien(s)," etc., and were disappointed in not finding them here. In truth, I believe producer/director Tim Burton and the older cast members in particular knew exactly what they were doing. They directed the film at a general audience to be sure, but also targeted a segment of older viewers like me; the Baby Boomers who came of age at the height of the Cold War and the threat of nuclear annihilation, and/or accidental contamination by nuclear fallout or waste wherein the consequences included things as harmless as "Blinky" the three-eyed fish of The Simpson's fame, to atomic mutations on steroids such as the giant ants in the 50s thriller, "Them." I am the quintessential member of that target audience; I'm 57 years old, male, and grew-up on a diet of Saturday afternoon and "late, late show" television that often included a healthy (or unhealthy depending upon one's views) dose of 1950s SciFi "classics," such as "Earth vs. The Flying Saucers", "War of the Worlds", "The Day The Earth Stood Still", the aforementioned "Them", "I Married A Monster From Outer Space", "The Thing From Another World", and others. Those were the high quality films; those with good scripts, good acting (e.g. Michael Rennie, Patricia Neal, etc.), and enjoyable, if not exactly believable, story lines. Then there were those of much lower quality, e.g. "Zontar, Thing From Venus", "Beast With A Million Eyes", "The Crawling Eye" (known in the UK as "The Trollenberg Terror"), and others. The thing is, at the time people of my generation loved them all, regardless of quality. They were escapist fun, period; and sometimes the cheesier they were, e.g. "Plan Nine From Outer Space," the better. One suspects that Tim Burton, two years younger than me, wasted a lot of Saturday afternoon watching such fare. We know Steven Spielberg did because he said so! Regardless, what Burton and the cast have done is that they created a very tongue-in-cheek and very campy homage to the entire 1950s SciFi genre. I don't want to be a spoiler but suffice it to say that there are sly, and some not so sly, allusions to much of the finest in 1950s schlock. I don't think this next observation will spoil anything, but perhaps one of the most significant, and I believe heartfelt, references to yesteryear is the appearance of the Martian "flying saucers." They clearly are meant to honor the work of the late Ray Harryhausen, the master of stop-action photography. Ray died only last month (May 7, 2013) at the age of 92, but his work as director, cinematographer, and special effects coordinator in such films as "Clash of the Titans", "Jason and the Argonauts", "It Came from Beneath the Sea", and "Earth vs. the Flying Saucers" just to name few, was considered to be the high tech leading edge of SFX in its time. Before the advent of today's computer generated wonders, Ray was a true wizard and even though computer generated graphics are used here, Burton's crew made the saucers look like the work of stop-action photography, which had to be something of a labor of love. In any event, while it may not be the be all and end all of film making, the movie nonetheless accomplishes it's goal of sort of taking us back to a somewhat simpler time, and doing it with equal parts humor and loving attention to cheesy detail.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Ahhhhhhhhh! Mars Attacks!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tbills2
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Okaaaay, aaaand 50,000 points is awarded to Mars Attacks!, for having the awesomest cast of A-list actors in all of movie history! DING * DING * DING * DING * DING * DING * DING Congratulations, Mars Attacks! Here now to claim their prize on the behalf of the filmmakers, please give a warm, Earthly welcome to the Martian Ambassador, from Mars! ACK! ACK! ACK! ACK! Wait, no! Audience, watch out! Get out of here, quick! Ahhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhh! Let's work our way through these top stars, shall we - Jack Nicholson is the coolest actor in Hollywood. Natalie Portman is the starlet of her generation. Glenn Close possesses such a prominent prestige. Annette Bening is peppy and very fine. The smart and sleek Pierce Brosnan who is oh so dashing. The greatly adored Michael J. Fox. America's Sweetheart, Sarah Jessica Parker. Danny DeVito, don't count him out. The strong and sexy Pam Grier. The endearingly hilarious Martin Short, who is so endearingly hilarious. The largely exuberant Jack Black. The rambunctiously sweet Christina Applegate. The greatest man in Vegas, Tom Jones. And the greatest football running-back, Jim Brown. Not too shabby, and you might even recognize a few more familiar faces. Let's work our way through their performances, shall we - Nicholson is purely Jack, 'nough said. Natalie Portman is too good. Close can overact with the best of 'em. Bening is endlessly appealing as a free spirit. Mr. Brosnan insists on pleasing. Michael J. Fox is really good at summoning his inner jerk. Sarah J. is too intelligent to act so witless. DeVito is noticeable even among the biggest stars. Pam Grier is openly big-hearted as she strengthens her legacy as an actress. Marty Short bares a comical confidence. Jack Black has a lot to give and seems preparing for fame. Christina Applegate is briefly buoyant. Tom Jones should stick to singing. And Jim Brown is actually pretty darn decent, he steals the spotlight. Mars Attacks! has good effects, considerable entertainment value, and it is pieced together nicely. Tim Burton loves to take every opportunity to delve into the dark arts, but his talents are best served on the lighter side, case in point, this and Edward Scissorhands.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    You kind of know where Tim Burton was going with it.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Jonny 99
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Tim Burton used his star power to assemble one of the highest power casts you'll see in a mid 90's film. Unfortunately, he doesn't give them that much to do. "Mars Attacks" much like "The Informant!" plays like a joke that doesn't provoke laughter as much as it does a sense of knowing where Burton was going with the film. Basically, he tries to lampoon the 1950's creature feature film particularly "The Day the Earth Stood Still" but an underlying Burton-ian meanspiritness and tendency toward strong violence sucks much of the fun out of the film. The writers provide only a modest amount of fun from which to take leaving Burton to rely on CGI red-spangled speedos on the Martians and the stuntcasting - including Tom Jones wasted by simply playing himself - to push the movie along. Burton cross the spoof line in a few spots and instead simply lifts ideas from much better films particularly Rod Steiger's General Decker a copy of George C Scott General Turgidson from "Dr. Stangelove." The plagiarism serves not as homage but as a sign that you could be watching a much better film. In short, better parody of the same material exists elsewhere.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A pretty good black comedy with Martians and a beautiful ensemble of characters
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Augusta Melbourne
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This stylistic feature of black comedy has put quite a mark on reflecting and perhaps parodying America's attitudes towards culture and materialism. The fact that the design of the UFOs and Martians were less shoddy and more of what we think of them means that it helps to look at these in terms of our assumptions. A great ensemble of character with their own time to shine, the comedy is affectionate as well as outrageous. It's not meant to be predictable, it's the fact that the characters should have seen this one coming. Also, this parody of clich&eacute;s and laughable scenes of science fiction from 1950's B movies should be more recognised. The glitzy costumes and visual flair isn't there just to look at.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of Tim Burton's best.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Alex Holland
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Tim Burton, has done many movies in his career but his funniest film to date is "Mars Attacks". The film is a love letter/spoof of the 50's era of sci-fi B movies,(which viewed today would be laughable). The plot is pretty paper thin but too be honest it's a Tim Burton movie. A group of cruel and tasteless aliens decide to destroy the earth for shits and giggles. While the army and a gong ho general want to nuke the aliens, the president and his peace loving professor want earth and mars to coincide but the aliens don't really care as they enjoy defacing famous landmarks and killing innocent people. The genius of Mars Attacks is that it's a comedy,while most alien invasion films are serious and depressing, Mars Attacks makes fun of the fact that it's a bad movie and does it perfectly. The cast is really second to none,Jack Nicholson is great as both the President and as sleezy alcholic casino owner Art Land. Other cast members include, Glenn Close as a bitchy first lady,Pierce Brosnan as a professor for the white house that wants to analyze and have peace with the martians,Danny Devito as a rude gambler, and even a young Jack Black as a redneck soldier. Mars Attacks is a very smart and funny movie because it doesn't takes itself seriously. I know Tim Burton never talks about this movie, but I think that he should be proud of one of the funniest spoofs ever made.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    ACK ACK ACK (Translated) "Do Not Run We Are Your Friends"
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    leonlouisricci
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    There is just one scene after another that is a colorful, bizarre, twisted and unique Tim Burton vision of life, here, and on Mars. The movie never lets up and is based on the equally colorful and beautifully bent trading cards put out by Topps in 1962 painted by the great Pulp artist Norm Saunders. The film is a faithful adaptation and includes most of the card images all presented in sharp primary colors and given a respectful representation. This is a top notch Black Comedy that is funny, violent, and irreverent. It is favorably factitious and an amazing adventure with a lurid and gross artistic quality associated with the Director's style and in-sensibilities. The stellar cast is not necessary but all seem to be having a lot of fun. The visuals are the star and the script is less impressive, but the overall effect is cutting edge cinema that has an appeal for the slightly off key karma of the underground but marketed for the main stream. The film's detractors are left with not much to complain about (but they do) except the movie's brazen belief that it is a design of the different for the norm. But for them it is ridiculed and unappreciated.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Sci-Fi Satire With A Hidden Agenda
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Dalbert Pringle
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    *Possible Spoilers!* "We come in peace!" Mars Attacks was a totally "cool" way for director Tim Burton to annihilate such despicable big-name actors as Jack Nicholson, Danny DeVito, Jack Black, Sarah Jesica Parker, Glenn Close, Michael J. Fox and Martin Short (Phew! What a list of all-star casualties, eh!?) - And have a helluva lot of fun dong it. I only wish that Burton had also managed to have that annoying flake, Annette Bening, gunned down and vaporized, as well. Hideous-looking alien-bastards from Mars (vicious, cruel, and deceptive), toting insta-fry ray guns, land on Earth, and after hoodwinking the gullible public into thinking that this is a visit of friendship, commence with a horrific attack of mass-destruction, blowing up everything in site to smithereens. Can nothing save Earth from these ugly, bubble-headed, little creeps and their nasty, sadistic destructiveness?? Well, little do these menacing Martian-midgets know that we have discovered our very own secret weapon against them that's even more devastating than all of the nuclear weapons in the world. Yes. Indeed. And, who would've ever thought that Grandma Norris's "Slim Whitman" records would actually serve as our only defense against the Martians and inevitably save the day? I found this Sci-Fi/Comedy/Action film from 1996 to be a really uncharacteristic picture from Tim Burton. Presented as a tribute to 1950's UFO movies, Mars Attacks (with its awesome visual effects) delivers a kooky blend of twisted humor and ultra-violence that, when it works (which is about two-thirds of the time), is guaranteed to put a smile on the face of any fan of B-Movie schlock. P.S. - Yes, I do agree that, when it came to bad taste, Burton certainly did push the limits when he had the Martians perform their head-transplanting job, using Poppy, the cute, little, bug-eyed chihuahua, in their awful experiment.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Good, if a bit overfull
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    pwoodstock23
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Mars Attacks! Is an engaging, funny science fiction film directed by Tim Burton about an alien invasion of Earth from Mars (as the title suggests). Thousands of Flying Saucers appear around Earth, claiming peaceful intentions. Surprising virtually no one, they open fire within 48 hours. The film then follows the president and his immediate inner circle, a few American families, an entrepreneur, a few casino employees and a few others as the deal with this. As you can probably tell, this movie is somewhat bloated character-wise. The movie spends 40 minutes introducing it's many many characters. Many of them go on to serve absolutely no importance (see: Jack Nicholson opening a casino, only for it to blow up, a subplot serving only to give him a second role, or Danny DeVito, who shows up briefly early in the movie, and later comes back only to yell at a few people, plead for his life, and die), but the sheer number of characters keeps it from becoming boring, even when the martians are blowing stuff up for quite a few minutes on end. Director Tim Burton brings his namesake creative imagery here, making the movie's Martians very memorable. For example, when one martian shakes the president's hand, his hand comes of with a long tail, which then impales the president and then extends into the flag of their country, as he falls over onto the war room table, with plenty of miniature UFOs. Oh yeah, spoilers. (pretty much everyone dies) The movie's comedy also keeps it interesting, culminating in a hilarious ending of extreme dues ex machinma played for laughs that is absolutely memorable. Overall, it is a funny, quirky movie that pays tribute to the sci-fi movies of the 50s, both in content and feel, which probably could have cut out a character or two (or maybe three)
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not the satire it wants to be.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Sergeant_Tibbs
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Tim Burton's Mars Attacks! is a homage to 1950s sci-fi that fits in with the ensemble disaster films of the 1990s. I've always been a big fan of Tim Burton, his Big Fish was my first taste of what cinema could be, but even though this film was during the peak of his power, it's still a big let down. It has an insanely huge cast of talent with Jack Nicholson (in two roles), Glenn Close, Natalie Portman, Annette Bening, Michael J. Fox, Danny DeVito, Rod Steiger and many more, all given stock desires and conflicts with none particularly focused on and few resolved. The cast was why I watched it as well as the fact that it's on my watchlist from university in regards to music in film so it was worth watching in some regard but despite my low expectations it was still quite a disappointment. The first half is significantly better than the eye-rolling second, even though not much plot development is made. It's spent slowly setting up all the characters and humanity's reaction to martians. It's quite amusing at times, but never laugh out loud, feeling like it's completely comprised of the quirky side characters of Burton's other films and lacking the protagonist to root for. It's all pretty half decent for what it is, but unfortunately it has horrible and flat special effects which it relies on more than anything. Maybe it was the best of its kind at the time (though Independence Day in the same year was far superior), this is very primitive and most of the time it doesn't look like it belongs in the film's reality. Even some of the non-CGI effects are very poor. Perhaps this was more than Burton could handle or producers intervened, but it doesn't work and he should've tried for a stop motion or puppet effect. It does have some good elements. Danny Elfman's creative score is the biggest part of the homage to the 1950s sci-fi and that music plays a big theme in the story. While the score features the theremin prominently as the alien's signature sound, calling back to The Day The Earth Stood Still, it is the in film pseudo-country music that defeats the aliens. This suggests the idea, regarding pop culture, of what is now considered ordinary, the eeriness of the theremin over the country. However, contrivances in the script are very bothersome and ruin most of its execution. There's little sense of escalation from the first half to the second. It's the cringeworthy comedic and hokey moments in the second half that completely ruin the film and quickly wears out its welcome becoming one awful gag after the other that's doesn't feel like the satire it wants to be. A very weak effort for Burton. 4/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Ridiculous attack, poor film making from Tim Burton
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    aldri-feb
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I used to love watching this movie when I was a kid. I felt the Martians character was creepy and somehow really fun, I watched it over and over again but never got bored. But after about 15 years and watching it again yesterday, my point of view about 'Mars Attacks!' suddenly change. This is a type of movie that gives different impression if you watched it in 1990s and nowadays. May be in 1996 or few years after, 'Mars Attacks!' is still fine and exceptional for viewers but it's boring and silly when viewers watch these days. In other words, this movie gets old for young generation. The storyline itself is more like B-movie. It has no heart and chemistry between their entire casts. I have no idea what was Tim Burton purpose by directing this poor movie. It's one of his worst movie I've ever seen, even worse than 'Dark Shadows'. The only thing that could save this movie is their casts. They didn't act remarkably though but it's fun to see star like Jack Nicholson, Glenn Close, Annette Benning, Pierce Brosnan, Danny De Vito and Michael J. Fox in a movie. And don't forget, it also had young artists that becomes popular these days like Natalie Portman, Jack Black and Sarah Jessica Parker. Overall, 'Mars Attacks!' is not a film that audience would enjoy nowadays, the more years you watch it, the more you dislike this movie. It's different with classic movie like 'Godfather', 'Star Wars' or 'Jurassic Park' that never gets old and everyone could still enjoy even for future generation.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Relax . . . It's Not Supposed To Be High Art!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    capteagen
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I used the summary I did because I get the feeling reading other reviews that people were expecting SFX like those of "Independence Day" or "Alien(s)," etc., and were disappointed in not finding them here. In truth, I believe producer/director Tim Burton and the older cast members in particular knew exactly what they were doing. They directed the film at a general audience to be sure, but also targeted a segment of older viewers like me; the Baby Boomers who came of age at the height of the Cold War and the threat of nuclear annihilation, and/or accidental contamination by nuclear fallout or waste wherein the consequences included things as harmless as "Blinky" the three-eyed fish of The Simpson's fame, to atomic mutations on steroids such as the giant ants in the 50s thriller, "Them." I am the quintessential member of that target audience; I'm 57 years old, male, and grew-up on a diet of Saturday afternoon and "late, late show" television that often included a healthy (or unhealthy depending upon one's views) dose of 1950s SciFi "classics," such as "Earth vs. The Flying Saucers", "War of the Worlds", "The Day The Earth Stood Still", the aforementioned "Them", "I Married A Monster From Outer Space", "The Thing From Another World", and others. Those were the high quality films; those with good scripts, good acting (e.g. Michael Rennie, Patricia Neal, etc.), and enjoyable, if not exactly believable, story lines. Then there were those of much lower quality, e.g. "Zontar, Thing From Venus", "Beast With A Million Eyes", "The Crawling Eye" (known in the UK as "The Trollenberg Terror"), and others. The thing is, at the time people of my generation loved them all, regardless of quality. They were escapist fun, period; and sometimes the cheesier they were, e.g. "Plan Nine From Outer Space," the better. One suspects that Tim Burton, two years younger than me, wasted a lot of Saturday afternoon watching such fare. We know Steven Spielberg did because he said so! Regardless, what Burton and the cast have done is that they created a very tongue-in-cheek and very campy homage to the entire 1950s SciFi genre. I don't want to be a spoiler but suffice it to say that there are sly, and some not so sly, allusions to much of the finest in 1950s schlock. I don't think this next observation will spoil anything, but perhaps one of the most significant, and I believe heartfelt, references to yesteryear is the appearance of the Martian "flying saucers." They clearly are meant to honor the work of the late Ray Harryhausen, the master of stop-action photography. Ray died only last month (May 7, 2013) at the age of 92, but his work as director, cinematographer, and special effects coordinator in such films as "Clash of the Titans", "Jason and the Argonauts", "It Came from Beneath the Sea", and "Earth vs. the Flying Saucers" just to name few, was considered to be the high tech leading edge of SFX in its time. Before the advent of today's computer generated wonders, Ray was a true wizard and even though computer generated graphics are used here, Burton's crew made the saucers look like the work of stop-action photography, which had to be something of a labor of love. In any event, while it may not be the be all and end all of film making, the movie nonetheless accomplishes it's goal of sort of taking us back to a somewhat simpler time, and doing it with equal parts humor and loving attention to cheesy detail.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Ahhhhhhhhh! Mars Attacks!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tbills2
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Okaaaay, aaaand 50,000 points is awarded to Mars Attacks!, for having the awesomest cast of A-list actors in all of movie history! DING * DING * DING * DING * DING * DING * DING Congratulations, Mars Attacks! Here now to claim their prize on the behalf of the filmmakers, please give a warm, Earthly welcome to the Martian Ambassador, from Mars! ACK! ACK! ACK! ACK! Wait, no! Audience, watch out! Get out of here, quick! Ahhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhh! Let's work our way through these top stars, shall we - Jack Nicholson is the coolest actor in Hollywood. Natalie Portman is the starlet of her generation. Glenn Close possesses such a prominent prestige. Annette Bening is peppy and very fine. The smart and sleek Pierce Brosnan who is oh so dashing. The greatly adored Michael J. Fox. America's Sweetheart, Sarah Jessica Parker. Danny DeVito, don't count him out. The strong and sexy Pam Grier. The endearingly hilarious Martin Short, who is so endearingly hilarious. The largely exuberant Jack Black. The rambunctiously sweet Christina Applegate. The greatest man in Vegas, Tom Jones. And the greatest football running-back, Jim Brown. Not too shabby, and you might even recognize a few more familiar faces. Let's work our way through their performances, shall we - Nicholson is purely Jack, 'nough said. Natalie Portman is too good. Close can overact with the best of 'em. Bening is endlessly appealing as a free spirit. Mr. Brosnan insists on pleasing. Michael J. Fox is really good at summoning his inner jerk. Sarah J. is too intelligent to act so witless. DeVito is noticeable even among the biggest stars. Pam Grier is openly big-hearted as she strengthens her legacy as an actress. Marty Short bares a comical confidence. Jack Black has a lot to give and seems preparing for fame. Christina Applegate is briefly buoyant. Tom Jones should stick to singing. And Jim Brown is actually pretty darn decent, he steals the spotlight. Mars Attacks! has good effects, considerable entertainment value, and it is pieced together nicely. Tim Burton loves to take every opportunity to delve into the dark arts, but his talents are best served on the lighter side, case in point, this and Edward Scissorhands.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    You kind of know where Tim Burton was going with it.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Jonny 99
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Tim Burton used his star power to assemble one of the highest power casts you'll see in a mid 90's film. Unfortunately, he doesn't give them that much to do. "Mars Attacks" much like "The Informant!" plays like a joke that doesn't provoke laughter as much as it does a sense of knowing where Burton was going with the film. Basically, he tries to lampoon the 1950's creature feature film particularly "The Day the Earth Stood Still" but an underlying Burton-ian meanspiritness and tendency toward strong violence sucks much of the fun out of the film. The writers provide only a modest amount of fun from which to take leaving Burton to rely on CGI red-spangled speedos on the Martians and the stuntcasting - including Tom Jones wasted by simply playing himself - to push the movie along. Burton cross the spoof line in a few spots and instead simply lifts ideas from much better films particularly Rod Steiger's General Decker a copy of George C Scott General Turgidson from "Dr. Stangelove." The plagiarism serves not as homage but as a sign that you could be watching a much better film. In short, better parody of the same material exists elsewhere.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A pretty good black comedy with Martians and a beautiful ensemble of characters
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Augusta Melbourne
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This stylistic feature of black comedy has put quite a mark on reflecting and perhaps parodying America's attitudes towards culture and materialism. The fact that the design of the UFOs and Martians were less shoddy and more of what we think of them means that it helps to look at these in terms of our assumptions. A great ensemble of character with their own time to shine, the comedy is affectionate as well as outrageous. It's not meant to be predictable, it's the fact that the characters should have seen this one coming. Also, this parody of clich&eacute;s and laughable scenes of science fiction from 1950's B movies should be more recognised. The glitzy costumes and visual flair isn't there just to look at.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of Tim Burton's best.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Alex Holland
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Tim Burton, has done many movies in his career but his funniest film to date is "Mars Attacks". The film is a love letter/spoof of the 50's era of sci-fi B movies,(which viewed today would be laughable). The plot is pretty paper thin but too be honest it's a Tim Burton movie. A group of cruel and tasteless aliens decide to destroy the earth for shits and giggles. While the army and a gong ho general want to nuke the aliens, the president and his peace loving professor want earth and mars to coincide but the aliens don't really care as they enjoy defacing famous landmarks and killing innocent people. The genius of Mars Attacks is that it's a comedy,while most alien invasion films are serious and depressing, Mars Attacks makes fun of the fact that it's a bad movie and does it perfectly. The cast is really second to none,Jack Nicholson is great as both the President and as sleezy alcholic casino owner Art Land. Other cast members include, Glenn Close as a bitchy first lady,Pierce Brosnan as a professor for the white house that wants to analyze and have peace with the martians,Danny Devito as a rude gambler, and even a young Jack Black as a redneck soldier. Mars Attacks is a very smart and funny movie because it doesn't takes itself seriously. I know Tim Burton never talks about this movie, but I think that he should be proud of one of the funniest spoofs ever made.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    ACK ACK ACK (Translated) "Do Not Run We Are Your Friends"
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    leonlouisricci
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    There is just one scene after another that is a colorful, bizarre, twisted and unique Tim Burton vision of life, here, and on Mars. The movie never lets up and is based on the equally colorful and beautifully bent trading cards put out by Topps in 1962 painted by the great Pulp artist Norm Saunders. The film is a faithful adaptation and includes most of the card images all presented in sharp primary colors and given a respectful representation. This is a top notch Black Comedy that is funny, violent, and irreverent. It is favorably factitious and an amazing adventure with a lurid and gross artistic quality associated with the Director's style and in-sensibilities. The stellar cast is not necessary but all seem to be having a lot of fun. The visuals are the star and the script is less impressive, but the overall effect is cutting edge cinema that has an appeal for the slightly off key karma of the underground but marketed for the main stream. The film's detractors are left with not much to complain about (but they do) except the movie's brazen belief that it is a design of the different for the norm. But for them it is ridiculed and unappreciated.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Sci-Fi Satire With A Hidden Agenda
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Dalbert Pringle
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    *Possible Spoilers!* "We come in peace!" Mars Attacks was a totally "cool" way for director Tim Burton to annihilate such despicable big-name actors as Jack Nicholson, Danny DeVito, Jack Black, Sarah Jesica Parker, Glenn Close, Michael J. Fox and Martin Short (Phew! What a list of all-star casualties, eh!?) - And have a helluva lot of fun dong it. I only wish that Burton had also managed to have that annoying flake, Annette Bening, gunned down and vaporized, as well. Hideous-looking alien-bastards from Mars (vicious, cruel, and deceptive), toting insta-fry ray guns, land on Earth, and after hoodwinking the gullible public into thinking that this is a visit of friendship, commence with a horrific attack of mass-destruction, blowing up everything in site to smithereens. Can nothing save Earth from these ugly, bubble-headed, little creeps and their nasty, sadistic destructiveness?? Well, little do these menacing Martian-midgets know that we have discovered our very own secret weapon against them that's even more devastating than all of the nuclear weapons in the world. Yes. Indeed. And, who would've ever thought that Grandma Norris's "Slim Whitman" records would actually serve as our only defense against the Martians and inevitably save the day? I found this Sci-Fi/Comedy/Action film from 1996 to be a really uncharacteristic picture from Tim Burton. Presented as a tribute to 1950's UFO movies, Mars Attacks (with its awesome visual effects) delivers a kooky blend of twisted humor and ultra-violence that, when it works (which is about two-thirds of the time), is guaranteed to put a smile on the face of any fan of B-Movie schlock. P.S. - Yes, I do agree that, when it came to bad taste, Burton certainly did push the limits when he had the Martians perform their head-transplanting job, using Poppy, the cute, little, bug-eyed chihuahua, in their awful experiment.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Good, if a bit overfull
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    pwoodstock23
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Mars Attacks! Is an engaging, funny science fiction film directed by Tim Burton about an alien invasion of Earth from Mars (as the title suggests). Thousands of Flying Saucers appear around Earth, claiming peaceful intentions. Surprising virtually no one, they open fire within 48 hours. The film then follows the president and his immediate inner circle, a few American families, an entrepreneur, a few casino employees and a few others as the deal with this. As you can probably tell, this movie is somewhat bloated character-wise. The movie spends 40 minutes introducing it's many many characters. Many of them go on to serve absolutely no importance (see: Jack Nicholson opening a casino, only for it to blow up, a subplot serving only to give him a second role, or Danny DeVito, who shows up briefly early in the movie, and later comes back only to yell at a few people, plead for his life, and die), but the sheer number of characters keeps it from becoming boring, even when the martians are blowing stuff up for quite a few minutes on end. Director Tim Burton brings his namesake creative imagery here, making the movie's Martians very memorable. For example, when one martian shakes the president's hand, his hand comes of with a long tail, which then impales the president and then extends into the flag of their country, as he falls over onto the war room table, with plenty of miniature UFOs. Oh yeah, spoilers. (pretty much everyone dies) The movie's comedy also keeps it interesting, culminating in a hilarious ending of extreme dues ex machinma played for laughs that is absolutely memorable. Overall, it is a funny, quirky movie that pays tribute to the sci-fi movies of the 50s, both in content and feel, which probably could have cut out a character or two (or maybe three)
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not the satire it wants to be.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Sergeant_Tibbs
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Tim Burton's Mars Attacks! is a homage to 1950s sci-fi that fits in with the ensemble disaster films of the 1990s. I've always been a big fan of Tim Burton, his Big Fish was my first taste of what cinema could be, but even though this film was during the peak of his power, it's still a big let down. It has an insanely huge cast of talent with Jack Nicholson (in two roles), Glenn Close, Natalie Portman, Annette Bening, Michael J. Fox, Danny DeVito, Rod Steiger and many more, all given stock desires and conflicts with none particularly focused on and few resolved. The cast was why I watched it as well as the fact that it's on my watchlist from university in regards to music in film so it was worth watching in some regard but despite my low expectations it was still quite a disappointment. The first half is significantly better than the eye-rolling second, even though not much plot development is made. It's spent slowly setting up all the characters and humanity's reaction to martians. It's quite amusing at times, but never laugh out loud, feeling like it's completely comprised of the quirky side characters of Burton's other films and lacking the protagonist to root for. It's all pretty half decent for what it is, but unfortunately it has horrible and flat special effects which it relies on more than anything. Maybe it was the best of its kind at the time (though Independence Day in the same year was far superior), this is very primitive and most of the time it doesn't look like it belongs in the film's reality. Even some of the non-CGI effects are very poor. Perhaps this was more than Burton could handle or producers intervened, but it doesn't work and he should've tried for a stop motion or puppet effect. It does have some good elements. Danny Elfman's creative score is the biggest part of the homage to the 1950s sci-fi and that music plays a big theme in the story. While the score features the theremin prominently as the alien's signature sound, calling back to The Day The Earth Stood Still, it is the in film pseudo-country music that defeats the aliens. This suggests the idea, regarding pop culture, of what is now considered ordinary, the eeriness of the theremin over the country. However, contrivances in the script are very bothersome and ruin most of its execution. There's little sense of escalation from the first half to the second. It's the cringeworthy comedic and hokey moments in the second half that completely ruin the film and quickly wears out its welcome becoming one awful gag after the other that's doesn't feel like the satire it wants to be. A very weak effort for Burton. 4/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Ridiculous attack, poor film making from Tim Burton
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    aldri-feb
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I used to love watching this movie when I was a kid. I felt the Martians character was creepy and somehow really fun, I watched it over and over again but never got bored. But after about 15 years and watching it again yesterday, my point of view about 'Mars Attacks!' suddenly change. This is a type of movie that gives different impression if you watched it in 1990s and nowadays. May be in 1996 or few years after, 'Mars Attacks!' is still fine and exceptional for viewers but it's boring and silly when viewers watch these days. In other words, this movie gets old for young generation. The storyline itself is more like B-movie. It has no heart and chemistry between their entire casts. I have no idea what was Tim Burton purpose by directing this poor movie. It's one of his worst movie I've ever seen, even worse than 'Dark Shadows'. The only thing that could save this movie is their casts. They didn't act remarkably though but it's fun to see star like Jack Nicholson, Glenn Close, Annette Benning, Pierce Brosnan, Danny De Vito and Michael J. Fox in a movie. And don't forget, it also had young artists that becomes popular these days like Natalie Portman, Jack Black and Sarah Jessica Parker. Overall, 'Mars Attacks!' is not a film that audience would enjoy nowadays, the more years you watch it, the more you dislike this movie. It's different with classic movie like 'Godfather', 'Star Wars' or 'Jurassic Park' that never gets old and everyone could still enjoy even for future generation.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Relax . . . It's Not Supposed To Be High Art!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    capteagen
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I used the summary I did because I get the feeling reading other reviews that people were expecting SFX like those of "Independence Day" or "Alien(s)," etc., and were disappointed in not finding them here. In truth, I believe producer/director Tim Burton and the older cast members in particular knew exactly what they were doing. They directed the film at a general audience to be sure, but also targeted a segment of older viewers like me; the Baby Boomers who came of age at the height of the Cold War and the threat of nuclear annihilation, and/or accidental contamination by nuclear fallout or waste wherein the consequences included things as harmless as "Blinky" the three-eyed fish of The Simpson's fame, to atomic mutations on steroids such as the giant ants in the 50s thriller, "Them." I am the quintessential member of that target audience; I'm 57 years old, male, and grew-up on a diet of Saturday afternoon and "late, late show" television that often included a healthy (or unhealthy depending upon one's views) dose of 1950s SciFi "classics," such as "Earth vs. The Flying Saucers", "War of the Worlds", "The Day The Earth Stood Still", the aforementioned "Them", "I Married A Monster From Outer Space", "The Thing From Another World", and others. Those were the high quality films; those with good scripts, good acting (e.g. Michael Rennie, Patricia Neal, etc.), and enjoyable, if not exactly believable, story lines. Then there were those of much lower quality, e.g. "Zontar, Thing From Venus", "Beast With A Million Eyes", "The Crawling Eye" (known in the UK as "The Trollenberg Terror"), and others. The thing is, at the time people of my generation loved them all, regardless of quality. They were escapist fun, period; and sometimes the cheesier they were, e.g. "Plan Nine From Outer Space," the better. One suspects that Tim Burton, two years younger than me, wasted a lot of Saturday afternoon watching such fare. We know Steven Spielberg did because he said so! Regardless, what Burton and the cast have done is that they created a very tongue-in-cheek and very campy homage to the entire 1950s SciFi genre. I don't want to be a spoiler but suffice it to say that there are sly, and some not so sly, allusions to much of the finest in 1950s schlock. I don't think this next observation will spoil anything, but perhaps one of the most significant, and I believe heartfelt, references to yesteryear is the appearance of the Martian "flying saucers." They clearly are meant to honor the work of the late Ray Harryhausen, the master of stop-action photography. Ray died only last month (May 7, 2013) at the age of 92, but his work as director, cinematographer, and special effects coordinator in such films as "Clash of the Titans", "Jason and the Argonauts", "It Came from Beneath the Sea", and "Earth vs. the Flying Saucers" just to name few, was considered to be the high tech leading edge of SFX in its time. Before the advent of today's computer generated wonders, Ray was a true wizard and even though computer generated graphics are used here, Burton's crew made the saucers look like the work of stop-action photography, which had to be something of a labor of love. In any event, while it may not be the be all and end all of film making, the movie nonetheless accomplishes it's goal of sort of taking us back to a somewhat simpler time, and doing it with equal parts humor and loving attention to cheesy detail.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Ahhhhhhhhh! Mars Attacks!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tbills2
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Okaaaay, aaaand 50,000 points is awarded to Mars Attacks!, for having the awesomest cast of A-list actors in all of movie history! DING * DING * DING * DING * DING * DING * DING Congratulations, Mars Attacks! Here now to claim their prize on the behalf of the filmmakers, please give a warm, Earthly welcome to the Martian Ambassador, from Mars! ACK! ACK! ACK! ACK! Wait, no! Audience, watch out! Get out of here, quick! Ahhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhh! Let's work our way through these top stars, shall we - Jack Nicholson is the coolest actor in Hollywood. Natalie Portman is the starlet of her generation. Glenn Close possesses such a prominent prestige. Annette Bening is peppy and very fine. The smart and sleek Pierce Brosnan who is oh so dashing. The greatly adored Michael J. Fox. America's Sweetheart, Sarah Jessica Parker. Danny DeVito, don't count him out. The strong and sexy Pam Grier. The endearingly hilarious Martin Short, who is so endearingly hilarious. The largely exuberant Jack Black. The rambunctiously sweet Christina Applegate. The greatest man in Vegas, Tom Jones. And the greatest football running-back, Jim Brown. Not too shabby, and you might even recognize a few more familiar faces. Let's work our way through their performances, shall we - Nicholson is purely Jack, 'nough said. Natalie Portman is too good. Close can overact with the best of 'em. Bening is endlessly appealing as a free spirit. Mr. Brosnan insists on pleasing. Michael J. Fox is really good at summoning his inner jerk. Sarah J. is too intelligent to act so witless. DeVito is noticeable even among the biggest stars. Pam Grier is openly big-hearted as she strengthens her legacy as an actress. Marty Short bares a comical confidence. Jack Black has a lot to give and seems preparing for fame. Christina Applegate is briefly buoyant. Tom Jones should stick to singing. And Jim Brown is actually pretty darn decent, he steals the spotlight. Mars Attacks! has good effects, considerable entertainment value, and it is pieced together nicely. Tim Burton loves to take every opportunity to delve into the dark arts, but his talents are best served on the lighter side, case in point, this and Edward Scissorhands.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    You kind of know where Tim Burton was going with it.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Jonny 99
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Tim Burton used his star power to assemble one of the highest power casts you'll see in a mid 90's film. Unfortunately, he doesn't give them that much to do. "Mars Attacks" much like "The Informant!" plays like a joke that doesn't provoke laughter as much as it does a sense of knowing where Burton was going with the film. Basically, he tries to lampoon the 1950's creature feature film particularly "The Day the Earth Stood Still" but an underlying Burton-ian meanspiritness and tendency toward strong violence sucks much of the fun out of the film. The writers provide only a modest amount of fun from which to take leaving Burton to rely on CGI red-spangled speedos on the Martians and the stuntcasting - including Tom Jones wasted by simply playing himself - to push the movie along. Burton cross the spoof line in a few spots and instead simply lifts ideas from much better films particularly Rod Steiger's General Decker a copy of George C Scott General Turgidson from "Dr. Stangelove." The plagiarism serves not as homage but as a sign that you could be watching a much better film. In short, better parody of the same material exists elsewhere.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A pretty good black comedy with Martians and a beautiful ensemble of characters
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Augusta Melbourne
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This stylistic feature of black comedy has put quite a mark on reflecting and perhaps parodying America's attitudes towards culture and materialism. The fact that the design of the UFOs and Martians were less shoddy and more of what we think of them means that it helps to look at these in terms of our assumptions. A great ensemble of character with their own time to shine, the comedy is affectionate as well as outrageous. It's not meant to be predictable, it's the fact that the characters should have seen this one coming. Also, this parody of clich&eacute;s and laughable scenes of science fiction from 1950's B movies should be more recognised. The glitzy costumes and visual flair isn't there just to look at.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of Tim Burton's best.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Alex Holland
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Tim Burton, has done many movies in his career but his funniest film to date is "Mars Attacks". The film is a love letter/spoof of the 50's era of sci-fi B movies,(which viewed today would be laughable). The plot is pretty paper thin but too be honest it's a Tim Burton movie. A group of cruel and tasteless aliens decide to destroy the earth for shits and giggles. While the army and a gong ho general want to nuke the aliens, the president and his peace loving professor want earth and mars to coincide but the aliens don't really care as they enjoy defacing famous landmarks and killing innocent people. The genius of Mars Attacks is that it's a comedy,while most alien invasion films are serious and depressing, Mars Attacks makes fun of the fact that it's a bad movie and does it perfectly. The cast is really second to none,Jack Nicholson is great as both the President and as sleezy alcholic casino owner Art Land. Other cast members include, Glenn Close as a bitchy first lady,Pierce Brosnan as a professor for the white house that wants to analyze and have peace with the martians,Danny Devito as a rude gambler, and even a young Jack Black as a redneck soldier. Mars Attacks is a very smart and funny movie because it doesn't takes itself seriously. I know Tim Burton never talks about this movie, but I think that he should be proud of one of the funniest spoofs ever made.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    ACK ACK ACK (Translated) "Do Not Run We Are Your Friends"
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    leonlouisricci
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    There is just one scene after another that is a colorful, bizarre, twisted and unique Tim Burton vision of life, here, and on Mars. The movie never lets up and is based on the equally colorful and beautifully bent trading cards put out by Topps in 1962 painted by the great Pulp artist Norm Saunders. The film is a faithful adaptation and includes most of the card images all presented in sharp primary colors and given a respectful representation. This is a top notch Black Comedy that is funny, violent, and irreverent. It is favorably factitious and an amazing adventure with a lurid and gross artistic quality associated with the Director's style and in-sensibilities. The stellar cast is not necessary but all seem to be having a lot of fun. The visuals are the star and the script is less impressive, but the overall effect is cutting edge cinema that has an appeal for the slightly off key karma of the underground but marketed for the main stream. The film's detractors are left with not much to complain about (but they do) except the movie's brazen belief that it is a design of the different for the norm. But for them it is ridiculed and unappreciated.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Sci-Fi Satire With A Hidden Agenda
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Dalbert Pringle
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    *Possible Spoilers!* "We come in peace!" Mars Attacks was a totally "cool" way for director Tim Burton to annihilate such despicable big-name actors as Jack Nicholson, Danny DeVito, Jack Black, Sarah Jesica Parker, Glenn Close, Michael J. Fox and Martin Short (Phew! What a list of all-star casualties, eh!?) - And have a helluva lot of fun dong it. I only wish that Burton had also managed to have that annoying flake, Annette Bening, gunned down and vaporized, as well. Hideous-looking alien-bastards from Mars (vicious, cruel, and deceptive), toting insta-fry ray guns, land on Earth, and after hoodwinking the gullible public into thinking that this is a visit of friendship, commence with a horrific attack of mass-destruction, blowing up everything in site to smithereens. Can nothing save Earth from these ugly, bubble-headed, little creeps and their nasty, sadistic destructiveness?? Well, little do these menacing Martian-midgets know that we have discovered our very own secret weapon against them that's even more devastating than all of the nuclear weapons in the world. Yes. Indeed. And, who would've ever thought that Grandma Norris's "Slim Whitman" records would actually serve as our only defense against the Martians and inevitably save the day? I found this Sci-Fi/Comedy/Action film from 1996 to be a really uncharacteristic picture from Tim Burton. Presented as a tribute to 1950's UFO movies, Mars Attacks (with its awesome visual effects) delivers a kooky blend of twisted humor and ultra-violence that, when it works (which is about two-thirds of the time), is guaranteed to put a smile on the face of any fan of B-Movie schlock. P.S. - Yes, I do agree that, when it came to bad taste, Burton certainly did push the limits when he had the Martians perform their head-transplanting job, using Poppy, the cute, little, bug-eyed chihuahua, in their awful experiment.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Good, if a bit overfull
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    pwoodstock23
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Mars Attacks! Is an engaging, funny science fiction film directed by Tim Burton about an alien invasion of Earth from Mars (as the title suggests). Thousands of Flying Saucers appear around Earth, claiming peaceful intentions. Surprising virtually no one, they open fire within 48 hours. The film then follows the president and his immediate inner circle, a few American families, an entrepreneur, a few casino employees and a few others as the deal with this. As you can probably tell, this movie is somewhat bloated character-wise. The movie spends 40 minutes introducing it's many many characters. Many of them go on to serve absolutely no importance (see: Jack Nicholson opening a casino, only for it to blow up, a subplot serving only to give him a second role, or Danny DeVito, who shows up briefly early in the movie, and later comes back only to yell at a few people, plead for his life, and die), but the sheer number of characters keeps it from becoming boring, even when the martians are blowing stuff up for quite a few minutes on end. Director Tim Burton brings his namesake creative imagery here, making the movie's Martians very memorable. For example, when one martian shakes the president's hand, his hand comes of with a long tail, which then impales the president and then extends into the flag of their country, as he falls over onto the war room table, with plenty of miniature UFOs. Oh yeah, spoilers. (pretty much everyone dies) The movie's comedy also keeps it interesting, culminating in a hilarious ending of extreme dues ex machinma played for laughs that is absolutely memorable. Overall, it is a funny, quirky movie that pays tribute to the sci-fi movies of the 50s, both in content and feel, which probably could have cut out a character or two (or maybe three)
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not the satire it wants to be.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Sergeant_Tibbs
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Tim Burton's Mars Attacks! is a homage to 1950s sci-fi that fits in with the ensemble disaster films of the 1990s. I've always been a big fan of Tim Burton, his Big Fish was my first taste of what cinema could be, but even though this film was during the peak of his power, it's still a big let down. It has an insanely huge cast of talent with Jack Nicholson (in two roles), Glenn Close, Natalie Portman, Annette Bening, Michael J. Fox, Danny DeVito, Rod Steiger and many more, all given stock desires and conflicts with none particularly focused on and few resolved. The cast was why I watched it as well as the fact that it's on my watchlist from university in regards to music in film so it was worth watching in some regard but despite my low expectations it was still quite a disappointment. The first half is significantly better than the eye-rolling second, even though not much plot development is made. It's spent slowly setting up all the characters and humanity's reaction to martians. It's quite amusing at times, but never laugh out loud, feeling like it's completely comprised of the quirky side characters of Burton's other films and lacking the protagonist to root for. It's all pretty half decent for what it is, but unfortunately it has horrible and flat special effects which it relies on more than anything. Maybe it was the best of its kind at the time (though Independence Day in the same year was far superior), this is very primitive and most of the time it doesn't look like it belongs in the film's reality. Even some of the non-CGI effects are very poor. Perhaps this was more than Burton could handle or producers intervened, but it doesn't work and he should've tried for a stop motion or puppet effect. It does have some good elements. Danny Elfman's creative score is the biggest part of the homage to the 1950s sci-fi and that music plays a big theme in the story. While the score features the theremin prominently as the alien's signature sound, calling back to The Day The Earth Stood Still, it is the in film pseudo-country music that defeats the aliens. This suggests the idea, regarding pop culture, of what is now considered ordinary, the eeriness of the theremin over the country. However, contrivances in the script are very bothersome and ruin most of its execution. There's little sense of escalation from the first half to the second. It's the cringeworthy comedic and hokey moments in the second half that completely ruin the film and quickly wears out its welcome becoming one awful gag after the other that's doesn't feel like the satire it wants to be. A very weak effort for Burton. 4/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Ridiculous attack, poor film making from Tim Burton
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    aldri-feb
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I used to love watching this movie when I was a kid. I felt the Martians character was creepy and somehow really fun, I watched it over and over again but never got bored. But after about 15 years and watching it again yesterday, my point of view about 'Mars Attacks!' suddenly change. This is a type of movie that gives different impression if you watched it in 1990s and nowadays. May be in 1996 or few years after, 'Mars Attacks!' is still fine and exceptional for viewers but it's boring and silly when viewers watch these days. In other words, this movie gets old for young generation. The storyline itself is more like B-movie. It has no heart and chemistry between their entire casts. I have no idea what was Tim Burton purpose by directing this poor movie. It's one of his worst movie I've ever seen, even worse than 'Dark Shadows'. The only thing that could save this movie is their casts. They didn't act remarkably though but it's fun to see star like Jack Nicholson, Glenn Close, Annette Benning, Pierce Brosnan, Danny De Vito and Michael J. Fox in a movie. And don't forget, it also had young artists that becomes popular these days like Natalie Portman, Jack Black and Sarah Jessica Parker. Overall, 'Mars Attacks!' is not a film that audience would enjoy nowadays, the more years you watch it, the more you dislike this movie. It's different with classic movie like 'Godfather', 'Star Wars' or 'Jurassic Park' that never gets old and everyone could still enjoy even for future generation.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Relax . . . It's Not Supposed To Be High Art!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    capteagen
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I used the summary I did because I get the feeling reading other reviews that people were expecting SFX like those of "Independence Day" or "Alien(s)," etc., and were disappointed in not finding them here. In truth, I believe producer/director Tim Burton and the older cast members in particular knew exactly what they were doing. They directed the film at a general audience to be sure, but also targeted a segment of older viewers like me; the Baby Boomers who came of age at the height of the Cold War and the threat of nuclear annihilation, and/or accidental contamination by nuclear fallout or waste wherein the consequences included things as harmless as "Blinky" the three-eyed fish of The Simpson's fame, to atomic mutations on steroids such as the giant ants in the 50s thriller, "Them." I am the quintessential member of that target audience; I'm 57 years old, male, and grew-up on a diet of Saturday afternoon and "late, late show" television that often included a healthy (or unhealthy depending upon one's views) dose of 1950s SciFi "classics," such as "Earth vs. The Flying Saucers", "War of the Worlds", "The Day The Earth Stood Still", the aforementioned "Them", "I Married A Monster From Outer Space", "The Thing From Another World", and others. Those were the high quality films; those with good scripts, good acting (e.g. Michael Rennie, Patricia Neal, etc.), and enjoyable, if not exactly believable, story lines. Then there were those of much lower quality, e.g. "Zontar, Thing From Venus", "Beast With A Million Eyes", "The Crawling Eye" (known in the UK as "The Trollenberg Terror"), and others. The thing is, at the time people of my generation loved them all, regardless of quality. They were escapist fun, period; and sometimes the cheesier they were, e.g. "Plan Nine From Outer Space," the better. One suspects that Tim Burton, two years younger than me, wasted a lot of Saturday afternoon watching such fare. We know Steven Spielberg did because he said so! Regardless, what Burton and the cast have done is that they created a very tongue-in-cheek and very campy homage to the entire 1950s SciFi genre. I don't want to be a spoiler but suffice it to say that there are sly, and some not so sly, allusions to much of the finest in 1950s schlock. I don't think this next observation will spoil anything, but perhaps one of the most significant, and I believe heartfelt, references to yesteryear is the appearance of the Martian "flying saucers." They clearly are meant to honor the work of the late Ray Harryhausen, the master of stop-action photography. Ray died only last month (May 7, 2013) at the age of 92, but his work as director, cinematographer, and special effects coordinator in such films as "Clash of the Titans", "Jason and the Argonauts", "It Came from Beneath the Sea", and "Earth vs. the Flying Saucers" just to name few, was considered to be the high tech leading edge of SFX in its time. Before the advent of today's computer generated wonders, Ray was a true wizard and even though computer generated graphics are used here, Burton's crew made the saucers look like the work of stop-action photography, which had to be something of a labor of love. In any event, while it may not be the be all and end all of film making, the movie nonetheless accomplishes it's goal of sort of taking us back to a somewhat simpler time, and doing it with equal parts humor and loving attention to cheesy detail.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Ahhhhhhhhh! Mars Attacks!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tbills2
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Okaaaay, aaaand 50,000 points is awarded to Mars Attacks!, for having the awesomest cast of A-list actors in all of movie history! DING * DING * DING * DING * DING * DING * DING Congratulations, Mars Attacks! Here now to claim their prize on the behalf of the filmmakers, please give a warm, Earthly welcome to the Martian Ambassador, from Mars! ACK! ACK! ACK! ACK! Wait, no! Audience, watch out! Get out of here, quick! Ahhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhh! Let's work our way through these top stars, shall we - Jack Nicholson is the coolest actor in Hollywood. Natalie Portman is the starlet of her generation. Glenn Close possesses such a prominent prestige. Annette Bening is peppy and very fine. The smart and sleek Pierce Brosnan who is oh so dashing. The greatly adored Michael J. Fox. America's Sweetheart, Sarah Jessica Parker. Danny DeVito, don't count him out. The strong and sexy Pam Grier. The endearingly hilarious Martin Short, who is so endearingly hilarious. The largely exuberant Jack Black. The rambunctiously sweet Christina Applegate. The greatest man in Vegas, Tom Jones. And the greatest football running-back, Jim Brown. Not too shabby, and you might even recognize a few more familiar faces. Let's work our way through their performances, shall we - Nicholson is purely Jack, 'nough said. Natalie Portman is too good. Close can overact with the best of 'em. Bening is endlessly appealing as a free spirit. Mr. Brosnan insists on pleasing. Michael J. Fox is really good at summoning his inner jerk. Sarah J. is too intelligent to act so witless. DeVito is noticeable even among the biggest stars. Pam Grier is openly big-hearted as she strengthens her legacy as an actress. Marty Short bares a comical confidence. Jack Black has a lot to give and seems preparing for fame. Christina Applegate is briefly buoyant. Tom Jones should stick to singing. And Jim Brown is actually pretty darn decent, he steals the spotlight. Mars Attacks! has good effects, considerable entertainment value, and it is pieced together nicely. Tim Burton loves to take every opportunity to delve into the dark arts, but his talents are best served on the lighter side, case in point, this and Edward Scissorhands.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    You kind of know where Tim Burton was going with it.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Jonny 99
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Tim Burton used his star power to assemble one of the highest power casts you'll see in a mid 90's film. Unfortunately, he doesn't give them that much to do. "Mars Attacks" much like "The Informant!" plays like a joke that doesn't provoke laughter as much as it does a sense of knowing where Burton was going with the film. Basically, he tries to lampoon the 1950's creature feature film particularly "The Day the Earth Stood Still" but an underlying Burton-ian meanspiritness and tendency toward strong violence sucks much of the fun out of the film. The writers provide only a modest amount of fun from which to take leaving Burton to rely on CGI red-spangled speedos on the Martians and the stuntcasting - including Tom Jones wasted by simply playing himself - to push the movie along. Burton cross the spoof line in a few spots and instead simply lifts ideas from much better films particularly Rod Steiger's General Decker a copy of George C Scott General Turgidson from "Dr. Stangelove." The plagiarism serves not as homage but as a sign that you could be watching a much better film. In short, better parody of the same material exists elsewhere.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A pretty good black comedy with Martians and a beautiful ensemble of characters
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Augusta Melbourne
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This stylistic feature of black comedy has put quite a mark on reflecting and perhaps parodying America's attitudes towards culture and materialism. The fact that the design of the UFOs and Martians were less shoddy and more of what we think of them means that it helps to look at these in terms of our assumptions. A great ensemble of character with their own time to shine, the comedy is affectionate as well as outrageous. It's not meant to be predictable, it's the fact that the characters should have seen this one coming. Also, this parody of clich&eacute;s and laughable scenes of science fiction from 1950's B movies should be more recognised. The glitzy costumes and visual flair isn't there just to look at.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of Tim Burton's best.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Alex Holland
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Tim Burton, has done many movies in his career but his funniest film to date is "Mars Attacks". The film is a love letter/spoof of the 50's era of sci-fi B movies,(which viewed today would be laughable). The plot is pretty paper thin but too be honest it's a Tim Burton movie. A group of cruel and tasteless aliens decide to destroy the earth for shits and giggles. While the army and a gong ho general want to nuke the aliens, the president and his peace loving professor want earth and mars to coincide but the aliens don't really care as they enjoy defacing famous landmarks and killing innocent people. The genius of Mars Attacks is that it's a comedy,while most alien invasion films are serious and depressing, Mars Attacks makes fun of the fact that it's a bad movie and does it perfectly. The cast is really second to none,Jack Nicholson is great as both the President and as sleezy alcholic casino owner Art Land. Other cast members include, Glenn Close as a bitchy first lady,Pierce Brosnan as a professor for the white house that wants to analyze and have peace with the martians,Danny Devito as a rude gambler, and even a young Jack Black as a redneck soldier. Mars Attacks is a very smart and funny movie because it doesn't takes itself seriously. I know Tim Burton never talks about this movie, but I think that he should be proud of one of the funniest spoofs ever made.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    ACK ACK ACK (Translated) "Do Not Run We Are Your Friends"
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    leonlouisricci
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    There is just one scene after another that is a colorful, bizarre, twisted and unique Tim Burton vision of life, here, and on Mars. The movie never lets up and is based on the equally colorful and beautifully bent trading cards put out by Topps in 1962 painted by the great Pulp artist Norm Saunders. The film is a faithful adaptation and includes most of the card images all presented in sharp primary colors and given a respectful representation. This is a top notch Black Comedy that is funny, violent, and irreverent. It is favorably factitious and an amazing adventure with a lurid and gross artistic quality associated with the Director's style and in-sensibilities. The stellar cast is not necessary but all seem to be having a lot of fun. The visuals are the star and the script is less impressive, but the overall effect is cutting edge cinema that has an appeal for the slightly off key karma of the underground but marketed for the main stream. The film's detractors are left with not much to complain about (but they do) except the movie's brazen belief that it is a design of the different for the norm. But for them it is ridiculed and unappreciated.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
 </reviews>
</filme>
