<filme>
 <id>
  24
 </id>
 <imdburl>
  http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0113326
 </imdburl>
 <ano>
  1995
 </ano>
 <titulo>
  Arrebentando em Nova York
 </titulo>
 <rating>
  6.6
 </rating>
 <sinopse>
  A young man visiting and helping his uncle in New York City finds himself forced to fight a street gang and the mob with his martial art skills.
 </sinopse>
 <storyline>
  Keong comes from Hong Kong to visit New York for his uncle's wedding. His uncle runs a market in the Bronx and Keong offers to help out while Uncle is on his honeymoon. During his stay in the Bronx, Keong befriends a neighbor kid and beats up some neighborhood thugs who cause problems at the market. Meanwhile, one of those petty thugs in the local gang stumbles into a criminal situation way over his head. Blinded by greed, his involvement draws his gang, the kid, Keong, and the whole neighborhood into a deadly crossfire. When the lazy cops fail to successfully resolve matters, Keong takes things into his own hands. Needless to say, much spectacular kung-fu and outrageous action sequences follow....
 </storyline>
 <generos>
  <genero>
   Action
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Comedy
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Crime
  </genero>
 </generos>
 <keywords>
  <keyword>
   gang
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   greed
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   wedding
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   martial arts
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   new york city
  </keyword>
 </keywords>
 <diretores>
  <diretor>
   Stanley Tong
  </diretor>
 </diretores>
 <escritores>
  <escritor>
   Edward Tang
  </escritor>
  <escritor>
   Fibe Ma
  </escritor>
 </escritores>
 <atores>
  <ator>
   Jackie Chan
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Anita Mui
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Fran&ccedil;oise Yip
  </ator>
 </atores>
 <reviews>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Funny and spectacular Jackie Chan movie in his first American super hit with highlights provided by a hovercraft
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ma-cortes
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Amusing and entertaining Chan film in which he demonstrates his sensational skills as a great action man . It deals with a young man named Keong (Jackie Chan) visiting and helping his uncle in New York City finds himself forced to fight a street gang and the mob with his martial art abilities . His uncle has a local Chinese supermarket, which he owns and is in the process of selling to Elaine (Anita Mui). Later on , Keong befriends a neighbor kid and his sister (Francois Yip) and beats up some neighborhood thugs . Hong Kong/US/Canada action comedy full of over-the-top struggles , excitement , thrills , ingenious stunts , slapstick , lots of brawls but with abundant humor and tongue-in-cheek . This fun movie is plenty of intrigue , unstopped action , and overwhelming stunt-work with breathtaking ending images including a hovercraft . Jackie Chan is top notch as one army man fighting a group of heinous villains and as always he makes his own stunts like is well showed at the final credits . Awesome , incredible stunts and brief comic touches , as usual ; the picture is better constructed than Chan's predecessors films . The lighting-paced storyline slows down at times , but frantic action sequences make up for it . Spotlights movie include spectacular fights , including bounds and leaps , impressive and interminable struggles , an impressive final struggle between Jackie Chan and enemies . The warehouse fight scene took twenty days to film, with Chan having to teach the local stunt players to fight "Hong Kong style". In addition other fine action sequences in overwhelming and extraordinary style . The script called for a leap from the top of a parking lot to a fire escape on the floor below on the building across the street , as is his custom, director Stanley Tong attempted the stunt before asking any actors to do so. He tried it with the help of a cable harness, but quickly decided it would be safer without the harness. The landing point was not visible from the point where the jump began, so tape was placed on the take-off point as a guide ,the jump was completed perfectly by 'Chan, Jackie' on the first attempt, doing his own stunts as is his custom . The jump was captured by four cameras. This is an acceptable action movie distinguished by nicely cinematography of the spectacular sequences , and contains agreeable sense of humor as well as previous entries . Jackie Chan usually forms couple to notorious actresses as Maggie Chung and Michelle Yeoh . In this outing Jackie teams up to gorgeous Francoise Yip (who broke her leg while filming the scene where she rides a motorbike across the tops of parked cars , she insisted on returning to the set after her leg was plastered at hospital) and prestigious Chinese actress Anita Mui , a fine action star in their own right but sadly she early died by cancer . Both of them starred together several films such as &uml;Mr Canton and Lady Rose&uml; and &uml;Legend of the drunken master&uml; . Filming in Vancouver, Canada on October 6th, 1994, Chan broke his right ankle while attempting the scene where he jumps onto the hovercraft. Despite the injury, he was present at the premiere of &uml;The legend of the drunken fighter&uml; at the Vancouver International Film Festival that night. Later in the production, Tong sprained his ankle, completing the film on crutches . Two stunt women also broke their legs during the filming of the motorcycle chase. The picture achieved big success in China , USA and all around the world . However , Jackie Chan's failed at Box-office in his American debut ,&uml;Battle creek brawl&uml; . Chan is a hard-working actor and director throughout his long and varied career . Chan usually pays overt homage to two of his greatest influences as Charles Chaplin and Harold Lloyd . He went on playing &uml;Cannoball&uml; , &uml;The protector&uml; and "Rumble in the Bronx", until getting all American success with &uml;Shangai Knights&uml; , &uml;The tuxedo&uml; , &uml;Around the world in 80 days&uml; and &uml;Rush hour&uml; trilogy , and the recent &uml;Karate kid&uml;. Of course , his biggest hits were &uml;The Police story&uml; series that won the Golden Horse Award, a Chinese version of the Oscar , the first was titled &uml;Police story (1985)&uml; directed by the same Chan , it was a perfect action film for enthusiastic of the genre ; the following was &uml;Police story 2 (1988)&uml; also pretty violent and with abundant humor touches . It's followed by &uml;Supercop&uml; or &uml;Police story 3&uml; and finally , &uml;Police story IV : Crime story&uml; . The picture is well produced by the great Asian producer Raymond Chow and Golden Harvest production and compellingly directed by Stanley Tong and helped by Jackie Chan . Rating : Acceptable and passable , the picture has its sensational moments here and there , but also with abundant humor touches mostly provided by its agile star , the super Jackie stunningly accompanied by Anita Mui and Francois Yip . It's a perfect action film for enthusiasts of the genre and especially for Jackie fans .
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Chan fighting and goofing but that's it - 69%
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Benjamin Cox
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/9/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    For many years, Jackie Chan had been working away in his little niche as the best dammed martial-arts comedy star in the business. But martial arts movies have been never mainstream since Bruce Lee roared into immortality in "Enter The Dragon" and Chan takes a very different path, one more based around physical comedy like a violent Buster Keaton. This was Chan's Hollywood debut and, frankly, it shows - there is some shockingly bad dubbing, the plot is really quite stupid and the acting is... yeah, well. Anyway, this is one of those films that you simply have to hang up your expectations and just enjoy. It reminded me, in an odd way, of "Smokey And The Bandit" - it's hardly a classic but in spite of its many flaws, there is a sense of infectious fun behind it. Chan plays Keung who visits his uncle in New York (Bill Tung) just as he marries and leaves Keung to manage his Chinese market. After concluding the sale of the market to the bookish Elaine (Anita Mui), Keung incurs the wrath of a biker gang led by Tony (Marc Akerstream) who trash the place and leave Keung bloodied and beat up in an alley. But while Keung tries to fight back, he befriends wheelchair-bound boy next door (Morgan Lam) and his sister Nancy (Fran&ccedil;oise Yip) - who is affiliated with the gang. And to make matters worse, the local mob have been responsible for a daring diamond heist and after a mix-up with another biker (Garvin Cross), Keung finds himself pursued by both the bikers and the mobsters. Like I said, the plot is as old-school as the fashions visible in the nightclub scene. Like another early Chan outing (namely, "Mr Nice Guy"), there are certain things you notice like how every female character in both movies find Chan irresistible or how a simple misunderstanding can get Chan into heaps of trouble. There are other things as well - neither films have gripping stories or even much in the way of cohesion. The dub doesn't help "Rumble In The Bronx", reducing each scene to its component dialogue and physical comedy and build-up to the real reason you watch this film - the action scenes. Chan excels as the physical stuff, leaping across the screen like a kung-fu kicking Daffy Duck and a lot of the gimmicky really works like the scene in the supermarket where Chan uses seemingly every prop in the vicinity. "Rumble In The Bronx" is less of a film and more of a celluloid resume for its star, allowing Chan to demonstrate his extraordinary ability to fling himself into every bad guy in the blink of an eye. I fully understand why Chan might choose this otherwise utterly forgettable film to break into bigger movies - it doesn't let things like a plot get in the way of Chan doing what he does best as well as showing off his comic timing which, whilst not brilliant, at least offers something more than a grimacing hero endlessly bashing the baddies until the credits roll. In most other martial-arts films, the end climax involves the lead baddie use a variety of weapons which will cause the hero to bleed but not enough to prevent good triumphing over evil. In this film, the climax is so ridiculous that even my wife burst out laughing. If you can drop your serious face and revel in the goofiness of it then this might entertain you as much as it did me. Just don't take it seriously because if anything, this is probably the least serious film I've seen all year.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    someone stole my cushion!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jcallows
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/7/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie is about a boy and his quest for a new cushion. Watch it for its creative fight scenes and for that girl who plays the boy's sister. Watch it also to laugh at the atrocious acting and dialog. Other than that, there's really no reason to watch. This film is basically a bunch of action sequences strung together with some dialog in between. The dialog can be summed up as "where are the diamonds?", "give me the diamonds!" and, of course, "someone stole my cushion!" But the action is where this film excels. As is the custom in all Jackie Chan films, this film is loaded with creative martial arts fighting and spectacular stunts. This film is definitely fun to watch. But it's kind of like watching porn. You will be tempted to fast forward through all the dialog to get to the good parts.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Awesome
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tigerstar154
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/6/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Rumble in the bronx I heard a lot about this movie and how it launched Jackie Chan's career in the west. i saw this and it was awesome despite the fact it was a typical 90s movie. Jackie Chan visits his uncle in NY and becomes involved with a motorcycle gang. The pluses: Jackie Chan and his action work, and the the girl who plays Nancy. The Minuses: Weird acting by white actors, kid was annoying, corny at times and melodramatic. Overall, Rumble in the bronx is great and funny at time. 8/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    my favourite jackie chan movie, a blast from start to finish
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    daworldismine
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/5/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    rumble in the bronx is one of my favourite movies of alltime, and my favourite jackie chan movie, no im not saying its his best, im saying its my favourite, to me it has some of his best fight scenes and stunts of the 90's, and the movie made him a world wide star whats not to love, and plus the movie is very funny, easily one of his funniest movies. the first jackie chan movie i ever taped off TV, and the one I've seen the most, to me rumble in the bronx is the best action movie of the 90's, perfect action, perfect comedy, perfect movie. jackie chan rarely fails to deliver, and this is one of his best movies, and i recommend it to anybody who wants to see some awesome action
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Jackie Chan in America
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ebiros2
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/11/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is one of the movies Jackie Chan made targeted for audience outside of Asia. The story takes place in New York with many American actors in the supporting role. To me this wasn't one of his best production, but there's one scene that blows me away every time I see it. This is the scene where Jackie takes a leap from the roof of one building into a balcony of the adjacent building. I don't think there was any wire attached to Jackie, so if he missed, he could have been dead, and he could have missed very easily. Some of the scenes look staged and isn't the natural Jackie Chan type scenes that I'm used to. Maybe the crew wasn't used to the American style production. It's really strange to discover that Jackie Chan movie looks below par compared to his own when it's way above average compared to other American action movie of this type. I also didn't like the senseless violence, but if wasn't so violent, maybe it wouldn't look like authentic America. Whatever the reason, they might have done it better. It's still a Jackie Chan movie, and you'll get that special dose of Jackie Chan action with this movie. If you're a Jackie Chan fan, it's sure to please you.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Chan at his Comical, Lightning-Quick Best
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Sean Lamberger
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/7/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Jackie Chan's first major American breakthrough remains his most energetic, entertaining spectacle. The film's storyline is a joke, with supposedly hardcore Bronx motorcycle gangs coming off like characters in a Saturday morning cartoon, but that's clearly not the point. The plot's only there to fill the space between fight scenes with a few randomly connected antagonizing situations, and in many instances its complete lack of any connection with reality is actually quite charming. The real focus, naturally, is on Chan's inventive use of his surroundings and blistering hand speed during his frequent clashes with gaudily-dressed bikers and, later on, suit-and-sunglasses adorned g-men. Regardless of locale, Jackie is somehow able to find an unsuspecting prop, then quickly put it to use in bludgeoning somewhere in the range of a dozen different combatants in wildly original ways, keeping audiences surprised and indulged. A kindergarten-grade story won't win this rumble any awards, but as a vehicle for its star's own inimitable style of celluloid-friendly martial arts it's perfect.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Streets of San Bronx
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    thesar-2
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/9/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I'd guess you'd have to call 'Rumble in the Bronx' an extreme example of a guilty pleasure. Though back in the 1990s, it was not my first introduction to Jackie Chan (the inferior 'Supercop' was) it was the one that got me hooked on his work. All the way through this viewing  the first in many years, the word "silly" kept popping up in my mind. It's dialogue, acting, stereotypes and shoddy cop work was so hilariously bad, I could only think this had to be written by someone who's only contact with the U.S.A. involves watching old 1970s cop hour-long dramas. And while some scenes were actually funny (SEE: the wrench threat) some were downright unintentionally funny (SEE: the toddler-toss and the entire closing on the golf course.) Leaving all that negative behind, it was an extreme joy watching Chan perform his own stunts in many, many inventive ways while simultaneously creating a very human and good-hearted character. The stunts were simply amazing and if one were to watch today for the first time, they need to know: he did them all himself, without a green screens, cables, etc. As arrogant as Chan is  I've read his biography, it's dripping with arrogance, he does have great gifts in originality, showmanship, pride in his work and making sure he never uses traditional American trickery/stunts. (This changes later in his work, when he was forced and got older, but this work and ones around it were all pure Chan.) Synopsis: Good-natured nephew Chan visits NYC and gets thrown in extraordinary circumstances: fighting both gangs and mob bosses while helping 2 women, his Uncle and a handicapped child. All that's irrelevant; what matters is once the action starts, it never lets up. And with an open-mind, what a fun rumble you'll have. Side Note: Wow.. not only was it painful for all the actors to get hurt during production (not to mention the roughly 16 dozen vehicles) it was also gut wrenching to watch the closing credits that showed mostly the unintentional crashes, broken bones, etc. You really have to hand it to the devotion of the crew, cast and Chan. Definitely Chan. My comments about his arrogance does not mean I don't admire the man, especially his extremely poor and underprivileged beginnings to the entertainer he became. He's one of the very few actors/action stars that no matter how incredibly silly his movies look to me  it has to be a culture thing, it's always a rush to see how long his fight scenes last, how inventive he becomes and simply how exciting they are.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Jackie cracks the west
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ed_two_o_nine
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/2/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Well here we go once again with the undisputed king of action comedy. The one and only Jackie Chan. While this is nowhere near Chan's best movie we can be grateful for the fact that this is the film that finally gave Chan his much deserved break in the USA. This is the story on Chan's character Keung who comes to the Bronx for his uncle's wedding and ends up caught up in a series of events that involve biker gangs, and diamond robbers. But really none of this matters this is just an excuse for Jackie to show of his amazing action skills (in the fight scenes which he also choreographed), and this he does to his usual amazing standards. There seems to be more edits in the fight scenes that is normal for Jackie but I suspect this might be down to one of two things. One making the film more palatable for a western audience. Or two that Jackie broke his ankle in the filming of this movie. Still tell me the last time you saw a western movie star leap from a roof on to the fire escape of the next building!!! Truly amazing stuff. On the down side the western characters and acting are very wooden but hey just enjoy Chan and hopefully then go seek out his Hong Kong movies.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Could The Road To The Dream Be More Enjoyable Than Fulfilling It ?!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ahmed elshikh (ahmed_abd_elreheem@yahoo.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/8/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is one of the best movies by (Jackie Chan), maybe more fun than the majority of his previous Asian ones and the other later American ones too. Here the action is so ambitious, the rhythm is hot, the production is big, the technique is above mediocre, and the heroine is sexier ! I think the first half was so good and catchy; however the second half about the diamonds was another movie ! I enjoyed the story of the first plot, and the huge Action of the second one. The matter of having 2 girls had never been used correctly, there was no use out of putting some love scenes for (Chan) and the market's owner, in the same time that he fell in love with the street girl simply and terminally !, so why the first storyline from the start?? Then look at the street gang, why all of this hatred for (Jackie)? They looked like another brainless pure evil comes from another previous movies like (The Enforcer), (Robocop), and (Police Academy). I hated also the matter of the nonexistent anticlimax, it's maybe a habit at (Chan)'s movies to watch the climax then PAAM the closing credits with the bloopers !!, here it was so provoking as we didn't know exactly what happened after, like they had no time to shoot more ! Sometimes it's a terrible habit as it makes the whole condition so deficient, especially the viewer's satisfaction. It's clear that (Chan) was determined to be a star in America, it was his dream, and it would never happen until 4 years after with (Rush Hour) which's not one of my favorites where Chan undoubtedly is less shining, maybe it succeeded because it was the right formula or the right time I don't know. But here like every Chan's movie the Action, as usual, exceeded everything. And the story, as ever, is just a superficial cover for fun with no possible deepness. It was enough for (Chan) and all of his team to assure how courageous, stubborn, and romantic the Asian is; in the same time that the American is so violent, criminal, and deranged whether poor or rich. Despite the balance that they made (kind American policemen, and one evil Asian in the street gang). On so many levels it proves how the Asian cinematic hero became better and his adventures became bigger since another very well known Asian-in-western-evil-world and I mean (Bruce Lee) at (Way of the Dragon) nearly 25 years earlier, to invade America itself (it was Italy in the first one), and to present Mad Mad world comic Action also through this maniac hero who, at the time, needed no stunts or wires ! So ultimately (Rumble in the Bronx - 1996) is nice strong action, where (Jackie) is in classical example for being a real icon, original star, and great clown. Makes you wonder a bit about what he lost, after fulfilling his dream, in next American movies.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Funny and spectacular Jackie Chan movie in his first American super hit with highlights provided by a hovercraft
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ma-cortes
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Amusing and entertaining Chan film in which he demonstrates his sensational skills as a great action man . It deals with a young man named Keong (Jackie Chan) visiting and helping his uncle in New York City finds himself forced to fight a street gang and the mob with his martial art abilities . His uncle has a local Chinese supermarket, which he owns and is in the process of selling to Elaine (Anita Mui). Later on , Keong befriends a neighbor kid and his sister (Francois Yip) and beats up some neighborhood thugs . Hong Kong/US/Canada action comedy full of over-the-top struggles , excitement , thrills , ingenious stunts , slapstick , lots of brawls but with abundant humor and tongue-in-cheek . This fun movie is plenty of intrigue , unstopped action , and overwhelming stunt-work with breathtaking ending images including a hovercraft . Jackie Chan is top notch as one army man fighting a group of heinous villains and as always he makes his own stunts like is well showed at the final credits . Awesome , incredible stunts and brief comic touches , as usual ; the picture is better constructed than Chan's predecessors films . The lighting-paced storyline slows down at times , but frantic action sequences make up for it . Spotlights movie include spectacular fights , including bounds and leaps , impressive and interminable struggles , an impressive final struggle between Jackie Chan and enemies . The warehouse fight scene took twenty days to film, with Chan having to teach the local stunt players to fight "Hong Kong style". In addition other fine action sequences in overwhelming and extraordinary style . The script called for a leap from the top of a parking lot to a fire escape on the floor below on the building across the street , as is his custom, director Stanley Tong attempted the stunt before asking any actors to do so. He tried it with the help of a cable harness, but quickly decided it would be safer without the harness. The landing point was not visible from the point where the jump began, so tape was placed on the take-off point as a guide ,the jump was completed perfectly by 'Chan, Jackie' on the first attempt, doing his own stunts as is his custom . The jump was captured by four cameras. This is an acceptable action movie distinguished by nicely cinematography of the spectacular sequences , and contains agreeable sense of humor as well as previous entries . Jackie Chan usually forms couple to notorious actresses as Maggie Chung and Michelle Yeoh . In this outing Jackie teams up to gorgeous Francoise Yip (who broke her leg while filming the scene where she rides a motorbike across the tops of parked cars , she insisted on returning to the set after her leg was plastered at hospital) and prestigious Chinese actress Anita Mui , a fine action star in their own right but sadly she early died by cancer . Both of them starred together several films such as &uml;Mr Canton and Lady Rose&uml; and &uml;Legend of the drunken master&uml; . Filming in Vancouver, Canada on October 6th, 1994, Chan broke his right ankle while attempting the scene where he jumps onto the hovercraft. Despite the injury, he was present at the premiere of &uml;The legend of the drunken fighter&uml; at the Vancouver International Film Festival that night. Later in the production, Tong sprained his ankle, completing the film on crutches . Two stunt women also broke their legs during the filming of the motorcycle chase. The picture achieved big success in China , USA and all around the world . However , Jackie Chan's failed at Box-office in his American debut ,&uml;Battle creek brawl&uml; . Chan is a hard-working actor and director throughout his long and varied career . Chan usually pays overt homage to two of his greatest influences as Charles Chaplin and Harold Lloyd . He went on playing &uml;Cannoball&uml; , &uml;The protector&uml; and "Rumble in the Bronx", until getting all American success with &uml;Shangai Knights&uml; , &uml;The tuxedo&uml; , &uml;Around the world in 80 days&uml; and &uml;Rush hour&uml; trilogy , and the recent &uml;Karate kid&uml;. Of course , his biggest hits were &uml;The Police story&uml; series that won the Golden Horse Award, a Chinese version of the Oscar , the first was titled &uml;Police story (1985)&uml; directed by the same Chan , it was a perfect action film for enthusiastic of the genre ; the following was &uml;Police story 2 (1988)&uml; also pretty violent and with abundant humor touches . It's followed by &uml;Supercop&uml; or &uml;Police story 3&uml; and finally , &uml;Police story IV : Crime story&uml; . The picture is well produced by the great Asian producer Raymond Chow and Golden Harvest production and compellingly directed by Stanley Tong and helped by Jackie Chan . Rating : Acceptable and passable , the picture has its sensational moments here and there , but also with abundant humor touches mostly provided by its agile star , the super Jackie stunningly accompanied by Anita Mui and Francois Yip . It's a perfect action film for enthusiasts of the genre and especially for Jackie fans .
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Chan fighting and goofing but that's it - 69%
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Benjamin Cox
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/9/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    For many years, Jackie Chan had been working away in his little niche as the best dammed martial-arts comedy star in the business. But martial arts movies have been never mainstream since Bruce Lee roared into immortality in "Enter The Dragon" and Chan takes a very different path, one more based around physical comedy like a violent Buster Keaton. This was Chan's Hollywood debut and, frankly, it shows - there is some shockingly bad dubbing, the plot is really quite stupid and the acting is... yeah, well. Anyway, this is one of those films that you simply have to hang up your expectations and just enjoy. It reminded me, in an odd way, of "Smokey And The Bandit" - it's hardly a classic but in spite of its many flaws, there is a sense of infectious fun behind it. Chan plays Keung who visits his uncle in New York (Bill Tung) just as he marries and leaves Keung to manage his Chinese market. After concluding the sale of the market to the bookish Elaine (Anita Mui), Keung incurs the wrath of a biker gang led by Tony (Marc Akerstream) who trash the place and leave Keung bloodied and beat up in an alley. But while Keung tries to fight back, he befriends wheelchair-bound boy next door (Morgan Lam) and his sister Nancy (Fran&ccedil;oise Yip) - who is affiliated with the gang. And to make matters worse, the local mob have been responsible for a daring diamond heist and after a mix-up with another biker (Garvin Cross), Keung finds himself pursued by both the bikers and the mobsters. Like I said, the plot is as old-school as the fashions visible in the nightclub scene. Like another early Chan outing (namely, "Mr Nice Guy"), there are certain things you notice like how every female character in both movies find Chan irresistible or how a simple misunderstanding can get Chan into heaps of trouble. There are other things as well - neither films have gripping stories or even much in the way of cohesion. The dub doesn't help "Rumble In The Bronx", reducing each scene to its component dialogue and physical comedy and build-up to the real reason you watch this film - the action scenes. Chan excels as the physical stuff, leaping across the screen like a kung-fu kicking Daffy Duck and a lot of the gimmicky really works like the scene in the supermarket where Chan uses seemingly every prop in the vicinity. "Rumble In The Bronx" is less of a film and more of a celluloid resume for its star, allowing Chan to demonstrate his extraordinary ability to fling himself into every bad guy in the blink of an eye. I fully understand why Chan might choose this otherwise utterly forgettable film to break into bigger movies - it doesn't let things like a plot get in the way of Chan doing what he does best as well as showing off his comic timing which, whilst not brilliant, at least offers something more than a grimacing hero endlessly bashing the baddies until the credits roll. In most other martial-arts films, the end climax involves the lead baddie use a variety of weapons which will cause the hero to bleed but not enough to prevent good triumphing over evil. In this film, the climax is so ridiculous that even my wife burst out laughing. If you can drop your serious face and revel in the goofiness of it then this might entertain you as much as it did me. Just don't take it seriously because if anything, this is probably the least serious film I've seen all year.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    someone stole my cushion!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jcallows
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/7/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie is about a boy and his quest for a new cushion. Watch it for its creative fight scenes and for that girl who plays the boy's sister. Watch it also to laugh at the atrocious acting and dialog. Other than that, there's really no reason to watch. This film is basically a bunch of action sequences strung together with some dialog in between. The dialog can be summed up as "where are the diamonds?", "give me the diamonds!" and, of course, "someone stole my cushion!" But the action is where this film excels. As is the custom in all Jackie Chan films, this film is loaded with creative martial arts fighting and spectacular stunts. This film is definitely fun to watch. But it's kind of like watching porn. You will be tempted to fast forward through all the dialog to get to the good parts.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Awesome
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tigerstar154
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/6/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Rumble in the bronx I heard a lot about this movie and how it launched Jackie Chan's career in the west. i saw this and it was awesome despite the fact it was a typical 90s movie. Jackie Chan visits his uncle in NY and becomes involved with a motorcycle gang. The pluses: Jackie Chan and his action work, and the the girl who plays Nancy. The Minuses: Weird acting by white actors, kid was annoying, corny at times and melodramatic. Overall, Rumble in the bronx is great and funny at time. 8/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    my favourite jackie chan movie, a blast from start to finish
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    daworldismine
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/5/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    rumble in the bronx is one of my favourite movies of alltime, and my favourite jackie chan movie, no im not saying its his best, im saying its my favourite, to me it has some of his best fight scenes and stunts of the 90's, and the movie made him a world wide star whats not to love, and plus the movie is very funny, easily one of his funniest movies. the first jackie chan movie i ever taped off TV, and the one I've seen the most, to me rumble in the bronx is the best action movie of the 90's, perfect action, perfect comedy, perfect movie. jackie chan rarely fails to deliver, and this is one of his best movies, and i recommend it to anybody who wants to see some awesome action
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Jackie Chan in America
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ebiros2
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/11/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is one of the movies Jackie Chan made targeted for audience outside of Asia. The story takes place in New York with many American actors in the supporting role. To me this wasn't one of his best production, but there's one scene that blows me away every time I see it. This is the scene where Jackie takes a leap from the roof of one building into a balcony of the adjacent building. I don't think there was any wire attached to Jackie, so if he missed, he could have been dead, and he could have missed very easily. Some of the scenes look staged and isn't the natural Jackie Chan type scenes that I'm used to. Maybe the crew wasn't used to the American style production. It's really strange to discover that Jackie Chan movie looks below par compared to his own when it's way above average compared to other American action movie of this type. I also didn't like the senseless violence, but if wasn't so violent, maybe it wouldn't look like authentic America. Whatever the reason, they might have done it better. It's still a Jackie Chan movie, and you'll get that special dose of Jackie Chan action with this movie. If you're a Jackie Chan fan, it's sure to please you.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Chan at his Comical, Lightning-Quick Best
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Sean Lamberger
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/7/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Jackie Chan's first major American breakthrough remains his most energetic, entertaining spectacle. The film's storyline is a joke, with supposedly hardcore Bronx motorcycle gangs coming off like characters in a Saturday morning cartoon, but that's clearly not the point. The plot's only there to fill the space between fight scenes with a few randomly connected antagonizing situations, and in many instances its complete lack of any connection with reality is actually quite charming. The real focus, naturally, is on Chan's inventive use of his surroundings and blistering hand speed during his frequent clashes with gaudily-dressed bikers and, later on, suit-and-sunglasses adorned g-men. Regardless of locale, Jackie is somehow able to find an unsuspecting prop, then quickly put it to use in bludgeoning somewhere in the range of a dozen different combatants in wildly original ways, keeping audiences surprised and indulged. A kindergarten-grade story won't win this rumble any awards, but as a vehicle for its star's own inimitable style of celluloid-friendly martial arts it's perfect.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Streets of San Bronx
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    thesar-2
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/9/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I'd guess you'd have to call 'Rumble in the Bronx' an extreme example of a guilty pleasure. Though back in the 1990s, it was not my first introduction to Jackie Chan (the inferior 'Supercop' was) it was the one that got me hooked on his work. All the way through this viewing  the first in many years, the word "silly" kept popping up in my mind. It's dialogue, acting, stereotypes and shoddy cop work was so hilariously bad, I could only think this had to be written by someone who's only contact with the U.S.A. involves watching old 1970s cop hour-long dramas. And while some scenes were actually funny (SEE: the wrench threat) some were downright unintentionally funny (SEE: the toddler-toss and the entire closing on the golf course.) Leaving all that negative behind, it was an extreme joy watching Chan perform his own stunts in many, many inventive ways while simultaneously creating a very human and good-hearted character. The stunts were simply amazing and if one were to watch today for the first time, they need to know: he did them all himself, without a green screens, cables, etc. As arrogant as Chan is  I've read his biography, it's dripping with arrogance, he does have great gifts in originality, showmanship, pride in his work and making sure he never uses traditional American trickery/stunts. (This changes later in his work, when he was forced and got older, but this work and ones around it were all pure Chan.) Synopsis: Good-natured nephew Chan visits NYC and gets thrown in extraordinary circumstances: fighting both gangs and mob bosses while helping 2 women, his Uncle and a handicapped child. All that's irrelevant; what matters is once the action starts, it never lets up. And with an open-mind, what a fun rumble you'll have. Side Note: Wow.. not only was it painful for all the actors to get hurt during production (not to mention the roughly 16 dozen vehicles) it was also gut wrenching to watch the closing credits that showed mostly the unintentional crashes, broken bones, etc. You really have to hand it to the devotion of the crew, cast and Chan. Definitely Chan. My comments about his arrogance does not mean I don't admire the man, especially his extremely poor and underprivileged beginnings to the entertainer he became. He's one of the very few actors/action stars that no matter how incredibly silly his movies look to me  it has to be a culture thing, it's always a rush to see how long his fight scenes last, how inventive he becomes and simply how exciting they are.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Jackie cracks the west
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ed_two_o_nine
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/2/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Well here we go once again with the undisputed king of action comedy. The one and only Jackie Chan. While this is nowhere near Chan's best movie we can be grateful for the fact that this is the film that finally gave Chan his much deserved break in the USA. This is the story on Chan's character Keung who comes to the Bronx for his uncle's wedding and ends up caught up in a series of events that involve biker gangs, and diamond robbers. But really none of this matters this is just an excuse for Jackie to show of his amazing action skills (in the fight scenes which he also choreographed), and this he does to his usual amazing standards. There seems to be more edits in the fight scenes that is normal for Jackie but I suspect this might be down to one of two things. One making the film more palatable for a western audience. Or two that Jackie broke his ankle in the filming of this movie. Still tell me the last time you saw a western movie star leap from a roof on to the fire escape of the next building!!! Truly amazing stuff. On the down side the western characters and acting are very wooden but hey just enjoy Chan and hopefully then go seek out his Hong Kong movies.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Could The Road To The Dream Be More Enjoyable Than Fulfilling It ?!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ahmed elshikh (ahmed_abd_elreheem@yahoo.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/8/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is one of the best movies by (Jackie Chan), maybe more fun than the majority of his previous Asian ones and the other later American ones too. Here the action is so ambitious, the rhythm is hot, the production is big, the technique is above mediocre, and the heroine is sexier ! I think the first half was so good and catchy; however the second half about the diamonds was another movie ! I enjoyed the story of the first plot, and the huge Action of the second one. The matter of having 2 girls had never been used correctly, there was no use out of putting some love scenes for (Chan) and the market's owner, in the same time that he fell in love with the street girl simply and terminally !, so why the first storyline from the start?? Then look at the street gang, why all of this hatred for (Jackie)? They looked like another brainless pure evil comes from another previous movies like (The Enforcer), (Robocop), and (Police Academy). I hated also the matter of the nonexistent anticlimax, it's maybe a habit at (Chan)'s movies to watch the climax then PAAM the closing credits with the bloopers !!, here it was so provoking as we didn't know exactly what happened after, like they had no time to shoot more ! Sometimes it's a terrible habit as it makes the whole condition so deficient, especially the viewer's satisfaction. It's clear that (Chan) was determined to be a star in America, it was his dream, and it would never happen until 4 years after with (Rush Hour) which's not one of my favorites where Chan undoubtedly is less shining, maybe it succeeded because it was the right formula or the right time I don't know. But here like every Chan's movie the Action, as usual, exceeded everything. And the story, as ever, is just a superficial cover for fun with no possible deepness. It was enough for (Chan) and all of his team to assure how courageous, stubborn, and romantic the Asian is; in the same time that the American is so violent, criminal, and deranged whether poor or rich. Despite the balance that they made (kind American policemen, and one evil Asian in the street gang). On so many levels it proves how the Asian cinematic hero became better and his adventures became bigger since another very well known Asian-in-western-evil-world and I mean (Bruce Lee) at (Way of the Dragon) nearly 25 years earlier, to invade America itself (it was Italy in the first one), and to present Mad Mad world comic Action also through this maniac hero who, at the time, needed no stunts or wires ! So ultimately (Rumble in the Bronx - 1996) is nice strong action, where (Jackie) is in classical example for being a real icon, original star, and great clown. Makes you wonder a bit about what he lost, after fulfilling his dream, in next American movies.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Funny and spectacular Jackie Chan movie in his first American super hit with highlights provided by a hovercraft
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ma-cortes
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Amusing and entertaining Chan film in which he demonstrates his sensational skills as a great action man . It deals with a young man named Keong (Jackie Chan) visiting and helping his uncle in New York City finds himself forced to fight a street gang and the mob with his martial art abilities . His uncle has a local Chinese supermarket, which he owns and is in the process of selling to Elaine (Anita Mui). Later on , Keong befriends a neighbor kid and his sister (Francois Yip) and beats up some neighborhood thugs . Hong Kong/US/Canada action comedy full of over-the-top struggles , excitement , thrills , ingenious stunts , slapstick , lots of brawls but with abundant humor and tongue-in-cheek . This fun movie is plenty of intrigue , unstopped action , and overwhelming stunt-work with breathtaking ending images including a hovercraft . Jackie Chan is top notch as one army man fighting a group of heinous villains and as always he makes his own stunts like is well showed at the final credits . Awesome , incredible stunts and brief comic touches , as usual ; the picture is better constructed than Chan's predecessors films . The lighting-paced storyline slows down at times , but frantic action sequences make up for it . Spotlights movie include spectacular fights , including bounds and leaps , impressive and interminable struggles , an impressive final struggle between Jackie Chan and enemies . The warehouse fight scene took twenty days to film, with Chan having to teach the local stunt players to fight "Hong Kong style". In addition other fine action sequences in overwhelming and extraordinary style . The script called for a leap from the top of a parking lot to a fire escape on the floor below on the building across the street , as is his custom, director Stanley Tong attempted the stunt before asking any actors to do so. He tried it with the help of a cable harness, but quickly decided it would be safer without the harness. The landing point was not visible from the point where the jump began, so tape was placed on the take-off point as a guide ,the jump was completed perfectly by 'Chan, Jackie' on the first attempt, doing his own stunts as is his custom . The jump was captured by four cameras. This is an acceptable action movie distinguished by nicely cinematography of the spectacular sequences , and contains agreeable sense of humor as well as previous entries . Jackie Chan usually forms couple to notorious actresses as Maggie Chung and Michelle Yeoh . In this outing Jackie teams up to gorgeous Francoise Yip (who broke her leg while filming the scene where she rides a motorbike across the tops of parked cars , she insisted on returning to the set after her leg was plastered at hospital) and prestigious Chinese actress Anita Mui , a fine action star in their own right but sadly she early died by cancer . Both of them starred together several films such as &uml;Mr Canton and Lady Rose&uml; and &uml;Legend of the drunken master&uml; . Filming in Vancouver, Canada on October 6th, 1994, Chan broke his right ankle while attempting the scene where he jumps onto the hovercraft. Despite the injury, he was present at the premiere of &uml;The legend of the drunken fighter&uml; at the Vancouver International Film Festival that night. Later in the production, Tong sprained his ankle, completing the film on crutches . Two stunt women also broke their legs during the filming of the motorcycle chase. The picture achieved big success in China , USA and all around the world . However , Jackie Chan's failed at Box-office in his American debut ,&uml;Battle creek brawl&uml; . Chan is a hard-working actor and director throughout his long and varied career . Chan usually pays overt homage to two of his greatest influences as Charles Chaplin and Harold Lloyd . He went on playing &uml;Cannoball&uml; , &uml;The protector&uml; and "Rumble in the Bronx", until getting all American success with &uml;Shangai Knights&uml; , &uml;The tuxedo&uml; , &uml;Around the world in 80 days&uml; and &uml;Rush hour&uml; trilogy , and the recent &uml;Karate kid&uml;. Of course , his biggest hits were &uml;The Police story&uml; series that won the Golden Horse Award, a Chinese version of the Oscar , the first was titled &uml;Police story (1985)&uml; directed by the same Chan , it was a perfect action film for enthusiastic of the genre ; the following was &uml;Police story 2 (1988)&uml; also pretty violent and with abundant humor touches . It's followed by &uml;Supercop&uml; or &uml;Police story 3&uml; and finally , &uml;Police story IV : Crime story&uml; . The picture is well produced by the great Asian producer Raymond Chow and Golden Harvest production and compellingly directed by Stanley Tong and helped by Jackie Chan . Rating : Acceptable and passable , the picture has its sensational moments here and there , but also with abundant humor touches mostly provided by its agile star , the super Jackie stunningly accompanied by Anita Mui and Francois Yip . It's a perfect action film for enthusiasts of the genre and especially for Jackie fans .
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Chan fighting and goofing but that's it - 69%
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Benjamin Cox
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/9/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    For many years, Jackie Chan had been working away in his little niche as the best dammed martial-arts comedy star in the business. But martial arts movies have been never mainstream since Bruce Lee roared into immortality in "Enter The Dragon" and Chan takes a very different path, one more based around physical comedy like a violent Buster Keaton. This was Chan's Hollywood debut and, frankly, it shows - there is some shockingly bad dubbing, the plot is really quite stupid and the acting is... yeah, well. Anyway, this is one of those films that you simply have to hang up your expectations and just enjoy. It reminded me, in an odd way, of "Smokey And The Bandit" - it's hardly a classic but in spite of its many flaws, there is a sense of infectious fun behind it. Chan plays Keung who visits his uncle in New York (Bill Tung) just as he marries and leaves Keung to manage his Chinese market. After concluding the sale of the market to the bookish Elaine (Anita Mui), Keung incurs the wrath of a biker gang led by Tony (Marc Akerstream) who trash the place and leave Keung bloodied and beat up in an alley. But while Keung tries to fight back, he befriends wheelchair-bound boy next door (Morgan Lam) and his sister Nancy (Fran&ccedil;oise Yip) - who is affiliated with the gang. And to make matters worse, the local mob have been responsible for a daring diamond heist and after a mix-up with another biker (Garvin Cross), Keung finds himself pursued by both the bikers and the mobsters. Like I said, the plot is as old-school as the fashions visible in the nightclub scene. Like another early Chan outing (namely, "Mr Nice Guy"), there are certain things you notice like how every female character in both movies find Chan irresistible or how a simple misunderstanding can get Chan into heaps of trouble. There are other things as well - neither films have gripping stories or even much in the way of cohesion. The dub doesn't help "Rumble In The Bronx", reducing each scene to its component dialogue and physical comedy and build-up to the real reason you watch this film - the action scenes. Chan excels as the physical stuff, leaping across the screen like a kung-fu kicking Daffy Duck and a lot of the gimmicky really works like the scene in the supermarket where Chan uses seemingly every prop in the vicinity. "Rumble In The Bronx" is less of a film and more of a celluloid resume for its star, allowing Chan to demonstrate his extraordinary ability to fling himself into every bad guy in the blink of an eye. I fully understand why Chan might choose this otherwise utterly forgettable film to break into bigger movies - it doesn't let things like a plot get in the way of Chan doing what he does best as well as showing off his comic timing which, whilst not brilliant, at least offers something more than a grimacing hero endlessly bashing the baddies until the credits roll. In most other martial-arts films, the end climax involves the lead baddie use a variety of weapons which will cause the hero to bleed but not enough to prevent good triumphing over evil. In this film, the climax is so ridiculous that even my wife burst out laughing. If you can drop your serious face and revel in the goofiness of it then this might entertain you as much as it did me. Just don't take it seriously because if anything, this is probably the least serious film I've seen all year.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    someone stole my cushion!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jcallows
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/7/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie is about a boy and his quest for a new cushion. Watch it for its creative fight scenes and for that girl who plays the boy's sister. Watch it also to laugh at the atrocious acting and dialog. Other than that, there's really no reason to watch. This film is basically a bunch of action sequences strung together with some dialog in between. The dialog can be summed up as "where are the diamonds?", "give me the diamonds!" and, of course, "someone stole my cushion!" But the action is where this film excels. As is the custom in all Jackie Chan films, this film is loaded with creative martial arts fighting and spectacular stunts. This film is definitely fun to watch. But it's kind of like watching porn. You will be tempted to fast forward through all the dialog to get to the good parts.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Awesome
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tigerstar154
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/6/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Rumble in the bronx I heard a lot about this movie and how it launched Jackie Chan's career in the west. i saw this and it was awesome despite the fact it was a typical 90s movie. Jackie Chan visits his uncle in NY and becomes involved with a motorcycle gang. The pluses: Jackie Chan and his action work, and the the girl who plays Nancy. The Minuses: Weird acting by white actors, kid was annoying, corny at times and melodramatic. Overall, Rumble in the bronx is great and funny at time. 8/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    my favourite jackie chan movie, a blast from start to finish
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    daworldismine
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/5/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    rumble in the bronx is one of my favourite movies of alltime, and my favourite jackie chan movie, no im not saying its his best, im saying its my favourite, to me it has some of his best fight scenes and stunts of the 90's, and the movie made him a world wide star whats not to love, and plus the movie is very funny, easily one of his funniest movies. the first jackie chan movie i ever taped off TV, and the one I've seen the most, to me rumble in the bronx is the best action movie of the 90's, perfect action, perfect comedy, perfect movie. jackie chan rarely fails to deliver, and this is one of his best movies, and i recommend it to anybody who wants to see some awesome action
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Jackie Chan in America
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ebiros2
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/11/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is one of the movies Jackie Chan made targeted for audience outside of Asia. The story takes place in New York with many American actors in the supporting role. To me this wasn't one of his best production, but there's one scene that blows me away every time I see it. This is the scene where Jackie takes a leap from the roof of one building into a balcony of the adjacent building. I don't think there was any wire attached to Jackie, so if he missed, he could have been dead, and he could have missed very easily. Some of the scenes look staged and isn't the natural Jackie Chan type scenes that I'm used to. Maybe the crew wasn't used to the American style production. It's really strange to discover that Jackie Chan movie looks below par compared to his own when it's way above average compared to other American action movie of this type. I also didn't like the senseless violence, but if wasn't so violent, maybe it wouldn't look like authentic America. Whatever the reason, they might have done it better. It's still a Jackie Chan movie, and you'll get that special dose of Jackie Chan action with this movie. If you're a Jackie Chan fan, it's sure to please you.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Chan at his Comical, Lightning-Quick Best
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Sean Lamberger
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/7/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Jackie Chan's first major American breakthrough remains his most energetic, entertaining spectacle. The film's storyline is a joke, with supposedly hardcore Bronx motorcycle gangs coming off like characters in a Saturday morning cartoon, but that's clearly not the point. The plot's only there to fill the space between fight scenes with a few randomly connected antagonizing situations, and in many instances its complete lack of any connection with reality is actually quite charming. The real focus, naturally, is on Chan's inventive use of his surroundings and blistering hand speed during his frequent clashes with gaudily-dressed bikers and, later on, suit-and-sunglasses adorned g-men. Regardless of locale, Jackie is somehow able to find an unsuspecting prop, then quickly put it to use in bludgeoning somewhere in the range of a dozen different combatants in wildly original ways, keeping audiences surprised and indulged. A kindergarten-grade story won't win this rumble any awards, but as a vehicle for its star's own inimitable style of celluloid-friendly martial arts it's perfect.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Streets of San Bronx
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    thesar-2
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/9/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I'd guess you'd have to call 'Rumble in the Bronx' an extreme example of a guilty pleasure. Though back in the 1990s, it was not my first introduction to Jackie Chan (the inferior 'Supercop' was) it was the one that got me hooked on his work. All the way through this viewing  the first in many years, the word "silly" kept popping up in my mind. It's dialogue, acting, stereotypes and shoddy cop work was so hilariously bad, I could only think this had to be written by someone who's only contact with the U.S.A. involves watching old 1970s cop hour-long dramas. And while some scenes were actually funny (SEE: the wrench threat) some were downright unintentionally funny (SEE: the toddler-toss and the entire closing on the golf course.) Leaving all that negative behind, it was an extreme joy watching Chan perform his own stunts in many, many inventive ways while simultaneously creating a very human and good-hearted character. The stunts were simply amazing and if one were to watch today for the first time, they need to know: he did them all himself, without a green screens, cables, etc. As arrogant as Chan is  I've read his biography, it's dripping with arrogance, he does have great gifts in originality, showmanship, pride in his work and making sure he never uses traditional American trickery/stunts. (This changes later in his work, when he was forced and got older, but this work and ones around it were all pure Chan.) Synopsis: Good-natured nephew Chan visits NYC and gets thrown in extraordinary circumstances: fighting both gangs and mob bosses while helping 2 women, his Uncle and a handicapped child. All that's irrelevant; what matters is once the action starts, it never lets up. And with an open-mind, what a fun rumble you'll have. Side Note: Wow.. not only was it painful for all the actors to get hurt during production (not to mention the roughly 16 dozen vehicles) it was also gut wrenching to watch the closing credits that showed mostly the unintentional crashes, broken bones, etc. You really have to hand it to the devotion of the crew, cast and Chan. Definitely Chan. My comments about his arrogance does not mean I don't admire the man, especially his extremely poor and underprivileged beginnings to the entertainer he became. He's one of the very few actors/action stars that no matter how incredibly silly his movies look to me  it has to be a culture thing, it's always a rush to see how long his fight scenes last, how inventive he becomes and simply how exciting they are.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Jackie cracks the west
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ed_two_o_nine
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/2/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Well here we go once again with the undisputed king of action comedy. The one and only Jackie Chan. While this is nowhere near Chan's best movie we can be grateful for the fact that this is the film that finally gave Chan his much deserved break in the USA. This is the story on Chan's character Keung who comes to the Bronx for his uncle's wedding and ends up caught up in a series of events that involve biker gangs, and diamond robbers. But really none of this matters this is just an excuse for Jackie to show of his amazing action skills (in the fight scenes which he also choreographed), and this he does to his usual amazing standards. There seems to be more edits in the fight scenes that is normal for Jackie but I suspect this might be down to one of two things. One making the film more palatable for a western audience. Or two that Jackie broke his ankle in the filming of this movie. Still tell me the last time you saw a western movie star leap from a roof on to the fire escape of the next building!!! Truly amazing stuff. On the down side the western characters and acting are very wooden but hey just enjoy Chan and hopefully then go seek out his Hong Kong movies.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Could The Road To The Dream Be More Enjoyable Than Fulfilling It ?!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ahmed elshikh (ahmed_abd_elreheem@yahoo.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/8/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is one of the best movies by (Jackie Chan), maybe more fun than the majority of his previous Asian ones and the other later American ones too. Here the action is so ambitious, the rhythm is hot, the production is big, the technique is above mediocre, and the heroine is sexier ! I think the first half was so good and catchy; however the second half about the diamonds was another movie ! I enjoyed the story of the first plot, and the huge Action of the second one. The matter of having 2 girls had never been used correctly, there was no use out of putting some love scenes for (Chan) and the market's owner, in the same time that he fell in love with the street girl simply and terminally !, so why the first storyline from the start?? Then look at the street gang, why all of this hatred for (Jackie)? They looked like another brainless pure evil comes from another previous movies like (The Enforcer), (Robocop), and (Police Academy). I hated also the matter of the nonexistent anticlimax, it's maybe a habit at (Chan)'s movies to watch the climax then PAAM the closing credits with the bloopers !!, here it was so provoking as we didn't know exactly what happened after, like they had no time to shoot more ! Sometimes it's a terrible habit as it makes the whole condition so deficient, especially the viewer's satisfaction. It's clear that (Chan) was determined to be a star in America, it was his dream, and it would never happen until 4 years after with (Rush Hour) which's not one of my favorites where Chan undoubtedly is less shining, maybe it succeeded because it was the right formula or the right time I don't know. But here like every Chan's movie the Action, as usual, exceeded everything. And the story, as ever, is just a superficial cover for fun with no possible deepness. It was enough for (Chan) and all of his team to assure how courageous, stubborn, and romantic the Asian is; in the same time that the American is so violent, criminal, and deranged whether poor or rich. Despite the balance that they made (kind American policemen, and one evil Asian in the street gang). On so many levels it proves how the Asian cinematic hero became better and his adventures became bigger since another very well known Asian-in-western-evil-world and I mean (Bruce Lee) at (Way of the Dragon) nearly 25 years earlier, to invade America itself (it was Italy in the first one), and to present Mad Mad world comic Action also through this maniac hero who, at the time, needed no stunts or wires ! So ultimately (Rumble in the Bronx - 1996) is nice strong action, where (Jackie) is in classical example for being a real icon, original star, and great clown. Makes you wonder a bit about what he lost, after fulfilling his dream, in next American movies.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Funny and spectacular Jackie Chan movie in his first American super hit with highlights provided by a hovercraft
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ma-cortes
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Amusing and entertaining Chan film in which he demonstrates his sensational skills as a great action man . It deals with a young man named Keong (Jackie Chan) visiting and helping his uncle in New York City finds himself forced to fight a street gang and the mob with his martial art abilities . His uncle has a local Chinese supermarket, which he owns and is in the process of selling to Elaine (Anita Mui). Later on , Keong befriends a neighbor kid and his sister (Francois Yip) and beats up some neighborhood thugs . Hong Kong/US/Canada action comedy full of over-the-top struggles , excitement , thrills , ingenious stunts , slapstick , lots of brawls but with abundant humor and tongue-in-cheek . This fun movie is plenty of intrigue , unstopped action , and overwhelming stunt-work with breathtaking ending images including a hovercraft . Jackie Chan is top notch as one army man fighting a group of heinous villains and as always he makes his own stunts like is well showed at the final credits . Awesome , incredible stunts and brief comic touches , as usual ; the picture is better constructed than Chan's predecessors films . The lighting-paced storyline slows down at times , but frantic action sequences make up for it . Spotlights movie include spectacular fights , including bounds and leaps , impressive and interminable struggles , an impressive final struggle between Jackie Chan and enemies . The warehouse fight scene took twenty days to film, with Chan having to teach the local stunt players to fight "Hong Kong style". In addition other fine action sequences in overwhelming and extraordinary style . The script called for a leap from the top of a parking lot to a fire escape on the floor below on the building across the street , as is his custom, director Stanley Tong attempted the stunt before asking any actors to do so. He tried it with the help of a cable harness, but quickly decided it would be safer without the harness. The landing point was not visible from the point where the jump began, so tape was placed on the take-off point as a guide ,the jump was completed perfectly by 'Chan, Jackie' on the first attempt, doing his own stunts as is his custom . The jump was captured by four cameras. This is an acceptable action movie distinguished by nicely cinematography of the spectacular sequences , and contains agreeable sense of humor as well as previous entries . Jackie Chan usually forms couple to notorious actresses as Maggie Chung and Michelle Yeoh . In this outing Jackie teams up to gorgeous Francoise Yip (who broke her leg while filming the scene where she rides a motorbike across the tops of parked cars , she insisted on returning to the set after her leg was plastered at hospital) and prestigious Chinese actress Anita Mui , a fine action star in their own right but sadly she early died by cancer . Both of them starred together several films such as &uml;Mr Canton and Lady Rose&uml; and &uml;Legend of the drunken master&uml; . Filming in Vancouver, Canada on October 6th, 1994, Chan broke his right ankle while attempting the scene where he jumps onto the hovercraft. Despite the injury, he was present at the premiere of &uml;The legend of the drunken fighter&uml; at the Vancouver International Film Festival that night. Later in the production, Tong sprained his ankle, completing the film on crutches . Two stunt women also broke their legs during the filming of the motorcycle chase. The picture achieved big success in China , USA and all around the world . However , Jackie Chan's failed at Box-office in his American debut ,&uml;Battle creek brawl&uml; . Chan is a hard-working actor and director throughout his long and varied career . Chan usually pays overt homage to two of his greatest influences as Charles Chaplin and Harold Lloyd . He went on playing &uml;Cannoball&uml; , &uml;The protector&uml; and "Rumble in the Bronx", until getting all American success with &uml;Shangai Knights&uml; , &uml;The tuxedo&uml; , &uml;Around the world in 80 days&uml; and &uml;Rush hour&uml; trilogy , and the recent &uml;Karate kid&uml;. Of course , his biggest hits were &uml;The Police story&uml; series that won the Golden Horse Award, a Chinese version of the Oscar , the first was titled &uml;Police story (1985)&uml; directed by the same Chan , it was a perfect action film for enthusiastic of the genre ; the following was &uml;Police story 2 (1988)&uml; also pretty violent and with abundant humor touches . It's followed by &uml;Supercop&uml; or &uml;Police story 3&uml; and finally , &uml;Police story IV : Crime story&uml; . The picture is well produced by the great Asian producer Raymond Chow and Golden Harvest production and compellingly directed by Stanley Tong and helped by Jackie Chan . Rating : Acceptable and passable , the picture has its sensational moments here and there , but also with abundant humor touches mostly provided by its agile star , the super Jackie stunningly accompanied by Anita Mui and Francois Yip . It's a perfect action film for enthusiasts of the genre and especially for Jackie fans .
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Chan fighting and goofing but that's it - 69%
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Benjamin Cox
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/9/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    For many years, Jackie Chan had been working away in his little niche as the best dammed martial-arts comedy star in the business. But martial arts movies have been never mainstream since Bruce Lee roared into immortality in "Enter The Dragon" and Chan takes a very different path, one more based around physical comedy like a violent Buster Keaton. This was Chan's Hollywood debut and, frankly, it shows - there is some shockingly bad dubbing, the plot is really quite stupid and the acting is... yeah, well. Anyway, this is one of those films that you simply have to hang up your expectations and just enjoy. It reminded me, in an odd way, of "Smokey And The Bandit" - it's hardly a classic but in spite of its many flaws, there is a sense of infectious fun behind it. Chan plays Keung who visits his uncle in New York (Bill Tung) just as he marries and leaves Keung to manage his Chinese market. After concluding the sale of the market to the bookish Elaine (Anita Mui), Keung incurs the wrath of a biker gang led by Tony (Marc Akerstream) who trash the place and leave Keung bloodied and beat up in an alley. But while Keung tries to fight back, he befriends wheelchair-bound boy next door (Morgan Lam) and his sister Nancy (Fran&ccedil;oise Yip) - who is affiliated with the gang. And to make matters worse, the local mob have been responsible for a daring diamond heist and after a mix-up with another biker (Garvin Cross), Keung finds himself pursued by both the bikers and the mobsters. Like I said, the plot is as old-school as the fashions visible in the nightclub scene. Like another early Chan outing (namely, "Mr Nice Guy"), there are certain things you notice like how every female character in both movies find Chan irresistible or how a simple misunderstanding can get Chan into heaps of trouble. There are other things as well - neither films have gripping stories or even much in the way of cohesion. The dub doesn't help "Rumble In The Bronx", reducing each scene to its component dialogue and physical comedy and build-up to the real reason you watch this film - the action scenes. Chan excels as the physical stuff, leaping across the screen like a kung-fu kicking Daffy Duck and a lot of the gimmicky really works like the scene in the supermarket where Chan uses seemingly every prop in the vicinity. "Rumble In The Bronx" is less of a film and more of a celluloid resume for its star, allowing Chan to demonstrate his extraordinary ability to fling himself into every bad guy in the blink of an eye. I fully understand why Chan might choose this otherwise utterly forgettable film to break into bigger movies - it doesn't let things like a plot get in the way of Chan doing what he does best as well as showing off his comic timing which, whilst not brilliant, at least offers something more than a grimacing hero endlessly bashing the baddies until the credits roll. In most other martial-arts films, the end climax involves the lead baddie use a variety of weapons which will cause the hero to bleed but not enough to prevent good triumphing over evil. In this film, the climax is so ridiculous that even my wife burst out laughing. If you can drop your serious face and revel in the goofiness of it then this might entertain you as much as it did me. Just don't take it seriously because if anything, this is probably the least serious film I've seen all year.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    someone stole my cushion!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jcallows
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/7/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie is about a boy and his quest for a new cushion. Watch it for its creative fight scenes and for that girl who plays the boy's sister. Watch it also to laugh at the atrocious acting and dialog. Other than that, there's really no reason to watch. This film is basically a bunch of action sequences strung together with some dialog in between. The dialog can be summed up as "where are the diamonds?", "give me the diamonds!" and, of course, "someone stole my cushion!" But the action is where this film excels. As is the custom in all Jackie Chan films, this film is loaded with creative martial arts fighting and spectacular stunts. This film is definitely fun to watch. But it's kind of like watching porn. You will be tempted to fast forward through all the dialog to get to the good parts.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Awesome
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tigerstar154
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/6/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Rumble in the bronx I heard a lot about this movie and how it launched Jackie Chan's career in the west. i saw this and it was awesome despite the fact it was a typical 90s movie. Jackie Chan visits his uncle in NY and becomes involved with a motorcycle gang. The pluses: Jackie Chan and his action work, and the the girl who plays Nancy. The Minuses: Weird acting by white actors, kid was annoying, corny at times and melodramatic. Overall, Rumble in the bronx is great and funny at time. 8/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    my favourite jackie chan movie, a blast from start to finish
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    daworldismine
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/5/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    rumble in the bronx is one of my favourite movies of alltime, and my favourite jackie chan movie, no im not saying its his best, im saying its my favourite, to me it has some of his best fight scenes and stunts of the 90's, and the movie made him a world wide star whats not to love, and plus the movie is very funny, easily one of his funniest movies. the first jackie chan movie i ever taped off TV, and the one I've seen the most, to me rumble in the bronx is the best action movie of the 90's, perfect action, perfect comedy, perfect movie. jackie chan rarely fails to deliver, and this is one of his best movies, and i recommend it to anybody who wants to see some awesome action
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Jackie Chan in America
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ebiros2
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/11/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is one of the movies Jackie Chan made targeted for audience outside of Asia. The story takes place in New York with many American actors in the supporting role. To me this wasn't one of his best production, but there's one scene that blows me away every time I see it. This is the scene where Jackie takes a leap from the roof of one building into a balcony of the adjacent building. I don't think there was any wire attached to Jackie, so if he missed, he could have been dead, and he could have missed very easily. Some of the scenes look staged and isn't the natural Jackie Chan type scenes that I'm used to. Maybe the crew wasn't used to the American style production. It's really strange to discover that Jackie Chan movie looks below par compared to his own when it's way above average compared to other American action movie of this type. I also didn't like the senseless violence, but if wasn't so violent, maybe it wouldn't look like authentic America. Whatever the reason, they might have done it better. It's still a Jackie Chan movie, and you'll get that special dose of Jackie Chan action with this movie. If you're a Jackie Chan fan, it's sure to please you.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Chan at his Comical, Lightning-Quick Best
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Sean Lamberger
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/7/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Jackie Chan's first major American breakthrough remains his most energetic, entertaining spectacle. The film's storyline is a joke, with supposedly hardcore Bronx motorcycle gangs coming off like characters in a Saturday morning cartoon, but that's clearly not the point. The plot's only there to fill the space between fight scenes with a few randomly connected antagonizing situations, and in many instances its complete lack of any connection with reality is actually quite charming. The real focus, naturally, is on Chan's inventive use of his surroundings and blistering hand speed during his frequent clashes with gaudily-dressed bikers and, later on, suit-and-sunglasses adorned g-men. Regardless of locale, Jackie is somehow able to find an unsuspecting prop, then quickly put it to use in bludgeoning somewhere in the range of a dozen different combatants in wildly original ways, keeping audiences surprised and indulged. A kindergarten-grade story won't win this rumble any awards, but as a vehicle for its star's own inimitable style of celluloid-friendly martial arts it's perfect.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Streets of San Bronx
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    thesar-2
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/9/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I'd guess you'd have to call 'Rumble in the Bronx' an extreme example of a guilty pleasure. Though back in the 1990s, it was not my first introduction to Jackie Chan (the inferior 'Supercop' was) it was the one that got me hooked on his work. All the way through this viewing  the first in many years, the word "silly" kept popping up in my mind. It's dialogue, acting, stereotypes and shoddy cop work was so hilariously bad, I could only think this had to be written by someone who's only contact with the U.S.A. involves watching old 1970s cop hour-long dramas. And while some scenes were actually funny (SEE: the wrench threat) some were downright unintentionally funny (SEE: the toddler-toss and the entire closing on the golf course.) Leaving all that negative behind, it was an extreme joy watching Chan perform his own stunts in many, many inventive ways while simultaneously creating a very human and good-hearted character. The stunts were simply amazing and if one were to watch today for the first time, they need to know: he did them all himself, without a green screens, cables, etc. As arrogant as Chan is  I've read his biography, it's dripping with arrogance, he does have great gifts in originality, showmanship, pride in his work and making sure he never uses traditional American trickery/stunts. (This changes later in his work, when he was forced and got older, but this work and ones around it were all pure Chan.) Synopsis: Good-natured nephew Chan visits NYC and gets thrown in extraordinary circumstances: fighting both gangs and mob bosses while helping 2 women, his Uncle and a handicapped child. All that's irrelevant; what matters is once the action starts, it never lets up. And with an open-mind, what a fun rumble you'll have. Side Note: Wow.. not only was it painful for all the actors to get hurt during production (not to mention the roughly 16 dozen vehicles) it was also gut wrenching to watch the closing credits that showed mostly the unintentional crashes, broken bones, etc. You really have to hand it to the devotion of the crew, cast and Chan. Definitely Chan. My comments about his arrogance does not mean I don't admire the man, especially his extremely poor and underprivileged beginnings to the entertainer he became. He's one of the very few actors/action stars that no matter how incredibly silly his movies look to me  it has to be a culture thing, it's always a rush to see how long his fight scenes last, how inventive he becomes and simply how exciting they are.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Jackie cracks the west
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ed_two_o_nine
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/2/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Well here we go once again with the undisputed king of action comedy. The one and only Jackie Chan. While this is nowhere near Chan's best movie we can be grateful for the fact that this is the film that finally gave Chan his much deserved break in the USA. This is the story on Chan's character Keung who comes to the Bronx for his uncle's wedding and ends up caught up in a series of events that involve biker gangs, and diamond robbers. But really none of this matters this is just an excuse for Jackie to show of his amazing action skills (in the fight scenes which he also choreographed), and this he does to his usual amazing standards. There seems to be more edits in the fight scenes that is normal for Jackie but I suspect this might be down to one of two things. One making the film more palatable for a western audience. Or two that Jackie broke his ankle in the filming of this movie. Still tell me the last time you saw a western movie star leap from a roof on to the fire escape of the next building!!! Truly amazing stuff. On the down side the western characters and acting are very wooden but hey just enjoy Chan and hopefully then go seek out his Hong Kong movies.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Could The Road To The Dream Be More Enjoyable Than Fulfilling It ?!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ahmed elshikh (ahmed_abd_elreheem@yahoo.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/8/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is one of the best movies by (Jackie Chan), maybe more fun than the majority of his previous Asian ones and the other later American ones too. Here the action is so ambitious, the rhythm is hot, the production is big, the technique is above mediocre, and the heroine is sexier ! I think the first half was so good and catchy; however the second half about the diamonds was another movie ! I enjoyed the story of the first plot, and the huge Action of the second one. The matter of having 2 girls had never been used correctly, there was no use out of putting some love scenes for (Chan) and the market's owner, in the same time that he fell in love with the street girl simply and terminally !, so why the first storyline from the start?? Then look at the street gang, why all of this hatred for (Jackie)? They looked like another brainless pure evil comes from another previous movies like (The Enforcer), (Robocop), and (Police Academy). I hated also the matter of the nonexistent anticlimax, it's maybe a habit at (Chan)'s movies to watch the climax then PAAM the closing credits with the bloopers !!, here it was so provoking as we didn't know exactly what happened after, like they had no time to shoot more ! Sometimes it's a terrible habit as it makes the whole condition so deficient, especially the viewer's satisfaction. It's clear that (Chan) was determined to be a star in America, it was his dream, and it would never happen until 4 years after with (Rush Hour) which's not one of my favorites where Chan undoubtedly is less shining, maybe it succeeded because it was the right formula or the right time I don't know. But here like every Chan's movie the Action, as usual, exceeded everything. And the story, as ever, is just a superficial cover for fun with no possible deepness. It was enough for (Chan) and all of his team to assure how courageous, stubborn, and romantic the Asian is; in the same time that the American is so violent, criminal, and deranged whether poor or rich. Despite the balance that they made (kind American policemen, and one evil Asian in the street gang). On so many levels it proves how the Asian cinematic hero became better and his adventures became bigger since another very well known Asian-in-western-evil-world and I mean (Bruce Lee) at (Way of the Dragon) nearly 25 years earlier, to invade America itself (it was Italy in the first one), and to present Mad Mad world comic Action also through this maniac hero who, at the time, needed no stunts or wires ! So ultimately (Rumble in the Bronx - 1996) is nice strong action, where (Jackie) is in classical example for being a real icon, original star, and great clown. Makes you wonder a bit about what he lost, after fulfilling his dream, in next American movies.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Funny and spectacular Jackie Chan movie in his first American super hit with highlights provided by a hovercraft
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ma-cortes
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Amusing and entertaining Chan film in which he demonstrates his sensational skills as a great action man . It deals with a young man named Keong (Jackie Chan) visiting and helping his uncle in New York City finds himself forced to fight a street gang and the mob with his martial art abilities . His uncle has a local Chinese supermarket, which he owns and is in the process of selling to Elaine (Anita Mui). Later on , Keong befriends a neighbor kid and his sister (Francois Yip) and beats up some neighborhood thugs . Hong Kong/US/Canada action comedy full of over-the-top struggles , excitement , thrills , ingenious stunts , slapstick , lots of brawls but with abundant humor and tongue-in-cheek . This fun movie is plenty of intrigue , unstopped action , and overwhelming stunt-work with breathtaking ending images including a hovercraft . Jackie Chan is top notch as one army man fighting a group of heinous villains and as always he makes his own stunts like is well showed at the final credits . Awesome , incredible stunts and brief comic touches , as usual ; the picture is better constructed than Chan's predecessors films . The lighting-paced storyline slows down at times , but frantic action sequences make up for it . Spotlights movie include spectacular fights , including bounds and leaps , impressive and interminable struggles , an impressive final struggle between Jackie Chan and enemies . The warehouse fight scene took twenty days to film, with Chan having to teach the local stunt players to fight "Hong Kong style". In addition other fine action sequences in overwhelming and extraordinary style . The script called for a leap from the top of a parking lot to a fire escape on the floor below on the building across the street , as is his custom, director Stanley Tong attempted the stunt before asking any actors to do so. He tried it with the help of a cable harness, but quickly decided it would be safer without the harness. The landing point was not visible from the point where the jump began, so tape was placed on the take-off point as a guide ,the jump was completed perfectly by 'Chan, Jackie' on the first attempt, doing his own stunts as is his custom . The jump was captured by four cameras. This is an acceptable action movie distinguished by nicely cinematography of the spectacular sequences , and contains agreeable sense of humor as well as previous entries . Jackie Chan usually forms couple to notorious actresses as Maggie Chung and Michelle Yeoh . In this outing Jackie teams up to gorgeous Francoise Yip (who broke her leg while filming the scene where she rides a motorbike across the tops of parked cars , she insisted on returning to the set after her leg was plastered at hospital) and prestigious Chinese actress Anita Mui , a fine action star in their own right but sadly she early died by cancer . Both of them starred together several films such as &uml;Mr Canton and Lady Rose&uml; and &uml;Legend of the drunken master&uml; . Filming in Vancouver, Canada on October 6th, 1994, Chan broke his right ankle while attempting the scene where he jumps onto the hovercraft. Despite the injury, he was present at the premiere of &uml;The legend of the drunken fighter&uml; at the Vancouver International Film Festival that night. Later in the production, Tong sprained his ankle, completing the film on crutches . Two stunt women also broke their legs during the filming of the motorcycle chase. The picture achieved big success in China , USA and all around the world . However , Jackie Chan's failed at Box-office in his American debut ,&uml;Battle creek brawl&uml; . Chan is a hard-working actor and director throughout his long and varied career . Chan usually pays overt homage to two of his greatest influences as Charles Chaplin and Harold Lloyd . He went on playing &uml;Cannoball&uml; , &uml;The protector&uml; and "Rumble in the Bronx", until getting all American success with &uml;Shangai Knights&uml; , &uml;The tuxedo&uml; , &uml;Around the world in 80 days&uml; and &uml;Rush hour&uml; trilogy , and the recent &uml;Karate kid&uml;. Of course , his biggest hits were &uml;The Police story&uml; series that won the Golden Horse Award, a Chinese version of the Oscar , the first was titled &uml;Police story (1985)&uml; directed by the same Chan , it was a perfect action film for enthusiastic of the genre ; the following was &uml;Police story 2 (1988)&uml; also pretty violent and with abundant humor touches . It's followed by &uml;Supercop&uml; or &uml;Police story 3&uml; and finally , &uml;Police story IV : Crime story&uml; . The picture is well produced by the great Asian producer Raymond Chow and Golden Harvest production and compellingly directed by Stanley Tong and helped by Jackie Chan . Rating : Acceptable and passable , the picture has its sensational moments here and there , but also with abundant humor touches mostly provided by its agile star , the super Jackie stunningly accompanied by Anita Mui and Francois Yip . It's a perfect action film for enthusiasts of the genre and especially for Jackie fans .
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Chan fighting and goofing but that's it - 69%
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Benjamin Cox
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/9/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    For many years, Jackie Chan had been working away in his little niche as the best dammed martial-arts comedy star in the business. But martial arts movies have been never mainstream since Bruce Lee roared into immortality in "Enter The Dragon" and Chan takes a very different path, one more based around physical comedy like a violent Buster Keaton. This was Chan's Hollywood debut and, frankly, it shows - there is some shockingly bad dubbing, the plot is really quite stupid and the acting is... yeah, well. Anyway, this is one of those films that you simply have to hang up your expectations and just enjoy. It reminded me, in an odd way, of "Smokey And The Bandit" - it's hardly a classic but in spite of its many flaws, there is a sense of infectious fun behind it. Chan plays Keung who visits his uncle in New York (Bill Tung) just as he marries and leaves Keung to manage his Chinese market. After concluding the sale of the market to the bookish Elaine (Anita Mui), Keung incurs the wrath of a biker gang led by Tony (Marc Akerstream) who trash the place and leave Keung bloodied and beat up in an alley. But while Keung tries to fight back, he befriends wheelchair-bound boy next door (Morgan Lam) and his sister Nancy (Fran&ccedil;oise Yip) - who is affiliated with the gang. And to make matters worse, the local mob have been responsible for a daring diamond heist and after a mix-up with another biker (Garvin Cross), Keung finds himself pursued by both the bikers and the mobsters. Like I said, the plot is as old-school as the fashions visible in the nightclub scene. Like another early Chan outing (namely, "Mr Nice Guy"), there are certain things you notice like how every female character in both movies find Chan irresistible or how a simple misunderstanding can get Chan into heaps of trouble. There are other things as well - neither films have gripping stories or even much in the way of cohesion. The dub doesn't help "Rumble In The Bronx", reducing each scene to its component dialogue and physical comedy and build-up to the real reason you watch this film - the action scenes. Chan excels as the physical stuff, leaping across the screen like a kung-fu kicking Daffy Duck and a lot of the gimmicky really works like the scene in the supermarket where Chan uses seemingly every prop in the vicinity. "Rumble In The Bronx" is less of a film and more of a celluloid resume for its star, allowing Chan to demonstrate his extraordinary ability to fling himself into every bad guy in the blink of an eye. I fully understand why Chan might choose this otherwise utterly forgettable film to break into bigger movies - it doesn't let things like a plot get in the way of Chan doing what he does best as well as showing off his comic timing which, whilst not brilliant, at least offers something more than a grimacing hero endlessly bashing the baddies until the credits roll. In most other martial-arts films, the end climax involves the lead baddie use a variety of weapons which will cause the hero to bleed but not enough to prevent good triumphing over evil. In this film, the climax is so ridiculous that even my wife burst out laughing. If you can drop your serious face and revel in the goofiness of it then this might entertain you as much as it did me. Just don't take it seriously because if anything, this is probably the least serious film I've seen all year.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    someone stole my cushion!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jcallows
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/7/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie is about a boy and his quest for a new cushion. Watch it for its creative fight scenes and for that girl who plays the boy's sister. Watch it also to laugh at the atrocious acting and dialog. Other than that, there's really no reason to watch. This film is basically a bunch of action sequences strung together with some dialog in between. The dialog can be summed up as "where are the diamonds?", "give me the diamonds!" and, of course, "someone stole my cushion!" But the action is where this film excels. As is the custom in all Jackie Chan films, this film is loaded with creative martial arts fighting and spectacular stunts. This film is definitely fun to watch. But it's kind of like watching porn. You will be tempted to fast forward through all the dialog to get to the good parts.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Awesome
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tigerstar154
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/6/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Rumble in the bronx I heard a lot about this movie and how it launched Jackie Chan's career in the west. i saw this and it was awesome despite the fact it was a typical 90s movie. Jackie Chan visits his uncle in NY and becomes involved with a motorcycle gang. The pluses: Jackie Chan and his action work, and the the girl who plays Nancy. The Minuses: Weird acting by white actors, kid was annoying, corny at times and melodramatic. Overall, Rumble in the bronx is great and funny at time. 8/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    my favourite jackie chan movie, a blast from start to finish
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    daworldismine
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/5/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    rumble in the bronx is one of my favourite movies of alltime, and my favourite jackie chan movie, no im not saying its his best, im saying its my favourite, to me it has some of his best fight scenes and stunts of the 90's, and the movie made him a world wide star whats not to love, and plus the movie is very funny, easily one of his funniest movies. the first jackie chan movie i ever taped off TV, and the one I've seen the most, to me rumble in the bronx is the best action movie of the 90's, perfect action, perfect comedy, perfect movie. jackie chan rarely fails to deliver, and this is one of his best movies, and i recommend it to anybody who wants to see some awesome action
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Jackie Chan in America
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ebiros2
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/11/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is one of the movies Jackie Chan made targeted for audience outside of Asia. The story takes place in New York with many American actors in the supporting role. To me this wasn't one of his best production, but there's one scene that blows me away every time I see it. This is the scene where Jackie takes a leap from the roof of one building into a balcony of the adjacent building. I don't think there was any wire attached to Jackie, so if he missed, he could have been dead, and he could have missed very easily. Some of the scenes look staged and isn't the natural Jackie Chan type scenes that I'm used to. Maybe the crew wasn't used to the American style production. It's really strange to discover that Jackie Chan movie looks below par compared to his own when it's way above average compared to other American action movie of this type. I also didn't like the senseless violence, but if wasn't so violent, maybe it wouldn't look like authentic America. Whatever the reason, they might have done it better. It's still a Jackie Chan movie, and you'll get that special dose of Jackie Chan action with this movie. If you're a Jackie Chan fan, it's sure to please you.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Chan at his Comical, Lightning-Quick Best
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Sean Lamberger
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/7/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Jackie Chan's first major American breakthrough remains his most energetic, entertaining spectacle. The film's storyline is a joke, with supposedly hardcore Bronx motorcycle gangs coming off like characters in a Saturday morning cartoon, but that's clearly not the point. The plot's only there to fill the space between fight scenes with a few randomly connected antagonizing situations, and in many instances its complete lack of any connection with reality is actually quite charming. The real focus, naturally, is on Chan's inventive use of his surroundings and blistering hand speed during his frequent clashes with gaudily-dressed bikers and, later on, suit-and-sunglasses adorned g-men. Regardless of locale, Jackie is somehow able to find an unsuspecting prop, then quickly put it to use in bludgeoning somewhere in the range of a dozen different combatants in wildly original ways, keeping audiences surprised and indulged. A kindergarten-grade story won't win this rumble any awards, but as a vehicle for its star's own inimitable style of celluloid-friendly martial arts it's perfect.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Streets of San Bronx
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    thesar-2
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/9/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I'd guess you'd have to call 'Rumble in the Bronx' an extreme example of a guilty pleasure. Though back in the 1990s, it was not my first introduction to Jackie Chan (the inferior 'Supercop' was) it was the one that got me hooked on his work. All the way through this viewing  the first in many years, the word "silly" kept popping up in my mind. It's dialogue, acting, stereotypes and shoddy cop work was so hilariously bad, I could only think this had to be written by someone who's only contact with the U.S.A. involves watching old 1970s cop hour-long dramas. And while some scenes were actually funny (SEE: the wrench threat) some were downright unintentionally funny (SEE: the toddler-toss and the entire closing on the golf course.) Leaving all that negative behind, it was an extreme joy watching Chan perform his own stunts in many, many inventive ways while simultaneously creating a very human and good-hearted character. The stunts were simply amazing and if one were to watch today for the first time, they need to know: he did them all himself, without a green screens, cables, etc. As arrogant as Chan is  I've read his biography, it's dripping with arrogance, he does have great gifts in originality, showmanship, pride in his work and making sure he never uses traditional American trickery/stunts. (This changes later in his work, when he was forced and got older, but this work and ones around it were all pure Chan.) Synopsis: Good-natured nephew Chan visits NYC and gets thrown in extraordinary circumstances: fighting both gangs and mob bosses while helping 2 women, his Uncle and a handicapped child. All that's irrelevant; what matters is once the action starts, it never lets up. And with an open-mind, what a fun rumble you'll have. Side Note: Wow.. not only was it painful for all the actors to get hurt during production (not to mention the roughly 16 dozen vehicles) it was also gut wrenching to watch the closing credits that showed mostly the unintentional crashes, broken bones, etc. You really have to hand it to the devotion of the crew, cast and Chan. Definitely Chan. My comments about his arrogance does not mean I don't admire the man, especially his extremely poor and underprivileged beginnings to the entertainer he became. He's one of the very few actors/action stars that no matter how incredibly silly his movies look to me  it has to be a culture thing, it's always a rush to see how long his fight scenes last, how inventive he becomes and simply how exciting they are.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Jackie cracks the west
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ed_two_o_nine
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/2/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Well here we go once again with the undisputed king of action comedy. The one and only Jackie Chan. While this is nowhere near Chan's best movie we can be grateful for the fact that this is the film that finally gave Chan his much deserved break in the USA. This is the story on Chan's character Keung who comes to the Bronx for his uncle's wedding and ends up caught up in a series of events that involve biker gangs, and diamond robbers. But really none of this matters this is just an excuse for Jackie to show of his amazing action skills (in the fight scenes which he also choreographed), and this he does to his usual amazing standards. There seems to be more edits in the fight scenes that is normal for Jackie but I suspect this might be down to one of two things. One making the film more palatable for a western audience. Or two that Jackie broke his ankle in the filming of this movie. Still tell me the last time you saw a western movie star leap from a roof on to the fire escape of the next building!!! Truly amazing stuff. On the down side the western characters and acting are very wooden but hey just enjoy Chan and hopefully then go seek out his Hong Kong movies.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Could The Road To The Dream Be More Enjoyable Than Fulfilling It ?!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ahmed elshikh (ahmed_abd_elreheem@yahoo.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/8/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is one of the best movies by (Jackie Chan), maybe more fun than the majority of his previous Asian ones and the other later American ones too. Here the action is so ambitious, the rhythm is hot, the production is big, the technique is above mediocre, and the heroine is sexier ! I think the first half was so good and catchy; however the second half about the diamonds was another movie ! I enjoyed the story of the first plot, and the huge Action of the second one. The matter of having 2 girls had never been used correctly, there was no use out of putting some love scenes for (Chan) and the market's owner, in the same time that he fell in love with the street girl simply and terminally !, so why the first storyline from the start?? Then look at the street gang, why all of this hatred for (Jackie)? They looked like another brainless pure evil comes from another previous movies like (The Enforcer), (Robocop), and (Police Academy). I hated also the matter of the nonexistent anticlimax, it's maybe a habit at (Chan)'s movies to watch the climax then PAAM the closing credits with the bloopers !!, here it was so provoking as we didn't know exactly what happened after, like they had no time to shoot more ! Sometimes it's a terrible habit as it makes the whole condition so deficient, especially the viewer's satisfaction. It's clear that (Chan) was determined to be a star in America, it was his dream, and it would never happen until 4 years after with (Rush Hour) which's not one of my favorites where Chan undoubtedly is less shining, maybe it succeeded because it was the right formula or the right time I don't know. But here like every Chan's movie the Action, as usual, exceeded everything. And the story, as ever, is just a superficial cover for fun with no possible deepness. It was enough for (Chan) and all of his team to assure how courageous, stubborn, and romantic the Asian is; in the same time that the American is so violent, criminal, and deranged whether poor or rich. Despite the balance that they made (kind American policemen, and one evil Asian in the street gang). On so many levels it proves how the Asian cinematic hero became better and his adventures became bigger since another very well known Asian-in-western-evil-world and I mean (Bruce Lee) at (Way of the Dragon) nearly 25 years earlier, to invade America itself (it was Italy in the first one), and to present Mad Mad world comic Action also through this maniac hero who, at the time, needed no stunts or wires ! So ultimately (Rumble in the Bronx - 1996) is nice strong action, where (Jackie) is in classical example for being a real icon, original star, and great clown. Makes you wonder a bit about what he lost, after fulfilling his dream, in next American movies.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Funny and spectacular Jackie Chan movie in his first American super hit with highlights provided by a hovercraft
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ma-cortes
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Amusing and entertaining Chan film in which he demonstrates his sensational skills as a great action man . It deals with a young man named Keong (Jackie Chan) visiting and helping his uncle in New York City finds himself forced to fight a street gang and the mob with his martial art abilities . His uncle has a local Chinese supermarket, which he owns and is in the process of selling to Elaine (Anita Mui). Later on , Keong befriends a neighbor kid and his sister (Francois Yip) and beats up some neighborhood thugs . Hong Kong/US/Canada action comedy full of over-the-top struggles , excitement , thrills , ingenious stunts , slapstick , lots of brawls but with abundant humor and tongue-in-cheek . This fun movie is plenty of intrigue , unstopped action , and overwhelming stunt-work with breathtaking ending images including a hovercraft . Jackie Chan is top notch as one army man fighting a group of heinous villains and as always he makes his own stunts like is well showed at the final credits . Awesome , incredible stunts and brief comic touches , as usual ; the picture is better constructed than Chan's predecessors films . The lighting-paced storyline slows down at times , but frantic action sequences make up for it . Spotlights movie include spectacular fights , including bounds and leaps , impressive and interminable struggles , an impressive final struggle between Jackie Chan and enemies . The warehouse fight scene took twenty days to film, with Chan having to teach the local stunt players to fight "Hong Kong style". In addition other fine action sequences in overwhelming and extraordinary style . The script called for a leap from the top of a parking lot to a fire escape on the floor below on the building across the street , as is his custom, director Stanley Tong attempted the stunt before asking any actors to do so. He tried it with the help of a cable harness, but quickly decided it would be safer without the harness. The landing point was not visible from the point where the jump began, so tape was placed on the take-off point as a guide ,the jump was completed perfectly by 'Chan, Jackie' on the first attempt, doing his own stunts as is his custom . The jump was captured by four cameras. This is an acceptable action movie distinguished by nicely cinematography of the spectacular sequences , and contains agreeable sense of humor as well as previous entries . Jackie Chan usually forms couple to notorious actresses as Maggie Chung and Michelle Yeoh . In this outing Jackie teams up to gorgeous Francoise Yip (who broke her leg while filming the scene where she rides a motorbike across the tops of parked cars , she insisted on returning to the set after her leg was plastered at hospital) and prestigious Chinese actress Anita Mui , a fine action star in their own right but sadly she early died by cancer . Both of them starred together several films such as &uml;Mr Canton and Lady Rose&uml; and &uml;Legend of the drunken master&uml; . Filming in Vancouver, Canada on October 6th, 1994, Chan broke his right ankle while attempting the scene where he jumps onto the hovercraft. Despite the injury, he was present at the premiere of &uml;The legend of the drunken fighter&uml; at the Vancouver International Film Festival that night. Later in the production, Tong sprained his ankle, completing the film on crutches . Two stunt women also broke their legs during the filming of the motorcycle chase. The picture achieved big success in China , USA and all around the world . However , Jackie Chan's failed at Box-office in his American debut ,&uml;Battle creek brawl&uml; . Chan is a hard-working actor and director throughout his long and varied career . Chan usually pays overt homage to two of his greatest influences as Charles Chaplin and Harold Lloyd . He went on playing &uml;Cannoball&uml; , &uml;The protector&uml; and "Rumble in the Bronx", until getting all American success with &uml;Shangai Knights&uml; , &uml;The tuxedo&uml; , &uml;Around the world in 80 days&uml; and &uml;Rush hour&uml; trilogy , and the recent &uml;Karate kid&uml;. Of course , his biggest hits were &uml;The Police story&uml; series that won the Golden Horse Award, a Chinese version of the Oscar , the first was titled &uml;Police story (1985)&uml; directed by the same Chan , it was a perfect action film for enthusiastic of the genre ; the following was &uml;Police story 2 (1988)&uml; also pretty violent and with abundant humor touches . It's followed by &uml;Supercop&uml; or &uml;Police story 3&uml; and finally , &uml;Police story IV : Crime story&uml; . The picture is well produced by the great Asian producer Raymond Chow and Golden Harvest production and compellingly directed by Stanley Tong and helped by Jackie Chan . Rating : Acceptable and passable , the picture has its sensational moments here and there , but also with abundant humor touches mostly provided by its agile star , the super Jackie stunningly accompanied by Anita Mui and Francois Yip . It's a perfect action film for enthusiasts of the genre and especially for Jackie fans .
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Chan fighting and goofing but that's it - 69%
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Benjamin Cox
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/9/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    For many years, Jackie Chan had been working away in his little niche as the best dammed martial-arts comedy star in the business. But martial arts movies have been never mainstream since Bruce Lee roared into immortality in "Enter The Dragon" and Chan takes a very different path, one more based around physical comedy like a violent Buster Keaton. This was Chan's Hollywood debut and, frankly, it shows - there is some shockingly bad dubbing, the plot is really quite stupid and the acting is... yeah, well. Anyway, this is one of those films that you simply have to hang up your expectations and just enjoy. It reminded me, in an odd way, of "Smokey And The Bandit" - it's hardly a classic but in spite of its many flaws, there is a sense of infectious fun behind it. Chan plays Keung who visits his uncle in New York (Bill Tung) just as he marries and leaves Keung to manage his Chinese market. After concluding the sale of the market to the bookish Elaine (Anita Mui), Keung incurs the wrath of a biker gang led by Tony (Marc Akerstream) who trash the place and leave Keung bloodied and beat up in an alley. But while Keung tries to fight back, he befriends wheelchair-bound boy next door (Morgan Lam) and his sister Nancy (Fran&ccedil;oise Yip) - who is affiliated with the gang. And to make matters worse, the local mob have been responsible for a daring diamond heist and after a mix-up with another biker (Garvin Cross), Keung finds himself pursued by both the bikers and the mobsters. Like I said, the plot is as old-school as the fashions visible in the nightclub scene. Like another early Chan outing (namely, "Mr Nice Guy"), there are certain things you notice like how every female character in both movies find Chan irresistible or how a simple misunderstanding can get Chan into heaps of trouble. There are other things as well - neither films have gripping stories or even much in the way of cohesion. The dub doesn't help "Rumble In The Bronx", reducing each scene to its component dialogue and physical comedy and build-up to the real reason you watch this film - the action scenes. Chan excels as the physical stuff, leaping across the screen like a kung-fu kicking Daffy Duck and a lot of the gimmicky really works like the scene in the supermarket where Chan uses seemingly every prop in the vicinity. "Rumble In The Bronx" is less of a film and more of a celluloid resume for its star, allowing Chan to demonstrate his extraordinary ability to fling himself into every bad guy in the blink of an eye. I fully understand why Chan might choose this otherwise utterly forgettable film to break into bigger movies - it doesn't let things like a plot get in the way of Chan doing what he does best as well as showing off his comic timing which, whilst not brilliant, at least offers something more than a grimacing hero endlessly bashing the baddies until the credits roll. In most other martial-arts films, the end climax involves the lead baddie use a variety of weapons which will cause the hero to bleed but not enough to prevent good triumphing over evil. In this film, the climax is so ridiculous that even my wife burst out laughing. If you can drop your serious face and revel in the goofiness of it then this might entertain you as much as it did me. Just don't take it seriously because if anything, this is probably the least serious film I've seen all year.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    someone stole my cushion!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jcallows
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/7/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie is about a boy and his quest for a new cushion. Watch it for its creative fight scenes and for that girl who plays the boy's sister. Watch it also to laugh at the atrocious acting and dialog. Other than that, there's really no reason to watch. This film is basically a bunch of action sequences strung together with some dialog in between. The dialog can be summed up as "where are the diamonds?", "give me the diamonds!" and, of course, "someone stole my cushion!" But the action is where this film excels. As is the custom in all Jackie Chan films, this film is loaded with creative martial arts fighting and spectacular stunts. This film is definitely fun to watch. But it's kind of like watching porn. You will be tempted to fast forward through all the dialog to get to the good parts.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Awesome
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tigerstar154
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/6/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Rumble in the bronx I heard a lot about this movie and how it launched Jackie Chan's career in the west. i saw this and it was awesome despite the fact it was a typical 90s movie. Jackie Chan visits his uncle in NY and becomes involved with a motorcycle gang. The pluses: Jackie Chan and his action work, and the the girl who plays Nancy. The Minuses: Weird acting by white actors, kid was annoying, corny at times and melodramatic. Overall, Rumble in the bronx is great and funny at time. 8/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    my favourite jackie chan movie, a blast from start to finish
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    daworldismine
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/5/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    rumble in the bronx is one of my favourite movies of alltime, and my favourite jackie chan movie, no im not saying its his best, im saying its my favourite, to me it has some of his best fight scenes and stunts of the 90's, and the movie made him a world wide star whats not to love, and plus the movie is very funny, easily one of his funniest movies. the first jackie chan movie i ever taped off TV, and the one I've seen the most, to me rumble in the bronx is the best action movie of the 90's, perfect action, perfect comedy, perfect movie. jackie chan rarely fails to deliver, and this is one of his best movies, and i recommend it to anybody who wants to see some awesome action
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Jackie Chan in America
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ebiros2
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/11/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is one of the movies Jackie Chan made targeted for audience outside of Asia. The story takes place in New York with many American actors in the supporting role. To me this wasn't one of his best production, but there's one scene that blows me away every time I see it. This is the scene where Jackie takes a leap from the roof of one building into a balcony of the adjacent building. I don't think there was any wire attached to Jackie, so if he missed, he could have been dead, and he could have missed very easily. Some of the scenes look staged and isn't the natural Jackie Chan type scenes that I'm used to. Maybe the crew wasn't used to the American style production. It's really strange to discover that Jackie Chan movie looks below par compared to his own when it's way above average compared to other American action movie of this type. I also didn't like the senseless violence, but if wasn't so violent, maybe it wouldn't look like authentic America. Whatever the reason, they might have done it better. It's still a Jackie Chan movie, and you'll get that special dose of Jackie Chan action with this movie. If you're a Jackie Chan fan, it's sure to please you.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Chan at his Comical, Lightning-Quick Best
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Sean Lamberger
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/7/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Jackie Chan's first major American breakthrough remains his most energetic, entertaining spectacle. The film's storyline is a joke, with supposedly hardcore Bronx motorcycle gangs coming off like characters in a Saturday morning cartoon, but that's clearly not the point. The plot's only there to fill the space between fight scenes with a few randomly connected antagonizing situations, and in many instances its complete lack of any connection with reality is actually quite charming. The real focus, naturally, is on Chan's inventive use of his surroundings and blistering hand speed during his frequent clashes with gaudily-dressed bikers and, later on, suit-and-sunglasses adorned g-men. Regardless of locale, Jackie is somehow able to find an unsuspecting prop, then quickly put it to use in bludgeoning somewhere in the range of a dozen different combatants in wildly original ways, keeping audiences surprised and indulged. A kindergarten-grade story won't win this rumble any awards, but as a vehicle for its star's own inimitable style of celluloid-friendly martial arts it's perfect.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Streets of San Bronx
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    thesar-2
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/9/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I'd guess you'd have to call 'Rumble in the Bronx' an extreme example of a guilty pleasure. Though back in the 1990s, it was not my first introduction to Jackie Chan (the inferior 'Supercop' was) it was the one that got me hooked on his work. All the way through this viewing  the first in many years, the word "silly" kept popping up in my mind. It's dialogue, acting, stereotypes and shoddy cop work was so hilariously bad, I could only think this had to be written by someone who's only contact with the U.S.A. involves watching old 1970s cop hour-long dramas. And while some scenes were actually funny (SEE: the wrench threat) some were downright unintentionally funny (SEE: the toddler-toss and the entire closing on the golf course.) Leaving all that negative behind, it was an extreme joy watching Chan perform his own stunts in many, many inventive ways while simultaneously creating a very human and good-hearted character. The stunts were simply amazing and if one were to watch today for the first time, they need to know: he did them all himself, without a green screens, cables, etc. As arrogant as Chan is  I've read his biography, it's dripping with arrogance, he does have great gifts in originality, showmanship, pride in his work and making sure he never uses traditional American trickery/stunts. (This changes later in his work, when he was forced and got older, but this work and ones around it were all pure Chan.) Synopsis: Good-natured nephew Chan visits NYC and gets thrown in extraordinary circumstances: fighting both gangs and mob bosses while helping 2 women, his Uncle and a handicapped child. All that's irrelevant; what matters is once the action starts, it never lets up. And with an open-mind, what a fun rumble you'll have. Side Note: Wow.. not only was it painful for all the actors to get hurt during production (not to mention the roughly 16 dozen vehicles) it was also gut wrenching to watch the closing credits that showed mostly the unintentional crashes, broken bones, etc. You really have to hand it to the devotion of the crew, cast and Chan. Definitely Chan. My comments about his arrogance does not mean I don't admire the man, especially his extremely poor and underprivileged beginnings to the entertainer he became. He's one of the very few actors/action stars that no matter how incredibly silly his movies look to me  it has to be a culture thing, it's always a rush to see how long his fight scenes last, how inventive he becomes and simply how exciting they are.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Jackie cracks the west
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ed_two_o_nine
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/2/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Well here we go once again with the undisputed king of action comedy. The one and only Jackie Chan. While this is nowhere near Chan's best movie we can be grateful for the fact that this is the film that finally gave Chan his much deserved break in the USA. This is the story on Chan's character Keung who comes to the Bronx for his uncle's wedding and ends up caught up in a series of events that involve biker gangs, and diamond robbers. But really none of this matters this is just an excuse for Jackie to show of his amazing action skills (in the fight scenes which he also choreographed), and this he does to his usual amazing standards. There seems to be more edits in the fight scenes that is normal for Jackie but I suspect this might be down to one of two things. One making the film more palatable for a western audience. Or two that Jackie broke his ankle in the filming of this movie. Still tell me the last time you saw a western movie star leap from a roof on to the fire escape of the next building!!! Truly amazing stuff. On the down side the western characters and acting are very wooden but hey just enjoy Chan and hopefully then go seek out his Hong Kong movies.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Could The Road To The Dream Be More Enjoyable Than Fulfilling It ?!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ahmed elshikh (ahmed_abd_elreheem@yahoo.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/8/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is one of the best movies by (Jackie Chan), maybe more fun than the majority of his previous Asian ones and the other later American ones too. Here the action is so ambitious, the rhythm is hot, the production is big, the technique is above mediocre, and the heroine is sexier ! I think the first half was so good and catchy; however the second half about the diamonds was another movie ! I enjoyed the story of the first plot, and the huge Action of the second one. The matter of having 2 girls had never been used correctly, there was no use out of putting some love scenes for (Chan) and the market's owner, in the same time that he fell in love with the street girl simply and terminally !, so why the first storyline from the start?? Then look at the street gang, why all of this hatred for (Jackie)? They looked like another brainless pure evil comes from another previous movies like (The Enforcer), (Robocop), and (Police Academy). I hated also the matter of the nonexistent anticlimax, it's maybe a habit at (Chan)'s movies to watch the climax then PAAM the closing credits with the bloopers !!, here it was so provoking as we didn't know exactly what happened after, like they had no time to shoot more ! Sometimes it's a terrible habit as it makes the whole condition so deficient, especially the viewer's satisfaction. It's clear that (Chan) was determined to be a star in America, it was his dream, and it would never happen until 4 years after with (Rush Hour) which's not one of my favorites where Chan undoubtedly is less shining, maybe it succeeded because it was the right formula or the right time I don't know. But here like every Chan's movie the Action, as usual, exceeded everything. And the story, as ever, is just a superficial cover for fun with no possible deepness. It was enough for (Chan) and all of his team to assure how courageous, stubborn, and romantic the Asian is; in the same time that the American is so violent, criminal, and deranged whether poor or rich. Despite the balance that they made (kind American policemen, and one evil Asian in the street gang). On so many levels it proves how the Asian cinematic hero became better and his adventures became bigger since another very well known Asian-in-western-evil-world and I mean (Bruce Lee) at (Way of the Dragon) nearly 25 years earlier, to invade America itself (it was Italy in the first one), and to present Mad Mad world comic Action also through this maniac hero who, at the time, needed no stunts or wires ! So ultimately (Rumble in the Bronx - 1996) is nice strong action, where (Jackie) is in classical example for being a real icon, original star, and great clown. Makes you wonder a bit about what he lost, after fulfilling his dream, in next American movies.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Funny and spectacular Jackie Chan movie in his first American super hit with highlights provided by a hovercraft
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ma-cortes
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Amusing and entertaining Chan film in which he demonstrates his sensational skills as a great action man . It deals with a young man named Keong (Jackie Chan) visiting and helping his uncle in New York City finds himself forced to fight a street gang and the mob with his martial art abilities . His uncle has a local Chinese supermarket, which he owns and is in the process of selling to Elaine (Anita Mui). Later on , Keong befriends a neighbor kid and his sister (Francois Yip) and beats up some neighborhood thugs . Hong Kong/US/Canada action comedy full of over-the-top struggles , excitement , thrills , ingenious stunts , slapstick , lots of brawls but with abundant humor and tongue-in-cheek . This fun movie is plenty of intrigue , unstopped action , and overwhelming stunt-work with breathtaking ending images including a hovercraft . Jackie Chan is top notch as one army man fighting a group of heinous villains and as always he makes his own stunts like is well showed at the final credits . Awesome , incredible stunts and brief comic touches , as usual ; the picture is better constructed than Chan's predecessors films . The lighting-paced storyline slows down at times , but frantic action sequences make up for it . Spotlights movie include spectacular fights , including bounds and leaps , impressive and interminable struggles , an impressive final struggle between Jackie Chan and enemies . The warehouse fight scene took twenty days to film, with Chan having to teach the local stunt players to fight "Hong Kong style". In addition other fine action sequences in overwhelming and extraordinary style . The script called for a leap from the top of a parking lot to a fire escape on the floor below on the building across the street , as is his custom, director Stanley Tong attempted the stunt before asking any actors to do so. He tried it with the help of a cable harness, but quickly decided it would be safer without the harness. The landing point was not visible from the point where the jump began, so tape was placed on the take-off point as a guide ,the jump was completed perfectly by 'Chan, Jackie' on the first attempt, doing his own stunts as is his custom . The jump was captured by four cameras. This is an acceptable action movie distinguished by nicely cinematography of the spectacular sequences , and contains agreeable sense of humor as well as previous entries . Jackie Chan usually forms couple to notorious actresses as Maggie Chung and Michelle Yeoh . In this outing Jackie teams up to gorgeous Francoise Yip (who broke her leg while filming the scene where she rides a motorbike across the tops of parked cars , she insisted on returning to the set after her leg was plastered at hospital) and prestigious Chinese actress Anita Mui , a fine action star in their own right but sadly she early died by cancer . Both of them starred together several films such as &uml;Mr Canton and Lady Rose&uml; and &uml;Legend of the drunken master&uml; . Filming in Vancouver, Canada on October 6th, 1994, Chan broke his right ankle while attempting the scene where he jumps onto the hovercraft. Despite the injury, he was present at the premiere of &uml;The legend of the drunken fighter&uml; at the Vancouver International Film Festival that night. Later in the production, Tong sprained his ankle, completing the film on crutches . Two stunt women also broke their legs during the filming of the motorcycle chase. The picture achieved big success in China , USA and all around the world . However , Jackie Chan's failed at Box-office in his American debut ,&uml;Battle creek brawl&uml; . Chan is a hard-working actor and director throughout his long and varied career . Chan usually pays overt homage to two of his greatest influences as Charles Chaplin and Harold Lloyd . He went on playing &uml;Cannoball&uml; , &uml;The protector&uml; and "Rumble in the Bronx", until getting all American success with &uml;Shangai Knights&uml; , &uml;The tuxedo&uml; , &uml;Around the world in 80 days&uml; and &uml;Rush hour&uml; trilogy , and the recent &uml;Karate kid&uml;. Of course , his biggest hits were &uml;The Police story&uml; series that won the Golden Horse Award, a Chinese version of the Oscar , the first was titled &uml;Police story (1985)&uml; directed by the same Chan , it was a perfect action film for enthusiastic of the genre ; the following was &uml;Police story 2 (1988)&uml; also pretty violent and with abundant humor touches . It's followed by &uml;Supercop&uml; or &uml;Police story 3&uml; and finally , &uml;Police story IV : Crime story&uml; . The picture is well produced by the great Asian producer Raymond Chow and Golden Harvest production and compellingly directed by Stanley Tong and helped by Jackie Chan . Rating : Acceptable and passable , the picture has its sensational moments here and there , but also with abundant humor touches mostly provided by its agile star , the super Jackie stunningly accompanied by Anita Mui and Francois Yip . It's a perfect action film for enthusiasts of the genre and especially for Jackie fans .
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Chan fighting and goofing but that's it - 69%
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Benjamin Cox
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/9/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    For many years, Jackie Chan had been working away in his little niche as the best dammed martial-arts comedy star in the business. But martial arts movies have been never mainstream since Bruce Lee roared into immortality in "Enter The Dragon" and Chan takes a very different path, one more based around physical comedy like a violent Buster Keaton. This was Chan's Hollywood debut and, frankly, it shows - there is some shockingly bad dubbing, the plot is really quite stupid and the acting is... yeah, well. Anyway, this is one of those films that you simply have to hang up your expectations and just enjoy. It reminded me, in an odd way, of "Smokey And The Bandit" - it's hardly a classic but in spite of its many flaws, there is a sense of infectious fun behind it. Chan plays Keung who visits his uncle in New York (Bill Tung) just as he marries and leaves Keung to manage his Chinese market. After concluding the sale of the market to the bookish Elaine (Anita Mui), Keung incurs the wrath of a biker gang led by Tony (Marc Akerstream) who trash the place and leave Keung bloodied and beat up in an alley. But while Keung tries to fight back, he befriends wheelchair-bound boy next door (Morgan Lam) and his sister Nancy (Fran&ccedil;oise Yip) - who is affiliated with the gang. And to make matters worse, the local mob have been responsible for a daring diamond heist and after a mix-up with another biker (Garvin Cross), Keung finds himself pursued by both the bikers and the mobsters. Like I said, the plot is as old-school as the fashions visible in the nightclub scene. Like another early Chan outing (namely, "Mr Nice Guy"), there are certain things you notice like how every female character in both movies find Chan irresistible or how a simple misunderstanding can get Chan into heaps of trouble. There are other things as well - neither films have gripping stories or even much in the way of cohesion. The dub doesn't help "Rumble In The Bronx", reducing each scene to its component dialogue and physical comedy and build-up to the real reason you watch this film - the action scenes. Chan excels as the physical stuff, leaping across the screen like a kung-fu kicking Daffy Duck and a lot of the gimmicky really works like the scene in the supermarket where Chan uses seemingly every prop in the vicinity. "Rumble In The Bronx" is less of a film and more of a celluloid resume for its star, allowing Chan to demonstrate his extraordinary ability to fling himself into every bad guy in the blink of an eye. I fully understand why Chan might choose this otherwise utterly forgettable film to break into bigger movies - it doesn't let things like a plot get in the way of Chan doing what he does best as well as showing off his comic timing which, whilst not brilliant, at least offers something more than a grimacing hero endlessly bashing the baddies until the credits roll. In most other martial-arts films, the end climax involves the lead baddie use a variety of weapons which will cause the hero to bleed but not enough to prevent good triumphing over evil. In this film, the climax is so ridiculous that even my wife burst out laughing. If you can drop your serious face and revel in the goofiness of it then this might entertain you as much as it did me. Just don't take it seriously because if anything, this is probably the least serious film I've seen all year.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    someone stole my cushion!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jcallows
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/7/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie is about a boy and his quest for a new cushion. Watch it for its creative fight scenes and for that girl who plays the boy's sister. Watch it also to laugh at the atrocious acting and dialog. Other than that, there's really no reason to watch. This film is basically a bunch of action sequences strung together with some dialog in between. The dialog can be summed up as "where are the diamonds?", "give me the diamonds!" and, of course, "someone stole my cushion!" But the action is where this film excels. As is the custom in all Jackie Chan films, this film is loaded with creative martial arts fighting and spectacular stunts. This film is definitely fun to watch. But it's kind of like watching porn. You will be tempted to fast forward through all the dialog to get to the good parts.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Awesome
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tigerstar154
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/6/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Rumble in the bronx I heard a lot about this movie and how it launched Jackie Chan's career in the west. i saw this and it was awesome despite the fact it was a typical 90s movie. Jackie Chan visits his uncle in NY and becomes involved with a motorcycle gang. The pluses: Jackie Chan and his action work, and the the girl who plays Nancy. The Minuses: Weird acting by white actors, kid was annoying, corny at times and melodramatic. Overall, Rumble in the bronx is great and funny at time. 8/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    my favourite jackie chan movie, a blast from start to finish
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    daworldismine
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/5/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    rumble in the bronx is one of my favourite movies of alltime, and my favourite jackie chan movie, no im not saying its his best, im saying its my favourite, to me it has some of his best fight scenes and stunts of the 90's, and the movie made him a world wide star whats not to love, and plus the movie is very funny, easily one of his funniest movies. the first jackie chan movie i ever taped off TV, and the one I've seen the most, to me rumble in the bronx is the best action movie of the 90's, perfect action, perfect comedy, perfect movie. jackie chan rarely fails to deliver, and this is one of his best movies, and i recommend it to anybody who wants to see some awesome action
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Jackie Chan in America
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ebiros2
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/11/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is one of the movies Jackie Chan made targeted for audience outside of Asia. The story takes place in New York with many American actors in the supporting role. To me this wasn't one of his best production, but there's one scene that blows me away every time I see it. This is the scene where Jackie takes a leap from the roof of one building into a balcony of the adjacent building. I don't think there was any wire attached to Jackie, so if he missed, he could have been dead, and he could have missed very easily. Some of the scenes look staged and isn't the natural Jackie Chan type scenes that I'm used to. Maybe the crew wasn't used to the American style production. It's really strange to discover that Jackie Chan movie looks below par compared to his own when it's way above average compared to other American action movie of this type. I also didn't like the senseless violence, but if wasn't so violent, maybe it wouldn't look like authentic America. Whatever the reason, they might have done it better. It's still a Jackie Chan movie, and you'll get that special dose of Jackie Chan action with this movie. If you're a Jackie Chan fan, it's sure to please you.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Chan at his Comical, Lightning-Quick Best
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Sean Lamberger
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/7/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Jackie Chan's first major American breakthrough remains his most energetic, entertaining spectacle. The film's storyline is a joke, with supposedly hardcore Bronx motorcycle gangs coming off like characters in a Saturday morning cartoon, but that's clearly not the point. The plot's only there to fill the space between fight scenes with a few randomly connected antagonizing situations, and in many instances its complete lack of any connection with reality is actually quite charming. The real focus, naturally, is on Chan's inventive use of his surroundings and blistering hand speed during his frequent clashes with gaudily-dressed bikers and, later on, suit-and-sunglasses adorned g-men. Regardless of locale, Jackie is somehow able to find an unsuspecting prop, then quickly put it to use in bludgeoning somewhere in the range of a dozen different combatants in wildly original ways, keeping audiences surprised and indulged. A kindergarten-grade story won't win this rumble any awards, but as a vehicle for its star's own inimitable style of celluloid-friendly martial arts it's perfect.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Streets of San Bronx
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    thesar-2
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/9/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I'd guess you'd have to call 'Rumble in the Bronx' an extreme example of a guilty pleasure. Though back in the 1990s, it was not my first introduction to Jackie Chan (the inferior 'Supercop' was) it was the one that got me hooked on his work. All the way through this viewing  the first in many years, the word "silly" kept popping up in my mind. It's dialogue, acting, stereotypes and shoddy cop work was so hilariously bad, I could only think this had to be written by someone who's only contact with the U.S.A. involves watching old 1970s cop hour-long dramas. And while some scenes were actually funny (SEE: the wrench threat) some were downright unintentionally funny (SEE: the toddler-toss and the entire closing on the golf course.) Leaving all that negative behind, it was an extreme joy watching Chan perform his own stunts in many, many inventive ways while simultaneously creating a very human and good-hearted character. The stunts were simply amazing and if one were to watch today for the first time, they need to know: he did them all himself, without a green screens, cables, etc. As arrogant as Chan is  I've read his biography, it's dripping with arrogance, he does have great gifts in originality, showmanship, pride in his work and making sure he never uses traditional American trickery/stunts. (This changes later in his work, when he was forced and got older, but this work and ones around it were all pure Chan.) Synopsis: Good-natured nephew Chan visits NYC and gets thrown in extraordinary circumstances: fighting both gangs and mob bosses while helping 2 women, his Uncle and a handicapped child. All that's irrelevant; what matters is once the action starts, it never lets up. And with an open-mind, what a fun rumble you'll have. Side Note: Wow.. not only was it painful for all the actors to get hurt during production (not to mention the roughly 16 dozen vehicles) it was also gut wrenching to watch the closing credits that showed mostly the unintentional crashes, broken bones, etc. You really have to hand it to the devotion of the crew, cast and Chan. Definitely Chan. My comments about his arrogance does not mean I don't admire the man, especially his extremely poor and underprivileged beginnings to the entertainer he became. He's one of the very few actors/action stars that no matter how incredibly silly his movies look to me  it has to be a culture thing, it's always a rush to see how long his fight scenes last, how inventive he becomes and simply how exciting they are.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Jackie cracks the west
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ed_two_o_nine
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/2/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Well here we go once again with the undisputed king of action comedy. The one and only Jackie Chan. While this is nowhere near Chan's best movie we can be grateful for the fact that this is the film that finally gave Chan his much deserved break in the USA. This is the story on Chan's character Keung who comes to the Bronx for his uncle's wedding and ends up caught up in a series of events that involve biker gangs, and diamond robbers. But really none of this matters this is just an excuse for Jackie to show of his amazing action skills (in the fight scenes which he also choreographed), and this he does to his usual amazing standards. There seems to be more edits in the fight scenes that is normal for Jackie but I suspect this might be down to one of two things. One making the film more palatable for a western audience. Or two that Jackie broke his ankle in the filming of this movie. Still tell me the last time you saw a western movie star leap from a roof on to the fire escape of the next building!!! Truly amazing stuff. On the down side the western characters and acting are very wooden but hey just enjoy Chan and hopefully then go seek out his Hong Kong movies.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Could The Road To The Dream Be More Enjoyable Than Fulfilling It ?!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ahmed elshikh (ahmed_abd_elreheem@yahoo.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/8/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is one of the best movies by (Jackie Chan), maybe more fun than the majority of his previous Asian ones and the other later American ones too. Here the action is so ambitious, the rhythm is hot, the production is big, the technique is above mediocre, and the heroine is sexier ! I think the first half was so good and catchy; however the second half about the diamonds was another movie ! I enjoyed the story of the first plot, and the huge Action of the second one. The matter of having 2 girls had never been used correctly, there was no use out of putting some love scenes for (Chan) and the market's owner, in the same time that he fell in love with the street girl simply and terminally !, so why the first storyline from the start?? Then look at the street gang, why all of this hatred for (Jackie)? They looked like another brainless pure evil comes from another previous movies like (The Enforcer), (Robocop), and (Police Academy). I hated also the matter of the nonexistent anticlimax, it's maybe a habit at (Chan)'s movies to watch the climax then PAAM the closing credits with the bloopers !!, here it was so provoking as we didn't know exactly what happened after, like they had no time to shoot more ! Sometimes it's a terrible habit as it makes the whole condition so deficient, especially the viewer's satisfaction. It's clear that (Chan) was determined to be a star in America, it was his dream, and it would never happen until 4 years after with (Rush Hour) which's not one of my favorites where Chan undoubtedly is less shining, maybe it succeeded because it was the right formula or the right time I don't know. But here like every Chan's movie the Action, as usual, exceeded everything. And the story, as ever, is just a superficial cover for fun with no possible deepness. It was enough for (Chan) and all of his team to assure how courageous, stubborn, and romantic the Asian is; in the same time that the American is so violent, criminal, and deranged whether poor or rich. Despite the balance that they made (kind American policemen, and one evil Asian in the street gang). On so many levels it proves how the Asian cinematic hero became better and his adventures became bigger since another very well known Asian-in-western-evil-world and I mean (Bruce Lee) at (Way of the Dragon) nearly 25 years earlier, to invade America itself (it was Italy in the first one), and to present Mad Mad world comic Action also through this maniac hero who, at the time, needed no stunts or wires ! So ultimately (Rumble in the Bronx - 1996) is nice strong action, where (Jackie) is in classical example for being a real icon, original star, and great clown. Makes you wonder a bit about what he lost, after fulfilling his dream, in next American movies.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Funny and spectacular Jackie Chan movie in his first American super hit with highlights provided by a hovercraft
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ma-cortes
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Amusing and entertaining Chan film in which he demonstrates his sensational skills as a great action man . It deals with a young man named Keong (Jackie Chan) visiting and helping his uncle in New York City finds himself forced to fight a street gang and the mob with his martial art abilities . His uncle has a local Chinese supermarket, which he owns and is in the process of selling to Elaine (Anita Mui). Later on , Keong befriends a neighbor kid and his sister (Francois Yip) and beats up some neighborhood thugs . Hong Kong/US/Canada action comedy full of over-the-top struggles , excitement , thrills , ingenious stunts , slapstick , lots of brawls but with abundant humor and tongue-in-cheek . This fun movie is plenty of intrigue , unstopped action , and overwhelming stunt-work with breathtaking ending images including a hovercraft . Jackie Chan is top notch as one army man fighting a group of heinous villains and as always he makes his own stunts like is well showed at the final credits . Awesome , incredible stunts and brief comic touches , as usual ; the picture is better constructed than Chan's predecessors films . The lighting-paced storyline slows down at times , but frantic action sequences make up for it . Spotlights movie include spectacular fights , including bounds and leaps , impressive and interminable struggles , an impressive final struggle between Jackie Chan and enemies . The warehouse fight scene took twenty days to film, with Chan having to teach the local stunt players to fight "Hong Kong style". In addition other fine action sequences in overwhelming and extraordinary style . The script called for a leap from the top of a parking lot to a fire escape on the floor below on the building across the street , as is his custom, director Stanley Tong attempted the stunt before asking any actors to do so. He tried it with the help of a cable harness, but quickly decided it would be safer without the harness. The landing point was not visible from the point where the jump began, so tape was placed on the take-off point as a guide ,the jump was completed perfectly by 'Chan, Jackie' on the first attempt, doing his own stunts as is his custom . The jump was captured by four cameras. This is an acceptable action movie distinguished by nicely cinematography of the spectacular sequences , and contains agreeable sense of humor as well as previous entries . Jackie Chan usually forms couple to notorious actresses as Maggie Chung and Michelle Yeoh . In this outing Jackie teams up to gorgeous Francoise Yip (who broke her leg while filming the scene where she rides a motorbike across the tops of parked cars , she insisted on returning to the set after her leg was plastered at hospital) and prestigious Chinese actress Anita Mui , a fine action star in their own right but sadly she early died by cancer . Both of them starred together several films such as &uml;Mr Canton and Lady Rose&uml; and &uml;Legend of the drunken master&uml; . Filming in Vancouver, Canada on October 6th, 1994, Chan broke his right ankle while attempting the scene where he jumps onto the hovercraft. Despite the injury, he was present at the premiere of &uml;The legend of the drunken fighter&uml; at the Vancouver International Film Festival that night. Later in the production, Tong sprained his ankle, completing the film on crutches . Two stunt women also broke their legs during the filming of the motorcycle chase. The picture achieved big success in China , USA and all around the world . However , Jackie Chan's failed at Box-office in his American debut ,&uml;Battle creek brawl&uml; . Chan is a hard-working actor and director throughout his long and varied career . Chan usually pays overt homage to two of his greatest influences as Charles Chaplin and Harold Lloyd . He went on playing &uml;Cannoball&uml; , &uml;The protector&uml; and "Rumble in the Bronx", until getting all American success with &uml;Shangai Knights&uml; , &uml;The tuxedo&uml; , &uml;Around the world in 80 days&uml; and &uml;Rush hour&uml; trilogy , and the recent &uml;Karate kid&uml;. Of course , his biggest hits were &uml;The Police story&uml; series that won the Golden Horse Award, a Chinese version of the Oscar , the first was titled &uml;Police story (1985)&uml; directed by the same Chan , it was a perfect action film for enthusiastic of the genre ; the following was &uml;Police story 2 (1988)&uml; also pretty violent and with abundant humor touches . It's followed by &uml;Supercop&uml; or &uml;Police story 3&uml; and finally , &uml;Police story IV : Crime story&uml; . The picture is well produced by the great Asian producer Raymond Chow and Golden Harvest production and compellingly directed by Stanley Tong and helped by Jackie Chan . Rating : Acceptable and passable , the picture has its sensational moments here and there , but also with abundant humor touches mostly provided by its agile star , the super Jackie stunningly accompanied by Anita Mui and Francois Yip . It's a perfect action film for enthusiasts of the genre and especially for Jackie fans .
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Chan fighting and goofing but that's it - 69%
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Benjamin Cox
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/9/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    For many years, Jackie Chan had been working away in his little niche as the best dammed martial-arts comedy star in the business. But martial arts movies have been never mainstream since Bruce Lee roared into immortality in "Enter The Dragon" and Chan takes a very different path, one more based around physical comedy like a violent Buster Keaton. This was Chan's Hollywood debut and, frankly, it shows - there is some shockingly bad dubbing, the plot is really quite stupid and the acting is... yeah, well. Anyway, this is one of those films that you simply have to hang up your expectations and just enjoy. It reminded me, in an odd way, of "Smokey And The Bandit" - it's hardly a classic but in spite of its many flaws, there is a sense of infectious fun behind it. Chan plays Keung who visits his uncle in New York (Bill Tung) just as he marries and leaves Keung to manage his Chinese market. After concluding the sale of the market to the bookish Elaine (Anita Mui), Keung incurs the wrath of a biker gang led by Tony (Marc Akerstream) who trash the place and leave Keung bloodied and beat up in an alley. But while Keung tries to fight back, he befriends wheelchair-bound boy next door (Morgan Lam) and his sister Nancy (Fran&ccedil;oise Yip) - who is affiliated with the gang. And to make matters worse, the local mob have been responsible for a daring diamond heist and after a mix-up with another biker (Garvin Cross), Keung finds himself pursued by both the bikers and the mobsters. Like I said, the plot is as old-school as the fashions visible in the nightclub scene. Like another early Chan outing (namely, "Mr Nice Guy"), there are certain things you notice like how every female character in both movies find Chan irresistible or how a simple misunderstanding can get Chan into heaps of trouble. There are other things as well - neither films have gripping stories or even much in the way of cohesion. The dub doesn't help "Rumble In The Bronx", reducing each scene to its component dialogue and physical comedy and build-up to the real reason you watch this film - the action scenes. Chan excels as the physical stuff, leaping across the screen like a kung-fu kicking Daffy Duck and a lot of the gimmicky really works like the scene in the supermarket where Chan uses seemingly every prop in the vicinity. "Rumble In The Bronx" is less of a film and more of a celluloid resume for its star, allowing Chan to demonstrate his extraordinary ability to fling himself into every bad guy in the blink of an eye. I fully understand why Chan might choose this otherwise utterly forgettable film to break into bigger movies - it doesn't let things like a plot get in the way of Chan doing what he does best as well as showing off his comic timing which, whilst not brilliant, at least offers something more than a grimacing hero endlessly bashing the baddies until the credits roll. In most other martial-arts films, the end climax involves the lead baddie use a variety of weapons which will cause the hero to bleed but not enough to prevent good triumphing over evil. In this film, the climax is so ridiculous that even my wife burst out laughing. If you can drop your serious face and revel in the goofiness of it then this might entertain you as much as it did me. Just don't take it seriously because if anything, this is probably the least serious film I've seen all year.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    someone stole my cushion!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jcallows
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/7/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie is about a boy and his quest for a new cushion. Watch it for its creative fight scenes and for that girl who plays the boy's sister. Watch it also to laugh at the atrocious acting and dialog. Other than that, there's really no reason to watch. This film is basically a bunch of action sequences strung together with some dialog in between. The dialog can be summed up as "where are the diamonds?", "give me the diamonds!" and, of course, "someone stole my cushion!" But the action is where this film excels. As is the custom in all Jackie Chan films, this film is loaded with creative martial arts fighting and spectacular stunts. This film is definitely fun to watch. But it's kind of like watching porn. You will be tempted to fast forward through all the dialog to get to the good parts.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Awesome
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tigerstar154
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/6/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Rumble in the bronx I heard a lot about this movie and how it launched Jackie Chan's career in the west. i saw this and it was awesome despite the fact it was a typical 90s movie. Jackie Chan visits his uncle in NY and becomes involved with a motorcycle gang. The pluses: Jackie Chan and his action work, and the the girl who plays Nancy. The Minuses: Weird acting by white actors, kid was annoying, corny at times and melodramatic. Overall, Rumble in the bronx is great and funny at time. 8/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    my favourite jackie chan movie, a blast from start to finish
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    daworldismine
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/5/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    rumble in the bronx is one of my favourite movies of alltime, and my favourite jackie chan movie, no im not saying its his best, im saying its my favourite, to me it has some of his best fight scenes and stunts of the 90's, and the movie made him a world wide star whats not to love, and plus the movie is very funny, easily one of his funniest movies. the first jackie chan movie i ever taped off TV, and the one I've seen the most, to me rumble in the bronx is the best action movie of the 90's, perfect action, perfect comedy, perfect movie. jackie chan rarely fails to deliver, and this is one of his best movies, and i recommend it to anybody who wants to see some awesome action
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Jackie Chan in America
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ebiros2
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/11/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is one of the movies Jackie Chan made targeted for audience outside of Asia. The story takes place in New York with many American actors in the supporting role. To me this wasn't one of his best production, but there's one scene that blows me away every time I see it. This is the scene where Jackie takes a leap from the roof of one building into a balcony of the adjacent building. I don't think there was any wire attached to Jackie, so if he missed, he could have been dead, and he could have missed very easily. Some of the scenes look staged and isn't the natural Jackie Chan type scenes that I'm used to. Maybe the crew wasn't used to the American style production. It's really strange to discover that Jackie Chan movie looks below par compared to his own when it's way above average compared to other American action movie of this type. I also didn't like the senseless violence, but if wasn't so violent, maybe it wouldn't look like authentic America. Whatever the reason, they might have done it better. It's still a Jackie Chan movie, and you'll get that special dose of Jackie Chan action with this movie. If you're a Jackie Chan fan, it's sure to please you.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Chan at his Comical, Lightning-Quick Best
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Sean Lamberger
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/7/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Jackie Chan's first major American breakthrough remains his most energetic, entertaining spectacle. The film's storyline is a joke, with supposedly hardcore Bronx motorcycle gangs coming off like characters in a Saturday morning cartoon, but that's clearly not the point. The plot's only there to fill the space between fight scenes with a few randomly connected antagonizing situations, and in many instances its complete lack of any connection with reality is actually quite charming. The real focus, naturally, is on Chan's inventive use of his surroundings and blistering hand speed during his frequent clashes with gaudily-dressed bikers and, later on, suit-and-sunglasses adorned g-men. Regardless of locale, Jackie is somehow able to find an unsuspecting prop, then quickly put it to use in bludgeoning somewhere in the range of a dozen different combatants in wildly original ways, keeping audiences surprised and indulged. A kindergarten-grade story won't win this rumble any awards, but as a vehicle for its star's own inimitable style of celluloid-friendly martial arts it's perfect.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Streets of San Bronx
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    thesar-2
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/9/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I'd guess you'd have to call 'Rumble in the Bronx' an extreme example of a guilty pleasure. Though back in the 1990s, it was not my first introduction to Jackie Chan (the inferior 'Supercop' was) it was the one that got me hooked on his work. All the way through this viewing  the first in many years, the word "silly" kept popping up in my mind. It's dialogue, acting, stereotypes and shoddy cop work was so hilariously bad, I could only think this had to be written by someone who's only contact with the U.S.A. involves watching old 1970s cop hour-long dramas. And while some scenes were actually funny (SEE: the wrench threat) some were downright unintentionally funny (SEE: the toddler-toss and the entire closing on the golf course.) Leaving all that negative behind, it was an extreme joy watching Chan perform his own stunts in many, many inventive ways while simultaneously creating a very human and good-hearted character. The stunts were simply amazing and if one were to watch today for the first time, they need to know: he did them all himself, without a green screens, cables, etc. As arrogant as Chan is  I've read his biography, it's dripping with arrogance, he does have great gifts in originality, showmanship, pride in his work and making sure he never uses traditional American trickery/stunts. (This changes later in his work, when he was forced and got older, but this work and ones around it were all pure Chan.) Synopsis: Good-natured nephew Chan visits NYC and gets thrown in extraordinary circumstances: fighting both gangs and mob bosses while helping 2 women, his Uncle and a handicapped child. All that's irrelevant; what matters is once the action starts, it never lets up. And with an open-mind, what a fun rumble you'll have. Side Note: Wow.. not only was it painful for all the actors to get hurt during production (not to mention the roughly 16 dozen vehicles) it was also gut wrenching to watch the closing credits that showed mostly the unintentional crashes, broken bones, etc. You really have to hand it to the devotion of the crew, cast and Chan. Definitely Chan. My comments about his arrogance does not mean I don't admire the man, especially his extremely poor and underprivileged beginnings to the entertainer he became. He's one of the very few actors/action stars that no matter how incredibly silly his movies look to me  it has to be a culture thing, it's always a rush to see how long his fight scenes last, how inventive he becomes and simply how exciting they are.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Jackie cracks the west
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ed_two_o_nine
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/2/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Well here we go once again with the undisputed king of action comedy. The one and only Jackie Chan. While this is nowhere near Chan's best movie we can be grateful for the fact that this is the film that finally gave Chan his much deserved break in the USA. This is the story on Chan's character Keung who comes to the Bronx for his uncle's wedding and ends up caught up in a series of events that involve biker gangs, and diamond robbers. But really none of this matters this is just an excuse for Jackie to show of his amazing action skills (in the fight scenes which he also choreographed), and this he does to his usual amazing standards. There seems to be more edits in the fight scenes that is normal for Jackie but I suspect this might be down to one of two things. One making the film more palatable for a western audience. Or two that Jackie broke his ankle in the filming of this movie. Still tell me the last time you saw a western movie star leap from a roof on to the fire escape of the next building!!! Truly amazing stuff. On the down side the western characters and acting are very wooden but hey just enjoy Chan and hopefully then go seek out his Hong Kong movies.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Could The Road To The Dream Be More Enjoyable Than Fulfilling It ?!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ahmed elshikh (ahmed_abd_elreheem@yahoo.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/8/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is one of the best movies by (Jackie Chan), maybe more fun than the majority of his previous Asian ones and the other later American ones too. Here the action is so ambitious, the rhythm is hot, the production is big, the technique is above mediocre, and the heroine is sexier ! I think the first half was so good and catchy; however the second half about the diamonds was another movie ! I enjoyed the story of the first plot, and the huge Action of the second one. The matter of having 2 girls had never been used correctly, there was no use out of putting some love scenes for (Chan) and the market's owner, in the same time that he fell in love with the street girl simply and terminally !, so why the first storyline from the start?? Then look at the street gang, why all of this hatred for (Jackie)? They looked like another brainless pure evil comes from another previous movies like (The Enforcer), (Robocop), and (Police Academy). I hated also the matter of the nonexistent anticlimax, it's maybe a habit at (Chan)'s movies to watch the climax then PAAM the closing credits with the bloopers !!, here it was so provoking as we didn't know exactly what happened after, like they had no time to shoot more ! Sometimes it's a terrible habit as it makes the whole condition so deficient, especially the viewer's satisfaction. It's clear that (Chan) was determined to be a star in America, it was his dream, and it would never happen until 4 years after with (Rush Hour) which's not one of my favorites where Chan undoubtedly is less shining, maybe it succeeded because it was the right formula or the right time I don't know. But here like every Chan's movie the Action, as usual, exceeded everything. And the story, as ever, is just a superficial cover for fun with no possible deepness. It was enough for (Chan) and all of his team to assure how courageous, stubborn, and romantic the Asian is; in the same time that the American is so violent, criminal, and deranged whether poor or rich. Despite the balance that they made (kind American policemen, and one evil Asian in the street gang). On so many levels it proves how the Asian cinematic hero became better and his adventures became bigger since another very well known Asian-in-western-evil-world and I mean (Bruce Lee) at (Way of the Dragon) nearly 25 years earlier, to invade America itself (it was Italy in the first one), and to present Mad Mad world comic Action also through this maniac hero who, at the time, needed no stunts or wires ! So ultimately (Rumble in the Bronx - 1996) is nice strong action, where (Jackie) is in classical example for being a real icon, original star, and great clown. Makes you wonder a bit about what he lost, after fulfilling his dream, in next American movies.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
 </reviews>
</filme>
