<filme>
 <id>
  244
 </id>
 <imdburl>
  http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0120152
 </imdburl>
 <ano>
  1997
 </ano>
 <titulo>
  Smilla's Sense of Snow
 </titulo>
 <rating>
  6.2
 </rating>
 <sinopse>
  Based on Peter Hoeg's bestseller, this film is set in snowy Copenhagen where a small boy is found dead after he fell off a roof. Smilla Jasperson, a close friend who lives in the same house... &nbsp;&raquo;
 </sinopse>
 <storyline>
  Based on Peter Hoeg's bestseller, this film is set in snowy Copenhagen where a small boy is found dead after he fell off a roof. Smilla Jasperson, a close friend who lives in the same house begins to suspect murder because she knows that the boy was afraid of heights and would not have played on the roof. As she begins to investigate, she is pulled deeper and deeper into a conspiracy that could very well mean her death.
 </storyline>
 <generos>
  <genero>
   Action
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Drama
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Sci-Fi
  </genero>
 </generos>
 <keywords>
  <keyword>
   boy
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   roof
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   greenland
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   snow
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   conspiracy
  </keyword>
 </keywords>
 <diretores>
  <diretor>
   Bille August
  </diretor>
 </diretores>
 <escritores>
  <escritor>
   Peter H&oslash;eg
  </escritor>
  <escritor>
   Ann Biderman
  </escritor>
 </escritores>
 <atores>
  <ator>
   Julia Ormond
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Ona Fletcher
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Agga Olsen
  </ator>
 </atores>
 <reviews>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Intriguing thriller turns into Lara Croft
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    kghispredi
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I really liked the main characters - a strong but seemingly cold-hearted woman and her strange neighbor who manages to be attractive and pitiful at the same time. One of the rare movies in which I was as much interested in the characters and their development as in the story line. Unfortunately half-way through the movie the events become more and more unbelievable and convoluted. People get killed, stuff explodes and our half-Inuit heroine goes through it like Lara Croft, with the difference that she keeps surviving not by skill or guns but by pure chance. The ending seems taken from an 80's James Bond movie. Disappointing for those of us who are not fond of evil scientist / mysterious forces clich&eacute;s.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    its nice and organized well
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    JeongHyun Park
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/9/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Had I not read the book, this video might have been good. Unfortunately I felt it fell well below satisfactory. The book is rich with many details about Greenland and the relationship between indigenous Greenlanders and Denmark. While I didn't expect the film to be able to pick up these nuances, I was particularly disappointed by the way the producer handled the necessary background details about Smilla. For example, there is no way that, given the relationship between her father and herself, they would have sat together to watch a film about her background. A voice over (such as in the novel) would have been a better solution.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A well-crafted thriller and Smilla is a very interesting heroine
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    margbcon (margbcon@yahoo.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/6/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    'Smilla's sense of snow' introduces us to Smilla Jasperson (played convincingly by Julia Ormond) a young laboratory assistant working at the University hospital in Copenhagen. Smilla appears initially to be well blended into the workplace and life of the city but soon we realize that she is not a city person; she has grown up in the vast and snow-covered plains of Greenland with her Inuit mother and moved to Copenhagen after her mother's death. Smilla one day after returning from work witnesses the fatal fall of a young Inuit boy falling from a terrace. The police arrives just after her and question her about the event. Despite being in a state of shock she manages to look at the scene and from the footprints on the snow she believes that the death was not accidental: the boy was pushed or nudged to jump under a threat. From that day on Smilla's life will change. She is determined to find out the truth seeking initially help from her father (who prepares to marry again) and then from her neighbor, the enigmatic mechanic played by (the always good) Gabriel Byrne. 'Smilla's sense of snow' is a very good thriller and Smilla is a very interesting heroine. We understand from the beginning that she does not feel comfortable in the city but at the same time tries to integrate without losing her Inuit identity. She seems fragile but her 'sense of snow' guides her to find the killer and her new identity. For her the death of the Inuit boy (that we get to know through a number of flashbacks) appears to signify the loss of her own innocence in a new world of norms and rules that she does not feel comfortable to abide by. The film is a well-crafted thriller from a good director (Bille August) with beautiful images of Copenhagen and the Arctic. A 8/10 from me.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Woman faces death, love, betrayal and redemption
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    aurora
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/6/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Movie plus: - the scenery - the boy - Julia and Gabriel - that a lot of the conversation was taken directly from the book. - the ending of the movie, I liked what the mechanic did - it wrapped it up a bit more than the book ending (and I had to cry while watching the final scene with the boy) Movie cons: - it was attempted but still Smilla's way of thinking did not cross over from the book to the movie - the driving scenes irritated me as it was fake - the boat scenes were too short - the living thing and the worms.. NO that was not how it was in the book (sorry for repeating myself) and it made the whole story a very bad SF one. Quite a nice adaption of the book, still the book is better... the way I watched this movie was reading the book a bit while watching the movie in bits during two days. Still I give it an 8 out of 10 and wish that somewhere in the future someone will try his or her hand on it again with more time and more danish and inuit actors.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Cartoon-like tale of an ice queen
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    evening1
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/12/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This film starts off promisingly with a dazzling display of nature at its most powerful. However, the extreme unlikeliness of the plot makes this movie a bit of a joke. I'll admit that Julia Ormand's performance is strong, and, for me, that Gabriel Bryne can never do any wrong. The premise about an innocent young boy getting killed is genuinely heartbreaking. However, the connection between the asteroid and the rest of this saga isn't clarified until the end, and one must put up with far too much ponderous dialog to make it worth the wait. (Why was it necessary to show repeated spats between Smilla and her stepmother? Who the hell cared?) The Gabriel Byrne character saves Smilla's butt so many times he practically personifies the literary device "deus ex machina." (OK, we get it!) Was this film intended for grown-ups or for the teenage boys who read superhero comics?
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Could have been good, but......
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    nat_mann
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/6/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie promises to be great but fails to deliver. Julia Ormond is gorgeous and her character is intriguing. It starts out as a tight suspenseful thriller, but comes completely unraveled at the end. A lot is made of Smilla's knowledge of snow but it's only used once. She has a deep interest in mathematics that is not used at all except to make a neat little speech about numbers. The film becomes implausible towards the end and the finale must have been grafted on from a tawdry B science fiction movie. I can't remember a more ludicrous explanation in any movie ever. Very disappointing after the good start.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Snow Job
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tedg (tedg@FilmsFolded.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/9/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is a replacement comment, the original having been removed because of a complaint. Ordinarily, when there is a book involved, I prefer to judge the movie as independently as I can. But in this case, the movie is so tepid, and the book so alive I cannot avoid it. Toward the end of the film, a bad guy explains that the thing in front of him is not a meteorite. They are cold and dead and this is warm and alive he says. Then the film blows it up. I felt this way about the possibilities of the novel. It was originally written in Danish I think, but the English translation I read was superb. It was fashioned as a thriller/mystery, but the journey was through an inventive inner dialog that abstracted the world of Copenhagen as if it were Inuit, and human love and intrigue as if it were snow. It was not life-altering but striking and extremely well done. In the same way that science fiction can make the world more real by slanting it a bit, this made some female urges and fears more real and accessible to me than usual. I was affected. Inner dialogs in film are hard. Shifting abstractions to a set unfamiliar to the viewer is even harder. Trying to fit squarely in the thriller movie genre makes it impossible. So the failure is easy to understand, at least superficially. But there is something in the way the book moved that could have been captured in film without stretching the vocabulary much. Apart from the clever starting point and narrative perspective, and similarly apart from the conventional ending the amazing thing was how one morphed to the other slowly, continuously, seamlessly and without the reader even noticing. There were some things carried over: the book went from an inner ice to a real ice world. It went from internal mental battles to internal physical battles to simple physical battles. But these were not what was relied on. There was a deliberate evolution of the narrative stance. This is extremely rare, I believe, and it was knowingly controlled. I wish something like this had conveyed in the film. As it is, there is a mystery, then some lovemaking, then the thriller. I'm going to give this a two just based on the book. Ted's Evaluation -- 2 of 3: Has some interesting elements.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Potential Packed
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gcd70
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/3/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    From what must be a fascinating, intriguing novel from Peter Hoeg came this potential packed thriller from the under-achieving director of "Les Miserables", Bille August. "Smilla's Feeling for Snow" starts off as a most interesting riddler about the suspicious death of a young boy that wreaks of a cover-up. An intuitive neighbour, Smilla, starts snooping around looking for clues to the mystery's solution. After painstakingly laying out the juicy premise, director August does nothing with the rest of the film, aside from tell the story, plain and simple. This same error ruined his version of "Les Mis" as well. His characters remain under-developed, and the plot is left to its own devices. Julia Ormond does reasonably well with her part and her accent. Gabriel Byrne gets to do very little, and his character remains an enigma throughout the film. The support cast don't get much of a go either. Some nice cinematography and a good music score save some face. Sunday, January 17, 1999 - Video
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    That's not snow you're sensing... it's disappointment
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Grann-Bach (Grann-Bach@jubii.dk)
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/12/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I haven't read the novel, though I'm afraid I can imagine it being superior to this. Honestly, I've been putting off watching this for years. It's cool that a Dane wrote it, and that another one directed it. And it was actually partially filmed here, as well as, unusually, up in Greenland, and a little bit of Inuktitut is spoken. It just doesn't feel like much of anything was beefed up for the purpose of putting it up on the silver screen, and the fact of the matter is, it has to be bigger than it does on the page. As far as what is translated from the book goes, the mystery does work well. It is fairly engaging, and keeps you guessing to an extent. With that said, you know who's behind it the moment you see him, since *the score instantly becomes ominous when the camera shows him*. This has its entertaining moments, and occasional humor. The performances are great, though these talented actors have all done better work elsewhere. Ormond fails to make the character particularly likable, and her accent does not convince. Editing and cinematography are nice enough. There is infrequent strong language, some violence and a sex scene in this. I recommend this to big fans of those involved in its production. 6/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Great start; poor finish
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    irish23
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/4/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It's rare that I don't fast-forward through a film these days. This was one film that had me riveted, though, at least for the first 3/4s of the picture. The quiet, tense thriller unfolded with perfect timing and ambiguous characters. The acting was top-notch and the characters multi- dimensional. Then suddenly the film takes a severe detour into "typical action movie." All subtlety is lost, characters become flat, pacing devolves and the whole thing becomes increasingly ridiculous. Enter the fast-forward! It was such a disappointment after that sustained great beginning. Who knows what happened. The end result leaves an unpleasant taste.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Intriguing thriller turns into Lara Croft
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    kghispredi
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I really liked the main characters - a strong but seemingly cold-hearted woman and her strange neighbor who manages to be attractive and pitiful at the same time. One of the rare movies in which I was as much interested in the characters and their development as in the story line. Unfortunately half-way through the movie the events become more and more unbelievable and convoluted. People get killed, stuff explodes and our half-Inuit heroine goes through it like Lara Croft, with the difference that she keeps surviving not by skill or guns but by pure chance. The ending seems taken from an 80's James Bond movie. Disappointing for those of us who are not fond of evil scientist / mysterious forces clich&eacute;s.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    its nice and organized well
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    JeongHyun Park
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/9/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Had I not read the book, this video might have been good. Unfortunately I felt it fell well below satisfactory. The book is rich with many details about Greenland and the relationship between indigenous Greenlanders and Denmark. While I didn't expect the film to be able to pick up these nuances, I was particularly disappointed by the way the producer handled the necessary background details about Smilla. For example, there is no way that, given the relationship between her father and herself, they would have sat together to watch a film about her background. A voice over (such as in the novel) would have been a better solution.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A well-crafted thriller and Smilla is a very interesting heroine
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    margbcon (margbcon@yahoo.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/6/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    'Smilla's sense of snow' introduces us to Smilla Jasperson (played convincingly by Julia Ormond) a young laboratory assistant working at the University hospital in Copenhagen. Smilla appears initially to be well blended into the workplace and life of the city but soon we realize that she is not a city person; she has grown up in the vast and snow-covered plains of Greenland with her Inuit mother and moved to Copenhagen after her mother's death. Smilla one day after returning from work witnesses the fatal fall of a young Inuit boy falling from a terrace. The police arrives just after her and question her about the event. Despite being in a state of shock she manages to look at the scene and from the footprints on the snow she believes that the death was not accidental: the boy was pushed or nudged to jump under a threat. From that day on Smilla's life will change. She is determined to find out the truth seeking initially help from her father (who prepares to marry again) and then from her neighbor, the enigmatic mechanic played by (the always good) Gabriel Byrne. 'Smilla's sense of snow' is a very good thriller and Smilla is a very interesting heroine. We understand from the beginning that she does not feel comfortable in the city but at the same time tries to integrate without losing her Inuit identity. She seems fragile but her 'sense of snow' guides her to find the killer and her new identity. For her the death of the Inuit boy (that we get to know through a number of flashbacks) appears to signify the loss of her own innocence in a new world of norms and rules that she does not feel comfortable to abide by. The film is a well-crafted thriller from a good director (Bille August) with beautiful images of Copenhagen and the Arctic. A 8/10 from me.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Woman faces death, love, betrayal and redemption
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    aurora
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/6/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Movie plus: - the scenery - the boy - Julia and Gabriel - that a lot of the conversation was taken directly from the book. - the ending of the movie, I liked what the mechanic did - it wrapped it up a bit more than the book ending (and I had to cry while watching the final scene with the boy) Movie cons: - it was attempted but still Smilla's way of thinking did not cross over from the book to the movie - the driving scenes irritated me as it was fake - the boat scenes were too short - the living thing and the worms.. NO that was not how it was in the book (sorry for repeating myself) and it made the whole story a very bad SF one. Quite a nice adaption of the book, still the book is better... the way I watched this movie was reading the book a bit while watching the movie in bits during two days. Still I give it an 8 out of 10 and wish that somewhere in the future someone will try his or her hand on it again with more time and more danish and inuit actors.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Cartoon-like tale of an ice queen
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    evening1
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/12/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This film starts off promisingly with a dazzling display of nature at its most powerful. However, the extreme unlikeliness of the plot makes this movie a bit of a joke. I'll admit that Julia Ormand's performance is strong, and, for me, that Gabriel Bryne can never do any wrong. The premise about an innocent young boy getting killed is genuinely heartbreaking. However, the connection between the asteroid and the rest of this saga isn't clarified until the end, and one must put up with far too much ponderous dialog to make it worth the wait. (Why was it necessary to show repeated spats between Smilla and her stepmother? Who the hell cared?) The Gabriel Byrne character saves Smilla's butt so many times he practically personifies the literary device "deus ex machina." (OK, we get it!) Was this film intended for grown-ups or for the teenage boys who read superhero comics?
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Could have been good, but......
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    nat_mann
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/6/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie promises to be great but fails to deliver. Julia Ormond is gorgeous and her character is intriguing. It starts out as a tight suspenseful thriller, but comes completely unraveled at the end. A lot is made of Smilla's knowledge of snow but it's only used once. She has a deep interest in mathematics that is not used at all except to make a neat little speech about numbers. The film becomes implausible towards the end and the finale must have been grafted on from a tawdry B science fiction movie. I can't remember a more ludicrous explanation in any movie ever. Very disappointing after the good start.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Snow Job
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tedg (tedg@FilmsFolded.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/9/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is a replacement comment, the original having been removed because of a complaint. Ordinarily, when there is a book involved, I prefer to judge the movie as independently as I can. But in this case, the movie is so tepid, and the book so alive I cannot avoid it. Toward the end of the film, a bad guy explains that the thing in front of him is not a meteorite. They are cold and dead and this is warm and alive he says. Then the film blows it up. I felt this way about the possibilities of the novel. It was originally written in Danish I think, but the English translation I read was superb. It was fashioned as a thriller/mystery, but the journey was through an inventive inner dialog that abstracted the world of Copenhagen as if it were Inuit, and human love and intrigue as if it were snow. It was not life-altering but striking and extremely well done. In the same way that science fiction can make the world more real by slanting it a bit, this made some female urges and fears more real and accessible to me than usual. I was affected. Inner dialogs in film are hard. Shifting abstractions to a set unfamiliar to the viewer is even harder. Trying to fit squarely in the thriller movie genre makes it impossible. So the failure is easy to understand, at least superficially. But there is something in the way the book moved that could have been captured in film without stretching the vocabulary much. Apart from the clever starting point and narrative perspective, and similarly apart from the conventional ending the amazing thing was how one morphed to the other slowly, continuously, seamlessly and without the reader even noticing. There were some things carried over: the book went from an inner ice to a real ice world. It went from internal mental battles to internal physical battles to simple physical battles. But these were not what was relied on. There was a deliberate evolution of the narrative stance. This is extremely rare, I believe, and it was knowingly controlled. I wish something like this had conveyed in the film. As it is, there is a mystery, then some lovemaking, then the thriller. I'm going to give this a two just based on the book. Ted's Evaluation -- 2 of 3: Has some interesting elements.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Potential Packed
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gcd70
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/3/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    From what must be a fascinating, intriguing novel from Peter Hoeg came this potential packed thriller from the under-achieving director of "Les Miserables", Bille August. "Smilla's Feeling for Snow" starts off as a most interesting riddler about the suspicious death of a young boy that wreaks of a cover-up. An intuitive neighbour, Smilla, starts snooping around looking for clues to the mystery's solution. After painstakingly laying out the juicy premise, director August does nothing with the rest of the film, aside from tell the story, plain and simple. This same error ruined his version of "Les Mis" as well. His characters remain under-developed, and the plot is left to its own devices. Julia Ormond does reasonably well with her part and her accent. Gabriel Byrne gets to do very little, and his character remains an enigma throughout the film. The support cast don't get much of a go either. Some nice cinematography and a good music score save some face. Sunday, January 17, 1999 - Video
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    That's not snow you're sensing... it's disappointment
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Grann-Bach (Grann-Bach@jubii.dk)
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/12/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I haven't read the novel, though I'm afraid I can imagine it being superior to this. Honestly, I've been putting off watching this for years. It's cool that a Dane wrote it, and that another one directed it. And it was actually partially filmed here, as well as, unusually, up in Greenland, and a little bit of Inuktitut is spoken. It just doesn't feel like much of anything was beefed up for the purpose of putting it up on the silver screen, and the fact of the matter is, it has to be bigger than it does on the page. As far as what is translated from the book goes, the mystery does work well. It is fairly engaging, and keeps you guessing to an extent. With that said, you know who's behind it the moment you see him, since *the score instantly becomes ominous when the camera shows him*. This has its entertaining moments, and occasional humor. The performances are great, though these talented actors have all done better work elsewhere. Ormond fails to make the character particularly likable, and her accent does not convince. Editing and cinematography are nice enough. There is infrequent strong language, some violence and a sex scene in this. I recommend this to big fans of those involved in its production. 6/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Great start; poor finish
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    irish23
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/4/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It's rare that I don't fast-forward through a film these days. This was one film that had me riveted, though, at least for the first 3/4s of the picture. The quiet, tense thriller unfolded with perfect timing and ambiguous characters. The acting was top-notch and the characters multi- dimensional. Then suddenly the film takes a severe detour into "typical action movie." All subtlety is lost, characters become flat, pacing devolves and the whole thing becomes increasingly ridiculous. Enter the fast-forward! It was such a disappointment after that sustained great beginning. Who knows what happened. The end result leaves an unpleasant taste.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Intriguing thriller turns into Lara Croft
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    kghispredi
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I really liked the main characters - a strong but seemingly cold-hearted woman and her strange neighbor who manages to be attractive and pitiful at the same time. One of the rare movies in which I was as much interested in the characters and their development as in the story line. Unfortunately half-way through the movie the events become more and more unbelievable and convoluted. People get killed, stuff explodes and our half-Inuit heroine goes through it like Lara Croft, with the difference that she keeps surviving not by skill or guns but by pure chance. The ending seems taken from an 80's James Bond movie. Disappointing for those of us who are not fond of evil scientist / mysterious forces clich&eacute;s.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    its nice and organized well
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    JeongHyun Park
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/9/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Had I not read the book, this video might have been good. Unfortunately I felt it fell well below satisfactory. The book is rich with many details about Greenland and the relationship between indigenous Greenlanders and Denmark. While I didn't expect the film to be able to pick up these nuances, I was particularly disappointed by the way the producer handled the necessary background details about Smilla. For example, there is no way that, given the relationship between her father and herself, they would have sat together to watch a film about her background. A voice over (such as in the novel) would have been a better solution.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A well-crafted thriller and Smilla is a very interesting heroine
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    margbcon (margbcon@yahoo.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/6/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    'Smilla's sense of snow' introduces us to Smilla Jasperson (played convincingly by Julia Ormond) a young laboratory assistant working at the University hospital in Copenhagen. Smilla appears initially to be well blended into the workplace and life of the city but soon we realize that she is not a city person; she has grown up in the vast and snow-covered plains of Greenland with her Inuit mother and moved to Copenhagen after her mother's death. Smilla one day after returning from work witnesses the fatal fall of a young Inuit boy falling from a terrace. The police arrives just after her and question her about the event. Despite being in a state of shock she manages to look at the scene and from the footprints on the snow she believes that the death was not accidental: the boy was pushed or nudged to jump under a threat. From that day on Smilla's life will change. She is determined to find out the truth seeking initially help from her father (who prepares to marry again) and then from her neighbor, the enigmatic mechanic played by (the always good) Gabriel Byrne. 'Smilla's sense of snow' is a very good thriller and Smilla is a very interesting heroine. We understand from the beginning that she does not feel comfortable in the city but at the same time tries to integrate without losing her Inuit identity. She seems fragile but her 'sense of snow' guides her to find the killer and her new identity. For her the death of the Inuit boy (that we get to know through a number of flashbacks) appears to signify the loss of her own innocence in a new world of norms and rules that she does not feel comfortable to abide by. The film is a well-crafted thriller from a good director (Bille August) with beautiful images of Copenhagen and the Arctic. A 8/10 from me.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Woman faces death, love, betrayal and redemption
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    aurora
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/6/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Movie plus: - the scenery - the boy - Julia and Gabriel - that a lot of the conversation was taken directly from the book. - the ending of the movie, I liked what the mechanic did - it wrapped it up a bit more than the book ending (and I had to cry while watching the final scene with the boy) Movie cons: - it was attempted but still Smilla's way of thinking did not cross over from the book to the movie - the driving scenes irritated me as it was fake - the boat scenes were too short - the living thing and the worms.. NO that was not how it was in the book (sorry for repeating myself) and it made the whole story a very bad SF one. Quite a nice adaption of the book, still the book is better... the way I watched this movie was reading the book a bit while watching the movie in bits during two days. Still I give it an 8 out of 10 and wish that somewhere in the future someone will try his or her hand on it again with more time and more danish and inuit actors.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Cartoon-like tale of an ice queen
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    evening1
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/12/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This film starts off promisingly with a dazzling display of nature at its most powerful. However, the extreme unlikeliness of the plot makes this movie a bit of a joke. I'll admit that Julia Ormand's performance is strong, and, for me, that Gabriel Bryne can never do any wrong. The premise about an innocent young boy getting killed is genuinely heartbreaking. However, the connection between the asteroid and the rest of this saga isn't clarified until the end, and one must put up with far too much ponderous dialog to make it worth the wait. (Why was it necessary to show repeated spats between Smilla and her stepmother? Who the hell cared?) The Gabriel Byrne character saves Smilla's butt so many times he practically personifies the literary device "deus ex machina." (OK, we get it!) Was this film intended for grown-ups or for the teenage boys who read superhero comics?
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Could have been good, but......
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    nat_mann
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/6/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie promises to be great but fails to deliver. Julia Ormond is gorgeous and her character is intriguing. It starts out as a tight suspenseful thriller, but comes completely unraveled at the end. A lot is made of Smilla's knowledge of snow but it's only used once. She has a deep interest in mathematics that is not used at all except to make a neat little speech about numbers. The film becomes implausible towards the end and the finale must have been grafted on from a tawdry B science fiction movie. I can't remember a more ludicrous explanation in any movie ever. Very disappointing after the good start.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Snow Job
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tedg (tedg@FilmsFolded.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/9/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is a replacement comment, the original having been removed because of a complaint. Ordinarily, when there is a book involved, I prefer to judge the movie as independently as I can. But in this case, the movie is so tepid, and the book so alive I cannot avoid it. Toward the end of the film, a bad guy explains that the thing in front of him is not a meteorite. They are cold and dead and this is warm and alive he says. Then the film blows it up. I felt this way about the possibilities of the novel. It was originally written in Danish I think, but the English translation I read was superb. It was fashioned as a thriller/mystery, but the journey was through an inventive inner dialog that abstracted the world of Copenhagen as if it were Inuit, and human love and intrigue as if it were snow. It was not life-altering but striking and extremely well done. In the same way that science fiction can make the world more real by slanting it a bit, this made some female urges and fears more real and accessible to me than usual. I was affected. Inner dialogs in film are hard. Shifting abstractions to a set unfamiliar to the viewer is even harder. Trying to fit squarely in the thriller movie genre makes it impossible. So the failure is easy to understand, at least superficially. But there is something in the way the book moved that could have been captured in film without stretching the vocabulary much. Apart from the clever starting point and narrative perspective, and similarly apart from the conventional ending the amazing thing was how one morphed to the other slowly, continuously, seamlessly and without the reader even noticing. There were some things carried over: the book went from an inner ice to a real ice world. It went from internal mental battles to internal physical battles to simple physical battles. But these were not what was relied on. There was a deliberate evolution of the narrative stance. This is extremely rare, I believe, and it was knowingly controlled. I wish something like this had conveyed in the film. As it is, there is a mystery, then some lovemaking, then the thriller. I'm going to give this a two just based on the book. Ted's Evaluation -- 2 of 3: Has some interesting elements.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Potential Packed
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gcd70
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/3/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    From what must be a fascinating, intriguing novel from Peter Hoeg came this potential packed thriller from the under-achieving director of "Les Miserables", Bille August. "Smilla's Feeling for Snow" starts off as a most interesting riddler about the suspicious death of a young boy that wreaks of a cover-up. An intuitive neighbour, Smilla, starts snooping around looking for clues to the mystery's solution. After painstakingly laying out the juicy premise, director August does nothing with the rest of the film, aside from tell the story, plain and simple. This same error ruined his version of "Les Mis" as well. His characters remain under-developed, and the plot is left to its own devices. Julia Ormond does reasonably well with her part and her accent. Gabriel Byrne gets to do very little, and his character remains an enigma throughout the film. The support cast don't get much of a go either. Some nice cinematography and a good music score save some face. Sunday, January 17, 1999 - Video
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    That's not snow you're sensing... it's disappointment
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Grann-Bach (Grann-Bach@jubii.dk)
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/12/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I haven't read the novel, though I'm afraid I can imagine it being superior to this. Honestly, I've been putting off watching this for years. It's cool that a Dane wrote it, and that another one directed it. And it was actually partially filmed here, as well as, unusually, up in Greenland, and a little bit of Inuktitut is spoken. It just doesn't feel like much of anything was beefed up for the purpose of putting it up on the silver screen, and the fact of the matter is, it has to be bigger than it does on the page. As far as what is translated from the book goes, the mystery does work well. It is fairly engaging, and keeps you guessing to an extent. With that said, you know who's behind it the moment you see him, since *the score instantly becomes ominous when the camera shows him*. This has its entertaining moments, and occasional humor. The performances are great, though these talented actors have all done better work elsewhere. Ormond fails to make the character particularly likable, and her accent does not convince. Editing and cinematography are nice enough. There is infrequent strong language, some violence and a sex scene in this. I recommend this to big fans of those involved in its production. 6/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Great start; poor finish
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    irish23
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/4/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It's rare that I don't fast-forward through a film these days. This was one film that had me riveted, though, at least for the first 3/4s of the picture. The quiet, tense thriller unfolded with perfect timing and ambiguous characters. The acting was top-notch and the characters multi- dimensional. Then suddenly the film takes a severe detour into "typical action movie." All subtlety is lost, characters become flat, pacing devolves and the whole thing becomes increasingly ridiculous. Enter the fast-forward! It was such a disappointment after that sustained great beginning. Who knows what happened. The end result leaves an unpleasant taste.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Intriguing thriller turns into Lara Croft
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    kghispredi
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I really liked the main characters - a strong but seemingly cold-hearted woman and her strange neighbor who manages to be attractive and pitiful at the same time. One of the rare movies in which I was as much interested in the characters and their development as in the story line. Unfortunately half-way through the movie the events become more and more unbelievable and convoluted. People get killed, stuff explodes and our half-Inuit heroine goes through it like Lara Croft, with the difference that she keeps surviving not by skill or guns but by pure chance. The ending seems taken from an 80's James Bond movie. Disappointing for those of us who are not fond of evil scientist / mysterious forces clich&eacute;s.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    its nice and organized well
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    JeongHyun Park
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/9/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Had I not read the book, this video might have been good. Unfortunately I felt it fell well below satisfactory. The book is rich with many details about Greenland and the relationship between indigenous Greenlanders and Denmark. While I didn't expect the film to be able to pick up these nuances, I was particularly disappointed by the way the producer handled the necessary background details about Smilla. For example, there is no way that, given the relationship between her father and herself, they would have sat together to watch a film about her background. A voice over (such as in the novel) would have been a better solution.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A well-crafted thriller and Smilla is a very interesting heroine
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    margbcon (margbcon@yahoo.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/6/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    'Smilla's sense of snow' introduces us to Smilla Jasperson (played convincingly by Julia Ormond) a young laboratory assistant working at the University hospital in Copenhagen. Smilla appears initially to be well blended into the workplace and life of the city but soon we realize that she is not a city person; she has grown up in the vast and snow-covered plains of Greenland with her Inuit mother and moved to Copenhagen after her mother's death. Smilla one day after returning from work witnesses the fatal fall of a young Inuit boy falling from a terrace. The police arrives just after her and question her about the event. Despite being in a state of shock she manages to look at the scene and from the footprints on the snow she believes that the death was not accidental: the boy was pushed or nudged to jump under a threat. From that day on Smilla's life will change. She is determined to find out the truth seeking initially help from her father (who prepares to marry again) and then from her neighbor, the enigmatic mechanic played by (the always good) Gabriel Byrne. 'Smilla's sense of snow' is a very good thriller and Smilla is a very interesting heroine. We understand from the beginning that she does not feel comfortable in the city but at the same time tries to integrate without losing her Inuit identity. She seems fragile but her 'sense of snow' guides her to find the killer and her new identity. For her the death of the Inuit boy (that we get to know through a number of flashbacks) appears to signify the loss of her own innocence in a new world of norms and rules that she does not feel comfortable to abide by. The film is a well-crafted thriller from a good director (Bille August) with beautiful images of Copenhagen and the Arctic. A 8/10 from me.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Woman faces death, love, betrayal and redemption
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    aurora
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/6/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Movie plus: - the scenery - the boy - Julia and Gabriel - that a lot of the conversation was taken directly from the book. - the ending of the movie, I liked what the mechanic did - it wrapped it up a bit more than the book ending (and I had to cry while watching the final scene with the boy) Movie cons: - it was attempted but still Smilla's way of thinking did not cross over from the book to the movie - the driving scenes irritated me as it was fake - the boat scenes were too short - the living thing and the worms.. NO that was not how it was in the book (sorry for repeating myself) and it made the whole story a very bad SF one. Quite a nice adaption of the book, still the book is better... the way I watched this movie was reading the book a bit while watching the movie in bits during two days. Still I give it an 8 out of 10 and wish that somewhere in the future someone will try his or her hand on it again with more time and more danish and inuit actors.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Cartoon-like tale of an ice queen
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    evening1
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/12/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This film starts off promisingly with a dazzling display of nature at its most powerful. However, the extreme unlikeliness of the plot makes this movie a bit of a joke. I'll admit that Julia Ormand's performance is strong, and, for me, that Gabriel Bryne can never do any wrong. The premise about an innocent young boy getting killed is genuinely heartbreaking. However, the connection between the asteroid and the rest of this saga isn't clarified until the end, and one must put up with far too much ponderous dialog to make it worth the wait. (Why was it necessary to show repeated spats between Smilla and her stepmother? Who the hell cared?) The Gabriel Byrne character saves Smilla's butt so many times he practically personifies the literary device "deus ex machina." (OK, we get it!) Was this film intended for grown-ups or for the teenage boys who read superhero comics?
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Could have been good, but......
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    nat_mann
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/6/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie promises to be great but fails to deliver. Julia Ormond is gorgeous and her character is intriguing. It starts out as a tight suspenseful thriller, but comes completely unraveled at the end. A lot is made of Smilla's knowledge of snow but it's only used once. She has a deep interest in mathematics that is not used at all except to make a neat little speech about numbers. The film becomes implausible towards the end and the finale must have been grafted on from a tawdry B science fiction movie. I can't remember a more ludicrous explanation in any movie ever. Very disappointing after the good start.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Snow Job
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tedg (tedg@FilmsFolded.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/9/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is a replacement comment, the original having been removed because of a complaint. Ordinarily, when there is a book involved, I prefer to judge the movie as independently as I can. But in this case, the movie is so tepid, and the book so alive I cannot avoid it. Toward the end of the film, a bad guy explains that the thing in front of him is not a meteorite. They are cold and dead and this is warm and alive he says. Then the film blows it up. I felt this way about the possibilities of the novel. It was originally written in Danish I think, but the English translation I read was superb. It was fashioned as a thriller/mystery, but the journey was through an inventive inner dialog that abstracted the world of Copenhagen as if it were Inuit, and human love and intrigue as if it were snow. It was not life-altering but striking and extremely well done. In the same way that science fiction can make the world more real by slanting it a bit, this made some female urges and fears more real and accessible to me than usual. I was affected. Inner dialogs in film are hard. Shifting abstractions to a set unfamiliar to the viewer is even harder. Trying to fit squarely in the thriller movie genre makes it impossible. So the failure is easy to understand, at least superficially. But there is something in the way the book moved that could have been captured in film without stretching the vocabulary much. Apart from the clever starting point and narrative perspective, and similarly apart from the conventional ending the amazing thing was how one morphed to the other slowly, continuously, seamlessly and without the reader even noticing. There were some things carried over: the book went from an inner ice to a real ice world. It went from internal mental battles to internal physical battles to simple physical battles. But these were not what was relied on. There was a deliberate evolution of the narrative stance. This is extremely rare, I believe, and it was knowingly controlled. I wish something like this had conveyed in the film. As it is, there is a mystery, then some lovemaking, then the thriller. I'm going to give this a two just based on the book. Ted's Evaluation -- 2 of 3: Has some interesting elements.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Potential Packed
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gcd70
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/3/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    From what must be a fascinating, intriguing novel from Peter Hoeg came this potential packed thriller from the under-achieving director of "Les Miserables", Bille August. "Smilla's Feeling for Snow" starts off as a most interesting riddler about the suspicious death of a young boy that wreaks of a cover-up. An intuitive neighbour, Smilla, starts snooping around looking for clues to the mystery's solution. After painstakingly laying out the juicy premise, director August does nothing with the rest of the film, aside from tell the story, plain and simple. This same error ruined his version of "Les Mis" as well. His characters remain under-developed, and the plot is left to its own devices. Julia Ormond does reasonably well with her part and her accent. Gabriel Byrne gets to do very little, and his character remains an enigma throughout the film. The support cast don't get much of a go either. Some nice cinematography and a good music score save some face. Sunday, January 17, 1999 - Video
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    That's not snow you're sensing... it's disappointment
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Grann-Bach (Grann-Bach@jubii.dk)
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/12/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I haven't read the novel, though I'm afraid I can imagine it being superior to this. Honestly, I've been putting off watching this for years. It's cool that a Dane wrote it, and that another one directed it. And it was actually partially filmed here, as well as, unusually, up in Greenland, and a little bit of Inuktitut is spoken. It just doesn't feel like much of anything was beefed up for the purpose of putting it up on the silver screen, and the fact of the matter is, it has to be bigger than it does on the page. As far as what is translated from the book goes, the mystery does work well. It is fairly engaging, and keeps you guessing to an extent. With that said, you know who's behind it the moment you see him, since *the score instantly becomes ominous when the camera shows him*. This has its entertaining moments, and occasional humor. The performances are great, though these talented actors have all done better work elsewhere. Ormond fails to make the character particularly likable, and her accent does not convince. Editing and cinematography are nice enough. There is infrequent strong language, some violence and a sex scene in this. I recommend this to big fans of those involved in its production. 6/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Great start; poor finish
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    irish23
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/4/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It's rare that I don't fast-forward through a film these days. This was one film that had me riveted, though, at least for the first 3/4s of the picture. The quiet, tense thriller unfolded with perfect timing and ambiguous characters. The acting was top-notch and the characters multi- dimensional. Then suddenly the film takes a severe detour into "typical action movie." All subtlety is lost, characters become flat, pacing devolves and the whole thing becomes increasingly ridiculous. Enter the fast-forward! It was such a disappointment after that sustained great beginning. Who knows what happened. The end result leaves an unpleasant taste.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Intriguing thriller turns into Lara Croft
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    kghispredi
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I really liked the main characters - a strong but seemingly cold-hearted woman and her strange neighbor who manages to be attractive and pitiful at the same time. One of the rare movies in which I was as much interested in the characters and their development as in the story line. Unfortunately half-way through the movie the events become more and more unbelievable and convoluted. People get killed, stuff explodes and our half-Inuit heroine goes through it like Lara Croft, with the difference that she keeps surviving not by skill or guns but by pure chance. The ending seems taken from an 80's James Bond movie. Disappointing for those of us who are not fond of evil scientist / mysterious forces clich&eacute;s.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    its nice and organized well
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    JeongHyun Park
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/9/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Had I not read the book, this video might have been good. Unfortunately I felt it fell well below satisfactory. The book is rich with many details about Greenland and the relationship between indigenous Greenlanders and Denmark. While I didn't expect the film to be able to pick up these nuances, I was particularly disappointed by the way the producer handled the necessary background details about Smilla. For example, there is no way that, given the relationship between her father and herself, they would have sat together to watch a film about her background. A voice over (such as in the novel) would have been a better solution.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A well-crafted thriller and Smilla is a very interesting heroine
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    margbcon (margbcon@yahoo.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/6/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    'Smilla's sense of snow' introduces us to Smilla Jasperson (played convincingly by Julia Ormond) a young laboratory assistant working at the University hospital in Copenhagen. Smilla appears initially to be well blended into the workplace and life of the city but soon we realize that she is not a city person; she has grown up in the vast and snow-covered plains of Greenland with her Inuit mother and moved to Copenhagen after her mother's death. Smilla one day after returning from work witnesses the fatal fall of a young Inuit boy falling from a terrace. The police arrives just after her and question her about the event. Despite being in a state of shock she manages to look at the scene and from the footprints on the snow she believes that the death was not accidental: the boy was pushed or nudged to jump under a threat. From that day on Smilla's life will change. She is determined to find out the truth seeking initially help from her father (who prepares to marry again) and then from her neighbor, the enigmatic mechanic played by (the always good) Gabriel Byrne. 'Smilla's sense of snow' is a very good thriller and Smilla is a very interesting heroine. We understand from the beginning that she does not feel comfortable in the city but at the same time tries to integrate without losing her Inuit identity. She seems fragile but her 'sense of snow' guides her to find the killer and her new identity. For her the death of the Inuit boy (that we get to know through a number of flashbacks) appears to signify the loss of her own innocence in a new world of norms and rules that she does not feel comfortable to abide by. The film is a well-crafted thriller from a good director (Bille August) with beautiful images of Copenhagen and the Arctic. A 8/10 from me.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Woman faces death, love, betrayal and redemption
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    aurora
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/6/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Movie plus: - the scenery - the boy - Julia and Gabriel - that a lot of the conversation was taken directly from the book. - the ending of the movie, I liked what the mechanic did - it wrapped it up a bit more than the book ending (and I had to cry while watching the final scene with the boy) Movie cons: - it was attempted but still Smilla's way of thinking did not cross over from the book to the movie - the driving scenes irritated me as it was fake - the boat scenes were too short - the living thing and the worms.. NO that was not how it was in the book (sorry for repeating myself) and it made the whole story a very bad SF one. Quite a nice adaption of the book, still the book is better... the way I watched this movie was reading the book a bit while watching the movie in bits during two days. Still I give it an 8 out of 10 and wish that somewhere in the future someone will try his or her hand on it again with more time and more danish and inuit actors.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Cartoon-like tale of an ice queen
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    evening1
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/12/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This film starts off promisingly with a dazzling display of nature at its most powerful. However, the extreme unlikeliness of the plot makes this movie a bit of a joke. I'll admit that Julia Ormand's performance is strong, and, for me, that Gabriel Bryne can never do any wrong. The premise about an innocent young boy getting killed is genuinely heartbreaking. However, the connection between the asteroid and the rest of this saga isn't clarified until the end, and one must put up with far too much ponderous dialog to make it worth the wait. (Why was it necessary to show repeated spats between Smilla and her stepmother? Who the hell cared?) The Gabriel Byrne character saves Smilla's butt so many times he practically personifies the literary device "deus ex machina." (OK, we get it!) Was this film intended for grown-ups or for the teenage boys who read superhero comics?
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Could have been good, but......
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    nat_mann
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/6/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie promises to be great but fails to deliver. Julia Ormond is gorgeous and her character is intriguing. It starts out as a tight suspenseful thriller, but comes completely unraveled at the end. A lot is made of Smilla's knowledge of snow but it's only used once. She has a deep interest in mathematics that is not used at all except to make a neat little speech about numbers. The film becomes implausible towards the end and the finale must have been grafted on from a tawdry B science fiction movie. I can't remember a more ludicrous explanation in any movie ever. Very disappointing after the good start.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Snow Job
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tedg (tedg@FilmsFolded.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/9/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is a replacement comment, the original having been removed because of a complaint. Ordinarily, when there is a book involved, I prefer to judge the movie as independently as I can. But in this case, the movie is so tepid, and the book so alive I cannot avoid it. Toward the end of the film, a bad guy explains that the thing in front of him is not a meteorite. They are cold and dead and this is warm and alive he says. Then the film blows it up. I felt this way about the possibilities of the novel. It was originally written in Danish I think, but the English translation I read was superb. It was fashioned as a thriller/mystery, but the journey was through an inventive inner dialog that abstracted the world of Copenhagen as if it were Inuit, and human love and intrigue as if it were snow. It was not life-altering but striking and extremely well done. In the same way that science fiction can make the world more real by slanting it a bit, this made some female urges and fears more real and accessible to me than usual. I was affected. Inner dialogs in film are hard. Shifting abstractions to a set unfamiliar to the viewer is even harder. Trying to fit squarely in the thriller movie genre makes it impossible. So the failure is easy to understand, at least superficially. But there is something in the way the book moved that could have been captured in film without stretching the vocabulary much. Apart from the clever starting point and narrative perspective, and similarly apart from the conventional ending the amazing thing was how one morphed to the other slowly, continuously, seamlessly and without the reader even noticing. There were some things carried over: the book went from an inner ice to a real ice world. It went from internal mental battles to internal physical battles to simple physical battles. But these were not what was relied on. There was a deliberate evolution of the narrative stance. This is extremely rare, I believe, and it was knowingly controlled. I wish something like this had conveyed in the film. As it is, there is a mystery, then some lovemaking, then the thriller. I'm going to give this a two just based on the book. Ted's Evaluation -- 2 of 3: Has some interesting elements.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Potential Packed
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gcd70
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/3/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    From what must be a fascinating, intriguing novel from Peter Hoeg came this potential packed thriller from the under-achieving director of "Les Miserables", Bille August. "Smilla's Feeling for Snow" starts off as a most interesting riddler about the suspicious death of a young boy that wreaks of a cover-up. An intuitive neighbour, Smilla, starts snooping around looking for clues to the mystery's solution. After painstakingly laying out the juicy premise, director August does nothing with the rest of the film, aside from tell the story, plain and simple. This same error ruined his version of "Les Mis" as well. His characters remain under-developed, and the plot is left to its own devices. Julia Ormond does reasonably well with her part and her accent. Gabriel Byrne gets to do very little, and his character remains an enigma throughout the film. The support cast don't get much of a go either. Some nice cinematography and a good music score save some face. Sunday, January 17, 1999 - Video
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    That's not snow you're sensing... it's disappointment
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Grann-Bach (Grann-Bach@jubii.dk)
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/12/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I haven't read the novel, though I'm afraid I can imagine it being superior to this. Honestly, I've been putting off watching this for years. It's cool that a Dane wrote it, and that another one directed it. And it was actually partially filmed here, as well as, unusually, up in Greenland, and a little bit of Inuktitut is spoken. It just doesn't feel like much of anything was beefed up for the purpose of putting it up on the silver screen, and the fact of the matter is, it has to be bigger than it does on the page. As far as what is translated from the book goes, the mystery does work well. It is fairly engaging, and keeps you guessing to an extent. With that said, you know who's behind it the moment you see him, since *the score instantly becomes ominous when the camera shows him*. This has its entertaining moments, and occasional humor. The performances are great, though these talented actors have all done better work elsewhere. Ormond fails to make the character particularly likable, and her accent does not convince. Editing and cinematography are nice enough. There is infrequent strong language, some violence and a sex scene in this. I recommend this to big fans of those involved in its production. 6/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Great start; poor finish
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    irish23
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/4/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It's rare that I don't fast-forward through a film these days. This was one film that had me riveted, though, at least for the first 3/4s of the picture. The quiet, tense thriller unfolded with perfect timing and ambiguous characters. The acting was top-notch and the characters multi- dimensional. Then suddenly the film takes a severe detour into "typical action movie." All subtlety is lost, characters become flat, pacing devolves and the whole thing becomes increasingly ridiculous. Enter the fast-forward! It was such a disappointment after that sustained great beginning. Who knows what happened. The end result leaves an unpleasant taste.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Intriguing thriller turns into Lara Croft
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    kghispredi
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I really liked the main characters - a strong but seemingly cold-hearted woman and her strange neighbor who manages to be attractive and pitiful at the same time. One of the rare movies in which I was as much interested in the characters and their development as in the story line. Unfortunately half-way through the movie the events become more and more unbelievable and convoluted. People get killed, stuff explodes and our half-Inuit heroine goes through it like Lara Croft, with the difference that she keeps surviving not by skill or guns but by pure chance. The ending seems taken from an 80's James Bond movie. Disappointing for those of us who are not fond of evil scientist / mysterious forces clich&eacute;s.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    its nice and organized well
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    JeongHyun Park
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/9/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Had I not read the book, this video might have been good. Unfortunately I felt it fell well below satisfactory. The book is rich with many details about Greenland and the relationship between indigenous Greenlanders and Denmark. While I didn't expect the film to be able to pick up these nuances, I was particularly disappointed by the way the producer handled the necessary background details about Smilla. For example, there is no way that, given the relationship between her father and herself, they would have sat together to watch a film about her background. A voice over (such as in the novel) would have been a better solution.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A well-crafted thriller and Smilla is a very interesting heroine
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    margbcon (margbcon@yahoo.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/6/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    'Smilla's sense of snow' introduces us to Smilla Jasperson (played convincingly by Julia Ormond) a young laboratory assistant working at the University hospital in Copenhagen. Smilla appears initially to be well blended into the workplace and life of the city but soon we realize that she is not a city person; she has grown up in the vast and snow-covered plains of Greenland with her Inuit mother and moved to Copenhagen after her mother's death. Smilla one day after returning from work witnesses the fatal fall of a young Inuit boy falling from a terrace. The police arrives just after her and question her about the event. Despite being in a state of shock she manages to look at the scene and from the footprints on the snow she believes that the death was not accidental: the boy was pushed or nudged to jump under a threat. From that day on Smilla's life will change. She is determined to find out the truth seeking initially help from her father (who prepares to marry again) and then from her neighbor, the enigmatic mechanic played by (the always good) Gabriel Byrne. 'Smilla's sense of snow' is a very good thriller and Smilla is a very interesting heroine. We understand from the beginning that she does not feel comfortable in the city but at the same time tries to integrate without losing her Inuit identity. She seems fragile but her 'sense of snow' guides her to find the killer and her new identity. For her the death of the Inuit boy (that we get to know through a number of flashbacks) appears to signify the loss of her own innocence in a new world of norms and rules that she does not feel comfortable to abide by. The film is a well-crafted thriller from a good director (Bille August) with beautiful images of Copenhagen and the Arctic. A 8/10 from me.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Woman faces death, love, betrayal and redemption
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    aurora
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/6/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Movie plus: - the scenery - the boy - Julia and Gabriel - that a lot of the conversation was taken directly from the book. - the ending of the movie, I liked what the mechanic did - it wrapped it up a bit more than the book ending (and I had to cry while watching the final scene with the boy) Movie cons: - it was attempted but still Smilla's way of thinking did not cross over from the book to the movie - the driving scenes irritated me as it was fake - the boat scenes were too short - the living thing and the worms.. NO that was not how it was in the book (sorry for repeating myself) and it made the whole story a very bad SF one. Quite a nice adaption of the book, still the book is better... the way I watched this movie was reading the book a bit while watching the movie in bits during two days. Still I give it an 8 out of 10 and wish that somewhere in the future someone will try his or her hand on it again with more time and more danish and inuit actors.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Cartoon-like tale of an ice queen
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    evening1
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/12/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This film starts off promisingly with a dazzling display of nature at its most powerful. However, the extreme unlikeliness of the plot makes this movie a bit of a joke. I'll admit that Julia Ormand's performance is strong, and, for me, that Gabriel Bryne can never do any wrong. The premise about an innocent young boy getting killed is genuinely heartbreaking. However, the connection between the asteroid and the rest of this saga isn't clarified until the end, and one must put up with far too much ponderous dialog to make it worth the wait. (Why was it necessary to show repeated spats between Smilla and her stepmother? Who the hell cared?) The Gabriel Byrne character saves Smilla's butt so many times he practically personifies the literary device "deus ex machina." (OK, we get it!) Was this film intended for grown-ups or for the teenage boys who read superhero comics?
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Could have been good, but......
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    nat_mann
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/6/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie promises to be great but fails to deliver. Julia Ormond is gorgeous and her character is intriguing. It starts out as a tight suspenseful thriller, but comes completely unraveled at the end. A lot is made of Smilla's knowledge of snow but it's only used once. She has a deep interest in mathematics that is not used at all except to make a neat little speech about numbers. The film becomes implausible towards the end and the finale must have been grafted on from a tawdry B science fiction movie. I can't remember a more ludicrous explanation in any movie ever. Very disappointing after the good start.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Snow Job
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tedg (tedg@FilmsFolded.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/9/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is a replacement comment, the original having been removed because of a complaint. Ordinarily, when there is a book involved, I prefer to judge the movie as independently as I can. But in this case, the movie is so tepid, and the book so alive I cannot avoid it. Toward the end of the film, a bad guy explains that the thing in front of him is not a meteorite. They are cold and dead and this is warm and alive he says. Then the film blows it up. I felt this way about the possibilities of the novel. It was originally written in Danish I think, but the English translation I read was superb. It was fashioned as a thriller/mystery, but the journey was through an inventive inner dialog that abstracted the world of Copenhagen as if it were Inuit, and human love and intrigue as if it were snow. It was not life-altering but striking and extremely well done. In the same way that science fiction can make the world more real by slanting it a bit, this made some female urges and fears more real and accessible to me than usual. I was affected. Inner dialogs in film are hard. Shifting abstractions to a set unfamiliar to the viewer is even harder. Trying to fit squarely in the thriller movie genre makes it impossible. So the failure is easy to understand, at least superficially. But there is something in the way the book moved that could have been captured in film without stretching the vocabulary much. Apart from the clever starting point and narrative perspective, and similarly apart from the conventional ending the amazing thing was how one morphed to the other slowly, continuously, seamlessly and without the reader even noticing. There were some things carried over: the book went from an inner ice to a real ice world. It went from internal mental battles to internal physical battles to simple physical battles. But these were not what was relied on. There was a deliberate evolution of the narrative stance. This is extremely rare, I believe, and it was knowingly controlled. I wish something like this had conveyed in the film. As it is, there is a mystery, then some lovemaking, then the thriller. I'm going to give this a two just based on the book. Ted's Evaluation -- 2 of 3: Has some interesting elements.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Potential Packed
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gcd70
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/3/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    From what must be a fascinating, intriguing novel from Peter Hoeg came this potential packed thriller from the under-achieving director of "Les Miserables", Bille August. "Smilla's Feeling for Snow" starts off as a most interesting riddler about the suspicious death of a young boy that wreaks of a cover-up. An intuitive neighbour, Smilla, starts snooping around looking for clues to the mystery's solution. After painstakingly laying out the juicy premise, director August does nothing with the rest of the film, aside from tell the story, plain and simple. This same error ruined his version of "Les Mis" as well. His characters remain under-developed, and the plot is left to its own devices. Julia Ormond does reasonably well with her part and her accent. Gabriel Byrne gets to do very little, and his character remains an enigma throughout the film. The support cast don't get much of a go either. Some nice cinematography and a good music score save some face. Sunday, January 17, 1999 - Video
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    That's not snow you're sensing... it's disappointment
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Grann-Bach (Grann-Bach@jubii.dk)
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/12/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I haven't read the novel, though I'm afraid I can imagine it being superior to this. Honestly, I've been putting off watching this for years. It's cool that a Dane wrote it, and that another one directed it. And it was actually partially filmed here, as well as, unusually, up in Greenland, and a little bit of Inuktitut is spoken. It just doesn't feel like much of anything was beefed up for the purpose of putting it up on the silver screen, and the fact of the matter is, it has to be bigger than it does on the page. As far as what is translated from the book goes, the mystery does work well. It is fairly engaging, and keeps you guessing to an extent. With that said, you know who's behind it the moment you see him, since *the score instantly becomes ominous when the camera shows him*. This has its entertaining moments, and occasional humor. The performances are great, though these talented actors have all done better work elsewhere. Ormond fails to make the character particularly likable, and her accent does not convince. Editing and cinematography are nice enough. There is infrequent strong language, some violence and a sex scene in this. I recommend this to big fans of those involved in its production. 6/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Great start; poor finish
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    irish23
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/4/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It's rare that I don't fast-forward through a film these days. This was one film that had me riveted, though, at least for the first 3/4s of the picture. The quiet, tense thriller unfolded with perfect timing and ambiguous characters. The acting was top-notch and the characters multi- dimensional. Then suddenly the film takes a severe detour into "typical action movie." All subtlety is lost, characters become flat, pacing devolves and the whole thing becomes increasingly ridiculous. Enter the fast-forward! It was such a disappointment after that sustained great beginning. Who knows what happened. The end result leaves an unpleasant taste.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Intriguing thriller turns into Lara Croft
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    kghispredi
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I really liked the main characters - a strong but seemingly cold-hearted woman and her strange neighbor who manages to be attractive and pitiful at the same time. One of the rare movies in which I was as much interested in the characters and their development as in the story line. Unfortunately half-way through the movie the events become more and more unbelievable and convoluted. People get killed, stuff explodes and our half-Inuit heroine goes through it like Lara Croft, with the difference that she keeps surviving not by skill or guns but by pure chance. The ending seems taken from an 80's James Bond movie. Disappointing for those of us who are not fond of evil scientist / mysterious forces clich&eacute;s.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    its nice and organized well
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    JeongHyun Park
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/9/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Had I not read the book, this video might have been good. Unfortunately I felt it fell well below satisfactory. The book is rich with many details about Greenland and the relationship between indigenous Greenlanders and Denmark. While I didn't expect the film to be able to pick up these nuances, I was particularly disappointed by the way the producer handled the necessary background details about Smilla. For example, there is no way that, given the relationship between her father and herself, they would have sat together to watch a film about her background. A voice over (such as in the novel) would have been a better solution.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A well-crafted thriller and Smilla is a very interesting heroine
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    margbcon (margbcon@yahoo.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/6/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    'Smilla's sense of snow' introduces us to Smilla Jasperson (played convincingly by Julia Ormond) a young laboratory assistant working at the University hospital in Copenhagen. Smilla appears initially to be well blended into the workplace and life of the city but soon we realize that she is not a city person; she has grown up in the vast and snow-covered plains of Greenland with her Inuit mother and moved to Copenhagen after her mother's death. Smilla one day after returning from work witnesses the fatal fall of a young Inuit boy falling from a terrace. The police arrives just after her and question her about the event. Despite being in a state of shock she manages to look at the scene and from the footprints on the snow she believes that the death was not accidental: the boy was pushed or nudged to jump under a threat. From that day on Smilla's life will change. She is determined to find out the truth seeking initially help from her father (who prepares to marry again) and then from her neighbor, the enigmatic mechanic played by (the always good) Gabriel Byrne. 'Smilla's sense of snow' is a very good thriller and Smilla is a very interesting heroine. We understand from the beginning that she does not feel comfortable in the city but at the same time tries to integrate without losing her Inuit identity. She seems fragile but her 'sense of snow' guides her to find the killer and her new identity. For her the death of the Inuit boy (that we get to know through a number of flashbacks) appears to signify the loss of her own innocence in a new world of norms and rules that she does not feel comfortable to abide by. The film is a well-crafted thriller from a good director (Bille August) with beautiful images of Copenhagen and the Arctic. A 8/10 from me.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Woman faces death, love, betrayal and redemption
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    aurora
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/6/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Movie plus: - the scenery - the boy - Julia and Gabriel - that a lot of the conversation was taken directly from the book. - the ending of the movie, I liked what the mechanic did - it wrapped it up a bit more than the book ending (and I had to cry while watching the final scene with the boy) Movie cons: - it was attempted but still Smilla's way of thinking did not cross over from the book to the movie - the driving scenes irritated me as it was fake - the boat scenes were too short - the living thing and the worms.. NO that was not how it was in the book (sorry for repeating myself) and it made the whole story a very bad SF one. Quite a nice adaption of the book, still the book is better... the way I watched this movie was reading the book a bit while watching the movie in bits during two days. Still I give it an 8 out of 10 and wish that somewhere in the future someone will try his or her hand on it again with more time and more danish and inuit actors.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Cartoon-like tale of an ice queen
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    evening1
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/12/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This film starts off promisingly with a dazzling display of nature at its most powerful. However, the extreme unlikeliness of the plot makes this movie a bit of a joke. I'll admit that Julia Ormand's performance is strong, and, for me, that Gabriel Bryne can never do any wrong. The premise about an innocent young boy getting killed is genuinely heartbreaking. However, the connection between the asteroid and the rest of this saga isn't clarified until the end, and one must put up with far too much ponderous dialog to make it worth the wait. (Why was it necessary to show repeated spats between Smilla and her stepmother? Who the hell cared?) The Gabriel Byrne character saves Smilla's butt so many times he practically personifies the literary device "deus ex machina." (OK, we get it!) Was this film intended for grown-ups or for the teenage boys who read superhero comics?
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Could have been good, but......
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    nat_mann
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/6/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie promises to be great but fails to deliver. Julia Ormond is gorgeous and her character is intriguing. It starts out as a tight suspenseful thriller, but comes completely unraveled at the end. A lot is made of Smilla's knowledge of snow but it's only used once. She has a deep interest in mathematics that is not used at all except to make a neat little speech about numbers. The film becomes implausible towards the end and the finale must have been grafted on from a tawdry B science fiction movie. I can't remember a more ludicrous explanation in any movie ever. Very disappointing after the good start.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Snow Job
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tedg (tedg@FilmsFolded.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/9/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is a replacement comment, the original having been removed because of a complaint. Ordinarily, when there is a book involved, I prefer to judge the movie as independently as I can. But in this case, the movie is so tepid, and the book so alive I cannot avoid it. Toward the end of the film, a bad guy explains that the thing in front of him is not a meteorite. They are cold and dead and this is warm and alive he says. Then the film blows it up. I felt this way about the possibilities of the novel. It was originally written in Danish I think, but the English translation I read was superb. It was fashioned as a thriller/mystery, but the journey was through an inventive inner dialog that abstracted the world of Copenhagen as if it were Inuit, and human love and intrigue as if it were snow. It was not life-altering but striking and extremely well done. In the same way that science fiction can make the world more real by slanting it a bit, this made some female urges and fears more real and accessible to me than usual. I was affected. Inner dialogs in film are hard. Shifting abstractions to a set unfamiliar to the viewer is even harder. Trying to fit squarely in the thriller movie genre makes it impossible. So the failure is easy to understand, at least superficially. But there is something in the way the book moved that could have been captured in film without stretching the vocabulary much. Apart from the clever starting point and narrative perspective, and similarly apart from the conventional ending the amazing thing was how one morphed to the other slowly, continuously, seamlessly and without the reader even noticing. There were some things carried over: the book went from an inner ice to a real ice world. It went from internal mental battles to internal physical battles to simple physical battles. But these were not what was relied on. There was a deliberate evolution of the narrative stance. This is extremely rare, I believe, and it was knowingly controlled. I wish something like this had conveyed in the film. As it is, there is a mystery, then some lovemaking, then the thriller. I'm going to give this a two just based on the book. Ted's Evaluation -- 2 of 3: Has some interesting elements.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Potential Packed
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gcd70
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/3/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    From what must be a fascinating, intriguing novel from Peter Hoeg came this potential packed thriller from the under-achieving director of "Les Miserables", Bille August. "Smilla's Feeling for Snow" starts off as a most interesting riddler about the suspicious death of a young boy that wreaks of a cover-up. An intuitive neighbour, Smilla, starts snooping around looking for clues to the mystery's solution. After painstakingly laying out the juicy premise, director August does nothing with the rest of the film, aside from tell the story, plain and simple. This same error ruined his version of "Les Mis" as well. His characters remain under-developed, and the plot is left to its own devices. Julia Ormond does reasonably well with her part and her accent. Gabriel Byrne gets to do very little, and his character remains an enigma throughout the film. The support cast don't get much of a go either. Some nice cinematography and a good music score save some face. Sunday, January 17, 1999 - Video
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    That's not snow you're sensing... it's disappointment
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Grann-Bach (Grann-Bach@jubii.dk)
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/12/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I haven't read the novel, though I'm afraid I can imagine it being superior to this. Honestly, I've been putting off watching this for years. It's cool that a Dane wrote it, and that another one directed it. And it was actually partially filmed here, as well as, unusually, up in Greenland, and a little bit of Inuktitut is spoken. It just doesn't feel like much of anything was beefed up for the purpose of putting it up on the silver screen, and the fact of the matter is, it has to be bigger than it does on the page. As far as what is translated from the book goes, the mystery does work well. It is fairly engaging, and keeps you guessing to an extent. With that said, you know who's behind it the moment you see him, since *the score instantly becomes ominous when the camera shows him*. This has its entertaining moments, and occasional humor. The performances are great, though these talented actors have all done better work elsewhere. Ormond fails to make the character particularly likable, and her accent does not convince. Editing and cinematography are nice enough. There is infrequent strong language, some violence and a sex scene in this. I recommend this to big fans of those involved in its production. 6/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Great start; poor finish
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    irish23
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/4/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It's rare that I don't fast-forward through a film these days. This was one film that had me riveted, though, at least for the first 3/4s of the picture. The quiet, tense thriller unfolded with perfect timing and ambiguous characters. The acting was top-notch and the characters multi- dimensional. Then suddenly the film takes a severe detour into "typical action movie." All subtlety is lost, characters become flat, pacing devolves and the whole thing becomes increasingly ridiculous. Enter the fast-forward! It was such a disappointment after that sustained great beginning. Who knows what happened. The end result leaves an unpleasant taste.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Intriguing thriller turns into Lara Croft
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    kghispredi
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I really liked the main characters - a strong but seemingly cold-hearted woman and her strange neighbor who manages to be attractive and pitiful at the same time. One of the rare movies in which I was as much interested in the characters and their development as in the story line. Unfortunately half-way through the movie the events become more and more unbelievable and convoluted. People get killed, stuff explodes and our half-Inuit heroine goes through it like Lara Croft, with the difference that she keeps surviving not by skill or guns but by pure chance. The ending seems taken from an 80's James Bond movie. Disappointing for those of us who are not fond of evil scientist / mysterious forces clich&eacute;s.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    its nice and organized well
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    JeongHyun Park
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/9/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Had I not read the book, this video might have been good. Unfortunately I felt it fell well below satisfactory. The book is rich with many details about Greenland and the relationship between indigenous Greenlanders and Denmark. While I didn't expect the film to be able to pick up these nuances, I was particularly disappointed by the way the producer handled the necessary background details about Smilla. For example, there is no way that, given the relationship between her father and herself, they would have sat together to watch a film about her background. A voice over (such as in the novel) would have been a better solution.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A well-crafted thriller and Smilla is a very interesting heroine
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    margbcon (margbcon@yahoo.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/6/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    'Smilla's sense of snow' introduces us to Smilla Jasperson (played convincingly by Julia Ormond) a young laboratory assistant working at the University hospital in Copenhagen. Smilla appears initially to be well blended into the workplace and life of the city but soon we realize that she is not a city person; she has grown up in the vast and snow-covered plains of Greenland with her Inuit mother and moved to Copenhagen after her mother's death. Smilla one day after returning from work witnesses the fatal fall of a young Inuit boy falling from a terrace. The police arrives just after her and question her about the event. Despite being in a state of shock she manages to look at the scene and from the footprints on the snow she believes that the death was not accidental: the boy was pushed or nudged to jump under a threat. From that day on Smilla's life will change. She is determined to find out the truth seeking initially help from her father (who prepares to marry again) and then from her neighbor, the enigmatic mechanic played by (the always good) Gabriel Byrne. 'Smilla's sense of snow' is a very good thriller and Smilla is a very interesting heroine. We understand from the beginning that she does not feel comfortable in the city but at the same time tries to integrate without losing her Inuit identity. She seems fragile but her 'sense of snow' guides her to find the killer and her new identity. For her the death of the Inuit boy (that we get to know through a number of flashbacks) appears to signify the loss of her own innocence in a new world of norms and rules that she does not feel comfortable to abide by. The film is a well-crafted thriller from a good director (Bille August) with beautiful images of Copenhagen and the Arctic. A 8/10 from me.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Woman faces death, love, betrayal and redemption
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    aurora
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/6/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Movie plus: - the scenery - the boy - Julia and Gabriel - that a lot of the conversation was taken directly from the book. - the ending of the movie, I liked what the mechanic did - it wrapped it up a bit more than the book ending (and I had to cry while watching the final scene with the boy) Movie cons: - it was attempted but still Smilla's way of thinking did not cross over from the book to the movie - the driving scenes irritated me as it was fake - the boat scenes were too short - the living thing and the worms.. NO that was not how it was in the book (sorry for repeating myself) and it made the whole story a very bad SF one. Quite a nice adaption of the book, still the book is better... the way I watched this movie was reading the book a bit while watching the movie in bits during two days. Still I give it an 8 out of 10 and wish that somewhere in the future someone will try his or her hand on it again with more time and more danish and inuit actors.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Cartoon-like tale of an ice queen
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    evening1
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/12/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This film starts off promisingly with a dazzling display of nature at its most powerful. However, the extreme unlikeliness of the plot makes this movie a bit of a joke. I'll admit that Julia Ormand's performance is strong, and, for me, that Gabriel Bryne can never do any wrong. The premise about an innocent young boy getting killed is genuinely heartbreaking. However, the connection between the asteroid and the rest of this saga isn't clarified until the end, and one must put up with far too much ponderous dialog to make it worth the wait. (Why was it necessary to show repeated spats between Smilla and her stepmother? Who the hell cared?) The Gabriel Byrne character saves Smilla's butt so many times he practically personifies the literary device "deus ex machina." (OK, we get it!) Was this film intended for grown-ups or for the teenage boys who read superhero comics?
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Could have been good, but......
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    nat_mann
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/6/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie promises to be great but fails to deliver. Julia Ormond is gorgeous and her character is intriguing. It starts out as a tight suspenseful thriller, but comes completely unraveled at the end. A lot is made of Smilla's knowledge of snow but it's only used once. She has a deep interest in mathematics that is not used at all except to make a neat little speech about numbers. The film becomes implausible towards the end and the finale must have been grafted on from a tawdry B science fiction movie. I can't remember a more ludicrous explanation in any movie ever. Very disappointing after the good start.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Snow Job
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tedg (tedg@FilmsFolded.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/9/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is a replacement comment, the original having been removed because of a complaint. Ordinarily, when there is a book involved, I prefer to judge the movie as independently as I can. But in this case, the movie is so tepid, and the book so alive I cannot avoid it. Toward the end of the film, a bad guy explains that the thing in front of him is not a meteorite. They are cold and dead and this is warm and alive he says. Then the film blows it up. I felt this way about the possibilities of the novel. It was originally written in Danish I think, but the English translation I read was superb. It was fashioned as a thriller/mystery, but the journey was through an inventive inner dialog that abstracted the world of Copenhagen as if it were Inuit, and human love and intrigue as if it were snow. It was not life-altering but striking and extremely well done. In the same way that science fiction can make the world more real by slanting it a bit, this made some female urges and fears more real and accessible to me than usual. I was affected. Inner dialogs in film are hard. Shifting abstractions to a set unfamiliar to the viewer is even harder. Trying to fit squarely in the thriller movie genre makes it impossible. So the failure is easy to understand, at least superficially. But there is something in the way the book moved that could have been captured in film without stretching the vocabulary much. Apart from the clever starting point and narrative perspective, and similarly apart from the conventional ending the amazing thing was how one morphed to the other slowly, continuously, seamlessly and without the reader even noticing. There were some things carried over: the book went from an inner ice to a real ice world. It went from internal mental battles to internal physical battles to simple physical battles. But these were not what was relied on. There was a deliberate evolution of the narrative stance. This is extremely rare, I believe, and it was knowingly controlled. I wish something like this had conveyed in the film. As it is, there is a mystery, then some lovemaking, then the thriller. I'm going to give this a two just based on the book. Ted's Evaluation -- 2 of 3: Has some interesting elements.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Potential Packed
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gcd70
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/3/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    From what must be a fascinating, intriguing novel from Peter Hoeg came this potential packed thriller from the under-achieving director of "Les Miserables", Bille August. "Smilla's Feeling for Snow" starts off as a most interesting riddler about the suspicious death of a young boy that wreaks of a cover-up. An intuitive neighbour, Smilla, starts snooping around looking for clues to the mystery's solution. After painstakingly laying out the juicy premise, director August does nothing with the rest of the film, aside from tell the story, plain and simple. This same error ruined his version of "Les Mis" as well. His characters remain under-developed, and the plot is left to its own devices. Julia Ormond does reasonably well with her part and her accent. Gabriel Byrne gets to do very little, and his character remains an enigma throughout the film. The support cast don't get much of a go either. Some nice cinematography and a good music score save some face. Sunday, January 17, 1999 - Video
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    That's not snow you're sensing... it's disappointment
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Grann-Bach (Grann-Bach@jubii.dk)
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/12/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I haven't read the novel, though I'm afraid I can imagine it being superior to this. Honestly, I've been putting off watching this for years. It's cool that a Dane wrote it, and that another one directed it. And it was actually partially filmed here, as well as, unusually, up in Greenland, and a little bit of Inuktitut is spoken. It just doesn't feel like much of anything was beefed up for the purpose of putting it up on the silver screen, and the fact of the matter is, it has to be bigger than it does on the page. As far as what is translated from the book goes, the mystery does work well. It is fairly engaging, and keeps you guessing to an extent. With that said, you know who's behind it the moment you see him, since *the score instantly becomes ominous when the camera shows him*. This has its entertaining moments, and occasional humor. The performances are great, though these talented actors have all done better work elsewhere. Ormond fails to make the character particularly likable, and her accent does not convince. Editing and cinematography are nice enough. There is infrequent strong language, some violence and a sex scene in this. I recommend this to big fans of those involved in its production. 6/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Great start; poor finish
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    irish23
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/4/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It's rare that I don't fast-forward through a film these days. This was one film that had me riveted, though, at least for the first 3/4s of the picture. The quiet, tense thriller unfolded with perfect timing and ambiguous characters. The acting was top-notch and the characters multi- dimensional. Then suddenly the film takes a severe detour into "typical action movie." All subtlety is lost, characters become flat, pacing devolves and the whole thing becomes increasingly ridiculous. Enter the fast-forward! It was such a disappointment after that sustained great beginning. Who knows what happened. The end result leaves an unpleasant taste.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Intriguing thriller turns into Lara Croft
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    kghispredi
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I really liked the main characters - a strong but seemingly cold-hearted woman and her strange neighbor who manages to be attractive and pitiful at the same time. One of the rare movies in which I was as much interested in the characters and their development as in the story line. Unfortunately half-way through the movie the events become more and more unbelievable and convoluted. People get killed, stuff explodes and our half-Inuit heroine goes through it like Lara Croft, with the difference that she keeps surviving not by skill or guns but by pure chance. The ending seems taken from an 80's James Bond movie. Disappointing for those of us who are not fond of evil scientist / mysterious forces clich&eacute;s.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    its nice and organized well
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    JeongHyun Park
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/9/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Had I not read the book, this video might have been good. Unfortunately I felt it fell well below satisfactory. The book is rich with many details about Greenland and the relationship between indigenous Greenlanders and Denmark. While I didn't expect the film to be able to pick up these nuances, I was particularly disappointed by the way the producer handled the necessary background details about Smilla. For example, there is no way that, given the relationship between her father and herself, they would have sat together to watch a film about her background. A voice over (such as in the novel) would have been a better solution.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A well-crafted thriller and Smilla is a very interesting heroine
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    margbcon (margbcon@yahoo.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/6/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    'Smilla's sense of snow' introduces us to Smilla Jasperson (played convincingly by Julia Ormond) a young laboratory assistant working at the University hospital in Copenhagen. Smilla appears initially to be well blended into the workplace and life of the city but soon we realize that she is not a city person; she has grown up in the vast and snow-covered plains of Greenland with her Inuit mother and moved to Copenhagen after her mother's death. Smilla one day after returning from work witnesses the fatal fall of a young Inuit boy falling from a terrace. The police arrives just after her and question her about the event. Despite being in a state of shock she manages to look at the scene and from the footprints on the snow she believes that the death was not accidental: the boy was pushed or nudged to jump under a threat. From that day on Smilla's life will change. She is determined to find out the truth seeking initially help from her father (who prepares to marry again) and then from her neighbor, the enigmatic mechanic played by (the always good) Gabriel Byrne. 'Smilla's sense of snow' is a very good thriller and Smilla is a very interesting heroine. We understand from the beginning that she does not feel comfortable in the city but at the same time tries to integrate without losing her Inuit identity. She seems fragile but her 'sense of snow' guides her to find the killer and her new identity. For her the death of the Inuit boy (that we get to know through a number of flashbacks) appears to signify the loss of her own innocence in a new world of norms and rules that she does not feel comfortable to abide by. The film is a well-crafted thriller from a good director (Bille August) with beautiful images of Copenhagen and the Arctic. A 8/10 from me.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Woman faces death, love, betrayal and redemption
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    aurora
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/6/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Movie plus: - the scenery - the boy - Julia and Gabriel - that a lot of the conversation was taken directly from the book. - the ending of the movie, I liked what the mechanic did - it wrapped it up a bit more than the book ending (and I had to cry while watching the final scene with the boy) Movie cons: - it was attempted but still Smilla's way of thinking did not cross over from the book to the movie - the driving scenes irritated me as it was fake - the boat scenes were too short - the living thing and the worms.. NO that was not how it was in the book (sorry for repeating myself) and it made the whole story a very bad SF one. Quite a nice adaption of the book, still the book is better... the way I watched this movie was reading the book a bit while watching the movie in bits during two days. Still I give it an 8 out of 10 and wish that somewhere in the future someone will try his or her hand on it again with more time and more danish and inuit actors.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Cartoon-like tale of an ice queen
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    evening1
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/12/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This film starts off promisingly with a dazzling display of nature at its most powerful. However, the extreme unlikeliness of the plot makes this movie a bit of a joke. I'll admit that Julia Ormand's performance is strong, and, for me, that Gabriel Bryne can never do any wrong. The premise about an innocent young boy getting killed is genuinely heartbreaking. However, the connection between the asteroid and the rest of this saga isn't clarified until the end, and one must put up with far too much ponderous dialog to make it worth the wait. (Why was it necessary to show repeated spats between Smilla and her stepmother? Who the hell cared?) The Gabriel Byrne character saves Smilla's butt so many times he practically personifies the literary device "deus ex machina." (OK, we get it!) Was this film intended for grown-ups or for the teenage boys who read superhero comics?
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Could have been good, but......
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    nat_mann
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/6/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie promises to be great but fails to deliver. Julia Ormond is gorgeous and her character is intriguing. It starts out as a tight suspenseful thriller, but comes completely unraveled at the end. A lot is made of Smilla's knowledge of snow but it's only used once. She has a deep interest in mathematics that is not used at all except to make a neat little speech about numbers. The film becomes implausible towards the end and the finale must have been grafted on from a tawdry B science fiction movie. I can't remember a more ludicrous explanation in any movie ever. Very disappointing after the good start.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Snow Job
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tedg (tedg@FilmsFolded.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/9/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is a replacement comment, the original having been removed because of a complaint. Ordinarily, when there is a book involved, I prefer to judge the movie as independently as I can. But in this case, the movie is so tepid, and the book so alive I cannot avoid it. Toward the end of the film, a bad guy explains that the thing in front of him is not a meteorite. They are cold and dead and this is warm and alive he says. Then the film blows it up. I felt this way about the possibilities of the novel. It was originally written in Danish I think, but the English translation I read was superb. It was fashioned as a thriller/mystery, but the journey was through an inventive inner dialog that abstracted the world of Copenhagen as if it were Inuit, and human love and intrigue as if it were snow. It was not life-altering but striking and extremely well done. In the same way that science fiction can make the world more real by slanting it a bit, this made some female urges and fears more real and accessible to me than usual. I was affected. Inner dialogs in film are hard. Shifting abstractions to a set unfamiliar to the viewer is even harder. Trying to fit squarely in the thriller movie genre makes it impossible. So the failure is easy to understand, at least superficially. But there is something in the way the book moved that could have been captured in film without stretching the vocabulary much. Apart from the clever starting point and narrative perspective, and similarly apart from the conventional ending the amazing thing was how one morphed to the other slowly, continuously, seamlessly and without the reader even noticing. There were some things carried over: the book went from an inner ice to a real ice world. It went from internal mental battles to internal physical battles to simple physical battles. But these were not what was relied on. There was a deliberate evolution of the narrative stance. This is extremely rare, I believe, and it was knowingly controlled. I wish something like this had conveyed in the film. As it is, there is a mystery, then some lovemaking, then the thriller. I'm going to give this a two just based on the book. Ted's Evaluation -- 2 of 3: Has some interesting elements.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Potential Packed
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gcd70
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/3/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    From what must be a fascinating, intriguing novel from Peter Hoeg came this potential packed thriller from the under-achieving director of "Les Miserables", Bille August. "Smilla's Feeling for Snow" starts off as a most interesting riddler about the suspicious death of a young boy that wreaks of a cover-up. An intuitive neighbour, Smilla, starts snooping around looking for clues to the mystery's solution. After painstakingly laying out the juicy premise, director August does nothing with the rest of the film, aside from tell the story, plain and simple. This same error ruined his version of "Les Mis" as well. His characters remain under-developed, and the plot is left to its own devices. Julia Ormond does reasonably well with her part and her accent. Gabriel Byrne gets to do very little, and his character remains an enigma throughout the film. The support cast don't get much of a go either. Some nice cinematography and a good music score save some face. Sunday, January 17, 1999 - Video
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    That's not snow you're sensing... it's disappointment
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Grann-Bach (Grann-Bach@jubii.dk)
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/12/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I haven't read the novel, though I'm afraid I can imagine it being superior to this. Honestly, I've been putting off watching this for years. It's cool that a Dane wrote it, and that another one directed it. And it was actually partially filmed here, as well as, unusually, up in Greenland, and a little bit of Inuktitut is spoken. It just doesn't feel like much of anything was beefed up for the purpose of putting it up on the silver screen, and the fact of the matter is, it has to be bigger than it does on the page. As far as what is translated from the book goes, the mystery does work well. It is fairly engaging, and keeps you guessing to an extent. With that said, you know who's behind it the moment you see him, since *the score instantly becomes ominous when the camera shows him*. This has its entertaining moments, and occasional humor. The performances are great, though these talented actors have all done better work elsewhere. Ormond fails to make the character particularly likable, and her accent does not convince. Editing and cinematography are nice enough. There is infrequent strong language, some violence and a sex scene in this. I recommend this to big fans of those involved in its production. 6/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Great start; poor finish
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    irish23
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/4/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It's rare that I don't fast-forward through a film these days. This was one film that had me riveted, though, at least for the first 3/4s of the picture. The quiet, tense thriller unfolded with perfect timing and ambiguous characters. The acting was top-notch and the characters multi- dimensional. Then suddenly the film takes a severe detour into "typical action movie." All subtlety is lost, characters become flat, pacing devolves and the whole thing becomes increasingly ridiculous. Enter the fast-forward! It was such a disappointment after that sustained great beginning. Who knows what happened. The end result leaves an unpleasant taste.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Intriguing thriller turns into Lara Croft
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    kghispredi
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I really liked the main characters - a strong but seemingly cold-hearted woman and her strange neighbor who manages to be attractive and pitiful at the same time. One of the rare movies in which I was as much interested in the characters and their development as in the story line. Unfortunately half-way through the movie the events become more and more unbelievable and convoluted. People get killed, stuff explodes and our half-Inuit heroine goes through it like Lara Croft, with the difference that she keeps surviving not by skill or guns but by pure chance. The ending seems taken from an 80's James Bond movie. Disappointing for those of us who are not fond of evil scientist / mysterious forces clich&eacute;s.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    its nice and organized well
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    JeongHyun Park
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/9/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Had I not read the book, this video might have been good. Unfortunately I felt it fell well below satisfactory. The book is rich with many details about Greenland and the relationship between indigenous Greenlanders and Denmark. While I didn't expect the film to be able to pick up these nuances, I was particularly disappointed by the way the producer handled the necessary background details about Smilla. For example, there is no way that, given the relationship between her father and herself, they would have sat together to watch a film about her background. A voice over (such as in the novel) would have been a better solution.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A well-crafted thriller and Smilla is a very interesting heroine
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    margbcon (margbcon@yahoo.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/6/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    'Smilla's sense of snow' introduces us to Smilla Jasperson (played convincingly by Julia Ormond) a young laboratory assistant working at the University hospital in Copenhagen. Smilla appears initially to be well blended into the workplace and life of the city but soon we realize that she is not a city person; she has grown up in the vast and snow-covered plains of Greenland with her Inuit mother and moved to Copenhagen after her mother's death. Smilla one day after returning from work witnesses the fatal fall of a young Inuit boy falling from a terrace. The police arrives just after her and question her about the event. Despite being in a state of shock she manages to look at the scene and from the footprints on the snow she believes that the death was not accidental: the boy was pushed or nudged to jump under a threat. From that day on Smilla's life will change. She is determined to find out the truth seeking initially help from her father (who prepares to marry again) and then from her neighbor, the enigmatic mechanic played by (the always good) Gabriel Byrne. 'Smilla's sense of snow' is a very good thriller and Smilla is a very interesting heroine. We understand from the beginning that she does not feel comfortable in the city but at the same time tries to integrate without losing her Inuit identity. She seems fragile but her 'sense of snow' guides her to find the killer and her new identity. For her the death of the Inuit boy (that we get to know through a number of flashbacks) appears to signify the loss of her own innocence in a new world of norms and rules that she does not feel comfortable to abide by. The film is a well-crafted thriller from a good director (Bille August) with beautiful images of Copenhagen and the Arctic. A 8/10 from me.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Woman faces death, love, betrayal and redemption
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    aurora
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/6/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Movie plus: - the scenery - the boy - Julia and Gabriel - that a lot of the conversation was taken directly from the book. - the ending of the movie, I liked what the mechanic did - it wrapped it up a bit more than the book ending (and I had to cry while watching the final scene with the boy) Movie cons: - it was attempted but still Smilla's way of thinking did not cross over from the book to the movie - the driving scenes irritated me as it was fake - the boat scenes were too short - the living thing and the worms.. NO that was not how it was in the book (sorry for repeating myself) and it made the whole story a very bad SF one. Quite a nice adaption of the book, still the book is better... the way I watched this movie was reading the book a bit while watching the movie in bits during two days. Still I give it an 8 out of 10 and wish that somewhere in the future someone will try his or her hand on it again with more time and more danish and inuit actors.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Cartoon-like tale of an ice queen
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    evening1
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/12/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This film starts off promisingly with a dazzling display of nature at its most powerful. However, the extreme unlikeliness of the plot makes this movie a bit of a joke. I'll admit that Julia Ormand's performance is strong, and, for me, that Gabriel Bryne can never do any wrong. The premise about an innocent young boy getting killed is genuinely heartbreaking. However, the connection between the asteroid and the rest of this saga isn't clarified until the end, and one must put up with far too much ponderous dialog to make it worth the wait. (Why was it necessary to show repeated spats between Smilla and her stepmother? Who the hell cared?) The Gabriel Byrne character saves Smilla's butt so many times he practically personifies the literary device "deus ex machina." (OK, we get it!) Was this film intended for grown-ups or for the teenage boys who read superhero comics?
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Could have been good, but......
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    nat_mann
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/6/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie promises to be great but fails to deliver. Julia Ormond is gorgeous and her character is intriguing. It starts out as a tight suspenseful thriller, but comes completely unraveled at the end. A lot is made of Smilla's knowledge of snow but it's only used once. She has a deep interest in mathematics that is not used at all except to make a neat little speech about numbers. The film becomes implausible towards the end and the finale must have been grafted on from a tawdry B science fiction movie. I can't remember a more ludicrous explanation in any movie ever. Very disappointing after the good start.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Snow Job
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tedg (tedg@FilmsFolded.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/9/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is a replacement comment, the original having been removed because of a complaint. Ordinarily, when there is a book involved, I prefer to judge the movie as independently as I can. But in this case, the movie is so tepid, and the book so alive I cannot avoid it. Toward the end of the film, a bad guy explains that the thing in front of him is not a meteorite. They are cold and dead and this is warm and alive he says. Then the film blows it up. I felt this way about the possibilities of the novel. It was originally written in Danish I think, but the English translation I read was superb. It was fashioned as a thriller/mystery, but the journey was through an inventive inner dialog that abstracted the world of Copenhagen as if it were Inuit, and human love and intrigue as if it were snow. It was not life-altering but striking and extremely well done. In the same way that science fiction can make the world more real by slanting it a bit, this made some female urges and fears more real and accessible to me than usual. I was affected. Inner dialogs in film are hard. Shifting abstractions to a set unfamiliar to the viewer is even harder. Trying to fit squarely in the thriller movie genre makes it impossible. So the failure is easy to understand, at least superficially. But there is something in the way the book moved that could have been captured in film without stretching the vocabulary much. Apart from the clever starting point and narrative perspective, and similarly apart from the conventional ending the amazing thing was how one morphed to the other slowly, continuously, seamlessly and without the reader even noticing. There were some things carried over: the book went from an inner ice to a real ice world. It went from internal mental battles to internal physical battles to simple physical battles. But these were not what was relied on. There was a deliberate evolution of the narrative stance. This is extremely rare, I believe, and it was knowingly controlled. I wish something like this had conveyed in the film. As it is, there is a mystery, then some lovemaking, then the thriller. I'm going to give this a two just based on the book. Ted's Evaluation -- 2 of 3: Has some interesting elements.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Potential Packed
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gcd70
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/3/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    From what must be a fascinating, intriguing novel from Peter Hoeg came this potential packed thriller from the under-achieving director of "Les Miserables", Bille August. "Smilla's Feeling for Snow" starts off as a most interesting riddler about the suspicious death of a young boy that wreaks of a cover-up. An intuitive neighbour, Smilla, starts snooping around looking for clues to the mystery's solution. After painstakingly laying out the juicy premise, director August does nothing with the rest of the film, aside from tell the story, plain and simple. This same error ruined his version of "Les Mis" as well. His characters remain under-developed, and the plot is left to its own devices. Julia Ormond does reasonably well with her part and her accent. Gabriel Byrne gets to do very little, and his character remains an enigma throughout the film. The support cast don't get much of a go either. Some nice cinematography and a good music score save some face. Sunday, January 17, 1999 - Video
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    That's not snow you're sensing... it's disappointment
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Grann-Bach (Grann-Bach@jubii.dk)
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/12/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I haven't read the novel, though I'm afraid I can imagine it being superior to this. Honestly, I've been putting off watching this for years. It's cool that a Dane wrote it, and that another one directed it. And it was actually partially filmed here, as well as, unusually, up in Greenland, and a little bit of Inuktitut is spoken. It just doesn't feel like much of anything was beefed up for the purpose of putting it up on the silver screen, and the fact of the matter is, it has to be bigger than it does on the page. As far as what is translated from the book goes, the mystery does work well. It is fairly engaging, and keeps you guessing to an extent. With that said, you know who's behind it the moment you see him, since *the score instantly becomes ominous when the camera shows him*. This has its entertaining moments, and occasional humor. The performances are great, though these talented actors have all done better work elsewhere. Ormond fails to make the character particularly likable, and her accent does not convince. Editing and cinematography are nice enough. There is infrequent strong language, some violence and a sex scene in this. I recommend this to big fans of those involved in its production. 6/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Great start; poor finish
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    irish23
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/4/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It's rare that I don't fast-forward through a film these days. This was one film that had me riveted, though, at least for the first 3/4s of the picture. The quiet, tense thriller unfolded with perfect timing and ambiguous characters. The acting was top-notch and the characters multi- dimensional. Then suddenly the film takes a severe detour into "typical action movie." All subtlety is lost, characters become flat, pacing devolves and the whole thing becomes increasingly ridiculous. Enter the fast-forward! It was such a disappointment after that sustained great beginning. Who knows what happened. The end result leaves an unpleasant taste.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
 </reviews>
</filme>
