<filme>
 <id>
  245
 </id>
 <imdburl>
  http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0118972
 </imdburl>
 <ano>
  1997
 </ano>
 <titulo>
  Inimigo &Iacute;ntimo
 </titulo>
 <rating>
  5.9
 </rating>
 <sinopse>
  A police officer uncovers the real identity of his houseguest, an IRA terrorist in hiding.
 </sinopse>
 <storyline>
  A thriller about an IRA gunman who draws an American family into the crossfire of terrorism. Frankie McGuire is one of the IRA's deadliest assassins. But when he is sent to the U.S. to buy weapons, Frankie is housed with the family of Tom O'Meara, a New York cop who knows nothing about Frankie's real identity. Their surprising friendship, and Tom's growing suspicions, force Frankie to choose between the promise of peace or a lifetime of murder.
 </storyline>
 <generos>
  <genero>
   Crime
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Drama
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Thriller
  </genero>
 </generos>
 <keywords>
  <keyword>
   terrorist
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   murder
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   police
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   ireland
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   terrorism
  </keyword>
 </keywords>
 <diretores>
  <diretor>
   Alan J. Pakula
  </diretor>
 </diretores>
 <escritores>
  <escritor>
   Kevin Jarre
  </escritor>
  <escritor>
   David Aaron Cohen
  </escritor>
 </escritores>
 <atores>
  <ator>
   Harrison Ford
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Brad Pitt
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Margaret Colin
  </ator>
 </atores>
 <reviews>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The IRA Versus The NYPD
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    zardoz-13
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Harrison Ford & Brad Pitt terrorist thriller "The Devil's Own" features New York cops, British assassins, IRA gunmen, and examples of modern-day intimidation. Nevertheless, it remains as old-fashioned and predictable as any episode of the western television classic "Gunsmoke." Veteran filmmaker Alan J. Pakula, whose credits include "Presumed Innocent" (1990) and "The Pelican Brief" (1994), has crafted a serious, above-average, tight-lipped melodrama that buckles more often than it should but delivers an attractive cast in a handsome actioneer. "V.I. Warshawski" scribe David Aaron Cohen, and "Family Business" scenarist Vincent Patrick and "Tombstone" writer Kevin Jarre collaborated on a screenplay that constitutes sheer hokum of an inspirational sort. Although the film sports a laugh or two, "The Devil's Own" emerges as a dark, tragic saga that "Godfather" lenser Gordon Willis has enhanced with his moody Rembrandt lighting. Brad Pitt is suitably cast as an Irish Republican Army gunman named Rory Devaney. When he was a lad, Rory saw merciless British gunmen gun down his dad at the supper table. He still lives with this bitter memory. He has grown up and become a ruthless killer who the British are prepared to track the earth to liquidate. The ever dependable Harrison Ford shows up later as Tom O'Meara, an honest Irish-American career cop with a wife, Sheila O'Meara (Margaret Colin of "Independence Day") and two daughters. A highly situated IRA sympathizer smuggles Roy into New York City on fake passports and obtains room and board for him in O'Meara's happy domicile. Naturally, Tom doesn't have a clue about Roy's notorious identity. He believes Rory is a construction worker. What O'Meara learns in one devastating betrayal after another is that Rory has come to America to buy surface-to-air missiles to be used against the British. When Tom learns the truth and finds himself pitted against Rory, the reality of the predicament takes on a deeper meaning for him. Meanwhile, Rory encounters Billy Burke (Treat Williams of "Hair") and his bunch of ham-fisted thugs who don't share his dedication to the cause. They simply want their loot for the contraband missiles that they have purchased for Rory. Burke makes the fatal mistake of double-crossing Rory. Although we want to believe that all lawmen are as dedicated as Ford's Tom O'Meara, our hero here seems incredibly saintly, a reincarnation of Dodge City Marshall Matt Dillon for the 1990s who turns shoplifters loose after catching them red-handed with the goods. When our hero's partner Edwin Diaz (well played by Ruben Blades) shoots a thief who had discarded his gun, O'Meara refuses to lie on his behalf. Afterward, O'Meara confides to Sheila that he cannot go on being a cop because of the shooting incident. O'Meara possesses principles that are far beyond believable. If Pakula and company err in over sanctifying Ford's straightforward N.Y.P.D. cop, they miss the boat completely with Pitt's renegade gunsel. While he is battling it out with British troops in blood-splattered Ireland, the Rory Devaney character is appropriately vicious. Once he reaches America, Roy treads somewhere between a hard-bitten villain and a tragic victim who constantly cradles Ford's youngest daughter. All of which dilutes the visceral turbulence that the filmmakers do such a good job of stirring up but never resolving. Hollywood used to steer clear of hot-potato political issues, but "The Devil's Own" appears to weigh its scales of cinematic justice in favor of the underdog IRA. Indeed, this Columbia Pictures Release is a movie with an Irish ending. The British come off looking more villainous than anybody else. Happily, "The Devils' Own" is not the botched film that Pitt has proclaimed in the press. While the movie ripples with violence, the violence here is used to decide who is morally culpable in a less-than-perfect world. The strategy that the filmmakers used in the final shoot-out to get you to bite your fingernails is well-staged but hopelessly heavy-handed. Men will show up for the shoot-outs, especially in the early parts of the action, while women may find themselves swooning over Pitt and Ford. Ultimately, "The Devil's Own" is an entertaining but pretentious load of nonsense that looks terrific on the big screen.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    given the fear of terrorism today....
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    blanche-2
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    ..."The Devil's Own" from 1997 isn't a great film. Starring Harrison Ford, Brad Pitt, Treat Williams, Ruben Blades, and Margaret Colin, the story concerns a Northern Ireland IRA terrorist, Frankie McGuire, who comes to New York to buy weapons. Using the name of Rory Delaney, a judge, Peter Fitzsimmons puts him up at the home of an Irish cop, Tom O'Meara. O'Meara has no idea of Frankie's identity. Rory has brought a ton of money with him and is supposed to make a deal with one Billy Burke (Williams). When he is told by his superiors in Ireland to hold off, Burke gets tough and wants the money. When Tom's house is robbed, his wife held at gunpoint, but nothing taken, Tom begins to wonder about his houseguest. With good reason. Tom himself is having a crisis of conscience when he supports his partner Eddie (Blades) by lying about a shooting. This could have been an excellent film, as it's about two men with completely different moral codes, both believing they're right. Frankie saw his father killed in front of him when he was eight years old, and this started him on the road to killings. Tom has drawn his gun only a few times in all the years he's been a police officer. The problem is that this is muddied by the script being somewhat pro-terrorism. In today's climate, pro-terrorist films with sympathetic killers don't go over well. As someone pointed out, if this had been about someone from the Middle East partly responsible for 9/11 portrayed this way, it probably wouldn't be made. Brad Pitt does a good job, despite some of his accent problems. Harrison Ford is solid but a little boring. The ending was the best part. We don't hear much about the Irish conflict anymore, but years ago, many charities purportedly for Irish children were fronts for collecting money to support the IRA. My sister pointed this out to an Irish friend once, who was about to give such a charity some money, and she said, "So what?" So what? Terrorism isn't right, no matter which side resorts to it. It's understandable that Frankie/Rory had strong feelings, but there are other ways to deal with them. Kind of annoying.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not really very good
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jmorrison-2
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The initial problem I had with this film is the fact that an IRA soldier, in New York to buy and transport weapons to bring back to Ireland, would bunk in with an NYPD Sergeant and his family. That sounds like asking for trouble to me. Not a smart move. I can't imagine the IRA sanctioning a rather reckless move like this. The large amount of money Pitt's character was carrying, and the importance of these weapons making it to Ireland had me shaking my head in disbelief that Rory (Pitt's character) would take such a risk of trying to pull this off right under this police sergeant's nose. Some on this site have complained about Brad Pitt's Irish accent, however I thought Pitt was easily the best part of this film. He succeeded in creating a troubled, but somewhat sympathetic character. It is his performance that I even gave this film a 4. Treat Williams was also very good as the mean, black-hearted weapons contact for Pitt's character in New York. I had enormous problems with Harrison Ford's efforts in this movie, if "efforts" is the right word. When Ford first burst on to the scene many years ago, he looked like a solid, creative acting talent. However, in recent years, he has taken on this goody-goody, moralistic, cutesy-pie, boy scout character style which he seems to hide behind, and it's just ridiculous, and reflects really lazy acting (see: "Air Force One" and "Patriot Games", to name two). It is truly irritating and disappointing, and brought this movie way down in my view. I had trouble swallowing the premise, but Ford's performance just made this cringe-inducing to me.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Cast Saves The Film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    SiliconDesertMan40
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/12/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A movie about Irishmen,The Devil's Own is an action thriller that stars Harrison Ford and Brad Pitt together with Rub&eacute;n Blades, Natascha McElhone, Julia Stiles and Treat Williams.This is about a policeman plays Good Samaritan to a visitor from Ireland, only to discover that he has a potentially deadly secret.This was the final film directed by Alan J. Pakula. Belfast-born Frankie McGuire saw his father gunned down by enemy soldiers at the age of eight, and when he grew up he joined the Irish Republican Army, determined that one day his father's death would be avenged. An especially ruthless "volunteer," Frankie is responsible for the death of 13 British soldiers and 11 policemen. After a particularly bloody battle, Frankie sails to the United States in a ragged tugboat he has restored; with a huge bundle of cash, Frankie intends to buy a stock of Stinger missiles from an underground arms dealer in America, Billy Burke. Upon arrival in New York, Frankie is met by a judge who is sympathetic to the IRA's cause and who arranges a place for him to stay. Using the name Rory Devaney, Frankie moves into the home of Tom O'Meara, a scrupulously honest cop. Tom is already in the midst of a personal crisis; his friend and partner Edwin Diaz recently shot a man that he knew was unarmed in the line of duty, and while Edwin wants Tom to help him cover up the matter, Tom's conscience will not allow it. When Tom begins to realize that "Rory" is not simply a man running from the violence of his homeland, he's torn between his sympathy for Frankie's tragic childhood and his desire to see justice served and prevent needless death in Ireland. Although it was it showed ignorance of the history of Northern Ireland and the issues involved are never mentioned,it becomes watchable to a degree due to the presence of Harrison Ford and Brad Pitt.Also,the story was somewhat formulaic,contrived and predictable. With Ford and Pitt,it would have been a disaster.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Hollywood Movie about the IRA
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    david-sarkies
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/12/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    When looking at this movie through the advertisements it sounds like an action movie where a cop (Harrison Ford) is chasing some murderous psychopath (Brad Pitt); that was the impression that I got, and the title doesn't really help that much either for it makes Pitt's character sound like some really evil and sadistic man. He is not. This movie is based around the IRA activities in Ireland and the main character is Brad Pitt. The entire movie is centered around him. The basic plot is that the British are gaining the upper hand because they have helicopters so Pitt must go over to the United States and smuggle some stinger missiles back into Northern Ireland to deal with it. The movie opens with Pitt's father being murdered and then moves to the present day where his character is being hunted down by the British. This quickly dissolves into a huge gun battle in the middle of Belfast where the British are basically using force of numbers to suppress the situation, and even then they fail to achieve their goal. The bulk of the movie takes place in the United States and has very little action. It revolves around Pitt arranging the deal. Unfortunately things go slightly wrong and the deal has to be postponed, which upsets the crime lord who is arranging it no end. There is very little in the way of constant pursuit between Harrison Ford and Brad Pitt. In most cases they are friends, though Ford is ignorant of the true nature of Pitt's character. It is only when the crime lord starts putting pressure onto Pitt that things start happening. When they do, the viewer (or at least myself) starts to have sympathy for Pitt. He is not an evil man, he is just a soldier fighting a war. There is a struggle between him and Ford for we like both but we know that they cannot help each other. The real enemy, and even Ford sees this, is the British. Even Harrison Ford has sympathy for Pitt's character by the end of the movie. The Devil's Own is neither a fast movie nor is it an action movie. The video labels it as a thriller but even then I didn't think much of that. It is hard to put it into a category. If you are looking for a fast action movie, then look for something else. Even though, I still liked this movie and thought that the character development was in itself quite good.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I Could Only Long to be Put Through More "Troubled Productions" Like This One.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jzappa
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/10/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Justice is the summation of all ethical responsibility, but there are conflicting slants on justice. This reality is at the heart of this ignorantly underrated and dismissed film, which meets just gently with The Troubles. Rather, it searches the sad natural history of violence and how individual and social variables shape our slants on it. This is a film of various different tensions in which nobody is unreservedly right or wrong. Characteristic of Pakula's films, The Devil's Own has a solemn, subdued atmosphere that mutely connotes magnitude and seriousness. Cinematographer Gordon Willis' inimitable use of light and dark is especially effective in a scene where Tom and Rory are caught in the sporadic lights of moving cars, a pertinent image for a story in which honor's moorland is so transitory. An Irish-American judge coordinates for Rory Devaney, an Irish rebel, to lodge in the suburban home of NYC police sergeant Tom O'Meara. This upright cop, his wife and their daughters haven't a clue as to Rory's real identity. While Rory is occupied obtaining Stinger missiles from Treat Williams' American gang boss, Rory discovers himself emotionally enticed by his host family's life. He hasn't known this sense of comfort and peace since childhood before his father was slain before his eyes by a British agent. As the arms deal plods on, ample time is left for the two men to connect, and for Rory to feel remorse facing Tom's morality and virtual pacifism. Meanwhile, Tom confronts the prime predicament of his career when his partner Ruben Blades shoots an unarmed offender in the back and then presumes upon him to suppress it. Tom chooses to retire. But before he can submit his badge, he's dragged into Rory's nightmare when it invades and terrorizes his home. Pitt and Ford give moving and realistic performances as two men whose fanatical dedication to justice puts them on a path to conflict. Instead of stressing epinephrine-boosting action sequences, Pakula fixes the film on the ethical clash between the resistance fighter and the unfaltering advocate of law and order. The action sequences are intermittent but vigorously ringing, with a premium put on the enduring formation of character. At an early stage of their growing personal rapport, Rory tells Tom, "Don't look for a happy ending. It's not an American story. It's an Irish one." The two actors have remarkable pull on one another. When they're together on screen, you want to focus on both of them. They don't seek to trump one another, but to enforce one another's sincerity. The Devil's Own unmistakably seeks to build a father-son histrionic between Tom who has no sons and Rory, and it succeeds mainly since it never labors overmuch to labor on emphasis. Their relationship is relaxed and unaffected. A game of pool here, a snippet of conversation there. And Pakula counts on the actors to create a bond without turning to banal dialogue or unseemly bursts of emotion. These are two understated, strong-minded men who just appear to admire and enjoy one another. And when Pitt turns unreservedly cold-blooded when he's forced into a corner, Pitt gives him the disillusionment of a guy who can't meet the expense of a conscience. This point is that it's unfeasible to choose sides, a point distinctive for a Hollywood film, a battle between people whose virtues were decided by their circumstances. Naysayers called the plot incoherent, just a lot of moral grappling, not all of which relevant. Funny how they didn't say that about the character of Mike Yanagita in Fargo, for instance. It's as if it was new to critics that emotional associations with the plot we care about could be made by characters whose experiences outside that main plot course it's important we see first-hand with them to grasp their ethical arcs.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Bad assessment of this movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Editingwhiz
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/9/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The lead review of this movie is vastly unfair. Just because it is written by some one from Belfast who professes to know it all about such topics doesn't mean what he says is relevant for everybody. The fact is that there are interesting relationships between the characters here, you feel empathy for the terrorist character (Brad Pitt), and you feel the pain of Harrison Ford's NYC cop when he partner is killed. The FBI and BI people are in the movie for about 3 minutes -- how can any conclusions be drawn about them? I personally thought it was a tight thriller and it kept my interest the whole time. Ford and Pitt were excellent in their roles. Pitt, despite what the other bloke said, kept his accent quite well throughout. I am a journalist who looks objectively at such things as film and entertainment, I just thought the top review sold this movie way way short.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Hypothetical and Moral Imperatives.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Robert J. Maxwell (rmax304823@yahoo.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/8/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Reuben Blades is the good-natured but fallible cop who is the friend and partner of officer Harrison Ford on the NYPD. The minute he showed up on screen I figured he was toast. The instrument of Blades' demise is Brad Pitt. Pitt is an IRA agent visiting the US to buy some guns and rockets from the ruthless entrepreneur Treat Williams. Pitt is a nice-looking, clean-shaven young man who finds room and board with Ford's accommodating family. Pitt, harboring a pustular hatred because of some politically caused childhood trauma, is gradually drawn into the peaceful life of Ford's household. They have a couple of lovely kids, say grace before meals, go to the same church as Pitt. They're Irish-American too. The only thing is that they haven't witnessed the suffering that Pitt has on the Auld Sod. It's really Pitt's movie. Harrison Ford cheats a little to save his partner's pension but is otherwise stalwart in upholding the law. Pitt, on the other hand, becomes a man of divided allegiances. He admires and respects Ford and his life style. He doesn't want the family to get into trouble. Yet here is Pitt, hiding a fortune in dollars under the floor of Ford's bathroom, about to buy guns so that the killing in Ireland can go on. The moral act, the moral imperative, is to reject the killing and embrace the warmth of family life. The hypothetical imperative is to complete his mission, smuggle the guns back into Ireland, and garner the accolades that are earned by heroes of the movement. That's not a moral act but it lays out what's in it for Pitt. I don't really want to get into it, partly because Immanuel Kant is complicated, partly because space is limited, and partly because I'm not sure I know what the hell I'm talking about. But my understanding is that you can determine whether a course is moral or not by asking what would happen if everyone followed it. Obviously, in this instance, the bloodshed in Ireland stops if Pitt overcomes his personal desire for revenge and stops shedding blood. The conflict and the final shoot out -- among several violent shoot outs -- is inevitable. And the confrontation involves more than just an uptight cop and a reckless revolutionary. The writers, of course, don't want to alienate those Irish-American viewers who are in thrall to what sociologists have called "the new ethnicity" -- a fiercely sentimental attachment to origins they know little about -- so they have Pitt explain (twice) that, "It's not an American problem; it's an Irish problem." Whatever that means. As Ford's wife, Margaret Colin is pretty and nurturing looking. Ford himself, looking old enough to have spent twenty-four years on the police force, isn't any more expressive than he usually is. He's not a bravura performer. He's reliable. Brad Pitt gives an absorbing and likable performance -- a quiet, appreciative, thoughtful, reckless revolutionary maniac -- who brings some unexpected touches to the role. He has more range than I'd been giving him credit for, although he can still turn in a wincingly wrong performance, as in "Seven." I've always admired Treat Williams's performances in a low-key way. He's been pretty good in some roles, like "Prince of the City," but I think his career has been knee-capped by his having a voice that isn't strong, and that sounds so natural that it seems he's not really able to enact a role.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I liked this movie!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    allwrangledup
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/6/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I won't argue some of the criticisms that I'm reading in other people's reviews here -- but I really liked this movie. I thought that Pitt and Harrison (and most of the others)did some solid acting in this movie. And I actually thought the accents were pretty decent! The action scenes may not have been entirely plausible, but they still worked overall. I liked the relationship storyline/s, and the fact that not everything was perfect. And it wasn't all predictable. Good movie overall. I would recommend it. I like action movies, I also like good "people" story lines. I thought this movie contained both. Like a good, easily readable book.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    All the same, Mr. Fitzsimmoms, if you're not confused, you don't know what's going' on.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    lastliberal
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/4/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It amazes me that people look at every film about political situations as if they should be documentaries. This is a film about the relationship between a New York cop (Harrison Ford), and an IRA terrorist (Brad Pitt) in the US to pick up weapons. It is not meant to be a polemic on the Irish situation. Ford plays a cop that cares about the law and about justice. His partner (Rub&eacute;n Blades) shoots an unarmed teen and Ford actually is the one who gets sick. "We are in the police business, not the revenge business," he tells him. Despite the fact that he has killed 20 men, Pitt comes off as his most lovable self. He fits in well with Ford's family. Things fall apart after the weapons deal is delayed and that's when the real action starts. Ford and Pitt were brilliant, although I hated the ending.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The IRA Versus The NYPD
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    zardoz-13
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Harrison Ford & Brad Pitt terrorist thriller "The Devil's Own" features New York cops, British assassins, IRA gunmen, and examples of modern-day intimidation. Nevertheless, it remains as old-fashioned and predictable as any episode of the western television classic "Gunsmoke." Veteran filmmaker Alan J. Pakula, whose credits include "Presumed Innocent" (1990) and "The Pelican Brief" (1994), has crafted a serious, above-average, tight-lipped melodrama that buckles more often than it should but delivers an attractive cast in a handsome actioneer. "V.I. Warshawski" scribe David Aaron Cohen, and "Family Business" scenarist Vincent Patrick and "Tombstone" writer Kevin Jarre collaborated on a screenplay that constitutes sheer hokum of an inspirational sort. Although the film sports a laugh or two, "The Devil's Own" emerges as a dark, tragic saga that "Godfather" lenser Gordon Willis has enhanced with his moody Rembrandt lighting. Brad Pitt is suitably cast as an Irish Republican Army gunman named Rory Devaney. When he was a lad, Rory saw merciless British gunmen gun down his dad at the supper table. He still lives with this bitter memory. He has grown up and become a ruthless killer who the British are prepared to track the earth to liquidate. The ever dependable Harrison Ford shows up later as Tom O'Meara, an honest Irish-American career cop with a wife, Sheila O'Meara (Margaret Colin of "Independence Day") and two daughters. A highly situated IRA sympathizer smuggles Roy into New York City on fake passports and obtains room and board for him in O'Meara's happy domicile. Naturally, Tom doesn't have a clue about Roy's notorious identity. He believes Rory is a construction worker. What O'Meara learns in one devastating betrayal after another is that Rory has come to America to buy surface-to-air missiles to be used against the British. When Tom learns the truth and finds himself pitted against Rory, the reality of the predicament takes on a deeper meaning for him. Meanwhile, Rory encounters Billy Burke (Treat Williams of "Hair") and his bunch of ham-fisted thugs who don't share his dedication to the cause. They simply want their loot for the contraband missiles that they have purchased for Rory. Burke makes the fatal mistake of double-crossing Rory. Although we want to believe that all lawmen are as dedicated as Ford's Tom O'Meara, our hero here seems incredibly saintly, a reincarnation of Dodge City Marshall Matt Dillon for the 1990s who turns shoplifters loose after catching them red-handed with the goods. When our hero's partner Edwin Diaz (well played by Ruben Blades) shoots a thief who had discarded his gun, O'Meara refuses to lie on his behalf. Afterward, O'Meara confides to Sheila that he cannot go on being a cop because of the shooting incident. O'Meara possesses principles that are far beyond believable. If Pakula and company err in over sanctifying Ford's straightforward N.Y.P.D. cop, they miss the boat completely with Pitt's renegade gunsel. While he is battling it out with British troops in blood-splattered Ireland, the Rory Devaney character is appropriately vicious. Once he reaches America, Roy treads somewhere between a hard-bitten villain and a tragic victim who constantly cradles Ford's youngest daughter. All of which dilutes the visceral turbulence that the filmmakers do such a good job of stirring up but never resolving. Hollywood used to steer clear of hot-potato political issues, but "The Devil's Own" appears to weigh its scales of cinematic justice in favor of the underdog IRA. Indeed, this Columbia Pictures Release is a movie with an Irish ending. The British come off looking more villainous than anybody else. Happily, "The Devils' Own" is not the botched film that Pitt has proclaimed in the press. While the movie ripples with violence, the violence here is used to decide who is morally culpable in a less-than-perfect world. The strategy that the filmmakers used in the final shoot-out to get you to bite your fingernails is well-staged but hopelessly heavy-handed. Men will show up for the shoot-outs, especially in the early parts of the action, while women may find themselves swooning over Pitt and Ford. Ultimately, "The Devil's Own" is an entertaining but pretentious load of nonsense that looks terrific on the big screen.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    given the fear of terrorism today....
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    blanche-2
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    ..."The Devil's Own" from 1997 isn't a great film. Starring Harrison Ford, Brad Pitt, Treat Williams, Ruben Blades, and Margaret Colin, the story concerns a Northern Ireland IRA terrorist, Frankie McGuire, who comes to New York to buy weapons. Using the name of Rory Delaney, a judge, Peter Fitzsimmons puts him up at the home of an Irish cop, Tom O'Meara. O'Meara has no idea of Frankie's identity. Rory has brought a ton of money with him and is supposed to make a deal with one Billy Burke (Williams). When he is told by his superiors in Ireland to hold off, Burke gets tough and wants the money. When Tom's house is robbed, his wife held at gunpoint, but nothing taken, Tom begins to wonder about his houseguest. With good reason. Tom himself is having a crisis of conscience when he supports his partner Eddie (Blades) by lying about a shooting. This could have been an excellent film, as it's about two men with completely different moral codes, both believing they're right. Frankie saw his father killed in front of him when he was eight years old, and this started him on the road to killings. Tom has drawn his gun only a few times in all the years he's been a police officer. The problem is that this is muddied by the script being somewhat pro-terrorism. In today's climate, pro-terrorist films with sympathetic killers don't go over well. As someone pointed out, if this had been about someone from the Middle East partly responsible for 9/11 portrayed this way, it probably wouldn't be made. Brad Pitt does a good job, despite some of his accent problems. Harrison Ford is solid but a little boring. The ending was the best part. We don't hear much about the Irish conflict anymore, but years ago, many charities purportedly for Irish children were fronts for collecting money to support the IRA. My sister pointed this out to an Irish friend once, who was about to give such a charity some money, and she said, "So what?" So what? Terrorism isn't right, no matter which side resorts to it. It's understandable that Frankie/Rory had strong feelings, but there are other ways to deal with them. Kind of annoying.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not really very good
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jmorrison-2
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The initial problem I had with this film is the fact that an IRA soldier, in New York to buy and transport weapons to bring back to Ireland, would bunk in with an NYPD Sergeant and his family. That sounds like asking for trouble to me. Not a smart move. I can't imagine the IRA sanctioning a rather reckless move like this. The large amount of money Pitt's character was carrying, and the importance of these weapons making it to Ireland had me shaking my head in disbelief that Rory (Pitt's character) would take such a risk of trying to pull this off right under this police sergeant's nose. Some on this site have complained about Brad Pitt's Irish accent, however I thought Pitt was easily the best part of this film. He succeeded in creating a troubled, but somewhat sympathetic character. It is his performance that I even gave this film a 4. Treat Williams was also very good as the mean, black-hearted weapons contact for Pitt's character in New York. I had enormous problems with Harrison Ford's efforts in this movie, if "efforts" is the right word. When Ford first burst on to the scene many years ago, he looked like a solid, creative acting talent. However, in recent years, he has taken on this goody-goody, moralistic, cutesy-pie, boy scout character style which he seems to hide behind, and it's just ridiculous, and reflects really lazy acting (see: "Air Force One" and "Patriot Games", to name two). It is truly irritating and disappointing, and brought this movie way down in my view. I had trouble swallowing the premise, but Ford's performance just made this cringe-inducing to me.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Cast Saves The Film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    SiliconDesertMan40
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/12/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A movie about Irishmen,The Devil's Own is an action thriller that stars Harrison Ford and Brad Pitt together with Rub&eacute;n Blades, Natascha McElhone, Julia Stiles and Treat Williams.This is about a policeman plays Good Samaritan to a visitor from Ireland, only to discover that he has a potentially deadly secret.This was the final film directed by Alan J. Pakula. Belfast-born Frankie McGuire saw his father gunned down by enemy soldiers at the age of eight, and when he grew up he joined the Irish Republican Army, determined that one day his father's death would be avenged. An especially ruthless "volunteer," Frankie is responsible for the death of 13 British soldiers and 11 policemen. After a particularly bloody battle, Frankie sails to the United States in a ragged tugboat he has restored; with a huge bundle of cash, Frankie intends to buy a stock of Stinger missiles from an underground arms dealer in America, Billy Burke. Upon arrival in New York, Frankie is met by a judge who is sympathetic to the IRA's cause and who arranges a place for him to stay. Using the name Rory Devaney, Frankie moves into the home of Tom O'Meara, a scrupulously honest cop. Tom is already in the midst of a personal crisis; his friend and partner Edwin Diaz recently shot a man that he knew was unarmed in the line of duty, and while Edwin wants Tom to help him cover up the matter, Tom's conscience will not allow it. When Tom begins to realize that "Rory" is not simply a man running from the violence of his homeland, he's torn between his sympathy for Frankie's tragic childhood and his desire to see justice served and prevent needless death in Ireland. Although it was it showed ignorance of the history of Northern Ireland and the issues involved are never mentioned,it becomes watchable to a degree due to the presence of Harrison Ford and Brad Pitt.Also,the story was somewhat formulaic,contrived and predictable. With Ford and Pitt,it would have been a disaster.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Hollywood Movie about the IRA
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    david-sarkies
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/12/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    When looking at this movie through the advertisements it sounds like an action movie where a cop (Harrison Ford) is chasing some murderous psychopath (Brad Pitt); that was the impression that I got, and the title doesn't really help that much either for it makes Pitt's character sound like some really evil and sadistic man. He is not. This movie is based around the IRA activities in Ireland and the main character is Brad Pitt. The entire movie is centered around him. The basic plot is that the British are gaining the upper hand because they have helicopters so Pitt must go over to the United States and smuggle some stinger missiles back into Northern Ireland to deal with it. The movie opens with Pitt's father being murdered and then moves to the present day where his character is being hunted down by the British. This quickly dissolves into a huge gun battle in the middle of Belfast where the British are basically using force of numbers to suppress the situation, and even then they fail to achieve their goal. The bulk of the movie takes place in the United States and has very little action. It revolves around Pitt arranging the deal. Unfortunately things go slightly wrong and the deal has to be postponed, which upsets the crime lord who is arranging it no end. There is very little in the way of constant pursuit between Harrison Ford and Brad Pitt. In most cases they are friends, though Ford is ignorant of the true nature of Pitt's character. It is only when the crime lord starts putting pressure onto Pitt that things start happening. When they do, the viewer (or at least myself) starts to have sympathy for Pitt. He is not an evil man, he is just a soldier fighting a war. There is a struggle between him and Ford for we like both but we know that they cannot help each other. The real enemy, and even Ford sees this, is the British. Even Harrison Ford has sympathy for Pitt's character by the end of the movie. The Devil's Own is neither a fast movie nor is it an action movie. The video labels it as a thriller but even then I didn't think much of that. It is hard to put it into a category. If you are looking for a fast action movie, then look for something else. Even though, I still liked this movie and thought that the character development was in itself quite good.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I Could Only Long to be Put Through More "Troubled Productions" Like This One.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jzappa
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/10/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Justice is the summation of all ethical responsibility, but there are conflicting slants on justice. This reality is at the heart of this ignorantly underrated and dismissed film, which meets just gently with The Troubles. Rather, it searches the sad natural history of violence and how individual and social variables shape our slants on it. This is a film of various different tensions in which nobody is unreservedly right or wrong. Characteristic of Pakula's films, The Devil's Own has a solemn, subdued atmosphere that mutely connotes magnitude and seriousness. Cinematographer Gordon Willis' inimitable use of light and dark is especially effective in a scene where Tom and Rory are caught in the sporadic lights of moving cars, a pertinent image for a story in which honor's moorland is so transitory. An Irish-American judge coordinates for Rory Devaney, an Irish rebel, to lodge in the suburban home of NYC police sergeant Tom O'Meara. This upright cop, his wife and their daughters haven't a clue as to Rory's real identity. While Rory is occupied obtaining Stinger missiles from Treat Williams' American gang boss, Rory discovers himself emotionally enticed by his host family's life. He hasn't known this sense of comfort and peace since childhood before his father was slain before his eyes by a British agent. As the arms deal plods on, ample time is left for the two men to connect, and for Rory to feel remorse facing Tom's morality and virtual pacifism. Meanwhile, Tom confronts the prime predicament of his career when his partner Ruben Blades shoots an unarmed offender in the back and then presumes upon him to suppress it. Tom chooses to retire. But before he can submit his badge, he's dragged into Rory's nightmare when it invades and terrorizes his home. Pitt and Ford give moving and realistic performances as two men whose fanatical dedication to justice puts them on a path to conflict. Instead of stressing epinephrine-boosting action sequences, Pakula fixes the film on the ethical clash between the resistance fighter and the unfaltering advocate of law and order. The action sequences are intermittent but vigorously ringing, with a premium put on the enduring formation of character. At an early stage of their growing personal rapport, Rory tells Tom, "Don't look for a happy ending. It's not an American story. It's an Irish one." The two actors have remarkable pull on one another. When they're together on screen, you want to focus on both of them. They don't seek to trump one another, but to enforce one another's sincerity. The Devil's Own unmistakably seeks to build a father-son histrionic between Tom who has no sons and Rory, and it succeeds mainly since it never labors overmuch to labor on emphasis. Their relationship is relaxed and unaffected. A game of pool here, a snippet of conversation there. And Pakula counts on the actors to create a bond without turning to banal dialogue or unseemly bursts of emotion. These are two understated, strong-minded men who just appear to admire and enjoy one another. And when Pitt turns unreservedly cold-blooded when he's forced into a corner, Pitt gives him the disillusionment of a guy who can't meet the expense of a conscience. This point is that it's unfeasible to choose sides, a point distinctive for a Hollywood film, a battle between people whose virtues were decided by their circumstances. Naysayers called the plot incoherent, just a lot of moral grappling, not all of which relevant. Funny how they didn't say that about the character of Mike Yanagita in Fargo, for instance. It's as if it was new to critics that emotional associations with the plot we care about could be made by characters whose experiences outside that main plot course it's important we see first-hand with them to grasp their ethical arcs.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Bad assessment of this movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Editingwhiz
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/9/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The lead review of this movie is vastly unfair. Just because it is written by some one from Belfast who professes to know it all about such topics doesn't mean what he says is relevant for everybody. The fact is that there are interesting relationships between the characters here, you feel empathy for the terrorist character (Brad Pitt), and you feel the pain of Harrison Ford's NYC cop when he partner is killed. The FBI and BI people are in the movie for about 3 minutes -- how can any conclusions be drawn about them? I personally thought it was a tight thriller and it kept my interest the whole time. Ford and Pitt were excellent in their roles. Pitt, despite what the other bloke said, kept his accent quite well throughout. I am a journalist who looks objectively at such things as film and entertainment, I just thought the top review sold this movie way way short.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Hypothetical and Moral Imperatives.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Robert J. Maxwell (rmax304823@yahoo.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/8/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Reuben Blades is the good-natured but fallible cop who is the friend and partner of officer Harrison Ford on the NYPD. The minute he showed up on screen I figured he was toast. The instrument of Blades' demise is Brad Pitt. Pitt is an IRA agent visiting the US to buy some guns and rockets from the ruthless entrepreneur Treat Williams. Pitt is a nice-looking, clean-shaven young man who finds room and board with Ford's accommodating family. Pitt, harboring a pustular hatred because of some politically caused childhood trauma, is gradually drawn into the peaceful life of Ford's household. They have a couple of lovely kids, say grace before meals, go to the same church as Pitt. They're Irish-American too. The only thing is that they haven't witnessed the suffering that Pitt has on the Auld Sod. It's really Pitt's movie. Harrison Ford cheats a little to save his partner's pension but is otherwise stalwart in upholding the law. Pitt, on the other hand, becomes a man of divided allegiances. He admires and respects Ford and his life style. He doesn't want the family to get into trouble. Yet here is Pitt, hiding a fortune in dollars under the floor of Ford's bathroom, about to buy guns so that the killing in Ireland can go on. The moral act, the moral imperative, is to reject the killing and embrace the warmth of family life. The hypothetical imperative is to complete his mission, smuggle the guns back into Ireland, and garner the accolades that are earned by heroes of the movement. That's not a moral act but it lays out what's in it for Pitt. I don't really want to get into it, partly because Immanuel Kant is complicated, partly because space is limited, and partly because I'm not sure I know what the hell I'm talking about. But my understanding is that you can determine whether a course is moral or not by asking what would happen if everyone followed it. Obviously, in this instance, the bloodshed in Ireland stops if Pitt overcomes his personal desire for revenge and stops shedding blood. The conflict and the final shoot out -- among several violent shoot outs -- is inevitable. And the confrontation involves more than just an uptight cop and a reckless revolutionary. The writers, of course, don't want to alienate those Irish-American viewers who are in thrall to what sociologists have called "the new ethnicity" -- a fiercely sentimental attachment to origins they know little about -- so they have Pitt explain (twice) that, "It's not an American problem; it's an Irish problem." Whatever that means. As Ford's wife, Margaret Colin is pretty and nurturing looking. Ford himself, looking old enough to have spent twenty-four years on the police force, isn't any more expressive than he usually is. He's not a bravura performer. He's reliable. Brad Pitt gives an absorbing and likable performance -- a quiet, appreciative, thoughtful, reckless revolutionary maniac -- who brings some unexpected touches to the role. He has more range than I'd been giving him credit for, although he can still turn in a wincingly wrong performance, as in "Seven." I've always admired Treat Williams's performances in a low-key way. He's been pretty good in some roles, like "Prince of the City," but I think his career has been knee-capped by his having a voice that isn't strong, and that sounds so natural that it seems he's not really able to enact a role.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I liked this movie!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    allwrangledup
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/6/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I won't argue some of the criticisms that I'm reading in other people's reviews here -- but I really liked this movie. I thought that Pitt and Harrison (and most of the others)did some solid acting in this movie. And I actually thought the accents were pretty decent! The action scenes may not have been entirely plausible, but they still worked overall. I liked the relationship storyline/s, and the fact that not everything was perfect. And it wasn't all predictable. Good movie overall. I would recommend it. I like action movies, I also like good "people" story lines. I thought this movie contained both. Like a good, easily readable book.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    All the same, Mr. Fitzsimmoms, if you're not confused, you don't know what's going' on.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    lastliberal
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/4/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It amazes me that people look at every film about political situations as if they should be documentaries. This is a film about the relationship between a New York cop (Harrison Ford), and an IRA terrorist (Brad Pitt) in the US to pick up weapons. It is not meant to be a polemic on the Irish situation. Ford plays a cop that cares about the law and about justice. His partner (Rub&eacute;n Blades) shoots an unarmed teen and Ford actually is the one who gets sick. "We are in the police business, not the revenge business," he tells him. Despite the fact that he has killed 20 men, Pitt comes off as his most lovable self. He fits in well with Ford's family. Things fall apart after the weapons deal is delayed and that's when the real action starts. Ford and Pitt were brilliant, although I hated the ending.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The IRA Versus The NYPD
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    zardoz-13
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Harrison Ford & Brad Pitt terrorist thriller "The Devil's Own" features New York cops, British assassins, IRA gunmen, and examples of modern-day intimidation. Nevertheless, it remains as old-fashioned and predictable as any episode of the western television classic "Gunsmoke." Veteran filmmaker Alan J. Pakula, whose credits include "Presumed Innocent" (1990) and "The Pelican Brief" (1994), has crafted a serious, above-average, tight-lipped melodrama that buckles more often than it should but delivers an attractive cast in a handsome actioneer. "V.I. Warshawski" scribe David Aaron Cohen, and "Family Business" scenarist Vincent Patrick and "Tombstone" writer Kevin Jarre collaborated on a screenplay that constitutes sheer hokum of an inspirational sort. Although the film sports a laugh or two, "The Devil's Own" emerges as a dark, tragic saga that "Godfather" lenser Gordon Willis has enhanced with his moody Rembrandt lighting. Brad Pitt is suitably cast as an Irish Republican Army gunman named Rory Devaney. When he was a lad, Rory saw merciless British gunmen gun down his dad at the supper table. He still lives with this bitter memory. He has grown up and become a ruthless killer who the British are prepared to track the earth to liquidate. The ever dependable Harrison Ford shows up later as Tom O'Meara, an honest Irish-American career cop with a wife, Sheila O'Meara (Margaret Colin of "Independence Day") and two daughters. A highly situated IRA sympathizer smuggles Roy into New York City on fake passports and obtains room and board for him in O'Meara's happy domicile. Naturally, Tom doesn't have a clue about Roy's notorious identity. He believes Rory is a construction worker. What O'Meara learns in one devastating betrayal after another is that Rory has come to America to buy surface-to-air missiles to be used against the British. When Tom learns the truth and finds himself pitted against Rory, the reality of the predicament takes on a deeper meaning for him. Meanwhile, Rory encounters Billy Burke (Treat Williams of "Hair") and his bunch of ham-fisted thugs who don't share his dedication to the cause. They simply want their loot for the contraband missiles that they have purchased for Rory. Burke makes the fatal mistake of double-crossing Rory. Although we want to believe that all lawmen are as dedicated as Ford's Tom O'Meara, our hero here seems incredibly saintly, a reincarnation of Dodge City Marshall Matt Dillon for the 1990s who turns shoplifters loose after catching them red-handed with the goods. When our hero's partner Edwin Diaz (well played by Ruben Blades) shoots a thief who had discarded his gun, O'Meara refuses to lie on his behalf. Afterward, O'Meara confides to Sheila that he cannot go on being a cop because of the shooting incident. O'Meara possesses principles that are far beyond believable. If Pakula and company err in over sanctifying Ford's straightforward N.Y.P.D. cop, they miss the boat completely with Pitt's renegade gunsel. While he is battling it out with British troops in blood-splattered Ireland, the Rory Devaney character is appropriately vicious. Once he reaches America, Roy treads somewhere between a hard-bitten villain and a tragic victim who constantly cradles Ford's youngest daughter. All of which dilutes the visceral turbulence that the filmmakers do such a good job of stirring up but never resolving. Hollywood used to steer clear of hot-potato political issues, but "The Devil's Own" appears to weigh its scales of cinematic justice in favor of the underdog IRA. Indeed, this Columbia Pictures Release is a movie with an Irish ending. The British come off looking more villainous than anybody else. Happily, "The Devils' Own" is not the botched film that Pitt has proclaimed in the press. While the movie ripples with violence, the violence here is used to decide who is morally culpable in a less-than-perfect world. The strategy that the filmmakers used in the final shoot-out to get you to bite your fingernails is well-staged but hopelessly heavy-handed. Men will show up for the shoot-outs, especially in the early parts of the action, while women may find themselves swooning over Pitt and Ford. Ultimately, "The Devil's Own" is an entertaining but pretentious load of nonsense that looks terrific on the big screen.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    given the fear of terrorism today....
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    blanche-2
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    ..."The Devil's Own" from 1997 isn't a great film. Starring Harrison Ford, Brad Pitt, Treat Williams, Ruben Blades, and Margaret Colin, the story concerns a Northern Ireland IRA terrorist, Frankie McGuire, who comes to New York to buy weapons. Using the name of Rory Delaney, a judge, Peter Fitzsimmons puts him up at the home of an Irish cop, Tom O'Meara. O'Meara has no idea of Frankie's identity. Rory has brought a ton of money with him and is supposed to make a deal with one Billy Burke (Williams). When he is told by his superiors in Ireland to hold off, Burke gets tough and wants the money. When Tom's house is robbed, his wife held at gunpoint, but nothing taken, Tom begins to wonder about his houseguest. With good reason. Tom himself is having a crisis of conscience when he supports his partner Eddie (Blades) by lying about a shooting. This could have been an excellent film, as it's about two men with completely different moral codes, both believing they're right. Frankie saw his father killed in front of him when he was eight years old, and this started him on the road to killings. Tom has drawn his gun only a few times in all the years he's been a police officer. The problem is that this is muddied by the script being somewhat pro-terrorism. In today's climate, pro-terrorist films with sympathetic killers don't go over well. As someone pointed out, if this had been about someone from the Middle East partly responsible for 9/11 portrayed this way, it probably wouldn't be made. Brad Pitt does a good job, despite some of his accent problems. Harrison Ford is solid but a little boring. The ending was the best part. We don't hear much about the Irish conflict anymore, but years ago, many charities purportedly for Irish children were fronts for collecting money to support the IRA. My sister pointed this out to an Irish friend once, who was about to give such a charity some money, and she said, "So what?" So what? Terrorism isn't right, no matter which side resorts to it. It's understandable that Frankie/Rory had strong feelings, but there are other ways to deal with them. Kind of annoying.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not really very good
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jmorrison-2
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The initial problem I had with this film is the fact that an IRA soldier, in New York to buy and transport weapons to bring back to Ireland, would bunk in with an NYPD Sergeant and his family. That sounds like asking for trouble to me. Not a smart move. I can't imagine the IRA sanctioning a rather reckless move like this. The large amount of money Pitt's character was carrying, and the importance of these weapons making it to Ireland had me shaking my head in disbelief that Rory (Pitt's character) would take such a risk of trying to pull this off right under this police sergeant's nose. Some on this site have complained about Brad Pitt's Irish accent, however I thought Pitt was easily the best part of this film. He succeeded in creating a troubled, but somewhat sympathetic character. It is his performance that I even gave this film a 4. Treat Williams was also very good as the mean, black-hearted weapons contact for Pitt's character in New York. I had enormous problems with Harrison Ford's efforts in this movie, if "efforts" is the right word. When Ford first burst on to the scene many years ago, he looked like a solid, creative acting talent. However, in recent years, he has taken on this goody-goody, moralistic, cutesy-pie, boy scout character style which he seems to hide behind, and it's just ridiculous, and reflects really lazy acting (see: "Air Force One" and "Patriot Games", to name two). It is truly irritating and disappointing, and brought this movie way down in my view. I had trouble swallowing the premise, but Ford's performance just made this cringe-inducing to me.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Cast Saves The Film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    SiliconDesertMan40
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/12/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A movie about Irishmen,The Devil's Own is an action thriller that stars Harrison Ford and Brad Pitt together with Rub&eacute;n Blades, Natascha McElhone, Julia Stiles and Treat Williams.This is about a policeman plays Good Samaritan to a visitor from Ireland, only to discover that he has a potentially deadly secret.This was the final film directed by Alan J. Pakula. Belfast-born Frankie McGuire saw his father gunned down by enemy soldiers at the age of eight, and when he grew up he joined the Irish Republican Army, determined that one day his father's death would be avenged. An especially ruthless "volunteer," Frankie is responsible for the death of 13 British soldiers and 11 policemen. After a particularly bloody battle, Frankie sails to the United States in a ragged tugboat he has restored; with a huge bundle of cash, Frankie intends to buy a stock of Stinger missiles from an underground arms dealer in America, Billy Burke. Upon arrival in New York, Frankie is met by a judge who is sympathetic to the IRA's cause and who arranges a place for him to stay. Using the name Rory Devaney, Frankie moves into the home of Tom O'Meara, a scrupulously honest cop. Tom is already in the midst of a personal crisis; his friend and partner Edwin Diaz recently shot a man that he knew was unarmed in the line of duty, and while Edwin wants Tom to help him cover up the matter, Tom's conscience will not allow it. When Tom begins to realize that "Rory" is not simply a man running from the violence of his homeland, he's torn between his sympathy for Frankie's tragic childhood and his desire to see justice served and prevent needless death in Ireland. Although it was it showed ignorance of the history of Northern Ireland and the issues involved are never mentioned,it becomes watchable to a degree due to the presence of Harrison Ford and Brad Pitt.Also,the story was somewhat formulaic,contrived and predictable. With Ford and Pitt,it would have been a disaster.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Hollywood Movie about the IRA
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    david-sarkies
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/12/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    When looking at this movie through the advertisements it sounds like an action movie where a cop (Harrison Ford) is chasing some murderous psychopath (Brad Pitt); that was the impression that I got, and the title doesn't really help that much either for it makes Pitt's character sound like some really evil and sadistic man. He is not. This movie is based around the IRA activities in Ireland and the main character is Brad Pitt. The entire movie is centered around him. The basic plot is that the British are gaining the upper hand because they have helicopters so Pitt must go over to the United States and smuggle some stinger missiles back into Northern Ireland to deal with it. The movie opens with Pitt's father being murdered and then moves to the present day where his character is being hunted down by the British. This quickly dissolves into a huge gun battle in the middle of Belfast where the British are basically using force of numbers to suppress the situation, and even then they fail to achieve their goal. The bulk of the movie takes place in the United States and has very little action. It revolves around Pitt arranging the deal. Unfortunately things go slightly wrong and the deal has to be postponed, which upsets the crime lord who is arranging it no end. There is very little in the way of constant pursuit between Harrison Ford and Brad Pitt. In most cases they are friends, though Ford is ignorant of the true nature of Pitt's character. It is only when the crime lord starts putting pressure onto Pitt that things start happening. When they do, the viewer (or at least myself) starts to have sympathy for Pitt. He is not an evil man, he is just a soldier fighting a war. There is a struggle between him and Ford for we like both but we know that they cannot help each other. The real enemy, and even Ford sees this, is the British. Even Harrison Ford has sympathy for Pitt's character by the end of the movie. The Devil's Own is neither a fast movie nor is it an action movie. The video labels it as a thriller but even then I didn't think much of that. It is hard to put it into a category. If you are looking for a fast action movie, then look for something else. Even though, I still liked this movie and thought that the character development was in itself quite good.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I Could Only Long to be Put Through More "Troubled Productions" Like This One.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jzappa
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/10/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Justice is the summation of all ethical responsibility, but there are conflicting slants on justice. This reality is at the heart of this ignorantly underrated and dismissed film, which meets just gently with The Troubles. Rather, it searches the sad natural history of violence and how individual and social variables shape our slants on it. This is a film of various different tensions in which nobody is unreservedly right or wrong. Characteristic of Pakula's films, The Devil's Own has a solemn, subdued atmosphere that mutely connotes magnitude and seriousness. Cinematographer Gordon Willis' inimitable use of light and dark is especially effective in a scene where Tom and Rory are caught in the sporadic lights of moving cars, a pertinent image for a story in which honor's moorland is so transitory. An Irish-American judge coordinates for Rory Devaney, an Irish rebel, to lodge in the suburban home of NYC police sergeant Tom O'Meara. This upright cop, his wife and their daughters haven't a clue as to Rory's real identity. While Rory is occupied obtaining Stinger missiles from Treat Williams' American gang boss, Rory discovers himself emotionally enticed by his host family's life. He hasn't known this sense of comfort and peace since childhood before his father was slain before his eyes by a British agent. As the arms deal plods on, ample time is left for the two men to connect, and for Rory to feel remorse facing Tom's morality and virtual pacifism. Meanwhile, Tom confronts the prime predicament of his career when his partner Ruben Blades shoots an unarmed offender in the back and then presumes upon him to suppress it. Tom chooses to retire. But before he can submit his badge, he's dragged into Rory's nightmare when it invades and terrorizes his home. Pitt and Ford give moving and realistic performances as two men whose fanatical dedication to justice puts them on a path to conflict. Instead of stressing epinephrine-boosting action sequences, Pakula fixes the film on the ethical clash between the resistance fighter and the unfaltering advocate of law and order. The action sequences are intermittent but vigorously ringing, with a premium put on the enduring formation of character. At an early stage of their growing personal rapport, Rory tells Tom, "Don't look for a happy ending. It's not an American story. It's an Irish one." The two actors have remarkable pull on one another. When they're together on screen, you want to focus on both of them. They don't seek to trump one another, but to enforce one another's sincerity. The Devil's Own unmistakably seeks to build a father-son histrionic between Tom who has no sons and Rory, and it succeeds mainly since it never labors overmuch to labor on emphasis. Their relationship is relaxed and unaffected. A game of pool here, a snippet of conversation there. And Pakula counts on the actors to create a bond without turning to banal dialogue or unseemly bursts of emotion. These are two understated, strong-minded men who just appear to admire and enjoy one another. And when Pitt turns unreservedly cold-blooded when he's forced into a corner, Pitt gives him the disillusionment of a guy who can't meet the expense of a conscience. This point is that it's unfeasible to choose sides, a point distinctive for a Hollywood film, a battle between people whose virtues were decided by their circumstances. Naysayers called the plot incoherent, just a lot of moral grappling, not all of which relevant. Funny how they didn't say that about the character of Mike Yanagita in Fargo, for instance. It's as if it was new to critics that emotional associations with the plot we care about could be made by characters whose experiences outside that main plot course it's important we see first-hand with them to grasp their ethical arcs.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Bad assessment of this movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Editingwhiz
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/9/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The lead review of this movie is vastly unfair. Just because it is written by some one from Belfast who professes to know it all about such topics doesn't mean what he says is relevant for everybody. The fact is that there are interesting relationships between the characters here, you feel empathy for the terrorist character (Brad Pitt), and you feel the pain of Harrison Ford's NYC cop when he partner is killed. The FBI and BI people are in the movie for about 3 minutes -- how can any conclusions be drawn about them? I personally thought it was a tight thriller and it kept my interest the whole time. Ford and Pitt were excellent in their roles. Pitt, despite what the other bloke said, kept his accent quite well throughout. I am a journalist who looks objectively at such things as film and entertainment, I just thought the top review sold this movie way way short.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Hypothetical and Moral Imperatives.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Robert J. Maxwell (rmax304823@yahoo.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/8/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Reuben Blades is the good-natured but fallible cop who is the friend and partner of officer Harrison Ford on the NYPD. The minute he showed up on screen I figured he was toast. The instrument of Blades' demise is Brad Pitt. Pitt is an IRA agent visiting the US to buy some guns and rockets from the ruthless entrepreneur Treat Williams. Pitt is a nice-looking, clean-shaven young man who finds room and board with Ford's accommodating family. Pitt, harboring a pustular hatred because of some politically caused childhood trauma, is gradually drawn into the peaceful life of Ford's household. They have a couple of lovely kids, say grace before meals, go to the same church as Pitt. They're Irish-American too. The only thing is that they haven't witnessed the suffering that Pitt has on the Auld Sod. It's really Pitt's movie. Harrison Ford cheats a little to save his partner's pension but is otherwise stalwart in upholding the law. Pitt, on the other hand, becomes a man of divided allegiances. He admires and respects Ford and his life style. He doesn't want the family to get into trouble. Yet here is Pitt, hiding a fortune in dollars under the floor of Ford's bathroom, about to buy guns so that the killing in Ireland can go on. The moral act, the moral imperative, is to reject the killing and embrace the warmth of family life. The hypothetical imperative is to complete his mission, smuggle the guns back into Ireland, and garner the accolades that are earned by heroes of the movement. That's not a moral act but it lays out what's in it for Pitt. I don't really want to get into it, partly because Immanuel Kant is complicated, partly because space is limited, and partly because I'm not sure I know what the hell I'm talking about. But my understanding is that you can determine whether a course is moral or not by asking what would happen if everyone followed it. Obviously, in this instance, the bloodshed in Ireland stops if Pitt overcomes his personal desire for revenge and stops shedding blood. The conflict and the final shoot out -- among several violent shoot outs -- is inevitable. And the confrontation involves more than just an uptight cop and a reckless revolutionary. The writers, of course, don't want to alienate those Irish-American viewers who are in thrall to what sociologists have called "the new ethnicity" -- a fiercely sentimental attachment to origins they know little about -- so they have Pitt explain (twice) that, "It's not an American problem; it's an Irish problem." Whatever that means. As Ford's wife, Margaret Colin is pretty and nurturing looking. Ford himself, looking old enough to have spent twenty-four years on the police force, isn't any more expressive than he usually is. He's not a bravura performer. He's reliable. Brad Pitt gives an absorbing and likable performance -- a quiet, appreciative, thoughtful, reckless revolutionary maniac -- who brings some unexpected touches to the role. He has more range than I'd been giving him credit for, although he can still turn in a wincingly wrong performance, as in "Seven." I've always admired Treat Williams's performances in a low-key way. He's been pretty good in some roles, like "Prince of the City," but I think his career has been knee-capped by his having a voice that isn't strong, and that sounds so natural that it seems he's not really able to enact a role.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I liked this movie!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    allwrangledup
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/6/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I won't argue some of the criticisms that I'm reading in other people's reviews here -- but I really liked this movie. I thought that Pitt and Harrison (and most of the others)did some solid acting in this movie. And I actually thought the accents were pretty decent! The action scenes may not have been entirely plausible, but they still worked overall. I liked the relationship storyline/s, and the fact that not everything was perfect. And it wasn't all predictable. Good movie overall. I would recommend it. I like action movies, I also like good "people" story lines. I thought this movie contained both. Like a good, easily readable book.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    All the same, Mr. Fitzsimmoms, if you're not confused, you don't know what's going' on.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    lastliberal
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/4/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It amazes me that people look at every film about political situations as if they should be documentaries. This is a film about the relationship between a New York cop (Harrison Ford), and an IRA terrorist (Brad Pitt) in the US to pick up weapons. It is not meant to be a polemic on the Irish situation. Ford plays a cop that cares about the law and about justice. His partner (Rub&eacute;n Blades) shoots an unarmed teen and Ford actually is the one who gets sick. "We are in the police business, not the revenge business," he tells him. Despite the fact that he has killed 20 men, Pitt comes off as his most lovable self. He fits in well with Ford's family. Things fall apart after the weapons deal is delayed and that's when the real action starts. Ford and Pitt were brilliant, although I hated the ending.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The IRA Versus The NYPD
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    zardoz-13
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Harrison Ford & Brad Pitt terrorist thriller "The Devil's Own" features New York cops, British assassins, IRA gunmen, and examples of modern-day intimidation. Nevertheless, it remains as old-fashioned and predictable as any episode of the western television classic "Gunsmoke." Veteran filmmaker Alan J. Pakula, whose credits include "Presumed Innocent" (1990) and "The Pelican Brief" (1994), has crafted a serious, above-average, tight-lipped melodrama that buckles more often than it should but delivers an attractive cast in a handsome actioneer. "V.I. Warshawski" scribe David Aaron Cohen, and "Family Business" scenarist Vincent Patrick and "Tombstone" writer Kevin Jarre collaborated on a screenplay that constitutes sheer hokum of an inspirational sort. Although the film sports a laugh or two, "The Devil's Own" emerges as a dark, tragic saga that "Godfather" lenser Gordon Willis has enhanced with his moody Rembrandt lighting. Brad Pitt is suitably cast as an Irish Republican Army gunman named Rory Devaney. When he was a lad, Rory saw merciless British gunmen gun down his dad at the supper table. He still lives with this bitter memory. He has grown up and become a ruthless killer who the British are prepared to track the earth to liquidate. The ever dependable Harrison Ford shows up later as Tom O'Meara, an honest Irish-American career cop with a wife, Sheila O'Meara (Margaret Colin of "Independence Day") and two daughters. A highly situated IRA sympathizer smuggles Roy into New York City on fake passports and obtains room and board for him in O'Meara's happy domicile. Naturally, Tom doesn't have a clue about Roy's notorious identity. He believes Rory is a construction worker. What O'Meara learns in one devastating betrayal after another is that Rory has come to America to buy surface-to-air missiles to be used against the British. When Tom learns the truth and finds himself pitted against Rory, the reality of the predicament takes on a deeper meaning for him. Meanwhile, Rory encounters Billy Burke (Treat Williams of "Hair") and his bunch of ham-fisted thugs who don't share his dedication to the cause. They simply want their loot for the contraband missiles that they have purchased for Rory. Burke makes the fatal mistake of double-crossing Rory. Although we want to believe that all lawmen are as dedicated as Ford's Tom O'Meara, our hero here seems incredibly saintly, a reincarnation of Dodge City Marshall Matt Dillon for the 1990s who turns shoplifters loose after catching them red-handed with the goods. When our hero's partner Edwin Diaz (well played by Ruben Blades) shoots a thief who had discarded his gun, O'Meara refuses to lie on his behalf. Afterward, O'Meara confides to Sheila that he cannot go on being a cop because of the shooting incident. O'Meara possesses principles that are far beyond believable. If Pakula and company err in over sanctifying Ford's straightforward N.Y.P.D. cop, they miss the boat completely with Pitt's renegade gunsel. While he is battling it out with British troops in blood-splattered Ireland, the Rory Devaney character is appropriately vicious. Once he reaches America, Roy treads somewhere between a hard-bitten villain and a tragic victim who constantly cradles Ford's youngest daughter. All of which dilutes the visceral turbulence that the filmmakers do such a good job of stirring up but never resolving. Hollywood used to steer clear of hot-potato political issues, but "The Devil's Own" appears to weigh its scales of cinematic justice in favor of the underdog IRA. Indeed, this Columbia Pictures Release is a movie with an Irish ending. The British come off looking more villainous than anybody else. Happily, "The Devils' Own" is not the botched film that Pitt has proclaimed in the press. While the movie ripples with violence, the violence here is used to decide who is morally culpable in a less-than-perfect world. The strategy that the filmmakers used in the final shoot-out to get you to bite your fingernails is well-staged but hopelessly heavy-handed. Men will show up for the shoot-outs, especially in the early parts of the action, while women may find themselves swooning over Pitt and Ford. Ultimately, "The Devil's Own" is an entertaining but pretentious load of nonsense that looks terrific on the big screen.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    given the fear of terrorism today....
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    blanche-2
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    ..."The Devil's Own" from 1997 isn't a great film. Starring Harrison Ford, Brad Pitt, Treat Williams, Ruben Blades, and Margaret Colin, the story concerns a Northern Ireland IRA terrorist, Frankie McGuire, who comes to New York to buy weapons. Using the name of Rory Delaney, a judge, Peter Fitzsimmons puts him up at the home of an Irish cop, Tom O'Meara. O'Meara has no idea of Frankie's identity. Rory has brought a ton of money with him and is supposed to make a deal with one Billy Burke (Williams). When he is told by his superiors in Ireland to hold off, Burke gets tough and wants the money. When Tom's house is robbed, his wife held at gunpoint, but nothing taken, Tom begins to wonder about his houseguest. With good reason. Tom himself is having a crisis of conscience when he supports his partner Eddie (Blades) by lying about a shooting. This could have been an excellent film, as it's about two men with completely different moral codes, both believing they're right. Frankie saw his father killed in front of him when he was eight years old, and this started him on the road to killings. Tom has drawn his gun only a few times in all the years he's been a police officer. The problem is that this is muddied by the script being somewhat pro-terrorism. In today's climate, pro-terrorist films with sympathetic killers don't go over well. As someone pointed out, if this had been about someone from the Middle East partly responsible for 9/11 portrayed this way, it probably wouldn't be made. Brad Pitt does a good job, despite some of his accent problems. Harrison Ford is solid but a little boring. The ending was the best part. We don't hear much about the Irish conflict anymore, but years ago, many charities purportedly for Irish children were fronts for collecting money to support the IRA. My sister pointed this out to an Irish friend once, who was about to give such a charity some money, and she said, "So what?" So what? Terrorism isn't right, no matter which side resorts to it. It's understandable that Frankie/Rory had strong feelings, but there are other ways to deal with them. Kind of annoying.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not really very good
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jmorrison-2
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The initial problem I had with this film is the fact that an IRA soldier, in New York to buy and transport weapons to bring back to Ireland, would bunk in with an NYPD Sergeant and his family. That sounds like asking for trouble to me. Not a smart move. I can't imagine the IRA sanctioning a rather reckless move like this. The large amount of money Pitt's character was carrying, and the importance of these weapons making it to Ireland had me shaking my head in disbelief that Rory (Pitt's character) would take such a risk of trying to pull this off right under this police sergeant's nose. Some on this site have complained about Brad Pitt's Irish accent, however I thought Pitt was easily the best part of this film. He succeeded in creating a troubled, but somewhat sympathetic character. It is his performance that I even gave this film a 4. Treat Williams was also very good as the mean, black-hearted weapons contact for Pitt's character in New York. I had enormous problems with Harrison Ford's efforts in this movie, if "efforts" is the right word. When Ford first burst on to the scene many years ago, he looked like a solid, creative acting talent. However, in recent years, he has taken on this goody-goody, moralistic, cutesy-pie, boy scout character style which he seems to hide behind, and it's just ridiculous, and reflects really lazy acting (see: "Air Force One" and "Patriot Games", to name two). It is truly irritating and disappointing, and brought this movie way down in my view. I had trouble swallowing the premise, but Ford's performance just made this cringe-inducing to me.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Cast Saves The Film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    SiliconDesertMan40
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/12/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A movie about Irishmen,The Devil's Own is an action thriller that stars Harrison Ford and Brad Pitt together with Rub&eacute;n Blades, Natascha McElhone, Julia Stiles and Treat Williams.This is about a policeman plays Good Samaritan to a visitor from Ireland, only to discover that he has a potentially deadly secret.This was the final film directed by Alan J. Pakula. Belfast-born Frankie McGuire saw his father gunned down by enemy soldiers at the age of eight, and when he grew up he joined the Irish Republican Army, determined that one day his father's death would be avenged. An especially ruthless "volunteer," Frankie is responsible for the death of 13 British soldiers and 11 policemen. After a particularly bloody battle, Frankie sails to the United States in a ragged tugboat he has restored; with a huge bundle of cash, Frankie intends to buy a stock of Stinger missiles from an underground arms dealer in America, Billy Burke. Upon arrival in New York, Frankie is met by a judge who is sympathetic to the IRA's cause and who arranges a place for him to stay. Using the name Rory Devaney, Frankie moves into the home of Tom O'Meara, a scrupulously honest cop. Tom is already in the midst of a personal crisis; his friend and partner Edwin Diaz recently shot a man that he knew was unarmed in the line of duty, and while Edwin wants Tom to help him cover up the matter, Tom's conscience will not allow it. When Tom begins to realize that "Rory" is not simply a man running from the violence of his homeland, he's torn between his sympathy for Frankie's tragic childhood and his desire to see justice served and prevent needless death in Ireland. Although it was it showed ignorance of the history of Northern Ireland and the issues involved are never mentioned,it becomes watchable to a degree due to the presence of Harrison Ford and Brad Pitt.Also,the story was somewhat formulaic,contrived and predictable. With Ford and Pitt,it would have been a disaster.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Hollywood Movie about the IRA
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    david-sarkies
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/12/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    When looking at this movie through the advertisements it sounds like an action movie where a cop (Harrison Ford) is chasing some murderous psychopath (Brad Pitt); that was the impression that I got, and the title doesn't really help that much either for it makes Pitt's character sound like some really evil and sadistic man. He is not. This movie is based around the IRA activities in Ireland and the main character is Brad Pitt. The entire movie is centered around him. The basic plot is that the British are gaining the upper hand because they have helicopters so Pitt must go over to the United States and smuggle some stinger missiles back into Northern Ireland to deal with it. The movie opens with Pitt's father being murdered and then moves to the present day where his character is being hunted down by the British. This quickly dissolves into a huge gun battle in the middle of Belfast where the British are basically using force of numbers to suppress the situation, and even then they fail to achieve their goal. The bulk of the movie takes place in the United States and has very little action. It revolves around Pitt arranging the deal. Unfortunately things go slightly wrong and the deal has to be postponed, which upsets the crime lord who is arranging it no end. There is very little in the way of constant pursuit between Harrison Ford and Brad Pitt. In most cases they are friends, though Ford is ignorant of the true nature of Pitt's character. It is only when the crime lord starts putting pressure onto Pitt that things start happening. When they do, the viewer (or at least myself) starts to have sympathy for Pitt. He is not an evil man, he is just a soldier fighting a war. There is a struggle between him and Ford for we like both but we know that they cannot help each other. The real enemy, and even Ford sees this, is the British. Even Harrison Ford has sympathy for Pitt's character by the end of the movie. The Devil's Own is neither a fast movie nor is it an action movie. The video labels it as a thriller but even then I didn't think much of that. It is hard to put it into a category. If you are looking for a fast action movie, then look for something else. Even though, I still liked this movie and thought that the character development was in itself quite good.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I Could Only Long to be Put Through More "Troubled Productions" Like This One.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jzappa
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/10/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Justice is the summation of all ethical responsibility, but there are conflicting slants on justice. This reality is at the heart of this ignorantly underrated and dismissed film, which meets just gently with The Troubles. Rather, it searches the sad natural history of violence and how individual and social variables shape our slants on it. This is a film of various different tensions in which nobody is unreservedly right or wrong. Characteristic of Pakula's films, The Devil's Own has a solemn, subdued atmosphere that mutely connotes magnitude and seriousness. Cinematographer Gordon Willis' inimitable use of light and dark is especially effective in a scene where Tom and Rory are caught in the sporadic lights of moving cars, a pertinent image for a story in which honor's moorland is so transitory. An Irish-American judge coordinates for Rory Devaney, an Irish rebel, to lodge in the suburban home of NYC police sergeant Tom O'Meara. This upright cop, his wife and their daughters haven't a clue as to Rory's real identity. While Rory is occupied obtaining Stinger missiles from Treat Williams' American gang boss, Rory discovers himself emotionally enticed by his host family's life. He hasn't known this sense of comfort and peace since childhood before his father was slain before his eyes by a British agent. As the arms deal plods on, ample time is left for the two men to connect, and for Rory to feel remorse facing Tom's morality and virtual pacifism. Meanwhile, Tom confronts the prime predicament of his career when his partner Ruben Blades shoots an unarmed offender in the back and then presumes upon him to suppress it. Tom chooses to retire. But before he can submit his badge, he's dragged into Rory's nightmare when it invades and terrorizes his home. Pitt and Ford give moving and realistic performances as two men whose fanatical dedication to justice puts them on a path to conflict. Instead of stressing epinephrine-boosting action sequences, Pakula fixes the film on the ethical clash between the resistance fighter and the unfaltering advocate of law and order. The action sequences are intermittent but vigorously ringing, with a premium put on the enduring formation of character. At an early stage of their growing personal rapport, Rory tells Tom, "Don't look for a happy ending. It's not an American story. It's an Irish one." The two actors have remarkable pull on one another. When they're together on screen, you want to focus on both of them. They don't seek to trump one another, but to enforce one another's sincerity. The Devil's Own unmistakably seeks to build a father-son histrionic between Tom who has no sons and Rory, and it succeeds mainly since it never labors overmuch to labor on emphasis. Their relationship is relaxed and unaffected. A game of pool here, a snippet of conversation there. And Pakula counts on the actors to create a bond without turning to banal dialogue or unseemly bursts of emotion. These are two understated, strong-minded men who just appear to admire and enjoy one another. And when Pitt turns unreservedly cold-blooded when he's forced into a corner, Pitt gives him the disillusionment of a guy who can't meet the expense of a conscience. This point is that it's unfeasible to choose sides, a point distinctive for a Hollywood film, a battle between people whose virtues were decided by their circumstances. Naysayers called the plot incoherent, just a lot of moral grappling, not all of which relevant. Funny how they didn't say that about the character of Mike Yanagita in Fargo, for instance. It's as if it was new to critics that emotional associations with the plot we care about could be made by characters whose experiences outside that main plot course it's important we see first-hand with them to grasp their ethical arcs.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Bad assessment of this movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Editingwhiz
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/9/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The lead review of this movie is vastly unfair. Just because it is written by some one from Belfast who professes to know it all about such topics doesn't mean what he says is relevant for everybody. The fact is that there are interesting relationships between the characters here, you feel empathy for the terrorist character (Brad Pitt), and you feel the pain of Harrison Ford's NYC cop when he partner is killed. The FBI and BI people are in the movie for about 3 minutes -- how can any conclusions be drawn about them? I personally thought it was a tight thriller and it kept my interest the whole time. Ford and Pitt were excellent in their roles. Pitt, despite what the other bloke said, kept his accent quite well throughout. I am a journalist who looks objectively at such things as film and entertainment, I just thought the top review sold this movie way way short.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Hypothetical and Moral Imperatives.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Robert J. Maxwell (rmax304823@yahoo.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/8/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Reuben Blades is the good-natured but fallible cop who is the friend and partner of officer Harrison Ford on the NYPD. The minute he showed up on screen I figured he was toast. The instrument of Blades' demise is Brad Pitt. Pitt is an IRA agent visiting the US to buy some guns and rockets from the ruthless entrepreneur Treat Williams. Pitt is a nice-looking, clean-shaven young man who finds room and board with Ford's accommodating family. Pitt, harboring a pustular hatred because of some politically caused childhood trauma, is gradually drawn into the peaceful life of Ford's household. They have a couple of lovely kids, say grace before meals, go to the same church as Pitt. They're Irish-American too. The only thing is that they haven't witnessed the suffering that Pitt has on the Auld Sod. It's really Pitt's movie. Harrison Ford cheats a little to save his partner's pension but is otherwise stalwart in upholding the law. Pitt, on the other hand, becomes a man of divided allegiances. He admires and respects Ford and his life style. He doesn't want the family to get into trouble. Yet here is Pitt, hiding a fortune in dollars under the floor of Ford's bathroom, about to buy guns so that the killing in Ireland can go on. The moral act, the moral imperative, is to reject the killing and embrace the warmth of family life. The hypothetical imperative is to complete his mission, smuggle the guns back into Ireland, and garner the accolades that are earned by heroes of the movement. That's not a moral act but it lays out what's in it for Pitt. I don't really want to get into it, partly because Immanuel Kant is complicated, partly because space is limited, and partly because I'm not sure I know what the hell I'm talking about. But my understanding is that you can determine whether a course is moral or not by asking what would happen if everyone followed it. Obviously, in this instance, the bloodshed in Ireland stops if Pitt overcomes his personal desire for revenge and stops shedding blood. The conflict and the final shoot out -- among several violent shoot outs -- is inevitable. And the confrontation involves more than just an uptight cop and a reckless revolutionary. The writers, of course, don't want to alienate those Irish-American viewers who are in thrall to what sociologists have called "the new ethnicity" -- a fiercely sentimental attachment to origins they know little about -- so they have Pitt explain (twice) that, "It's not an American problem; it's an Irish problem." Whatever that means. As Ford's wife, Margaret Colin is pretty and nurturing looking. Ford himself, looking old enough to have spent twenty-four years on the police force, isn't any more expressive than he usually is. He's not a bravura performer. He's reliable. Brad Pitt gives an absorbing and likable performance -- a quiet, appreciative, thoughtful, reckless revolutionary maniac -- who brings some unexpected touches to the role. He has more range than I'd been giving him credit for, although he can still turn in a wincingly wrong performance, as in "Seven." I've always admired Treat Williams's performances in a low-key way. He's been pretty good in some roles, like "Prince of the City," but I think his career has been knee-capped by his having a voice that isn't strong, and that sounds so natural that it seems he's not really able to enact a role.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I liked this movie!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    allwrangledup
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/6/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I won't argue some of the criticisms that I'm reading in other people's reviews here -- but I really liked this movie. I thought that Pitt and Harrison (and most of the others)did some solid acting in this movie. And I actually thought the accents were pretty decent! The action scenes may not have been entirely plausible, but they still worked overall. I liked the relationship storyline/s, and the fact that not everything was perfect. And it wasn't all predictable. Good movie overall. I would recommend it. I like action movies, I also like good "people" story lines. I thought this movie contained both. Like a good, easily readable book.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    All the same, Mr. Fitzsimmoms, if you're not confused, you don't know what's going' on.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    lastliberal
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/4/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It amazes me that people look at every film about political situations as if they should be documentaries. This is a film about the relationship between a New York cop (Harrison Ford), and an IRA terrorist (Brad Pitt) in the US to pick up weapons. It is not meant to be a polemic on the Irish situation. Ford plays a cop that cares about the law and about justice. His partner (Rub&eacute;n Blades) shoots an unarmed teen and Ford actually is the one who gets sick. "We are in the police business, not the revenge business," he tells him. Despite the fact that he has killed 20 men, Pitt comes off as his most lovable self. He fits in well with Ford's family. Things fall apart after the weapons deal is delayed and that's when the real action starts. Ford and Pitt were brilliant, although I hated the ending.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The IRA Versus The NYPD
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    zardoz-13
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Harrison Ford & Brad Pitt terrorist thriller "The Devil's Own" features New York cops, British assassins, IRA gunmen, and examples of modern-day intimidation. Nevertheless, it remains as old-fashioned and predictable as any episode of the western television classic "Gunsmoke." Veteran filmmaker Alan J. Pakula, whose credits include "Presumed Innocent" (1990) and "The Pelican Brief" (1994), has crafted a serious, above-average, tight-lipped melodrama that buckles more often than it should but delivers an attractive cast in a handsome actioneer. "V.I. Warshawski" scribe David Aaron Cohen, and "Family Business" scenarist Vincent Patrick and "Tombstone" writer Kevin Jarre collaborated on a screenplay that constitutes sheer hokum of an inspirational sort. Although the film sports a laugh or two, "The Devil's Own" emerges as a dark, tragic saga that "Godfather" lenser Gordon Willis has enhanced with his moody Rembrandt lighting. Brad Pitt is suitably cast as an Irish Republican Army gunman named Rory Devaney. When he was a lad, Rory saw merciless British gunmen gun down his dad at the supper table. He still lives with this bitter memory. He has grown up and become a ruthless killer who the British are prepared to track the earth to liquidate. The ever dependable Harrison Ford shows up later as Tom O'Meara, an honest Irish-American career cop with a wife, Sheila O'Meara (Margaret Colin of "Independence Day") and two daughters. A highly situated IRA sympathizer smuggles Roy into New York City on fake passports and obtains room and board for him in O'Meara's happy domicile. Naturally, Tom doesn't have a clue about Roy's notorious identity. He believes Rory is a construction worker. What O'Meara learns in one devastating betrayal after another is that Rory has come to America to buy surface-to-air missiles to be used against the British. When Tom learns the truth and finds himself pitted against Rory, the reality of the predicament takes on a deeper meaning for him. Meanwhile, Rory encounters Billy Burke (Treat Williams of "Hair") and his bunch of ham-fisted thugs who don't share his dedication to the cause. They simply want their loot for the contraband missiles that they have purchased for Rory. Burke makes the fatal mistake of double-crossing Rory. Although we want to believe that all lawmen are as dedicated as Ford's Tom O'Meara, our hero here seems incredibly saintly, a reincarnation of Dodge City Marshall Matt Dillon for the 1990s who turns shoplifters loose after catching them red-handed with the goods. When our hero's partner Edwin Diaz (well played by Ruben Blades) shoots a thief who had discarded his gun, O'Meara refuses to lie on his behalf. Afterward, O'Meara confides to Sheila that he cannot go on being a cop because of the shooting incident. O'Meara possesses principles that are far beyond believable. If Pakula and company err in over sanctifying Ford's straightforward N.Y.P.D. cop, they miss the boat completely with Pitt's renegade gunsel. While he is battling it out with British troops in blood-splattered Ireland, the Rory Devaney character is appropriately vicious. Once he reaches America, Roy treads somewhere between a hard-bitten villain and a tragic victim who constantly cradles Ford's youngest daughter. All of which dilutes the visceral turbulence that the filmmakers do such a good job of stirring up but never resolving. Hollywood used to steer clear of hot-potato political issues, but "The Devil's Own" appears to weigh its scales of cinematic justice in favor of the underdog IRA. Indeed, this Columbia Pictures Release is a movie with an Irish ending. The British come off looking more villainous than anybody else. Happily, "The Devils' Own" is not the botched film that Pitt has proclaimed in the press. While the movie ripples with violence, the violence here is used to decide who is morally culpable in a less-than-perfect world. The strategy that the filmmakers used in the final shoot-out to get you to bite your fingernails is well-staged but hopelessly heavy-handed. Men will show up for the shoot-outs, especially in the early parts of the action, while women may find themselves swooning over Pitt and Ford. Ultimately, "The Devil's Own" is an entertaining but pretentious load of nonsense that looks terrific on the big screen.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    given the fear of terrorism today....
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    blanche-2
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    ..."The Devil's Own" from 1997 isn't a great film. Starring Harrison Ford, Brad Pitt, Treat Williams, Ruben Blades, and Margaret Colin, the story concerns a Northern Ireland IRA terrorist, Frankie McGuire, who comes to New York to buy weapons. Using the name of Rory Delaney, a judge, Peter Fitzsimmons puts him up at the home of an Irish cop, Tom O'Meara. O'Meara has no idea of Frankie's identity. Rory has brought a ton of money with him and is supposed to make a deal with one Billy Burke (Williams). When he is told by his superiors in Ireland to hold off, Burke gets tough and wants the money. When Tom's house is robbed, his wife held at gunpoint, but nothing taken, Tom begins to wonder about his houseguest. With good reason. Tom himself is having a crisis of conscience when he supports his partner Eddie (Blades) by lying about a shooting. This could have been an excellent film, as it's about two men with completely different moral codes, both believing they're right. Frankie saw his father killed in front of him when he was eight years old, and this started him on the road to killings. Tom has drawn his gun only a few times in all the years he's been a police officer. The problem is that this is muddied by the script being somewhat pro-terrorism. In today's climate, pro-terrorist films with sympathetic killers don't go over well. As someone pointed out, if this had been about someone from the Middle East partly responsible for 9/11 portrayed this way, it probably wouldn't be made. Brad Pitt does a good job, despite some of his accent problems. Harrison Ford is solid but a little boring. The ending was the best part. We don't hear much about the Irish conflict anymore, but years ago, many charities purportedly for Irish children were fronts for collecting money to support the IRA. My sister pointed this out to an Irish friend once, who was about to give such a charity some money, and she said, "So what?" So what? Terrorism isn't right, no matter which side resorts to it. It's understandable that Frankie/Rory had strong feelings, but there are other ways to deal with them. Kind of annoying.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not really very good
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jmorrison-2
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The initial problem I had with this film is the fact that an IRA soldier, in New York to buy and transport weapons to bring back to Ireland, would bunk in with an NYPD Sergeant and his family. That sounds like asking for trouble to me. Not a smart move. I can't imagine the IRA sanctioning a rather reckless move like this. The large amount of money Pitt's character was carrying, and the importance of these weapons making it to Ireland had me shaking my head in disbelief that Rory (Pitt's character) would take such a risk of trying to pull this off right under this police sergeant's nose. Some on this site have complained about Brad Pitt's Irish accent, however I thought Pitt was easily the best part of this film. He succeeded in creating a troubled, but somewhat sympathetic character. It is his performance that I even gave this film a 4. Treat Williams was also very good as the mean, black-hearted weapons contact for Pitt's character in New York. I had enormous problems with Harrison Ford's efforts in this movie, if "efforts" is the right word. When Ford first burst on to the scene many years ago, he looked like a solid, creative acting talent. However, in recent years, he has taken on this goody-goody, moralistic, cutesy-pie, boy scout character style which he seems to hide behind, and it's just ridiculous, and reflects really lazy acting (see: "Air Force One" and "Patriot Games", to name two). It is truly irritating and disappointing, and brought this movie way down in my view. I had trouble swallowing the premise, but Ford's performance just made this cringe-inducing to me.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Cast Saves The Film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    SiliconDesertMan40
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/12/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A movie about Irishmen,The Devil's Own is an action thriller that stars Harrison Ford and Brad Pitt together with Rub&eacute;n Blades, Natascha McElhone, Julia Stiles and Treat Williams.This is about a policeman plays Good Samaritan to a visitor from Ireland, only to discover that he has a potentially deadly secret.This was the final film directed by Alan J. Pakula. Belfast-born Frankie McGuire saw his father gunned down by enemy soldiers at the age of eight, and when he grew up he joined the Irish Republican Army, determined that one day his father's death would be avenged. An especially ruthless "volunteer," Frankie is responsible for the death of 13 British soldiers and 11 policemen. After a particularly bloody battle, Frankie sails to the United States in a ragged tugboat he has restored; with a huge bundle of cash, Frankie intends to buy a stock of Stinger missiles from an underground arms dealer in America, Billy Burke. Upon arrival in New York, Frankie is met by a judge who is sympathetic to the IRA's cause and who arranges a place for him to stay. Using the name Rory Devaney, Frankie moves into the home of Tom O'Meara, a scrupulously honest cop. Tom is already in the midst of a personal crisis; his friend and partner Edwin Diaz recently shot a man that he knew was unarmed in the line of duty, and while Edwin wants Tom to help him cover up the matter, Tom's conscience will not allow it. When Tom begins to realize that "Rory" is not simply a man running from the violence of his homeland, he's torn between his sympathy for Frankie's tragic childhood and his desire to see justice served and prevent needless death in Ireland. Although it was it showed ignorance of the history of Northern Ireland and the issues involved are never mentioned,it becomes watchable to a degree due to the presence of Harrison Ford and Brad Pitt.Also,the story was somewhat formulaic,contrived and predictable. With Ford and Pitt,it would have been a disaster.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Hollywood Movie about the IRA
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    david-sarkies
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/12/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    When looking at this movie through the advertisements it sounds like an action movie where a cop (Harrison Ford) is chasing some murderous psychopath (Brad Pitt); that was the impression that I got, and the title doesn't really help that much either for it makes Pitt's character sound like some really evil and sadistic man. He is not. This movie is based around the IRA activities in Ireland and the main character is Brad Pitt. The entire movie is centered around him. The basic plot is that the British are gaining the upper hand because they have helicopters so Pitt must go over to the United States and smuggle some stinger missiles back into Northern Ireland to deal with it. The movie opens with Pitt's father being murdered and then moves to the present day where his character is being hunted down by the British. This quickly dissolves into a huge gun battle in the middle of Belfast where the British are basically using force of numbers to suppress the situation, and even then they fail to achieve their goal. The bulk of the movie takes place in the United States and has very little action. It revolves around Pitt arranging the deal. Unfortunately things go slightly wrong and the deal has to be postponed, which upsets the crime lord who is arranging it no end. There is very little in the way of constant pursuit between Harrison Ford and Brad Pitt. In most cases they are friends, though Ford is ignorant of the true nature of Pitt's character. It is only when the crime lord starts putting pressure onto Pitt that things start happening. When they do, the viewer (or at least myself) starts to have sympathy for Pitt. He is not an evil man, he is just a soldier fighting a war. There is a struggle between him and Ford for we like both but we know that they cannot help each other. The real enemy, and even Ford sees this, is the British. Even Harrison Ford has sympathy for Pitt's character by the end of the movie. The Devil's Own is neither a fast movie nor is it an action movie. The video labels it as a thriller but even then I didn't think much of that. It is hard to put it into a category. If you are looking for a fast action movie, then look for something else. Even though, I still liked this movie and thought that the character development was in itself quite good.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I Could Only Long to be Put Through More "Troubled Productions" Like This One.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jzappa
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/10/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Justice is the summation of all ethical responsibility, but there are conflicting slants on justice. This reality is at the heart of this ignorantly underrated and dismissed film, which meets just gently with The Troubles. Rather, it searches the sad natural history of violence and how individual and social variables shape our slants on it. This is a film of various different tensions in which nobody is unreservedly right or wrong. Characteristic of Pakula's films, The Devil's Own has a solemn, subdued atmosphere that mutely connotes magnitude and seriousness. Cinematographer Gordon Willis' inimitable use of light and dark is especially effective in a scene where Tom and Rory are caught in the sporadic lights of moving cars, a pertinent image for a story in which honor's moorland is so transitory. An Irish-American judge coordinates for Rory Devaney, an Irish rebel, to lodge in the suburban home of NYC police sergeant Tom O'Meara. This upright cop, his wife and their daughters haven't a clue as to Rory's real identity. While Rory is occupied obtaining Stinger missiles from Treat Williams' American gang boss, Rory discovers himself emotionally enticed by his host family's life. He hasn't known this sense of comfort and peace since childhood before his father was slain before his eyes by a British agent. As the arms deal plods on, ample time is left for the two men to connect, and for Rory to feel remorse facing Tom's morality and virtual pacifism. Meanwhile, Tom confronts the prime predicament of his career when his partner Ruben Blades shoots an unarmed offender in the back and then presumes upon him to suppress it. Tom chooses to retire. But before he can submit his badge, he's dragged into Rory's nightmare when it invades and terrorizes his home. Pitt and Ford give moving and realistic performances as two men whose fanatical dedication to justice puts them on a path to conflict. Instead of stressing epinephrine-boosting action sequences, Pakula fixes the film on the ethical clash between the resistance fighter and the unfaltering advocate of law and order. The action sequences are intermittent but vigorously ringing, with a premium put on the enduring formation of character. At an early stage of their growing personal rapport, Rory tells Tom, "Don't look for a happy ending. It's not an American story. It's an Irish one." The two actors have remarkable pull on one another. When they're together on screen, you want to focus on both of them. They don't seek to trump one another, but to enforce one another's sincerity. The Devil's Own unmistakably seeks to build a father-son histrionic between Tom who has no sons and Rory, and it succeeds mainly since it never labors overmuch to labor on emphasis. Their relationship is relaxed and unaffected. A game of pool here, a snippet of conversation there. And Pakula counts on the actors to create a bond without turning to banal dialogue or unseemly bursts of emotion. These are two understated, strong-minded men who just appear to admire and enjoy one another. And when Pitt turns unreservedly cold-blooded when he's forced into a corner, Pitt gives him the disillusionment of a guy who can't meet the expense of a conscience. This point is that it's unfeasible to choose sides, a point distinctive for a Hollywood film, a battle between people whose virtues were decided by their circumstances. Naysayers called the plot incoherent, just a lot of moral grappling, not all of which relevant. Funny how they didn't say that about the character of Mike Yanagita in Fargo, for instance. It's as if it was new to critics that emotional associations with the plot we care about could be made by characters whose experiences outside that main plot course it's important we see first-hand with them to grasp their ethical arcs.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Bad assessment of this movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Editingwhiz
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/9/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The lead review of this movie is vastly unfair. Just because it is written by some one from Belfast who professes to know it all about such topics doesn't mean what he says is relevant for everybody. The fact is that there are interesting relationships between the characters here, you feel empathy for the terrorist character (Brad Pitt), and you feel the pain of Harrison Ford's NYC cop when he partner is killed. The FBI and BI people are in the movie for about 3 minutes -- how can any conclusions be drawn about them? I personally thought it was a tight thriller and it kept my interest the whole time. Ford and Pitt were excellent in their roles. Pitt, despite what the other bloke said, kept his accent quite well throughout. I am a journalist who looks objectively at such things as film and entertainment, I just thought the top review sold this movie way way short.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Hypothetical and Moral Imperatives.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Robert J. Maxwell (rmax304823@yahoo.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/8/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Reuben Blades is the good-natured but fallible cop who is the friend and partner of officer Harrison Ford on the NYPD. The minute he showed up on screen I figured he was toast. The instrument of Blades' demise is Brad Pitt. Pitt is an IRA agent visiting the US to buy some guns and rockets from the ruthless entrepreneur Treat Williams. Pitt is a nice-looking, clean-shaven young man who finds room and board with Ford's accommodating family. Pitt, harboring a pustular hatred because of some politically caused childhood trauma, is gradually drawn into the peaceful life of Ford's household. They have a couple of lovely kids, say grace before meals, go to the same church as Pitt. They're Irish-American too. The only thing is that they haven't witnessed the suffering that Pitt has on the Auld Sod. It's really Pitt's movie. Harrison Ford cheats a little to save his partner's pension but is otherwise stalwart in upholding the law. Pitt, on the other hand, becomes a man of divided allegiances. He admires and respects Ford and his life style. He doesn't want the family to get into trouble. Yet here is Pitt, hiding a fortune in dollars under the floor of Ford's bathroom, about to buy guns so that the killing in Ireland can go on. The moral act, the moral imperative, is to reject the killing and embrace the warmth of family life. The hypothetical imperative is to complete his mission, smuggle the guns back into Ireland, and garner the accolades that are earned by heroes of the movement. That's not a moral act but it lays out what's in it for Pitt. I don't really want to get into it, partly because Immanuel Kant is complicated, partly because space is limited, and partly because I'm not sure I know what the hell I'm talking about. But my understanding is that you can determine whether a course is moral or not by asking what would happen if everyone followed it. Obviously, in this instance, the bloodshed in Ireland stops if Pitt overcomes his personal desire for revenge and stops shedding blood. The conflict and the final shoot out -- among several violent shoot outs -- is inevitable. And the confrontation involves more than just an uptight cop and a reckless revolutionary. The writers, of course, don't want to alienate those Irish-American viewers who are in thrall to what sociologists have called "the new ethnicity" -- a fiercely sentimental attachment to origins they know little about -- so they have Pitt explain (twice) that, "It's not an American problem; it's an Irish problem." Whatever that means. As Ford's wife, Margaret Colin is pretty and nurturing looking. Ford himself, looking old enough to have spent twenty-four years on the police force, isn't any more expressive than he usually is. He's not a bravura performer. He's reliable. Brad Pitt gives an absorbing and likable performance -- a quiet, appreciative, thoughtful, reckless revolutionary maniac -- who brings some unexpected touches to the role. He has more range than I'd been giving him credit for, although he can still turn in a wincingly wrong performance, as in "Seven." I've always admired Treat Williams's performances in a low-key way. He's been pretty good in some roles, like "Prince of the City," but I think his career has been knee-capped by his having a voice that isn't strong, and that sounds so natural that it seems he's not really able to enact a role.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I liked this movie!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    allwrangledup
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/6/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I won't argue some of the criticisms that I'm reading in other people's reviews here -- but I really liked this movie. I thought that Pitt and Harrison (and most of the others)did some solid acting in this movie. And I actually thought the accents were pretty decent! The action scenes may not have been entirely plausible, but they still worked overall. I liked the relationship storyline/s, and the fact that not everything was perfect. And it wasn't all predictable. Good movie overall. I would recommend it. I like action movies, I also like good "people" story lines. I thought this movie contained both. Like a good, easily readable book.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    All the same, Mr. Fitzsimmoms, if you're not confused, you don't know what's going' on.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    lastliberal
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/4/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It amazes me that people look at every film about political situations as if they should be documentaries. This is a film about the relationship between a New York cop (Harrison Ford), and an IRA terrorist (Brad Pitt) in the US to pick up weapons. It is not meant to be a polemic on the Irish situation. Ford plays a cop that cares about the law and about justice. His partner (Rub&eacute;n Blades) shoots an unarmed teen and Ford actually is the one who gets sick. "We are in the police business, not the revenge business," he tells him. Despite the fact that he has killed 20 men, Pitt comes off as his most lovable self. He fits in well with Ford's family. Things fall apart after the weapons deal is delayed and that's when the real action starts. Ford and Pitt were brilliant, although I hated the ending.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The IRA Versus The NYPD
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    zardoz-13
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Harrison Ford & Brad Pitt terrorist thriller "The Devil's Own" features New York cops, British assassins, IRA gunmen, and examples of modern-day intimidation. Nevertheless, it remains as old-fashioned and predictable as any episode of the western television classic "Gunsmoke." Veteran filmmaker Alan J. Pakula, whose credits include "Presumed Innocent" (1990) and "The Pelican Brief" (1994), has crafted a serious, above-average, tight-lipped melodrama that buckles more often than it should but delivers an attractive cast in a handsome actioneer. "V.I. Warshawski" scribe David Aaron Cohen, and "Family Business" scenarist Vincent Patrick and "Tombstone" writer Kevin Jarre collaborated on a screenplay that constitutes sheer hokum of an inspirational sort. Although the film sports a laugh or two, "The Devil's Own" emerges as a dark, tragic saga that "Godfather" lenser Gordon Willis has enhanced with his moody Rembrandt lighting. Brad Pitt is suitably cast as an Irish Republican Army gunman named Rory Devaney. When he was a lad, Rory saw merciless British gunmen gun down his dad at the supper table. He still lives with this bitter memory. He has grown up and become a ruthless killer who the British are prepared to track the earth to liquidate. The ever dependable Harrison Ford shows up later as Tom O'Meara, an honest Irish-American career cop with a wife, Sheila O'Meara (Margaret Colin of "Independence Day") and two daughters. A highly situated IRA sympathizer smuggles Roy into New York City on fake passports and obtains room and board for him in O'Meara's happy domicile. Naturally, Tom doesn't have a clue about Roy's notorious identity. He believes Rory is a construction worker. What O'Meara learns in one devastating betrayal after another is that Rory has come to America to buy surface-to-air missiles to be used against the British. When Tom learns the truth and finds himself pitted against Rory, the reality of the predicament takes on a deeper meaning for him. Meanwhile, Rory encounters Billy Burke (Treat Williams of "Hair") and his bunch of ham-fisted thugs who don't share his dedication to the cause. They simply want their loot for the contraband missiles that they have purchased for Rory. Burke makes the fatal mistake of double-crossing Rory. Although we want to believe that all lawmen are as dedicated as Ford's Tom O'Meara, our hero here seems incredibly saintly, a reincarnation of Dodge City Marshall Matt Dillon for the 1990s who turns shoplifters loose after catching them red-handed with the goods. When our hero's partner Edwin Diaz (well played by Ruben Blades) shoots a thief who had discarded his gun, O'Meara refuses to lie on his behalf. Afterward, O'Meara confides to Sheila that he cannot go on being a cop because of the shooting incident. O'Meara possesses principles that are far beyond believable. If Pakula and company err in over sanctifying Ford's straightforward N.Y.P.D. cop, they miss the boat completely with Pitt's renegade gunsel. While he is battling it out with British troops in blood-splattered Ireland, the Rory Devaney character is appropriately vicious. Once he reaches America, Roy treads somewhere between a hard-bitten villain and a tragic victim who constantly cradles Ford's youngest daughter. All of which dilutes the visceral turbulence that the filmmakers do such a good job of stirring up but never resolving. Hollywood used to steer clear of hot-potato political issues, but "The Devil's Own" appears to weigh its scales of cinematic justice in favor of the underdog IRA. Indeed, this Columbia Pictures Release is a movie with an Irish ending. The British come off looking more villainous than anybody else. Happily, "The Devils' Own" is not the botched film that Pitt has proclaimed in the press. While the movie ripples with violence, the violence here is used to decide who is morally culpable in a less-than-perfect world. The strategy that the filmmakers used in the final shoot-out to get you to bite your fingernails is well-staged but hopelessly heavy-handed. Men will show up for the shoot-outs, especially in the early parts of the action, while women may find themselves swooning over Pitt and Ford. Ultimately, "The Devil's Own" is an entertaining but pretentious load of nonsense that looks terrific on the big screen.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    given the fear of terrorism today....
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    blanche-2
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    ..."The Devil's Own" from 1997 isn't a great film. Starring Harrison Ford, Brad Pitt, Treat Williams, Ruben Blades, and Margaret Colin, the story concerns a Northern Ireland IRA terrorist, Frankie McGuire, who comes to New York to buy weapons. Using the name of Rory Delaney, a judge, Peter Fitzsimmons puts him up at the home of an Irish cop, Tom O'Meara. O'Meara has no idea of Frankie's identity. Rory has brought a ton of money with him and is supposed to make a deal with one Billy Burke (Williams). When he is told by his superiors in Ireland to hold off, Burke gets tough and wants the money. When Tom's house is robbed, his wife held at gunpoint, but nothing taken, Tom begins to wonder about his houseguest. With good reason. Tom himself is having a crisis of conscience when he supports his partner Eddie (Blades) by lying about a shooting. This could have been an excellent film, as it's about two men with completely different moral codes, both believing they're right. Frankie saw his father killed in front of him when he was eight years old, and this started him on the road to killings. Tom has drawn his gun only a few times in all the years he's been a police officer. The problem is that this is muddied by the script being somewhat pro-terrorism. In today's climate, pro-terrorist films with sympathetic killers don't go over well. As someone pointed out, if this had been about someone from the Middle East partly responsible for 9/11 portrayed this way, it probably wouldn't be made. Brad Pitt does a good job, despite some of his accent problems. Harrison Ford is solid but a little boring. The ending was the best part. We don't hear much about the Irish conflict anymore, but years ago, many charities purportedly for Irish children were fronts for collecting money to support the IRA. My sister pointed this out to an Irish friend once, who was about to give such a charity some money, and she said, "So what?" So what? Terrorism isn't right, no matter which side resorts to it. It's understandable that Frankie/Rory had strong feelings, but there are other ways to deal with them. Kind of annoying.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not really very good
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jmorrison-2
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The initial problem I had with this film is the fact that an IRA soldier, in New York to buy and transport weapons to bring back to Ireland, would bunk in with an NYPD Sergeant and his family. That sounds like asking for trouble to me. Not a smart move. I can't imagine the IRA sanctioning a rather reckless move like this. The large amount of money Pitt's character was carrying, and the importance of these weapons making it to Ireland had me shaking my head in disbelief that Rory (Pitt's character) would take such a risk of trying to pull this off right under this police sergeant's nose. Some on this site have complained about Brad Pitt's Irish accent, however I thought Pitt was easily the best part of this film. He succeeded in creating a troubled, but somewhat sympathetic character. It is his performance that I even gave this film a 4. Treat Williams was also very good as the mean, black-hearted weapons contact for Pitt's character in New York. I had enormous problems with Harrison Ford's efforts in this movie, if "efforts" is the right word. When Ford first burst on to the scene many years ago, he looked like a solid, creative acting talent. However, in recent years, he has taken on this goody-goody, moralistic, cutesy-pie, boy scout character style which he seems to hide behind, and it's just ridiculous, and reflects really lazy acting (see: "Air Force One" and "Patriot Games", to name two). It is truly irritating and disappointing, and brought this movie way down in my view. I had trouble swallowing the premise, but Ford's performance just made this cringe-inducing to me.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Cast Saves The Film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    SiliconDesertMan40
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/12/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A movie about Irishmen,The Devil's Own is an action thriller that stars Harrison Ford and Brad Pitt together with Rub&eacute;n Blades, Natascha McElhone, Julia Stiles and Treat Williams.This is about a policeman plays Good Samaritan to a visitor from Ireland, only to discover that he has a potentially deadly secret.This was the final film directed by Alan J. Pakula. Belfast-born Frankie McGuire saw his father gunned down by enemy soldiers at the age of eight, and when he grew up he joined the Irish Republican Army, determined that one day his father's death would be avenged. An especially ruthless "volunteer," Frankie is responsible for the death of 13 British soldiers and 11 policemen. After a particularly bloody battle, Frankie sails to the United States in a ragged tugboat he has restored; with a huge bundle of cash, Frankie intends to buy a stock of Stinger missiles from an underground arms dealer in America, Billy Burke. Upon arrival in New York, Frankie is met by a judge who is sympathetic to the IRA's cause and who arranges a place for him to stay. Using the name Rory Devaney, Frankie moves into the home of Tom O'Meara, a scrupulously honest cop. Tom is already in the midst of a personal crisis; his friend and partner Edwin Diaz recently shot a man that he knew was unarmed in the line of duty, and while Edwin wants Tom to help him cover up the matter, Tom's conscience will not allow it. When Tom begins to realize that "Rory" is not simply a man running from the violence of his homeland, he's torn between his sympathy for Frankie's tragic childhood and his desire to see justice served and prevent needless death in Ireland. Although it was it showed ignorance of the history of Northern Ireland and the issues involved are never mentioned,it becomes watchable to a degree due to the presence of Harrison Ford and Brad Pitt.Also,the story was somewhat formulaic,contrived and predictable. With Ford and Pitt,it would have been a disaster.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Hollywood Movie about the IRA
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    david-sarkies
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/12/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    When looking at this movie through the advertisements it sounds like an action movie where a cop (Harrison Ford) is chasing some murderous psychopath (Brad Pitt); that was the impression that I got, and the title doesn't really help that much either for it makes Pitt's character sound like some really evil and sadistic man. He is not. This movie is based around the IRA activities in Ireland and the main character is Brad Pitt. The entire movie is centered around him. The basic plot is that the British are gaining the upper hand because they have helicopters so Pitt must go over to the United States and smuggle some stinger missiles back into Northern Ireland to deal with it. The movie opens with Pitt's father being murdered and then moves to the present day where his character is being hunted down by the British. This quickly dissolves into a huge gun battle in the middle of Belfast where the British are basically using force of numbers to suppress the situation, and even then they fail to achieve their goal. The bulk of the movie takes place in the United States and has very little action. It revolves around Pitt arranging the deal. Unfortunately things go slightly wrong and the deal has to be postponed, which upsets the crime lord who is arranging it no end. There is very little in the way of constant pursuit between Harrison Ford and Brad Pitt. In most cases they are friends, though Ford is ignorant of the true nature of Pitt's character. It is only when the crime lord starts putting pressure onto Pitt that things start happening. When they do, the viewer (or at least myself) starts to have sympathy for Pitt. He is not an evil man, he is just a soldier fighting a war. There is a struggle between him and Ford for we like both but we know that they cannot help each other. The real enemy, and even Ford sees this, is the British. Even Harrison Ford has sympathy for Pitt's character by the end of the movie. The Devil's Own is neither a fast movie nor is it an action movie. The video labels it as a thriller but even then I didn't think much of that. It is hard to put it into a category. If you are looking for a fast action movie, then look for something else. Even though, I still liked this movie and thought that the character development was in itself quite good.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I Could Only Long to be Put Through More "Troubled Productions" Like This One.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jzappa
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/10/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Justice is the summation of all ethical responsibility, but there are conflicting slants on justice. This reality is at the heart of this ignorantly underrated and dismissed film, which meets just gently with The Troubles. Rather, it searches the sad natural history of violence and how individual and social variables shape our slants on it. This is a film of various different tensions in which nobody is unreservedly right or wrong. Characteristic of Pakula's films, The Devil's Own has a solemn, subdued atmosphere that mutely connotes magnitude and seriousness. Cinematographer Gordon Willis' inimitable use of light and dark is especially effective in a scene where Tom and Rory are caught in the sporadic lights of moving cars, a pertinent image for a story in which honor's moorland is so transitory. An Irish-American judge coordinates for Rory Devaney, an Irish rebel, to lodge in the suburban home of NYC police sergeant Tom O'Meara. This upright cop, his wife and their daughters haven't a clue as to Rory's real identity. While Rory is occupied obtaining Stinger missiles from Treat Williams' American gang boss, Rory discovers himself emotionally enticed by his host family's life. He hasn't known this sense of comfort and peace since childhood before his father was slain before his eyes by a British agent. As the arms deal plods on, ample time is left for the two men to connect, and for Rory to feel remorse facing Tom's morality and virtual pacifism. Meanwhile, Tom confronts the prime predicament of his career when his partner Ruben Blades shoots an unarmed offender in the back and then presumes upon him to suppress it. Tom chooses to retire. But before he can submit his badge, he's dragged into Rory's nightmare when it invades and terrorizes his home. Pitt and Ford give moving and realistic performances as two men whose fanatical dedication to justice puts them on a path to conflict. Instead of stressing epinephrine-boosting action sequences, Pakula fixes the film on the ethical clash between the resistance fighter and the unfaltering advocate of law and order. The action sequences are intermittent but vigorously ringing, with a premium put on the enduring formation of character. At an early stage of their growing personal rapport, Rory tells Tom, "Don't look for a happy ending. It's not an American story. It's an Irish one." The two actors have remarkable pull on one another. When they're together on screen, you want to focus on both of them. They don't seek to trump one another, but to enforce one another's sincerity. The Devil's Own unmistakably seeks to build a father-son histrionic between Tom who has no sons and Rory, and it succeeds mainly since it never labors overmuch to labor on emphasis. Their relationship is relaxed and unaffected. A game of pool here, a snippet of conversation there. And Pakula counts on the actors to create a bond without turning to banal dialogue or unseemly bursts of emotion. These are two understated, strong-minded men who just appear to admire and enjoy one another. And when Pitt turns unreservedly cold-blooded when he's forced into a corner, Pitt gives him the disillusionment of a guy who can't meet the expense of a conscience. This point is that it's unfeasible to choose sides, a point distinctive for a Hollywood film, a battle between people whose virtues were decided by their circumstances. Naysayers called the plot incoherent, just a lot of moral grappling, not all of which relevant. Funny how they didn't say that about the character of Mike Yanagita in Fargo, for instance. It's as if it was new to critics that emotional associations with the plot we care about could be made by characters whose experiences outside that main plot course it's important we see first-hand with them to grasp their ethical arcs.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Bad assessment of this movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Editingwhiz
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/9/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The lead review of this movie is vastly unfair. Just because it is written by some one from Belfast who professes to know it all about such topics doesn't mean what he says is relevant for everybody. The fact is that there are interesting relationships between the characters here, you feel empathy for the terrorist character (Brad Pitt), and you feel the pain of Harrison Ford's NYC cop when he partner is killed. The FBI and BI people are in the movie for about 3 minutes -- how can any conclusions be drawn about them? I personally thought it was a tight thriller and it kept my interest the whole time. Ford and Pitt were excellent in their roles. Pitt, despite what the other bloke said, kept his accent quite well throughout. I am a journalist who looks objectively at such things as film and entertainment, I just thought the top review sold this movie way way short.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Hypothetical and Moral Imperatives.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Robert J. Maxwell (rmax304823@yahoo.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/8/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Reuben Blades is the good-natured but fallible cop who is the friend and partner of officer Harrison Ford on the NYPD. The minute he showed up on screen I figured he was toast. The instrument of Blades' demise is Brad Pitt. Pitt is an IRA agent visiting the US to buy some guns and rockets from the ruthless entrepreneur Treat Williams. Pitt is a nice-looking, clean-shaven young man who finds room and board with Ford's accommodating family. Pitt, harboring a pustular hatred because of some politically caused childhood trauma, is gradually drawn into the peaceful life of Ford's household. They have a couple of lovely kids, say grace before meals, go to the same church as Pitt. They're Irish-American too. The only thing is that they haven't witnessed the suffering that Pitt has on the Auld Sod. It's really Pitt's movie. Harrison Ford cheats a little to save his partner's pension but is otherwise stalwart in upholding the law. Pitt, on the other hand, becomes a man of divided allegiances. He admires and respects Ford and his life style. He doesn't want the family to get into trouble. Yet here is Pitt, hiding a fortune in dollars under the floor of Ford's bathroom, about to buy guns so that the killing in Ireland can go on. The moral act, the moral imperative, is to reject the killing and embrace the warmth of family life. The hypothetical imperative is to complete his mission, smuggle the guns back into Ireland, and garner the accolades that are earned by heroes of the movement. That's not a moral act but it lays out what's in it for Pitt. I don't really want to get into it, partly because Immanuel Kant is complicated, partly because space is limited, and partly because I'm not sure I know what the hell I'm talking about. But my understanding is that you can determine whether a course is moral or not by asking what would happen if everyone followed it. Obviously, in this instance, the bloodshed in Ireland stops if Pitt overcomes his personal desire for revenge and stops shedding blood. The conflict and the final shoot out -- among several violent shoot outs -- is inevitable. And the confrontation involves more than just an uptight cop and a reckless revolutionary. The writers, of course, don't want to alienate those Irish-American viewers who are in thrall to what sociologists have called "the new ethnicity" -- a fiercely sentimental attachment to origins they know little about -- so they have Pitt explain (twice) that, "It's not an American problem; it's an Irish problem." Whatever that means. As Ford's wife, Margaret Colin is pretty and nurturing looking. Ford himself, looking old enough to have spent twenty-four years on the police force, isn't any more expressive than he usually is. He's not a bravura performer. He's reliable. Brad Pitt gives an absorbing and likable performance -- a quiet, appreciative, thoughtful, reckless revolutionary maniac -- who brings some unexpected touches to the role. He has more range than I'd been giving him credit for, although he can still turn in a wincingly wrong performance, as in "Seven." I've always admired Treat Williams's performances in a low-key way. He's been pretty good in some roles, like "Prince of the City," but I think his career has been knee-capped by his having a voice that isn't strong, and that sounds so natural that it seems he's not really able to enact a role.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I liked this movie!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    allwrangledup
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/6/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I won't argue some of the criticisms that I'm reading in other people's reviews here -- but I really liked this movie. I thought that Pitt and Harrison (and most of the others)did some solid acting in this movie. And I actually thought the accents were pretty decent! The action scenes may not have been entirely plausible, but they still worked overall. I liked the relationship storyline/s, and the fact that not everything was perfect. And it wasn't all predictable. Good movie overall. I would recommend it. I like action movies, I also like good "people" story lines. I thought this movie contained both. Like a good, easily readable book.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    All the same, Mr. Fitzsimmoms, if you're not confused, you don't know what's going' on.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    lastliberal
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/4/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It amazes me that people look at every film about political situations as if they should be documentaries. This is a film about the relationship between a New York cop (Harrison Ford), and an IRA terrorist (Brad Pitt) in the US to pick up weapons. It is not meant to be a polemic on the Irish situation. Ford plays a cop that cares about the law and about justice. His partner (Rub&eacute;n Blades) shoots an unarmed teen and Ford actually is the one who gets sick. "We are in the police business, not the revenge business," he tells him. Despite the fact that he has killed 20 men, Pitt comes off as his most lovable self. He fits in well with Ford's family. Things fall apart after the weapons deal is delayed and that's when the real action starts. Ford and Pitt were brilliant, although I hated the ending.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The IRA Versus The NYPD
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    zardoz-13
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Harrison Ford & Brad Pitt terrorist thriller "The Devil's Own" features New York cops, British assassins, IRA gunmen, and examples of modern-day intimidation. Nevertheless, it remains as old-fashioned and predictable as any episode of the western television classic "Gunsmoke." Veteran filmmaker Alan J. Pakula, whose credits include "Presumed Innocent" (1990) and "The Pelican Brief" (1994), has crafted a serious, above-average, tight-lipped melodrama that buckles more often than it should but delivers an attractive cast in a handsome actioneer. "V.I. Warshawski" scribe David Aaron Cohen, and "Family Business" scenarist Vincent Patrick and "Tombstone" writer Kevin Jarre collaborated on a screenplay that constitutes sheer hokum of an inspirational sort. Although the film sports a laugh or two, "The Devil's Own" emerges as a dark, tragic saga that "Godfather" lenser Gordon Willis has enhanced with his moody Rembrandt lighting. Brad Pitt is suitably cast as an Irish Republican Army gunman named Rory Devaney. When he was a lad, Rory saw merciless British gunmen gun down his dad at the supper table. He still lives with this bitter memory. He has grown up and become a ruthless killer who the British are prepared to track the earth to liquidate. The ever dependable Harrison Ford shows up later as Tom O'Meara, an honest Irish-American career cop with a wife, Sheila O'Meara (Margaret Colin of "Independence Day") and two daughters. A highly situated IRA sympathizer smuggles Roy into New York City on fake passports and obtains room and board for him in O'Meara's happy domicile. Naturally, Tom doesn't have a clue about Roy's notorious identity. He believes Rory is a construction worker. What O'Meara learns in one devastating betrayal after another is that Rory has come to America to buy surface-to-air missiles to be used against the British. When Tom learns the truth and finds himself pitted against Rory, the reality of the predicament takes on a deeper meaning for him. Meanwhile, Rory encounters Billy Burke (Treat Williams of "Hair") and his bunch of ham-fisted thugs who don't share his dedication to the cause. They simply want their loot for the contraband missiles that they have purchased for Rory. Burke makes the fatal mistake of double-crossing Rory. Although we want to believe that all lawmen are as dedicated as Ford's Tom O'Meara, our hero here seems incredibly saintly, a reincarnation of Dodge City Marshall Matt Dillon for the 1990s who turns shoplifters loose after catching them red-handed with the goods. When our hero's partner Edwin Diaz (well played by Ruben Blades) shoots a thief who had discarded his gun, O'Meara refuses to lie on his behalf. Afterward, O'Meara confides to Sheila that he cannot go on being a cop because of the shooting incident. O'Meara possesses principles that are far beyond believable. If Pakula and company err in over sanctifying Ford's straightforward N.Y.P.D. cop, they miss the boat completely with Pitt's renegade gunsel. While he is battling it out with British troops in blood-splattered Ireland, the Rory Devaney character is appropriately vicious. Once he reaches America, Roy treads somewhere between a hard-bitten villain and a tragic victim who constantly cradles Ford's youngest daughter. All of which dilutes the visceral turbulence that the filmmakers do such a good job of stirring up but never resolving. Hollywood used to steer clear of hot-potato political issues, but "The Devil's Own" appears to weigh its scales of cinematic justice in favor of the underdog IRA. Indeed, this Columbia Pictures Release is a movie with an Irish ending. The British come off looking more villainous than anybody else. Happily, "The Devils' Own" is not the botched film that Pitt has proclaimed in the press. While the movie ripples with violence, the violence here is used to decide who is morally culpable in a less-than-perfect world. The strategy that the filmmakers used in the final shoot-out to get you to bite your fingernails is well-staged but hopelessly heavy-handed. Men will show up for the shoot-outs, especially in the early parts of the action, while women may find themselves swooning over Pitt and Ford. Ultimately, "The Devil's Own" is an entertaining but pretentious load of nonsense that looks terrific on the big screen.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    given the fear of terrorism today....
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    blanche-2
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    ..."The Devil's Own" from 1997 isn't a great film. Starring Harrison Ford, Brad Pitt, Treat Williams, Ruben Blades, and Margaret Colin, the story concerns a Northern Ireland IRA terrorist, Frankie McGuire, who comes to New York to buy weapons. Using the name of Rory Delaney, a judge, Peter Fitzsimmons puts him up at the home of an Irish cop, Tom O'Meara. O'Meara has no idea of Frankie's identity. Rory has brought a ton of money with him and is supposed to make a deal with one Billy Burke (Williams). When he is told by his superiors in Ireland to hold off, Burke gets tough and wants the money. When Tom's house is robbed, his wife held at gunpoint, but nothing taken, Tom begins to wonder about his houseguest. With good reason. Tom himself is having a crisis of conscience when he supports his partner Eddie (Blades) by lying about a shooting. This could have been an excellent film, as it's about two men with completely different moral codes, both believing they're right. Frankie saw his father killed in front of him when he was eight years old, and this started him on the road to killings. Tom has drawn his gun only a few times in all the years he's been a police officer. The problem is that this is muddied by the script being somewhat pro-terrorism. In today's climate, pro-terrorist films with sympathetic killers don't go over well. As someone pointed out, if this had been about someone from the Middle East partly responsible for 9/11 portrayed this way, it probably wouldn't be made. Brad Pitt does a good job, despite some of his accent problems. Harrison Ford is solid but a little boring. The ending was the best part. We don't hear much about the Irish conflict anymore, but years ago, many charities purportedly for Irish children were fronts for collecting money to support the IRA. My sister pointed this out to an Irish friend once, who was about to give such a charity some money, and she said, "So what?" So what? Terrorism isn't right, no matter which side resorts to it. It's understandable that Frankie/Rory had strong feelings, but there are other ways to deal with them. Kind of annoying.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not really very good
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jmorrison-2
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The initial problem I had with this film is the fact that an IRA soldier, in New York to buy and transport weapons to bring back to Ireland, would bunk in with an NYPD Sergeant and his family. That sounds like asking for trouble to me. Not a smart move. I can't imagine the IRA sanctioning a rather reckless move like this. The large amount of money Pitt's character was carrying, and the importance of these weapons making it to Ireland had me shaking my head in disbelief that Rory (Pitt's character) would take such a risk of trying to pull this off right under this police sergeant's nose. Some on this site have complained about Brad Pitt's Irish accent, however I thought Pitt was easily the best part of this film. He succeeded in creating a troubled, but somewhat sympathetic character. It is his performance that I even gave this film a 4. Treat Williams was also very good as the mean, black-hearted weapons contact for Pitt's character in New York. I had enormous problems with Harrison Ford's efforts in this movie, if "efforts" is the right word. When Ford first burst on to the scene many years ago, he looked like a solid, creative acting talent. However, in recent years, he has taken on this goody-goody, moralistic, cutesy-pie, boy scout character style which he seems to hide behind, and it's just ridiculous, and reflects really lazy acting (see: "Air Force One" and "Patriot Games", to name two). It is truly irritating and disappointing, and brought this movie way down in my view. I had trouble swallowing the premise, but Ford's performance just made this cringe-inducing to me.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Cast Saves The Film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    SiliconDesertMan40
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/12/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A movie about Irishmen,The Devil's Own is an action thriller that stars Harrison Ford and Brad Pitt together with Rub&eacute;n Blades, Natascha McElhone, Julia Stiles and Treat Williams.This is about a policeman plays Good Samaritan to a visitor from Ireland, only to discover that he has a potentially deadly secret.This was the final film directed by Alan J. Pakula. Belfast-born Frankie McGuire saw his father gunned down by enemy soldiers at the age of eight, and when he grew up he joined the Irish Republican Army, determined that one day his father's death would be avenged. An especially ruthless "volunteer," Frankie is responsible for the death of 13 British soldiers and 11 policemen. After a particularly bloody battle, Frankie sails to the United States in a ragged tugboat he has restored; with a huge bundle of cash, Frankie intends to buy a stock of Stinger missiles from an underground arms dealer in America, Billy Burke. Upon arrival in New York, Frankie is met by a judge who is sympathetic to the IRA's cause and who arranges a place for him to stay. Using the name Rory Devaney, Frankie moves into the home of Tom O'Meara, a scrupulously honest cop. Tom is already in the midst of a personal crisis; his friend and partner Edwin Diaz recently shot a man that he knew was unarmed in the line of duty, and while Edwin wants Tom to help him cover up the matter, Tom's conscience will not allow it. When Tom begins to realize that "Rory" is not simply a man running from the violence of his homeland, he's torn between his sympathy for Frankie's tragic childhood and his desire to see justice served and prevent needless death in Ireland. Although it was it showed ignorance of the history of Northern Ireland and the issues involved are never mentioned,it becomes watchable to a degree due to the presence of Harrison Ford and Brad Pitt.Also,the story was somewhat formulaic,contrived and predictable. With Ford and Pitt,it would have been a disaster.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Hollywood Movie about the IRA
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    david-sarkies
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/12/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    When looking at this movie through the advertisements it sounds like an action movie where a cop (Harrison Ford) is chasing some murderous psychopath (Brad Pitt); that was the impression that I got, and the title doesn't really help that much either for it makes Pitt's character sound like some really evil and sadistic man. He is not. This movie is based around the IRA activities in Ireland and the main character is Brad Pitt. The entire movie is centered around him. The basic plot is that the British are gaining the upper hand because they have helicopters so Pitt must go over to the United States and smuggle some stinger missiles back into Northern Ireland to deal with it. The movie opens with Pitt's father being murdered and then moves to the present day where his character is being hunted down by the British. This quickly dissolves into a huge gun battle in the middle of Belfast where the British are basically using force of numbers to suppress the situation, and even then they fail to achieve their goal. The bulk of the movie takes place in the United States and has very little action. It revolves around Pitt arranging the deal. Unfortunately things go slightly wrong and the deal has to be postponed, which upsets the crime lord who is arranging it no end. There is very little in the way of constant pursuit between Harrison Ford and Brad Pitt. In most cases they are friends, though Ford is ignorant of the true nature of Pitt's character. It is only when the crime lord starts putting pressure onto Pitt that things start happening. When they do, the viewer (or at least myself) starts to have sympathy for Pitt. He is not an evil man, he is just a soldier fighting a war. There is a struggle between him and Ford for we like both but we know that they cannot help each other. The real enemy, and even Ford sees this, is the British. Even Harrison Ford has sympathy for Pitt's character by the end of the movie. The Devil's Own is neither a fast movie nor is it an action movie. The video labels it as a thriller but even then I didn't think much of that. It is hard to put it into a category. If you are looking for a fast action movie, then look for something else. Even though, I still liked this movie and thought that the character development was in itself quite good.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I Could Only Long to be Put Through More "Troubled Productions" Like This One.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jzappa
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/10/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Justice is the summation of all ethical responsibility, but there are conflicting slants on justice. This reality is at the heart of this ignorantly underrated and dismissed film, which meets just gently with The Troubles. Rather, it searches the sad natural history of violence and how individual and social variables shape our slants on it. This is a film of various different tensions in which nobody is unreservedly right or wrong. Characteristic of Pakula's films, The Devil's Own has a solemn, subdued atmosphere that mutely connotes magnitude and seriousness. Cinematographer Gordon Willis' inimitable use of light and dark is especially effective in a scene where Tom and Rory are caught in the sporadic lights of moving cars, a pertinent image for a story in which honor's moorland is so transitory. An Irish-American judge coordinates for Rory Devaney, an Irish rebel, to lodge in the suburban home of NYC police sergeant Tom O'Meara. This upright cop, his wife and their daughters haven't a clue as to Rory's real identity. While Rory is occupied obtaining Stinger missiles from Treat Williams' American gang boss, Rory discovers himself emotionally enticed by his host family's life. He hasn't known this sense of comfort and peace since childhood before his father was slain before his eyes by a British agent. As the arms deal plods on, ample time is left for the two men to connect, and for Rory to feel remorse facing Tom's morality and virtual pacifism. Meanwhile, Tom confronts the prime predicament of his career when his partner Ruben Blades shoots an unarmed offender in the back and then presumes upon him to suppress it. Tom chooses to retire. But before he can submit his badge, he's dragged into Rory's nightmare when it invades and terrorizes his home. Pitt and Ford give moving and realistic performances as two men whose fanatical dedication to justice puts them on a path to conflict. Instead of stressing epinephrine-boosting action sequences, Pakula fixes the film on the ethical clash between the resistance fighter and the unfaltering advocate of law and order. The action sequences are intermittent but vigorously ringing, with a premium put on the enduring formation of character. At an early stage of their growing personal rapport, Rory tells Tom, "Don't look for a happy ending. It's not an American story. It's an Irish one." The two actors have remarkable pull on one another. When they're together on screen, you want to focus on both of them. They don't seek to trump one another, but to enforce one another's sincerity. The Devil's Own unmistakably seeks to build a father-son histrionic between Tom who has no sons and Rory, and it succeeds mainly since it never labors overmuch to labor on emphasis. Their relationship is relaxed and unaffected. A game of pool here, a snippet of conversation there. And Pakula counts on the actors to create a bond without turning to banal dialogue or unseemly bursts of emotion. These are two understated, strong-minded men who just appear to admire and enjoy one another. And when Pitt turns unreservedly cold-blooded when he's forced into a corner, Pitt gives him the disillusionment of a guy who can't meet the expense of a conscience. This point is that it's unfeasible to choose sides, a point distinctive for a Hollywood film, a battle between people whose virtues were decided by their circumstances. Naysayers called the plot incoherent, just a lot of moral grappling, not all of which relevant. Funny how they didn't say that about the character of Mike Yanagita in Fargo, for instance. It's as if it was new to critics that emotional associations with the plot we care about could be made by characters whose experiences outside that main plot course it's important we see first-hand with them to grasp their ethical arcs.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Bad assessment of this movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Editingwhiz
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/9/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The lead review of this movie is vastly unfair. Just because it is written by some one from Belfast who professes to know it all about such topics doesn't mean what he says is relevant for everybody. The fact is that there are interesting relationships between the characters here, you feel empathy for the terrorist character (Brad Pitt), and you feel the pain of Harrison Ford's NYC cop when he partner is killed. The FBI and BI people are in the movie for about 3 minutes -- how can any conclusions be drawn about them? I personally thought it was a tight thriller and it kept my interest the whole time. Ford and Pitt were excellent in their roles. Pitt, despite what the other bloke said, kept his accent quite well throughout. I am a journalist who looks objectively at such things as film and entertainment, I just thought the top review sold this movie way way short.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Hypothetical and Moral Imperatives.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Robert J. Maxwell (rmax304823@yahoo.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/8/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Reuben Blades is the good-natured but fallible cop who is the friend and partner of officer Harrison Ford on the NYPD. The minute he showed up on screen I figured he was toast. The instrument of Blades' demise is Brad Pitt. Pitt is an IRA agent visiting the US to buy some guns and rockets from the ruthless entrepreneur Treat Williams. Pitt is a nice-looking, clean-shaven young man who finds room and board with Ford's accommodating family. Pitt, harboring a pustular hatred because of some politically caused childhood trauma, is gradually drawn into the peaceful life of Ford's household. They have a couple of lovely kids, say grace before meals, go to the same church as Pitt. They're Irish-American too. The only thing is that they haven't witnessed the suffering that Pitt has on the Auld Sod. It's really Pitt's movie. Harrison Ford cheats a little to save his partner's pension but is otherwise stalwart in upholding the law. Pitt, on the other hand, becomes a man of divided allegiances. He admires and respects Ford and his life style. He doesn't want the family to get into trouble. Yet here is Pitt, hiding a fortune in dollars under the floor of Ford's bathroom, about to buy guns so that the killing in Ireland can go on. The moral act, the moral imperative, is to reject the killing and embrace the warmth of family life. The hypothetical imperative is to complete his mission, smuggle the guns back into Ireland, and garner the accolades that are earned by heroes of the movement. That's not a moral act but it lays out what's in it for Pitt. I don't really want to get into it, partly because Immanuel Kant is complicated, partly because space is limited, and partly because I'm not sure I know what the hell I'm talking about. But my understanding is that you can determine whether a course is moral or not by asking what would happen if everyone followed it. Obviously, in this instance, the bloodshed in Ireland stops if Pitt overcomes his personal desire for revenge and stops shedding blood. The conflict and the final shoot out -- among several violent shoot outs -- is inevitable. And the confrontation involves more than just an uptight cop and a reckless revolutionary. The writers, of course, don't want to alienate those Irish-American viewers who are in thrall to what sociologists have called "the new ethnicity" -- a fiercely sentimental attachment to origins they know little about -- so they have Pitt explain (twice) that, "It's not an American problem; it's an Irish problem." Whatever that means. As Ford's wife, Margaret Colin is pretty and nurturing looking. Ford himself, looking old enough to have spent twenty-four years on the police force, isn't any more expressive than he usually is. He's not a bravura performer. He's reliable. Brad Pitt gives an absorbing and likable performance -- a quiet, appreciative, thoughtful, reckless revolutionary maniac -- who brings some unexpected touches to the role. He has more range than I'd been giving him credit for, although he can still turn in a wincingly wrong performance, as in "Seven." I've always admired Treat Williams's performances in a low-key way. He's been pretty good in some roles, like "Prince of the City," but I think his career has been knee-capped by his having a voice that isn't strong, and that sounds so natural that it seems he's not really able to enact a role.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I liked this movie!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    allwrangledup
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/6/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I won't argue some of the criticisms that I'm reading in other people's reviews here -- but I really liked this movie. I thought that Pitt and Harrison (and most of the others)did some solid acting in this movie. And I actually thought the accents were pretty decent! The action scenes may not have been entirely plausible, but they still worked overall. I liked the relationship storyline/s, and the fact that not everything was perfect. And it wasn't all predictable. Good movie overall. I would recommend it. I like action movies, I also like good "people" story lines. I thought this movie contained both. Like a good, easily readable book.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    All the same, Mr. Fitzsimmoms, if you're not confused, you don't know what's going' on.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    lastliberal
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/4/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It amazes me that people look at every film about political situations as if they should be documentaries. This is a film about the relationship between a New York cop (Harrison Ford), and an IRA terrorist (Brad Pitt) in the US to pick up weapons. It is not meant to be a polemic on the Irish situation. Ford plays a cop that cares about the law and about justice. His partner (Rub&eacute;n Blades) shoots an unarmed teen and Ford actually is the one who gets sick. "We are in the police business, not the revenge business," he tells him. Despite the fact that he has killed 20 men, Pitt comes off as his most lovable self. He fits in well with Ford's family. Things fall apart after the weapons deal is delayed and that's when the real action starts. Ford and Pitt were brilliant, although I hated the ending.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The IRA Versus The NYPD
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    zardoz-13
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Harrison Ford & Brad Pitt terrorist thriller "The Devil's Own" features New York cops, British assassins, IRA gunmen, and examples of modern-day intimidation. Nevertheless, it remains as old-fashioned and predictable as any episode of the western television classic "Gunsmoke." Veteran filmmaker Alan J. Pakula, whose credits include "Presumed Innocent" (1990) and "The Pelican Brief" (1994), has crafted a serious, above-average, tight-lipped melodrama that buckles more often than it should but delivers an attractive cast in a handsome actioneer. "V.I. Warshawski" scribe David Aaron Cohen, and "Family Business" scenarist Vincent Patrick and "Tombstone" writer Kevin Jarre collaborated on a screenplay that constitutes sheer hokum of an inspirational sort. Although the film sports a laugh or two, "The Devil's Own" emerges as a dark, tragic saga that "Godfather" lenser Gordon Willis has enhanced with his moody Rembrandt lighting. Brad Pitt is suitably cast as an Irish Republican Army gunman named Rory Devaney. When he was a lad, Rory saw merciless British gunmen gun down his dad at the supper table. He still lives with this bitter memory. He has grown up and become a ruthless killer who the British are prepared to track the earth to liquidate. The ever dependable Harrison Ford shows up later as Tom O'Meara, an honest Irish-American career cop with a wife, Sheila O'Meara (Margaret Colin of "Independence Day") and two daughters. A highly situated IRA sympathizer smuggles Roy into New York City on fake passports and obtains room and board for him in O'Meara's happy domicile. Naturally, Tom doesn't have a clue about Roy's notorious identity. He believes Rory is a construction worker. What O'Meara learns in one devastating betrayal after another is that Rory has come to America to buy surface-to-air missiles to be used against the British. When Tom learns the truth and finds himself pitted against Rory, the reality of the predicament takes on a deeper meaning for him. Meanwhile, Rory encounters Billy Burke (Treat Williams of "Hair") and his bunch of ham-fisted thugs who don't share his dedication to the cause. They simply want their loot for the contraband missiles that they have purchased for Rory. Burke makes the fatal mistake of double-crossing Rory. Although we want to believe that all lawmen are as dedicated as Ford's Tom O'Meara, our hero here seems incredibly saintly, a reincarnation of Dodge City Marshall Matt Dillon for the 1990s who turns shoplifters loose after catching them red-handed with the goods. When our hero's partner Edwin Diaz (well played by Ruben Blades) shoots a thief who had discarded his gun, O'Meara refuses to lie on his behalf. Afterward, O'Meara confides to Sheila that he cannot go on being a cop because of the shooting incident. O'Meara possesses principles that are far beyond believable. If Pakula and company err in over sanctifying Ford's straightforward N.Y.P.D. cop, they miss the boat completely with Pitt's renegade gunsel. While he is battling it out with British troops in blood-splattered Ireland, the Rory Devaney character is appropriately vicious. Once he reaches America, Roy treads somewhere between a hard-bitten villain and a tragic victim who constantly cradles Ford's youngest daughter. All of which dilutes the visceral turbulence that the filmmakers do such a good job of stirring up but never resolving. Hollywood used to steer clear of hot-potato political issues, but "The Devil's Own" appears to weigh its scales of cinematic justice in favor of the underdog IRA. Indeed, this Columbia Pictures Release is a movie with an Irish ending. The British come off looking more villainous than anybody else. Happily, "The Devils' Own" is not the botched film that Pitt has proclaimed in the press. While the movie ripples with violence, the violence here is used to decide who is morally culpable in a less-than-perfect world. The strategy that the filmmakers used in the final shoot-out to get you to bite your fingernails is well-staged but hopelessly heavy-handed. Men will show up for the shoot-outs, especially in the early parts of the action, while women may find themselves swooning over Pitt and Ford. Ultimately, "The Devil's Own" is an entertaining but pretentious load of nonsense that looks terrific on the big screen.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    given the fear of terrorism today....
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    blanche-2
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    ..."The Devil's Own" from 1997 isn't a great film. Starring Harrison Ford, Brad Pitt, Treat Williams, Ruben Blades, and Margaret Colin, the story concerns a Northern Ireland IRA terrorist, Frankie McGuire, who comes to New York to buy weapons. Using the name of Rory Delaney, a judge, Peter Fitzsimmons puts him up at the home of an Irish cop, Tom O'Meara. O'Meara has no idea of Frankie's identity. Rory has brought a ton of money with him and is supposed to make a deal with one Billy Burke (Williams). When he is told by his superiors in Ireland to hold off, Burke gets tough and wants the money. When Tom's house is robbed, his wife held at gunpoint, but nothing taken, Tom begins to wonder about his houseguest. With good reason. Tom himself is having a crisis of conscience when he supports his partner Eddie (Blades) by lying about a shooting. This could have been an excellent film, as it's about two men with completely different moral codes, both believing they're right. Frankie saw his father killed in front of him when he was eight years old, and this started him on the road to killings. Tom has drawn his gun only a few times in all the years he's been a police officer. The problem is that this is muddied by the script being somewhat pro-terrorism. In today's climate, pro-terrorist films with sympathetic killers don't go over well. As someone pointed out, if this had been about someone from the Middle East partly responsible for 9/11 portrayed this way, it probably wouldn't be made. Brad Pitt does a good job, despite some of his accent problems. Harrison Ford is solid but a little boring. The ending was the best part. We don't hear much about the Irish conflict anymore, but years ago, many charities purportedly for Irish children were fronts for collecting money to support the IRA. My sister pointed this out to an Irish friend once, who was about to give such a charity some money, and she said, "So what?" So what? Terrorism isn't right, no matter which side resorts to it. It's understandable that Frankie/Rory had strong feelings, but there are other ways to deal with them. Kind of annoying.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not really very good
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jmorrison-2
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The initial problem I had with this film is the fact that an IRA soldier, in New York to buy and transport weapons to bring back to Ireland, would bunk in with an NYPD Sergeant and his family. That sounds like asking for trouble to me. Not a smart move. I can't imagine the IRA sanctioning a rather reckless move like this. The large amount of money Pitt's character was carrying, and the importance of these weapons making it to Ireland had me shaking my head in disbelief that Rory (Pitt's character) would take such a risk of trying to pull this off right under this police sergeant's nose. Some on this site have complained about Brad Pitt's Irish accent, however I thought Pitt was easily the best part of this film. He succeeded in creating a troubled, but somewhat sympathetic character. It is his performance that I even gave this film a 4. Treat Williams was also very good as the mean, black-hearted weapons contact for Pitt's character in New York. I had enormous problems with Harrison Ford's efforts in this movie, if "efforts" is the right word. When Ford first burst on to the scene many years ago, he looked like a solid, creative acting talent. However, in recent years, he has taken on this goody-goody, moralistic, cutesy-pie, boy scout character style which he seems to hide behind, and it's just ridiculous, and reflects really lazy acting (see: "Air Force One" and "Patriot Games", to name two). It is truly irritating and disappointing, and brought this movie way down in my view. I had trouble swallowing the premise, but Ford's performance just made this cringe-inducing to me.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Cast Saves The Film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    SiliconDesertMan40
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/12/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A movie about Irishmen,The Devil's Own is an action thriller that stars Harrison Ford and Brad Pitt together with Rub&eacute;n Blades, Natascha McElhone, Julia Stiles and Treat Williams.This is about a policeman plays Good Samaritan to a visitor from Ireland, only to discover that he has a potentially deadly secret.This was the final film directed by Alan J. Pakula. Belfast-born Frankie McGuire saw his father gunned down by enemy soldiers at the age of eight, and when he grew up he joined the Irish Republican Army, determined that one day his father's death would be avenged. An especially ruthless "volunteer," Frankie is responsible for the death of 13 British soldiers and 11 policemen. After a particularly bloody battle, Frankie sails to the United States in a ragged tugboat he has restored; with a huge bundle of cash, Frankie intends to buy a stock of Stinger missiles from an underground arms dealer in America, Billy Burke. Upon arrival in New York, Frankie is met by a judge who is sympathetic to the IRA's cause and who arranges a place for him to stay. Using the name Rory Devaney, Frankie moves into the home of Tom O'Meara, a scrupulously honest cop. Tom is already in the midst of a personal crisis; his friend and partner Edwin Diaz recently shot a man that he knew was unarmed in the line of duty, and while Edwin wants Tom to help him cover up the matter, Tom's conscience will not allow it. When Tom begins to realize that "Rory" is not simply a man running from the violence of his homeland, he's torn between his sympathy for Frankie's tragic childhood and his desire to see justice served and prevent needless death in Ireland. Although it was it showed ignorance of the history of Northern Ireland and the issues involved are never mentioned,it becomes watchable to a degree due to the presence of Harrison Ford and Brad Pitt.Also,the story was somewhat formulaic,contrived and predictable. With Ford and Pitt,it would have been a disaster.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Hollywood Movie about the IRA
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    david-sarkies
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/12/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    When looking at this movie through the advertisements it sounds like an action movie where a cop (Harrison Ford) is chasing some murderous psychopath (Brad Pitt); that was the impression that I got, and the title doesn't really help that much either for it makes Pitt's character sound like some really evil and sadistic man. He is not. This movie is based around the IRA activities in Ireland and the main character is Brad Pitt. The entire movie is centered around him. The basic plot is that the British are gaining the upper hand because they have helicopters so Pitt must go over to the United States and smuggle some stinger missiles back into Northern Ireland to deal with it. The movie opens with Pitt's father being murdered and then moves to the present day where his character is being hunted down by the British. This quickly dissolves into a huge gun battle in the middle of Belfast where the British are basically using force of numbers to suppress the situation, and even then they fail to achieve their goal. The bulk of the movie takes place in the United States and has very little action. It revolves around Pitt arranging the deal. Unfortunately things go slightly wrong and the deal has to be postponed, which upsets the crime lord who is arranging it no end. There is very little in the way of constant pursuit between Harrison Ford and Brad Pitt. In most cases they are friends, though Ford is ignorant of the true nature of Pitt's character. It is only when the crime lord starts putting pressure onto Pitt that things start happening. When they do, the viewer (or at least myself) starts to have sympathy for Pitt. He is not an evil man, he is just a soldier fighting a war. There is a struggle between him and Ford for we like both but we know that they cannot help each other. The real enemy, and even Ford sees this, is the British. Even Harrison Ford has sympathy for Pitt's character by the end of the movie. The Devil's Own is neither a fast movie nor is it an action movie. The video labels it as a thriller but even then I didn't think much of that. It is hard to put it into a category. If you are looking for a fast action movie, then look for something else. Even though, I still liked this movie and thought that the character development was in itself quite good.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I Could Only Long to be Put Through More "Troubled Productions" Like This One.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jzappa
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/10/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Justice is the summation of all ethical responsibility, but there are conflicting slants on justice. This reality is at the heart of this ignorantly underrated and dismissed film, which meets just gently with The Troubles. Rather, it searches the sad natural history of violence and how individual and social variables shape our slants on it. This is a film of various different tensions in which nobody is unreservedly right or wrong. Characteristic of Pakula's films, The Devil's Own has a solemn, subdued atmosphere that mutely connotes magnitude and seriousness. Cinematographer Gordon Willis' inimitable use of light and dark is especially effective in a scene where Tom and Rory are caught in the sporadic lights of moving cars, a pertinent image for a story in which honor's moorland is so transitory. An Irish-American judge coordinates for Rory Devaney, an Irish rebel, to lodge in the suburban home of NYC police sergeant Tom O'Meara. This upright cop, his wife and their daughters haven't a clue as to Rory's real identity. While Rory is occupied obtaining Stinger missiles from Treat Williams' American gang boss, Rory discovers himself emotionally enticed by his host family's life. He hasn't known this sense of comfort and peace since childhood before his father was slain before his eyes by a British agent. As the arms deal plods on, ample time is left for the two men to connect, and for Rory to feel remorse facing Tom's morality and virtual pacifism. Meanwhile, Tom confronts the prime predicament of his career when his partner Ruben Blades shoots an unarmed offender in the back and then presumes upon him to suppress it. Tom chooses to retire. But before he can submit his badge, he's dragged into Rory's nightmare when it invades and terrorizes his home. Pitt and Ford give moving and realistic performances as two men whose fanatical dedication to justice puts them on a path to conflict. Instead of stressing epinephrine-boosting action sequences, Pakula fixes the film on the ethical clash between the resistance fighter and the unfaltering advocate of law and order. The action sequences are intermittent but vigorously ringing, with a premium put on the enduring formation of character. At an early stage of their growing personal rapport, Rory tells Tom, "Don't look for a happy ending. It's not an American story. It's an Irish one." The two actors have remarkable pull on one another. When they're together on screen, you want to focus on both of them. They don't seek to trump one another, but to enforce one another's sincerity. The Devil's Own unmistakably seeks to build a father-son histrionic between Tom who has no sons and Rory, and it succeeds mainly since it never labors overmuch to labor on emphasis. Their relationship is relaxed and unaffected. A game of pool here, a snippet of conversation there. And Pakula counts on the actors to create a bond without turning to banal dialogue or unseemly bursts of emotion. These are two understated, strong-minded men who just appear to admire and enjoy one another. And when Pitt turns unreservedly cold-blooded when he's forced into a corner, Pitt gives him the disillusionment of a guy who can't meet the expense of a conscience. This point is that it's unfeasible to choose sides, a point distinctive for a Hollywood film, a battle between people whose virtues were decided by their circumstances. Naysayers called the plot incoherent, just a lot of moral grappling, not all of which relevant. Funny how they didn't say that about the character of Mike Yanagita in Fargo, for instance. It's as if it was new to critics that emotional associations with the plot we care about could be made by characters whose experiences outside that main plot course it's important we see first-hand with them to grasp their ethical arcs.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Bad assessment of this movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Editingwhiz
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/9/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The lead review of this movie is vastly unfair. Just because it is written by some one from Belfast who professes to know it all about such topics doesn't mean what he says is relevant for everybody. The fact is that there are interesting relationships between the characters here, you feel empathy for the terrorist character (Brad Pitt), and you feel the pain of Harrison Ford's NYC cop when he partner is killed. The FBI and BI people are in the movie for about 3 minutes -- how can any conclusions be drawn about them? I personally thought it was a tight thriller and it kept my interest the whole time. Ford and Pitt were excellent in their roles. Pitt, despite what the other bloke said, kept his accent quite well throughout. I am a journalist who looks objectively at such things as film and entertainment, I just thought the top review sold this movie way way short.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Hypothetical and Moral Imperatives.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Robert J. Maxwell (rmax304823@yahoo.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/8/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Reuben Blades is the good-natured but fallible cop who is the friend and partner of officer Harrison Ford on the NYPD. The minute he showed up on screen I figured he was toast. The instrument of Blades' demise is Brad Pitt. Pitt is an IRA agent visiting the US to buy some guns and rockets from the ruthless entrepreneur Treat Williams. Pitt is a nice-looking, clean-shaven young man who finds room and board with Ford's accommodating family. Pitt, harboring a pustular hatred because of some politically caused childhood trauma, is gradually drawn into the peaceful life of Ford's household. They have a couple of lovely kids, say grace before meals, go to the same church as Pitt. They're Irish-American too. The only thing is that they haven't witnessed the suffering that Pitt has on the Auld Sod. It's really Pitt's movie. Harrison Ford cheats a little to save his partner's pension but is otherwise stalwart in upholding the law. Pitt, on the other hand, becomes a man of divided allegiances. He admires and respects Ford and his life style. He doesn't want the family to get into trouble. Yet here is Pitt, hiding a fortune in dollars under the floor of Ford's bathroom, about to buy guns so that the killing in Ireland can go on. The moral act, the moral imperative, is to reject the killing and embrace the warmth of family life. The hypothetical imperative is to complete his mission, smuggle the guns back into Ireland, and garner the accolades that are earned by heroes of the movement. That's not a moral act but it lays out what's in it for Pitt. I don't really want to get into it, partly because Immanuel Kant is complicated, partly because space is limited, and partly because I'm not sure I know what the hell I'm talking about. But my understanding is that you can determine whether a course is moral or not by asking what would happen if everyone followed it. Obviously, in this instance, the bloodshed in Ireland stops if Pitt overcomes his personal desire for revenge and stops shedding blood. The conflict and the final shoot out -- among several violent shoot outs -- is inevitable. And the confrontation involves more than just an uptight cop and a reckless revolutionary. The writers, of course, don't want to alienate those Irish-American viewers who are in thrall to what sociologists have called "the new ethnicity" -- a fiercely sentimental attachment to origins they know little about -- so they have Pitt explain (twice) that, "It's not an American problem; it's an Irish problem." Whatever that means. As Ford's wife, Margaret Colin is pretty and nurturing looking. Ford himself, looking old enough to have spent twenty-four years on the police force, isn't any more expressive than he usually is. He's not a bravura performer. He's reliable. Brad Pitt gives an absorbing and likable performance -- a quiet, appreciative, thoughtful, reckless revolutionary maniac -- who brings some unexpected touches to the role. He has more range than I'd been giving him credit for, although he can still turn in a wincingly wrong performance, as in "Seven." I've always admired Treat Williams's performances in a low-key way. He's been pretty good in some roles, like "Prince of the City," but I think his career has been knee-capped by his having a voice that isn't strong, and that sounds so natural that it seems he's not really able to enact a role.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I liked this movie!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    allwrangledup
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/6/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I won't argue some of the criticisms that I'm reading in other people's reviews here -- but I really liked this movie. I thought that Pitt and Harrison (and most of the others)did some solid acting in this movie. And I actually thought the accents were pretty decent! The action scenes may not have been entirely plausible, but they still worked overall. I liked the relationship storyline/s, and the fact that not everything was perfect. And it wasn't all predictable. Good movie overall. I would recommend it. I like action movies, I also like good "people" story lines. I thought this movie contained both. Like a good, easily readable book.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    All the same, Mr. Fitzsimmoms, if you're not confused, you don't know what's going' on.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    lastliberal
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/4/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It amazes me that people look at every film about political situations as if they should be documentaries. This is a film about the relationship between a New York cop (Harrison Ford), and an IRA terrorist (Brad Pitt) in the US to pick up weapons. It is not meant to be a polemic on the Irish situation. Ford plays a cop that cares about the law and about justice. His partner (Rub&eacute;n Blades) shoots an unarmed teen and Ford actually is the one who gets sick. "We are in the police business, not the revenge business," he tells him. Despite the fact that he has killed 20 men, Pitt comes off as his most lovable self. He fits in well with Ford's family. Things fall apart after the weapons deal is delayed and that's when the real action starts. Ford and Pitt were brilliant, although I hated the ending.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The IRA Versus The NYPD
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    zardoz-13
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Harrison Ford & Brad Pitt terrorist thriller "The Devil's Own" features New York cops, British assassins, IRA gunmen, and examples of modern-day intimidation. Nevertheless, it remains as old-fashioned and predictable as any episode of the western television classic "Gunsmoke." Veteran filmmaker Alan J. Pakula, whose credits include "Presumed Innocent" (1990) and "The Pelican Brief" (1994), has crafted a serious, above-average, tight-lipped melodrama that buckles more often than it should but delivers an attractive cast in a handsome actioneer. "V.I. Warshawski" scribe David Aaron Cohen, and "Family Business" scenarist Vincent Patrick and "Tombstone" writer Kevin Jarre collaborated on a screenplay that constitutes sheer hokum of an inspirational sort. Although the film sports a laugh or two, "The Devil's Own" emerges as a dark, tragic saga that "Godfather" lenser Gordon Willis has enhanced with his moody Rembrandt lighting. Brad Pitt is suitably cast as an Irish Republican Army gunman named Rory Devaney. When he was a lad, Rory saw merciless British gunmen gun down his dad at the supper table. He still lives with this bitter memory. He has grown up and become a ruthless killer who the British are prepared to track the earth to liquidate. The ever dependable Harrison Ford shows up later as Tom O'Meara, an honest Irish-American career cop with a wife, Sheila O'Meara (Margaret Colin of "Independence Day") and two daughters. A highly situated IRA sympathizer smuggles Roy into New York City on fake passports and obtains room and board for him in O'Meara's happy domicile. Naturally, Tom doesn't have a clue about Roy's notorious identity. He believes Rory is a construction worker. What O'Meara learns in one devastating betrayal after another is that Rory has come to America to buy surface-to-air missiles to be used against the British. When Tom learns the truth and finds himself pitted against Rory, the reality of the predicament takes on a deeper meaning for him. Meanwhile, Rory encounters Billy Burke (Treat Williams of "Hair") and his bunch of ham-fisted thugs who don't share his dedication to the cause. They simply want their loot for the contraband missiles that they have purchased for Rory. Burke makes the fatal mistake of double-crossing Rory. Although we want to believe that all lawmen are as dedicated as Ford's Tom O'Meara, our hero here seems incredibly saintly, a reincarnation of Dodge City Marshall Matt Dillon for the 1990s who turns shoplifters loose after catching them red-handed with the goods. When our hero's partner Edwin Diaz (well played by Ruben Blades) shoots a thief who had discarded his gun, O'Meara refuses to lie on his behalf. Afterward, O'Meara confides to Sheila that he cannot go on being a cop because of the shooting incident. O'Meara possesses principles that are far beyond believable. If Pakula and company err in over sanctifying Ford's straightforward N.Y.P.D. cop, they miss the boat completely with Pitt's renegade gunsel. While he is battling it out with British troops in blood-splattered Ireland, the Rory Devaney character is appropriately vicious. Once he reaches America, Roy treads somewhere between a hard-bitten villain and a tragic victim who constantly cradles Ford's youngest daughter. All of which dilutes the visceral turbulence that the filmmakers do such a good job of stirring up but never resolving. Hollywood used to steer clear of hot-potato political issues, but "The Devil's Own" appears to weigh its scales of cinematic justice in favor of the underdog IRA. Indeed, this Columbia Pictures Release is a movie with an Irish ending. The British come off looking more villainous than anybody else. Happily, "The Devils' Own" is not the botched film that Pitt has proclaimed in the press. While the movie ripples with violence, the violence here is used to decide who is morally culpable in a less-than-perfect world. The strategy that the filmmakers used in the final shoot-out to get you to bite your fingernails is well-staged but hopelessly heavy-handed. Men will show up for the shoot-outs, especially in the early parts of the action, while women may find themselves swooning over Pitt and Ford. Ultimately, "The Devil's Own" is an entertaining but pretentious load of nonsense that looks terrific on the big screen.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    given the fear of terrorism today....
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    blanche-2
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    ..."The Devil's Own" from 1997 isn't a great film. Starring Harrison Ford, Brad Pitt, Treat Williams, Ruben Blades, and Margaret Colin, the story concerns a Northern Ireland IRA terrorist, Frankie McGuire, who comes to New York to buy weapons. Using the name of Rory Delaney, a judge, Peter Fitzsimmons puts him up at the home of an Irish cop, Tom O'Meara. O'Meara has no idea of Frankie's identity. Rory has brought a ton of money with him and is supposed to make a deal with one Billy Burke (Williams). When he is told by his superiors in Ireland to hold off, Burke gets tough and wants the money. When Tom's house is robbed, his wife held at gunpoint, but nothing taken, Tom begins to wonder about his houseguest. With good reason. Tom himself is having a crisis of conscience when he supports his partner Eddie (Blades) by lying about a shooting. This could have been an excellent film, as it's about two men with completely different moral codes, both believing they're right. Frankie saw his father killed in front of him when he was eight years old, and this started him on the road to killings. Tom has drawn his gun only a few times in all the years he's been a police officer. The problem is that this is muddied by the script being somewhat pro-terrorism. In today's climate, pro-terrorist films with sympathetic killers don't go over well. As someone pointed out, if this had been about someone from the Middle East partly responsible for 9/11 portrayed this way, it probably wouldn't be made. Brad Pitt does a good job, despite some of his accent problems. Harrison Ford is solid but a little boring. The ending was the best part. We don't hear much about the Irish conflict anymore, but years ago, many charities purportedly for Irish children were fronts for collecting money to support the IRA. My sister pointed this out to an Irish friend once, who was about to give such a charity some money, and she said, "So what?" So what? Terrorism isn't right, no matter which side resorts to it. It's understandable that Frankie/Rory had strong feelings, but there are other ways to deal with them. Kind of annoying.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not really very good
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jmorrison-2
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The initial problem I had with this film is the fact that an IRA soldier, in New York to buy and transport weapons to bring back to Ireland, would bunk in with an NYPD Sergeant and his family. That sounds like asking for trouble to me. Not a smart move. I can't imagine the IRA sanctioning a rather reckless move like this. The large amount of money Pitt's character was carrying, and the importance of these weapons making it to Ireland had me shaking my head in disbelief that Rory (Pitt's character) would take such a risk of trying to pull this off right under this police sergeant's nose. Some on this site have complained about Brad Pitt's Irish accent, however I thought Pitt was easily the best part of this film. He succeeded in creating a troubled, but somewhat sympathetic character. It is his performance that I even gave this film a 4. Treat Williams was also very good as the mean, black-hearted weapons contact for Pitt's character in New York. I had enormous problems with Harrison Ford's efforts in this movie, if "efforts" is the right word. When Ford first burst on to the scene many years ago, he looked like a solid, creative acting talent. However, in recent years, he has taken on this goody-goody, moralistic, cutesy-pie, boy scout character style which he seems to hide behind, and it's just ridiculous, and reflects really lazy acting (see: "Air Force One" and "Patriot Games", to name two). It is truly irritating and disappointing, and brought this movie way down in my view. I had trouble swallowing the premise, but Ford's performance just made this cringe-inducing to me.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Cast Saves The Film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    SiliconDesertMan40
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/12/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A movie about Irishmen,The Devil's Own is an action thriller that stars Harrison Ford and Brad Pitt together with Rub&eacute;n Blades, Natascha McElhone, Julia Stiles and Treat Williams.This is about a policeman plays Good Samaritan to a visitor from Ireland, only to discover that he has a potentially deadly secret.This was the final film directed by Alan J. Pakula. Belfast-born Frankie McGuire saw his father gunned down by enemy soldiers at the age of eight, and when he grew up he joined the Irish Republican Army, determined that one day his father's death would be avenged. An especially ruthless "volunteer," Frankie is responsible for the death of 13 British soldiers and 11 policemen. After a particularly bloody battle, Frankie sails to the United States in a ragged tugboat he has restored; with a huge bundle of cash, Frankie intends to buy a stock of Stinger missiles from an underground arms dealer in America, Billy Burke. Upon arrival in New York, Frankie is met by a judge who is sympathetic to the IRA's cause and who arranges a place for him to stay. Using the name Rory Devaney, Frankie moves into the home of Tom O'Meara, a scrupulously honest cop. Tom is already in the midst of a personal crisis; his friend and partner Edwin Diaz recently shot a man that he knew was unarmed in the line of duty, and while Edwin wants Tom to help him cover up the matter, Tom's conscience will not allow it. When Tom begins to realize that "Rory" is not simply a man running from the violence of his homeland, he's torn between his sympathy for Frankie's tragic childhood and his desire to see justice served and prevent needless death in Ireland. Although it was it showed ignorance of the history of Northern Ireland and the issues involved are never mentioned,it becomes watchable to a degree due to the presence of Harrison Ford and Brad Pitt.Also,the story was somewhat formulaic,contrived and predictable. With Ford and Pitt,it would have been a disaster.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Hollywood Movie about the IRA
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    david-sarkies
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/12/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    When looking at this movie through the advertisements it sounds like an action movie where a cop (Harrison Ford) is chasing some murderous psychopath (Brad Pitt); that was the impression that I got, and the title doesn't really help that much either for it makes Pitt's character sound like some really evil and sadistic man. He is not. This movie is based around the IRA activities in Ireland and the main character is Brad Pitt. The entire movie is centered around him. The basic plot is that the British are gaining the upper hand because they have helicopters so Pitt must go over to the United States and smuggle some stinger missiles back into Northern Ireland to deal with it. The movie opens with Pitt's father being murdered and then moves to the present day where his character is being hunted down by the British. This quickly dissolves into a huge gun battle in the middle of Belfast where the British are basically using force of numbers to suppress the situation, and even then they fail to achieve their goal. The bulk of the movie takes place in the United States and has very little action. It revolves around Pitt arranging the deal. Unfortunately things go slightly wrong and the deal has to be postponed, which upsets the crime lord who is arranging it no end. There is very little in the way of constant pursuit between Harrison Ford and Brad Pitt. In most cases they are friends, though Ford is ignorant of the true nature of Pitt's character. It is only when the crime lord starts putting pressure onto Pitt that things start happening. When they do, the viewer (or at least myself) starts to have sympathy for Pitt. He is not an evil man, he is just a soldier fighting a war. There is a struggle between him and Ford for we like both but we know that they cannot help each other. The real enemy, and even Ford sees this, is the British. Even Harrison Ford has sympathy for Pitt's character by the end of the movie. The Devil's Own is neither a fast movie nor is it an action movie. The video labels it as a thriller but even then I didn't think much of that. It is hard to put it into a category. If you are looking for a fast action movie, then look for something else. Even though, I still liked this movie and thought that the character development was in itself quite good.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I Could Only Long to be Put Through More "Troubled Productions" Like This One.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jzappa
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/10/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Justice is the summation of all ethical responsibility, but there are conflicting slants on justice. This reality is at the heart of this ignorantly underrated and dismissed film, which meets just gently with The Troubles. Rather, it searches the sad natural history of violence and how individual and social variables shape our slants on it. This is a film of various different tensions in which nobody is unreservedly right or wrong. Characteristic of Pakula's films, The Devil's Own has a solemn, subdued atmosphere that mutely connotes magnitude and seriousness. Cinematographer Gordon Willis' inimitable use of light and dark is especially effective in a scene where Tom and Rory are caught in the sporadic lights of moving cars, a pertinent image for a story in which honor's moorland is so transitory. An Irish-American judge coordinates for Rory Devaney, an Irish rebel, to lodge in the suburban home of NYC police sergeant Tom O'Meara. This upright cop, his wife and their daughters haven't a clue as to Rory's real identity. While Rory is occupied obtaining Stinger missiles from Treat Williams' American gang boss, Rory discovers himself emotionally enticed by his host family's life. He hasn't known this sense of comfort and peace since childhood before his father was slain before his eyes by a British agent. As the arms deal plods on, ample time is left for the two men to connect, and for Rory to feel remorse facing Tom's morality and virtual pacifism. Meanwhile, Tom confronts the prime predicament of his career when his partner Ruben Blades shoots an unarmed offender in the back and then presumes upon him to suppress it. Tom chooses to retire. But before he can submit his badge, he's dragged into Rory's nightmare when it invades and terrorizes his home. Pitt and Ford give moving and realistic performances as two men whose fanatical dedication to justice puts them on a path to conflict. Instead of stressing epinephrine-boosting action sequences, Pakula fixes the film on the ethical clash between the resistance fighter and the unfaltering advocate of law and order. The action sequences are intermittent but vigorously ringing, with a premium put on the enduring formation of character. At an early stage of their growing personal rapport, Rory tells Tom, "Don't look for a happy ending. It's not an American story. It's an Irish one." The two actors have remarkable pull on one another. When they're together on screen, you want to focus on both of them. They don't seek to trump one another, but to enforce one another's sincerity. The Devil's Own unmistakably seeks to build a father-son histrionic between Tom who has no sons and Rory, and it succeeds mainly since it never labors overmuch to labor on emphasis. Their relationship is relaxed and unaffected. A game of pool here, a snippet of conversation there. And Pakula counts on the actors to create a bond without turning to banal dialogue or unseemly bursts of emotion. These are two understated, strong-minded men who just appear to admire and enjoy one another. And when Pitt turns unreservedly cold-blooded when he's forced into a corner, Pitt gives him the disillusionment of a guy who can't meet the expense of a conscience. This point is that it's unfeasible to choose sides, a point distinctive for a Hollywood film, a battle between people whose virtues were decided by their circumstances. Naysayers called the plot incoherent, just a lot of moral grappling, not all of which relevant. Funny how they didn't say that about the character of Mike Yanagita in Fargo, for instance. It's as if it was new to critics that emotional associations with the plot we care about could be made by characters whose experiences outside that main plot course it's important we see first-hand with them to grasp their ethical arcs.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Bad assessment of this movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Editingwhiz
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/9/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The lead review of this movie is vastly unfair. Just because it is written by some one from Belfast who professes to know it all about such topics doesn't mean what he says is relevant for everybody. The fact is that there are interesting relationships between the characters here, you feel empathy for the terrorist character (Brad Pitt), and you feel the pain of Harrison Ford's NYC cop when he partner is killed. The FBI and BI people are in the movie for about 3 minutes -- how can any conclusions be drawn about them? I personally thought it was a tight thriller and it kept my interest the whole time. Ford and Pitt were excellent in their roles. Pitt, despite what the other bloke said, kept his accent quite well throughout. I am a journalist who looks objectively at such things as film and entertainment, I just thought the top review sold this movie way way short.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Hypothetical and Moral Imperatives.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Robert J. Maxwell (rmax304823@yahoo.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/8/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Reuben Blades is the good-natured but fallible cop who is the friend and partner of officer Harrison Ford on the NYPD. The minute he showed up on screen I figured he was toast. The instrument of Blades' demise is Brad Pitt. Pitt is an IRA agent visiting the US to buy some guns and rockets from the ruthless entrepreneur Treat Williams. Pitt is a nice-looking, clean-shaven young man who finds room and board with Ford's accommodating family. Pitt, harboring a pustular hatred because of some politically caused childhood trauma, is gradually drawn into the peaceful life of Ford's household. They have a couple of lovely kids, say grace before meals, go to the same church as Pitt. They're Irish-American too. The only thing is that they haven't witnessed the suffering that Pitt has on the Auld Sod. It's really Pitt's movie. Harrison Ford cheats a little to save his partner's pension but is otherwise stalwart in upholding the law. Pitt, on the other hand, becomes a man of divided allegiances. He admires and respects Ford and his life style. He doesn't want the family to get into trouble. Yet here is Pitt, hiding a fortune in dollars under the floor of Ford's bathroom, about to buy guns so that the killing in Ireland can go on. The moral act, the moral imperative, is to reject the killing and embrace the warmth of family life. The hypothetical imperative is to complete his mission, smuggle the guns back into Ireland, and garner the accolades that are earned by heroes of the movement. That's not a moral act but it lays out what's in it for Pitt. I don't really want to get into it, partly because Immanuel Kant is complicated, partly because space is limited, and partly because I'm not sure I know what the hell I'm talking about. But my understanding is that you can determine whether a course is moral or not by asking what would happen if everyone followed it. Obviously, in this instance, the bloodshed in Ireland stops if Pitt overcomes his personal desire for revenge and stops shedding blood. The conflict and the final shoot out -- among several violent shoot outs -- is inevitable. And the confrontation involves more than just an uptight cop and a reckless revolutionary. The writers, of course, don't want to alienate those Irish-American viewers who are in thrall to what sociologists have called "the new ethnicity" -- a fiercely sentimental attachment to origins they know little about -- so they have Pitt explain (twice) that, "It's not an American problem; it's an Irish problem." Whatever that means. As Ford's wife, Margaret Colin is pretty and nurturing looking. Ford himself, looking old enough to have spent twenty-four years on the police force, isn't any more expressive than he usually is. He's not a bravura performer. He's reliable. Brad Pitt gives an absorbing and likable performance -- a quiet, appreciative, thoughtful, reckless revolutionary maniac -- who brings some unexpected touches to the role. He has more range than I'd been giving him credit for, although he can still turn in a wincingly wrong performance, as in "Seven." I've always admired Treat Williams's performances in a low-key way. He's been pretty good in some roles, like "Prince of the City," but I think his career has been knee-capped by his having a voice that isn't strong, and that sounds so natural that it seems he's not really able to enact a role.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I liked this movie!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    allwrangledup
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/6/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I won't argue some of the criticisms that I'm reading in other people's reviews here -- but I really liked this movie. I thought that Pitt and Harrison (and most of the others)did some solid acting in this movie. And I actually thought the accents were pretty decent! The action scenes may not have been entirely plausible, but they still worked overall. I liked the relationship storyline/s, and the fact that not everything was perfect. And it wasn't all predictable. Good movie overall. I would recommend it. I like action movies, I also like good "people" story lines. I thought this movie contained both. Like a good, easily readable book.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    All the same, Mr. Fitzsimmoms, if you're not confused, you don't know what's going' on.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    lastliberal
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/4/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It amazes me that people look at every film about political situations as if they should be documentaries. This is a film about the relationship between a New York cop (Harrison Ford), and an IRA terrorist (Brad Pitt) in the US to pick up weapons. It is not meant to be a polemic on the Irish situation. Ford plays a cop that cares about the law and about justice. His partner (Rub&eacute;n Blades) shoots an unarmed teen and Ford actually is the one who gets sick. "We are in the police business, not the revenge business," he tells him. Despite the fact that he has killed 20 men, Pitt comes off as his most lovable self. He fits in well with Ford's family. Things fall apart after the weapons deal is delayed and that's when the real action starts. Ford and Pitt were brilliant, although I hated the ending.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The IRA Versus The NYPD
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    zardoz-13
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Harrison Ford & Brad Pitt terrorist thriller "The Devil's Own" features New York cops, British assassins, IRA gunmen, and examples of modern-day intimidation. Nevertheless, it remains as old-fashioned and predictable as any episode of the western television classic "Gunsmoke." Veteran filmmaker Alan J. Pakula, whose credits include "Presumed Innocent" (1990) and "The Pelican Brief" (1994), has crafted a serious, above-average, tight-lipped melodrama that buckles more often than it should but delivers an attractive cast in a handsome actioneer. "V.I. Warshawski" scribe David Aaron Cohen, and "Family Business" scenarist Vincent Patrick and "Tombstone" writer Kevin Jarre collaborated on a screenplay that constitutes sheer hokum of an inspirational sort. Although the film sports a laugh or two, "The Devil's Own" emerges as a dark, tragic saga that "Godfather" lenser Gordon Willis has enhanced with his moody Rembrandt lighting. Brad Pitt is suitably cast as an Irish Republican Army gunman named Rory Devaney. When he was a lad, Rory saw merciless British gunmen gun down his dad at the supper table. He still lives with this bitter memory. He has grown up and become a ruthless killer who the British are prepared to track the earth to liquidate. The ever dependable Harrison Ford shows up later as Tom O'Meara, an honest Irish-American career cop with a wife, Sheila O'Meara (Margaret Colin of "Independence Day") and two daughters. A highly situated IRA sympathizer smuggles Roy into New York City on fake passports and obtains room and board for him in O'Meara's happy domicile. Naturally, Tom doesn't have a clue about Roy's notorious identity. He believes Rory is a construction worker. What O'Meara learns in one devastating betrayal after another is that Rory has come to America to buy surface-to-air missiles to be used against the British. When Tom learns the truth and finds himself pitted against Rory, the reality of the predicament takes on a deeper meaning for him. Meanwhile, Rory encounters Billy Burke (Treat Williams of "Hair") and his bunch of ham-fisted thugs who don't share his dedication to the cause. They simply want their loot for the contraband missiles that they have purchased for Rory. Burke makes the fatal mistake of double-crossing Rory. Although we want to believe that all lawmen are as dedicated as Ford's Tom O'Meara, our hero here seems incredibly saintly, a reincarnation of Dodge City Marshall Matt Dillon for the 1990s who turns shoplifters loose after catching them red-handed with the goods. When our hero's partner Edwin Diaz (well played by Ruben Blades) shoots a thief who had discarded his gun, O'Meara refuses to lie on his behalf. Afterward, O'Meara confides to Sheila that he cannot go on being a cop because of the shooting incident. O'Meara possesses principles that are far beyond believable. If Pakula and company err in over sanctifying Ford's straightforward N.Y.P.D. cop, they miss the boat completely with Pitt's renegade gunsel. While he is battling it out with British troops in blood-splattered Ireland, the Rory Devaney character is appropriately vicious. Once he reaches America, Roy treads somewhere between a hard-bitten villain and a tragic victim who constantly cradles Ford's youngest daughter. All of which dilutes the visceral turbulence that the filmmakers do such a good job of stirring up but never resolving. Hollywood used to steer clear of hot-potato political issues, but "The Devil's Own" appears to weigh its scales of cinematic justice in favor of the underdog IRA. Indeed, this Columbia Pictures Release is a movie with an Irish ending. The British come off looking more villainous than anybody else. Happily, "The Devils' Own" is not the botched film that Pitt has proclaimed in the press. While the movie ripples with violence, the violence here is used to decide who is morally culpable in a less-than-perfect world. The strategy that the filmmakers used in the final shoot-out to get you to bite your fingernails is well-staged but hopelessly heavy-handed. Men will show up for the shoot-outs, especially in the early parts of the action, while women may find themselves swooning over Pitt and Ford. Ultimately, "The Devil's Own" is an entertaining but pretentious load of nonsense that looks terrific on the big screen.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    given the fear of terrorism today....
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    blanche-2
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    ..."The Devil's Own" from 1997 isn't a great film. Starring Harrison Ford, Brad Pitt, Treat Williams, Ruben Blades, and Margaret Colin, the story concerns a Northern Ireland IRA terrorist, Frankie McGuire, who comes to New York to buy weapons. Using the name of Rory Delaney, a judge, Peter Fitzsimmons puts him up at the home of an Irish cop, Tom O'Meara. O'Meara has no idea of Frankie's identity. Rory has brought a ton of money with him and is supposed to make a deal with one Billy Burke (Williams). When he is told by his superiors in Ireland to hold off, Burke gets tough and wants the money. When Tom's house is robbed, his wife held at gunpoint, but nothing taken, Tom begins to wonder about his houseguest. With good reason. Tom himself is having a crisis of conscience when he supports his partner Eddie (Blades) by lying about a shooting. This could have been an excellent film, as it's about two men with completely different moral codes, both believing they're right. Frankie saw his father killed in front of him when he was eight years old, and this started him on the road to killings. Tom has drawn his gun only a few times in all the years he's been a police officer. The problem is that this is muddied by the script being somewhat pro-terrorism. In today's climate, pro-terrorist films with sympathetic killers don't go over well. As someone pointed out, if this had been about someone from the Middle East partly responsible for 9/11 portrayed this way, it probably wouldn't be made. Brad Pitt does a good job, despite some of his accent problems. Harrison Ford is solid but a little boring. The ending was the best part. We don't hear much about the Irish conflict anymore, but years ago, many charities purportedly for Irish children were fronts for collecting money to support the IRA. My sister pointed this out to an Irish friend once, who was about to give such a charity some money, and she said, "So what?" So what? Terrorism isn't right, no matter which side resorts to it. It's understandable that Frankie/Rory had strong feelings, but there are other ways to deal with them. Kind of annoying.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not really very good
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jmorrison-2
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The initial problem I had with this film is the fact that an IRA soldier, in New York to buy and transport weapons to bring back to Ireland, would bunk in with an NYPD Sergeant and his family. That sounds like asking for trouble to me. Not a smart move. I can't imagine the IRA sanctioning a rather reckless move like this. The large amount of money Pitt's character was carrying, and the importance of these weapons making it to Ireland had me shaking my head in disbelief that Rory (Pitt's character) would take such a risk of trying to pull this off right under this police sergeant's nose. Some on this site have complained about Brad Pitt's Irish accent, however I thought Pitt was easily the best part of this film. He succeeded in creating a troubled, but somewhat sympathetic character. It is his performance that I even gave this film a 4. Treat Williams was also very good as the mean, black-hearted weapons contact for Pitt's character in New York. I had enormous problems with Harrison Ford's efforts in this movie, if "efforts" is the right word. When Ford first burst on to the scene many years ago, he looked like a solid, creative acting talent. However, in recent years, he has taken on this goody-goody, moralistic, cutesy-pie, boy scout character style which he seems to hide behind, and it's just ridiculous, and reflects really lazy acting (see: "Air Force One" and "Patriot Games", to name two). It is truly irritating and disappointing, and brought this movie way down in my view. I had trouble swallowing the premise, but Ford's performance just made this cringe-inducing to me.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Cast Saves The Film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    SiliconDesertMan40
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/12/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A movie about Irishmen,The Devil's Own is an action thriller that stars Harrison Ford and Brad Pitt together with Rub&eacute;n Blades, Natascha McElhone, Julia Stiles and Treat Williams.This is about a policeman plays Good Samaritan to a visitor from Ireland, only to discover that he has a potentially deadly secret.This was the final film directed by Alan J. Pakula. Belfast-born Frankie McGuire saw his father gunned down by enemy soldiers at the age of eight, and when he grew up he joined the Irish Republican Army, determined that one day his father's death would be avenged. An especially ruthless "volunteer," Frankie is responsible for the death of 13 British soldiers and 11 policemen. After a particularly bloody battle, Frankie sails to the United States in a ragged tugboat he has restored; with a huge bundle of cash, Frankie intends to buy a stock of Stinger missiles from an underground arms dealer in America, Billy Burke. Upon arrival in New York, Frankie is met by a judge who is sympathetic to the IRA's cause and who arranges a place for him to stay. Using the name Rory Devaney, Frankie moves into the home of Tom O'Meara, a scrupulously honest cop. Tom is already in the midst of a personal crisis; his friend and partner Edwin Diaz recently shot a man that he knew was unarmed in the line of duty, and while Edwin wants Tom to help him cover up the matter, Tom's conscience will not allow it. When Tom begins to realize that "Rory" is not simply a man running from the violence of his homeland, he's torn between his sympathy for Frankie's tragic childhood and his desire to see justice served and prevent needless death in Ireland. Although it was it showed ignorance of the history of Northern Ireland and the issues involved are never mentioned,it becomes watchable to a degree due to the presence of Harrison Ford and Brad Pitt.Also,the story was somewhat formulaic,contrived and predictable. With Ford and Pitt,it would have been a disaster.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Hollywood Movie about the IRA
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    david-sarkies
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/12/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    When looking at this movie through the advertisements it sounds like an action movie where a cop (Harrison Ford) is chasing some murderous psychopath (Brad Pitt); that was the impression that I got, and the title doesn't really help that much either for it makes Pitt's character sound like some really evil and sadistic man. He is not. This movie is based around the IRA activities in Ireland and the main character is Brad Pitt. The entire movie is centered around him. The basic plot is that the British are gaining the upper hand because they have helicopters so Pitt must go over to the United States and smuggle some stinger missiles back into Northern Ireland to deal with it. The movie opens with Pitt's father being murdered and then moves to the present day where his character is being hunted down by the British. This quickly dissolves into a huge gun battle in the middle of Belfast where the British are basically using force of numbers to suppress the situation, and even then they fail to achieve their goal. The bulk of the movie takes place in the United States and has very little action. It revolves around Pitt arranging the deal. Unfortunately things go slightly wrong and the deal has to be postponed, which upsets the crime lord who is arranging it no end. There is very little in the way of constant pursuit between Harrison Ford and Brad Pitt. In most cases they are friends, though Ford is ignorant of the true nature of Pitt's character. It is only when the crime lord starts putting pressure onto Pitt that things start happening. When they do, the viewer (or at least myself) starts to have sympathy for Pitt. He is not an evil man, he is just a soldier fighting a war. There is a struggle between him and Ford for we like both but we know that they cannot help each other. The real enemy, and even Ford sees this, is the British. Even Harrison Ford has sympathy for Pitt's character by the end of the movie. The Devil's Own is neither a fast movie nor is it an action movie. The video labels it as a thriller but even then I didn't think much of that. It is hard to put it into a category. If you are looking for a fast action movie, then look for something else. Even though, I still liked this movie and thought that the character development was in itself quite good.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I Could Only Long to be Put Through More "Troubled Productions" Like This One.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jzappa
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/10/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Justice is the summation of all ethical responsibility, but there are conflicting slants on justice. This reality is at the heart of this ignorantly underrated and dismissed film, which meets just gently with The Troubles. Rather, it searches the sad natural history of violence and how individual and social variables shape our slants on it. This is a film of various different tensions in which nobody is unreservedly right or wrong. Characteristic of Pakula's films, The Devil's Own has a solemn, subdued atmosphere that mutely connotes magnitude and seriousness. Cinematographer Gordon Willis' inimitable use of light and dark is especially effective in a scene where Tom and Rory are caught in the sporadic lights of moving cars, a pertinent image for a story in which honor's moorland is so transitory. An Irish-American judge coordinates for Rory Devaney, an Irish rebel, to lodge in the suburban home of NYC police sergeant Tom O'Meara. This upright cop, his wife and their daughters haven't a clue as to Rory's real identity. While Rory is occupied obtaining Stinger missiles from Treat Williams' American gang boss, Rory discovers himself emotionally enticed by his host family's life. He hasn't known this sense of comfort and peace since childhood before his father was slain before his eyes by a British agent. As the arms deal plods on, ample time is left for the two men to connect, and for Rory to feel remorse facing Tom's morality and virtual pacifism. Meanwhile, Tom confronts the prime predicament of his career when his partner Ruben Blades shoots an unarmed offender in the back and then presumes upon him to suppress it. Tom chooses to retire. But before he can submit his badge, he's dragged into Rory's nightmare when it invades and terrorizes his home. Pitt and Ford give moving and realistic performances as two men whose fanatical dedication to justice puts them on a path to conflict. Instead of stressing epinephrine-boosting action sequences, Pakula fixes the film on the ethical clash between the resistance fighter and the unfaltering advocate of law and order. The action sequences are intermittent but vigorously ringing, with a premium put on the enduring formation of character. At an early stage of their growing personal rapport, Rory tells Tom, "Don't look for a happy ending. It's not an American story. It's an Irish one." The two actors have remarkable pull on one another. When they're together on screen, you want to focus on both of them. They don't seek to trump one another, but to enforce one another's sincerity. The Devil's Own unmistakably seeks to build a father-son histrionic between Tom who has no sons and Rory, and it succeeds mainly since it never labors overmuch to labor on emphasis. Their relationship is relaxed and unaffected. A game of pool here, a snippet of conversation there. And Pakula counts on the actors to create a bond without turning to banal dialogue or unseemly bursts of emotion. These are two understated, strong-minded men who just appear to admire and enjoy one another. And when Pitt turns unreservedly cold-blooded when he's forced into a corner, Pitt gives him the disillusionment of a guy who can't meet the expense of a conscience. This point is that it's unfeasible to choose sides, a point distinctive for a Hollywood film, a battle between people whose virtues were decided by their circumstances. Naysayers called the plot incoherent, just a lot of moral grappling, not all of which relevant. Funny how they didn't say that about the character of Mike Yanagita in Fargo, for instance. It's as if it was new to critics that emotional associations with the plot we care about could be made by characters whose experiences outside that main plot course it's important we see first-hand with them to grasp their ethical arcs.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Bad assessment of this movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Editingwhiz
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/9/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The lead review of this movie is vastly unfair. Just because it is written by some one from Belfast who professes to know it all about such topics doesn't mean what he says is relevant for everybody. The fact is that there are interesting relationships between the characters here, you feel empathy for the terrorist character (Brad Pitt), and you feel the pain of Harrison Ford's NYC cop when he partner is killed. The FBI and BI people are in the movie for about 3 minutes -- how can any conclusions be drawn about them? I personally thought it was a tight thriller and it kept my interest the whole time. Ford and Pitt were excellent in their roles. Pitt, despite what the other bloke said, kept his accent quite well throughout. I am a journalist who looks objectively at such things as film and entertainment, I just thought the top review sold this movie way way short.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Hypothetical and Moral Imperatives.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Robert J. Maxwell (rmax304823@yahoo.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/8/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Reuben Blades is the good-natured but fallible cop who is the friend and partner of officer Harrison Ford on the NYPD. The minute he showed up on screen I figured he was toast. The instrument of Blades' demise is Brad Pitt. Pitt is an IRA agent visiting the US to buy some guns and rockets from the ruthless entrepreneur Treat Williams. Pitt is a nice-looking, clean-shaven young man who finds room and board with Ford's accommodating family. Pitt, harboring a pustular hatred because of some politically caused childhood trauma, is gradually drawn into the peaceful life of Ford's household. They have a couple of lovely kids, say grace before meals, go to the same church as Pitt. They're Irish-American too. The only thing is that they haven't witnessed the suffering that Pitt has on the Auld Sod. It's really Pitt's movie. Harrison Ford cheats a little to save his partner's pension but is otherwise stalwart in upholding the law. Pitt, on the other hand, becomes a man of divided allegiances. He admires and respects Ford and his life style. He doesn't want the family to get into trouble. Yet here is Pitt, hiding a fortune in dollars under the floor of Ford's bathroom, about to buy guns so that the killing in Ireland can go on. The moral act, the moral imperative, is to reject the killing and embrace the warmth of family life. The hypothetical imperative is to complete his mission, smuggle the guns back into Ireland, and garner the accolades that are earned by heroes of the movement. That's not a moral act but it lays out what's in it for Pitt. I don't really want to get into it, partly because Immanuel Kant is complicated, partly because space is limited, and partly because I'm not sure I know what the hell I'm talking about. But my understanding is that you can determine whether a course is moral or not by asking what would happen if everyone followed it. Obviously, in this instance, the bloodshed in Ireland stops if Pitt overcomes his personal desire for revenge and stops shedding blood. The conflict and the final shoot out -- among several violent shoot outs -- is inevitable. And the confrontation involves more than just an uptight cop and a reckless revolutionary. The writers, of course, don't want to alienate those Irish-American viewers who are in thrall to what sociologists have called "the new ethnicity" -- a fiercely sentimental attachment to origins they know little about -- so they have Pitt explain (twice) that, "It's not an American problem; it's an Irish problem." Whatever that means. As Ford's wife, Margaret Colin is pretty and nurturing looking. Ford himself, looking old enough to have spent twenty-four years on the police force, isn't any more expressive than he usually is. He's not a bravura performer. He's reliable. Brad Pitt gives an absorbing and likable performance -- a quiet, appreciative, thoughtful, reckless revolutionary maniac -- who brings some unexpected touches to the role. He has more range than I'd been giving him credit for, although he can still turn in a wincingly wrong performance, as in "Seven." I've always admired Treat Williams's performances in a low-key way. He's been pretty good in some roles, like "Prince of the City," but I think his career has been knee-capped by his having a voice that isn't strong, and that sounds so natural that it seems he's not really able to enact a role.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I liked this movie!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    allwrangledup
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/6/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I won't argue some of the criticisms that I'm reading in other people's reviews here -- but I really liked this movie. I thought that Pitt and Harrison (and most of the others)did some solid acting in this movie. And I actually thought the accents were pretty decent! The action scenes may not have been entirely plausible, but they still worked overall. I liked the relationship storyline/s, and the fact that not everything was perfect. And it wasn't all predictable. Good movie overall. I would recommend it. I like action movies, I also like good "people" story lines. I thought this movie contained both. Like a good, easily readable book.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    All the same, Mr. Fitzsimmoms, if you're not confused, you don't know what's going' on.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    lastliberal
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/4/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It amazes me that people look at every film about political situations as if they should be documentaries. This is a film about the relationship between a New York cop (Harrison Ford), and an IRA terrorist (Brad Pitt) in the US to pick up weapons. It is not meant to be a polemic on the Irish situation. Ford plays a cop that cares about the law and about justice. His partner (Rub&eacute;n Blades) shoots an unarmed teen and Ford actually is the one who gets sick. "We are in the police business, not the revenge business," he tells him. Despite the fact that he has killed 20 men, Pitt comes off as his most lovable self. He fits in well with Ford's family. Things fall apart after the weapons deal is delayed and that's when the real action starts. Ford and Pitt were brilliant, although I hated the ending.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
 </reviews>
</filme>
