<filme>
 <id>
  246
 </id>
 <imdburl>
  http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0118842
 </imdburl>
 <ano>
  1997
 </ano>
 <titulo>
  Procura-se Amy
 </titulo>
 <rating>
  7.3
 </rating>
 <sinopse>
  Holden and Banky are comic book artists. Everything's going good for them until they meet Alyssa, also a comic book artist. Holden falls for her, but his hopes are crushed when he finds out she's gay.
 </sinopse>
 <storyline>
  A pair of comic book authors named Holden McNeil and Banky Edwards, who live in New Jersey, have been best friends since 20 years. They spend their time working in their studio, and in the evenings they are going out. But their friendship is about to be disputed for the first time in their life, when a beautiful young lesbian woman named Alyssa Jones enters their life and Holden falls in love with her. Now Holden has to deal with Banky's jealousy, and with his new girlfriend's very rich past.
 </storyline>
 <generos>
  <genero>
   Comedy
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Drama
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Romance
  </genero>
 </generos>
 <keywords>
  <keyword>
   comic book
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   lesbian
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   friendship
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   gay
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   homosexual
  </keyword>
 </keywords>
 <diretores>
  <diretor>
   Kevin Smith
  </diretor>
 </diretores>
 <escritores>
  <escritor>
   Kevin Smith
  </escritor>
 </escritores>
 <atores>
  <ator>
   Ben Affleck
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Joey Lauren Adams
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Ethan Suplee
  </ator>
 </atores>
 <reviews>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    an unconventional comedy that deals with realistic issues
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    joshjmuir
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Spoilers may appear so do not fear. I thoroughly enjoyed this film and having watched this an adult I have been able to enjoy all the subtle messages that are contained within. I have become so fed up of the traditional Hollywood formula so this was a breath of fresh air. For all the criticism of Ben Affleck as an actor this film seemed to accommodate his style and he pulled of an impressive performance. The complex relationship between his and Joey Lauren Adams character's is thought provoking and asks real questions. Somewhat of a rarity in film nowadays. Credit should be given to the supporting actors as they add to the emotional nuances that the script provided and most importantly portrayed realistic people with actual problems and life struggles. I like Kevin Smith and enjoy his take on film and hope that he continues to ask real questions and most importantly continue making films driven by his own passion. If I were to find any flaw in this premise it will have to be in that Joey Lauren Adams's Character refers to herself as a lesbian but she clearly has had intimate relationships with men, this might attributed to confusion within her own sexuality or that for that period in time she is only dating women but even if that is the case that would still make her bisexual. Perhaps this is just a commentary on how some men view lesbianism as the dialogue in the film does actually address this. Thought Provoking.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An underrated gem by the inventive Kevin Smith
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    JavikKatarn
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    With his debut feature, Clerks, Kevin Smith was granted the credentials to become one of the leading directors of indie cinema. The film about two friends working in a convenience store was a big hit with critics and audiences and became one of the defining films of the 90s. Smith followed it up in 1995 with Mallrats. Mallrats was a financial bomb and was poorly received by critics for its different style and humour to Clerks. Whilst nowhere near the more thoughtful and clever Clerks, Mallrats is a light-hearted and funny comedy with a lot of charm. Despite Mallrats' failure, Smith went on to direct a more sophisticated and heartfelt comedy called Chasing Amy. Chasing Amy was similar to Clerks in that it was a dramatic film with a lot of humour but it was more tonally upbeat and even had some emotional resonance. Chasing Amy is a terrific romantic comedy with a lot of charm and emotion, making it Smith's most potent work as a filmmaker though it lacks some of the influential appeal that Clerks had. Holden McNeil and Banky Edwards are two friends who work as comic book artists with their current series, the superhero duo of Bluntman and Chronic. At a convention, they meet a fellow comic book artist named Alyssa, who writes feminist graphic novels. After one night hanging out with Alyssa, Holden realizes that he is in love with her but his dreams of being with her are tarnished when he discovers that she is a lesbian. Alyssa still wants to be friends with Holden and they spend more time together. But Holden is unable to hide his true feelings for her and in a heartfelt confession, pours his heart out to her. Alyssa is at first hesitant about being involved with Holden but immediately returns his love back to him. Chasing Amy is one of those films that could've ended up being a gross- out comedy considering the source material was out-there for the time. But Smith manages to keep it from being crass and embarrassing. The closest to gross-out humour here is one scene where Alyssa and Banky compare 'battle-scars' from past sexual encounters together in a homage to Jaws. Most of the comedy is more cynical and sardonic but not subtle. There are many moments that are at most guaranteed to raise a bout of laughter like when Star Wars is accused of being white supremacist propaganda or when Banky reacts to Alyssa kissing a woman and then realizing he is in a lesbian bar juxtaposed to Holden's shocked choking up of discovering his fantasy doesn't got for his type. Most importantly though is the relationships between the characters. Holden and Alyssa are one of my favourite romantic couples in film and the chemistry between Ben Affleck and Joey Lauren Adams sells it along with Smith's writing. The two have a clear connection whether merely friendly or romantic. Holden breaking down to Alyssa and confessing his love for her has to go down as one of the best confession scenes in film and the writing along with Affleck's performance sells it. Those who doubt the guy's acting abilities only need to watch his performance here. Adams' voice at first gets a bit grating but she also gives a great performance as Alyssa, making for a perfect romantic foil. Jason Lee has some of the best lines in the film as Banky but his character isn't as developed or strong as the other two. His dismissive attitude toward Alyssa for being a lesbian followed by him being revealed as gay himself feels a bit too tagged on but it doesn't hurt the film and Lee does have some good chemistry with Affleck to support him. Jay and Silent Bob, the duo from Smith's View Askewniverse films, also make an appearance in one scene. Chasing Amy is a solid rom-com with a lot of dramatic heft and emotional resonance to it. Smith's writing is at its peak here and the comedy is just as vulgar and amusing this time around. The efforts of the actors are also worth noting in bringing this film to life, making for a deep connection with the characters and their issues. Smith has made a terrific comedy that is funny, touching and all around deep. If only Jersey Girl could achieve this much.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A review from the year 2013
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    JustStone
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I wouldn't consider myself a huge Kevin Smith fan, but I do enjoy his films. I like Mallrats, Clerks, Jay & Silent Bob Strike Back, in particular because they establish a common thread with Jay & Silent Bob, and they don't take themselves too seriously. Kevin Smith is a master of dirty, lewd, crude and downright offensive dialogue, I get that and for the most part I can appreciate it. When he was first making his films in the 90's, this was a somewhat controversial, as he was paving the way for the "nerd comedy" and doing so with vulgar dialogue, gay jokes, and touchy subject matter. Back in the 90's there really were no films about the comic-con sub culture, and serious gay themed films were rare and far and few between. However its 2013, and the comic book culture has risen to the mainstream. You can't go to a theater these days without seeing a superhero movie in the marquee, gays rights have been more accepted and gay characters are everywhere in the media. Kevin Smith type films are par for the course, and his subject matter is no longer as controversial because so much has changed. I mean you can thank Smith for some of this change, he helped push both comic book films into the mainstream, and in a way, made a film about a lesbian before its was as socially and widely acceptable. So kudos to him. Where am I going with this? Well, as someone who gets Kevin Smith's comedy and dialogue, watching Chasing Amy for the first time in 2013 was really a let down. For some reason out of all the Smith films I've seen, I never got to Chasing Amy, so I was kind of saving it for a rainy day. I knew it is his most critically acclaimed, and coming out right after Mallrats it was his first real dramatic film that wasn't just suppose to be strictly comedic. This films takes its self serious because its about serious subject matter. Maybe I had built it up a bit in my head because of all this, I don't know, but when the rainy day finally came and I sat down to watch it, I wasn't impressed. The first thing I noticed is how much Kevin Smith films don't age well when the subject matter is serious in tone. First because of what I said before, its 2013, these topics are no longer controversial or risqu&eacute; in any way. Making a film about trying to make a lesbian straight, is no longer new or revelatory. The second thing I notice is how much Smith is trying to prove himself as a relevant and hip writer/director in this film. I think this was the film he wanted to be taken seriously for, and for the most part he did get noticed and recognized at the time, but now its just seems kind of like he was trying too hard. The dialogue seems too hip, too self aware, that it kind of takes away from the plot. Every character has to have a snappy comeback or a clever line of dialogue, it kind of gets annoying after the first half an hour. I mean people always praise Smith for how "real" his characters are or how clever his dialogue is, but all I kept thinking was how nobody I know talks like this. Its just seems pretty well, pre-written. Lastly, the plot itself I hate to say was pretty mediocre, and in my opinion not very fleshed out. Like I said, Smith was really trying to prove himself as a writer/director here, and it shows. It almost seems this was Smith's way of learning how to make a proper three act "Hollywood" mainstream film, and because he wasn't a seasoned writer/director at this point, it seems like he was learning as he went along. Joey Lauren Adams as Alyssa is somewhat annoying, and although she has that I-know-I'm-clever smirk and dialogue throughout, I don't really see the attraction. Ben Affleck and Jason Lee as Holden and Banky are fine, but they are just the two typical guy buddies who throw out gay jokes every second that seem to be in every Smith movie. I'm OK with how Holden and Alyssa fall for each other, but by the time we get to third act and we find out about Alyssa's past, and Holden's "final solution" it just falls apart, and to me made very little sense. I think Smith needed more experience as a screen writer at this point, and this was his experiment with a serious and mainstream film. For the most part he succeeded, as it was critically acclaimed at the time, but I think it had more to do with the then touchy subject matter which is now dated, and the way he wrote scripts, which is now just a Kevin Smith film. I like Kevin Smith, but this is a flawed film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Gunga.....
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    DustinRahksi
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Since it's the summer of comedy, and this was on my list and it got an depressing emotion out of me, I thought I'd review it. This definitely feels like Kevin Smiths most heartfelt film, it's not to big on the comedy. The best part of this film is that I was thoroughly interested, I only ever checked the runtime because I wanted it to be a little longer. Do not read if sensitive. Let just sum it up. The characters were believable for the most part, Joey Lauren Adams surprisingly didn't annoyed me, that's a first for her. Banky was the only character I actually cared about, even if he was a bit of an as-hole. Holden was just your average every man. And I'll get to Alyssa in a bit. Jay and silent bob only have one scene, I thought there would be more of them since they are on the cover, but oh well. There was a lot of good scenes, my favorites being the hockey rink scene and Silent Bobs story. Those had more weight to the story. Now comes the biggest thing people love to argue over, Alyssa's past. I've looked up and down the forums here, and people love talking about this. Well, it did bring a lot of drama into the story. Don't get sensitive over this, but yes, Alyssa was a slut, no argument there. Just watch the film and count how many sexual relations she talks about, your a joke if you don't think she isn't. The part about this that hit me the most was, this is very much a real thing, just look at people now-a-days. How would you react if your girlfriend or boyfriend was a whore, it's disgusting to think about. I would have taken Holden's side, even though his proposal in the end was a very dumb thing to do. Of course she truly did love him, but hey, she did some sick things, that no amount of Listerine can wash away. I probably would have just walked away from it. I for one have zero tolerance for loose women, so yeah it's understandable. Then people will cry, she was trying to find that someone, so a threesome is finding that someone, making a dirty film is finding that someone, sleeping around is finding that someone. BS, that's called being a slut, plain and simple, there is no argument. People like this spread diseases, it's not so bad being a virgin. Anyway, the film should have ended after the apartment proposal, because the rest doesn't make it any less depressing. Anyway, I feel like watching this movie again right now.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Engaging indie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Charles Herold (cherold)
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I haven't see that many Kevin Smith movies, and the ones I have seen were a mixed bag, but Chasing Amy is a genuinely entertaining and thoughtful movie. Jason Lee is very good, Affleck is decent, and Adams isn't bad once you get used to her Kewpie-doll voice. It's a movie that tries to think outside the conventions of movies, and while it doesn't entirely succeed, it does offer some surprises. This is also a movie that you will respond to differently depending on where you are in your own life. I saw it twice about ten year apart and liked it both times, but not necessarily for the same reasons. And a friend of mine saw the movie completely differently the second time she saw it. In short, it's funny and sometimes touching and it has something to say.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    This movie will mean different things to different viewers
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tvrose890
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    There is a lot more going on in this movie than meets the eye. But, the parable by Silent Bob pretty much sums it all up for me. The lifestyles, both traditional and alternative, seem to be diversions to the real message. The only absurd scene in the movie is when Holden arranges a meeting with Alyssa and Banky. The scene was totally unnecessary and it seemed like an awkward attempt to get to the final result. It was the only scene that turned me off. Like, who would propose such a thing to a person you supposedly love more than anything? Anyways, Holden blows it much like many of us have blown it when it comes to screwing up our relationships. We think of every reason in the book to why the relationship is wrong when in reality we are not ready to grow a relationship. The parable by Bob sums it all up on why we are chasing Amy. We can spend a lifetime looking for something we've lost.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A little late, but not TOO late, I hope
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Steviereno
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Spoiler alert. "Chasing Amy" is a small movie that does everything it set out to do. It is the kind of small movie all independent movies try to be, but that almost none achieve. It shows little lives, little people, little events in ways and language we all can understand and identify with. Even if we haven't fallen in love with a lesbian or written a successful comic book, we all want to know what it might be like - and the former, would be, for most of us, confusing; the latter would be less glamorous. And no, neither one for any of us would be a subject for an epic film - but would most likely be a film like "Chasing Amy." There are moments of confusion for Holden, as his absorbed ideas about homosexuality are challenged by reality, and his feelings when confronted with open sexuality in an undisguised, un-Hollywood young hotty, in Alyssa. He's lived a cloistered life; that is made abundantly clear by Kevin Smith's excellent reality-based writing and directing. Smith obviously know the world he is portraying. "Chasing Amy" is, in a way, like "Before Sunset" but with a lesbian, and without Paris - the one that got away, and with Holden wondering what in the world he was supposed to do. This is a movie I loved from moment one. I had not seen "Clerks", so it was my introduction to Kevin Smith. I got a thing going for Joey Lauren Adams that is still going on. And Jay and Silent Bob are the funniest two characters I've seen in films in decades. Any of us who doesn't know a Jay has simply not lived in the USA of the late 20th century till now. This is a movie I never miss seeing if the opportunity comes up. The bar booth scene with Banky and Alyssa comparing dating notes is priceless - right up there with Jack Nicholson ordering a sandwich in the diner in "Five Easy Pieces." I'd give "Cahsin Amy" a 10, but, though it achieves everything it sets out to do, it is just that one little bit that Kevin Smith didn't try to do with it that holds me back. Heck, if he had tried for more, he might have messed it up, so I should be glad he didn't. It is pretty much perfect the way it is. I debated between 9 and 10, and my 9.49 has to round down...LOL Great flick!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Chasing Amy  Very emotional and unusual romance with some jokes and a bit of tragedy
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Avid Climber
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Chasing Amy is about the one that got away, and how stupid and hurtful we can be when we're confronted something that test the limit of our knowledge. Romance with a few gags, a tragedy, a movie where you can stop and think. What would you have done? Personally, I think the girl and the black guy are very wise. The two white dudes are pure vanilla stupid. The emotional scenes are touching, and the dialogs are as solid as Kevin Smith can make them. The story is captivating with nice novel ideas, and the maturity of the treatment in the subject matter is beyond reproach. Joey Lauren Adams is little known as actresses go, but she gives us a powerful and very emotional performance. Ben Affleck might not be at his best, but it is still a pretty good performance. While you just want to slap some sense into Jason Lee's character, he plays the uncouth badmouth with little respect like a pro. Looking for a nice romance with an offbeat sentiment and you don't mind if it's not as slick as the high budget flicks Hollywood produces? This is yours. Try it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Bitter-Sweet Romantic Story With A Pulsating Heart
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Nick-leonardi
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Chasing Amy is a 1997 Comedy film directed by Kevin Smith and starring Ben Affleck, Jason Lee, and Joey Lauren Adams. Regarding the movie, opinions among Kevin Smith fans and moviegoers are polarizing to one another: many consider it to be his most entertaining film, others, his least successful. What is certain is that it's the most accessible, mainstream- friendly film of his. Holden (Affleck) and Banky (Lee) are two best friends and comic book artists, sharing the same apartment. At a comic book convention, they meet the lively Alyssa, another comic book artist. Holden falls in love with her almost immediately, while Banky clearly feels opposite feelings. Holden's world however is turned upside down when he finds out she's a lesbian. They do however become best friends, and surprisingly, they start a romantic relationship; but soon some facts concerning Alyssa's past will come to Holden's knowing, and all of the sudden things start getting more complicated, especially due to Alyssa's unstable sexual preference. The romantic side of the film is by no means a traditional one, in neither its warm-up, nor in its consequence. A great and hilarious script makes all of the main characters very likable and funny, including the one of Jason Lee, and especially the brief ones of Jay and Silent Bob, the two reoccurring characters in Kevin Smith's films, Silent Bob being played by Smith himself. Considering the subject matter, however, it would have been nice to have added a bit more depth to the story: Chasing Amy could have been a clever meditation on how rudely America's gay culture is treated by heterosexuals, despite being it a respected culture with a lot of supporters. It also seems that Kevin Smith didn't always pace the film in such an effective manner: some parts are too rushed and for that reason, it kills the natural flow a bit. It wouldn't have hurt to have made the movie a bit longer, considering the fact that it is very unlikely Smith wouldn't be able to forge an extra amount of great, heart-felt and hilarious scenes.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Chasing Amy, a textbook example of a good Rom-com
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    MisureRebellion
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    In Kevin Smith's 3rd film, Chasing Amy concerns Holden McNeil, a comic book artist, with best Banky Edwards beside him every step of the way, the two have become a hit with their comic book series, Bluntman & Chronic, based on the two characters Jay & Silent Bob, from the previous two films, (Clerks. & Mallrats). At a comic convention, Holden meets Alyssa, the girl he's only dreamed of, but he is crushed when he finds out that she is a lesbian. This is a what every Rom-com should be, it shouldn't try following the hot buttons of pop culture, it should be an original idea, with a cast of characters we should actually care about! Kevin Smith knew what we wanted, not something done a thousand times, but it should be something from your life, not something from a movie you saw on TV last night, it should be a story that we can level with as a theater going audience! I honestly can't remember the last time I made a bet that I could make a girl cool in time for the prom! The film is a definite 8.5 ticket stub in my books! The film is on Netflix for instant streaming, it's a definite check it out!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    an unconventional comedy that deals with realistic issues
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    joshjmuir
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Spoilers may appear so do not fear. I thoroughly enjoyed this film and having watched this an adult I have been able to enjoy all the subtle messages that are contained within. I have become so fed up of the traditional Hollywood formula so this was a breath of fresh air. For all the criticism of Ben Affleck as an actor this film seemed to accommodate his style and he pulled of an impressive performance. The complex relationship between his and Joey Lauren Adams character's is thought provoking and asks real questions. Somewhat of a rarity in film nowadays. Credit should be given to the supporting actors as they add to the emotional nuances that the script provided and most importantly portrayed realistic people with actual problems and life struggles. I like Kevin Smith and enjoy his take on film and hope that he continues to ask real questions and most importantly continue making films driven by his own passion. If I were to find any flaw in this premise it will have to be in that Joey Lauren Adams's Character refers to herself as a lesbian but she clearly has had intimate relationships with men, this might attributed to confusion within her own sexuality or that for that period in time she is only dating women but even if that is the case that would still make her bisexual. Perhaps this is just a commentary on how some men view lesbianism as the dialogue in the film does actually address this. Thought Provoking.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An underrated gem by the inventive Kevin Smith
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    JavikKatarn
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    With his debut feature, Clerks, Kevin Smith was granted the credentials to become one of the leading directors of indie cinema. The film about two friends working in a convenience store was a big hit with critics and audiences and became one of the defining films of the 90s. Smith followed it up in 1995 with Mallrats. Mallrats was a financial bomb and was poorly received by critics for its different style and humour to Clerks. Whilst nowhere near the more thoughtful and clever Clerks, Mallrats is a light-hearted and funny comedy with a lot of charm. Despite Mallrats' failure, Smith went on to direct a more sophisticated and heartfelt comedy called Chasing Amy. Chasing Amy was similar to Clerks in that it was a dramatic film with a lot of humour but it was more tonally upbeat and even had some emotional resonance. Chasing Amy is a terrific romantic comedy with a lot of charm and emotion, making it Smith's most potent work as a filmmaker though it lacks some of the influential appeal that Clerks had. Holden McNeil and Banky Edwards are two friends who work as comic book artists with their current series, the superhero duo of Bluntman and Chronic. At a convention, they meet a fellow comic book artist named Alyssa, who writes feminist graphic novels. After one night hanging out with Alyssa, Holden realizes that he is in love with her but his dreams of being with her are tarnished when he discovers that she is a lesbian. Alyssa still wants to be friends with Holden and they spend more time together. But Holden is unable to hide his true feelings for her and in a heartfelt confession, pours his heart out to her. Alyssa is at first hesitant about being involved with Holden but immediately returns his love back to him. Chasing Amy is one of those films that could've ended up being a gross- out comedy considering the source material was out-there for the time. But Smith manages to keep it from being crass and embarrassing. The closest to gross-out humour here is one scene where Alyssa and Banky compare 'battle-scars' from past sexual encounters together in a homage to Jaws. Most of the comedy is more cynical and sardonic but not subtle. There are many moments that are at most guaranteed to raise a bout of laughter like when Star Wars is accused of being white supremacist propaganda or when Banky reacts to Alyssa kissing a woman and then realizing he is in a lesbian bar juxtaposed to Holden's shocked choking up of discovering his fantasy doesn't got for his type. Most importantly though is the relationships between the characters. Holden and Alyssa are one of my favourite romantic couples in film and the chemistry between Ben Affleck and Joey Lauren Adams sells it along with Smith's writing. The two have a clear connection whether merely friendly or romantic. Holden breaking down to Alyssa and confessing his love for her has to go down as one of the best confession scenes in film and the writing along with Affleck's performance sells it. Those who doubt the guy's acting abilities only need to watch his performance here. Adams' voice at first gets a bit grating but she also gives a great performance as Alyssa, making for a perfect romantic foil. Jason Lee has some of the best lines in the film as Banky but his character isn't as developed or strong as the other two. His dismissive attitude toward Alyssa for being a lesbian followed by him being revealed as gay himself feels a bit too tagged on but it doesn't hurt the film and Lee does have some good chemistry with Affleck to support him. Jay and Silent Bob, the duo from Smith's View Askewniverse films, also make an appearance in one scene. Chasing Amy is a solid rom-com with a lot of dramatic heft and emotional resonance to it. Smith's writing is at its peak here and the comedy is just as vulgar and amusing this time around. The efforts of the actors are also worth noting in bringing this film to life, making for a deep connection with the characters and their issues. Smith has made a terrific comedy that is funny, touching and all around deep. If only Jersey Girl could achieve this much.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A review from the year 2013
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    JustStone
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I wouldn't consider myself a huge Kevin Smith fan, but I do enjoy his films. I like Mallrats, Clerks, Jay & Silent Bob Strike Back, in particular because they establish a common thread with Jay & Silent Bob, and they don't take themselves too seriously. Kevin Smith is a master of dirty, lewd, crude and downright offensive dialogue, I get that and for the most part I can appreciate it. When he was first making his films in the 90's, this was a somewhat controversial, as he was paving the way for the "nerd comedy" and doing so with vulgar dialogue, gay jokes, and touchy subject matter. Back in the 90's there really were no films about the comic-con sub culture, and serious gay themed films were rare and far and few between. However its 2013, and the comic book culture has risen to the mainstream. You can't go to a theater these days without seeing a superhero movie in the marquee, gays rights have been more accepted and gay characters are everywhere in the media. Kevin Smith type films are par for the course, and his subject matter is no longer as controversial because so much has changed. I mean you can thank Smith for some of this change, he helped push both comic book films into the mainstream, and in a way, made a film about a lesbian before its was as socially and widely acceptable. So kudos to him. Where am I going with this? Well, as someone who gets Kevin Smith's comedy and dialogue, watching Chasing Amy for the first time in 2013 was really a let down. For some reason out of all the Smith films I've seen, I never got to Chasing Amy, so I was kind of saving it for a rainy day. I knew it is his most critically acclaimed, and coming out right after Mallrats it was his first real dramatic film that wasn't just suppose to be strictly comedic. This films takes its self serious because its about serious subject matter. Maybe I had built it up a bit in my head because of all this, I don't know, but when the rainy day finally came and I sat down to watch it, I wasn't impressed. The first thing I noticed is how much Kevin Smith films don't age well when the subject matter is serious in tone. First because of what I said before, its 2013, these topics are no longer controversial or risqu&eacute; in any way. Making a film about trying to make a lesbian straight, is no longer new or revelatory. The second thing I notice is how much Smith is trying to prove himself as a relevant and hip writer/director in this film. I think this was the film he wanted to be taken seriously for, and for the most part he did get noticed and recognized at the time, but now its just seems kind of like he was trying too hard. The dialogue seems too hip, too self aware, that it kind of takes away from the plot. Every character has to have a snappy comeback or a clever line of dialogue, it kind of gets annoying after the first half an hour. I mean people always praise Smith for how "real" his characters are or how clever his dialogue is, but all I kept thinking was how nobody I know talks like this. Its just seems pretty well, pre-written. Lastly, the plot itself I hate to say was pretty mediocre, and in my opinion not very fleshed out. Like I said, Smith was really trying to prove himself as a writer/director here, and it shows. It almost seems this was Smith's way of learning how to make a proper three act "Hollywood" mainstream film, and because he wasn't a seasoned writer/director at this point, it seems like he was learning as he went along. Joey Lauren Adams as Alyssa is somewhat annoying, and although she has that I-know-I'm-clever smirk and dialogue throughout, I don't really see the attraction. Ben Affleck and Jason Lee as Holden and Banky are fine, but they are just the two typical guy buddies who throw out gay jokes every second that seem to be in every Smith movie. I'm OK with how Holden and Alyssa fall for each other, but by the time we get to third act and we find out about Alyssa's past, and Holden's "final solution" it just falls apart, and to me made very little sense. I think Smith needed more experience as a screen writer at this point, and this was his experiment with a serious and mainstream film. For the most part he succeeded, as it was critically acclaimed at the time, but I think it had more to do with the then touchy subject matter which is now dated, and the way he wrote scripts, which is now just a Kevin Smith film. I like Kevin Smith, but this is a flawed film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Gunga.....
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    DustinRahksi
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Since it's the summer of comedy, and this was on my list and it got an depressing emotion out of me, I thought I'd review it. This definitely feels like Kevin Smiths most heartfelt film, it's not to big on the comedy. The best part of this film is that I was thoroughly interested, I only ever checked the runtime because I wanted it to be a little longer. Do not read if sensitive. Let just sum it up. The characters were believable for the most part, Joey Lauren Adams surprisingly didn't annoyed me, that's a first for her. Banky was the only character I actually cared about, even if he was a bit of an as-hole. Holden was just your average every man. And I'll get to Alyssa in a bit. Jay and silent bob only have one scene, I thought there would be more of them since they are on the cover, but oh well. There was a lot of good scenes, my favorites being the hockey rink scene and Silent Bobs story. Those had more weight to the story. Now comes the biggest thing people love to argue over, Alyssa's past. I've looked up and down the forums here, and people love talking about this. Well, it did bring a lot of drama into the story. Don't get sensitive over this, but yes, Alyssa was a slut, no argument there. Just watch the film and count how many sexual relations she talks about, your a joke if you don't think she isn't. The part about this that hit me the most was, this is very much a real thing, just look at people now-a-days. How would you react if your girlfriend or boyfriend was a whore, it's disgusting to think about. I would have taken Holden's side, even though his proposal in the end was a very dumb thing to do. Of course she truly did love him, but hey, she did some sick things, that no amount of Listerine can wash away. I probably would have just walked away from it. I for one have zero tolerance for loose women, so yeah it's understandable. Then people will cry, she was trying to find that someone, so a threesome is finding that someone, making a dirty film is finding that someone, sleeping around is finding that someone. BS, that's called being a slut, plain and simple, there is no argument. People like this spread diseases, it's not so bad being a virgin. Anyway, the film should have ended after the apartment proposal, because the rest doesn't make it any less depressing. Anyway, I feel like watching this movie again right now.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Engaging indie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Charles Herold (cherold)
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I haven't see that many Kevin Smith movies, and the ones I have seen were a mixed bag, but Chasing Amy is a genuinely entertaining and thoughtful movie. Jason Lee is very good, Affleck is decent, and Adams isn't bad once you get used to her Kewpie-doll voice. It's a movie that tries to think outside the conventions of movies, and while it doesn't entirely succeed, it does offer some surprises. This is also a movie that you will respond to differently depending on where you are in your own life. I saw it twice about ten year apart and liked it both times, but not necessarily for the same reasons. And a friend of mine saw the movie completely differently the second time she saw it. In short, it's funny and sometimes touching and it has something to say.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    This movie will mean different things to different viewers
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tvrose890
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    There is a lot more going on in this movie than meets the eye. But, the parable by Silent Bob pretty much sums it all up for me. The lifestyles, both traditional and alternative, seem to be diversions to the real message. The only absurd scene in the movie is when Holden arranges a meeting with Alyssa and Banky. The scene was totally unnecessary and it seemed like an awkward attempt to get to the final result. It was the only scene that turned me off. Like, who would propose such a thing to a person you supposedly love more than anything? Anyways, Holden blows it much like many of us have blown it when it comes to screwing up our relationships. We think of every reason in the book to why the relationship is wrong when in reality we are not ready to grow a relationship. The parable by Bob sums it all up on why we are chasing Amy. We can spend a lifetime looking for something we've lost.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A little late, but not TOO late, I hope
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Steviereno
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Spoiler alert. "Chasing Amy" is a small movie that does everything it set out to do. It is the kind of small movie all independent movies try to be, but that almost none achieve. It shows little lives, little people, little events in ways and language we all can understand and identify with. Even if we haven't fallen in love with a lesbian or written a successful comic book, we all want to know what it might be like - and the former, would be, for most of us, confusing; the latter would be less glamorous. And no, neither one for any of us would be a subject for an epic film - but would most likely be a film like "Chasing Amy." There are moments of confusion for Holden, as his absorbed ideas about homosexuality are challenged by reality, and his feelings when confronted with open sexuality in an undisguised, un-Hollywood young hotty, in Alyssa. He's lived a cloistered life; that is made abundantly clear by Kevin Smith's excellent reality-based writing and directing. Smith obviously know the world he is portraying. "Chasing Amy" is, in a way, like "Before Sunset" but with a lesbian, and without Paris - the one that got away, and with Holden wondering what in the world he was supposed to do. This is a movie I loved from moment one. I had not seen "Clerks", so it was my introduction to Kevin Smith. I got a thing going for Joey Lauren Adams that is still going on. And Jay and Silent Bob are the funniest two characters I've seen in films in decades. Any of us who doesn't know a Jay has simply not lived in the USA of the late 20th century till now. This is a movie I never miss seeing if the opportunity comes up. The bar booth scene with Banky and Alyssa comparing dating notes is priceless - right up there with Jack Nicholson ordering a sandwich in the diner in "Five Easy Pieces." I'd give "Cahsin Amy" a 10, but, though it achieves everything it sets out to do, it is just that one little bit that Kevin Smith didn't try to do with it that holds me back. Heck, if he had tried for more, he might have messed it up, so I should be glad he didn't. It is pretty much perfect the way it is. I debated between 9 and 10, and my 9.49 has to round down...LOL Great flick!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Chasing Amy  Very emotional and unusual romance with some jokes and a bit of tragedy
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Avid Climber
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Chasing Amy is about the one that got away, and how stupid and hurtful we can be when we're confronted something that test the limit of our knowledge. Romance with a few gags, a tragedy, a movie where you can stop and think. What would you have done? Personally, I think the girl and the black guy are very wise. The two white dudes are pure vanilla stupid. The emotional scenes are touching, and the dialogs are as solid as Kevin Smith can make them. The story is captivating with nice novel ideas, and the maturity of the treatment in the subject matter is beyond reproach. Joey Lauren Adams is little known as actresses go, but she gives us a powerful and very emotional performance. Ben Affleck might not be at his best, but it is still a pretty good performance. While you just want to slap some sense into Jason Lee's character, he plays the uncouth badmouth with little respect like a pro. Looking for a nice romance with an offbeat sentiment and you don't mind if it's not as slick as the high budget flicks Hollywood produces? This is yours. Try it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Bitter-Sweet Romantic Story With A Pulsating Heart
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Nick-leonardi
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Chasing Amy is a 1997 Comedy film directed by Kevin Smith and starring Ben Affleck, Jason Lee, and Joey Lauren Adams. Regarding the movie, opinions among Kevin Smith fans and moviegoers are polarizing to one another: many consider it to be his most entertaining film, others, his least successful. What is certain is that it's the most accessible, mainstream- friendly film of his. Holden (Affleck) and Banky (Lee) are two best friends and comic book artists, sharing the same apartment. At a comic book convention, they meet the lively Alyssa, another comic book artist. Holden falls in love with her almost immediately, while Banky clearly feels opposite feelings. Holden's world however is turned upside down when he finds out she's a lesbian. They do however become best friends, and surprisingly, they start a romantic relationship; but soon some facts concerning Alyssa's past will come to Holden's knowing, and all of the sudden things start getting more complicated, especially due to Alyssa's unstable sexual preference. The romantic side of the film is by no means a traditional one, in neither its warm-up, nor in its consequence. A great and hilarious script makes all of the main characters very likable and funny, including the one of Jason Lee, and especially the brief ones of Jay and Silent Bob, the two reoccurring characters in Kevin Smith's films, Silent Bob being played by Smith himself. Considering the subject matter, however, it would have been nice to have added a bit more depth to the story: Chasing Amy could have been a clever meditation on how rudely America's gay culture is treated by heterosexuals, despite being it a respected culture with a lot of supporters. It also seems that Kevin Smith didn't always pace the film in such an effective manner: some parts are too rushed and for that reason, it kills the natural flow a bit. It wouldn't have hurt to have made the movie a bit longer, considering the fact that it is very unlikely Smith wouldn't be able to forge an extra amount of great, heart-felt and hilarious scenes.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Chasing Amy, a textbook example of a good Rom-com
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    MisureRebellion
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    In Kevin Smith's 3rd film, Chasing Amy concerns Holden McNeil, a comic book artist, with best Banky Edwards beside him every step of the way, the two have become a hit with their comic book series, Bluntman & Chronic, based on the two characters Jay & Silent Bob, from the previous two films, (Clerks. & Mallrats). At a comic convention, Holden meets Alyssa, the girl he's only dreamed of, but he is crushed when he finds out that she is a lesbian. This is a what every Rom-com should be, it shouldn't try following the hot buttons of pop culture, it should be an original idea, with a cast of characters we should actually care about! Kevin Smith knew what we wanted, not something done a thousand times, but it should be something from your life, not something from a movie you saw on TV last night, it should be a story that we can level with as a theater going audience! I honestly can't remember the last time I made a bet that I could make a girl cool in time for the prom! The film is a definite 8.5 ticket stub in my books! The film is on Netflix for instant streaming, it's a definite check it out!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    an unconventional comedy that deals with realistic issues
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    joshjmuir
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Spoilers may appear so do not fear. I thoroughly enjoyed this film and having watched this an adult I have been able to enjoy all the subtle messages that are contained within. I have become so fed up of the traditional Hollywood formula so this was a breath of fresh air. For all the criticism of Ben Affleck as an actor this film seemed to accommodate his style and he pulled of an impressive performance. The complex relationship between his and Joey Lauren Adams character's is thought provoking and asks real questions. Somewhat of a rarity in film nowadays. Credit should be given to the supporting actors as they add to the emotional nuances that the script provided and most importantly portrayed realistic people with actual problems and life struggles. I like Kevin Smith and enjoy his take on film and hope that he continues to ask real questions and most importantly continue making films driven by his own passion. If I were to find any flaw in this premise it will have to be in that Joey Lauren Adams's Character refers to herself as a lesbian but she clearly has had intimate relationships with men, this might attributed to confusion within her own sexuality or that for that period in time she is only dating women but even if that is the case that would still make her bisexual. Perhaps this is just a commentary on how some men view lesbianism as the dialogue in the film does actually address this. Thought Provoking.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An underrated gem by the inventive Kevin Smith
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    JavikKatarn
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    With his debut feature, Clerks, Kevin Smith was granted the credentials to become one of the leading directors of indie cinema. The film about two friends working in a convenience store was a big hit with critics and audiences and became one of the defining films of the 90s. Smith followed it up in 1995 with Mallrats. Mallrats was a financial bomb and was poorly received by critics for its different style and humour to Clerks. Whilst nowhere near the more thoughtful and clever Clerks, Mallrats is a light-hearted and funny comedy with a lot of charm. Despite Mallrats' failure, Smith went on to direct a more sophisticated and heartfelt comedy called Chasing Amy. Chasing Amy was similar to Clerks in that it was a dramatic film with a lot of humour but it was more tonally upbeat and even had some emotional resonance. Chasing Amy is a terrific romantic comedy with a lot of charm and emotion, making it Smith's most potent work as a filmmaker though it lacks some of the influential appeal that Clerks had. Holden McNeil and Banky Edwards are two friends who work as comic book artists with their current series, the superhero duo of Bluntman and Chronic. At a convention, they meet a fellow comic book artist named Alyssa, who writes feminist graphic novels. After one night hanging out with Alyssa, Holden realizes that he is in love with her but his dreams of being with her are tarnished when he discovers that she is a lesbian. Alyssa still wants to be friends with Holden and they spend more time together. But Holden is unable to hide his true feelings for her and in a heartfelt confession, pours his heart out to her. Alyssa is at first hesitant about being involved with Holden but immediately returns his love back to him. Chasing Amy is one of those films that could've ended up being a gross- out comedy considering the source material was out-there for the time. But Smith manages to keep it from being crass and embarrassing. The closest to gross-out humour here is one scene where Alyssa and Banky compare 'battle-scars' from past sexual encounters together in a homage to Jaws. Most of the comedy is more cynical and sardonic but not subtle. There are many moments that are at most guaranteed to raise a bout of laughter like when Star Wars is accused of being white supremacist propaganda or when Banky reacts to Alyssa kissing a woman and then realizing he is in a lesbian bar juxtaposed to Holden's shocked choking up of discovering his fantasy doesn't got for his type. Most importantly though is the relationships between the characters. Holden and Alyssa are one of my favourite romantic couples in film and the chemistry between Ben Affleck and Joey Lauren Adams sells it along with Smith's writing. The two have a clear connection whether merely friendly or romantic. Holden breaking down to Alyssa and confessing his love for her has to go down as one of the best confession scenes in film and the writing along with Affleck's performance sells it. Those who doubt the guy's acting abilities only need to watch his performance here. Adams' voice at first gets a bit grating but she also gives a great performance as Alyssa, making for a perfect romantic foil. Jason Lee has some of the best lines in the film as Banky but his character isn't as developed or strong as the other two. His dismissive attitude toward Alyssa for being a lesbian followed by him being revealed as gay himself feels a bit too tagged on but it doesn't hurt the film and Lee does have some good chemistry with Affleck to support him. Jay and Silent Bob, the duo from Smith's View Askewniverse films, also make an appearance in one scene. Chasing Amy is a solid rom-com with a lot of dramatic heft and emotional resonance to it. Smith's writing is at its peak here and the comedy is just as vulgar and amusing this time around. The efforts of the actors are also worth noting in bringing this film to life, making for a deep connection with the characters and their issues. Smith has made a terrific comedy that is funny, touching and all around deep. If only Jersey Girl could achieve this much.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A review from the year 2013
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    JustStone
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I wouldn't consider myself a huge Kevin Smith fan, but I do enjoy his films. I like Mallrats, Clerks, Jay & Silent Bob Strike Back, in particular because they establish a common thread with Jay & Silent Bob, and they don't take themselves too seriously. Kevin Smith is a master of dirty, lewd, crude and downright offensive dialogue, I get that and for the most part I can appreciate it. When he was first making his films in the 90's, this was a somewhat controversial, as he was paving the way for the "nerd comedy" and doing so with vulgar dialogue, gay jokes, and touchy subject matter. Back in the 90's there really were no films about the comic-con sub culture, and serious gay themed films were rare and far and few between. However its 2013, and the comic book culture has risen to the mainstream. You can't go to a theater these days without seeing a superhero movie in the marquee, gays rights have been more accepted and gay characters are everywhere in the media. Kevin Smith type films are par for the course, and his subject matter is no longer as controversial because so much has changed. I mean you can thank Smith for some of this change, he helped push both comic book films into the mainstream, and in a way, made a film about a lesbian before its was as socially and widely acceptable. So kudos to him. Where am I going with this? Well, as someone who gets Kevin Smith's comedy and dialogue, watching Chasing Amy for the first time in 2013 was really a let down. For some reason out of all the Smith films I've seen, I never got to Chasing Amy, so I was kind of saving it for a rainy day. I knew it is his most critically acclaimed, and coming out right after Mallrats it was his first real dramatic film that wasn't just suppose to be strictly comedic. This films takes its self serious because its about serious subject matter. Maybe I had built it up a bit in my head because of all this, I don't know, but when the rainy day finally came and I sat down to watch it, I wasn't impressed. The first thing I noticed is how much Kevin Smith films don't age well when the subject matter is serious in tone. First because of what I said before, its 2013, these topics are no longer controversial or risqu&eacute; in any way. Making a film about trying to make a lesbian straight, is no longer new or revelatory. The second thing I notice is how much Smith is trying to prove himself as a relevant and hip writer/director in this film. I think this was the film he wanted to be taken seriously for, and for the most part he did get noticed and recognized at the time, but now its just seems kind of like he was trying too hard. The dialogue seems too hip, too self aware, that it kind of takes away from the plot. Every character has to have a snappy comeback or a clever line of dialogue, it kind of gets annoying after the first half an hour. I mean people always praise Smith for how "real" his characters are or how clever his dialogue is, but all I kept thinking was how nobody I know talks like this. Its just seems pretty well, pre-written. Lastly, the plot itself I hate to say was pretty mediocre, and in my opinion not very fleshed out. Like I said, Smith was really trying to prove himself as a writer/director here, and it shows. It almost seems this was Smith's way of learning how to make a proper three act "Hollywood" mainstream film, and because he wasn't a seasoned writer/director at this point, it seems like he was learning as he went along. Joey Lauren Adams as Alyssa is somewhat annoying, and although she has that I-know-I'm-clever smirk and dialogue throughout, I don't really see the attraction. Ben Affleck and Jason Lee as Holden and Banky are fine, but they are just the two typical guy buddies who throw out gay jokes every second that seem to be in every Smith movie. I'm OK with how Holden and Alyssa fall for each other, but by the time we get to third act and we find out about Alyssa's past, and Holden's "final solution" it just falls apart, and to me made very little sense. I think Smith needed more experience as a screen writer at this point, and this was his experiment with a serious and mainstream film. For the most part he succeeded, as it was critically acclaimed at the time, but I think it had more to do with the then touchy subject matter which is now dated, and the way he wrote scripts, which is now just a Kevin Smith film. I like Kevin Smith, but this is a flawed film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Gunga.....
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    DustinRahksi
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Since it's the summer of comedy, and this was on my list and it got an depressing emotion out of me, I thought I'd review it. This definitely feels like Kevin Smiths most heartfelt film, it's not to big on the comedy. The best part of this film is that I was thoroughly interested, I only ever checked the runtime because I wanted it to be a little longer. Do not read if sensitive. Let just sum it up. The characters were believable for the most part, Joey Lauren Adams surprisingly didn't annoyed me, that's a first for her. Banky was the only character I actually cared about, even if he was a bit of an as-hole. Holden was just your average every man. And I'll get to Alyssa in a bit. Jay and silent bob only have one scene, I thought there would be more of them since they are on the cover, but oh well. There was a lot of good scenes, my favorites being the hockey rink scene and Silent Bobs story. Those had more weight to the story. Now comes the biggest thing people love to argue over, Alyssa's past. I've looked up and down the forums here, and people love talking about this. Well, it did bring a lot of drama into the story. Don't get sensitive over this, but yes, Alyssa was a slut, no argument there. Just watch the film and count how many sexual relations she talks about, your a joke if you don't think she isn't. The part about this that hit me the most was, this is very much a real thing, just look at people now-a-days. How would you react if your girlfriend or boyfriend was a whore, it's disgusting to think about. I would have taken Holden's side, even though his proposal in the end was a very dumb thing to do. Of course she truly did love him, but hey, she did some sick things, that no amount of Listerine can wash away. I probably would have just walked away from it. I for one have zero tolerance for loose women, so yeah it's understandable. Then people will cry, she was trying to find that someone, so a threesome is finding that someone, making a dirty film is finding that someone, sleeping around is finding that someone. BS, that's called being a slut, plain and simple, there is no argument. People like this spread diseases, it's not so bad being a virgin. Anyway, the film should have ended after the apartment proposal, because the rest doesn't make it any less depressing. Anyway, I feel like watching this movie again right now.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Engaging indie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Charles Herold (cherold)
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I haven't see that many Kevin Smith movies, and the ones I have seen were a mixed bag, but Chasing Amy is a genuinely entertaining and thoughtful movie. Jason Lee is very good, Affleck is decent, and Adams isn't bad once you get used to her Kewpie-doll voice. It's a movie that tries to think outside the conventions of movies, and while it doesn't entirely succeed, it does offer some surprises. This is also a movie that you will respond to differently depending on where you are in your own life. I saw it twice about ten year apart and liked it both times, but not necessarily for the same reasons. And a friend of mine saw the movie completely differently the second time she saw it. In short, it's funny and sometimes touching and it has something to say.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    This movie will mean different things to different viewers
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tvrose890
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    There is a lot more going on in this movie than meets the eye. But, the parable by Silent Bob pretty much sums it all up for me. The lifestyles, both traditional and alternative, seem to be diversions to the real message. The only absurd scene in the movie is when Holden arranges a meeting with Alyssa and Banky. The scene was totally unnecessary and it seemed like an awkward attempt to get to the final result. It was the only scene that turned me off. Like, who would propose such a thing to a person you supposedly love more than anything? Anyways, Holden blows it much like many of us have blown it when it comes to screwing up our relationships. We think of every reason in the book to why the relationship is wrong when in reality we are not ready to grow a relationship. The parable by Bob sums it all up on why we are chasing Amy. We can spend a lifetime looking for something we've lost.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A little late, but not TOO late, I hope
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Steviereno
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Spoiler alert. "Chasing Amy" is a small movie that does everything it set out to do. It is the kind of small movie all independent movies try to be, but that almost none achieve. It shows little lives, little people, little events in ways and language we all can understand and identify with. Even if we haven't fallen in love with a lesbian or written a successful comic book, we all want to know what it might be like - and the former, would be, for most of us, confusing; the latter would be less glamorous. And no, neither one for any of us would be a subject for an epic film - but would most likely be a film like "Chasing Amy." There are moments of confusion for Holden, as his absorbed ideas about homosexuality are challenged by reality, and his feelings when confronted with open sexuality in an undisguised, un-Hollywood young hotty, in Alyssa. He's lived a cloistered life; that is made abundantly clear by Kevin Smith's excellent reality-based writing and directing. Smith obviously know the world he is portraying. "Chasing Amy" is, in a way, like "Before Sunset" but with a lesbian, and without Paris - the one that got away, and with Holden wondering what in the world he was supposed to do. This is a movie I loved from moment one. I had not seen "Clerks", so it was my introduction to Kevin Smith. I got a thing going for Joey Lauren Adams that is still going on. And Jay and Silent Bob are the funniest two characters I've seen in films in decades. Any of us who doesn't know a Jay has simply not lived in the USA of the late 20th century till now. This is a movie I never miss seeing if the opportunity comes up. The bar booth scene with Banky and Alyssa comparing dating notes is priceless - right up there with Jack Nicholson ordering a sandwich in the diner in "Five Easy Pieces." I'd give "Cahsin Amy" a 10, but, though it achieves everything it sets out to do, it is just that one little bit that Kevin Smith didn't try to do with it that holds me back. Heck, if he had tried for more, he might have messed it up, so I should be glad he didn't. It is pretty much perfect the way it is. I debated between 9 and 10, and my 9.49 has to round down...LOL Great flick!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Chasing Amy  Very emotional and unusual romance with some jokes and a bit of tragedy
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Avid Climber
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Chasing Amy is about the one that got away, and how stupid and hurtful we can be when we're confronted something that test the limit of our knowledge. Romance with a few gags, a tragedy, a movie where you can stop and think. What would you have done? Personally, I think the girl and the black guy are very wise. The two white dudes are pure vanilla stupid. The emotional scenes are touching, and the dialogs are as solid as Kevin Smith can make them. The story is captivating with nice novel ideas, and the maturity of the treatment in the subject matter is beyond reproach. Joey Lauren Adams is little known as actresses go, but she gives us a powerful and very emotional performance. Ben Affleck might not be at his best, but it is still a pretty good performance. While you just want to slap some sense into Jason Lee's character, he plays the uncouth badmouth with little respect like a pro. Looking for a nice romance with an offbeat sentiment and you don't mind if it's not as slick as the high budget flicks Hollywood produces? This is yours. Try it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Bitter-Sweet Romantic Story With A Pulsating Heart
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Nick-leonardi
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Chasing Amy is a 1997 Comedy film directed by Kevin Smith and starring Ben Affleck, Jason Lee, and Joey Lauren Adams. Regarding the movie, opinions among Kevin Smith fans and moviegoers are polarizing to one another: many consider it to be his most entertaining film, others, his least successful. What is certain is that it's the most accessible, mainstream- friendly film of his. Holden (Affleck) and Banky (Lee) are two best friends and comic book artists, sharing the same apartment. At a comic book convention, they meet the lively Alyssa, another comic book artist. Holden falls in love with her almost immediately, while Banky clearly feels opposite feelings. Holden's world however is turned upside down when he finds out she's a lesbian. They do however become best friends, and surprisingly, they start a romantic relationship; but soon some facts concerning Alyssa's past will come to Holden's knowing, and all of the sudden things start getting more complicated, especially due to Alyssa's unstable sexual preference. The romantic side of the film is by no means a traditional one, in neither its warm-up, nor in its consequence. A great and hilarious script makes all of the main characters very likable and funny, including the one of Jason Lee, and especially the brief ones of Jay and Silent Bob, the two reoccurring characters in Kevin Smith's films, Silent Bob being played by Smith himself. Considering the subject matter, however, it would have been nice to have added a bit more depth to the story: Chasing Amy could have been a clever meditation on how rudely America's gay culture is treated by heterosexuals, despite being it a respected culture with a lot of supporters. It also seems that Kevin Smith didn't always pace the film in such an effective manner: some parts are too rushed and for that reason, it kills the natural flow a bit. It wouldn't have hurt to have made the movie a bit longer, considering the fact that it is very unlikely Smith wouldn't be able to forge an extra amount of great, heart-felt and hilarious scenes.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Chasing Amy, a textbook example of a good Rom-com
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    MisureRebellion
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    In Kevin Smith's 3rd film, Chasing Amy concerns Holden McNeil, a comic book artist, with best Banky Edwards beside him every step of the way, the two have become a hit with their comic book series, Bluntman & Chronic, based on the two characters Jay & Silent Bob, from the previous two films, (Clerks. & Mallrats). At a comic convention, Holden meets Alyssa, the girl he's only dreamed of, but he is crushed when he finds out that she is a lesbian. This is a what every Rom-com should be, it shouldn't try following the hot buttons of pop culture, it should be an original idea, with a cast of characters we should actually care about! Kevin Smith knew what we wanted, not something done a thousand times, but it should be something from your life, not something from a movie you saw on TV last night, it should be a story that we can level with as a theater going audience! I honestly can't remember the last time I made a bet that I could make a girl cool in time for the prom! The film is a definite 8.5 ticket stub in my books! The film is on Netflix for instant streaming, it's a definite check it out!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    an unconventional comedy that deals with realistic issues
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    joshjmuir
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Spoilers may appear so do not fear. I thoroughly enjoyed this film and having watched this an adult I have been able to enjoy all the subtle messages that are contained within. I have become so fed up of the traditional Hollywood formula so this was a breath of fresh air. For all the criticism of Ben Affleck as an actor this film seemed to accommodate his style and he pulled of an impressive performance. The complex relationship between his and Joey Lauren Adams character's is thought provoking and asks real questions. Somewhat of a rarity in film nowadays. Credit should be given to the supporting actors as they add to the emotional nuances that the script provided and most importantly portrayed realistic people with actual problems and life struggles. I like Kevin Smith and enjoy his take on film and hope that he continues to ask real questions and most importantly continue making films driven by his own passion. If I were to find any flaw in this premise it will have to be in that Joey Lauren Adams's Character refers to herself as a lesbian but she clearly has had intimate relationships with men, this might attributed to confusion within her own sexuality or that for that period in time she is only dating women but even if that is the case that would still make her bisexual. Perhaps this is just a commentary on how some men view lesbianism as the dialogue in the film does actually address this. Thought Provoking.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An underrated gem by the inventive Kevin Smith
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    JavikKatarn
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    With his debut feature, Clerks, Kevin Smith was granted the credentials to become one of the leading directors of indie cinema. The film about two friends working in a convenience store was a big hit with critics and audiences and became one of the defining films of the 90s. Smith followed it up in 1995 with Mallrats. Mallrats was a financial bomb and was poorly received by critics for its different style and humour to Clerks. Whilst nowhere near the more thoughtful and clever Clerks, Mallrats is a light-hearted and funny comedy with a lot of charm. Despite Mallrats' failure, Smith went on to direct a more sophisticated and heartfelt comedy called Chasing Amy. Chasing Amy was similar to Clerks in that it was a dramatic film with a lot of humour but it was more tonally upbeat and even had some emotional resonance. Chasing Amy is a terrific romantic comedy with a lot of charm and emotion, making it Smith's most potent work as a filmmaker though it lacks some of the influential appeal that Clerks had. Holden McNeil and Banky Edwards are two friends who work as comic book artists with their current series, the superhero duo of Bluntman and Chronic. At a convention, they meet a fellow comic book artist named Alyssa, who writes feminist graphic novels. After one night hanging out with Alyssa, Holden realizes that he is in love with her but his dreams of being with her are tarnished when he discovers that she is a lesbian. Alyssa still wants to be friends with Holden and they spend more time together. But Holden is unable to hide his true feelings for her and in a heartfelt confession, pours his heart out to her. Alyssa is at first hesitant about being involved with Holden but immediately returns his love back to him. Chasing Amy is one of those films that could've ended up being a gross- out comedy considering the source material was out-there for the time. But Smith manages to keep it from being crass and embarrassing. The closest to gross-out humour here is one scene where Alyssa and Banky compare 'battle-scars' from past sexual encounters together in a homage to Jaws. Most of the comedy is more cynical and sardonic but not subtle. There are many moments that are at most guaranteed to raise a bout of laughter like when Star Wars is accused of being white supremacist propaganda or when Banky reacts to Alyssa kissing a woman and then realizing he is in a lesbian bar juxtaposed to Holden's shocked choking up of discovering his fantasy doesn't got for his type. Most importantly though is the relationships between the characters. Holden and Alyssa are one of my favourite romantic couples in film and the chemistry between Ben Affleck and Joey Lauren Adams sells it along with Smith's writing. The two have a clear connection whether merely friendly or romantic. Holden breaking down to Alyssa and confessing his love for her has to go down as one of the best confession scenes in film and the writing along with Affleck's performance sells it. Those who doubt the guy's acting abilities only need to watch his performance here. Adams' voice at first gets a bit grating but she also gives a great performance as Alyssa, making for a perfect romantic foil. Jason Lee has some of the best lines in the film as Banky but his character isn't as developed or strong as the other two. His dismissive attitude toward Alyssa for being a lesbian followed by him being revealed as gay himself feels a bit too tagged on but it doesn't hurt the film and Lee does have some good chemistry with Affleck to support him. Jay and Silent Bob, the duo from Smith's View Askewniverse films, also make an appearance in one scene. Chasing Amy is a solid rom-com with a lot of dramatic heft and emotional resonance to it. Smith's writing is at its peak here and the comedy is just as vulgar and amusing this time around. The efforts of the actors are also worth noting in bringing this film to life, making for a deep connection with the characters and their issues. Smith has made a terrific comedy that is funny, touching and all around deep. If only Jersey Girl could achieve this much.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A review from the year 2013
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    JustStone
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I wouldn't consider myself a huge Kevin Smith fan, but I do enjoy his films. I like Mallrats, Clerks, Jay & Silent Bob Strike Back, in particular because they establish a common thread with Jay & Silent Bob, and they don't take themselves too seriously. Kevin Smith is a master of dirty, lewd, crude and downright offensive dialogue, I get that and for the most part I can appreciate it. When he was first making his films in the 90's, this was a somewhat controversial, as he was paving the way for the "nerd comedy" and doing so with vulgar dialogue, gay jokes, and touchy subject matter. Back in the 90's there really were no films about the comic-con sub culture, and serious gay themed films were rare and far and few between. However its 2013, and the comic book culture has risen to the mainstream. You can't go to a theater these days without seeing a superhero movie in the marquee, gays rights have been more accepted and gay characters are everywhere in the media. Kevin Smith type films are par for the course, and his subject matter is no longer as controversial because so much has changed. I mean you can thank Smith for some of this change, he helped push both comic book films into the mainstream, and in a way, made a film about a lesbian before its was as socially and widely acceptable. So kudos to him. Where am I going with this? Well, as someone who gets Kevin Smith's comedy and dialogue, watching Chasing Amy for the first time in 2013 was really a let down. For some reason out of all the Smith films I've seen, I never got to Chasing Amy, so I was kind of saving it for a rainy day. I knew it is his most critically acclaimed, and coming out right after Mallrats it was his first real dramatic film that wasn't just suppose to be strictly comedic. This films takes its self serious because its about serious subject matter. Maybe I had built it up a bit in my head because of all this, I don't know, but when the rainy day finally came and I sat down to watch it, I wasn't impressed. The first thing I noticed is how much Kevin Smith films don't age well when the subject matter is serious in tone. First because of what I said before, its 2013, these topics are no longer controversial or risqu&eacute; in any way. Making a film about trying to make a lesbian straight, is no longer new or revelatory. The second thing I notice is how much Smith is trying to prove himself as a relevant and hip writer/director in this film. I think this was the film he wanted to be taken seriously for, and for the most part he did get noticed and recognized at the time, but now its just seems kind of like he was trying too hard. The dialogue seems too hip, too self aware, that it kind of takes away from the plot. Every character has to have a snappy comeback or a clever line of dialogue, it kind of gets annoying after the first half an hour. I mean people always praise Smith for how "real" his characters are or how clever his dialogue is, but all I kept thinking was how nobody I know talks like this. Its just seems pretty well, pre-written. Lastly, the plot itself I hate to say was pretty mediocre, and in my opinion not very fleshed out. Like I said, Smith was really trying to prove himself as a writer/director here, and it shows. It almost seems this was Smith's way of learning how to make a proper three act "Hollywood" mainstream film, and because he wasn't a seasoned writer/director at this point, it seems like he was learning as he went along. Joey Lauren Adams as Alyssa is somewhat annoying, and although she has that I-know-I'm-clever smirk and dialogue throughout, I don't really see the attraction. Ben Affleck and Jason Lee as Holden and Banky are fine, but they are just the two typical guy buddies who throw out gay jokes every second that seem to be in every Smith movie. I'm OK with how Holden and Alyssa fall for each other, but by the time we get to third act and we find out about Alyssa's past, and Holden's "final solution" it just falls apart, and to me made very little sense. I think Smith needed more experience as a screen writer at this point, and this was his experiment with a serious and mainstream film. For the most part he succeeded, as it was critically acclaimed at the time, but I think it had more to do with the then touchy subject matter which is now dated, and the way he wrote scripts, which is now just a Kevin Smith film. I like Kevin Smith, but this is a flawed film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Gunga.....
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    DustinRahksi
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Since it's the summer of comedy, and this was on my list and it got an depressing emotion out of me, I thought I'd review it. This definitely feels like Kevin Smiths most heartfelt film, it's not to big on the comedy. The best part of this film is that I was thoroughly interested, I only ever checked the runtime because I wanted it to be a little longer. Do not read if sensitive. Let just sum it up. The characters were believable for the most part, Joey Lauren Adams surprisingly didn't annoyed me, that's a first for her. Banky was the only character I actually cared about, even if he was a bit of an as-hole. Holden was just your average every man. And I'll get to Alyssa in a bit. Jay and silent bob only have one scene, I thought there would be more of them since they are on the cover, but oh well. There was a lot of good scenes, my favorites being the hockey rink scene and Silent Bobs story. Those had more weight to the story. Now comes the biggest thing people love to argue over, Alyssa's past. I've looked up and down the forums here, and people love talking about this. Well, it did bring a lot of drama into the story. Don't get sensitive over this, but yes, Alyssa was a slut, no argument there. Just watch the film and count how many sexual relations she talks about, your a joke if you don't think she isn't. The part about this that hit me the most was, this is very much a real thing, just look at people now-a-days. How would you react if your girlfriend or boyfriend was a whore, it's disgusting to think about. I would have taken Holden's side, even though his proposal in the end was a very dumb thing to do. Of course she truly did love him, but hey, she did some sick things, that no amount of Listerine can wash away. I probably would have just walked away from it. I for one have zero tolerance for loose women, so yeah it's understandable. Then people will cry, she was trying to find that someone, so a threesome is finding that someone, making a dirty film is finding that someone, sleeping around is finding that someone. BS, that's called being a slut, plain and simple, there is no argument. People like this spread diseases, it's not so bad being a virgin. Anyway, the film should have ended after the apartment proposal, because the rest doesn't make it any less depressing. Anyway, I feel like watching this movie again right now.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Engaging indie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Charles Herold (cherold)
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I haven't see that many Kevin Smith movies, and the ones I have seen were a mixed bag, but Chasing Amy is a genuinely entertaining and thoughtful movie. Jason Lee is very good, Affleck is decent, and Adams isn't bad once you get used to her Kewpie-doll voice. It's a movie that tries to think outside the conventions of movies, and while it doesn't entirely succeed, it does offer some surprises. This is also a movie that you will respond to differently depending on where you are in your own life. I saw it twice about ten year apart and liked it both times, but not necessarily for the same reasons. And a friend of mine saw the movie completely differently the second time she saw it. In short, it's funny and sometimes touching and it has something to say.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    This movie will mean different things to different viewers
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tvrose890
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    There is a lot more going on in this movie than meets the eye. But, the parable by Silent Bob pretty much sums it all up for me. The lifestyles, both traditional and alternative, seem to be diversions to the real message. The only absurd scene in the movie is when Holden arranges a meeting with Alyssa and Banky. The scene was totally unnecessary and it seemed like an awkward attempt to get to the final result. It was the only scene that turned me off. Like, who would propose such a thing to a person you supposedly love more than anything? Anyways, Holden blows it much like many of us have blown it when it comes to screwing up our relationships. We think of every reason in the book to why the relationship is wrong when in reality we are not ready to grow a relationship. The parable by Bob sums it all up on why we are chasing Amy. We can spend a lifetime looking for something we've lost.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A little late, but not TOO late, I hope
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Steviereno
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Spoiler alert. "Chasing Amy" is a small movie that does everything it set out to do. It is the kind of small movie all independent movies try to be, but that almost none achieve. It shows little lives, little people, little events in ways and language we all can understand and identify with. Even if we haven't fallen in love with a lesbian or written a successful comic book, we all want to know what it might be like - and the former, would be, for most of us, confusing; the latter would be less glamorous. And no, neither one for any of us would be a subject for an epic film - but would most likely be a film like "Chasing Amy." There are moments of confusion for Holden, as his absorbed ideas about homosexuality are challenged by reality, and his feelings when confronted with open sexuality in an undisguised, un-Hollywood young hotty, in Alyssa. He's lived a cloistered life; that is made abundantly clear by Kevin Smith's excellent reality-based writing and directing. Smith obviously know the world he is portraying. "Chasing Amy" is, in a way, like "Before Sunset" but with a lesbian, and without Paris - the one that got away, and with Holden wondering what in the world he was supposed to do. This is a movie I loved from moment one. I had not seen "Clerks", so it was my introduction to Kevin Smith. I got a thing going for Joey Lauren Adams that is still going on. And Jay and Silent Bob are the funniest two characters I've seen in films in decades. Any of us who doesn't know a Jay has simply not lived in the USA of the late 20th century till now. This is a movie I never miss seeing if the opportunity comes up. The bar booth scene with Banky and Alyssa comparing dating notes is priceless - right up there with Jack Nicholson ordering a sandwich in the diner in "Five Easy Pieces." I'd give "Cahsin Amy" a 10, but, though it achieves everything it sets out to do, it is just that one little bit that Kevin Smith didn't try to do with it that holds me back. Heck, if he had tried for more, he might have messed it up, so I should be glad he didn't. It is pretty much perfect the way it is. I debated between 9 and 10, and my 9.49 has to round down...LOL Great flick!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Chasing Amy  Very emotional and unusual romance with some jokes and a bit of tragedy
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Avid Climber
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Chasing Amy is about the one that got away, and how stupid and hurtful we can be when we're confronted something that test the limit of our knowledge. Romance with a few gags, a tragedy, a movie where you can stop and think. What would you have done? Personally, I think the girl and the black guy are very wise. The two white dudes are pure vanilla stupid. The emotional scenes are touching, and the dialogs are as solid as Kevin Smith can make them. The story is captivating with nice novel ideas, and the maturity of the treatment in the subject matter is beyond reproach. Joey Lauren Adams is little known as actresses go, but she gives us a powerful and very emotional performance. Ben Affleck might not be at his best, but it is still a pretty good performance. While you just want to slap some sense into Jason Lee's character, he plays the uncouth badmouth with little respect like a pro. Looking for a nice romance with an offbeat sentiment and you don't mind if it's not as slick as the high budget flicks Hollywood produces? This is yours. Try it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Bitter-Sweet Romantic Story With A Pulsating Heart
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Nick-leonardi
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Chasing Amy is a 1997 Comedy film directed by Kevin Smith and starring Ben Affleck, Jason Lee, and Joey Lauren Adams. Regarding the movie, opinions among Kevin Smith fans and moviegoers are polarizing to one another: many consider it to be his most entertaining film, others, his least successful. What is certain is that it's the most accessible, mainstream- friendly film of his. Holden (Affleck) and Banky (Lee) are two best friends and comic book artists, sharing the same apartment. At a comic book convention, they meet the lively Alyssa, another comic book artist. Holden falls in love with her almost immediately, while Banky clearly feels opposite feelings. Holden's world however is turned upside down when he finds out she's a lesbian. They do however become best friends, and surprisingly, they start a romantic relationship; but soon some facts concerning Alyssa's past will come to Holden's knowing, and all of the sudden things start getting more complicated, especially due to Alyssa's unstable sexual preference. The romantic side of the film is by no means a traditional one, in neither its warm-up, nor in its consequence. A great and hilarious script makes all of the main characters very likable and funny, including the one of Jason Lee, and especially the brief ones of Jay and Silent Bob, the two reoccurring characters in Kevin Smith's films, Silent Bob being played by Smith himself. Considering the subject matter, however, it would have been nice to have added a bit more depth to the story: Chasing Amy could have been a clever meditation on how rudely America's gay culture is treated by heterosexuals, despite being it a respected culture with a lot of supporters. It also seems that Kevin Smith didn't always pace the film in such an effective manner: some parts are too rushed and for that reason, it kills the natural flow a bit. It wouldn't have hurt to have made the movie a bit longer, considering the fact that it is very unlikely Smith wouldn't be able to forge an extra amount of great, heart-felt and hilarious scenes.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Chasing Amy, a textbook example of a good Rom-com
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    MisureRebellion
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    In Kevin Smith's 3rd film, Chasing Amy concerns Holden McNeil, a comic book artist, with best Banky Edwards beside him every step of the way, the two have become a hit with their comic book series, Bluntman & Chronic, based on the two characters Jay & Silent Bob, from the previous two films, (Clerks. & Mallrats). At a comic convention, Holden meets Alyssa, the girl he's only dreamed of, but he is crushed when he finds out that she is a lesbian. This is a what every Rom-com should be, it shouldn't try following the hot buttons of pop culture, it should be an original idea, with a cast of characters we should actually care about! Kevin Smith knew what we wanted, not something done a thousand times, but it should be something from your life, not something from a movie you saw on TV last night, it should be a story that we can level with as a theater going audience! I honestly can't remember the last time I made a bet that I could make a girl cool in time for the prom! The film is a definite 8.5 ticket stub in my books! The film is on Netflix for instant streaming, it's a definite check it out!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    an unconventional comedy that deals with realistic issues
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    joshjmuir
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Spoilers may appear so do not fear. I thoroughly enjoyed this film and having watched this an adult I have been able to enjoy all the subtle messages that are contained within. I have become so fed up of the traditional Hollywood formula so this was a breath of fresh air. For all the criticism of Ben Affleck as an actor this film seemed to accommodate his style and he pulled of an impressive performance. The complex relationship between his and Joey Lauren Adams character's is thought provoking and asks real questions. Somewhat of a rarity in film nowadays. Credit should be given to the supporting actors as they add to the emotional nuances that the script provided and most importantly portrayed realistic people with actual problems and life struggles. I like Kevin Smith and enjoy his take on film and hope that he continues to ask real questions and most importantly continue making films driven by his own passion. If I were to find any flaw in this premise it will have to be in that Joey Lauren Adams's Character refers to herself as a lesbian but she clearly has had intimate relationships with men, this might attributed to confusion within her own sexuality or that for that period in time she is only dating women but even if that is the case that would still make her bisexual. Perhaps this is just a commentary on how some men view lesbianism as the dialogue in the film does actually address this. Thought Provoking.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An underrated gem by the inventive Kevin Smith
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    JavikKatarn
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    With his debut feature, Clerks, Kevin Smith was granted the credentials to become one of the leading directors of indie cinema. The film about two friends working in a convenience store was a big hit with critics and audiences and became one of the defining films of the 90s. Smith followed it up in 1995 with Mallrats. Mallrats was a financial bomb and was poorly received by critics for its different style and humour to Clerks. Whilst nowhere near the more thoughtful and clever Clerks, Mallrats is a light-hearted and funny comedy with a lot of charm. Despite Mallrats' failure, Smith went on to direct a more sophisticated and heartfelt comedy called Chasing Amy. Chasing Amy was similar to Clerks in that it was a dramatic film with a lot of humour but it was more tonally upbeat and even had some emotional resonance. Chasing Amy is a terrific romantic comedy with a lot of charm and emotion, making it Smith's most potent work as a filmmaker though it lacks some of the influential appeal that Clerks had. Holden McNeil and Banky Edwards are two friends who work as comic book artists with their current series, the superhero duo of Bluntman and Chronic. At a convention, they meet a fellow comic book artist named Alyssa, who writes feminist graphic novels. After one night hanging out with Alyssa, Holden realizes that he is in love with her but his dreams of being with her are tarnished when he discovers that she is a lesbian. Alyssa still wants to be friends with Holden and they spend more time together. But Holden is unable to hide his true feelings for her and in a heartfelt confession, pours his heart out to her. Alyssa is at first hesitant about being involved with Holden but immediately returns his love back to him. Chasing Amy is one of those films that could've ended up being a gross- out comedy considering the source material was out-there for the time. But Smith manages to keep it from being crass and embarrassing. The closest to gross-out humour here is one scene where Alyssa and Banky compare 'battle-scars' from past sexual encounters together in a homage to Jaws. Most of the comedy is more cynical and sardonic but not subtle. There are many moments that are at most guaranteed to raise a bout of laughter like when Star Wars is accused of being white supremacist propaganda or when Banky reacts to Alyssa kissing a woman and then realizing he is in a lesbian bar juxtaposed to Holden's shocked choking up of discovering his fantasy doesn't got for his type. Most importantly though is the relationships between the characters. Holden and Alyssa are one of my favourite romantic couples in film and the chemistry between Ben Affleck and Joey Lauren Adams sells it along with Smith's writing. The two have a clear connection whether merely friendly or romantic. Holden breaking down to Alyssa and confessing his love for her has to go down as one of the best confession scenes in film and the writing along with Affleck's performance sells it. Those who doubt the guy's acting abilities only need to watch his performance here. Adams' voice at first gets a bit grating but she also gives a great performance as Alyssa, making for a perfect romantic foil. Jason Lee has some of the best lines in the film as Banky but his character isn't as developed or strong as the other two. His dismissive attitude toward Alyssa for being a lesbian followed by him being revealed as gay himself feels a bit too tagged on but it doesn't hurt the film and Lee does have some good chemistry with Affleck to support him. Jay and Silent Bob, the duo from Smith's View Askewniverse films, also make an appearance in one scene. Chasing Amy is a solid rom-com with a lot of dramatic heft and emotional resonance to it. Smith's writing is at its peak here and the comedy is just as vulgar and amusing this time around. The efforts of the actors are also worth noting in bringing this film to life, making for a deep connection with the characters and their issues. Smith has made a terrific comedy that is funny, touching and all around deep. If only Jersey Girl could achieve this much.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A review from the year 2013
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    JustStone
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I wouldn't consider myself a huge Kevin Smith fan, but I do enjoy his films. I like Mallrats, Clerks, Jay & Silent Bob Strike Back, in particular because they establish a common thread with Jay & Silent Bob, and they don't take themselves too seriously. Kevin Smith is a master of dirty, lewd, crude and downright offensive dialogue, I get that and for the most part I can appreciate it. When he was first making his films in the 90's, this was a somewhat controversial, as he was paving the way for the "nerd comedy" and doing so with vulgar dialogue, gay jokes, and touchy subject matter. Back in the 90's there really were no films about the comic-con sub culture, and serious gay themed films were rare and far and few between. However its 2013, and the comic book culture has risen to the mainstream. You can't go to a theater these days without seeing a superhero movie in the marquee, gays rights have been more accepted and gay characters are everywhere in the media. Kevin Smith type films are par for the course, and his subject matter is no longer as controversial because so much has changed. I mean you can thank Smith for some of this change, he helped push both comic book films into the mainstream, and in a way, made a film about a lesbian before its was as socially and widely acceptable. So kudos to him. Where am I going with this? Well, as someone who gets Kevin Smith's comedy and dialogue, watching Chasing Amy for the first time in 2013 was really a let down. For some reason out of all the Smith films I've seen, I never got to Chasing Amy, so I was kind of saving it for a rainy day. I knew it is his most critically acclaimed, and coming out right after Mallrats it was his first real dramatic film that wasn't just suppose to be strictly comedic. This films takes its self serious because its about serious subject matter. Maybe I had built it up a bit in my head because of all this, I don't know, but when the rainy day finally came and I sat down to watch it, I wasn't impressed. The first thing I noticed is how much Kevin Smith films don't age well when the subject matter is serious in tone. First because of what I said before, its 2013, these topics are no longer controversial or risqu&eacute; in any way. Making a film about trying to make a lesbian straight, is no longer new or revelatory. The second thing I notice is how much Smith is trying to prove himself as a relevant and hip writer/director in this film. I think this was the film he wanted to be taken seriously for, and for the most part he did get noticed and recognized at the time, but now its just seems kind of like he was trying too hard. The dialogue seems too hip, too self aware, that it kind of takes away from the plot. Every character has to have a snappy comeback or a clever line of dialogue, it kind of gets annoying after the first half an hour. I mean people always praise Smith for how "real" his characters are or how clever his dialogue is, but all I kept thinking was how nobody I know talks like this. Its just seems pretty well, pre-written. Lastly, the plot itself I hate to say was pretty mediocre, and in my opinion not very fleshed out. Like I said, Smith was really trying to prove himself as a writer/director here, and it shows. It almost seems this was Smith's way of learning how to make a proper three act "Hollywood" mainstream film, and because he wasn't a seasoned writer/director at this point, it seems like he was learning as he went along. Joey Lauren Adams as Alyssa is somewhat annoying, and although she has that I-know-I'm-clever smirk and dialogue throughout, I don't really see the attraction. Ben Affleck and Jason Lee as Holden and Banky are fine, but they are just the two typical guy buddies who throw out gay jokes every second that seem to be in every Smith movie. I'm OK with how Holden and Alyssa fall for each other, but by the time we get to third act and we find out about Alyssa's past, and Holden's "final solution" it just falls apart, and to me made very little sense. I think Smith needed more experience as a screen writer at this point, and this was his experiment with a serious and mainstream film. For the most part he succeeded, as it was critically acclaimed at the time, but I think it had more to do with the then touchy subject matter which is now dated, and the way he wrote scripts, which is now just a Kevin Smith film. I like Kevin Smith, but this is a flawed film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Gunga.....
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    DustinRahksi
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Since it's the summer of comedy, and this was on my list and it got an depressing emotion out of me, I thought I'd review it. This definitely feels like Kevin Smiths most heartfelt film, it's not to big on the comedy. The best part of this film is that I was thoroughly interested, I only ever checked the runtime because I wanted it to be a little longer. Do not read if sensitive. Let just sum it up. The characters were believable for the most part, Joey Lauren Adams surprisingly didn't annoyed me, that's a first for her. Banky was the only character I actually cared about, even if he was a bit of an as-hole. Holden was just your average every man. And I'll get to Alyssa in a bit. Jay and silent bob only have one scene, I thought there would be more of them since they are on the cover, but oh well. There was a lot of good scenes, my favorites being the hockey rink scene and Silent Bobs story. Those had more weight to the story. Now comes the biggest thing people love to argue over, Alyssa's past. I've looked up and down the forums here, and people love talking about this. Well, it did bring a lot of drama into the story. Don't get sensitive over this, but yes, Alyssa was a slut, no argument there. Just watch the film and count how many sexual relations she talks about, your a joke if you don't think she isn't. The part about this that hit me the most was, this is very much a real thing, just look at people now-a-days. How would you react if your girlfriend or boyfriend was a whore, it's disgusting to think about. I would have taken Holden's side, even though his proposal in the end was a very dumb thing to do. Of course she truly did love him, but hey, she did some sick things, that no amount of Listerine can wash away. I probably would have just walked away from it. I for one have zero tolerance for loose women, so yeah it's understandable. Then people will cry, she was trying to find that someone, so a threesome is finding that someone, making a dirty film is finding that someone, sleeping around is finding that someone. BS, that's called being a slut, plain and simple, there is no argument. People like this spread diseases, it's not so bad being a virgin. Anyway, the film should have ended after the apartment proposal, because the rest doesn't make it any less depressing. Anyway, I feel like watching this movie again right now.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Engaging indie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Charles Herold (cherold)
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I haven't see that many Kevin Smith movies, and the ones I have seen were a mixed bag, but Chasing Amy is a genuinely entertaining and thoughtful movie. Jason Lee is very good, Affleck is decent, and Adams isn't bad once you get used to her Kewpie-doll voice. It's a movie that tries to think outside the conventions of movies, and while it doesn't entirely succeed, it does offer some surprises. This is also a movie that you will respond to differently depending on where you are in your own life. I saw it twice about ten year apart and liked it both times, but not necessarily for the same reasons. And a friend of mine saw the movie completely differently the second time she saw it. In short, it's funny and sometimes touching and it has something to say.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    This movie will mean different things to different viewers
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tvrose890
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    There is a lot more going on in this movie than meets the eye. But, the parable by Silent Bob pretty much sums it all up for me. The lifestyles, both traditional and alternative, seem to be diversions to the real message. The only absurd scene in the movie is when Holden arranges a meeting with Alyssa and Banky. The scene was totally unnecessary and it seemed like an awkward attempt to get to the final result. It was the only scene that turned me off. Like, who would propose such a thing to a person you supposedly love more than anything? Anyways, Holden blows it much like many of us have blown it when it comes to screwing up our relationships. We think of every reason in the book to why the relationship is wrong when in reality we are not ready to grow a relationship. The parable by Bob sums it all up on why we are chasing Amy. We can spend a lifetime looking for something we've lost.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A little late, but not TOO late, I hope
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Steviereno
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Spoiler alert. "Chasing Amy" is a small movie that does everything it set out to do. It is the kind of small movie all independent movies try to be, but that almost none achieve. It shows little lives, little people, little events in ways and language we all can understand and identify with. Even if we haven't fallen in love with a lesbian or written a successful comic book, we all want to know what it might be like - and the former, would be, for most of us, confusing; the latter would be less glamorous. And no, neither one for any of us would be a subject for an epic film - but would most likely be a film like "Chasing Amy." There are moments of confusion for Holden, as his absorbed ideas about homosexuality are challenged by reality, and his feelings when confronted with open sexuality in an undisguised, un-Hollywood young hotty, in Alyssa. He's lived a cloistered life; that is made abundantly clear by Kevin Smith's excellent reality-based writing and directing. Smith obviously know the world he is portraying. "Chasing Amy" is, in a way, like "Before Sunset" but with a lesbian, and without Paris - the one that got away, and with Holden wondering what in the world he was supposed to do. This is a movie I loved from moment one. I had not seen "Clerks", so it was my introduction to Kevin Smith. I got a thing going for Joey Lauren Adams that is still going on. And Jay and Silent Bob are the funniest two characters I've seen in films in decades. Any of us who doesn't know a Jay has simply not lived in the USA of the late 20th century till now. This is a movie I never miss seeing if the opportunity comes up. The bar booth scene with Banky and Alyssa comparing dating notes is priceless - right up there with Jack Nicholson ordering a sandwich in the diner in "Five Easy Pieces." I'd give "Cahsin Amy" a 10, but, though it achieves everything it sets out to do, it is just that one little bit that Kevin Smith didn't try to do with it that holds me back. Heck, if he had tried for more, he might have messed it up, so I should be glad he didn't. It is pretty much perfect the way it is. I debated between 9 and 10, and my 9.49 has to round down...LOL Great flick!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Chasing Amy  Very emotional and unusual romance with some jokes and a bit of tragedy
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Avid Climber
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Chasing Amy is about the one that got away, and how stupid and hurtful we can be when we're confronted something that test the limit of our knowledge. Romance with a few gags, a tragedy, a movie where you can stop and think. What would you have done? Personally, I think the girl and the black guy are very wise. The two white dudes are pure vanilla stupid. The emotional scenes are touching, and the dialogs are as solid as Kevin Smith can make them. The story is captivating with nice novel ideas, and the maturity of the treatment in the subject matter is beyond reproach. Joey Lauren Adams is little known as actresses go, but she gives us a powerful and very emotional performance. Ben Affleck might not be at his best, but it is still a pretty good performance. While you just want to slap some sense into Jason Lee's character, he plays the uncouth badmouth with little respect like a pro. Looking for a nice romance with an offbeat sentiment and you don't mind if it's not as slick as the high budget flicks Hollywood produces? This is yours. Try it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Bitter-Sweet Romantic Story With A Pulsating Heart
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Nick-leonardi
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Chasing Amy is a 1997 Comedy film directed by Kevin Smith and starring Ben Affleck, Jason Lee, and Joey Lauren Adams. Regarding the movie, opinions among Kevin Smith fans and moviegoers are polarizing to one another: many consider it to be his most entertaining film, others, his least successful. What is certain is that it's the most accessible, mainstream- friendly film of his. Holden (Affleck) and Banky (Lee) are two best friends and comic book artists, sharing the same apartment. At a comic book convention, they meet the lively Alyssa, another comic book artist. Holden falls in love with her almost immediately, while Banky clearly feels opposite feelings. Holden's world however is turned upside down when he finds out she's a lesbian. They do however become best friends, and surprisingly, they start a romantic relationship; but soon some facts concerning Alyssa's past will come to Holden's knowing, and all of the sudden things start getting more complicated, especially due to Alyssa's unstable sexual preference. The romantic side of the film is by no means a traditional one, in neither its warm-up, nor in its consequence. A great and hilarious script makes all of the main characters very likable and funny, including the one of Jason Lee, and especially the brief ones of Jay and Silent Bob, the two reoccurring characters in Kevin Smith's films, Silent Bob being played by Smith himself. Considering the subject matter, however, it would have been nice to have added a bit more depth to the story: Chasing Amy could have been a clever meditation on how rudely America's gay culture is treated by heterosexuals, despite being it a respected culture with a lot of supporters. It also seems that Kevin Smith didn't always pace the film in such an effective manner: some parts are too rushed and for that reason, it kills the natural flow a bit. It wouldn't have hurt to have made the movie a bit longer, considering the fact that it is very unlikely Smith wouldn't be able to forge an extra amount of great, heart-felt and hilarious scenes.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Chasing Amy, a textbook example of a good Rom-com
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    MisureRebellion
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    In Kevin Smith's 3rd film, Chasing Amy concerns Holden McNeil, a comic book artist, with best Banky Edwards beside him every step of the way, the two have become a hit with their comic book series, Bluntman & Chronic, based on the two characters Jay & Silent Bob, from the previous two films, (Clerks. & Mallrats). At a comic convention, Holden meets Alyssa, the girl he's only dreamed of, but he is crushed when he finds out that she is a lesbian. This is a what every Rom-com should be, it shouldn't try following the hot buttons of pop culture, it should be an original idea, with a cast of characters we should actually care about! Kevin Smith knew what we wanted, not something done a thousand times, but it should be something from your life, not something from a movie you saw on TV last night, it should be a story that we can level with as a theater going audience! I honestly can't remember the last time I made a bet that I could make a girl cool in time for the prom! The film is a definite 8.5 ticket stub in my books! The film is on Netflix for instant streaming, it's a definite check it out!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    an unconventional comedy that deals with realistic issues
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    joshjmuir
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Spoilers may appear so do not fear. I thoroughly enjoyed this film and having watched this an adult I have been able to enjoy all the subtle messages that are contained within. I have become so fed up of the traditional Hollywood formula so this was a breath of fresh air. For all the criticism of Ben Affleck as an actor this film seemed to accommodate his style and he pulled of an impressive performance. The complex relationship between his and Joey Lauren Adams character's is thought provoking and asks real questions. Somewhat of a rarity in film nowadays. Credit should be given to the supporting actors as they add to the emotional nuances that the script provided and most importantly portrayed realistic people with actual problems and life struggles. I like Kevin Smith and enjoy his take on film and hope that he continues to ask real questions and most importantly continue making films driven by his own passion. If I were to find any flaw in this premise it will have to be in that Joey Lauren Adams's Character refers to herself as a lesbian but she clearly has had intimate relationships with men, this might attributed to confusion within her own sexuality or that for that period in time she is only dating women but even if that is the case that would still make her bisexual. Perhaps this is just a commentary on how some men view lesbianism as the dialogue in the film does actually address this. Thought Provoking.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An underrated gem by the inventive Kevin Smith
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    JavikKatarn
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    With his debut feature, Clerks, Kevin Smith was granted the credentials to become one of the leading directors of indie cinema. The film about two friends working in a convenience store was a big hit with critics and audiences and became one of the defining films of the 90s. Smith followed it up in 1995 with Mallrats. Mallrats was a financial bomb and was poorly received by critics for its different style and humour to Clerks. Whilst nowhere near the more thoughtful and clever Clerks, Mallrats is a light-hearted and funny comedy with a lot of charm. Despite Mallrats' failure, Smith went on to direct a more sophisticated and heartfelt comedy called Chasing Amy. Chasing Amy was similar to Clerks in that it was a dramatic film with a lot of humour but it was more tonally upbeat and even had some emotional resonance. Chasing Amy is a terrific romantic comedy with a lot of charm and emotion, making it Smith's most potent work as a filmmaker though it lacks some of the influential appeal that Clerks had. Holden McNeil and Banky Edwards are two friends who work as comic book artists with their current series, the superhero duo of Bluntman and Chronic. At a convention, they meet a fellow comic book artist named Alyssa, who writes feminist graphic novels. After one night hanging out with Alyssa, Holden realizes that he is in love with her but his dreams of being with her are tarnished when he discovers that she is a lesbian. Alyssa still wants to be friends with Holden and they spend more time together. But Holden is unable to hide his true feelings for her and in a heartfelt confession, pours his heart out to her. Alyssa is at first hesitant about being involved with Holden but immediately returns his love back to him. Chasing Amy is one of those films that could've ended up being a gross- out comedy considering the source material was out-there for the time. But Smith manages to keep it from being crass and embarrassing. The closest to gross-out humour here is one scene where Alyssa and Banky compare 'battle-scars' from past sexual encounters together in a homage to Jaws. Most of the comedy is more cynical and sardonic but not subtle. There are many moments that are at most guaranteed to raise a bout of laughter like when Star Wars is accused of being white supremacist propaganda or when Banky reacts to Alyssa kissing a woman and then realizing he is in a lesbian bar juxtaposed to Holden's shocked choking up of discovering his fantasy doesn't got for his type. Most importantly though is the relationships between the characters. Holden and Alyssa are one of my favourite romantic couples in film and the chemistry between Ben Affleck and Joey Lauren Adams sells it along with Smith's writing. The two have a clear connection whether merely friendly or romantic. Holden breaking down to Alyssa and confessing his love for her has to go down as one of the best confession scenes in film and the writing along with Affleck's performance sells it. Those who doubt the guy's acting abilities only need to watch his performance here. Adams' voice at first gets a bit grating but she also gives a great performance as Alyssa, making for a perfect romantic foil. Jason Lee has some of the best lines in the film as Banky but his character isn't as developed or strong as the other two. His dismissive attitude toward Alyssa for being a lesbian followed by him being revealed as gay himself feels a bit too tagged on but it doesn't hurt the film and Lee does have some good chemistry with Affleck to support him. Jay and Silent Bob, the duo from Smith's View Askewniverse films, also make an appearance in one scene. Chasing Amy is a solid rom-com with a lot of dramatic heft and emotional resonance to it. Smith's writing is at its peak here and the comedy is just as vulgar and amusing this time around. The efforts of the actors are also worth noting in bringing this film to life, making for a deep connection with the characters and their issues. Smith has made a terrific comedy that is funny, touching and all around deep. If only Jersey Girl could achieve this much.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A review from the year 2013
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    JustStone
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I wouldn't consider myself a huge Kevin Smith fan, but I do enjoy his films. I like Mallrats, Clerks, Jay & Silent Bob Strike Back, in particular because they establish a common thread with Jay & Silent Bob, and they don't take themselves too seriously. Kevin Smith is a master of dirty, lewd, crude and downright offensive dialogue, I get that and for the most part I can appreciate it. When he was first making his films in the 90's, this was a somewhat controversial, as he was paving the way for the "nerd comedy" and doing so with vulgar dialogue, gay jokes, and touchy subject matter. Back in the 90's there really were no films about the comic-con sub culture, and serious gay themed films were rare and far and few between. However its 2013, and the comic book culture has risen to the mainstream. You can't go to a theater these days without seeing a superhero movie in the marquee, gays rights have been more accepted and gay characters are everywhere in the media. Kevin Smith type films are par for the course, and his subject matter is no longer as controversial because so much has changed. I mean you can thank Smith for some of this change, he helped push both comic book films into the mainstream, and in a way, made a film about a lesbian before its was as socially and widely acceptable. So kudos to him. Where am I going with this? Well, as someone who gets Kevin Smith's comedy and dialogue, watching Chasing Amy for the first time in 2013 was really a let down. For some reason out of all the Smith films I've seen, I never got to Chasing Amy, so I was kind of saving it for a rainy day. I knew it is his most critically acclaimed, and coming out right after Mallrats it was his first real dramatic film that wasn't just suppose to be strictly comedic. This films takes its self serious because its about serious subject matter. Maybe I had built it up a bit in my head because of all this, I don't know, but when the rainy day finally came and I sat down to watch it, I wasn't impressed. The first thing I noticed is how much Kevin Smith films don't age well when the subject matter is serious in tone. First because of what I said before, its 2013, these topics are no longer controversial or risqu&eacute; in any way. Making a film about trying to make a lesbian straight, is no longer new or revelatory. The second thing I notice is how much Smith is trying to prove himself as a relevant and hip writer/director in this film. I think this was the film he wanted to be taken seriously for, and for the most part he did get noticed and recognized at the time, but now its just seems kind of like he was trying too hard. The dialogue seems too hip, too self aware, that it kind of takes away from the plot. Every character has to have a snappy comeback or a clever line of dialogue, it kind of gets annoying after the first half an hour. I mean people always praise Smith for how "real" his characters are or how clever his dialogue is, but all I kept thinking was how nobody I know talks like this. Its just seems pretty well, pre-written. Lastly, the plot itself I hate to say was pretty mediocre, and in my opinion not very fleshed out. Like I said, Smith was really trying to prove himself as a writer/director here, and it shows. It almost seems this was Smith's way of learning how to make a proper three act "Hollywood" mainstream film, and because he wasn't a seasoned writer/director at this point, it seems like he was learning as he went along. Joey Lauren Adams as Alyssa is somewhat annoying, and although she has that I-know-I'm-clever smirk and dialogue throughout, I don't really see the attraction. Ben Affleck and Jason Lee as Holden and Banky are fine, but they are just the two typical guy buddies who throw out gay jokes every second that seem to be in every Smith movie. I'm OK with how Holden and Alyssa fall for each other, but by the time we get to third act and we find out about Alyssa's past, and Holden's "final solution" it just falls apart, and to me made very little sense. I think Smith needed more experience as a screen writer at this point, and this was his experiment with a serious and mainstream film. For the most part he succeeded, as it was critically acclaimed at the time, but I think it had more to do with the then touchy subject matter which is now dated, and the way he wrote scripts, which is now just a Kevin Smith film. I like Kevin Smith, but this is a flawed film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Gunga.....
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    DustinRahksi
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Since it's the summer of comedy, and this was on my list and it got an depressing emotion out of me, I thought I'd review it. This definitely feels like Kevin Smiths most heartfelt film, it's not to big on the comedy. The best part of this film is that I was thoroughly interested, I only ever checked the runtime because I wanted it to be a little longer. Do not read if sensitive. Let just sum it up. The characters were believable for the most part, Joey Lauren Adams surprisingly didn't annoyed me, that's a first for her. Banky was the only character I actually cared about, even if he was a bit of an as-hole. Holden was just your average every man. And I'll get to Alyssa in a bit. Jay and silent bob only have one scene, I thought there would be more of them since they are on the cover, but oh well. There was a lot of good scenes, my favorites being the hockey rink scene and Silent Bobs story. Those had more weight to the story. Now comes the biggest thing people love to argue over, Alyssa's past. I've looked up and down the forums here, and people love talking about this. Well, it did bring a lot of drama into the story. Don't get sensitive over this, but yes, Alyssa was a slut, no argument there. Just watch the film and count how many sexual relations she talks about, your a joke if you don't think she isn't. The part about this that hit me the most was, this is very much a real thing, just look at people now-a-days. How would you react if your girlfriend or boyfriend was a whore, it's disgusting to think about. I would have taken Holden's side, even though his proposal in the end was a very dumb thing to do. Of course she truly did love him, but hey, she did some sick things, that no amount of Listerine can wash away. I probably would have just walked away from it. I for one have zero tolerance for loose women, so yeah it's understandable. Then people will cry, she was trying to find that someone, so a threesome is finding that someone, making a dirty film is finding that someone, sleeping around is finding that someone. BS, that's called being a slut, plain and simple, there is no argument. People like this spread diseases, it's not so bad being a virgin. Anyway, the film should have ended after the apartment proposal, because the rest doesn't make it any less depressing. Anyway, I feel like watching this movie again right now.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Engaging indie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Charles Herold (cherold)
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I haven't see that many Kevin Smith movies, and the ones I have seen were a mixed bag, but Chasing Amy is a genuinely entertaining and thoughtful movie. Jason Lee is very good, Affleck is decent, and Adams isn't bad once you get used to her Kewpie-doll voice. It's a movie that tries to think outside the conventions of movies, and while it doesn't entirely succeed, it does offer some surprises. This is also a movie that you will respond to differently depending on where you are in your own life. I saw it twice about ten year apart and liked it both times, but not necessarily for the same reasons. And a friend of mine saw the movie completely differently the second time she saw it. In short, it's funny and sometimes touching and it has something to say.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    This movie will mean different things to different viewers
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tvrose890
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    There is a lot more going on in this movie than meets the eye. But, the parable by Silent Bob pretty much sums it all up for me. The lifestyles, both traditional and alternative, seem to be diversions to the real message. The only absurd scene in the movie is when Holden arranges a meeting with Alyssa and Banky. The scene was totally unnecessary and it seemed like an awkward attempt to get to the final result. It was the only scene that turned me off. Like, who would propose such a thing to a person you supposedly love more than anything? Anyways, Holden blows it much like many of us have blown it when it comes to screwing up our relationships. We think of every reason in the book to why the relationship is wrong when in reality we are not ready to grow a relationship. The parable by Bob sums it all up on why we are chasing Amy. We can spend a lifetime looking for something we've lost.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A little late, but not TOO late, I hope
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Steviereno
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Spoiler alert. "Chasing Amy" is a small movie that does everything it set out to do. It is the kind of small movie all independent movies try to be, but that almost none achieve. It shows little lives, little people, little events in ways and language we all can understand and identify with. Even if we haven't fallen in love with a lesbian or written a successful comic book, we all want to know what it might be like - and the former, would be, for most of us, confusing; the latter would be less glamorous. And no, neither one for any of us would be a subject for an epic film - but would most likely be a film like "Chasing Amy." There are moments of confusion for Holden, as his absorbed ideas about homosexuality are challenged by reality, and his feelings when confronted with open sexuality in an undisguised, un-Hollywood young hotty, in Alyssa. He's lived a cloistered life; that is made abundantly clear by Kevin Smith's excellent reality-based writing and directing. Smith obviously know the world he is portraying. "Chasing Amy" is, in a way, like "Before Sunset" but with a lesbian, and without Paris - the one that got away, and with Holden wondering what in the world he was supposed to do. This is a movie I loved from moment one. I had not seen "Clerks", so it was my introduction to Kevin Smith. I got a thing going for Joey Lauren Adams that is still going on. And Jay and Silent Bob are the funniest two characters I've seen in films in decades. Any of us who doesn't know a Jay has simply not lived in the USA of the late 20th century till now. This is a movie I never miss seeing if the opportunity comes up. The bar booth scene with Banky and Alyssa comparing dating notes is priceless - right up there with Jack Nicholson ordering a sandwich in the diner in "Five Easy Pieces." I'd give "Cahsin Amy" a 10, but, though it achieves everything it sets out to do, it is just that one little bit that Kevin Smith didn't try to do with it that holds me back. Heck, if he had tried for more, he might have messed it up, so I should be glad he didn't. It is pretty much perfect the way it is. I debated between 9 and 10, and my 9.49 has to round down...LOL Great flick!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Chasing Amy  Very emotional and unusual romance with some jokes and a bit of tragedy
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Avid Climber
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Chasing Amy is about the one that got away, and how stupid and hurtful we can be when we're confronted something that test the limit of our knowledge. Romance with a few gags, a tragedy, a movie where you can stop and think. What would you have done? Personally, I think the girl and the black guy are very wise. The two white dudes are pure vanilla stupid. The emotional scenes are touching, and the dialogs are as solid as Kevin Smith can make them. The story is captivating with nice novel ideas, and the maturity of the treatment in the subject matter is beyond reproach. Joey Lauren Adams is little known as actresses go, but she gives us a powerful and very emotional performance. Ben Affleck might not be at his best, but it is still a pretty good performance. While you just want to slap some sense into Jason Lee's character, he plays the uncouth badmouth with little respect like a pro. Looking for a nice romance with an offbeat sentiment and you don't mind if it's not as slick as the high budget flicks Hollywood produces? This is yours. Try it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Bitter-Sweet Romantic Story With A Pulsating Heart
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Nick-leonardi
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Chasing Amy is a 1997 Comedy film directed by Kevin Smith and starring Ben Affleck, Jason Lee, and Joey Lauren Adams. Regarding the movie, opinions among Kevin Smith fans and moviegoers are polarizing to one another: many consider it to be his most entertaining film, others, his least successful. What is certain is that it's the most accessible, mainstream- friendly film of his. Holden (Affleck) and Banky (Lee) are two best friends and comic book artists, sharing the same apartment. At a comic book convention, they meet the lively Alyssa, another comic book artist. Holden falls in love with her almost immediately, while Banky clearly feels opposite feelings. Holden's world however is turned upside down when he finds out she's a lesbian. They do however become best friends, and surprisingly, they start a romantic relationship; but soon some facts concerning Alyssa's past will come to Holden's knowing, and all of the sudden things start getting more complicated, especially due to Alyssa's unstable sexual preference. The romantic side of the film is by no means a traditional one, in neither its warm-up, nor in its consequence. A great and hilarious script makes all of the main characters very likable and funny, including the one of Jason Lee, and especially the brief ones of Jay and Silent Bob, the two reoccurring characters in Kevin Smith's films, Silent Bob being played by Smith himself. Considering the subject matter, however, it would have been nice to have added a bit more depth to the story: Chasing Amy could have been a clever meditation on how rudely America's gay culture is treated by heterosexuals, despite being it a respected culture with a lot of supporters. It also seems that Kevin Smith didn't always pace the film in such an effective manner: some parts are too rushed and for that reason, it kills the natural flow a bit. It wouldn't have hurt to have made the movie a bit longer, considering the fact that it is very unlikely Smith wouldn't be able to forge an extra amount of great, heart-felt and hilarious scenes.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Chasing Amy, a textbook example of a good Rom-com
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    MisureRebellion
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    In Kevin Smith's 3rd film, Chasing Amy concerns Holden McNeil, a comic book artist, with best Banky Edwards beside him every step of the way, the two have become a hit with their comic book series, Bluntman & Chronic, based on the two characters Jay & Silent Bob, from the previous two films, (Clerks. & Mallrats). At a comic convention, Holden meets Alyssa, the girl he's only dreamed of, but he is crushed when he finds out that she is a lesbian. This is a what every Rom-com should be, it shouldn't try following the hot buttons of pop culture, it should be an original idea, with a cast of characters we should actually care about! Kevin Smith knew what we wanted, not something done a thousand times, but it should be something from your life, not something from a movie you saw on TV last night, it should be a story that we can level with as a theater going audience! I honestly can't remember the last time I made a bet that I could make a girl cool in time for the prom! The film is a definite 8.5 ticket stub in my books! The film is on Netflix for instant streaming, it's a definite check it out!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    an unconventional comedy that deals with realistic issues
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    joshjmuir
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Spoilers may appear so do not fear. I thoroughly enjoyed this film and having watched this an adult I have been able to enjoy all the subtle messages that are contained within. I have become so fed up of the traditional Hollywood formula so this was a breath of fresh air. For all the criticism of Ben Affleck as an actor this film seemed to accommodate his style and he pulled of an impressive performance. The complex relationship between his and Joey Lauren Adams character's is thought provoking and asks real questions. Somewhat of a rarity in film nowadays. Credit should be given to the supporting actors as they add to the emotional nuances that the script provided and most importantly portrayed realistic people with actual problems and life struggles. I like Kevin Smith and enjoy his take on film and hope that he continues to ask real questions and most importantly continue making films driven by his own passion. If I were to find any flaw in this premise it will have to be in that Joey Lauren Adams's Character refers to herself as a lesbian but she clearly has had intimate relationships with men, this might attributed to confusion within her own sexuality or that for that period in time she is only dating women but even if that is the case that would still make her bisexual. Perhaps this is just a commentary on how some men view lesbianism as the dialogue in the film does actually address this. Thought Provoking.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An underrated gem by the inventive Kevin Smith
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    JavikKatarn
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    With his debut feature, Clerks, Kevin Smith was granted the credentials to become one of the leading directors of indie cinema. The film about two friends working in a convenience store was a big hit with critics and audiences and became one of the defining films of the 90s. Smith followed it up in 1995 with Mallrats. Mallrats was a financial bomb and was poorly received by critics for its different style and humour to Clerks. Whilst nowhere near the more thoughtful and clever Clerks, Mallrats is a light-hearted and funny comedy with a lot of charm. Despite Mallrats' failure, Smith went on to direct a more sophisticated and heartfelt comedy called Chasing Amy. Chasing Amy was similar to Clerks in that it was a dramatic film with a lot of humour but it was more tonally upbeat and even had some emotional resonance. Chasing Amy is a terrific romantic comedy with a lot of charm and emotion, making it Smith's most potent work as a filmmaker though it lacks some of the influential appeal that Clerks had. Holden McNeil and Banky Edwards are two friends who work as comic book artists with their current series, the superhero duo of Bluntman and Chronic. At a convention, they meet a fellow comic book artist named Alyssa, who writes feminist graphic novels. After one night hanging out with Alyssa, Holden realizes that he is in love with her but his dreams of being with her are tarnished when he discovers that she is a lesbian. Alyssa still wants to be friends with Holden and they spend more time together. But Holden is unable to hide his true feelings for her and in a heartfelt confession, pours his heart out to her. Alyssa is at first hesitant about being involved with Holden but immediately returns his love back to him. Chasing Amy is one of those films that could've ended up being a gross- out comedy considering the source material was out-there for the time. But Smith manages to keep it from being crass and embarrassing. The closest to gross-out humour here is one scene where Alyssa and Banky compare 'battle-scars' from past sexual encounters together in a homage to Jaws. Most of the comedy is more cynical and sardonic but not subtle. There are many moments that are at most guaranteed to raise a bout of laughter like when Star Wars is accused of being white supremacist propaganda or when Banky reacts to Alyssa kissing a woman and then realizing he is in a lesbian bar juxtaposed to Holden's shocked choking up of discovering his fantasy doesn't got for his type. Most importantly though is the relationships between the characters. Holden and Alyssa are one of my favourite romantic couples in film and the chemistry between Ben Affleck and Joey Lauren Adams sells it along with Smith's writing. The two have a clear connection whether merely friendly or romantic. Holden breaking down to Alyssa and confessing his love for her has to go down as one of the best confession scenes in film and the writing along with Affleck's performance sells it. Those who doubt the guy's acting abilities only need to watch his performance here. Adams' voice at first gets a bit grating but she also gives a great performance as Alyssa, making for a perfect romantic foil. Jason Lee has some of the best lines in the film as Banky but his character isn't as developed or strong as the other two. His dismissive attitude toward Alyssa for being a lesbian followed by him being revealed as gay himself feels a bit too tagged on but it doesn't hurt the film and Lee does have some good chemistry with Affleck to support him. Jay and Silent Bob, the duo from Smith's View Askewniverse films, also make an appearance in one scene. Chasing Amy is a solid rom-com with a lot of dramatic heft and emotional resonance to it. Smith's writing is at its peak here and the comedy is just as vulgar and amusing this time around. The efforts of the actors are also worth noting in bringing this film to life, making for a deep connection with the characters and their issues. Smith has made a terrific comedy that is funny, touching and all around deep. If only Jersey Girl could achieve this much.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A review from the year 2013
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    JustStone
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I wouldn't consider myself a huge Kevin Smith fan, but I do enjoy his films. I like Mallrats, Clerks, Jay & Silent Bob Strike Back, in particular because they establish a common thread with Jay & Silent Bob, and they don't take themselves too seriously. Kevin Smith is a master of dirty, lewd, crude and downright offensive dialogue, I get that and for the most part I can appreciate it. When he was first making his films in the 90's, this was a somewhat controversial, as he was paving the way for the "nerd comedy" and doing so with vulgar dialogue, gay jokes, and touchy subject matter. Back in the 90's there really were no films about the comic-con sub culture, and serious gay themed films were rare and far and few between. However its 2013, and the comic book culture has risen to the mainstream. You can't go to a theater these days without seeing a superhero movie in the marquee, gays rights have been more accepted and gay characters are everywhere in the media. Kevin Smith type films are par for the course, and his subject matter is no longer as controversial because so much has changed. I mean you can thank Smith for some of this change, he helped push both comic book films into the mainstream, and in a way, made a film about a lesbian before its was as socially and widely acceptable. So kudos to him. Where am I going with this? Well, as someone who gets Kevin Smith's comedy and dialogue, watching Chasing Amy for the first time in 2013 was really a let down. For some reason out of all the Smith films I've seen, I never got to Chasing Amy, so I was kind of saving it for a rainy day. I knew it is his most critically acclaimed, and coming out right after Mallrats it was his first real dramatic film that wasn't just suppose to be strictly comedic. This films takes its self serious because its about serious subject matter. Maybe I had built it up a bit in my head because of all this, I don't know, but when the rainy day finally came and I sat down to watch it, I wasn't impressed. The first thing I noticed is how much Kevin Smith films don't age well when the subject matter is serious in tone. First because of what I said before, its 2013, these topics are no longer controversial or risqu&eacute; in any way. Making a film about trying to make a lesbian straight, is no longer new or revelatory. The second thing I notice is how much Smith is trying to prove himself as a relevant and hip writer/director in this film. I think this was the film he wanted to be taken seriously for, and for the most part he did get noticed and recognized at the time, but now its just seems kind of like he was trying too hard. The dialogue seems too hip, too self aware, that it kind of takes away from the plot. Every character has to have a snappy comeback or a clever line of dialogue, it kind of gets annoying after the first half an hour. I mean people always praise Smith for how "real" his characters are or how clever his dialogue is, but all I kept thinking was how nobody I know talks like this. Its just seems pretty well, pre-written. Lastly, the plot itself I hate to say was pretty mediocre, and in my opinion not very fleshed out. Like I said, Smith was really trying to prove himself as a writer/director here, and it shows. It almost seems this was Smith's way of learning how to make a proper three act "Hollywood" mainstream film, and because he wasn't a seasoned writer/director at this point, it seems like he was learning as he went along. Joey Lauren Adams as Alyssa is somewhat annoying, and although she has that I-know-I'm-clever smirk and dialogue throughout, I don't really see the attraction. Ben Affleck and Jason Lee as Holden and Banky are fine, but they are just the two typical guy buddies who throw out gay jokes every second that seem to be in every Smith movie. I'm OK with how Holden and Alyssa fall for each other, but by the time we get to third act and we find out about Alyssa's past, and Holden's "final solution" it just falls apart, and to me made very little sense. I think Smith needed more experience as a screen writer at this point, and this was his experiment with a serious and mainstream film. For the most part he succeeded, as it was critically acclaimed at the time, but I think it had more to do with the then touchy subject matter which is now dated, and the way he wrote scripts, which is now just a Kevin Smith film. I like Kevin Smith, but this is a flawed film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Gunga.....
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    DustinRahksi
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Since it's the summer of comedy, and this was on my list and it got an depressing emotion out of me, I thought I'd review it. This definitely feels like Kevin Smiths most heartfelt film, it's not to big on the comedy. The best part of this film is that I was thoroughly interested, I only ever checked the runtime because I wanted it to be a little longer. Do not read if sensitive. Let just sum it up. The characters were believable for the most part, Joey Lauren Adams surprisingly didn't annoyed me, that's a first for her. Banky was the only character I actually cared about, even if he was a bit of an as-hole. Holden was just your average every man. And I'll get to Alyssa in a bit. Jay and silent bob only have one scene, I thought there would be more of them since they are on the cover, but oh well. There was a lot of good scenes, my favorites being the hockey rink scene and Silent Bobs story. Those had more weight to the story. Now comes the biggest thing people love to argue over, Alyssa's past. I've looked up and down the forums here, and people love talking about this. Well, it did bring a lot of drama into the story. Don't get sensitive over this, but yes, Alyssa was a slut, no argument there. Just watch the film and count how many sexual relations she talks about, your a joke if you don't think she isn't. The part about this that hit me the most was, this is very much a real thing, just look at people now-a-days. How would you react if your girlfriend or boyfriend was a whore, it's disgusting to think about. I would have taken Holden's side, even though his proposal in the end was a very dumb thing to do. Of course she truly did love him, but hey, she did some sick things, that no amount of Listerine can wash away. I probably would have just walked away from it. I for one have zero tolerance for loose women, so yeah it's understandable. Then people will cry, she was trying to find that someone, so a threesome is finding that someone, making a dirty film is finding that someone, sleeping around is finding that someone. BS, that's called being a slut, plain and simple, there is no argument. People like this spread diseases, it's not so bad being a virgin. Anyway, the film should have ended after the apartment proposal, because the rest doesn't make it any less depressing. Anyway, I feel like watching this movie again right now.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Engaging indie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Charles Herold (cherold)
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I haven't see that many Kevin Smith movies, and the ones I have seen were a mixed bag, but Chasing Amy is a genuinely entertaining and thoughtful movie. Jason Lee is very good, Affleck is decent, and Adams isn't bad once you get used to her Kewpie-doll voice. It's a movie that tries to think outside the conventions of movies, and while it doesn't entirely succeed, it does offer some surprises. This is also a movie that you will respond to differently depending on where you are in your own life. I saw it twice about ten year apart and liked it both times, but not necessarily for the same reasons. And a friend of mine saw the movie completely differently the second time she saw it. In short, it's funny and sometimes touching and it has something to say.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    This movie will mean different things to different viewers
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tvrose890
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    There is a lot more going on in this movie than meets the eye. But, the parable by Silent Bob pretty much sums it all up for me. The lifestyles, both traditional and alternative, seem to be diversions to the real message. The only absurd scene in the movie is when Holden arranges a meeting with Alyssa and Banky. The scene was totally unnecessary and it seemed like an awkward attempt to get to the final result. It was the only scene that turned me off. Like, who would propose such a thing to a person you supposedly love more than anything? Anyways, Holden blows it much like many of us have blown it when it comes to screwing up our relationships. We think of every reason in the book to why the relationship is wrong when in reality we are not ready to grow a relationship. The parable by Bob sums it all up on why we are chasing Amy. We can spend a lifetime looking for something we've lost.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A little late, but not TOO late, I hope
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Steviereno
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Spoiler alert. "Chasing Amy" is a small movie that does everything it set out to do. It is the kind of small movie all independent movies try to be, but that almost none achieve. It shows little lives, little people, little events in ways and language we all can understand and identify with. Even if we haven't fallen in love with a lesbian or written a successful comic book, we all want to know what it might be like - and the former, would be, for most of us, confusing; the latter would be less glamorous. And no, neither one for any of us would be a subject for an epic film - but would most likely be a film like "Chasing Amy." There are moments of confusion for Holden, as his absorbed ideas about homosexuality are challenged by reality, and his feelings when confronted with open sexuality in an undisguised, un-Hollywood young hotty, in Alyssa. He's lived a cloistered life; that is made abundantly clear by Kevin Smith's excellent reality-based writing and directing. Smith obviously know the world he is portraying. "Chasing Amy" is, in a way, like "Before Sunset" but with a lesbian, and without Paris - the one that got away, and with Holden wondering what in the world he was supposed to do. This is a movie I loved from moment one. I had not seen "Clerks", so it was my introduction to Kevin Smith. I got a thing going for Joey Lauren Adams that is still going on. And Jay and Silent Bob are the funniest two characters I've seen in films in decades. Any of us who doesn't know a Jay has simply not lived in the USA of the late 20th century till now. This is a movie I never miss seeing if the opportunity comes up. The bar booth scene with Banky and Alyssa comparing dating notes is priceless - right up there with Jack Nicholson ordering a sandwich in the diner in "Five Easy Pieces." I'd give "Cahsin Amy" a 10, but, though it achieves everything it sets out to do, it is just that one little bit that Kevin Smith didn't try to do with it that holds me back. Heck, if he had tried for more, he might have messed it up, so I should be glad he didn't. It is pretty much perfect the way it is. I debated between 9 and 10, and my 9.49 has to round down...LOL Great flick!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Chasing Amy  Very emotional and unusual romance with some jokes and a bit of tragedy
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Avid Climber
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Chasing Amy is about the one that got away, and how stupid and hurtful we can be when we're confronted something that test the limit of our knowledge. Romance with a few gags, a tragedy, a movie where you can stop and think. What would you have done? Personally, I think the girl and the black guy are very wise. The two white dudes are pure vanilla stupid. The emotional scenes are touching, and the dialogs are as solid as Kevin Smith can make them. The story is captivating with nice novel ideas, and the maturity of the treatment in the subject matter is beyond reproach. Joey Lauren Adams is little known as actresses go, but she gives us a powerful and very emotional performance. Ben Affleck might not be at his best, but it is still a pretty good performance. While you just want to slap some sense into Jason Lee's character, he plays the uncouth badmouth with little respect like a pro. Looking for a nice romance with an offbeat sentiment and you don't mind if it's not as slick as the high budget flicks Hollywood produces? This is yours. Try it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Bitter-Sweet Romantic Story With A Pulsating Heart
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Nick-leonardi
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Chasing Amy is a 1997 Comedy film directed by Kevin Smith and starring Ben Affleck, Jason Lee, and Joey Lauren Adams. Regarding the movie, opinions among Kevin Smith fans and moviegoers are polarizing to one another: many consider it to be his most entertaining film, others, his least successful. What is certain is that it's the most accessible, mainstream- friendly film of his. Holden (Affleck) and Banky (Lee) are two best friends and comic book artists, sharing the same apartment. At a comic book convention, they meet the lively Alyssa, another comic book artist. Holden falls in love with her almost immediately, while Banky clearly feels opposite feelings. Holden's world however is turned upside down when he finds out she's a lesbian. They do however become best friends, and surprisingly, they start a romantic relationship; but soon some facts concerning Alyssa's past will come to Holden's knowing, and all of the sudden things start getting more complicated, especially due to Alyssa's unstable sexual preference. The romantic side of the film is by no means a traditional one, in neither its warm-up, nor in its consequence. A great and hilarious script makes all of the main characters very likable and funny, including the one of Jason Lee, and especially the brief ones of Jay and Silent Bob, the two reoccurring characters in Kevin Smith's films, Silent Bob being played by Smith himself. Considering the subject matter, however, it would have been nice to have added a bit more depth to the story: Chasing Amy could have been a clever meditation on how rudely America's gay culture is treated by heterosexuals, despite being it a respected culture with a lot of supporters. It also seems that Kevin Smith didn't always pace the film in such an effective manner: some parts are too rushed and for that reason, it kills the natural flow a bit. It wouldn't have hurt to have made the movie a bit longer, considering the fact that it is very unlikely Smith wouldn't be able to forge an extra amount of great, heart-felt and hilarious scenes.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Chasing Amy, a textbook example of a good Rom-com
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    MisureRebellion
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    In Kevin Smith's 3rd film, Chasing Amy concerns Holden McNeil, a comic book artist, with best Banky Edwards beside him every step of the way, the two have become a hit with their comic book series, Bluntman & Chronic, based on the two characters Jay & Silent Bob, from the previous two films, (Clerks. & Mallrats). At a comic convention, Holden meets Alyssa, the girl he's only dreamed of, but he is crushed when he finds out that she is a lesbian. This is a what every Rom-com should be, it shouldn't try following the hot buttons of pop culture, it should be an original idea, with a cast of characters we should actually care about! Kevin Smith knew what we wanted, not something done a thousand times, but it should be something from your life, not something from a movie you saw on TV last night, it should be a story that we can level with as a theater going audience! I honestly can't remember the last time I made a bet that I could make a girl cool in time for the prom! The film is a definite 8.5 ticket stub in my books! The film is on Netflix for instant streaming, it's a definite check it out!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    an unconventional comedy that deals with realistic issues
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    joshjmuir
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Spoilers may appear so do not fear. I thoroughly enjoyed this film and having watched this an adult I have been able to enjoy all the subtle messages that are contained within. I have become so fed up of the traditional Hollywood formula so this was a breath of fresh air. For all the criticism of Ben Affleck as an actor this film seemed to accommodate his style and he pulled of an impressive performance. The complex relationship between his and Joey Lauren Adams character's is thought provoking and asks real questions. Somewhat of a rarity in film nowadays. Credit should be given to the supporting actors as they add to the emotional nuances that the script provided and most importantly portrayed realistic people with actual problems and life struggles. I like Kevin Smith and enjoy his take on film and hope that he continues to ask real questions and most importantly continue making films driven by his own passion. If I were to find any flaw in this premise it will have to be in that Joey Lauren Adams's Character refers to herself as a lesbian but she clearly has had intimate relationships with men, this might attributed to confusion within her own sexuality or that for that period in time she is only dating women but even if that is the case that would still make her bisexual. Perhaps this is just a commentary on how some men view lesbianism as the dialogue in the film does actually address this. Thought Provoking.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An underrated gem by the inventive Kevin Smith
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    JavikKatarn
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    With his debut feature, Clerks, Kevin Smith was granted the credentials to become one of the leading directors of indie cinema. The film about two friends working in a convenience store was a big hit with critics and audiences and became one of the defining films of the 90s. Smith followed it up in 1995 with Mallrats. Mallrats was a financial bomb and was poorly received by critics for its different style and humour to Clerks. Whilst nowhere near the more thoughtful and clever Clerks, Mallrats is a light-hearted and funny comedy with a lot of charm. Despite Mallrats' failure, Smith went on to direct a more sophisticated and heartfelt comedy called Chasing Amy. Chasing Amy was similar to Clerks in that it was a dramatic film with a lot of humour but it was more tonally upbeat and even had some emotional resonance. Chasing Amy is a terrific romantic comedy with a lot of charm and emotion, making it Smith's most potent work as a filmmaker though it lacks some of the influential appeal that Clerks had. Holden McNeil and Banky Edwards are two friends who work as comic book artists with their current series, the superhero duo of Bluntman and Chronic. At a convention, they meet a fellow comic book artist named Alyssa, who writes feminist graphic novels. After one night hanging out with Alyssa, Holden realizes that he is in love with her but his dreams of being with her are tarnished when he discovers that she is a lesbian. Alyssa still wants to be friends with Holden and they spend more time together. But Holden is unable to hide his true feelings for her and in a heartfelt confession, pours his heart out to her. Alyssa is at first hesitant about being involved with Holden but immediately returns his love back to him. Chasing Amy is one of those films that could've ended up being a gross- out comedy considering the source material was out-there for the time. But Smith manages to keep it from being crass and embarrassing. The closest to gross-out humour here is one scene where Alyssa and Banky compare 'battle-scars' from past sexual encounters together in a homage to Jaws. Most of the comedy is more cynical and sardonic but not subtle. There are many moments that are at most guaranteed to raise a bout of laughter like when Star Wars is accused of being white supremacist propaganda or when Banky reacts to Alyssa kissing a woman and then realizing he is in a lesbian bar juxtaposed to Holden's shocked choking up of discovering his fantasy doesn't got for his type. Most importantly though is the relationships between the characters. Holden and Alyssa are one of my favourite romantic couples in film and the chemistry between Ben Affleck and Joey Lauren Adams sells it along with Smith's writing. The two have a clear connection whether merely friendly or romantic. Holden breaking down to Alyssa and confessing his love for her has to go down as one of the best confession scenes in film and the writing along with Affleck's performance sells it. Those who doubt the guy's acting abilities only need to watch his performance here. Adams' voice at first gets a bit grating but she also gives a great performance as Alyssa, making for a perfect romantic foil. Jason Lee has some of the best lines in the film as Banky but his character isn't as developed or strong as the other two. His dismissive attitude toward Alyssa for being a lesbian followed by him being revealed as gay himself feels a bit too tagged on but it doesn't hurt the film and Lee does have some good chemistry with Affleck to support him. Jay and Silent Bob, the duo from Smith's View Askewniverse films, also make an appearance in one scene. Chasing Amy is a solid rom-com with a lot of dramatic heft and emotional resonance to it. Smith's writing is at its peak here and the comedy is just as vulgar and amusing this time around. The efforts of the actors are also worth noting in bringing this film to life, making for a deep connection with the characters and their issues. Smith has made a terrific comedy that is funny, touching and all around deep. If only Jersey Girl could achieve this much.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A review from the year 2013
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    JustStone
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I wouldn't consider myself a huge Kevin Smith fan, but I do enjoy his films. I like Mallrats, Clerks, Jay & Silent Bob Strike Back, in particular because they establish a common thread with Jay & Silent Bob, and they don't take themselves too seriously. Kevin Smith is a master of dirty, lewd, crude and downright offensive dialogue, I get that and for the most part I can appreciate it. When he was first making his films in the 90's, this was a somewhat controversial, as he was paving the way for the "nerd comedy" and doing so with vulgar dialogue, gay jokes, and touchy subject matter. Back in the 90's there really were no films about the comic-con sub culture, and serious gay themed films were rare and far and few between. However its 2013, and the comic book culture has risen to the mainstream. You can't go to a theater these days without seeing a superhero movie in the marquee, gays rights have been more accepted and gay characters are everywhere in the media. Kevin Smith type films are par for the course, and his subject matter is no longer as controversial because so much has changed. I mean you can thank Smith for some of this change, he helped push both comic book films into the mainstream, and in a way, made a film about a lesbian before its was as socially and widely acceptable. So kudos to him. Where am I going with this? Well, as someone who gets Kevin Smith's comedy and dialogue, watching Chasing Amy for the first time in 2013 was really a let down. For some reason out of all the Smith films I've seen, I never got to Chasing Amy, so I was kind of saving it for a rainy day. I knew it is his most critically acclaimed, and coming out right after Mallrats it was his first real dramatic film that wasn't just suppose to be strictly comedic. This films takes its self serious because its about serious subject matter. Maybe I had built it up a bit in my head because of all this, I don't know, but when the rainy day finally came and I sat down to watch it, I wasn't impressed. The first thing I noticed is how much Kevin Smith films don't age well when the subject matter is serious in tone. First because of what I said before, its 2013, these topics are no longer controversial or risqu&eacute; in any way. Making a film about trying to make a lesbian straight, is no longer new or revelatory. The second thing I notice is how much Smith is trying to prove himself as a relevant and hip writer/director in this film. I think this was the film he wanted to be taken seriously for, and for the most part he did get noticed and recognized at the time, but now its just seems kind of like he was trying too hard. The dialogue seems too hip, too self aware, that it kind of takes away from the plot. Every character has to have a snappy comeback or a clever line of dialogue, it kind of gets annoying after the first half an hour. I mean people always praise Smith for how "real" his characters are or how clever his dialogue is, but all I kept thinking was how nobody I know talks like this. Its just seems pretty well, pre-written. Lastly, the plot itself I hate to say was pretty mediocre, and in my opinion not very fleshed out. Like I said, Smith was really trying to prove himself as a writer/director here, and it shows. It almost seems this was Smith's way of learning how to make a proper three act "Hollywood" mainstream film, and because he wasn't a seasoned writer/director at this point, it seems like he was learning as he went along. Joey Lauren Adams as Alyssa is somewhat annoying, and although she has that I-know-I'm-clever smirk and dialogue throughout, I don't really see the attraction. Ben Affleck and Jason Lee as Holden and Banky are fine, but they are just the two typical guy buddies who throw out gay jokes every second that seem to be in every Smith movie. I'm OK with how Holden and Alyssa fall for each other, but by the time we get to third act and we find out about Alyssa's past, and Holden's "final solution" it just falls apart, and to me made very little sense. I think Smith needed more experience as a screen writer at this point, and this was his experiment with a serious and mainstream film. For the most part he succeeded, as it was critically acclaimed at the time, but I think it had more to do with the then touchy subject matter which is now dated, and the way he wrote scripts, which is now just a Kevin Smith film. I like Kevin Smith, but this is a flawed film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Gunga.....
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    DustinRahksi
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Since it's the summer of comedy, and this was on my list and it got an depressing emotion out of me, I thought I'd review it. This definitely feels like Kevin Smiths most heartfelt film, it's not to big on the comedy. The best part of this film is that I was thoroughly interested, I only ever checked the runtime because I wanted it to be a little longer. Do not read if sensitive. Let just sum it up. The characters were believable for the most part, Joey Lauren Adams surprisingly didn't annoyed me, that's a first for her. Banky was the only character I actually cared about, even if he was a bit of an as-hole. Holden was just your average every man. And I'll get to Alyssa in a bit. Jay and silent bob only have one scene, I thought there would be more of them since they are on the cover, but oh well. There was a lot of good scenes, my favorites being the hockey rink scene and Silent Bobs story. Those had more weight to the story. Now comes the biggest thing people love to argue over, Alyssa's past. I've looked up and down the forums here, and people love talking about this. Well, it did bring a lot of drama into the story. Don't get sensitive over this, but yes, Alyssa was a slut, no argument there. Just watch the film and count how many sexual relations she talks about, your a joke if you don't think she isn't. The part about this that hit me the most was, this is very much a real thing, just look at people now-a-days. How would you react if your girlfriend or boyfriend was a whore, it's disgusting to think about. I would have taken Holden's side, even though his proposal in the end was a very dumb thing to do. Of course she truly did love him, but hey, she did some sick things, that no amount of Listerine can wash away. I probably would have just walked away from it. I for one have zero tolerance for loose women, so yeah it's understandable. Then people will cry, she was trying to find that someone, so a threesome is finding that someone, making a dirty film is finding that someone, sleeping around is finding that someone. BS, that's called being a slut, plain and simple, there is no argument. People like this spread diseases, it's not so bad being a virgin. Anyway, the film should have ended after the apartment proposal, because the rest doesn't make it any less depressing. Anyway, I feel like watching this movie again right now.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Engaging indie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Charles Herold (cherold)
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I haven't see that many Kevin Smith movies, and the ones I have seen were a mixed bag, but Chasing Amy is a genuinely entertaining and thoughtful movie. Jason Lee is very good, Affleck is decent, and Adams isn't bad once you get used to her Kewpie-doll voice. It's a movie that tries to think outside the conventions of movies, and while it doesn't entirely succeed, it does offer some surprises. This is also a movie that you will respond to differently depending on where you are in your own life. I saw it twice about ten year apart and liked it both times, but not necessarily for the same reasons. And a friend of mine saw the movie completely differently the second time she saw it. In short, it's funny and sometimes touching and it has something to say.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    This movie will mean different things to different viewers
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tvrose890
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    There is a lot more going on in this movie than meets the eye. But, the parable by Silent Bob pretty much sums it all up for me. The lifestyles, both traditional and alternative, seem to be diversions to the real message. The only absurd scene in the movie is when Holden arranges a meeting with Alyssa and Banky. The scene was totally unnecessary and it seemed like an awkward attempt to get to the final result. It was the only scene that turned me off. Like, who would propose such a thing to a person you supposedly love more than anything? Anyways, Holden blows it much like many of us have blown it when it comes to screwing up our relationships. We think of every reason in the book to why the relationship is wrong when in reality we are not ready to grow a relationship. The parable by Bob sums it all up on why we are chasing Amy. We can spend a lifetime looking for something we've lost.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A little late, but not TOO late, I hope
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Steviereno
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Spoiler alert. "Chasing Amy" is a small movie that does everything it set out to do. It is the kind of small movie all independent movies try to be, but that almost none achieve. It shows little lives, little people, little events in ways and language we all can understand and identify with. Even if we haven't fallen in love with a lesbian or written a successful comic book, we all want to know what it might be like - and the former, would be, for most of us, confusing; the latter would be less glamorous. And no, neither one for any of us would be a subject for an epic film - but would most likely be a film like "Chasing Amy." There are moments of confusion for Holden, as his absorbed ideas about homosexuality are challenged by reality, and his feelings when confronted with open sexuality in an undisguised, un-Hollywood young hotty, in Alyssa. He's lived a cloistered life; that is made abundantly clear by Kevin Smith's excellent reality-based writing and directing. Smith obviously know the world he is portraying. "Chasing Amy" is, in a way, like "Before Sunset" but with a lesbian, and without Paris - the one that got away, and with Holden wondering what in the world he was supposed to do. This is a movie I loved from moment one. I had not seen "Clerks", so it was my introduction to Kevin Smith. I got a thing going for Joey Lauren Adams that is still going on. And Jay and Silent Bob are the funniest two characters I've seen in films in decades. Any of us who doesn't know a Jay has simply not lived in the USA of the late 20th century till now. This is a movie I never miss seeing if the opportunity comes up. The bar booth scene with Banky and Alyssa comparing dating notes is priceless - right up there with Jack Nicholson ordering a sandwich in the diner in "Five Easy Pieces." I'd give "Cahsin Amy" a 10, but, though it achieves everything it sets out to do, it is just that one little bit that Kevin Smith didn't try to do with it that holds me back. Heck, if he had tried for more, he might have messed it up, so I should be glad he didn't. It is pretty much perfect the way it is. I debated between 9 and 10, and my 9.49 has to round down...LOL Great flick!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Chasing Amy  Very emotional and unusual romance with some jokes and a bit of tragedy
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Avid Climber
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Chasing Amy is about the one that got away, and how stupid and hurtful we can be when we're confronted something that test the limit of our knowledge. Romance with a few gags, a tragedy, a movie where you can stop and think. What would you have done? Personally, I think the girl and the black guy are very wise. The two white dudes are pure vanilla stupid. The emotional scenes are touching, and the dialogs are as solid as Kevin Smith can make them. The story is captivating with nice novel ideas, and the maturity of the treatment in the subject matter is beyond reproach. Joey Lauren Adams is little known as actresses go, but she gives us a powerful and very emotional performance. Ben Affleck might not be at his best, but it is still a pretty good performance. While you just want to slap some sense into Jason Lee's character, he plays the uncouth badmouth with little respect like a pro. Looking for a nice romance with an offbeat sentiment and you don't mind if it's not as slick as the high budget flicks Hollywood produces? This is yours. Try it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Bitter-Sweet Romantic Story With A Pulsating Heart
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Nick-leonardi
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Chasing Amy is a 1997 Comedy film directed by Kevin Smith and starring Ben Affleck, Jason Lee, and Joey Lauren Adams. Regarding the movie, opinions among Kevin Smith fans and moviegoers are polarizing to one another: many consider it to be his most entertaining film, others, his least successful. What is certain is that it's the most accessible, mainstream- friendly film of his. Holden (Affleck) and Banky (Lee) are two best friends and comic book artists, sharing the same apartment. At a comic book convention, they meet the lively Alyssa, another comic book artist. Holden falls in love with her almost immediately, while Banky clearly feels opposite feelings. Holden's world however is turned upside down when he finds out she's a lesbian. They do however become best friends, and surprisingly, they start a romantic relationship; but soon some facts concerning Alyssa's past will come to Holden's knowing, and all of the sudden things start getting more complicated, especially due to Alyssa's unstable sexual preference. The romantic side of the film is by no means a traditional one, in neither its warm-up, nor in its consequence. A great and hilarious script makes all of the main characters very likable and funny, including the one of Jason Lee, and especially the brief ones of Jay and Silent Bob, the two reoccurring characters in Kevin Smith's films, Silent Bob being played by Smith himself. Considering the subject matter, however, it would have been nice to have added a bit more depth to the story: Chasing Amy could have been a clever meditation on how rudely America's gay culture is treated by heterosexuals, despite being it a respected culture with a lot of supporters. It also seems that Kevin Smith didn't always pace the film in such an effective manner: some parts are too rushed and for that reason, it kills the natural flow a bit. It wouldn't have hurt to have made the movie a bit longer, considering the fact that it is very unlikely Smith wouldn't be able to forge an extra amount of great, heart-felt and hilarious scenes.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Chasing Amy, a textbook example of a good Rom-com
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    MisureRebellion
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    In Kevin Smith's 3rd film, Chasing Amy concerns Holden McNeil, a comic book artist, with best Banky Edwards beside him every step of the way, the two have become a hit with their comic book series, Bluntman & Chronic, based on the two characters Jay & Silent Bob, from the previous two films, (Clerks. & Mallrats). At a comic convention, Holden meets Alyssa, the girl he's only dreamed of, but he is crushed when he finds out that she is a lesbian. This is a what every Rom-com should be, it shouldn't try following the hot buttons of pop culture, it should be an original idea, with a cast of characters we should actually care about! Kevin Smith knew what we wanted, not something done a thousand times, but it should be something from your life, not something from a movie you saw on TV last night, it should be a story that we can level with as a theater going audience! I honestly can't remember the last time I made a bet that I could make a girl cool in time for the prom! The film is a definite 8.5 ticket stub in my books! The film is on Netflix for instant streaming, it's a definite check it out!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    an unconventional comedy that deals with realistic issues
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    joshjmuir
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Spoilers may appear so do not fear. I thoroughly enjoyed this film and having watched this an adult I have been able to enjoy all the subtle messages that are contained within. I have become so fed up of the traditional Hollywood formula so this was a breath of fresh air. For all the criticism of Ben Affleck as an actor this film seemed to accommodate his style and he pulled of an impressive performance. The complex relationship between his and Joey Lauren Adams character's is thought provoking and asks real questions. Somewhat of a rarity in film nowadays. Credit should be given to the supporting actors as they add to the emotional nuances that the script provided and most importantly portrayed realistic people with actual problems and life struggles. I like Kevin Smith and enjoy his take on film and hope that he continues to ask real questions and most importantly continue making films driven by his own passion. If I were to find any flaw in this premise it will have to be in that Joey Lauren Adams's Character refers to herself as a lesbian but she clearly has had intimate relationships with men, this might attributed to confusion within her own sexuality or that for that period in time she is only dating women but even if that is the case that would still make her bisexual. Perhaps this is just a commentary on how some men view lesbianism as the dialogue in the film does actually address this. Thought Provoking.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An underrated gem by the inventive Kevin Smith
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    JavikKatarn
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    With his debut feature, Clerks, Kevin Smith was granted the credentials to become one of the leading directors of indie cinema. The film about two friends working in a convenience store was a big hit with critics and audiences and became one of the defining films of the 90s. Smith followed it up in 1995 with Mallrats. Mallrats was a financial bomb and was poorly received by critics for its different style and humour to Clerks. Whilst nowhere near the more thoughtful and clever Clerks, Mallrats is a light-hearted and funny comedy with a lot of charm. Despite Mallrats' failure, Smith went on to direct a more sophisticated and heartfelt comedy called Chasing Amy. Chasing Amy was similar to Clerks in that it was a dramatic film with a lot of humour but it was more tonally upbeat and even had some emotional resonance. Chasing Amy is a terrific romantic comedy with a lot of charm and emotion, making it Smith's most potent work as a filmmaker though it lacks some of the influential appeal that Clerks had. Holden McNeil and Banky Edwards are two friends who work as comic book artists with their current series, the superhero duo of Bluntman and Chronic. At a convention, they meet a fellow comic book artist named Alyssa, who writes feminist graphic novels. After one night hanging out with Alyssa, Holden realizes that he is in love with her but his dreams of being with her are tarnished when he discovers that she is a lesbian. Alyssa still wants to be friends with Holden and they spend more time together. But Holden is unable to hide his true feelings for her and in a heartfelt confession, pours his heart out to her. Alyssa is at first hesitant about being involved with Holden but immediately returns his love back to him. Chasing Amy is one of those films that could've ended up being a gross- out comedy considering the source material was out-there for the time. But Smith manages to keep it from being crass and embarrassing. The closest to gross-out humour here is one scene where Alyssa and Banky compare 'battle-scars' from past sexual encounters together in a homage to Jaws. Most of the comedy is more cynical and sardonic but not subtle. There are many moments that are at most guaranteed to raise a bout of laughter like when Star Wars is accused of being white supremacist propaganda or when Banky reacts to Alyssa kissing a woman and then realizing he is in a lesbian bar juxtaposed to Holden's shocked choking up of discovering his fantasy doesn't got for his type. Most importantly though is the relationships between the characters. Holden and Alyssa are one of my favourite romantic couples in film and the chemistry between Ben Affleck and Joey Lauren Adams sells it along with Smith's writing. The two have a clear connection whether merely friendly or romantic. Holden breaking down to Alyssa and confessing his love for her has to go down as one of the best confession scenes in film and the writing along with Affleck's performance sells it. Those who doubt the guy's acting abilities only need to watch his performance here. Adams' voice at first gets a bit grating but she also gives a great performance as Alyssa, making for a perfect romantic foil. Jason Lee has some of the best lines in the film as Banky but his character isn't as developed or strong as the other two. His dismissive attitude toward Alyssa for being a lesbian followed by him being revealed as gay himself feels a bit too tagged on but it doesn't hurt the film and Lee does have some good chemistry with Affleck to support him. Jay and Silent Bob, the duo from Smith's View Askewniverse films, also make an appearance in one scene. Chasing Amy is a solid rom-com with a lot of dramatic heft and emotional resonance to it. Smith's writing is at its peak here and the comedy is just as vulgar and amusing this time around. The efforts of the actors are also worth noting in bringing this film to life, making for a deep connection with the characters and their issues. Smith has made a terrific comedy that is funny, touching and all around deep. If only Jersey Girl could achieve this much.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A review from the year 2013
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    JustStone
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I wouldn't consider myself a huge Kevin Smith fan, but I do enjoy his films. I like Mallrats, Clerks, Jay & Silent Bob Strike Back, in particular because they establish a common thread with Jay & Silent Bob, and they don't take themselves too seriously. Kevin Smith is a master of dirty, lewd, crude and downright offensive dialogue, I get that and for the most part I can appreciate it. When he was first making his films in the 90's, this was a somewhat controversial, as he was paving the way for the "nerd comedy" and doing so with vulgar dialogue, gay jokes, and touchy subject matter. Back in the 90's there really were no films about the comic-con sub culture, and serious gay themed films were rare and far and few between. However its 2013, and the comic book culture has risen to the mainstream. You can't go to a theater these days without seeing a superhero movie in the marquee, gays rights have been more accepted and gay characters are everywhere in the media. Kevin Smith type films are par for the course, and his subject matter is no longer as controversial because so much has changed. I mean you can thank Smith for some of this change, he helped push both comic book films into the mainstream, and in a way, made a film about a lesbian before its was as socially and widely acceptable. So kudos to him. Where am I going with this? Well, as someone who gets Kevin Smith's comedy and dialogue, watching Chasing Amy for the first time in 2013 was really a let down. For some reason out of all the Smith films I've seen, I never got to Chasing Amy, so I was kind of saving it for a rainy day. I knew it is his most critically acclaimed, and coming out right after Mallrats it was his first real dramatic film that wasn't just suppose to be strictly comedic. This films takes its self serious because its about serious subject matter. Maybe I had built it up a bit in my head because of all this, I don't know, but when the rainy day finally came and I sat down to watch it, I wasn't impressed. The first thing I noticed is how much Kevin Smith films don't age well when the subject matter is serious in tone. First because of what I said before, its 2013, these topics are no longer controversial or risqu&eacute; in any way. Making a film about trying to make a lesbian straight, is no longer new or revelatory. The second thing I notice is how much Smith is trying to prove himself as a relevant and hip writer/director in this film. I think this was the film he wanted to be taken seriously for, and for the most part he did get noticed and recognized at the time, but now its just seems kind of like he was trying too hard. The dialogue seems too hip, too self aware, that it kind of takes away from the plot. Every character has to have a snappy comeback or a clever line of dialogue, it kind of gets annoying after the first half an hour. I mean people always praise Smith for how "real" his characters are or how clever his dialogue is, but all I kept thinking was how nobody I know talks like this. Its just seems pretty well, pre-written. Lastly, the plot itself I hate to say was pretty mediocre, and in my opinion not very fleshed out. Like I said, Smith was really trying to prove himself as a writer/director here, and it shows. It almost seems this was Smith's way of learning how to make a proper three act "Hollywood" mainstream film, and because he wasn't a seasoned writer/director at this point, it seems like he was learning as he went along. Joey Lauren Adams as Alyssa is somewhat annoying, and although she has that I-know-I'm-clever smirk and dialogue throughout, I don't really see the attraction. Ben Affleck and Jason Lee as Holden and Banky are fine, but they are just the two typical guy buddies who throw out gay jokes every second that seem to be in every Smith movie. I'm OK with how Holden and Alyssa fall for each other, but by the time we get to third act and we find out about Alyssa's past, and Holden's "final solution" it just falls apart, and to me made very little sense. I think Smith needed more experience as a screen writer at this point, and this was his experiment with a serious and mainstream film. For the most part he succeeded, as it was critically acclaimed at the time, but I think it had more to do with the then touchy subject matter which is now dated, and the way he wrote scripts, which is now just a Kevin Smith film. I like Kevin Smith, but this is a flawed film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Gunga.....
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    DustinRahksi
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Since it's the summer of comedy, and this was on my list and it got an depressing emotion out of me, I thought I'd review it. This definitely feels like Kevin Smiths most heartfelt film, it's not to big on the comedy. The best part of this film is that I was thoroughly interested, I only ever checked the runtime because I wanted it to be a little longer. Do not read if sensitive. Let just sum it up. The characters were believable for the most part, Joey Lauren Adams surprisingly didn't annoyed me, that's a first for her. Banky was the only character I actually cared about, even if he was a bit of an as-hole. Holden was just your average every man. And I'll get to Alyssa in a bit. Jay and silent bob only have one scene, I thought there would be more of them since they are on the cover, but oh well. There was a lot of good scenes, my favorites being the hockey rink scene and Silent Bobs story. Those had more weight to the story. Now comes the biggest thing people love to argue over, Alyssa's past. I've looked up and down the forums here, and people love talking about this. Well, it did bring a lot of drama into the story. Don't get sensitive over this, but yes, Alyssa was a slut, no argument there. Just watch the film and count how many sexual relations she talks about, your a joke if you don't think she isn't. The part about this that hit me the most was, this is very much a real thing, just look at people now-a-days. How would you react if your girlfriend or boyfriend was a whore, it's disgusting to think about. I would have taken Holden's side, even though his proposal in the end was a very dumb thing to do. Of course she truly did love him, but hey, she did some sick things, that no amount of Listerine can wash away. I probably would have just walked away from it. I for one have zero tolerance for loose women, so yeah it's understandable. Then people will cry, she was trying to find that someone, so a threesome is finding that someone, making a dirty film is finding that someone, sleeping around is finding that someone. BS, that's called being a slut, plain and simple, there is no argument. People like this spread diseases, it's not so bad being a virgin. Anyway, the film should have ended after the apartment proposal, because the rest doesn't make it any less depressing. Anyway, I feel like watching this movie again right now.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Engaging indie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Charles Herold (cherold)
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I haven't see that many Kevin Smith movies, and the ones I have seen were a mixed bag, but Chasing Amy is a genuinely entertaining and thoughtful movie. Jason Lee is very good, Affleck is decent, and Adams isn't bad once you get used to her Kewpie-doll voice. It's a movie that tries to think outside the conventions of movies, and while it doesn't entirely succeed, it does offer some surprises. This is also a movie that you will respond to differently depending on where you are in your own life. I saw it twice about ten year apart and liked it both times, but not necessarily for the same reasons. And a friend of mine saw the movie completely differently the second time she saw it. In short, it's funny and sometimes touching and it has something to say.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    This movie will mean different things to different viewers
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tvrose890
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    There is a lot more going on in this movie than meets the eye. But, the parable by Silent Bob pretty much sums it all up for me. The lifestyles, both traditional and alternative, seem to be diversions to the real message. The only absurd scene in the movie is when Holden arranges a meeting with Alyssa and Banky. The scene was totally unnecessary and it seemed like an awkward attempt to get to the final result. It was the only scene that turned me off. Like, who would propose such a thing to a person you supposedly love more than anything? Anyways, Holden blows it much like many of us have blown it when it comes to screwing up our relationships. We think of every reason in the book to why the relationship is wrong when in reality we are not ready to grow a relationship. The parable by Bob sums it all up on why we are chasing Amy. We can spend a lifetime looking for something we've lost.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A little late, but not TOO late, I hope
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Steviereno
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Spoiler alert. "Chasing Amy" is a small movie that does everything it set out to do. It is the kind of small movie all independent movies try to be, but that almost none achieve. It shows little lives, little people, little events in ways and language we all can understand and identify with. Even if we haven't fallen in love with a lesbian or written a successful comic book, we all want to know what it might be like - and the former, would be, for most of us, confusing; the latter would be less glamorous. And no, neither one for any of us would be a subject for an epic film - but would most likely be a film like "Chasing Amy." There are moments of confusion for Holden, as his absorbed ideas about homosexuality are challenged by reality, and his feelings when confronted with open sexuality in an undisguised, un-Hollywood young hotty, in Alyssa. He's lived a cloistered life; that is made abundantly clear by Kevin Smith's excellent reality-based writing and directing. Smith obviously know the world he is portraying. "Chasing Amy" is, in a way, like "Before Sunset" but with a lesbian, and without Paris - the one that got away, and with Holden wondering what in the world he was supposed to do. This is a movie I loved from moment one. I had not seen "Clerks", so it was my introduction to Kevin Smith. I got a thing going for Joey Lauren Adams that is still going on. And Jay and Silent Bob are the funniest two characters I've seen in films in decades. Any of us who doesn't know a Jay has simply not lived in the USA of the late 20th century till now. This is a movie I never miss seeing if the opportunity comes up. The bar booth scene with Banky and Alyssa comparing dating notes is priceless - right up there with Jack Nicholson ordering a sandwich in the diner in "Five Easy Pieces." I'd give "Cahsin Amy" a 10, but, though it achieves everything it sets out to do, it is just that one little bit that Kevin Smith didn't try to do with it that holds me back. Heck, if he had tried for more, he might have messed it up, so I should be glad he didn't. It is pretty much perfect the way it is. I debated between 9 and 10, and my 9.49 has to round down...LOL Great flick!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Chasing Amy  Very emotional and unusual romance with some jokes and a bit of tragedy
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Avid Climber
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Chasing Amy is about the one that got away, and how stupid and hurtful we can be when we're confronted something that test the limit of our knowledge. Romance with a few gags, a tragedy, a movie where you can stop and think. What would you have done? Personally, I think the girl and the black guy are very wise. The two white dudes are pure vanilla stupid. The emotional scenes are touching, and the dialogs are as solid as Kevin Smith can make them. The story is captivating with nice novel ideas, and the maturity of the treatment in the subject matter is beyond reproach. Joey Lauren Adams is little known as actresses go, but she gives us a powerful and very emotional performance. Ben Affleck might not be at his best, but it is still a pretty good performance. While you just want to slap some sense into Jason Lee's character, he plays the uncouth badmouth with little respect like a pro. Looking for a nice romance with an offbeat sentiment and you don't mind if it's not as slick as the high budget flicks Hollywood produces? This is yours. Try it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Bitter-Sweet Romantic Story With A Pulsating Heart
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Nick-leonardi
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Chasing Amy is a 1997 Comedy film directed by Kevin Smith and starring Ben Affleck, Jason Lee, and Joey Lauren Adams. Regarding the movie, opinions among Kevin Smith fans and moviegoers are polarizing to one another: many consider it to be his most entertaining film, others, his least successful. What is certain is that it's the most accessible, mainstream- friendly film of his. Holden (Affleck) and Banky (Lee) are two best friends and comic book artists, sharing the same apartment. At a comic book convention, they meet the lively Alyssa, another comic book artist. Holden falls in love with her almost immediately, while Banky clearly feels opposite feelings. Holden's world however is turned upside down when he finds out she's a lesbian. They do however become best friends, and surprisingly, they start a romantic relationship; but soon some facts concerning Alyssa's past will come to Holden's knowing, and all of the sudden things start getting more complicated, especially due to Alyssa's unstable sexual preference. The romantic side of the film is by no means a traditional one, in neither its warm-up, nor in its consequence. A great and hilarious script makes all of the main characters very likable and funny, including the one of Jason Lee, and especially the brief ones of Jay and Silent Bob, the two reoccurring characters in Kevin Smith's films, Silent Bob being played by Smith himself. Considering the subject matter, however, it would have been nice to have added a bit more depth to the story: Chasing Amy could have been a clever meditation on how rudely America's gay culture is treated by heterosexuals, despite being it a respected culture with a lot of supporters. It also seems that Kevin Smith didn't always pace the film in such an effective manner: some parts are too rushed and for that reason, it kills the natural flow a bit. It wouldn't have hurt to have made the movie a bit longer, considering the fact that it is very unlikely Smith wouldn't be able to forge an extra amount of great, heart-felt and hilarious scenes.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Chasing Amy, a textbook example of a good Rom-com
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    MisureRebellion
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    In Kevin Smith's 3rd film, Chasing Amy concerns Holden McNeil, a comic book artist, with best Banky Edwards beside him every step of the way, the two have become a hit with their comic book series, Bluntman & Chronic, based on the two characters Jay & Silent Bob, from the previous two films, (Clerks. & Mallrats). At a comic convention, Holden meets Alyssa, the girl he's only dreamed of, but he is crushed when he finds out that she is a lesbian. This is a what every Rom-com should be, it shouldn't try following the hot buttons of pop culture, it should be an original idea, with a cast of characters we should actually care about! Kevin Smith knew what we wanted, not something done a thousand times, but it should be something from your life, not something from a movie you saw on TV last night, it should be a story that we can level with as a theater going audience! I honestly can't remember the last time I made a bet that I could make a girl cool in time for the prom! The film is a definite 8.5 ticket stub in my books! The film is on Netflix for instant streaming, it's a definite check it out!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    an unconventional comedy that deals with realistic issues
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    joshjmuir
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Spoilers may appear so do not fear. I thoroughly enjoyed this film and having watched this an adult I have been able to enjoy all the subtle messages that are contained within. I have become so fed up of the traditional Hollywood formula so this was a breath of fresh air. For all the criticism of Ben Affleck as an actor this film seemed to accommodate his style and he pulled of an impressive performance. The complex relationship between his and Joey Lauren Adams character's is thought provoking and asks real questions. Somewhat of a rarity in film nowadays. Credit should be given to the supporting actors as they add to the emotional nuances that the script provided and most importantly portrayed realistic people with actual problems and life struggles. I like Kevin Smith and enjoy his take on film and hope that he continues to ask real questions and most importantly continue making films driven by his own passion. If I were to find any flaw in this premise it will have to be in that Joey Lauren Adams's Character refers to herself as a lesbian but she clearly has had intimate relationships with men, this might attributed to confusion within her own sexuality or that for that period in time she is only dating women but even if that is the case that would still make her bisexual. Perhaps this is just a commentary on how some men view lesbianism as the dialogue in the film does actually address this. Thought Provoking.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An underrated gem by the inventive Kevin Smith
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    JavikKatarn
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    With his debut feature, Clerks, Kevin Smith was granted the credentials to become one of the leading directors of indie cinema. The film about two friends working in a convenience store was a big hit with critics and audiences and became one of the defining films of the 90s. Smith followed it up in 1995 with Mallrats. Mallrats was a financial bomb and was poorly received by critics for its different style and humour to Clerks. Whilst nowhere near the more thoughtful and clever Clerks, Mallrats is a light-hearted and funny comedy with a lot of charm. Despite Mallrats' failure, Smith went on to direct a more sophisticated and heartfelt comedy called Chasing Amy. Chasing Amy was similar to Clerks in that it was a dramatic film with a lot of humour but it was more tonally upbeat and even had some emotional resonance. Chasing Amy is a terrific romantic comedy with a lot of charm and emotion, making it Smith's most potent work as a filmmaker though it lacks some of the influential appeal that Clerks had. Holden McNeil and Banky Edwards are two friends who work as comic book artists with their current series, the superhero duo of Bluntman and Chronic. At a convention, they meet a fellow comic book artist named Alyssa, who writes feminist graphic novels. After one night hanging out with Alyssa, Holden realizes that he is in love with her but his dreams of being with her are tarnished when he discovers that she is a lesbian. Alyssa still wants to be friends with Holden and they spend more time together. But Holden is unable to hide his true feelings for her and in a heartfelt confession, pours his heart out to her. Alyssa is at first hesitant about being involved with Holden but immediately returns his love back to him. Chasing Amy is one of those films that could've ended up being a gross- out comedy considering the source material was out-there for the time. But Smith manages to keep it from being crass and embarrassing. The closest to gross-out humour here is one scene where Alyssa and Banky compare 'battle-scars' from past sexual encounters together in a homage to Jaws. Most of the comedy is more cynical and sardonic but not subtle. There are many moments that are at most guaranteed to raise a bout of laughter like when Star Wars is accused of being white supremacist propaganda or when Banky reacts to Alyssa kissing a woman and then realizing he is in a lesbian bar juxtaposed to Holden's shocked choking up of discovering his fantasy doesn't got for his type. Most importantly though is the relationships between the characters. Holden and Alyssa are one of my favourite romantic couples in film and the chemistry between Ben Affleck and Joey Lauren Adams sells it along with Smith's writing. The two have a clear connection whether merely friendly or romantic. Holden breaking down to Alyssa and confessing his love for her has to go down as one of the best confession scenes in film and the writing along with Affleck's performance sells it. Those who doubt the guy's acting abilities only need to watch his performance here. Adams' voice at first gets a bit grating but she also gives a great performance as Alyssa, making for a perfect romantic foil. Jason Lee has some of the best lines in the film as Banky but his character isn't as developed or strong as the other two. His dismissive attitude toward Alyssa for being a lesbian followed by him being revealed as gay himself feels a bit too tagged on but it doesn't hurt the film and Lee does have some good chemistry with Affleck to support him. Jay and Silent Bob, the duo from Smith's View Askewniverse films, also make an appearance in one scene. Chasing Amy is a solid rom-com with a lot of dramatic heft and emotional resonance to it. Smith's writing is at its peak here and the comedy is just as vulgar and amusing this time around. The efforts of the actors are also worth noting in bringing this film to life, making for a deep connection with the characters and their issues. Smith has made a terrific comedy that is funny, touching and all around deep. If only Jersey Girl could achieve this much.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A review from the year 2013
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    JustStone
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I wouldn't consider myself a huge Kevin Smith fan, but I do enjoy his films. I like Mallrats, Clerks, Jay & Silent Bob Strike Back, in particular because they establish a common thread with Jay & Silent Bob, and they don't take themselves too seriously. Kevin Smith is a master of dirty, lewd, crude and downright offensive dialogue, I get that and for the most part I can appreciate it. When he was first making his films in the 90's, this was a somewhat controversial, as he was paving the way for the "nerd comedy" and doing so with vulgar dialogue, gay jokes, and touchy subject matter. Back in the 90's there really were no films about the comic-con sub culture, and serious gay themed films were rare and far and few between. However its 2013, and the comic book culture has risen to the mainstream. You can't go to a theater these days without seeing a superhero movie in the marquee, gays rights have been more accepted and gay characters are everywhere in the media. Kevin Smith type films are par for the course, and his subject matter is no longer as controversial because so much has changed. I mean you can thank Smith for some of this change, he helped push both comic book films into the mainstream, and in a way, made a film about a lesbian before its was as socially and widely acceptable. So kudos to him. Where am I going with this? Well, as someone who gets Kevin Smith's comedy and dialogue, watching Chasing Amy for the first time in 2013 was really a let down. For some reason out of all the Smith films I've seen, I never got to Chasing Amy, so I was kind of saving it for a rainy day. I knew it is his most critically acclaimed, and coming out right after Mallrats it was his first real dramatic film that wasn't just suppose to be strictly comedic. This films takes its self serious because its about serious subject matter. Maybe I had built it up a bit in my head because of all this, I don't know, but when the rainy day finally came and I sat down to watch it, I wasn't impressed. The first thing I noticed is how much Kevin Smith films don't age well when the subject matter is serious in tone. First because of what I said before, its 2013, these topics are no longer controversial or risqu&eacute; in any way. Making a film about trying to make a lesbian straight, is no longer new or revelatory. The second thing I notice is how much Smith is trying to prove himself as a relevant and hip writer/director in this film. I think this was the film he wanted to be taken seriously for, and for the most part he did get noticed and recognized at the time, but now its just seems kind of like he was trying too hard. The dialogue seems too hip, too self aware, that it kind of takes away from the plot. Every character has to have a snappy comeback or a clever line of dialogue, it kind of gets annoying after the first half an hour. I mean people always praise Smith for how "real" his characters are or how clever his dialogue is, but all I kept thinking was how nobody I know talks like this. Its just seems pretty well, pre-written. Lastly, the plot itself I hate to say was pretty mediocre, and in my opinion not very fleshed out. Like I said, Smith was really trying to prove himself as a writer/director here, and it shows. It almost seems this was Smith's way of learning how to make a proper three act "Hollywood" mainstream film, and because he wasn't a seasoned writer/director at this point, it seems like he was learning as he went along. Joey Lauren Adams as Alyssa is somewhat annoying, and although she has that I-know-I'm-clever smirk and dialogue throughout, I don't really see the attraction. Ben Affleck and Jason Lee as Holden and Banky are fine, but they are just the two typical guy buddies who throw out gay jokes every second that seem to be in every Smith movie. I'm OK with how Holden and Alyssa fall for each other, but by the time we get to third act and we find out about Alyssa's past, and Holden's "final solution" it just falls apart, and to me made very little sense. I think Smith needed more experience as a screen writer at this point, and this was his experiment with a serious and mainstream film. For the most part he succeeded, as it was critically acclaimed at the time, but I think it had more to do with the then touchy subject matter which is now dated, and the way he wrote scripts, which is now just a Kevin Smith film. I like Kevin Smith, but this is a flawed film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Gunga.....
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    DustinRahksi
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Since it's the summer of comedy, and this was on my list and it got an depressing emotion out of me, I thought I'd review it. This definitely feels like Kevin Smiths most heartfelt film, it's not to big on the comedy. The best part of this film is that I was thoroughly interested, I only ever checked the runtime because I wanted it to be a little longer. Do not read if sensitive. Let just sum it up. The characters were believable for the most part, Joey Lauren Adams surprisingly didn't annoyed me, that's a first for her. Banky was the only character I actually cared about, even if he was a bit of an as-hole. Holden was just your average every man. And I'll get to Alyssa in a bit. Jay and silent bob only have one scene, I thought there would be more of them since they are on the cover, but oh well. There was a lot of good scenes, my favorites being the hockey rink scene and Silent Bobs story. Those had more weight to the story. Now comes the biggest thing people love to argue over, Alyssa's past. I've looked up and down the forums here, and people love talking about this. Well, it did bring a lot of drama into the story. Don't get sensitive over this, but yes, Alyssa was a slut, no argument there. Just watch the film and count how many sexual relations she talks about, your a joke if you don't think she isn't. The part about this that hit me the most was, this is very much a real thing, just look at people now-a-days. How would you react if your girlfriend or boyfriend was a whore, it's disgusting to think about. I would have taken Holden's side, even though his proposal in the end was a very dumb thing to do. Of course she truly did love him, but hey, she did some sick things, that no amount of Listerine can wash away. I probably would have just walked away from it. I for one have zero tolerance for loose women, so yeah it's understandable. Then people will cry, she was trying to find that someone, so a threesome is finding that someone, making a dirty film is finding that someone, sleeping around is finding that someone. BS, that's called being a slut, plain and simple, there is no argument. People like this spread diseases, it's not so bad being a virgin. Anyway, the film should have ended after the apartment proposal, because the rest doesn't make it any less depressing. Anyway, I feel like watching this movie again right now.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Engaging indie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Charles Herold (cherold)
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I haven't see that many Kevin Smith movies, and the ones I have seen were a mixed bag, but Chasing Amy is a genuinely entertaining and thoughtful movie. Jason Lee is very good, Affleck is decent, and Adams isn't bad once you get used to her Kewpie-doll voice. It's a movie that tries to think outside the conventions of movies, and while it doesn't entirely succeed, it does offer some surprises. This is also a movie that you will respond to differently depending on where you are in your own life. I saw it twice about ten year apart and liked it both times, but not necessarily for the same reasons. And a friend of mine saw the movie completely differently the second time she saw it. In short, it's funny and sometimes touching and it has something to say.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    This movie will mean different things to different viewers
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tvrose890
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    There is a lot more going on in this movie than meets the eye. But, the parable by Silent Bob pretty much sums it all up for me. The lifestyles, both traditional and alternative, seem to be diversions to the real message. The only absurd scene in the movie is when Holden arranges a meeting with Alyssa and Banky. The scene was totally unnecessary and it seemed like an awkward attempt to get to the final result. It was the only scene that turned me off. Like, who would propose such a thing to a person you supposedly love more than anything? Anyways, Holden blows it much like many of us have blown it when it comes to screwing up our relationships. We think of every reason in the book to why the relationship is wrong when in reality we are not ready to grow a relationship. The parable by Bob sums it all up on why we are chasing Amy. We can spend a lifetime looking for something we've lost.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A little late, but not TOO late, I hope
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Steviereno
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Spoiler alert. "Chasing Amy" is a small movie that does everything it set out to do. It is the kind of small movie all independent movies try to be, but that almost none achieve. It shows little lives, little people, little events in ways and language we all can understand and identify with. Even if we haven't fallen in love with a lesbian or written a successful comic book, we all want to know what it might be like - and the former, would be, for most of us, confusing; the latter would be less glamorous. And no, neither one for any of us would be a subject for an epic film - but would most likely be a film like "Chasing Amy." There are moments of confusion for Holden, as his absorbed ideas about homosexuality are challenged by reality, and his feelings when confronted with open sexuality in an undisguised, un-Hollywood young hotty, in Alyssa. He's lived a cloistered life; that is made abundantly clear by Kevin Smith's excellent reality-based writing and directing. Smith obviously know the world he is portraying. "Chasing Amy" is, in a way, like "Before Sunset" but with a lesbian, and without Paris - the one that got away, and with Holden wondering what in the world he was supposed to do. This is a movie I loved from moment one. I had not seen "Clerks", so it was my introduction to Kevin Smith. I got a thing going for Joey Lauren Adams that is still going on. And Jay and Silent Bob are the funniest two characters I've seen in films in decades. Any of us who doesn't know a Jay has simply not lived in the USA of the late 20th century till now. This is a movie I never miss seeing if the opportunity comes up. The bar booth scene with Banky and Alyssa comparing dating notes is priceless - right up there with Jack Nicholson ordering a sandwich in the diner in "Five Easy Pieces." I'd give "Cahsin Amy" a 10, but, though it achieves everything it sets out to do, it is just that one little bit that Kevin Smith didn't try to do with it that holds me back. Heck, if he had tried for more, he might have messed it up, so I should be glad he didn't. It is pretty much perfect the way it is. I debated between 9 and 10, and my 9.49 has to round down...LOL Great flick!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Chasing Amy  Very emotional and unusual romance with some jokes and a bit of tragedy
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Avid Climber
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Chasing Amy is about the one that got away, and how stupid and hurtful we can be when we're confronted something that test the limit of our knowledge. Romance with a few gags, a tragedy, a movie where you can stop and think. What would you have done? Personally, I think the girl and the black guy are very wise. The two white dudes are pure vanilla stupid. The emotional scenes are touching, and the dialogs are as solid as Kevin Smith can make them. The story is captivating with nice novel ideas, and the maturity of the treatment in the subject matter is beyond reproach. Joey Lauren Adams is little known as actresses go, but she gives us a powerful and very emotional performance. Ben Affleck might not be at his best, but it is still a pretty good performance. While you just want to slap some sense into Jason Lee's character, he plays the uncouth badmouth with little respect like a pro. Looking for a nice romance with an offbeat sentiment and you don't mind if it's not as slick as the high budget flicks Hollywood produces? This is yours. Try it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Bitter-Sweet Romantic Story With A Pulsating Heart
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Nick-leonardi
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Chasing Amy is a 1997 Comedy film directed by Kevin Smith and starring Ben Affleck, Jason Lee, and Joey Lauren Adams. Regarding the movie, opinions among Kevin Smith fans and moviegoers are polarizing to one another: many consider it to be his most entertaining film, others, his least successful. What is certain is that it's the most accessible, mainstream- friendly film of his. Holden (Affleck) and Banky (Lee) are two best friends and comic book artists, sharing the same apartment. At a comic book convention, they meet the lively Alyssa, another comic book artist. Holden falls in love with her almost immediately, while Banky clearly feels opposite feelings. Holden's world however is turned upside down when he finds out she's a lesbian. They do however become best friends, and surprisingly, they start a romantic relationship; but soon some facts concerning Alyssa's past will come to Holden's knowing, and all of the sudden things start getting more complicated, especially due to Alyssa's unstable sexual preference. The romantic side of the film is by no means a traditional one, in neither its warm-up, nor in its consequence. A great and hilarious script makes all of the main characters very likable and funny, including the one of Jason Lee, and especially the brief ones of Jay and Silent Bob, the two reoccurring characters in Kevin Smith's films, Silent Bob being played by Smith himself. Considering the subject matter, however, it would have been nice to have added a bit more depth to the story: Chasing Amy could have been a clever meditation on how rudely America's gay culture is treated by heterosexuals, despite being it a respected culture with a lot of supporters. It also seems that Kevin Smith didn't always pace the film in such an effective manner: some parts are too rushed and for that reason, it kills the natural flow a bit. It wouldn't have hurt to have made the movie a bit longer, considering the fact that it is very unlikely Smith wouldn't be able to forge an extra amount of great, heart-felt and hilarious scenes.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Chasing Amy, a textbook example of a good Rom-com
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    MisureRebellion
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    In Kevin Smith's 3rd film, Chasing Amy concerns Holden McNeil, a comic book artist, with best Banky Edwards beside him every step of the way, the two have become a hit with their comic book series, Bluntman & Chronic, based on the two characters Jay & Silent Bob, from the previous two films, (Clerks. & Mallrats). At a comic convention, Holden meets Alyssa, the girl he's only dreamed of, but he is crushed when he finds out that she is a lesbian. This is a what every Rom-com should be, it shouldn't try following the hot buttons of pop culture, it should be an original idea, with a cast of characters we should actually care about! Kevin Smith knew what we wanted, not something done a thousand times, but it should be something from your life, not something from a movie you saw on TV last night, it should be a story that we can level with as a theater going audience! I honestly can't remember the last time I made a bet that I could make a girl cool in time for the prom! The film is a definite 8.5 ticket stub in my books! The film is on Netflix for instant streaming, it's a definite check it out!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
 </reviews>
</filme>
