<filme>
 <id>
  248
 </id>
 <imdburl>
  http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0119229
 </imdburl>
 <ano>
  1997
 </ano>
 <titulo>
  Matador em Conflito
 </titulo>
 <rating>
  7.3
 </rating>
 <sinopse>
  Martin Blank is a professional assassin. He is sent on a mission to a small Detroit suburb, Grosse Pointe, and, by coincidence, his ten-year high school reunion party is taking place there at the same time.
 </sinopse>
 <storyline>
  Martin Blank is a freelance hitman who starts to develop a conscience, which causes him to muff a couple of routine assignments. On the advice of his secretary and his psychiatrist, he attends his 10th year High School reunion in Grosse Pointe, Michigan (a Detroit suburb where he's also contracted to kill someone). Hot on his tail are a couple of over-enthusiastic federal agents, another assassin who wants to kill him, and Grocer, an assassin who wants him to join an "Assassin's Union."
 </storyline>
 <generos>
  <genero>
   Action
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Comedy
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Crime
  </genero>
 </generos>
 <keywords>
  <keyword>
   assassin
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   reunion
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   high school
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   high school reunion
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   suburb
  </keyword>
 </keywords>
 <diretores>
  <diretor>
   George Armitage
  </diretor>
 </diretores>
 <escritores>
  <escritor>
   Tom Jankiewicz
  </escritor>
  <escritor>
   D.V. DeVincentis
  </escritor>
 </escritores>
 <atores>
  <ator>
   John Cusack
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Minnie Driver
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Dan Aykroyd
  </ator>
 </atores>
 <reviews>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Dialog Funnier Than Plot
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    leonlouisricci
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This Black Comedy has its moments. There are a number of Funny Lines but the Comedic Situations don't fare as well. For example, the totally banal Radio Station Scene, the Real Estate Piece just lies there without Wit and there are others, especially the whole Romantic Subplot with Near Zero Chemistry. The Action and the Violence are much better. These are done with an intensity and Style befitting the Movie's Conceit, especially the Finale and the short but incredible Hand to Hand confrontation in the Halls of the High School that is High Style. The Movie works most of the time but when it doesn't the thing screams to a halt and exposes itself as ill fitted and overplayed. Like the Convenience Store Set-Piece or the Mother and Child Reunion. Overall this is Overrated but still a better than Average work that is well done if you can accept some pretty Bad Acting from Sister Cusack and Minnie Driver. Both do some unwatchable Overreaching. But the rest of the Cast is Fine and some of the Writing is Clever and Cool, but beware that in spots this shows some pretty glaring Missteps. The Movie initially Flopped but has gained some Cult recognition for its irreverent Subject Matter and attempts at Ultra-Hipness. One final Blow, the Clash was an Important Group, but here the Joe Strummer Music is way overdone and the whole Soundtrack is surprisingly Anemic considering that it is in your Face (Ears) so intrusively. The White-Bread Reggae is embarrassing, thankfully it includes Johnny Nash's Seminal Chart-Topper for some redemption.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Funny, cool '90s movie with a fantastic fight scene
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Mike Bloxham
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A sharp and witty romantic comedy with some really excellent dialogue. I'm not normally a big fan of Cusack but he is perfect in the role of Martin Blank. Minnie Driver looks beautiful and does a great job. Some uneven parts, the ending isn't amazing. My favourite part was the fight at the reunion dance, it's just brilliantly executed, one of the most exciting fights I've seen committed to film. Maybe it's because you actually see John Cusack throwing high kicks and not some stuntman filmed from behind, there is a very authentic feel to it. Martin Blank is wandering through the corridors of his high school, he's just shared a kiss with Driver, he comes across his old locker, jimmies it open and finds a ten year old spliff he stashed there. He smiles and crumbles the flaky joint, dreamy with nostalgia and the possibilities of life, happier than he's been in years. A hit-man steps around the corner, Blank's reaction is instantaneous, instinctive, he gets in the first blow before the enemy has even raised his gun and in the blink of an eye the two killers are fighting to the death. It's just an outstanding scene.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Thriller With Something For Everyone
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    seymourblack-1
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    With its offbeat combination of comedy, romance and action, "Grosse Pointe Blank" is a highly entertaining thriller that has something for everyone. Its plot is unpredictable, its characters are wonderfully eccentric and its dialogue is sharp and witty. It's also full of terrific performances and boasts a nostalgic 1980s soundtrack that provides an enjoyable accompaniment to all the craziness that takes place on-screen. Martin Q Blank (John Cusack) is a very successful hit-man who's going through an existential crisis and to make matters worse, his most recent assignment didn't go according to plan. On the advice of his therapist and his secretary, he's persuaded to attend his 10-year high school reunion in the town of Grosse Pointe, Michigan so that he can reconnect with his past, in the hope that doing so, might help to improve his current state of mind. Conveniently, he also has a professional reason for returning to his home town as he has another contract to fulfil for the same client he so recently disappointed. The first person that Martin looks up in Grosse Pointe is his high school sweetheart Debi (Minnie Driver) who's now a DJ on the local radio station. Martin had disappeared out of her life without explanation on the night when they'd arranged to go to the school prom together, but by his own admission, she'd remained in his thoughts and dreams ever since. He openly admits that he's now a professional hit-man but she naturally takes this remark as a joke. Some factors linked to his current line of work make Martin's visit to Grosse Pointe a little more complicated and dangerous than Debi could possibly imagine as, not only is he being followed by two operatives from the National Security Agency, but also a couple of independent hit-men called Grocer (Dan Aykroyd) and Felix LePoubelle (Benny Urquidez) are on his tail and looking for trouble. Martin and Debi go to the high school reunion and meet a number of their old classmates, but when Martin wanders away from the main hall into a quiet corridor, LePoubelle attacks him and Martin, without hesitation, kills his assailant. Debi soon arrives on the scene and then, in a state of shock and panic, runs away. Another of Martin's old classmates Paul Spericki (Jeremy Piven) arrives shortly after and helps Martin to dispose of the body in the school furnace. Further difficulties follow for Martin in his dealings with Debi and Grocer and even his professional assignment proves to be far from straightforward. A great deal of danger and numerous surprises then also have to be confronted as Martin tries again to reconcile with Debi and attempts to get out of Grosse Pointe alive. John Cusack is very likable and funny as a guy whose career started in the Army and then took a number of unexpected twists that eventually brought him to a point in his life where he began to feel lost and unfulfilled. His talent for comedy is really impressive and he's also faultless in the action sequences. Alan Arkin is fantastic as Martin's terrified shrink and Joan Cusack is marvellous as his very intense secretary. Dan Aykroyd excels as Martin's greatest professional rival and Minnie Driver is effective in showing the chemistry that still exists between her and Martin as well as the bitterness she continues to feel about the way he abandoned her a decade before. "Grosse Pointe Blank" is a real one-off with numerous laugh-out-loud moments and is also highly recommended.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Hits the target but misses the bull's eye - 73%
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Benjamin Cox
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This has been on my radar since it was released and at last, I can cross it off. I like John Cusack as an actor (though I'll forget about "2012" for the purposes of this argument!) and this had all the feel of a smart-aleck comic thriller that normally appeals to me. And it does but something's missing. It has witty dialogue, genuine laughs, an amazing soundtrack and surprisingly decent action but by being a jack-of-all-trades, it ends up a master of none. However, this is still worth your attention simply by being a little different from the usual Hollywood film about hit men. Cusack plays Martin Blank, an experienced professional killer who finds himself beginning to question his career choice. After turning down an offer to join an assassin's union led by his rival Grocer (Dan Aykroyd), Blank is contacted by his broker (Joan Cusack) with an odd proposition - his ten year high school reunion is taking place in Grosse Pointe, Michigan at the same time as a job is required in Detroit. Reluctantly, Martin agrees while thinking he can make amends with Debi (Minnie Driver), the girl he stood up at the prom ten years ago. But Blank has other concerns - he is pursued to Grosse Pointe by a couple of feds (Hank Azaria and K. Todd Freeman), another hit-man wanting to collect the price on Blank's head (Benny Urquidez) and Grocer who doesn't take too kindly to rejection... If you're not sure what to make of "Grosse Pointe Blank" then you're not alone - the film veers wildly from energetic action thriller to romantic comedy which, if I'm honest, slowed the film down something chronic. Cusack and Driver are a good couple though, with real chemistry between them that sparkles on screen. But as Blank's two worlds begin to collide, things seriously begin to unravel in the film. Take the moment when Blank is forced to rely on his school buddy Paul (Jeremy Piven) to dispose of a body - at no point does Paul react with horror the way I suspect I might, nor does he question the scenario at all. It's a shame because there is much to like - Aykroyd is brilliantly psychotic as Grocer while the film's blistering soundtrack (by Joe Strummer of The Clash, of all people) is a real winner as well. There are also lots of references to other movies from "You Only Live Twice" to "The Warriors" which help the movie barrel along. "Grosse Pointe Blank" is a good film but I wanted something more. It isn't as original as it thinks it is and its split personality prevents the film from being a great action film. The romantic subplot works as well as the action scenes which are full of noise, fire and debris flying about the place. I also felt Alan Arkin was underused as Blank's long-suffering therapist and that more could have been made of the premise. A hit-man suffering a crisis of confidence has been covered before in many movies but I doubt that a high school reunion dance featured in any of them. I can just about recommend "Grosse Pointe Blank" simply by being a little different from other hit-man-related films out there. At least it's not anything as adrenaline-fuelled as "Hitman" or "Assassins" - both of which were disappointingly one-dimensional action outings - but it has a depth to it that I can appreciate. I just wished that it was a bit braver in the script and that it was as clever as it thinks it is.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Relaxing fun
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    hedin_88
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Rarely does a movie entertain, make you laugh, keep you hooked with lovable characters and on top if it all, it relaxes. I've watched it a long time ago and it stuck with me, somewhere in the back of my head and i decided to give it another view just now. This movie is simple so you're gonna love it after a hard day just to ease your mind and relax. The characters are simple people who have their past and present explored and who find themselves in the process. Its not about issues and unresolved problems, drama and pain. There is no place for that in this kind of filming. Its up there with Mumford, another movie i liked which shares the traits- a movie made to ease your mind and feel good after watching it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    It just gets better with each viewing
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ryansassy1
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    When I first saw GPB in the '90s I was impressed enough to buy the soundtrack. Now, after having watched it about a ten times in as many years on cable, I realized how stupid it was not to have bought the DVD already. The upside to that is that now there's blu-ray and hopefully, a few extras included..? Well it will be a real sin if that turns out not to be the case! Sorry, I can't help myself. This film is fantastic, in my Top 5 list of '90s films for certain. John Cusack reportedly co-wrote the script, and that makes sense because it's clever and built on witty dialog -- playing perfectly to his strengths. His electrifying chemistry with Minnie Driver, Dan Ackroyd and what the heck, the entire supporting cast, demonstrates pure casting genius and ensures GPB will remain fresh and memorable upon many repeat viewings. The plot reads like an understated Quentin Tarrantino joint. Martin Blank is a professional assassin who is invited to his 10 year High School reunion in Grosse Pointe, MI. Urged by his therapist on the premise that it might be good for him, he decides to attend. Martin contacts old buddies, attempts to reconnect with his long-lost love, reminisces a bit about his childhood, visits his ailing mom in her nursing home, and what the heck--decides to complete an "assignment" while he's there. He runs into a few glitches on his journey of the soul, but exploding convenience stores and murderous rival assassins can't deflect Martin' growing moral conscience and his determination to win back the girl he stood up on Prom night. Grosse Pointe Blank is hard to pin down. This is a black comedy, but strangely uplifting at the same time. It has plenty of shooting action, martial arts and a dash of James Bond coolness, but it's not about that, really; it asks deeper philosophical questions of the sanctity of life and the power of love and forgiveness. And of course at the heart of it all, there's the relatable conundrum of those torturous High School Reunions. GPB is John Cusack, Minnie Driver, Dan Ackroyd and Joan Cusack at the top of their forms. It also features some of the best tracks from the musical talent of the '80s. If you are a fan of any of theirs, it is a must-see.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    All hail the 0.9%
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    cmoyton
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/9/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    .....who voted this sacred cow a score of one. Ugggggh. Words almost fail me. I'm sick too of all the word play and puns around the film title. How it is so funny and quirky. A perfect light blend of action, comedy and romance. Wrong. This is exactly the type of movie that upper storey hotel rooms were made for so that you can throw the TV out the window. Normally i like Cusack. He is a fine, versatile actor who has done his fair share of comedy and romance. Alas he lapses into the aura of smugness and self congratulation that oozes throughout the length of the film. Stupid can be good like Dumb and Dumber. Even Burn After Reading which was a second rate Coen brothers effort. But when stupid is just stupid, it's stupid.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Good Movie With A Different Storyline,
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Dillon Harris
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Grosse Pointe Blank is a good movie with a good,albeit different,storyline,a good cast and some good twists to it too.I've never been a huge fan of John Cusack,but I did appreciate his role as Martin Q. Blank in this.I really enjoyed Dan Aykroyds role as Grocer and Hank Azaria as Steven Lardner,because I've always been a big fan of the two of them,Dan Aykroyd for great comedy films he wrote and starred in such as Ghostbusters and The Blues Brothers,and Hank Azaria because of his many voice roles on The Simpsons.They could have gotten a much more attractive female lead for this movie,no offense on her,but Minnie Driver is not good looking,someone like Cameron Diaz would have been much better for the role of Debi Newberry. An assassin is sent on a mission to a place called Grosse Pointe,and by an amazing coincidence,it is where his ten year high school reunion is taking place at the same time.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Mirror in the bathroom.....
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    FlashCallahan
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/3/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Martin Blank is a freelance hit-man who starts to develop a conscience, which causes him to fluff a couple of routine assignments. On the advice of his secretary and his psychiatrist, he attends his 10th year High School reunion in Grosse Pointe, Michigan (a Detroit suburb where he's also contracted to kill someone). Hot on his tail are a couple of over-enthusiastic federal agents, another assassin who wants to kill him, and Grocer, an assassin who wants him to join an Assassin's Union....... If you thought that the wedding singer was a little too sweet for your liking, then this is the perfect antidote to that other Eighties movie of 1997. And while that movie is very good in it's own respect, this is dark, deluded, funny, and most of all, a very touching tale about finding yourself and facing your demons. It's not laugh out loud funny, it can be very deep in scenes, but it takes the rough with the smooth, and for every dark moment, there soon is a piece of music,or line that makes the film a perfect example of cinema today. Cusack is at his finest here, taking every single character he played in the eighties, and making them Martin Blank, a man who appears to be stuck in purgatory, and only the voice on the radio can save him. The script is cracking, the action enough to satisfy any action fan, and the romance for the ladies. All in all, it's the perfect date movie, with endless references to eighties movie (Better Off Dead, and Ghostbusters for example) and one of the best soundtracks for a film ever. Do not miss this movie, especially if you have fond memories of the decade that fashion forgot.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Deep, Rough and Charmingly Hilarious
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Sean Lamberger
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Much funnier than I'd remembered, this twisting tale of competing hit men and their uncharacteristically jovial attempts to rid the world of one other also finds the time to address the loss of innocence, the reflections of a milestone high school reunion and the baggage of leading a necessarily isolated lifestyle. John Cusack is fantastic as the acidic, sarcastic prodigal son, returning to his home town on business while also giving serious thought to abandoning his violent ways for good. Great supporting work helps that role to flower even further, especially in the forms of his grinning, kill-happy competition, (a joyously nasty dark turn by Dan Aykroyd) the jilted love interest he left high and dry ten years back (Minnie Driver at her most smokin') and his flippant, hard-nosed assistant (Joan Cusack). One of the greatest soundtracks ever, plus work on the original score by former Clash frontman Joe Strummer, takes this whole package over the top. Strongly recommended.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Dialog Funnier Than Plot
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    leonlouisricci
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This Black Comedy has its moments. There are a number of Funny Lines but the Comedic Situations don't fare as well. For example, the totally banal Radio Station Scene, the Real Estate Piece just lies there without Wit and there are others, especially the whole Romantic Subplot with Near Zero Chemistry. The Action and the Violence are much better. These are done with an intensity and Style befitting the Movie's Conceit, especially the Finale and the short but incredible Hand to Hand confrontation in the Halls of the High School that is High Style. The Movie works most of the time but when it doesn't the thing screams to a halt and exposes itself as ill fitted and overplayed. Like the Convenience Store Set-Piece or the Mother and Child Reunion. Overall this is Overrated but still a better than Average work that is well done if you can accept some pretty Bad Acting from Sister Cusack and Minnie Driver. Both do some unwatchable Overreaching. But the rest of the Cast is Fine and some of the Writing is Clever and Cool, but beware that in spots this shows some pretty glaring Missteps. The Movie initially Flopped but has gained some Cult recognition for its irreverent Subject Matter and attempts at Ultra-Hipness. One final Blow, the Clash was an Important Group, but here the Joe Strummer Music is way overdone and the whole Soundtrack is surprisingly Anemic considering that it is in your Face (Ears) so intrusively. The White-Bread Reggae is embarrassing, thankfully it includes Johnny Nash's Seminal Chart-Topper for some redemption.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Funny, cool '90s movie with a fantastic fight scene
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Mike Bloxham
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A sharp and witty romantic comedy with some really excellent dialogue. I'm not normally a big fan of Cusack but he is perfect in the role of Martin Blank. Minnie Driver looks beautiful and does a great job. Some uneven parts, the ending isn't amazing. My favourite part was the fight at the reunion dance, it's just brilliantly executed, one of the most exciting fights I've seen committed to film. Maybe it's because you actually see John Cusack throwing high kicks and not some stuntman filmed from behind, there is a very authentic feel to it. Martin Blank is wandering through the corridors of his high school, he's just shared a kiss with Driver, he comes across his old locker, jimmies it open and finds a ten year old spliff he stashed there. He smiles and crumbles the flaky joint, dreamy with nostalgia and the possibilities of life, happier than he's been in years. A hit-man steps around the corner, Blank's reaction is instantaneous, instinctive, he gets in the first blow before the enemy has even raised his gun and in the blink of an eye the two killers are fighting to the death. It's just an outstanding scene.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Thriller With Something For Everyone
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    seymourblack-1
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    With its offbeat combination of comedy, romance and action, "Grosse Pointe Blank" is a highly entertaining thriller that has something for everyone. Its plot is unpredictable, its characters are wonderfully eccentric and its dialogue is sharp and witty. It's also full of terrific performances and boasts a nostalgic 1980s soundtrack that provides an enjoyable accompaniment to all the craziness that takes place on-screen. Martin Q Blank (John Cusack) is a very successful hit-man who's going through an existential crisis and to make matters worse, his most recent assignment didn't go according to plan. On the advice of his therapist and his secretary, he's persuaded to attend his 10-year high school reunion in the town of Grosse Pointe, Michigan so that he can reconnect with his past, in the hope that doing so, might help to improve his current state of mind. Conveniently, he also has a professional reason for returning to his home town as he has another contract to fulfil for the same client he so recently disappointed. The first person that Martin looks up in Grosse Pointe is his high school sweetheart Debi (Minnie Driver) who's now a DJ on the local radio station. Martin had disappeared out of her life without explanation on the night when they'd arranged to go to the school prom together, but by his own admission, she'd remained in his thoughts and dreams ever since. He openly admits that he's now a professional hit-man but she naturally takes this remark as a joke. Some factors linked to his current line of work make Martin's visit to Grosse Pointe a little more complicated and dangerous than Debi could possibly imagine as, not only is he being followed by two operatives from the National Security Agency, but also a couple of independent hit-men called Grocer (Dan Aykroyd) and Felix LePoubelle (Benny Urquidez) are on his tail and looking for trouble. Martin and Debi go to the high school reunion and meet a number of their old classmates, but when Martin wanders away from the main hall into a quiet corridor, LePoubelle attacks him and Martin, without hesitation, kills his assailant. Debi soon arrives on the scene and then, in a state of shock and panic, runs away. Another of Martin's old classmates Paul Spericki (Jeremy Piven) arrives shortly after and helps Martin to dispose of the body in the school furnace. Further difficulties follow for Martin in his dealings with Debi and Grocer and even his professional assignment proves to be far from straightforward. A great deal of danger and numerous surprises then also have to be confronted as Martin tries again to reconcile with Debi and attempts to get out of Grosse Pointe alive. John Cusack is very likable and funny as a guy whose career started in the Army and then took a number of unexpected twists that eventually brought him to a point in his life where he began to feel lost and unfulfilled. His talent for comedy is really impressive and he's also faultless in the action sequences. Alan Arkin is fantastic as Martin's terrified shrink and Joan Cusack is marvellous as his very intense secretary. Dan Aykroyd excels as Martin's greatest professional rival and Minnie Driver is effective in showing the chemistry that still exists between her and Martin as well as the bitterness she continues to feel about the way he abandoned her a decade before. "Grosse Pointe Blank" is a real one-off with numerous laugh-out-loud moments and is also highly recommended.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Hits the target but misses the bull's eye - 73%
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Benjamin Cox
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This has been on my radar since it was released and at last, I can cross it off. I like John Cusack as an actor (though I'll forget about "2012" for the purposes of this argument!) and this had all the feel of a smart-aleck comic thriller that normally appeals to me. And it does but something's missing. It has witty dialogue, genuine laughs, an amazing soundtrack and surprisingly decent action but by being a jack-of-all-trades, it ends up a master of none. However, this is still worth your attention simply by being a little different from the usual Hollywood film about hit men. Cusack plays Martin Blank, an experienced professional killer who finds himself beginning to question his career choice. After turning down an offer to join an assassin's union led by his rival Grocer (Dan Aykroyd), Blank is contacted by his broker (Joan Cusack) with an odd proposition - his ten year high school reunion is taking place in Grosse Pointe, Michigan at the same time as a job is required in Detroit. Reluctantly, Martin agrees while thinking he can make amends with Debi (Minnie Driver), the girl he stood up at the prom ten years ago. But Blank has other concerns - he is pursued to Grosse Pointe by a couple of feds (Hank Azaria and K. Todd Freeman), another hit-man wanting to collect the price on Blank's head (Benny Urquidez) and Grocer who doesn't take too kindly to rejection... If you're not sure what to make of "Grosse Pointe Blank" then you're not alone - the film veers wildly from energetic action thriller to romantic comedy which, if I'm honest, slowed the film down something chronic. Cusack and Driver are a good couple though, with real chemistry between them that sparkles on screen. But as Blank's two worlds begin to collide, things seriously begin to unravel in the film. Take the moment when Blank is forced to rely on his school buddy Paul (Jeremy Piven) to dispose of a body - at no point does Paul react with horror the way I suspect I might, nor does he question the scenario at all. It's a shame because there is much to like - Aykroyd is brilliantly psychotic as Grocer while the film's blistering soundtrack (by Joe Strummer of The Clash, of all people) is a real winner as well. There are also lots of references to other movies from "You Only Live Twice" to "The Warriors" which help the movie barrel along. "Grosse Pointe Blank" is a good film but I wanted something more. It isn't as original as it thinks it is and its split personality prevents the film from being a great action film. The romantic subplot works as well as the action scenes which are full of noise, fire and debris flying about the place. I also felt Alan Arkin was underused as Blank's long-suffering therapist and that more could have been made of the premise. A hit-man suffering a crisis of confidence has been covered before in many movies but I doubt that a high school reunion dance featured in any of them. I can just about recommend "Grosse Pointe Blank" simply by being a little different from other hit-man-related films out there. At least it's not anything as adrenaline-fuelled as "Hitman" or "Assassins" - both of which were disappointingly one-dimensional action outings - but it has a depth to it that I can appreciate. I just wished that it was a bit braver in the script and that it was as clever as it thinks it is.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Relaxing fun
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    hedin_88
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Rarely does a movie entertain, make you laugh, keep you hooked with lovable characters and on top if it all, it relaxes. I've watched it a long time ago and it stuck with me, somewhere in the back of my head and i decided to give it another view just now. This movie is simple so you're gonna love it after a hard day just to ease your mind and relax. The characters are simple people who have their past and present explored and who find themselves in the process. Its not about issues and unresolved problems, drama and pain. There is no place for that in this kind of filming. Its up there with Mumford, another movie i liked which shares the traits- a movie made to ease your mind and feel good after watching it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    It just gets better with each viewing
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ryansassy1
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    When I first saw GPB in the '90s I was impressed enough to buy the soundtrack. Now, after having watched it about a ten times in as many years on cable, I realized how stupid it was not to have bought the DVD already. The upside to that is that now there's blu-ray and hopefully, a few extras included..? Well it will be a real sin if that turns out not to be the case! Sorry, I can't help myself. This film is fantastic, in my Top 5 list of '90s films for certain. John Cusack reportedly co-wrote the script, and that makes sense because it's clever and built on witty dialog -- playing perfectly to his strengths. His electrifying chemistry with Minnie Driver, Dan Ackroyd and what the heck, the entire supporting cast, demonstrates pure casting genius and ensures GPB will remain fresh and memorable upon many repeat viewings. The plot reads like an understated Quentin Tarrantino joint. Martin Blank is a professional assassin who is invited to his 10 year High School reunion in Grosse Pointe, MI. Urged by his therapist on the premise that it might be good for him, he decides to attend. Martin contacts old buddies, attempts to reconnect with his long-lost love, reminisces a bit about his childhood, visits his ailing mom in her nursing home, and what the heck--decides to complete an "assignment" while he's there. He runs into a few glitches on his journey of the soul, but exploding convenience stores and murderous rival assassins can't deflect Martin' growing moral conscience and his determination to win back the girl he stood up on Prom night. Grosse Pointe Blank is hard to pin down. This is a black comedy, but strangely uplifting at the same time. It has plenty of shooting action, martial arts and a dash of James Bond coolness, but it's not about that, really; it asks deeper philosophical questions of the sanctity of life and the power of love and forgiveness. And of course at the heart of it all, there's the relatable conundrum of those torturous High School Reunions. GPB is John Cusack, Minnie Driver, Dan Ackroyd and Joan Cusack at the top of their forms. It also features some of the best tracks from the musical talent of the '80s. If you are a fan of any of theirs, it is a must-see.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    All hail the 0.9%
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    cmoyton
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/9/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    .....who voted this sacred cow a score of one. Ugggggh. Words almost fail me. I'm sick too of all the word play and puns around the film title. How it is so funny and quirky. A perfect light blend of action, comedy and romance. Wrong. This is exactly the type of movie that upper storey hotel rooms were made for so that you can throw the TV out the window. Normally i like Cusack. He is a fine, versatile actor who has done his fair share of comedy and romance. Alas he lapses into the aura of smugness and self congratulation that oozes throughout the length of the film. Stupid can be good like Dumb and Dumber. Even Burn After Reading which was a second rate Coen brothers effort. But when stupid is just stupid, it's stupid.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Good Movie With A Different Storyline,
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Dillon Harris
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Grosse Pointe Blank is a good movie with a good,albeit different,storyline,a good cast and some good twists to it too.I've never been a huge fan of John Cusack,but I did appreciate his role as Martin Q. Blank in this.I really enjoyed Dan Aykroyds role as Grocer and Hank Azaria as Steven Lardner,because I've always been a big fan of the two of them,Dan Aykroyd for great comedy films he wrote and starred in such as Ghostbusters and The Blues Brothers,and Hank Azaria because of his many voice roles on The Simpsons.They could have gotten a much more attractive female lead for this movie,no offense on her,but Minnie Driver is not good looking,someone like Cameron Diaz would have been much better for the role of Debi Newberry. An assassin is sent on a mission to a place called Grosse Pointe,and by an amazing coincidence,it is where his ten year high school reunion is taking place at the same time.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Mirror in the bathroom.....
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    FlashCallahan
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/3/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Martin Blank is a freelance hit-man who starts to develop a conscience, which causes him to fluff a couple of routine assignments. On the advice of his secretary and his psychiatrist, he attends his 10th year High School reunion in Grosse Pointe, Michigan (a Detroit suburb where he's also contracted to kill someone). Hot on his tail are a couple of over-enthusiastic federal agents, another assassin who wants to kill him, and Grocer, an assassin who wants him to join an Assassin's Union....... If you thought that the wedding singer was a little too sweet for your liking, then this is the perfect antidote to that other Eighties movie of 1997. And while that movie is very good in it's own respect, this is dark, deluded, funny, and most of all, a very touching tale about finding yourself and facing your demons. It's not laugh out loud funny, it can be very deep in scenes, but it takes the rough with the smooth, and for every dark moment, there soon is a piece of music,or line that makes the film a perfect example of cinema today. Cusack is at his finest here, taking every single character he played in the eighties, and making them Martin Blank, a man who appears to be stuck in purgatory, and only the voice on the radio can save him. The script is cracking, the action enough to satisfy any action fan, and the romance for the ladies. All in all, it's the perfect date movie, with endless references to eighties movie (Better Off Dead, and Ghostbusters for example) and one of the best soundtracks for a film ever. Do not miss this movie, especially if you have fond memories of the decade that fashion forgot.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Deep, Rough and Charmingly Hilarious
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Sean Lamberger
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Much funnier than I'd remembered, this twisting tale of competing hit men and their uncharacteristically jovial attempts to rid the world of one other also finds the time to address the loss of innocence, the reflections of a milestone high school reunion and the baggage of leading a necessarily isolated lifestyle. John Cusack is fantastic as the acidic, sarcastic prodigal son, returning to his home town on business while also giving serious thought to abandoning his violent ways for good. Great supporting work helps that role to flower even further, especially in the forms of his grinning, kill-happy competition, (a joyously nasty dark turn by Dan Aykroyd) the jilted love interest he left high and dry ten years back (Minnie Driver at her most smokin') and his flippant, hard-nosed assistant (Joan Cusack). One of the greatest soundtracks ever, plus work on the original score by former Clash frontman Joe Strummer, takes this whole package over the top. Strongly recommended.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Dialog Funnier Than Plot
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    leonlouisricci
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This Black Comedy has its moments. There are a number of Funny Lines but the Comedic Situations don't fare as well. For example, the totally banal Radio Station Scene, the Real Estate Piece just lies there without Wit and there are others, especially the whole Romantic Subplot with Near Zero Chemistry. The Action and the Violence are much better. These are done with an intensity and Style befitting the Movie's Conceit, especially the Finale and the short but incredible Hand to Hand confrontation in the Halls of the High School that is High Style. The Movie works most of the time but when it doesn't the thing screams to a halt and exposes itself as ill fitted and overplayed. Like the Convenience Store Set-Piece or the Mother and Child Reunion. Overall this is Overrated but still a better than Average work that is well done if you can accept some pretty Bad Acting from Sister Cusack and Minnie Driver. Both do some unwatchable Overreaching. But the rest of the Cast is Fine and some of the Writing is Clever and Cool, but beware that in spots this shows some pretty glaring Missteps. The Movie initially Flopped but has gained some Cult recognition for its irreverent Subject Matter and attempts at Ultra-Hipness. One final Blow, the Clash was an Important Group, but here the Joe Strummer Music is way overdone and the whole Soundtrack is surprisingly Anemic considering that it is in your Face (Ears) so intrusively. The White-Bread Reggae is embarrassing, thankfully it includes Johnny Nash's Seminal Chart-Topper for some redemption.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Funny, cool '90s movie with a fantastic fight scene
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Mike Bloxham
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A sharp and witty romantic comedy with some really excellent dialogue. I'm not normally a big fan of Cusack but he is perfect in the role of Martin Blank. Minnie Driver looks beautiful and does a great job. Some uneven parts, the ending isn't amazing. My favourite part was the fight at the reunion dance, it's just brilliantly executed, one of the most exciting fights I've seen committed to film. Maybe it's because you actually see John Cusack throwing high kicks and not some stuntman filmed from behind, there is a very authentic feel to it. Martin Blank is wandering through the corridors of his high school, he's just shared a kiss with Driver, he comes across his old locker, jimmies it open and finds a ten year old spliff he stashed there. He smiles and crumbles the flaky joint, dreamy with nostalgia and the possibilities of life, happier than he's been in years. A hit-man steps around the corner, Blank's reaction is instantaneous, instinctive, he gets in the first blow before the enemy has even raised his gun and in the blink of an eye the two killers are fighting to the death. It's just an outstanding scene.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Thriller With Something For Everyone
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    seymourblack-1
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    With its offbeat combination of comedy, romance and action, "Grosse Pointe Blank" is a highly entertaining thriller that has something for everyone. Its plot is unpredictable, its characters are wonderfully eccentric and its dialogue is sharp and witty. It's also full of terrific performances and boasts a nostalgic 1980s soundtrack that provides an enjoyable accompaniment to all the craziness that takes place on-screen. Martin Q Blank (John Cusack) is a very successful hit-man who's going through an existential crisis and to make matters worse, his most recent assignment didn't go according to plan. On the advice of his therapist and his secretary, he's persuaded to attend his 10-year high school reunion in the town of Grosse Pointe, Michigan so that he can reconnect with his past, in the hope that doing so, might help to improve his current state of mind. Conveniently, he also has a professional reason for returning to his home town as he has another contract to fulfil for the same client he so recently disappointed. The first person that Martin looks up in Grosse Pointe is his high school sweetheart Debi (Minnie Driver) who's now a DJ on the local radio station. Martin had disappeared out of her life without explanation on the night when they'd arranged to go to the school prom together, but by his own admission, she'd remained in his thoughts and dreams ever since. He openly admits that he's now a professional hit-man but she naturally takes this remark as a joke. Some factors linked to his current line of work make Martin's visit to Grosse Pointe a little more complicated and dangerous than Debi could possibly imagine as, not only is he being followed by two operatives from the National Security Agency, but also a couple of independent hit-men called Grocer (Dan Aykroyd) and Felix LePoubelle (Benny Urquidez) are on his tail and looking for trouble. Martin and Debi go to the high school reunion and meet a number of their old classmates, but when Martin wanders away from the main hall into a quiet corridor, LePoubelle attacks him and Martin, without hesitation, kills his assailant. Debi soon arrives on the scene and then, in a state of shock and panic, runs away. Another of Martin's old classmates Paul Spericki (Jeremy Piven) arrives shortly after and helps Martin to dispose of the body in the school furnace. Further difficulties follow for Martin in his dealings with Debi and Grocer and even his professional assignment proves to be far from straightforward. A great deal of danger and numerous surprises then also have to be confronted as Martin tries again to reconcile with Debi and attempts to get out of Grosse Pointe alive. John Cusack is very likable and funny as a guy whose career started in the Army and then took a number of unexpected twists that eventually brought him to a point in his life where he began to feel lost and unfulfilled. His talent for comedy is really impressive and he's also faultless in the action sequences. Alan Arkin is fantastic as Martin's terrified shrink and Joan Cusack is marvellous as his very intense secretary. Dan Aykroyd excels as Martin's greatest professional rival and Minnie Driver is effective in showing the chemistry that still exists between her and Martin as well as the bitterness she continues to feel about the way he abandoned her a decade before. "Grosse Pointe Blank" is a real one-off with numerous laugh-out-loud moments and is also highly recommended.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Hits the target but misses the bull's eye - 73%
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Benjamin Cox
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This has been on my radar since it was released and at last, I can cross it off. I like John Cusack as an actor (though I'll forget about "2012" for the purposes of this argument!) and this had all the feel of a smart-aleck comic thriller that normally appeals to me. And it does but something's missing. It has witty dialogue, genuine laughs, an amazing soundtrack and surprisingly decent action but by being a jack-of-all-trades, it ends up a master of none. However, this is still worth your attention simply by being a little different from the usual Hollywood film about hit men. Cusack plays Martin Blank, an experienced professional killer who finds himself beginning to question his career choice. After turning down an offer to join an assassin's union led by his rival Grocer (Dan Aykroyd), Blank is contacted by his broker (Joan Cusack) with an odd proposition - his ten year high school reunion is taking place in Grosse Pointe, Michigan at the same time as a job is required in Detroit. Reluctantly, Martin agrees while thinking he can make amends with Debi (Minnie Driver), the girl he stood up at the prom ten years ago. But Blank has other concerns - he is pursued to Grosse Pointe by a couple of feds (Hank Azaria and K. Todd Freeman), another hit-man wanting to collect the price on Blank's head (Benny Urquidez) and Grocer who doesn't take too kindly to rejection... If you're not sure what to make of "Grosse Pointe Blank" then you're not alone - the film veers wildly from energetic action thriller to romantic comedy which, if I'm honest, slowed the film down something chronic. Cusack and Driver are a good couple though, with real chemistry between them that sparkles on screen. But as Blank's two worlds begin to collide, things seriously begin to unravel in the film. Take the moment when Blank is forced to rely on his school buddy Paul (Jeremy Piven) to dispose of a body - at no point does Paul react with horror the way I suspect I might, nor does he question the scenario at all. It's a shame because there is much to like - Aykroyd is brilliantly psychotic as Grocer while the film's blistering soundtrack (by Joe Strummer of The Clash, of all people) is a real winner as well. There are also lots of references to other movies from "You Only Live Twice" to "The Warriors" which help the movie barrel along. "Grosse Pointe Blank" is a good film but I wanted something more. It isn't as original as it thinks it is and its split personality prevents the film from being a great action film. The romantic subplot works as well as the action scenes which are full of noise, fire and debris flying about the place. I also felt Alan Arkin was underused as Blank's long-suffering therapist and that more could have been made of the premise. A hit-man suffering a crisis of confidence has been covered before in many movies but I doubt that a high school reunion dance featured in any of them. I can just about recommend "Grosse Pointe Blank" simply by being a little different from other hit-man-related films out there. At least it's not anything as adrenaline-fuelled as "Hitman" or "Assassins" - both of which were disappointingly one-dimensional action outings - but it has a depth to it that I can appreciate. I just wished that it was a bit braver in the script and that it was as clever as it thinks it is.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Relaxing fun
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    hedin_88
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Rarely does a movie entertain, make you laugh, keep you hooked with lovable characters and on top if it all, it relaxes. I've watched it a long time ago and it stuck with me, somewhere in the back of my head and i decided to give it another view just now. This movie is simple so you're gonna love it after a hard day just to ease your mind and relax. The characters are simple people who have their past and present explored and who find themselves in the process. Its not about issues and unresolved problems, drama and pain. There is no place for that in this kind of filming. Its up there with Mumford, another movie i liked which shares the traits- a movie made to ease your mind and feel good after watching it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    It just gets better with each viewing
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ryansassy1
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    When I first saw GPB in the '90s I was impressed enough to buy the soundtrack. Now, after having watched it about a ten times in as many years on cable, I realized how stupid it was not to have bought the DVD already. The upside to that is that now there's blu-ray and hopefully, a few extras included..? Well it will be a real sin if that turns out not to be the case! Sorry, I can't help myself. This film is fantastic, in my Top 5 list of '90s films for certain. John Cusack reportedly co-wrote the script, and that makes sense because it's clever and built on witty dialog -- playing perfectly to his strengths. His electrifying chemistry with Minnie Driver, Dan Ackroyd and what the heck, the entire supporting cast, demonstrates pure casting genius and ensures GPB will remain fresh and memorable upon many repeat viewings. The plot reads like an understated Quentin Tarrantino joint. Martin Blank is a professional assassin who is invited to his 10 year High School reunion in Grosse Pointe, MI. Urged by his therapist on the premise that it might be good for him, he decides to attend. Martin contacts old buddies, attempts to reconnect with his long-lost love, reminisces a bit about his childhood, visits his ailing mom in her nursing home, and what the heck--decides to complete an "assignment" while he's there. He runs into a few glitches on his journey of the soul, but exploding convenience stores and murderous rival assassins can't deflect Martin' growing moral conscience and his determination to win back the girl he stood up on Prom night. Grosse Pointe Blank is hard to pin down. This is a black comedy, but strangely uplifting at the same time. It has plenty of shooting action, martial arts and a dash of James Bond coolness, but it's not about that, really; it asks deeper philosophical questions of the sanctity of life and the power of love and forgiveness. And of course at the heart of it all, there's the relatable conundrum of those torturous High School Reunions. GPB is John Cusack, Minnie Driver, Dan Ackroyd and Joan Cusack at the top of their forms. It also features some of the best tracks from the musical talent of the '80s. If you are a fan of any of theirs, it is a must-see.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    All hail the 0.9%
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    cmoyton
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/9/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    .....who voted this sacred cow a score of one. Ugggggh. Words almost fail me. I'm sick too of all the word play and puns around the film title. How it is so funny and quirky. A perfect light blend of action, comedy and romance. Wrong. This is exactly the type of movie that upper storey hotel rooms were made for so that you can throw the TV out the window. Normally i like Cusack. He is a fine, versatile actor who has done his fair share of comedy and romance. Alas he lapses into the aura of smugness and self congratulation that oozes throughout the length of the film. Stupid can be good like Dumb and Dumber. Even Burn After Reading which was a second rate Coen brothers effort. But when stupid is just stupid, it's stupid.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Good Movie With A Different Storyline,
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Dillon Harris
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Grosse Pointe Blank is a good movie with a good,albeit different,storyline,a good cast and some good twists to it too.I've never been a huge fan of John Cusack,but I did appreciate his role as Martin Q. Blank in this.I really enjoyed Dan Aykroyds role as Grocer and Hank Azaria as Steven Lardner,because I've always been a big fan of the two of them,Dan Aykroyd for great comedy films he wrote and starred in such as Ghostbusters and The Blues Brothers,and Hank Azaria because of his many voice roles on The Simpsons.They could have gotten a much more attractive female lead for this movie,no offense on her,but Minnie Driver is not good looking,someone like Cameron Diaz would have been much better for the role of Debi Newberry. An assassin is sent on a mission to a place called Grosse Pointe,and by an amazing coincidence,it is where his ten year high school reunion is taking place at the same time.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Mirror in the bathroom.....
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    FlashCallahan
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/3/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Martin Blank is a freelance hit-man who starts to develop a conscience, which causes him to fluff a couple of routine assignments. On the advice of his secretary and his psychiatrist, he attends his 10th year High School reunion in Grosse Pointe, Michigan (a Detroit suburb where he's also contracted to kill someone). Hot on his tail are a couple of over-enthusiastic federal agents, another assassin who wants to kill him, and Grocer, an assassin who wants him to join an Assassin's Union....... If you thought that the wedding singer was a little too sweet for your liking, then this is the perfect antidote to that other Eighties movie of 1997. And while that movie is very good in it's own respect, this is dark, deluded, funny, and most of all, a very touching tale about finding yourself and facing your demons. It's not laugh out loud funny, it can be very deep in scenes, but it takes the rough with the smooth, and for every dark moment, there soon is a piece of music,or line that makes the film a perfect example of cinema today. Cusack is at his finest here, taking every single character he played in the eighties, and making them Martin Blank, a man who appears to be stuck in purgatory, and only the voice on the radio can save him. The script is cracking, the action enough to satisfy any action fan, and the romance for the ladies. All in all, it's the perfect date movie, with endless references to eighties movie (Better Off Dead, and Ghostbusters for example) and one of the best soundtracks for a film ever. Do not miss this movie, especially if you have fond memories of the decade that fashion forgot.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Deep, Rough and Charmingly Hilarious
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Sean Lamberger
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Much funnier than I'd remembered, this twisting tale of competing hit men and their uncharacteristically jovial attempts to rid the world of one other also finds the time to address the loss of innocence, the reflections of a milestone high school reunion and the baggage of leading a necessarily isolated lifestyle. John Cusack is fantastic as the acidic, sarcastic prodigal son, returning to his home town on business while also giving serious thought to abandoning his violent ways for good. Great supporting work helps that role to flower even further, especially in the forms of his grinning, kill-happy competition, (a joyously nasty dark turn by Dan Aykroyd) the jilted love interest he left high and dry ten years back (Minnie Driver at her most smokin') and his flippant, hard-nosed assistant (Joan Cusack). One of the greatest soundtracks ever, plus work on the original score by former Clash frontman Joe Strummer, takes this whole package over the top. Strongly recommended.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Dialog Funnier Than Plot
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    leonlouisricci
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This Black Comedy has its moments. There are a number of Funny Lines but the Comedic Situations don't fare as well. For example, the totally banal Radio Station Scene, the Real Estate Piece just lies there without Wit and there are others, especially the whole Romantic Subplot with Near Zero Chemistry. The Action and the Violence are much better. These are done with an intensity and Style befitting the Movie's Conceit, especially the Finale and the short but incredible Hand to Hand confrontation in the Halls of the High School that is High Style. The Movie works most of the time but when it doesn't the thing screams to a halt and exposes itself as ill fitted and overplayed. Like the Convenience Store Set-Piece or the Mother and Child Reunion. Overall this is Overrated but still a better than Average work that is well done if you can accept some pretty Bad Acting from Sister Cusack and Minnie Driver. Both do some unwatchable Overreaching. But the rest of the Cast is Fine and some of the Writing is Clever and Cool, but beware that in spots this shows some pretty glaring Missteps. The Movie initially Flopped but has gained some Cult recognition for its irreverent Subject Matter and attempts at Ultra-Hipness. One final Blow, the Clash was an Important Group, but here the Joe Strummer Music is way overdone and the whole Soundtrack is surprisingly Anemic considering that it is in your Face (Ears) so intrusively. The White-Bread Reggae is embarrassing, thankfully it includes Johnny Nash's Seminal Chart-Topper for some redemption.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Funny, cool '90s movie with a fantastic fight scene
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Mike Bloxham
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A sharp and witty romantic comedy with some really excellent dialogue. I'm not normally a big fan of Cusack but he is perfect in the role of Martin Blank. Minnie Driver looks beautiful and does a great job. Some uneven parts, the ending isn't amazing. My favourite part was the fight at the reunion dance, it's just brilliantly executed, one of the most exciting fights I've seen committed to film. Maybe it's because you actually see John Cusack throwing high kicks and not some stuntman filmed from behind, there is a very authentic feel to it. Martin Blank is wandering through the corridors of his high school, he's just shared a kiss with Driver, he comes across his old locker, jimmies it open and finds a ten year old spliff he stashed there. He smiles and crumbles the flaky joint, dreamy with nostalgia and the possibilities of life, happier than he's been in years. A hit-man steps around the corner, Blank's reaction is instantaneous, instinctive, he gets in the first blow before the enemy has even raised his gun and in the blink of an eye the two killers are fighting to the death. It's just an outstanding scene.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Thriller With Something For Everyone
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    seymourblack-1
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    With its offbeat combination of comedy, romance and action, "Grosse Pointe Blank" is a highly entertaining thriller that has something for everyone. Its plot is unpredictable, its characters are wonderfully eccentric and its dialogue is sharp and witty. It's also full of terrific performances and boasts a nostalgic 1980s soundtrack that provides an enjoyable accompaniment to all the craziness that takes place on-screen. Martin Q Blank (John Cusack) is a very successful hit-man who's going through an existential crisis and to make matters worse, his most recent assignment didn't go according to plan. On the advice of his therapist and his secretary, he's persuaded to attend his 10-year high school reunion in the town of Grosse Pointe, Michigan so that he can reconnect with his past, in the hope that doing so, might help to improve his current state of mind. Conveniently, he also has a professional reason for returning to his home town as he has another contract to fulfil for the same client he so recently disappointed. The first person that Martin looks up in Grosse Pointe is his high school sweetheart Debi (Minnie Driver) who's now a DJ on the local radio station. Martin had disappeared out of her life without explanation on the night when they'd arranged to go to the school prom together, but by his own admission, she'd remained in his thoughts and dreams ever since. He openly admits that he's now a professional hit-man but she naturally takes this remark as a joke. Some factors linked to his current line of work make Martin's visit to Grosse Pointe a little more complicated and dangerous than Debi could possibly imagine as, not only is he being followed by two operatives from the National Security Agency, but also a couple of independent hit-men called Grocer (Dan Aykroyd) and Felix LePoubelle (Benny Urquidez) are on his tail and looking for trouble. Martin and Debi go to the high school reunion and meet a number of their old classmates, but when Martin wanders away from the main hall into a quiet corridor, LePoubelle attacks him and Martin, without hesitation, kills his assailant. Debi soon arrives on the scene and then, in a state of shock and panic, runs away. Another of Martin's old classmates Paul Spericki (Jeremy Piven) arrives shortly after and helps Martin to dispose of the body in the school furnace. Further difficulties follow for Martin in his dealings with Debi and Grocer and even his professional assignment proves to be far from straightforward. A great deal of danger and numerous surprises then also have to be confronted as Martin tries again to reconcile with Debi and attempts to get out of Grosse Pointe alive. John Cusack is very likable and funny as a guy whose career started in the Army and then took a number of unexpected twists that eventually brought him to a point in his life where he began to feel lost and unfulfilled. His talent for comedy is really impressive and he's also faultless in the action sequences. Alan Arkin is fantastic as Martin's terrified shrink and Joan Cusack is marvellous as his very intense secretary. Dan Aykroyd excels as Martin's greatest professional rival and Minnie Driver is effective in showing the chemistry that still exists between her and Martin as well as the bitterness she continues to feel about the way he abandoned her a decade before. "Grosse Pointe Blank" is a real one-off with numerous laugh-out-loud moments and is also highly recommended.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Hits the target but misses the bull's eye - 73%
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Benjamin Cox
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This has been on my radar since it was released and at last, I can cross it off. I like John Cusack as an actor (though I'll forget about "2012" for the purposes of this argument!) and this had all the feel of a smart-aleck comic thriller that normally appeals to me. And it does but something's missing. It has witty dialogue, genuine laughs, an amazing soundtrack and surprisingly decent action but by being a jack-of-all-trades, it ends up a master of none. However, this is still worth your attention simply by being a little different from the usual Hollywood film about hit men. Cusack plays Martin Blank, an experienced professional killer who finds himself beginning to question his career choice. After turning down an offer to join an assassin's union led by his rival Grocer (Dan Aykroyd), Blank is contacted by his broker (Joan Cusack) with an odd proposition - his ten year high school reunion is taking place in Grosse Pointe, Michigan at the same time as a job is required in Detroit. Reluctantly, Martin agrees while thinking he can make amends with Debi (Minnie Driver), the girl he stood up at the prom ten years ago. But Blank has other concerns - he is pursued to Grosse Pointe by a couple of feds (Hank Azaria and K. Todd Freeman), another hit-man wanting to collect the price on Blank's head (Benny Urquidez) and Grocer who doesn't take too kindly to rejection... If you're not sure what to make of "Grosse Pointe Blank" then you're not alone - the film veers wildly from energetic action thriller to romantic comedy which, if I'm honest, slowed the film down something chronic. Cusack and Driver are a good couple though, with real chemistry between them that sparkles on screen. But as Blank's two worlds begin to collide, things seriously begin to unravel in the film. Take the moment when Blank is forced to rely on his school buddy Paul (Jeremy Piven) to dispose of a body - at no point does Paul react with horror the way I suspect I might, nor does he question the scenario at all. It's a shame because there is much to like - Aykroyd is brilliantly psychotic as Grocer while the film's blistering soundtrack (by Joe Strummer of The Clash, of all people) is a real winner as well. There are also lots of references to other movies from "You Only Live Twice" to "The Warriors" which help the movie barrel along. "Grosse Pointe Blank" is a good film but I wanted something more. It isn't as original as it thinks it is and its split personality prevents the film from being a great action film. The romantic subplot works as well as the action scenes which are full of noise, fire and debris flying about the place. I also felt Alan Arkin was underused as Blank's long-suffering therapist and that more could have been made of the premise. A hit-man suffering a crisis of confidence has been covered before in many movies but I doubt that a high school reunion dance featured in any of them. I can just about recommend "Grosse Pointe Blank" simply by being a little different from other hit-man-related films out there. At least it's not anything as adrenaline-fuelled as "Hitman" or "Assassins" - both of which were disappointingly one-dimensional action outings - but it has a depth to it that I can appreciate. I just wished that it was a bit braver in the script and that it was as clever as it thinks it is.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Relaxing fun
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    hedin_88
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Rarely does a movie entertain, make you laugh, keep you hooked with lovable characters and on top if it all, it relaxes. I've watched it a long time ago and it stuck with me, somewhere in the back of my head and i decided to give it another view just now. This movie is simple so you're gonna love it after a hard day just to ease your mind and relax. The characters are simple people who have their past and present explored and who find themselves in the process. Its not about issues and unresolved problems, drama and pain. There is no place for that in this kind of filming. Its up there with Mumford, another movie i liked which shares the traits- a movie made to ease your mind and feel good after watching it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    It just gets better with each viewing
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ryansassy1
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    When I first saw GPB in the '90s I was impressed enough to buy the soundtrack. Now, after having watched it about a ten times in as many years on cable, I realized how stupid it was not to have bought the DVD already. The upside to that is that now there's blu-ray and hopefully, a few extras included..? Well it will be a real sin if that turns out not to be the case! Sorry, I can't help myself. This film is fantastic, in my Top 5 list of '90s films for certain. John Cusack reportedly co-wrote the script, and that makes sense because it's clever and built on witty dialog -- playing perfectly to his strengths. His electrifying chemistry with Minnie Driver, Dan Ackroyd and what the heck, the entire supporting cast, demonstrates pure casting genius and ensures GPB will remain fresh and memorable upon many repeat viewings. The plot reads like an understated Quentin Tarrantino joint. Martin Blank is a professional assassin who is invited to his 10 year High School reunion in Grosse Pointe, MI. Urged by his therapist on the premise that it might be good for him, he decides to attend. Martin contacts old buddies, attempts to reconnect with his long-lost love, reminisces a bit about his childhood, visits his ailing mom in her nursing home, and what the heck--decides to complete an "assignment" while he's there. He runs into a few glitches on his journey of the soul, but exploding convenience stores and murderous rival assassins can't deflect Martin' growing moral conscience and his determination to win back the girl he stood up on Prom night. Grosse Pointe Blank is hard to pin down. This is a black comedy, but strangely uplifting at the same time. It has plenty of shooting action, martial arts and a dash of James Bond coolness, but it's not about that, really; it asks deeper philosophical questions of the sanctity of life and the power of love and forgiveness. And of course at the heart of it all, there's the relatable conundrum of those torturous High School Reunions. GPB is John Cusack, Minnie Driver, Dan Ackroyd and Joan Cusack at the top of their forms. It also features some of the best tracks from the musical talent of the '80s. If you are a fan of any of theirs, it is a must-see.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    All hail the 0.9%
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    cmoyton
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/9/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    .....who voted this sacred cow a score of one. Ugggggh. Words almost fail me. I'm sick too of all the word play and puns around the film title. How it is so funny and quirky. A perfect light blend of action, comedy and romance. Wrong. This is exactly the type of movie that upper storey hotel rooms were made for so that you can throw the TV out the window. Normally i like Cusack. He is a fine, versatile actor who has done his fair share of comedy and romance. Alas he lapses into the aura of smugness and self congratulation that oozes throughout the length of the film. Stupid can be good like Dumb and Dumber. Even Burn After Reading which was a second rate Coen brothers effort. But when stupid is just stupid, it's stupid.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Good Movie With A Different Storyline,
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Dillon Harris
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Grosse Pointe Blank is a good movie with a good,albeit different,storyline,a good cast and some good twists to it too.I've never been a huge fan of John Cusack,but I did appreciate his role as Martin Q. Blank in this.I really enjoyed Dan Aykroyds role as Grocer and Hank Azaria as Steven Lardner,because I've always been a big fan of the two of them,Dan Aykroyd for great comedy films he wrote and starred in such as Ghostbusters and The Blues Brothers,and Hank Azaria because of his many voice roles on The Simpsons.They could have gotten a much more attractive female lead for this movie,no offense on her,but Minnie Driver is not good looking,someone like Cameron Diaz would have been much better for the role of Debi Newberry. An assassin is sent on a mission to a place called Grosse Pointe,and by an amazing coincidence,it is where his ten year high school reunion is taking place at the same time.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Mirror in the bathroom.....
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    FlashCallahan
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/3/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Martin Blank is a freelance hit-man who starts to develop a conscience, which causes him to fluff a couple of routine assignments. On the advice of his secretary and his psychiatrist, he attends his 10th year High School reunion in Grosse Pointe, Michigan (a Detroit suburb where he's also contracted to kill someone). Hot on his tail are a couple of over-enthusiastic federal agents, another assassin who wants to kill him, and Grocer, an assassin who wants him to join an Assassin's Union....... If you thought that the wedding singer was a little too sweet for your liking, then this is the perfect antidote to that other Eighties movie of 1997. And while that movie is very good in it's own respect, this is dark, deluded, funny, and most of all, a very touching tale about finding yourself and facing your demons. It's not laugh out loud funny, it can be very deep in scenes, but it takes the rough with the smooth, and for every dark moment, there soon is a piece of music,or line that makes the film a perfect example of cinema today. Cusack is at his finest here, taking every single character he played in the eighties, and making them Martin Blank, a man who appears to be stuck in purgatory, and only the voice on the radio can save him. The script is cracking, the action enough to satisfy any action fan, and the romance for the ladies. All in all, it's the perfect date movie, with endless references to eighties movie (Better Off Dead, and Ghostbusters for example) and one of the best soundtracks for a film ever. Do not miss this movie, especially if you have fond memories of the decade that fashion forgot.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Deep, Rough and Charmingly Hilarious
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Sean Lamberger
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Much funnier than I'd remembered, this twisting tale of competing hit men and their uncharacteristically jovial attempts to rid the world of one other also finds the time to address the loss of innocence, the reflections of a milestone high school reunion and the baggage of leading a necessarily isolated lifestyle. John Cusack is fantastic as the acidic, sarcastic prodigal son, returning to his home town on business while also giving serious thought to abandoning his violent ways for good. Great supporting work helps that role to flower even further, especially in the forms of his grinning, kill-happy competition, (a joyously nasty dark turn by Dan Aykroyd) the jilted love interest he left high and dry ten years back (Minnie Driver at her most smokin') and his flippant, hard-nosed assistant (Joan Cusack). One of the greatest soundtracks ever, plus work on the original score by former Clash frontman Joe Strummer, takes this whole package over the top. Strongly recommended.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Dialog Funnier Than Plot
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    leonlouisricci
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This Black Comedy has its moments. There are a number of Funny Lines but the Comedic Situations don't fare as well. For example, the totally banal Radio Station Scene, the Real Estate Piece just lies there without Wit and there are others, especially the whole Romantic Subplot with Near Zero Chemistry. The Action and the Violence are much better. These are done with an intensity and Style befitting the Movie's Conceit, especially the Finale and the short but incredible Hand to Hand confrontation in the Halls of the High School that is High Style. The Movie works most of the time but when it doesn't the thing screams to a halt and exposes itself as ill fitted and overplayed. Like the Convenience Store Set-Piece or the Mother and Child Reunion. Overall this is Overrated but still a better than Average work that is well done if you can accept some pretty Bad Acting from Sister Cusack and Minnie Driver. Both do some unwatchable Overreaching. But the rest of the Cast is Fine and some of the Writing is Clever and Cool, but beware that in spots this shows some pretty glaring Missteps. The Movie initially Flopped but has gained some Cult recognition for its irreverent Subject Matter and attempts at Ultra-Hipness. One final Blow, the Clash was an Important Group, but here the Joe Strummer Music is way overdone and the whole Soundtrack is surprisingly Anemic considering that it is in your Face (Ears) so intrusively. The White-Bread Reggae is embarrassing, thankfully it includes Johnny Nash's Seminal Chart-Topper for some redemption.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Funny, cool '90s movie with a fantastic fight scene
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Mike Bloxham
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A sharp and witty romantic comedy with some really excellent dialogue. I'm not normally a big fan of Cusack but he is perfect in the role of Martin Blank. Minnie Driver looks beautiful and does a great job. Some uneven parts, the ending isn't amazing. My favourite part was the fight at the reunion dance, it's just brilliantly executed, one of the most exciting fights I've seen committed to film. Maybe it's because you actually see John Cusack throwing high kicks and not some stuntman filmed from behind, there is a very authentic feel to it. Martin Blank is wandering through the corridors of his high school, he's just shared a kiss with Driver, he comes across his old locker, jimmies it open and finds a ten year old spliff he stashed there. He smiles and crumbles the flaky joint, dreamy with nostalgia and the possibilities of life, happier than he's been in years. A hit-man steps around the corner, Blank's reaction is instantaneous, instinctive, he gets in the first blow before the enemy has even raised his gun and in the blink of an eye the two killers are fighting to the death. It's just an outstanding scene.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Thriller With Something For Everyone
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    seymourblack-1
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    With its offbeat combination of comedy, romance and action, "Grosse Pointe Blank" is a highly entertaining thriller that has something for everyone. Its plot is unpredictable, its characters are wonderfully eccentric and its dialogue is sharp and witty. It's also full of terrific performances and boasts a nostalgic 1980s soundtrack that provides an enjoyable accompaniment to all the craziness that takes place on-screen. Martin Q Blank (John Cusack) is a very successful hit-man who's going through an existential crisis and to make matters worse, his most recent assignment didn't go according to plan. On the advice of his therapist and his secretary, he's persuaded to attend his 10-year high school reunion in the town of Grosse Pointe, Michigan so that he can reconnect with his past, in the hope that doing so, might help to improve his current state of mind. Conveniently, he also has a professional reason for returning to his home town as he has another contract to fulfil for the same client he so recently disappointed. The first person that Martin looks up in Grosse Pointe is his high school sweetheart Debi (Minnie Driver) who's now a DJ on the local radio station. Martin had disappeared out of her life without explanation on the night when they'd arranged to go to the school prom together, but by his own admission, she'd remained in his thoughts and dreams ever since. He openly admits that he's now a professional hit-man but she naturally takes this remark as a joke. Some factors linked to his current line of work make Martin's visit to Grosse Pointe a little more complicated and dangerous than Debi could possibly imagine as, not only is he being followed by two operatives from the National Security Agency, but also a couple of independent hit-men called Grocer (Dan Aykroyd) and Felix LePoubelle (Benny Urquidez) are on his tail and looking for trouble. Martin and Debi go to the high school reunion and meet a number of their old classmates, but when Martin wanders away from the main hall into a quiet corridor, LePoubelle attacks him and Martin, without hesitation, kills his assailant. Debi soon arrives on the scene and then, in a state of shock and panic, runs away. Another of Martin's old classmates Paul Spericki (Jeremy Piven) arrives shortly after and helps Martin to dispose of the body in the school furnace. Further difficulties follow for Martin in his dealings with Debi and Grocer and even his professional assignment proves to be far from straightforward. A great deal of danger and numerous surprises then also have to be confronted as Martin tries again to reconcile with Debi and attempts to get out of Grosse Pointe alive. John Cusack is very likable and funny as a guy whose career started in the Army and then took a number of unexpected twists that eventually brought him to a point in his life where he began to feel lost and unfulfilled. His talent for comedy is really impressive and he's also faultless in the action sequences. Alan Arkin is fantastic as Martin's terrified shrink and Joan Cusack is marvellous as his very intense secretary. Dan Aykroyd excels as Martin's greatest professional rival and Minnie Driver is effective in showing the chemistry that still exists between her and Martin as well as the bitterness she continues to feel about the way he abandoned her a decade before. "Grosse Pointe Blank" is a real one-off with numerous laugh-out-loud moments and is also highly recommended.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Hits the target but misses the bull's eye - 73%
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Benjamin Cox
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This has been on my radar since it was released and at last, I can cross it off. I like John Cusack as an actor (though I'll forget about "2012" for the purposes of this argument!) and this had all the feel of a smart-aleck comic thriller that normally appeals to me. And it does but something's missing. It has witty dialogue, genuine laughs, an amazing soundtrack and surprisingly decent action but by being a jack-of-all-trades, it ends up a master of none. However, this is still worth your attention simply by being a little different from the usual Hollywood film about hit men. Cusack plays Martin Blank, an experienced professional killer who finds himself beginning to question his career choice. After turning down an offer to join an assassin's union led by his rival Grocer (Dan Aykroyd), Blank is contacted by his broker (Joan Cusack) with an odd proposition - his ten year high school reunion is taking place in Grosse Pointe, Michigan at the same time as a job is required in Detroit. Reluctantly, Martin agrees while thinking he can make amends with Debi (Minnie Driver), the girl he stood up at the prom ten years ago. But Blank has other concerns - he is pursued to Grosse Pointe by a couple of feds (Hank Azaria and K. Todd Freeman), another hit-man wanting to collect the price on Blank's head (Benny Urquidez) and Grocer who doesn't take too kindly to rejection... If you're not sure what to make of "Grosse Pointe Blank" then you're not alone - the film veers wildly from energetic action thriller to romantic comedy which, if I'm honest, slowed the film down something chronic. Cusack and Driver are a good couple though, with real chemistry between them that sparkles on screen. But as Blank's two worlds begin to collide, things seriously begin to unravel in the film. Take the moment when Blank is forced to rely on his school buddy Paul (Jeremy Piven) to dispose of a body - at no point does Paul react with horror the way I suspect I might, nor does he question the scenario at all. It's a shame because there is much to like - Aykroyd is brilliantly psychotic as Grocer while the film's blistering soundtrack (by Joe Strummer of The Clash, of all people) is a real winner as well. There are also lots of references to other movies from "You Only Live Twice" to "The Warriors" which help the movie barrel along. "Grosse Pointe Blank" is a good film but I wanted something more. It isn't as original as it thinks it is and its split personality prevents the film from being a great action film. The romantic subplot works as well as the action scenes which are full of noise, fire and debris flying about the place. I also felt Alan Arkin was underused as Blank's long-suffering therapist and that more could have been made of the premise. A hit-man suffering a crisis of confidence has been covered before in many movies but I doubt that a high school reunion dance featured in any of them. I can just about recommend "Grosse Pointe Blank" simply by being a little different from other hit-man-related films out there. At least it's not anything as adrenaline-fuelled as "Hitman" or "Assassins" - both of which were disappointingly one-dimensional action outings - but it has a depth to it that I can appreciate. I just wished that it was a bit braver in the script and that it was as clever as it thinks it is.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Relaxing fun
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    hedin_88
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Rarely does a movie entertain, make you laugh, keep you hooked with lovable characters and on top if it all, it relaxes. I've watched it a long time ago and it stuck with me, somewhere in the back of my head and i decided to give it another view just now. This movie is simple so you're gonna love it after a hard day just to ease your mind and relax. The characters are simple people who have their past and present explored and who find themselves in the process. Its not about issues and unresolved problems, drama and pain. There is no place for that in this kind of filming. Its up there with Mumford, another movie i liked which shares the traits- a movie made to ease your mind and feel good after watching it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    It just gets better with each viewing
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ryansassy1
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    When I first saw GPB in the '90s I was impressed enough to buy the soundtrack. Now, after having watched it about a ten times in as many years on cable, I realized how stupid it was not to have bought the DVD already. The upside to that is that now there's blu-ray and hopefully, a few extras included..? Well it will be a real sin if that turns out not to be the case! Sorry, I can't help myself. This film is fantastic, in my Top 5 list of '90s films for certain. John Cusack reportedly co-wrote the script, and that makes sense because it's clever and built on witty dialog -- playing perfectly to his strengths. His electrifying chemistry with Minnie Driver, Dan Ackroyd and what the heck, the entire supporting cast, demonstrates pure casting genius and ensures GPB will remain fresh and memorable upon many repeat viewings. The plot reads like an understated Quentin Tarrantino joint. Martin Blank is a professional assassin who is invited to his 10 year High School reunion in Grosse Pointe, MI. Urged by his therapist on the premise that it might be good for him, he decides to attend. Martin contacts old buddies, attempts to reconnect with his long-lost love, reminisces a bit about his childhood, visits his ailing mom in her nursing home, and what the heck--decides to complete an "assignment" while he's there. He runs into a few glitches on his journey of the soul, but exploding convenience stores and murderous rival assassins can't deflect Martin' growing moral conscience and his determination to win back the girl he stood up on Prom night. Grosse Pointe Blank is hard to pin down. This is a black comedy, but strangely uplifting at the same time. It has plenty of shooting action, martial arts and a dash of James Bond coolness, but it's not about that, really; it asks deeper philosophical questions of the sanctity of life and the power of love and forgiveness. And of course at the heart of it all, there's the relatable conundrum of those torturous High School Reunions. GPB is John Cusack, Minnie Driver, Dan Ackroyd and Joan Cusack at the top of their forms. It also features some of the best tracks from the musical talent of the '80s. If you are a fan of any of theirs, it is a must-see.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    All hail the 0.9%
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    cmoyton
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/9/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    .....who voted this sacred cow a score of one. Ugggggh. Words almost fail me. I'm sick too of all the word play and puns around the film title. How it is so funny and quirky. A perfect light blend of action, comedy and romance. Wrong. This is exactly the type of movie that upper storey hotel rooms were made for so that you can throw the TV out the window. Normally i like Cusack. He is a fine, versatile actor who has done his fair share of comedy and romance. Alas he lapses into the aura of smugness and self congratulation that oozes throughout the length of the film. Stupid can be good like Dumb and Dumber. Even Burn After Reading which was a second rate Coen brothers effort. But when stupid is just stupid, it's stupid.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Good Movie With A Different Storyline,
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Dillon Harris
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Grosse Pointe Blank is a good movie with a good,albeit different,storyline,a good cast and some good twists to it too.I've never been a huge fan of John Cusack,but I did appreciate his role as Martin Q. Blank in this.I really enjoyed Dan Aykroyds role as Grocer and Hank Azaria as Steven Lardner,because I've always been a big fan of the two of them,Dan Aykroyd for great comedy films he wrote and starred in such as Ghostbusters and The Blues Brothers,and Hank Azaria because of his many voice roles on The Simpsons.They could have gotten a much more attractive female lead for this movie,no offense on her,but Minnie Driver is not good looking,someone like Cameron Diaz would have been much better for the role of Debi Newberry. An assassin is sent on a mission to a place called Grosse Pointe,and by an amazing coincidence,it is where his ten year high school reunion is taking place at the same time.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Mirror in the bathroom.....
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    FlashCallahan
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/3/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Martin Blank is a freelance hit-man who starts to develop a conscience, which causes him to fluff a couple of routine assignments. On the advice of his secretary and his psychiatrist, he attends his 10th year High School reunion in Grosse Pointe, Michigan (a Detroit suburb where he's also contracted to kill someone). Hot on his tail are a couple of over-enthusiastic federal agents, another assassin who wants to kill him, and Grocer, an assassin who wants him to join an Assassin's Union....... If you thought that the wedding singer was a little too sweet for your liking, then this is the perfect antidote to that other Eighties movie of 1997. And while that movie is very good in it's own respect, this is dark, deluded, funny, and most of all, a very touching tale about finding yourself and facing your demons. It's not laugh out loud funny, it can be very deep in scenes, but it takes the rough with the smooth, and for every dark moment, there soon is a piece of music,or line that makes the film a perfect example of cinema today. Cusack is at his finest here, taking every single character he played in the eighties, and making them Martin Blank, a man who appears to be stuck in purgatory, and only the voice on the radio can save him. The script is cracking, the action enough to satisfy any action fan, and the romance for the ladies. All in all, it's the perfect date movie, with endless references to eighties movie (Better Off Dead, and Ghostbusters for example) and one of the best soundtracks for a film ever. Do not miss this movie, especially if you have fond memories of the decade that fashion forgot.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Deep, Rough and Charmingly Hilarious
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Sean Lamberger
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Much funnier than I'd remembered, this twisting tale of competing hit men and their uncharacteristically jovial attempts to rid the world of one other also finds the time to address the loss of innocence, the reflections of a milestone high school reunion and the baggage of leading a necessarily isolated lifestyle. John Cusack is fantastic as the acidic, sarcastic prodigal son, returning to his home town on business while also giving serious thought to abandoning his violent ways for good. Great supporting work helps that role to flower even further, especially in the forms of his grinning, kill-happy competition, (a joyously nasty dark turn by Dan Aykroyd) the jilted love interest he left high and dry ten years back (Minnie Driver at her most smokin') and his flippant, hard-nosed assistant (Joan Cusack). One of the greatest soundtracks ever, plus work on the original score by former Clash frontman Joe Strummer, takes this whole package over the top. Strongly recommended.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Dialog Funnier Than Plot
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    leonlouisricci
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This Black Comedy has its moments. There are a number of Funny Lines but the Comedic Situations don't fare as well. For example, the totally banal Radio Station Scene, the Real Estate Piece just lies there without Wit and there are others, especially the whole Romantic Subplot with Near Zero Chemistry. The Action and the Violence are much better. These are done with an intensity and Style befitting the Movie's Conceit, especially the Finale and the short but incredible Hand to Hand confrontation in the Halls of the High School that is High Style. The Movie works most of the time but when it doesn't the thing screams to a halt and exposes itself as ill fitted and overplayed. Like the Convenience Store Set-Piece or the Mother and Child Reunion. Overall this is Overrated but still a better than Average work that is well done if you can accept some pretty Bad Acting from Sister Cusack and Minnie Driver. Both do some unwatchable Overreaching. But the rest of the Cast is Fine and some of the Writing is Clever and Cool, but beware that in spots this shows some pretty glaring Missteps. The Movie initially Flopped but has gained some Cult recognition for its irreverent Subject Matter and attempts at Ultra-Hipness. One final Blow, the Clash was an Important Group, but here the Joe Strummer Music is way overdone and the whole Soundtrack is surprisingly Anemic considering that it is in your Face (Ears) so intrusively. The White-Bread Reggae is embarrassing, thankfully it includes Johnny Nash's Seminal Chart-Topper for some redemption.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Funny, cool '90s movie with a fantastic fight scene
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Mike Bloxham
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A sharp and witty romantic comedy with some really excellent dialogue. I'm not normally a big fan of Cusack but he is perfect in the role of Martin Blank. Minnie Driver looks beautiful and does a great job. Some uneven parts, the ending isn't amazing. My favourite part was the fight at the reunion dance, it's just brilliantly executed, one of the most exciting fights I've seen committed to film. Maybe it's because you actually see John Cusack throwing high kicks and not some stuntman filmed from behind, there is a very authentic feel to it. Martin Blank is wandering through the corridors of his high school, he's just shared a kiss with Driver, he comes across his old locker, jimmies it open and finds a ten year old spliff he stashed there. He smiles and crumbles the flaky joint, dreamy with nostalgia and the possibilities of life, happier than he's been in years. A hit-man steps around the corner, Blank's reaction is instantaneous, instinctive, he gets in the first blow before the enemy has even raised his gun and in the blink of an eye the two killers are fighting to the death. It's just an outstanding scene.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Thriller With Something For Everyone
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    seymourblack-1
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    With its offbeat combination of comedy, romance and action, "Grosse Pointe Blank" is a highly entertaining thriller that has something for everyone. Its plot is unpredictable, its characters are wonderfully eccentric and its dialogue is sharp and witty. It's also full of terrific performances and boasts a nostalgic 1980s soundtrack that provides an enjoyable accompaniment to all the craziness that takes place on-screen. Martin Q Blank (John Cusack) is a very successful hit-man who's going through an existential crisis and to make matters worse, his most recent assignment didn't go according to plan. On the advice of his therapist and his secretary, he's persuaded to attend his 10-year high school reunion in the town of Grosse Pointe, Michigan so that he can reconnect with his past, in the hope that doing so, might help to improve his current state of mind. Conveniently, he also has a professional reason for returning to his home town as he has another contract to fulfil for the same client he so recently disappointed. The first person that Martin looks up in Grosse Pointe is his high school sweetheart Debi (Minnie Driver) who's now a DJ on the local radio station. Martin had disappeared out of her life without explanation on the night when they'd arranged to go to the school prom together, but by his own admission, she'd remained in his thoughts and dreams ever since. He openly admits that he's now a professional hit-man but she naturally takes this remark as a joke. Some factors linked to his current line of work make Martin's visit to Grosse Pointe a little more complicated and dangerous than Debi could possibly imagine as, not only is he being followed by two operatives from the National Security Agency, but also a couple of independent hit-men called Grocer (Dan Aykroyd) and Felix LePoubelle (Benny Urquidez) are on his tail and looking for trouble. Martin and Debi go to the high school reunion and meet a number of their old classmates, but when Martin wanders away from the main hall into a quiet corridor, LePoubelle attacks him and Martin, without hesitation, kills his assailant. Debi soon arrives on the scene and then, in a state of shock and panic, runs away. Another of Martin's old classmates Paul Spericki (Jeremy Piven) arrives shortly after and helps Martin to dispose of the body in the school furnace. Further difficulties follow for Martin in his dealings with Debi and Grocer and even his professional assignment proves to be far from straightforward. A great deal of danger and numerous surprises then also have to be confronted as Martin tries again to reconcile with Debi and attempts to get out of Grosse Pointe alive. John Cusack is very likable and funny as a guy whose career started in the Army and then took a number of unexpected twists that eventually brought him to a point in his life where he began to feel lost and unfulfilled. His talent for comedy is really impressive and he's also faultless in the action sequences. Alan Arkin is fantastic as Martin's terrified shrink and Joan Cusack is marvellous as his very intense secretary. Dan Aykroyd excels as Martin's greatest professional rival and Minnie Driver is effective in showing the chemistry that still exists between her and Martin as well as the bitterness she continues to feel about the way he abandoned her a decade before. "Grosse Pointe Blank" is a real one-off with numerous laugh-out-loud moments and is also highly recommended.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Hits the target but misses the bull's eye - 73%
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Benjamin Cox
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This has been on my radar since it was released and at last, I can cross it off. I like John Cusack as an actor (though I'll forget about "2012" for the purposes of this argument!) and this had all the feel of a smart-aleck comic thriller that normally appeals to me. And it does but something's missing. It has witty dialogue, genuine laughs, an amazing soundtrack and surprisingly decent action but by being a jack-of-all-trades, it ends up a master of none. However, this is still worth your attention simply by being a little different from the usual Hollywood film about hit men. Cusack plays Martin Blank, an experienced professional killer who finds himself beginning to question his career choice. After turning down an offer to join an assassin's union led by his rival Grocer (Dan Aykroyd), Blank is contacted by his broker (Joan Cusack) with an odd proposition - his ten year high school reunion is taking place in Grosse Pointe, Michigan at the same time as a job is required in Detroit. Reluctantly, Martin agrees while thinking he can make amends with Debi (Minnie Driver), the girl he stood up at the prom ten years ago. But Blank has other concerns - he is pursued to Grosse Pointe by a couple of feds (Hank Azaria and K. Todd Freeman), another hit-man wanting to collect the price on Blank's head (Benny Urquidez) and Grocer who doesn't take too kindly to rejection... If you're not sure what to make of "Grosse Pointe Blank" then you're not alone - the film veers wildly from energetic action thriller to romantic comedy which, if I'm honest, slowed the film down something chronic. Cusack and Driver are a good couple though, with real chemistry between them that sparkles on screen. But as Blank's two worlds begin to collide, things seriously begin to unravel in the film. Take the moment when Blank is forced to rely on his school buddy Paul (Jeremy Piven) to dispose of a body - at no point does Paul react with horror the way I suspect I might, nor does he question the scenario at all. It's a shame because there is much to like - Aykroyd is brilliantly psychotic as Grocer while the film's blistering soundtrack (by Joe Strummer of The Clash, of all people) is a real winner as well. There are also lots of references to other movies from "You Only Live Twice" to "The Warriors" which help the movie barrel along. "Grosse Pointe Blank" is a good film but I wanted something more. It isn't as original as it thinks it is and its split personality prevents the film from being a great action film. The romantic subplot works as well as the action scenes which are full of noise, fire and debris flying about the place. I also felt Alan Arkin was underused as Blank's long-suffering therapist and that more could have been made of the premise. A hit-man suffering a crisis of confidence has been covered before in many movies but I doubt that a high school reunion dance featured in any of them. I can just about recommend "Grosse Pointe Blank" simply by being a little different from other hit-man-related films out there. At least it's not anything as adrenaline-fuelled as "Hitman" or "Assassins" - both of which were disappointingly one-dimensional action outings - but it has a depth to it that I can appreciate. I just wished that it was a bit braver in the script and that it was as clever as it thinks it is.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Relaxing fun
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    hedin_88
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Rarely does a movie entertain, make you laugh, keep you hooked with lovable characters and on top if it all, it relaxes. I've watched it a long time ago and it stuck with me, somewhere in the back of my head and i decided to give it another view just now. This movie is simple so you're gonna love it after a hard day just to ease your mind and relax. The characters are simple people who have their past and present explored and who find themselves in the process. Its not about issues and unresolved problems, drama and pain. There is no place for that in this kind of filming. Its up there with Mumford, another movie i liked which shares the traits- a movie made to ease your mind and feel good after watching it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    It just gets better with each viewing
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ryansassy1
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    When I first saw GPB in the '90s I was impressed enough to buy the soundtrack. Now, after having watched it about a ten times in as many years on cable, I realized how stupid it was not to have bought the DVD already. The upside to that is that now there's blu-ray and hopefully, a few extras included..? Well it will be a real sin if that turns out not to be the case! Sorry, I can't help myself. This film is fantastic, in my Top 5 list of '90s films for certain. John Cusack reportedly co-wrote the script, and that makes sense because it's clever and built on witty dialog -- playing perfectly to his strengths. His electrifying chemistry with Minnie Driver, Dan Ackroyd and what the heck, the entire supporting cast, demonstrates pure casting genius and ensures GPB will remain fresh and memorable upon many repeat viewings. The plot reads like an understated Quentin Tarrantino joint. Martin Blank is a professional assassin who is invited to his 10 year High School reunion in Grosse Pointe, MI. Urged by his therapist on the premise that it might be good for him, he decides to attend. Martin contacts old buddies, attempts to reconnect with his long-lost love, reminisces a bit about his childhood, visits his ailing mom in her nursing home, and what the heck--decides to complete an "assignment" while he's there. He runs into a few glitches on his journey of the soul, but exploding convenience stores and murderous rival assassins can't deflect Martin' growing moral conscience and his determination to win back the girl he stood up on Prom night. Grosse Pointe Blank is hard to pin down. This is a black comedy, but strangely uplifting at the same time. It has plenty of shooting action, martial arts and a dash of James Bond coolness, but it's not about that, really; it asks deeper philosophical questions of the sanctity of life and the power of love and forgiveness. And of course at the heart of it all, there's the relatable conundrum of those torturous High School Reunions. GPB is John Cusack, Minnie Driver, Dan Ackroyd and Joan Cusack at the top of their forms. It also features some of the best tracks from the musical talent of the '80s. If you are a fan of any of theirs, it is a must-see.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    All hail the 0.9%
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    cmoyton
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/9/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    .....who voted this sacred cow a score of one. Ugggggh. Words almost fail me. I'm sick too of all the word play and puns around the film title. How it is so funny and quirky. A perfect light blend of action, comedy and romance. Wrong. This is exactly the type of movie that upper storey hotel rooms were made for so that you can throw the TV out the window. Normally i like Cusack. He is a fine, versatile actor who has done his fair share of comedy and romance. Alas he lapses into the aura of smugness and self congratulation that oozes throughout the length of the film. Stupid can be good like Dumb and Dumber. Even Burn After Reading which was a second rate Coen brothers effort. But when stupid is just stupid, it's stupid.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Good Movie With A Different Storyline,
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Dillon Harris
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Grosse Pointe Blank is a good movie with a good,albeit different,storyline,a good cast and some good twists to it too.I've never been a huge fan of John Cusack,but I did appreciate his role as Martin Q. Blank in this.I really enjoyed Dan Aykroyds role as Grocer and Hank Azaria as Steven Lardner,because I've always been a big fan of the two of them,Dan Aykroyd for great comedy films he wrote and starred in such as Ghostbusters and The Blues Brothers,and Hank Azaria because of his many voice roles on The Simpsons.They could have gotten a much more attractive female lead for this movie,no offense on her,but Minnie Driver is not good looking,someone like Cameron Diaz would have been much better for the role of Debi Newberry. An assassin is sent on a mission to a place called Grosse Pointe,and by an amazing coincidence,it is where his ten year high school reunion is taking place at the same time.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Mirror in the bathroom.....
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    FlashCallahan
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/3/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Martin Blank is a freelance hit-man who starts to develop a conscience, which causes him to fluff a couple of routine assignments. On the advice of his secretary and his psychiatrist, he attends his 10th year High School reunion in Grosse Pointe, Michigan (a Detroit suburb where he's also contracted to kill someone). Hot on his tail are a couple of over-enthusiastic federal agents, another assassin who wants to kill him, and Grocer, an assassin who wants him to join an Assassin's Union....... If you thought that the wedding singer was a little too sweet for your liking, then this is the perfect antidote to that other Eighties movie of 1997. And while that movie is very good in it's own respect, this is dark, deluded, funny, and most of all, a very touching tale about finding yourself and facing your demons. It's not laugh out loud funny, it can be very deep in scenes, but it takes the rough with the smooth, and for every dark moment, there soon is a piece of music,or line that makes the film a perfect example of cinema today. Cusack is at his finest here, taking every single character he played in the eighties, and making them Martin Blank, a man who appears to be stuck in purgatory, and only the voice on the radio can save him. The script is cracking, the action enough to satisfy any action fan, and the romance for the ladies. All in all, it's the perfect date movie, with endless references to eighties movie (Better Off Dead, and Ghostbusters for example) and one of the best soundtracks for a film ever. Do not miss this movie, especially if you have fond memories of the decade that fashion forgot.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Deep, Rough and Charmingly Hilarious
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Sean Lamberger
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Much funnier than I'd remembered, this twisting tale of competing hit men and their uncharacteristically jovial attempts to rid the world of one other also finds the time to address the loss of innocence, the reflections of a milestone high school reunion and the baggage of leading a necessarily isolated lifestyle. John Cusack is fantastic as the acidic, sarcastic prodigal son, returning to his home town on business while also giving serious thought to abandoning his violent ways for good. Great supporting work helps that role to flower even further, especially in the forms of his grinning, kill-happy competition, (a joyously nasty dark turn by Dan Aykroyd) the jilted love interest he left high and dry ten years back (Minnie Driver at her most smokin') and his flippant, hard-nosed assistant (Joan Cusack). One of the greatest soundtracks ever, plus work on the original score by former Clash frontman Joe Strummer, takes this whole package over the top. Strongly recommended.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Dialog Funnier Than Plot
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    leonlouisricci
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This Black Comedy has its moments. There are a number of Funny Lines but the Comedic Situations don't fare as well. For example, the totally banal Radio Station Scene, the Real Estate Piece just lies there without Wit and there are others, especially the whole Romantic Subplot with Near Zero Chemistry. The Action and the Violence are much better. These are done with an intensity and Style befitting the Movie's Conceit, especially the Finale and the short but incredible Hand to Hand confrontation in the Halls of the High School that is High Style. The Movie works most of the time but when it doesn't the thing screams to a halt and exposes itself as ill fitted and overplayed. Like the Convenience Store Set-Piece or the Mother and Child Reunion. Overall this is Overrated but still a better than Average work that is well done if you can accept some pretty Bad Acting from Sister Cusack and Minnie Driver. Both do some unwatchable Overreaching. But the rest of the Cast is Fine and some of the Writing is Clever and Cool, but beware that in spots this shows some pretty glaring Missteps. The Movie initially Flopped but has gained some Cult recognition for its irreverent Subject Matter and attempts at Ultra-Hipness. One final Blow, the Clash was an Important Group, but here the Joe Strummer Music is way overdone and the whole Soundtrack is surprisingly Anemic considering that it is in your Face (Ears) so intrusively. The White-Bread Reggae is embarrassing, thankfully it includes Johnny Nash's Seminal Chart-Topper for some redemption.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Funny, cool '90s movie with a fantastic fight scene
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Mike Bloxham
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A sharp and witty romantic comedy with some really excellent dialogue. I'm not normally a big fan of Cusack but he is perfect in the role of Martin Blank. Minnie Driver looks beautiful and does a great job. Some uneven parts, the ending isn't amazing. My favourite part was the fight at the reunion dance, it's just brilliantly executed, one of the most exciting fights I've seen committed to film. Maybe it's because you actually see John Cusack throwing high kicks and not some stuntman filmed from behind, there is a very authentic feel to it. Martin Blank is wandering through the corridors of his high school, he's just shared a kiss with Driver, he comes across his old locker, jimmies it open and finds a ten year old spliff he stashed there. He smiles and crumbles the flaky joint, dreamy with nostalgia and the possibilities of life, happier than he's been in years. A hit-man steps around the corner, Blank's reaction is instantaneous, instinctive, he gets in the first blow before the enemy has even raised his gun and in the blink of an eye the two killers are fighting to the death. It's just an outstanding scene.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Thriller With Something For Everyone
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    seymourblack-1
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    With its offbeat combination of comedy, romance and action, "Grosse Pointe Blank" is a highly entertaining thriller that has something for everyone. Its plot is unpredictable, its characters are wonderfully eccentric and its dialogue is sharp and witty. It's also full of terrific performances and boasts a nostalgic 1980s soundtrack that provides an enjoyable accompaniment to all the craziness that takes place on-screen. Martin Q Blank (John Cusack) is a very successful hit-man who's going through an existential crisis and to make matters worse, his most recent assignment didn't go according to plan. On the advice of his therapist and his secretary, he's persuaded to attend his 10-year high school reunion in the town of Grosse Pointe, Michigan so that he can reconnect with his past, in the hope that doing so, might help to improve his current state of mind. Conveniently, he also has a professional reason for returning to his home town as he has another contract to fulfil for the same client he so recently disappointed. The first person that Martin looks up in Grosse Pointe is his high school sweetheart Debi (Minnie Driver) who's now a DJ on the local radio station. Martin had disappeared out of her life without explanation on the night when they'd arranged to go to the school prom together, but by his own admission, she'd remained in his thoughts and dreams ever since. He openly admits that he's now a professional hit-man but she naturally takes this remark as a joke. Some factors linked to his current line of work make Martin's visit to Grosse Pointe a little more complicated and dangerous than Debi could possibly imagine as, not only is he being followed by two operatives from the National Security Agency, but also a couple of independent hit-men called Grocer (Dan Aykroyd) and Felix LePoubelle (Benny Urquidez) are on his tail and looking for trouble. Martin and Debi go to the high school reunion and meet a number of their old classmates, but when Martin wanders away from the main hall into a quiet corridor, LePoubelle attacks him and Martin, without hesitation, kills his assailant. Debi soon arrives on the scene and then, in a state of shock and panic, runs away. Another of Martin's old classmates Paul Spericki (Jeremy Piven) arrives shortly after and helps Martin to dispose of the body in the school furnace. Further difficulties follow for Martin in his dealings with Debi and Grocer and even his professional assignment proves to be far from straightforward. A great deal of danger and numerous surprises then also have to be confronted as Martin tries again to reconcile with Debi and attempts to get out of Grosse Pointe alive. John Cusack is very likable and funny as a guy whose career started in the Army and then took a number of unexpected twists that eventually brought him to a point in his life where he began to feel lost and unfulfilled. His talent for comedy is really impressive and he's also faultless in the action sequences. Alan Arkin is fantastic as Martin's terrified shrink and Joan Cusack is marvellous as his very intense secretary. Dan Aykroyd excels as Martin's greatest professional rival and Minnie Driver is effective in showing the chemistry that still exists between her and Martin as well as the bitterness she continues to feel about the way he abandoned her a decade before. "Grosse Pointe Blank" is a real one-off with numerous laugh-out-loud moments and is also highly recommended.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Hits the target but misses the bull's eye - 73%
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Benjamin Cox
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This has been on my radar since it was released and at last, I can cross it off. I like John Cusack as an actor (though I'll forget about "2012" for the purposes of this argument!) and this had all the feel of a smart-aleck comic thriller that normally appeals to me. And it does but something's missing. It has witty dialogue, genuine laughs, an amazing soundtrack and surprisingly decent action but by being a jack-of-all-trades, it ends up a master of none. However, this is still worth your attention simply by being a little different from the usual Hollywood film about hit men. Cusack plays Martin Blank, an experienced professional killer who finds himself beginning to question his career choice. After turning down an offer to join an assassin's union led by his rival Grocer (Dan Aykroyd), Blank is contacted by his broker (Joan Cusack) with an odd proposition - his ten year high school reunion is taking place in Grosse Pointe, Michigan at the same time as a job is required in Detroit. Reluctantly, Martin agrees while thinking he can make amends with Debi (Minnie Driver), the girl he stood up at the prom ten years ago. But Blank has other concerns - he is pursued to Grosse Pointe by a couple of feds (Hank Azaria and K. Todd Freeman), another hit-man wanting to collect the price on Blank's head (Benny Urquidez) and Grocer who doesn't take too kindly to rejection... If you're not sure what to make of "Grosse Pointe Blank" then you're not alone - the film veers wildly from energetic action thriller to romantic comedy which, if I'm honest, slowed the film down something chronic. Cusack and Driver are a good couple though, with real chemistry between them that sparkles on screen. But as Blank's two worlds begin to collide, things seriously begin to unravel in the film. Take the moment when Blank is forced to rely on his school buddy Paul (Jeremy Piven) to dispose of a body - at no point does Paul react with horror the way I suspect I might, nor does he question the scenario at all. It's a shame because there is much to like - Aykroyd is brilliantly psychotic as Grocer while the film's blistering soundtrack (by Joe Strummer of The Clash, of all people) is a real winner as well. There are also lots of references to other movies from "You Only Live Twice" to "The Warriors" which help the movie barrel along. "Grosse Pointe Blank" is a good film but I wanted something more. It isn't as original as it thinks it is and its split personality prevents the film from being a great action film. The romantic subplot works as well as the action scenes which are full of noise, fire and debris flying about the place. I also felt Alan Arkin was underused as Blank's long-suffering therapist and that more could have been made of the premise. A hit-man suffering a crisis of confidence has been covered before in many movies but I doubt that a high school reunion dance featured in any of them. I can just about recommend "Grosse Pointe Blank" simply by being a little different from other hit-man-related films out there. At least it's not anything as adrenaline-fuelled as "Hitman" or "Assassins" - both of which were disappointingly one-dimensional action outings - but it has a depth to it that I can appreciate. I just wished that it was a bit braver in the script and that it was as clever as it thinks it is.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Relaxing fun
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    hedin_88
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Rarely does a movie entertain, make you laugh, keep you hooked with lovable characters and on top if it all, it relaxes. I've watched it a long time ago and it stuck with me, somewhere in the back of my head and i decided to give it another view just now. This movie is simple so you're gonna love it after a hard day just to ease your mind and relax. The characters are simple people who have their past and present explored and who find themselves in the process. Its not about issues and unresolved problems, drama and pain. There is no place for that in this kind of filming. Its up there with Mumford, another movie i liked which shares the traits- a movie made to ease your mind and feel good after watching it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    It just gets better with each viewing
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ryansassy1
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    When I first saw GPB in the '90s I was impressed enough to buy the soundtrack. Now, after having watched it about a ten times in as many years on cable, I realized how stupid it was not to have bought the DVD already. The upside to that is that now there's blu-ray and hopefully, a few extras included..? Well it will be a real sin if that turns out not to be the case! Sorry, I can't help myself. This film is fantastic, in my Top 5 list of '90s films for certain. John Cusack reportedly co-wrote the script, and that makes sense because it's clever and built on witty dialog -- playing perfectly to his strengths. His electrifying chemistry with Minnie Driver, Dan Ackroyd and what the heck, the entire supporting cast, demonstrates pure casting genius and ensures GPB will remain fresh and memorable upon many repeat viewings. The plot reads like an understated Quentin Tarrantino joint. Martin Blank is a professional assassin who is invited to his 10 year High School reunion in Grosse Pointe, MI. Urged by his therapist on the premise that it might be good for him, he decides to attend. Martin contacts old buddies, attempts to reconnect with his long-lost love, reminisces a bit about his childhood, visits his ailing mom in her nursing home, and what the heck--decides to complete an "assignment" while he's there. He runs into a few glitches on his journey of the soul, but exploding convenience stores and murderous rival assassins can't deflect Martin' growing moral conscience and his determination to win back the girl he stood up on Prom night. Grosse Pointe Blank is hard to pin down. This is a black comedy, but strangely uplifting at the same time. It has plenty of shooting action, martial arts and a dash of James Bond coolness, but it's not about that, really; it asks deeper philosophical questions of the sanctity of life and the power of love and forgiveness. And of course at the heart of it all, there's the relatable conundrum of those torturous High School Reunions. GPB is John Cusack, Minnie Driver, Dan Ackroyd and Joan Cusack at the top of their forms. It also features some of the best tracks from the musical talent of the '80s. If you are a fan of any of theirs, it is a must-see.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    All hail the 0.9%
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    cmoyton
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/9/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    .....who voted this sacred cow a score of one. Ugggggh. Words almost fail me. I'm sick too of all the word play and puns around the film title. How it is so funny and quirky. A perfect light blend of action, comedy and romance. Wrong. This is exactly the type of movie that upper storey hotel rooms were made for so that you can throw the TV out the window. Normally i like Cusack. He is a fine, versatile actor who has done his fair share of comedy and romance. Alas he lapses into the aura of smugness and self congratulation that oozes throughout the length of the film. Stupid can be good like Dumb and Dumber. Even Burn After Reading which was a second rate Coen brothers effort. But when stupid is just stupid, it's stupid.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Good Movie With A Different Storyline,
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Dillon Harris
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Grosse Pointe Blank is a good movie with a good,albeit different,storyline,a good cast and some good twists to it too.I've never been a huge fan of John Cusack,but I did appreciate his role as Martin Q. Blank in this.I really enjoyed Dan Aykroyds role as Grocer and Hank Azaria as Steven Lardner,because I've always been a big fan of the two of them,Dan Aykroyd for great comedy films he wrote and starred in such as Ghostbusters and The Blues Brothers,and Hank Azaria because of his many voice roles on The Simpsons.They could have gotten a much more attractive female lead for this movie,no offense on her,but Minnie Driver is not good looking,someone like Cameron Diaz would have been much better for the role of Debi Newberry. An assassin is sent on a mission to a place called Grosse Pointe,and by an amazing coincidence,it is where his ten year high school reunion is taking place at the same time.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Mirror in the bathroom.....
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    FlashCallahan
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/3/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Martin Blank is a freelance hit-man who starts to develop a conscience, which causes him to fluff a couple of routine assignments. On the advice of his secretary and his psychiatrist, he attends his 10th year High School reunion in Grosse Pointe, Michigan (a Detroit suburb where he's also contracted to kill someone). Hot on his tail are a couple of over-enthusiastic federal agents, another assassin who wants to kill him, and Grocer, an assassin who wants him to join an Assassin's Union....... If you thought that the wedding singer was a little too sweet for your liking, then this is the perfect antidote to that other Eighties movie of 1997. And while that movie is very good in it's own respect, this is dark, deluded, funny, and most of all, a very touching tale about finding yourself and facing your demons. It's not laugh out loud funny, it can be very deep in scenes, but it takes the rough with the smooth, and for every dark moment, there soon is a piece of music,or line that makes the film a perfect example of cinema today. Cusack is at his finest here, taking every single character he played in the eighties, and making them Martin Blank, a man who appears to be stuck in purgatory, and only the voice on the radio can save him. The script is cracking, the action enough to satisfy any action fan, and the romance for the ladies. All in all, it's the perfect date movie, with endless references to eighties movie (Better Off Dead, and Ghostbusters for example) and one of the best soundtracks for a film ever. Do not miss this movie, especially if you have fond memories of the decade that fashion forgot.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Deep, Rough and Charmingly Hilarious
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Sean Lamberger
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Much funnier than I'd remembered, this twisting tale of competing hit men and their uncharacteristically jovial attempts to rid the world of one other also finds the time to address the loss of innocence, the reflections of a milestone high school reunion and the baggage of leading a necessarily isolated lifestyle. John Cusack is fantastic as the acidic, sarcastic prodigal son, returning to his home town on business while also giving serious thought to abandoning his violent ways for good. Great supporting work helps that role to flower even further, especially in the forms of his grinning, kill-happy competition, (a joyously nasty dark turn by Dan Aykroyd) the jilted love interest he left high and dry ten years back (Minnie Driver at her most smokin') and his flippant, hard-nosed assistant (Joan Cusack). One of the greatest soundtracks ever, plus work on the original score by former Clash frontman Joe Strummer, takes this whole package over the top. Strongly recommended.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Dialog Funnier Than Plot
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    leonlouisricci
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This Black Comedy has its moments. There are a number of Funny Lines but the Comedic Situations don't fare as well. For example, the totally banal Radio Station Scene, the Real Estate Piece just lies there without Wit and there are others, especially the whole Romantic Subplot with Near Zero Chemistry. The Action and the Violence are much better. These are done with an intensity and Style befitting the Movie's Conceit, especially the Finale and the short but incredible Hand to Hand confrontation in the Halls of the High School that is High Style. The Movie works most of the time but when it doesn't the thing screams to a halt and exposes itself as ill fitted and overplayed. Like the Convenience Store Set-Piece or the Mother and Child Reunion. Overall this is Overrated but still a better than Average work that is well done if you can accept some pretty Bad Acting from Sister Cusack and Minnie Driver. Both do some unwatchable Overreaching. But the rest of the Cast is Fine and some of the Writing is Clever and Cool, but beware that in spots this shows some pretty glaring Missteps. The Movie initially Flopped but has gained some Cult recognition for its irreverent Subject Matter and attempts at Ultra-Hipness. One final Blow, the Clash was an Important Group, but here the Joe Strummer Music is way overdone and the whole Soundtrack is surprisingly Anemic considering that it is in your Face (Ears) so intrusively. The White-Bread Reggae is embarrassing, thankfully it includes Johnny Nash's Seminal Chart-Topper for some redemption.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Funny, cool '90s movie with a fantastic fight scene
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Mike Bloxham
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A sharp and witty romantic comedy with some really excellent dialogue. I'm not normally a big fan of Cusack but he is perfect in the role of Martin Blank. Minnie Driver looks beautiful and does a great job. Some uneven parts, the ending isn't amazing. My favourite part was the fight at the reunion dance, it's just brilliantly executed, one of the most exciting fights I've seen committed to film. Maybe it's because you actually see John Cusack throwing high kicks and not some stuntman filmed from behind, there is a very authentic feel to it. Martin Blank is wandering through the corridors of his high school, he's just shared a kiss with Driver, he comes across his old locker, jimmies it open and finds a ten year old spliff he stashed there. He smiles and crumbles the flaky joint, dreamy with nostalgia and the possibilities of life, happier than he's been in years. A hit-man steps around the corner, Blank's reaction is instantaneous, instinctive, he gets in the first blow before the enemy has even raised his gun and in the blink of an eye the two killers are fighting to the death. It's just an outstanding scene.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Thriller With Something For Everyone
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    seymourblack-1
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    With its offbeat combination of comedy, romance and action, "Grosse Pointe Blank" is a highly entertaining thriller that has something for everyone. Its plot is unpredictable, its characters are wonderfully eccentric and its dialogue is sharp and witty. It's also full of terrific performances and boasts a nostalgic 1980s soundtrack that provides an enjoyable accompaniment to all the craziness that takes place on-screen. Martin Q Blank (John Cusack) is a very successful hit-man who's going through an existential crisis and to make matters worse, his most recent assignment didn't go according to plan. On the advice of his therapist and his secretary, he's persuaded to attend his 10-year high school reunion in the town of Grosse Pointe, Michigan so that he can reconnect with his past, in the hope that doing so, might help to improve his current state of mind. Conveniently, he also has a professional reason for returning to his home town as he has another contract to fulfil for the same client he so recently disappointed. The first person that Martin looks up in Grosse Pointe is his high school sweetheart Debi (Minnie Driver) who's now a DJ on the local radio station. Martin had disappeared out of her life without explanation on the night when they'd arranged to go to the school prom together, but by his own admission, she'd remained in his thoughts and dreams ever since. He openly admits that he's now a professional hit-man but she naturally takes this remark as a joke. Some factors linked to his current line of work make Martin's visit to Grosse Pointe a little more complicated and dangerous than Debi could possibly imagine as, not only is he being followed by two operatives from the National Security Agency, but also a couple of independent hit-men called Grocer (Dan Aykroyd) and Felix LePoubelle (Benny Urquidez) are on his tail and looking for trouble. Martin and Debi go to the high school reunion and meet a number of their old classmates, but when Martin wanders away from the main hall into a quiet corridor, LePoubelle attacks him and Martin, without hesitation, kills his assailant. Debi soon arrives on the scene and then, in a state of shock and panic, runs away. Another of Martin's old classmates Paul Spericki (Jeremy Piven) arrives shortly after and helps Martin to dispose of the body in the school furnace. Further difficulties follow for Martin in his dealings with Debi and Grocer and even his professional assignment proves to be far from straightforward. A great deal of danger and numerous surprises then also have to be confronted as Martin tries again to reconcile with Debi and attempts to get out of Grosse Pointe alive. John Cusack is very likable and funny as a guy whose career started in the Army and then took a number of unexpected twists that eventually brought him to a point in his life where he began to feel lost and unfulfilled. His talent for comedy is really impressive and he's also faultless in the action sequences. Alan Arkin is fantastic as Martin's terrified shrink and Joan Cusack is marvellous as his very intense secretary. Dan Aykroyd excels as Martin's greatest professional rival and Minnie Driver is effective in showing the chemistry that still exists between her and Martin as well as the bitterness she continues to feel about the way he abandoned her a decade before. "Grosse Pointe Blank" is a real one-off with numerous laugh-out-loud moments and is also highly recommended.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Hits the target but misses the bull's eye - 73%
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Benjamin Cox
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This has been on my radar since it was released and at last, I can cross it off. I like John Cusack as an actor (though I'll forget about "2012" for the purposes of this argument!) and this had all the feel of a smart-aleck comic thriller that normally appeals to me. And it does but something's missing. It has witty dialogue, genuine laughs, an amazing soundtrack and surprisingly decent action but by being a jack-of-all-trades, it ends up a master of none. However, this is still worth your attention simply by being a little different from the usual Hollywood film about hit men. Cusack plays Martin Blank, an experienced professional killer who finds himself beginning to question his career choice. After turning down an offer to join an assassin's union led by his rival Grocer (Dan Aykroyd), Blank is contacted by his broker (Joan Cusack) with an odd proposition - his ten year high school reunion is taking place in Grosse Pointe, Michigan at the same time as a job is required in Detroit. Reluctantly, Martin agrees while thinking he can make amends with Debi (Minnie Driver), the girl he stood up at the prom ten years ago. But Blank has other concerns - he is pursued to Grosse Pointe by a couple of feds (Hank Azaria and K. Todd Freeman), another hit-man wanting to collect the price on Blank's head (Benny Urquidez) and Grocer who doesn't take too kindly to rejection... If you're not sure what to make of "Grosse Pointe Blank" then you're not alone - the film veers wildly from energetic action thriller to romantic comedy which, if I'm honest, slowed the film down something chronic. Cusack and Driver are a good couple though, with real chemistry between them that sparkles on screen. But as Blank's two worlds begin to collide, things seriously begin to unravel in the film. Take the moment when Blank is forced to rely on his school buddy Paul (Jeremy Piven) to dispose of a body - at no point does Paul react with horror the way I suspect I might, nor does he question the scenario at all. It's a shame because there is much to like - Aykroyd is brilliantly psychotic as Grocer while the film's blistering soundtrack (by Joe Strummer of The Clash, of all people) is a real winner as well. There are also lots of references to other movies from "You Only Live Twice" to "The Warriors" which help the movie barrel along. "Grosse Pointe Blank" is a good film but I wanted something more. It isn't as original as it thinks it is and its split personality prevents the film from being a great action film. The romantic subplot works as well as the action scenes which are full of noise, fire and debris flying about the place. I also felt Alan Arkin was underused as Blank's long-suffering therapist and that more could have been made of the premise. A hit-man suffering a crisis of confidence has been covered before in many movies but I doubt that a high school reunion dance featured in any of them. I can just about recommend "Grosse Pointe Blank" simply by being a little different from other hit-man-related films out there. At least it's not anything as adrenaline-fuelled as "Hitman" or "Assassins" - both of which were disappointingly one-dimensional action outings - but it has a depth to it that I can appreciate. I just wished that it was a bit braver in the script and that it was as clever as it thinks it is.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Relaxing fun
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    hedin_88
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Rarely does a movie entertain, make you laugh, keep you hooked with lovable characters and on top if it all, it relaxes. I've watched it a long time ago and it stuck with me, somewhere in the back of my head and i decided to give it another view just now. This movie is simple so you're gonna love it after a hard day just to ease your mind and relax. The characters are simple people who have their past and present explored and who find themselves in the process. Its not about issues and unresolved problems, drama and pain. There is no place for that in this kind of filming. Its up there with Mumford, another movie i liked which shares the traits- a movie made to ease your mind and feel good after watching it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    It just gets better with each viewing
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ryansassy1
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    When I first saw GPB in the '90s I was impressed enough to buy the soundtrack. Now, after having watched it about a ten times in as many years on cable, I realized how stupid it was not to have bought the DVD already. The upside to that is that now there's blu-ray and hopefully, a few extras included..? Well it will be a real sin if that turns out not to be the case! Sorry, I can't help myself. This film is fantastic, in my Top 5 list of '90s films for certain. John Cusack reportedly co-wrote the script, and that makes sense because it's clever and built on witty dialog -- playing perfectly to his strengths. His electrifying chemistry with Minnie Driver, Dan Ackroyd and what the heck, the entire supporting cast, demonstrates pure casting genius and ensures GPB will remain fresh and memorable upon many repeat viewings. The plot reads like an understated Quentin Tarrantino joint. Martin Blank is a professional assassin who is invited to his 10 year High School reunion in Grosse Pointe, MI. Urged by his therapist on the premise that it might be good for him, he decides to attend. Martin contacts old buddies, attempts to reconnect with his long-lost love, reminisces a bit about his childhood, visits his ailing mom in her nursing home, and what the heck--decides to complete an "assignment" while he's there. He runs into a few glitches on his journey of the soul, but exploding convenience stores and murderous rival assassins can't deflect Martin' growing moral conscience and his determination to win back the girl he stood up on Prom night. Grosse Pointe Blank is hard to pin down. This is a black comedy, but strangely uplifting at the same time. It has plenty of shooting action, martial arts and a dash of James Bond coolness, but it's not about that, really; it asks deeper philosophical questions of the sanctity of life and the power of love and forgiveness. And of course at the heart of it all, there's the relatable conundrum of those torturous High School Reunions. GPB is John Cusack, Minnie Driver, Dan Ackroyd and Joan Cusack at the top of their forms. It also features some of the best tracks from the musical talent of the '80s. If you are a fan of any of theirs, it is a must-see.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    All hail the 0.9%
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    cmoyton
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/9/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    .....who voted this sacred cow a score of one. Ugggggh. Words almost fail me. I'm sick too of all the word play and puns around the film title. How it is so funny and quirky. A perfect light blend of action, comedy and romance. Wrong. This is exactly the type of movie that upper storey hotel rooms were made for so that you can throw the TV out the window. Normally i like Cusack. He is a fine, versatile actor who has done his fair share of comedy and romance. Alas he lapses into the aura of smugness and self congratulation that oozes throughout the length of the film. Stupid can be good like Dumb and Dumber. Even Burn After Reading which was a second rate Coen brothers effort. But when stupid is just stupid, it's stupid.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Good Movie With A Different Storyline,
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Dillon Harris
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Grosse Pointe Blank is a good movie with a good,albeit different,storyline,a good cast and some good twists to it too.I've never been a huge fan of John Cusack,but I did appreciate his role as Martin Q. Blank in this.I really enjoyed Dan Aykroyds role as Grocer and Hank Azaria as Steven Lardner,because I've always been a big fan of the two of them,Dan Aykroyd for great comedy films he wrote and starred in such as Ghostbusters and The Blues Brothers,and Hank Azaria because of his many voice roles on The Simpsons.They could have gotten a much more attractive female lead for this movie,no offense on her,but Minnie Driver is not good looking,someone like Cameron Diaz would have been much better for the role of Debi Newberry. An assassin is sent on a mission to a place called Grosse Pointe,and by an amazing coincidence,it is where his ten year high school reunion is taking place at the same time.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Mirror in the bathroom.....
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    FlashCallahan
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/3/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Martin Blank is a freelance hit-man who starts to develop a conscience, which causes him to fluff a couple of routine assignments. On the advice of his secretary and his psychiatrist, he attends his 10th year High School reunion in Grosse Pointe, Michigan (a Detroit suburb where he's also contracted to kill someone). Hot on his tail are a couple of over-enthusiastic federal agents, another assassin who wants to kill him, and Grocer, an assassin who wants him to join an Assassin's Union....... If you thought that the wedding singer was a little too sweet for your liking, then this is the perfect antidote to that other Eighties movie of 1997. And while that movie is very good in it's own respect, this is dark, deluded, funny, and most of all, a very touching tale about finding yourself and facing your demons. It's not laugh out loud funny, it can be very deep in scenes, but it takes the rough with the smooth, and for every dark moment, there soon is a piece of music,or line that makes the film a perfect example of cinema today. Cusack is at his finest here, taking every single character he played in the eighties, and making them Martin Blank, a man who appears to be stuck in purgatory, and only the voice on the radio can save him. The script is cracking, the action enough to satisfy any action fan, and the romance for the ladies. All in all, it's the perfect date movie, with endless references to eighties movie (Better Off Dead, and Ghostbusters for example) and one of the best soundtracks for a film ever. Do not miss this movie, especially if you have fond memories of the decade that fashion forgot.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Deep, Rough and Charmingly Hilarious
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Sean Lamberger
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Much funnier than I'd remembered, this twisting tale of competing hit men and their uncharacteristically jovial attempts to rid the world of one other also finds the time to address the loss of innocence, the reflections of a milestone high school reunion and the baggage of leading a necessarily isolated lifestyle. John Cusack is fantastic as the acidic, sarcastic prodigal son, returning to his home town on business while also giving serious thought to abandoning his violent ways for good. Great supporting work helps that role to flower even further, especially in the forms of his grinning, kill-happy competition, (a joyously nasty dark turn by Dan Aykroyd) the jilted love interest he left high and dry ten years back (Minnie Driver at her most smokin') and his flippant, hard-nosed assistant (Joan Cusack). One of the greatest soundtracks ever, plus work on the original score by former Clash frontman Joe Strummer, takes this whole package over the top. Strongly recommended.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Dialog Funnier Than Plot
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    leonlouisricci
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This Black Comedy has its moments. There are a number of Funny Lines but the Comedic Situations don't fare as well. For example, the totally banal Radio Station Scene, the Real Estate Piece just lies there without Wit and there are others, especially the whole Romantic Subplot with Near Zero Chemistry. The Action and the Violence are much better. These are done with an intensity and Style befitting the Movie's Conceit, especially the Finale and the short but incredible Hand to Hand confrontation in the Halls of the High School that is High Style. The Movie works most of the time but when it doesn't the thing screams to a halt and exposes itself as ill fitted and overplayed. Like the Convenience Store Set-Piece or the Mother and Child Reunion. Overall this is Overrated but still a better than Average work that is well done if you can accept some pretty Bad Acting from Sister Cusack and Minnie Driver. Both do some unwatchable Overreaching. But the rest of the Cast is Fine and some of the Writing is Clever and Cool, but beware that in spots this shows some pretty glaring Missteps. The Movie initially Flopped but has gained some Cult recognition for its irreverent Subject Matter and attempts at Ultra-Hipness. One final Blow, the Clash was an Important Group, but here the Joe Strummer Music is way overdone and the whole Soundtrack is surprisingly Anemic considering that it is in your Face (Ears) so intrusively. The White-Bread Reggae is embarrassing, thankfully it includes Johnny Nash's Seminal Chart-Topper for some redemption.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Funny, cool '90s movie with a fantastic fight scene
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Mike Bloxham
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A sharp and witty romantic comedy with some really excellent dialogue. I'm not normally a big fan of Cusack but he is perfect in the role of Martin Blank. Minnie Driver looks beautiful and does a great job. Some uneven parts, the ending isn't amazing. My favourite part was the fight at the reunion dance, it's just brilliantly executed, one of the most exciting fights I've seen committed to film. Maybe it's because you actually see John Cusack throwing high kicks and not some stuntman filmed from behind, there is a very authentic feel to it. Martin Blank is wandering through the corridors of his high school, he's just shared a kiss with Driver, he comes across his old locker, jimmies it open and finds a ten year old spliff he stashed there. He smiles and crumbles the flaky joint, dreamy with nostalgia and the possibilities of life, happier than he's been in years. A hit-man steps around the corner, Blank's reaction is instantaneous, instinctive, he gets in the first blow before the enemy has even raised his gun and in the blink of an eye the two killers are fighting to the death. It's just an outstanding scene.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Thriller With Something For Everyone
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    seymourblack-1
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    With its offbeat combination of comedy, romance and action, "Grosse Pointe Blank" is a highly entertaining thriller that has something for everyone. Its plot is unpredictable, its characters are wonderfully eccentric and its dialogue is sharp and witty. It's also full of terrific performances and boasts a nostalgic 1980s soundtrack that provides an enjoyable accompaniment to all the craziness that takes place on-screen. Martin Q Blank (John Cusack) is a very successful hit-man who's going through an existential crisis and to make matters worse, his most recent assignment didn't go according to plan. On the advice of his therapist and his secretary, he's persuaded to attend his 10-year high school reunion in the town of Grosse Pointe, Michigan so that he can reconnect with his past, in the hope that doing so, might help to improve his current state of mind. Conveniently, he also has a professional reason for returning to his home town as he has another contract to fulfil for the same client he so recently disappointed. The first person that Martin looks up in Grosse Pointe is his high school sweetheart Debi (Minnie Driver) who's now a DJ on the local radio station. Martin had disappeared out of her life without explanation on the night when they'd arranged to go to the school prom together, but by his own admission, she'd remained in his thoughts and dreams ever since. He openly admits that he's now a professional hit-man but she naturally takes this remark as a joke. Some factors linked to his current line of work make Martin's visit to Grosse Pointe a little more complicated and dangerous than Debi could possibly imagine as, not only is he being followed by two operatives from the National Security Agency, but also a couple of independent hit-men called Grocer (Dan Aykroyd) and Felix LePoubelle (Benny Urquidez) are on his tail and looking for trouble. Martin and Debi go to the high school reunion and meet a number of their old classmates, but when Martin wanders away from the main hall into a quiet corridor, LePoubelle attacks him and Martin, without hesitation, kills his assailant. Debi soon arrives on the scene and then, in a state of shock and panic, runs away. Another of Martin's old classmates Paul Spericki (Jeremy Piven) arrives shortly after and helps Martin to dispose of the body in the school furnace. Further difficulties follow for Martin in his dealings with Debi and Grocer and even his professional assignment proves to be far from straightforward. A great deal of danger and numerous surprises then also have to be confronted as Martin tries again to reconcile with Debi and attempts to get out of Grosse Pointe alive. John Cusack is very likable and funny as a guy whose career started in the Army and then took a number of unexpected twists that eventually brought him to a point in his life where he began to feel lost and unfulfilled. His talent for comedy is really impressive and he's also faultless in the action sequences. Alan Arkin is fantastic as Martin's terrified shrink and Joan Cusack is marvellous as his very intense secretary. Dan Aykroyd excels as Martin's greatest professional rival and Minnie Driver is effective in showing the chemistry that still exists between her and Martin as well as the bitterness she continues to feel about the way he abandoned her a decade before. "Grosse Pointe Blank" is a real one-off with numerous laugh-out-loud moments and is also highly recommended.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Hits the target but misses the bull's eye - 73%
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Benjamin Cox
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This has been on my radar since it was released and at last, I can cross it off. I like John Cusack as an actor (though I'll forget about "2012" for the purposes of this argument!) and this had all the feel of a smart-aleck comic thriller that normally appeals to me. And it does but something's missing. It has witty dialogue, genuine laughs, an amazing soundtrack and surprisingly decent action but by being a jack-of-all-trades, it ends up a master of none. However, this is still worth your attention simply by being a little different from the usual Hollywood film about hit men. Cusack plays Martin Blank, an experienced professional killer who finds himself beginning to question his career choice. After turning down an offer to join an assassin's union led by his rival Grocer (Dan Aykroyd), Blank is contacted by his broker (Joan Cusack) with an odd proposition - his ten year high school reunion is taking place in Grosse Pointe, Michigan at the same time as a job is required in Detroit. Reluctantly, Martin agrees while thinking he can make amends with Debi (Minnie Driver), the girl he stood up at the prom ten years ago. But Blank has other concerns - he is pursued to Grosse Pointe by a couple of feds (Hank Azaria and K. Todd Freeman), another hit-man wanting to collect the price on Blank's head (Benny Urquidez) and Grocer who doesn't take too kindly to rejection... If you're not sure what to make of "Grosse Pointe Blank" then you're not alone - the film veers wildly from energetic action thriller to romantic comedy which, if I'm honest, slowed the film down something chronic. Cusack and Driver are a good couple though, with real chemistry between them that sparkles on screen. But as Blank's two worlds begin to collide, things seriously begin to unravel in the film. Take the moment when Blank is forced to rely on his school buddy Paul (Jeremy Piven) to dispose of a body - at no point does Paul react with horror the way I suspect I might, nor does he question the scenario at all. It's a shame because there is much to like - Aykroyd is brilliantly psychotic as Grocer while the film's blistering soundtrack (by Joe Strummer of The Clash, of all people) is a real winner as well. There are also lots of references to other movies from "You Only Live Twice" to "The Warriors" which help the movie barrel along. "Grosse Pointe Blank" is a good film but I wanted something more. It isn't as original as it thinks it is and its split personality prevents the film from being a great action film. The romantic subplot works as well as the action scenes which are full of noise, fire and debris flying about the place. I also felt Alan Arkin was underused as Blank's long-suffering therapist and that more could have been made of the premise. A hit-man suffering a crisis of confidence has been covered before in many movies but I doubt that a high school reunion dance featured in any of them. I can just about recommend "Grosse Pointe Blank" simply by being a little different from other hit-man-related films out there. At least it's not anything as adrenaline-fuelled as "Hitman" or "Assassins" - both of which were disappointingly one-dimensional action outings - but it has a depth to it that I can appreciate. I just wished that it was a bit braver in the script and that it was as clever as it thinks it is.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Relaxing fun
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    hedin_88
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Rarely does a movie entertain, make you laugh, keep you hooked with lovable characters and on top if it all, it relaxes. I've watched it a long time ago and it stuck with me, somewhere in the back of my head and i decided to give it another view just now. This movie is simple so you're gonna love it after a hard day just to ease your mind and relax. The characters are simple people who have their past and present explored and who find themselves in the process. Its not about issues and unresolved problems, drama and pain. There is no place for that in this kind of filming. Its up there with Mumford, another movie i liked which shares the traits- a movie made to ease your mind and feel good after watching it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    It just gets better with each viewing
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ryansassy1
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    When I first saw GPB in the '90s I was impressed enough to buy the soundtrack. Now, after having watched it about a ten times in as many years on cable, I realized how stupid it was not to have bought the DVD already. The upside to that is that now there's blu-ray and hopefully, a few extras included..? Well it will be a real sin if that turns out not to be the case! Sorry, I can't help myself. This film is fantastic, in my Top 5 list of '90s films for certain. John Cusack reportedly co-wrote the script, and that makes sense because it's clever and built on witty dialog -- playing perfectly to his strengths. His electrifying chemistry with Minnie Driver, Dan Ackroyd and what the heck, the entire supporting cast, demonstrates pure casting genius and ensures GPB will remain fresh and memorable upon many repeat viewings. The plot reads like an understated Quentin Tarrantino joint. Martin Blank is a professional assassin who is invited to his 10 year High School reunion in Grosse Pointe, MI. Urged by his therapist on the premise that it might be good for him, he decides to attend. Martin contacts old buddies, attempts to reconnect with his long-lost love, reminisces a bit about his childhood, visits his ailing mom in her nursing home, and what the heck--decides to complete an "assignment" while he's there. He runs into a few glitches on his journey of the soul, but exploding convenience stores and murderous rival assassins can't deflect Martin' growing moral conscience and his determination to win back the girl he stood up on Prom night. Grosse Pointe Blank is hard to pin down. This is a black comedy, but strangely uplifting at the same time. It has plenty of shooting action, martial arts and a dash of James Bond coolness, but it's not about that, really; it asks deeper philosophical questions of the sanctity of life and the power of love and forgiveness. And of course at the heart of it all, there's the relatable conundrum of those torturous High School Reunions. GPB is John Cusack, Minnie Driver, Dan Ackroyd and Joan Cusack at the top of their forms. It also features some of the best tracks from the musical talent of the '80s. If you are a fan of any of theirs, it is a must-see.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    All hail the 0.9%
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    cmoyton
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/9/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    .....who voted this sacred cow a score of one. Ugggggh. Words almost fail me. I'm sick too of all the word play and puns around the film title. How it is so funny and quirky. A perfect light blend of action, comedy and romance. Wrong. This is exactly the type of movie that upper storey hotel rooms were made for so that you can throw the TV out the window. Normally i like Cusack. He is a fine, versatile actor who has done his fair share of comedy and romance. Alas he lapses into the aura of smugness and self congratulation that oozes throughout the length of the film. Stupid can be good like Dumb and Dumber. Even Burn After Reading which was a second rate Coen brothers effort. But when stupid is just stupid, it's stupid.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Good Movie With A Different Storyline,
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Dillon Harris
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Grosse Pointe Blank is a good movie with a good,albeit different,storyline,a good cast and some good twists to it too.I've never been a huge fan of John Cusack,but I did appreciate his role as Martin Q. Blank in this.I really enjoyed Dan Aykroyds role as Grocer and Hank Azaria as Steven Lardner,because I've always been a big fan of the two of them,Dan Aykroyd for great comedy films he wrote and starred in such as Ghostbusters and The Blues Brothers,and Hank Azaria because of his many voice roles on The Simpsons.They could have gotten a much more attractive female lead for this movie,no offense on her,but Minnie Driver is not good looking,someone like Cameron Diaz would have been much better for the role of Debi Newberry. An assassin is sent on a mission to a place called Grosse Pointe,and by an amazing coincidence,it is where his ten year high school reunion is taking place at the same time.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Mirror in the bathroom.....
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    FlashCallahan
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/3/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Martin Blank is a freelance hit-man who starts to develop a conscience, which causes him to fluff a couple of routine assignments. On the advice of his secretary and his psychiatrist, he attends his 10th year High School reunion in Grosse Pointe, Michigan (a Detroit suburb where he's also contracted to kill someone). Hot on his tail are a couple of over-enthusiastic federal agents, another assassin who wants to kill him, and Grocer, an assassin who wants him to join an Assassin's Union....... If you thought that the wedding singer was a little too sweet for your liking, then this is the perfect antidote to that other Eighties movie of 1997. And while that movie is very good in it's own respect, this is dark, deluded, funny, and most of all, a very touching tale about finding yourself and facing your demons. It's not laugh out loud funny, it can be very deep in scenes, but it takes the rough with the smooth, and for every dark moment, there soon is a piece of music,or line that makes the film a perfect example of cinema today. Cusack is at his finest here, taking every single character he played in the eighties, and making them Martin Blank, a man who appears to be stuck in purgatory, and only the voice on the radio can save him. The script is cracking, the action enough to satisfy any action fan, and the romance for the ladies. All in all, it's the perfect date movie, with endless references to eighties movie (Better Off Dead, and Ghostbusters for example) and one of the best soundtracks for a film ever. Do not miss this movie, especially if you have fond memories of the decade that fashion forgot.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Deep, Rough and Charmingly Hilarious
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Sean Lamberger
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Much funnier than I'd remembered, this twisting tale of competing hit men and their uncharacteristically jovial attempts to rid the world of one other also finds the time to address the loss of innocence, the reflections of a milestone high school reunion and the baggage of leading a necessarily isolated lifestyle. John Cusack is fantastic as the acidic, sarcastic prodigal son, returning to his home town on business while also giving serious thought to abandoning his violent ways for good. Great supporting work helps that role to flower even further, especially in the forms of his grinning, kill-happy competition, (a joyously nasty dark turn by Dan Aykroyd) the jilted love interest he left high and dry ten years back (Minnie Driver at her most smokin') and his flippant, hard-nosed assistant (Joan Cusack). One of the greatest soundtracks ever, plus work on the original score by former Clash frontman Joe Strummer, takes this whole package over the top. Strongly recommended.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Dialog Funnier Than Plot
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    leonlouisricci
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This Black Comedy has its moments. There are a number of Funny Lines but the Comedic Situations don't fare as well. For example, the totally banal Radio Station Scene, the Real Estate Piece just lies there without Wit and there are others, especially the whole Romantic Subplot with Near Zero Chemistry. The Action and the Violence are much better. These are done with an intensity and Style befitting the Movie's Conceit, especially the Finale and the short but incredible Hand to Hand confrontation in the Halls of the High School that is High Style. The Movie works most of the time but when it doesn't the thing screams to a halt and exposes itself as ill fitted and overplayed. Like the Convenience Store Set-Piece or the Mother and Child Reunion. Overall this is Overrated but still a better than Average work that is well done if you can accept some pretty Bad Acting from Sister Cusack and Minnie Driver. Both do some unwatchable Overreaching. But the rest of the Cast is Fine and some of the Writing is Clever and Cool, but beware that in spots this shows some pretty glaring Missteps. The Movie initially Flopped but has gained some Cult recognition for its irreverent Subject Matter and attempts at Ultra-Hipness. One final Blow, the Clash was an Important Group, but here the Joe Strummer Music is way overdone and the whole Soundtrack is surprisingly Anemic considering that it is in your Face (Ears) so intrusively. The White-Bread Reggae is embarrassing, thankfully it includes Johnny Nash's Seminal Chart-Topper for some redemption.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Funny, cool '90s movie with a fantastic fight scene
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Mike Bloxham
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A sharp and witty romantic comedy with some really excellent dialogue. I'm not normally a big fan of Cusack but he is perfect in the role of Martin Blank. Minnie Driver looks beautiful and does a great job. Some uneven parts, the ending isn't amazing. My favourite part was the fight at the reunion dance, it's just brilliantly executed, one of the most exciting fights I've seen committed to film. Maybe it's because you actually see John Cusack throwing high kicks and not some stuntman filmed from behind, there is a very authentic feel to it. Martin Blank is wandering through the corridors of his high school, he's just shared a kiss with Driver, he comes across his old locker, jimmies it open and finds a ten year old spliff he stashed there. He smiles and crumbles the flaky joint, dreamy with nostalgia and the possibilities of life, happier than he's been in years. A hit-man steps around the corner, Blank's reaction is instantaneous, instinctive, he gets in the first blow before the enemy has even raised his gun and in the blink of an eye the two killers are fighting to the death. It's just an outstanding scene.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Thriller With Something For Everyone
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    seymourblack-1
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    With its offbeat combination of comedy, romance and action, "Grosse Pointe Blank" is a highly entertaining thriller that has something for everyone. Its plot is unpredictable, its characters are wonderfully eccentric and its dialogue is sharp and witty. It's also full of terrific performances and boasts a nostalgic 1980s soundtrack that provides an enjoyable accompaniment to all the craziness that takes place on-screen. Martin Q Blank (John Cusack) is a very successful hit-man who's going through an existential crisis and to make matters worse, his most recent assignment didn't go according to plan. On the advice of his therapist and his secretary, he's persuaded to attend his 10-year high school reunion in the town of Grosse Pointe, Michigan so that he can reconnect with his past, in the hope that doing so, might help to improve his current state of mind. Conveniently, he also has a professional reason for returning to his home town as he has another contract to fulfil for the same client he so recently disappointed. The first person that Martin looks up in Grosse Pointe is his high school sweetheart Debi (Minnie Driver) who's now a DJ on the local radio station. Martin had disappeared out of her life without explanation on the night when they'd arranged to go to the school prom together, but by his own admission, she'd remained in his thoughts and dreams ever since. He openly admits that he's now a professional hit-man but she naturally takes this remark as a joke. Some factors linked to his current line of work make Martin's visit to Grosse Pointe a little more complicated and dangerous than Debi could possibly imagine as, not only is he being followed by two operatives from the National Security Agency, but also a couple of independent hit-men called Grocer (Dan Aykroyd) and Felix LePoubelle (Benny Urquidez) are on his tail and looking for trouble. Martin and Debi go to the high school reunion and meet a number of their old classmates, but when Martin wanders away from the main hall into a quiet corridor, LePoubelle attacks him and Martin, without hesitation, kills his assailant. Debi soon arrives on the scene and then, in a state of shock and panic, runs away. Another of Martin's old classmates Paul Spericki (Jeremy Piven) arrives shortly after and helps Martin to dispose of the body in the school furnace. Further difficulties follow for Martin in his dealings with Debi and Grocer and even his professional assignment proves to be far from straightforward. A great deal of danger and numerous surprises then also have to be confronted as Martin tries again to reconcile with Debi and attempts to get out of Grosse Pointe alive. John Cusack is very likable and funny as a guy whose career started in the Army and then took a number of unexpected twists that eventually brought him to a point in his life where he began to feel lost and unfulfilled. His talent for comedy is really impressive and he's also faultless in the action sequences. Alan Arkin is fantastic as Martin's terrified shrink and Joan Cusack is marvellous as his very intense secretary. Dan Aykroyd excels as Martin's greatest professional rival and Minnie Driver is effective in showing the chemistry that still exists between her and Martin as well as the bitterness she continues to feel about the way he abandoned her a decade before. "Grosse Pointe Blank" is a real one-off with numerous laugh-out-loud moments and is also highly recommended.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Hits the target but misses the bull's eye - 73%
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Benjamin Cox
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This has been on my radar since it was released and at last, I can cross it off. I like John Cusack as an actor (though I'll forget about "2012" for the purposes of this argument!) and this had all the feel of a smart-aleck comic thriller that normally appeals to me. And it does but something's missing. It has witty dialogue, genuine laughs, an amazing soundtrack and surprisingly decent action but by being a jack-of-all-trades, it ends up a master of none. However, this is still worth your attention simply by being a little different from the usual Hollywood film about hit men. Cusack plays Martin Blank, an experienced professional killer who finds himself beginning to question his career choice. After turning down an offer to join an assassin's union led by his rival Grocer (Dan Aykroyd), Blank is contacted by his broker (Joan Cusack) with an odd proposition - his ten year high school reunion is taking place in Grosse Pointe, Michigan at the same time as a job is required in Detroit. Reluctantly, Martin agrees while thinking he can make amends with Debi (Minnie Driver), the girl he stood up at the prom ten years ago. But Blank has other concerns - he is pursued to Grosse Pointe by a couple of feds (Hank Azaria and K. Todd Freeman), another hit-man wanting to collect the price on Blank's head (Benny Urquidez) and Grocer who doesn't take too kindly to rejection... If you're not sure what to make of "Grosse Pointe Blank" then you're not alone - the film veers wildly from energetic action thriller to romantic comedy which, if I'm honest, slowed the film down something chronic. Cusack and Driver are a good couple though, with real chemistry between them that sparkles on screen. But as Blank's two worlds begin to collide, things seriously begin to unravel in the film. Take the moment when Blank is forced to rely on his school buddy Paul (Jeremy Piven) to dispose of a body - at no point does Paul react with horror the way I suspect I might, nor does he question the scenario at all. It's a shame because there is much to like - Aykroyd is brilliantly psychotic as Grocer while the film's blistering soundtrack (by Joe Strummer of The Clash, of all people) is a real winner as well. There are also lots of references to other movies from "You Only Live Twice" to "The Warriors" which help the movie barrel along. "Grosse Pointe Blank" is a good film but I wanted something more. It isn't as original as it thinks it is and its split personality prevents the film from being a great action film. The romantic subplot works as well as the action scenes which are full of noise, fire and debris flying about the place. I also felt Alan Arkin was underused as Blank's long-suffering therapist and that more could have been made of the premise. A hit-man suffering a crisis of confidence has been covered before in many movies but I doubt that a high school reunion dance featured in any of them. I can just about recommend "Grosse Pointe Blank" simply by being a little different from other hit-man-related films out there. At least it's not anything as adrenaline-fuelled as "Hitman" or "Assassins" - both of which were disappointingly one-dimensional action outings - but it has a depth to it that I can appreciate. I just wished that it was a bit braver in the script and that it was as clever as it thinks it is.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Relaxing fun
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    hedin_88
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Rarely does a movie entertain, make you laugh, keep you hooked with lovable characters and on top if it all, it relaxes. I've watched it a long time ago and it stuck with me, somewhere in the back of my head and i decided to give it another view just now. This movie is simple so you're gonna love it after a hard day just to ease your mind and relax. The characters are simple people who have their past and present explored and who find themselves in the process. Its not about issues and unresolved problems, drama and pain. There is no place for that in this kind of filming. Its up there with Mumford, another movie i liked which shares the traits- a movie made to ease your mind and feel good after watching it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    It just gets better with each viewing
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ryansassy1
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    When I first saw GPB in the '90s I was impressed enough to buy the soundtrack. Now, after having watched it about a ten times in as many years on cable, I realized how stupid it was not to have bought the DVD already. The upside to that is that now there's blu-ray and hopefully, a few extras included..? Well it will be a real sin if that turns out not to be the case! Sorry, I can't help myself. This film is fantastic, in my Top 5 list of '90s films for certain. John Cusack reportedly co-wrote the script, and that makes sense because it's clever and built on witty dialog -- playing perfectly to his strengths. His electrifying chemistry with Minnie Driver, Dan Ackroyd and what the heck, the entire supporting cast, demonstrates pure casting genius and ensures GPB will remain fresh and memorable upon many repeat viewings. The plot reads like an understated Quentin Tarrantino joint. Martin Blank is a professional assassin who is invited to his 10 year High School reunion in Grosse Pointe, MI. Urged by his therapist on the premise that it might be good for him, he decides to attend. Martin contacts old buddies, attempts to reconnect with his long-lost love, reminisces a bit about his childhood, visits his ailing mom in her nursing home, and what the heck--decides to complete an "assignment" while he's there. He runs into a few glitches on his journey of the soul, but exploding convenience stores and murderous rival assassins can't deflect Martin' growing moral conscience and his determination to win back the girl he stood up on Prom night. Grosse Pointe Blank is hard to pin down. This is a black comedy, but strangely uplifting at the same time. It has plenty of shooting action, martial arts and a dash of James Bond coolness, but it's not about that, really; it asks deeper philosophical questions of the sanctity of life and the power of love and forgiveness. And of course at the heart of it all, there's the relatable conundrum of those torturous High School Reunions. GPB is John Cusack, Minnie Driver, Dan Ackroyd and Joan Cusack at the top of their forms. It also features some of the best tracks from the musical talent of the '80s. If you are a fan of any of theirs, it is a must-see.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    All hail the 0.9%
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    cmoyton
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/9/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    .....who voted this sacred cow a score of one. Ugggggh. Words almost fail me. I'm sick too of all the word play and puns around the film title. How it is so funny and quirky. A perfect light blend of action, comedy and romance. Wrong. This is exactly the type of movie that upper storey hotel rooms were made for so that you can throw the TV out the window. Normally i like Cusack. He is a fine, versatile actor who has done his fair share of comedy and romance. Alas he lapses into the aura of smugness and self congratulation that oozes throughout the length of the film. Stupid can be good like Dumb and Dumber. Even Burn After Reading which was a second rate Coen brothers effort. But when stupid is just stupid, it's stupid.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Good Movie With A Different Storyline,
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Dillon Harris
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Grosse Pointe Blank is a good movie with a good,albeit different,storyline,a good cast and some good twists to it too.I've never been a huge fan of John Cusack,but I did appreciate his role as Martin Q. Blank in this.I really enjoyed Dan Aykroyds role as Grocer and Hank Azaria as Steven Lardner,because I've always been a big fan of the two of them,Dan Aykroyd for great comedy films he wrote and starred in such as Ghostbusters and The Blues Brothers,and Hank Azaria because of his many voice roles on The Simpsons.They could have gotten a much more attractive female lead for this movie,no offense on her,but Minnie Driver is not good looking,someone like Cameron Diaz would have been much better for the role of Debi Newberry. An assassin is sent on a mission to a place called Grosse Pointe,and by an amazing coincidence,it is where his ten year high school reunion is taking place at the same time.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Mirror in the bathroom.....
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    FlashCallahan
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/3/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Martin Blank is a freelance hit-man who starts to develop a conscience, which causes him to fluff a couple of routine assignments. On the advice of his secretary and his psychiatrist, he attends his 10th year High School reunion in Grosse Pointe, Michigan (a Detroit suburb where he's also contracted to kill someone). Hot on his tail are a couple of over-enthusiastic federal agents, another assassin who wants to kill him, and Grocer, an assassin who wants him to join an Assassin's Union....... If you thought that the wedding singer was a little too sweet for your liking, then this is the perfect antidote to that other Eighties movie of 1997. And while that movie is very good in it's own respect, this is dark, deluded, funny, and most of all, a very touching tale about finding yourself and facing your demons. It's not laugh out loud funny, it can be very deep in scenes, but it takes the rough with the smooth, and for every dark moment, there soon is a piece of music,or line that makes the film a perfect example of cinema today. Cusack is at his finest here, taking every single character he played in the eighties, and making them Martin Blank, a man who appears to be stuck in purgatory, and only the voice on the radio can save him. The script is cracking, the action enough to satisfy any action fan, and the romance for the ladies. All in all, it's the perfect date movie, with endless references to eighties movie (Better Off Dead, and Ghostbusters for example) and one of the best soundtracks for a film ever. Do not miss this movie, especially if you have fond memories of the decade that fashion forgot.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Deep, Rough and Charmingly Hilarious
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Sean Lamberger
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Much funnier than I'd remembered, this twisting tale of competing hit men and their uncharacteristically jovial attempts to rid the world of one other also finds the time to address the loss of innocence, the reflections of a milestone high school reunion and the baggage of leading a necessarily isolated lifestyle. John Cusack is fantastic as the acidic, sarcastic prodigal son, returning to his home town on business while also giving serious thought to abandoning his violent ways for good. Great supporting work helps that role to flower even further, especially in the forms of his grinning, kill-happy competition, (a joyously nasty dark turn by Dan Aykroyd) the jilted love interest he left high and dry ten years back (Minnie Driver at her most smokin') and his flippant, hard-nosed assistant (Joan Cusack). One of the greatest soundtracks ever, plus work on the original score by former Clash frontman Joe Strummer, takes this whole package over the top. Strongly recommended.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
 </reviews>
</filme>
