<filme>
 <id>
  25
 </id>
 <imdburl>
  http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0115685
 </imdburl>
 <ano>
  1996
 </ano>
 <titulo>
  The Birdcage - A Gaiola das Loucas
 </titulo>
 <rating>
  6.7
 </rating>
 <sinopse>
  A gay cabaret owner and his drag queen companion agree to put up a false straight front so that their son can introduce them to his fianc&eacute;e's right-wing moralistic parents.
 </sinopse>
 <storyline>
  Armand Goldman owns a popular drag nightclub in South Miami Beach. His long-time lover Albert stars there as Starina. "Their" son Val (actually Armand's by his one heterosexual fling, twenty years before) comes home to announce his engagement to Barbara Keely, daughter of Kevin Keely, US Senator, and vice president of the Committee for Moral Order. The Senator and family descend upon South Beach to meet Val and his father and "mother..." and what ensues is comic chaos.
 </storyline>
 <generos>
  <genero>
   Comedy
  </genero>
 </generos>
 <keywords>
  <keyword>
   senator
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   drag
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   south beach
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   nightclub
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   coalition for moral order
  </keyword>
 </keywords>
 <diretores>
  <diretor>
   Mike Nichols
  </diretor>
 </diretores>
 <escritores>
  <escritor>
   Jean Poiret
  </escritor>
  <escritor>
   Francis Veber
  </escritor>
 </escritores>
 <atores>
  <ator>
   Robin Williams
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Nathan Lane
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Gene Hackman
  </ator>
 </atores>
 <reviews>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Funniest movie I have ever seen
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bluebook-master
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Rarely does a movie cause me to laugh out loud so much as The Birdcage. The cast of characters is extraordinary. The interaction between Gene Hackman and Nathan Lane is priceless. Dan Futterman is not only drop dead gorgeous but his chemistry with Robin Williams is a perfect match. The dinner party reaches a climax with everyone singing "I could have danced all right" with Gene Hackman and Nathan Lane ballroom dancing. The closing scene with Gene Hackman dancing in drag and saying his white dress makes him look fat caused me to cry I was laughing so much. Whoever masterminded this cast of actors knew what they were doing. The film pokes fun at both the absurdity of right wing Republicans and over the top gay men running a nightclub - all humor done very tastefully. For an evening of pure entertainment you've got to see this movies- more than once.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The funniest gay-duo ever, with Robin Williams as the straight-man, so to speak 
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ElMaruecan82
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Traduttore, tradittore" the Italian adage seems to indicate that the transposition of a concept or an artistic creation to another language would inevitably betray its spirit. It's true that most of the times, comedy is the most likely genre to suffer from adaptation and the most eloquent proof can be found in the love-and-hate relationship between French comedies and their much inferior American remakes. Almost every Francis Veber's script for instance, was remade for American audience, and needless to say that some films turns out to be sour disasters, or average entertainments at best. Directed by Mike Nichols, "The Birdcage" is the remake of 'Birds of Feathers' ("La Cage aux Folles"), the greatest Italian-French comedy, starring Ugo Tognazzi and Michel Serrault, and one of the most successful French productions in America. Although it was fair for Nichols to assume that the 1996' audience wouldn't be familiar with the original film, it was risky as well to embrace such a politically incorrect theme, featuring a gay couple with one acting like a hysterical diva, and transpose it in the 90's where the 70's archetypes were no longer held as comedic devices. Needless to say that the performances of the whole cast was crucial, let alone Nathan Lane, who is the highlight of the show. The plot is pure screwball material, Armand (Williams) lives with Albert (Lane) for twenty years, Armand owns a gay burlesque bar in South Florida named "The Birdcage" and directs the very show where Albert stars. Albert acts like a capricious prima donna all the time, always seeming at the edge of a nervous breakdown, praising for attention, he's obviously the "lady" in the couple, and it seems quite fresh to see Williams as the most restrained one, and not let himself carried away by Albert's caprices. The rest of the house also features a Hank Azaria as a Guatemalan butler named Agador, his accent, extraordinary capability to imitate Estefan's "Konga" and some crazy one-liners are really under-appreciated. The routine is broken when Val, Armand's son announces his engagement with the daughter of a republican and notoriously conservative, a Senator named Kevin Keeley (Gene Hackman). Keeley isn't in a better phase because his closest friend and President of the Coalition of Moral Virtues was found dead with an underage black prostitute, a synthesis of every worst- case situation that can undermine a political career. Naturally, his daughter (a pre-McBeal Calista Flockhart) is forced to lie about Armand's profession and Keeley's wife (Dianne Wiest) seize the wedding as an opportunity to clear Keeley from the prejudice caused by the scandal. With these two set-ups, the movie takes off for one of the funniest and most enjoyable recent comedy of errors. Some would naturally get offended by Lane's portrayal of Albert, but the fact is that the film is precisely funny because he's effeminate. It gives its flavor to the scene where he wants to pretend he's Val's uncle, and then learns from Albert how to butter a toast like a man, and not get upset if it gets pierced, and walk like John Wayne. Albert's high pitched screams and overly-gay mannerisms contribute to some of the film's most laugh-out-loud moments and can't take you off totally off-guard, but Lane doesn't overplay them, he finds the right note in an over-the-top personality. And it never shows as well as in the scene where he comes, dressed like a man, only to betray some pink socks, that make even more obvious the fact that he's gay. And that's the basis of the whole comical premise, the more you pretend not to be something, the more it shows. But one thing Lane shows without pretending is how loving and caring he's for Val, and that's what makes his character so endearing and engaging. He's a clown but a sad and funny one, while Williams is the 'straight' man, comically speaking of course, and when a champagne bottle suddenly pops, the effect is immediate, it's pure comedic gold. There are two levels of comedies, where Williams is both the straight man and the clown of a masquerade, no wonder he spent the whole night drinking. Talk about a comical existential nightmare. The secret of "The Birdcage" is to remain faithful to the spirit of the first film, but not without taking some perspective from the original material. The fact that they're Jewish adds another running their name, is it Goldman or Coleman, is the 'd' silent or what? The political undertones are accentuated, maybe because it was before the election campaign, but they seem to be more fitting for the American context, and Gene Hackman is absolutely perfect as the Republican Senator who tries to hide his desperation between a cold facade, he's even more interesting than the original character because the screenplay enriches his personality with his genuine fondness on Albert. And we understand the Senator, Lane plays a drag with such genuine tenderness that we empathize with his desire to help Val. But since we know that it's meant to fail, we can only enjoy the way they keep the Senator believing. And it's indeed funny how Albert touches the Senator's heart when pretending to be Val's mother "they don't make women like that anymore", maybe in a way, Albert fulfilled his all-time dream to be a woman and be treated as well. "The Birdcage" is a film that should have deserved more recognition, less than a remake, it's more of a refreshing and modernization of the 70's version, and it's so lively, so flamboyant, so comical, it seems to reconcile with an idea of the 'gay' culture, that no matter how stereotypical it is, remains more enjoyable than its claim for banality. The style is dated but not the tone. "The Birdcage" deserves all its praises, it's not only one of the few successful American remakes of French comedies, it's more intelligent than what it seems  and it's funny as hell.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    If you don't get this movie, try some more gum
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ironhorse_iv
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I know that look. Hit me, go on. Hit me with why this movie isn't good, because I don't see that face plant of why I should hate this Mike Nichol's film. Yes, it might look like a pale copy of the original La Cage aux Folles, the 1978's French film in itself based on the 1973's play by Jean Poiret, but it's not a drag. Well, it's a drag in another way, but what I like about this remake is how they turns something from French, into a funny American movie. Armand Goldman (Robin Williams) owns a popular drag nightclub in South Miami Beach with his long-time lover Albert Goldman (Nathan Lane). Nathan Lane as Albert is a annoying character with his fits, non-stop complaining and diva like attitude. Some audience members might find the character too irritation to bother with the movie. Some audience members will look past that, due to fact that Albert is so hysterical due to his overreactions to everything. If some people dislike him, they would love the crude humor toward him from Armand. As much as Armand can not stand him, he sticks with Albert. Within the comedy, is a small great speech scene by Armand to Albert. These are two gay men of a certain age, and years of ostracism, threats and taunts would have conditioned them both to avoid any PDAs, no matter how strong the feeling between them. The speech gives the moment enormous poignancy feeling of genuine, heartfelt and caring to Albert. This scene is especially lovely, a great juxtaposition to the rest of the film which is wonderfully silly and comedic. Nathan Lane isn't the only one that nearly steals the movie from Robin Williams, as Armand's maid Agador Spartacus (Hank Azaria) takes a bite of funny throughout the film, with singing and dancing to music, making lousy food, and tripping over his own feet. Watching Agador was a delight, and pans away from Nathan Lane enough times, that we able to rest from his big, brassy yelling and complaining. Soon the Goldman's son Val (Dan Futterman) comes home to announce his engagement to Barbara Keely (Calista Flockhart), daughter of Kevin Keely (Gene Hackman), US Senator, and vice president of the extreme Committee for Moral Order and his wife (Dianne Wiest). First off, the actor Dan Futterman and Calista Flockhart were too old for the role, it felt weird in a way to see Calista play a awkward 18 year old. Both are in later scenes, boozing and smoking. Are we suppose to believe that a conservatism senator would allow his daughter to underage drink? Clearly both are wrong actors for the job. Gene Hackman as Kevin Keely is so extreme right conservatism, it makes the character seem like a political cartoon caricature less than a normal person. Kevin Keely decide to allow Barbara to marry Val only if they meet Val and his family at South Beach and use the marriage to get the media off of the scandal of his co-founder that been focus on him. While in Miami, Val fearing the worst like the Senator will not allow Barbara to marry him. Val tries to convince his father to hide his relationship with Albert and the fact that he is gay and Jewish. At first, Armand stood tall for his right to be open about his sexuality and his religious views, but seeing how much it would mean for him. He allow the dinner to happen, and to make himself seem straight and asking to get rid of Albert for the day was over the line. I just can't stand Dan Futterman's character, for this, what a jerk. First off, Calista's character is clearly old enough to get marry with or without her father permission, and second off, it was the 90's. It wasn't the Leave it to Beaver pre-sexualism freedom 1960's here. I felt it was wrong how Val treats his father to hide who his Father was, ask Albert to leave, all for a girl who only knew for a year. The whole thing was shameful on the part of the character. I know he wasn't in shame of his father's lifestyle, but he knew that Keelys wouldn't understand, and I know without this premise there is no movie, but still he only admit his fault to due to being catch, rather than seeing his wrongs on how he treated his father and Albert the last few days. I also felt the ending was a cop-out, as it's seem like there should had been an extra scene to show how the movie's plot got resolved. Yes it might seem like a bird-brained delight, but you just can't help loving it, and not taking it too serious. The movie acts less like La Cage aux Folles and more like a modern "You can't take it with you", a 1938 film. The music in the film is catchy, love the use of Sister Sledge- We are family, Gloria Estefan- conga, and Alan Lerner- I could have danced all night. It add with the positive good mood of the film. The whole singing scene before dinner was the best. What the movie does well is going beyond the stereotypes to see the character's depth and humanity, and that's why this movie should be check out. Try it, and you will find yourself liking it as much as I do.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not enjoyable
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    WakenPayne
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The main plot of this movie is basically that a gay club owner and his drag queen partner have a son that's getting married. For some reason they pose as being straight (with Nathan Lane in drag posing as his mother) to get the bride's parents approval or giving them the impression that they're straight because the father of the bride has anti-gay political views. I personally found the movie not really that funny at all, full of really bad gay jokes. I don't mind gay jokes (for a fact I have laughed hysterically at a couple over my teenage years) but that is really all this movie has to offer in terms of entertainment. I found the plot to be pointless (but that maybe just who I am). So if you like gay jokes then watch this, but don't really expect anything else.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Delightful Fun
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Jason Shaw
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    ￼ Put simply this is a glitzy, colourful, modern remake of La Cage aux Folles in which Robin Williams stars as the hairy and sweaty Armand, South Beach drag club owner alongside the incomparable Nathan Lane as the star and Armund's lover and partner Albert. Just like the original version, their lives are turned upside down and inside out when Armund's son, Val, comes home to announce he is getting married to an ultra-conservative senator's daughter called Barbara. Everything goes haywire and speeds up to comic high gear when those future in-laws come down to meet their daughters intended and his family. Scandal is what the senator wants to avoid at the great cost, you cannot blame him, and his co-founder of the coalition for moral order partnership has just been found dead in the bed of an underage black prostitute. There are laughs a plenty when first Armund and then Albert try and play it butch, they desperately need a woman and it's so not often you hear a couple of middle aged gay men scream that! In steps the wonderful and delightful Christine Baranski who always lights up the screen with a presence that is electrifying. However, is life that simple, that easy? You bet your sweet little arse it ain't! Barbara tells her parents that Armand is a cultural attach&eacute; to Greece, whilst Albert is a housewife, and that they divide their time between Greece and Florida. It is only a little white lie really, just as changing their last name from Goldman to Coleman is. The evening of the meeting arrives, the apartment above the drag club is transformed from gay paradise to near austere monastery, Val's real mother, Katherine (Baranski) is held up by traffic and a boat and out pops Albert as a wonderful creation of freakishly good yet awfully bad middle-aged mother. Armand and Val are both horrified at first but have no option to go along with the fa&ccedil;ade, which for some bizarre reason in this movie world works. More jokes, no proper meal and the most amazing china dinner service of naked boys playing leap- frog and still the senator and his wife do not catch on. Until that is at the door arrives Katherine, introducing herself as Val's mother and the whole charade is shot to pieces, just as TV news crews arrive out front How on earth can the senator and his wife leave the drag club without some kind of mass scandal erupting and ending his political career? The answer is simple, drag up and we are treated to the wonderful scene of Gene Hackman in a dress making the late great Bea Arthur look as feminine as a virginal princess. It is a great feel good movie, full of lightness, the jokes and funny situation fire by in rapid succession that you will probably not catch them all on the first viewing. Robin William's is superb as the nightclub owner even if he does sweat profusely at times and almost cracks up completely in the kitchen scene with the houseman come butler. I adore Nathan Lane, with his scene stealing 'Starina' performance and utter camp flamboyant majesty. Gene Hackman is equally good as the chocolate addicted extreme right wing senator with his sour face and dry delivery. As a modern re-make of a seventies classic it is both successful and complimentary, it also stands up on its own, which is a jolly good job, and for I am sure, the vast majority of its audience would not have seen La Cage aux Folles. Sure, it is lightweight, sure, it plays a little to stereotype, but it goes beyond them, reaching in to the human side and honest inner core aspect admirably. It is outrageously camp, unashamedly so, blatantly exotic and wonderfully charming, a great feel good movie. Read more and find out where this film made it in the Top 50 Most Influential Gay Movies of All Time book, search on Amazon for Top 50 Most Influential Gay Movies of All Time, or visit - http://www.amazon.co.uk/dp/B007FU7HPO
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    What a Hoot!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Ron-72
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/4/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I saw the original French film in 1979 - it was good, but not all that memorable. I saw the Broadway musical in 1983 - liked "I Am What I Am" and that was about all. But this version is just wonderful, probably because Mike Nichols and Elaine May who've known each other since forever worked on the script and Nichols can direct anything, especially with the cast he has here. They're all great, but Nathan Lane and Hank Azaria steal the show, and I don't think I've ever seen Gene Hackman as funny...I didn't know he could do comedy. What a collection of award-winners we have here, and thoroughly deserving of their SAG award for ensemble work.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not quite there...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    oceansroar
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/3/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Birdcage is a remake of a French film which i might have seen, but was too young, so i will check it soon. i am almost willing to bet that as usual with remakes of foreign films Hollywood fails. Perhaps they should promote the actual original films to the American audience, but i suppose the average American (not an intentional jab at American, since i have seen it around the world) will not watch a subtitled film. The story is about Armand, a gay man (Robin Williams) that owns a drag nightclub, in which his lover (Nathan Lane) performs as the starring act. The couple raised a son together for 20 years. The 20 year old son is now wanting to get married, but there are some complications, which make for a few hilarious moments, but only a few. i love the cast of this film, especially Robin Williams. When he is left to his own devices he can be brilliant or over the top, so he really needs a great director that allows him more room to fly, but a leash to pull him back to our atmosphere. This director held the leash too tightly, so Robin never quite got there. Nathan Lane steals most of the thunder from Robin, but he is a little over the top at times. Hank Azaria is brilliant as Agador the houseman. The cast is great, except Calista Flockhart seems a little drab in this film. If you have not watched it, then i recommended that you see it once, but keep an open mind, after all it is about a gay family. i gave it 5/10 because it does not hold up as well as it did in 1996 and the film as a whole was just not quite there.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of half a dozen verions of La Cage aux Folles out there, and Nathan Lane is devastating
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    secondtake
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/7/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Birdcage (1996) Well, there is always something great about a Mike Nichols film, and this one, written and directed by Nichols, is no exception. It is however a story that has had better presentations (see below) and I'm not sure why Nichols opted for such an un-original material. The movie really is great in some ways, and has terrific moments, but it doesn't transcend, as the best Nichols films certainly do. Robin Williams, the apparent big name on the marquee, is the weakest link in the cast (not including the two young people, who are fine but routine). But the rest of the main actors, Nathan Lane as the drag queen most of all, but Gene Hackman as a conservative senator and Dianne Wiest as his wife, are an amazing ensemble. Throw in consistently funny and clever writing (a functioanl adaptation), good camera-work, obviously attractive sets (this is South Beach in Miami), and a lively soundtrack and you sort of can't go far wrong. Is it brilliant? No way. It doesn't need to be. It's got jokes that will fade with time, topical references and timely jabs, but overall it's just perky and funny top to bottom. And relentlessly. And yes, it pushes its point hard, about how we're all people and relationships are relationships, and that's where the comedy matters, making sure you don't take the delivery too seriously. If you have doubts that it's a farce with a silver lining, just wait until you see Gene Hackman at the end. You might argue that the social message is all that matters, and of course that's true to some ways of thinking (and in some camps of criticism), but that would limit the point of the whole affair. And as time goes on and people get more used to the idea of gay culture and gay people as just another aspect of life, well, the sensational aspects of the movie will water down. But that's fine. Besides being inevitable, it points to the other parts of the film, the Shakespearean cross-dressing, the play on identities, the constant repartee. It's funny and fun and yet smart, too. The plot, at its core, is an Americanized version of the original French play (from 1973) La Cage aux Folles (which means roughly "Cage of Drag Queens" if you take into account the slang for folles). And there is of course the famous two versions of the Broadway musical version (the 1983 and 2004 versions, not to mention the current one which started in 2010). It's a great story with a long life, clearly. And the playful interaction of the ensemble is perfect for the stage. Yet this isn't the play nor the musical, but the film, with a new name. And the photographic aspects are pretty wonderful, too. Take just the opening shot coming in on a helicopter over the water and seamlessly (almost, there's a frame or two glitch) gliding right into the night club, The Birdcage. And if you don't think the story has legs, there is a 1978 Italian version of the play (not the musical) on film. The advantage of the American version for American audiences is the references are still slightly recognizable (the Bob Dole comments are already seeming like history, however). Anyway, don't see this for Robin Williams. He's fine, but not the crackup fast talker that he's best at. And it isn't him, but Nathan Lane, who gets to cross-dress. Fabulously. You'll see.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Birds of a Feather
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    edwardtjbrown
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/5/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    In his younger days, Armand Goldman (Robin Williams) was a struggling, gay stage actor who decided to have a one night stand with a female friend (Christine Baranski). The result of this brief fling was Val Goldman (Futterman), who, in the present day, is engaged to be married to a lovely woman. Despite some initial misgivings that Val is too young to be married, Val's parents, Armand Goldman and his husband Albert, (Nathan Lane), agree to support the wedding. Yet, Barbra Keeley (Calita Rockhart), the bride-to-be, comes from a prominent political family in the middle of a tough re-election campaign. U.S. Senator Keeley, who thinks Bob Dole is too liberal, is the co-founder of a Christian Coalition-type interest group dedicated enacting laws promoting "moral order". He and his wife also feel that their daughter is too young to be married, and want to 'table' the wedding until after the campaign, especially when the head of the Moral Order Coalition is found dead in the bed of an underage, African American, prostitute. Seeing the writing on the wall, Barbara begins a clever ruse to depict the Goldman family as a traditional, white, Christian, Republican family whose politics are to the right of Patrick Buchanan, Jerry Falwell and Pat Roberston. Val convinces his parents to go to great lengths, changing their house, dress, mannerisms, religion and politics, to pull off this charade as the in-laws meet for dinner. As one might guess, much of the comedy in this film involves a 1990's satire of the right-wing politics, as well as the media's post-OJ Simpson trial (1995) obsession with tabloid and scandal driven news. Robin Williams and Nathan Lane are great together, although they show each other little affection, with Lane playing the more stereotypical gay man/drag queen entertainer, which manages to avoid coming off as mean spirited. Likewise, the Keeley are as stuffy as they are right-wing, but the film allows each of the family members to develop a character and story arch beyond simple card board cut outs. Oddly enough, the film does not really address gay rights, beyond the, often comedic, contrasts between the two families and the assumptions that are made. Armand and Albert are financially successful, owners of a hip nightclub. They live in a trendy, upscale urban neighborhood where discrimination and harassment does not seem to exist. Gays serving open in the military and legal recognition of same-sex marriage are mentioned, but Armand and Albert seem to be a couple that exists just slightly out of reality. They do argue over a palimony agreement and I am not sure how the film could have been anything else, given when it was made. In the early - mid 1990s, Hollywood films were just beginning to depict gay people in a manner that did not involve them being predatory, suicidal, homicidal manics. Yes, the film clearly mocks the stuffy, uptight future in-laws. Yes, it mocks their right-wing politics and prejudices directed at gay people as well as racial, religious and ethnic minorities. As great, witty and funny as this film is, sometimes it cannot hide its age.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Funny!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    nama chakravorty
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/2/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A remake of the 1978 film, La Cage aux Folles, 'The Birdcage' is an amusingly enjoyable film. Mike Nichols continues his magic in this 1996 cult-hit, The legendary filmmaker, along-with a stellar cast and a freaky screenplay, makes a truly funny film about everything gone haywire! 'The Birdcage' is about a gay cabaret owner and his drag queen companion agree to put up a false straight front so that their son can introduce them to his fianc&eacute;'s right-wing moralistic parents. Source taken from IMDb! To be honest, the film begins tepidly and it takes time to grasp each and every character's intentions and further plans. But once you get into the groove, you enter a joyride. The entire last hour, right after Gene Hackman & Co enter Williams house, there is hardly a moment when you don't laugh. Also, watching Gene Hackman as a drag in the climax, is simply hilarious! Mike Nichols directs the film with his usual midas touch. He is amongst the most talented filmmakers ever. The adapted Screenplay is full of absurd, funny, hilarious & strange situations. Cinematography by Emmanuel Lubezki is perfect. Editing could've been sharper. Now to the performances! With such a stellar cast coming under one roof, one expects nothing but exemplary acting. Each and Every Actor delivers in here. Robin Williams, Gene Hackman, Nathan Lane & Dianne Wiest are absolutely flawless. Dan Futterman, Calista Flockhart & Hank Azaria are at par with the seniors! On the whole, A Comedy that needs a watch. An absurd yet lovable experience! Thumbs Up!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Funniest movie I have ever seen
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bluebook-master
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Rarely does a movie cause me to laugh out loud so much as The Birdcage. The cast of characters is extraordinary. The interaction between Gene Hackman and Nathan Lane is priceless. Dan Futterman is not only drop dead gorgeous but his chemistry with Robin Williams is a perfect match. The dinner party reaches a climax with everyone singing "I could have danced all right" with Gene Hackman and Nathan Lane ballroom dancing. The closing scene with Gene Hackman dancing in drag and saying his white dress makes him look fat caused me to cry I was laughing so much. Whoever masterminded this cast of actors knew what they were doing. The film pokes fun at both the absurdity of right wing Republicans and over the top gay men running a nightclub - all humor done very tastefully. For an evening of pure entertainment you've got to see this movies- more than once.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The funniest gay-duo ever, with Robin Williams as the straight-man, so to speak 
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ElMaruecan82
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Traduttore, tradittore" the Italian adage seems to indicate that the transposition of a concept or an artistic creation to another language would inevitably betray its spirit. It's true that most of the times, comedy is the most likely genre to suffer from adaptation and the most eloquent proof can be found in the love-and-hate relationship between French comedies and their much inferior American remakes. Almost every Francis Veber's script for instance, was remade for American audience, and needless to say that some films turns out to be sour disasters, or average entertainments at best. Directed by Mike Nichols, "The Birdcage" is the remake of 'Birds of Feathers' ("La Cage aux Folles"), the greatest Italian-French comedy, starring Ugo Tognazzi and Michel Serrault, and one of the most successful French productions in America. Although it was fair for Nichols to assume that the 1996' audience wouldn't be familiar with the original film, it was risky as well to embrace such a politically incorrect theme, featuring a gay couple with one acting like a hysterical diva, and transpose it in the 90's where the 70's archetypes were no longer held as comedic devices. Needless to say that the performances of the whole cast was crucial, let alone Nathan Lane, who is the highlight of the show. The plot is pure screwball material, Armand (Williams) lives with Albert (Lane) for twenty years, Armand owns a gay burlesque bar in South Florida named "The Birdcage" and directs the very show where Albert stars. Albert acts like a capricious prima donna all the time, always seeming at the edge of a nervous breakdown, praising for attention, he's obviously the "lady" in the couple, and it seems quite fresh to see Williams as the most restrained one, and not let himself carried away by Albert's caprices. The rest of the house also features a Hank Azaria as a Guatemalan butler named Agador, his accent, extraordinary capability to imitate Estefan's "Konga" and some crazy one-liners are really under-appreciated. The routine is broken when Val, Armand's son announces his engagement with the daughter of a republican and notoriously conservative, a Senator named Kevin Keeley (Gene Hackman). Keeley isn't in a better phase because his closest friend and President of the Coalition of Moral Virtues was found dead with an underage black prostitute, a synthesis of every worst- case situation that can undermine a political career. Naturally, his daughter (a pre-McBeal Calista Flockhart) is forced to lie about Armand's profession and Keeley's wife (Dianne Wiest) seize the wedding as an opportunity to clear Keeley from the prejudice caused by the scandal. With these two set-ups, the movie takes off for one of the funniest and most enjoyable recent comedy of errors. Some would naturally get offended by Lane's portrayal of Albert, but the fact is that the film is precisely funny because he's effeminate. It gives its flavor to the scene where he wants to pretend he's Val's uncle, and then learns from Albert how to butter a toast like a man, and not get upset if it gets pierced, and walk like John Wayne. Albert's high pitched screams and overly-gay mannerisms contribute to some of the film's most laugh-out-loud moments and can't take you off totally off-guard, but Lane doesn't overplay them, he finds the right note in an over-the-top personality. And it never shows as well as in the scene where he comes, dressed like a man, only to betray some pink socks, that make even more obvious the fact that he's gay. And that's the basis of the whole comical premise, the more you pretend not to be something, the more it shows. But one thing Lane shows without pretending is how loving and caring he's for Val, and that's what makes his character so endearing and engaging. He's a clown but a sad and funny one, while Williams is the 'straight' man, comically speaking of course, and when a champagne bottle suddenly pops, the effect is immediate, it's pure comedic gold. There are two levels of comedies, where Williams is both the straight man and the clown of a masquerade, no wonder he spent the whole night drinking. Talk about a comical existential nightmare. The secret of "The Birdcage" is to remain faithful to the spirit of the first film, but not without taking some perspective from the original material. The fact that they're Jewish adds another running their name, is it Goldman or Coleman, is the 'd' silent or what? The political undertones are accentuated, maybe because it was before the election campaign, but they seem to be more fitting for the American context, and Gene Hackman is absolutely perfect as the Republican Senator who tries to hide his desperation between a cold facade, he's even more interesting than the original character because the screenplay enriches his personality with his genuine fondness on Albert. And we understand the Senator, Lane plays a drag with such genuine tenderness that we empathize with his desire to help Val. But since we know that it's meant to fail, we can only enjoy the way they keep the Senator believing. And it's indeed funny how Albert touches the Senator's heart when pretending to be Val's mother "they don't make women like that anymore", maybe in a way, Albert fulfilled his all-time dream to be a woman and be treated as well. "The Birdcage" is a film that should have deserved more recognition, less than a remake, it's more of a refreshing and modernization of the 70's version, and it's so lively, so flamboyant, so comical, it seems to reconcile with an idea of the 'gay' culture, that no matter how stereotypical it is, remains more enjoyable than its claim for banality. The style is dated but not the tone. "The Birdcage" deserves all its praises, it's not only one of the few successful American remakes of French comedies, it's more intelligent than what it seems  and it's funny as hell.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    If you don't get this movie, try some more gum
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ironhorse_iv
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I know that look. Hit me, go on. Hit me with why this movie isn't good, because I don't see that face plant of why I should hate this Mike Nichol's film. Yes, it might look like a pale copy of the original La Cage aux Folles, the 1978's French film in itself based on the 1973's play by Jean Poiret, but it's not a drag. Well, it's a drag in another way, but what I like about this remake is how they turns something from French, into a funny American movie. Armand Goldman (Robin Williams) owns a popular drag nightclub in South Miami Beach with his long-time lover Albert Goldman (Nathan Lane). Nathan Lane as Albert is a annoying character with his fits, non-stop complaining and diva like attitude. Some audience members might find the character too irritation to bother with the movie. Some audience members will look past that, due to fact that Albert is so hysterical due to his overreactions to everything. If some people dislike him, they would love the crude humor toward him from Armand. As much as Armand can not stand him, he sticks with Albert. Within the comedy, is a small great speech scene by Armand to Albert. These are two gay men of a certain age, and years of ostracism, threats and taunts would have conditioned them both to avoid any PDAs, no matter how strong the feeling between them. The speech gives the moment enormous poignancy feeling of genuine, heartfelt and caring to Albert. This scene is especially lovely, a great juxtaposition to the rest of the film which is wonderfully silly and comedic. Nathan Lane isn't the only one that nearly steals the movie from Robin Williams, as Armand's maid Agador Spartacus (Hank Azaria) takes a bite of funny throughout the film, with singing and dancing to music, making lousy food, and tripping over his own feet. Watching Agador was a delight, and pans away from Nathan Lane enough times, that we able to rest from his big, brassy yelling and complaining. Soon the Goldman's son Val (Dan Futterman) comes home to announce his engagement to Barbara Keely (Calista Flockhart), daughter of Kevin Keely (Gene Hackman), US Senator, and vice president of the extreme Committee for Moral Order and his wife (Dianne Wiest). First off, the actor Dan Futterman and Calista Flockhart were too old for the role, it felt weird in a way to see Calista play a awkward 18 year old. Both are in later scenes, boozing and smoking. Are we suppose to believe that a conservatism senator would allow his daughter to underage drink? Clearly both are wrong actors for the job. Gene Hackman as Kevin Keely is so extreme right conservatism, it makes the character seem like a political cartoon caricature less than a normal person. Kevin Keely decide to allow Barbara to marry Val only if they meet Val and his family at South Beach and use the marriage to get the media off of the scandal of his co-founder that been focus on him. While in Miami, Val fearing the worst like the Senator will not allow Barbara to marry him. Val tries to convince his father to hide his relationship with Albert and the fact that he is gay and Jewish. At first, Armand stood tall for his right to be open about his sexuality and his religious views, but seeing how much it would mean for him. He allow the dinner to happen, and to make himself seem straight and asking to get rid of Albert for the day was over the line. I just can't stand Dan Futterman's character, for this, what a jerk. First off, Calista's character is clearly old enough to get marry with or without her father permission, and second off, it was the 90's. It wasn't the Leave it to Beaver pre-sexualism freedom 1960's here. I felt it was wrong how Val treats his father to hide who his Father was, ask Albert to leave, all for a girl who only knew for a year. The whole thing was shameful on the part of the character. I know he wasn't in shame of his father's lifestyle, but he knew that Keelys wouldn't understand, and I know without this premise there is no movie, but still he only admit his fault to due to being catch, rather than seeing his wrongs on how he treated his father and Albert the last few days. I also felt the ending was a cop-out, as it's seem like there should had been an extra scene to show how the movie's plot got resolved. Yes it might seem like a bird-brained delight, but you just can't help loving it, and not taking it too serious. The movie acts less like La Cage aux Folles and more like a modern "You can't take it with you", a 1938 film. The music in the film is catchy, love the use of Sister Sledge- We are family, Gloria Estefan- conga, and Alan Lerner- I could have danced all night. It add with the positive good mood of the film. The whole singing scene before dinner was the best. What the movie does well is going beyond the stereotypes to see the character's depth and humanity, and that's why this movie should be check out. Try it, and you will find yourself liking it as much as I do.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not enjoyable
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    WakenPayne
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The main plot of this movie is basically that a gay club owner and his drag queen partner have a son that's getting married. For some reason they pose as being straight (with Nathan Lane in drag posing as his mother) to get the bride's parents approval or giving them the impression that they're straight because the father of the bride has anti-gay political views. I personally found the movie not really that funny at all, full of really bad gay jokes. I don't mind gay jokes (for a fact I have laughed hysterically at a couple over my teenage years) but that is really all this movie has to offer in terms of entertainment. I found the plot to be pointless (but that maybe just who I am). So if you like gay jokes then watch this, but don't really expect anything else.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Delightful Fun
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Jason Shaw
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    ￼ Put simply this is a glitzy, colourful, modern remake of La Cage aux Folles in which Robin Williams stars as the hairy and sweaty Armand, South Beach drag club owner alongside the incomparable Nathan Lane as the star and Armund's lover and partner Albert. Just like the original version, their lives are turned upside down and inside out when Armund's son, Val, comes home to announce he is getting married to an ultra-conservative senator's daughter called Barbara. Everything goes haywire and speeds up to comic high gear when those future in-laws come down to meet their daughters intended and his family. Scandal is what the senator wants to avoid at the great cost, you cannot blame him, and his co-founder of the coalition for moral order partnership has just been found dead in the bed of an underage black prostitute. There are laughs a plenty when first Armund and then Albert try and play it butch, they desperately need a woman and it's so not often you hear a couple of middle aged gay men scream that! In steps the wonderful and delightful Christine Baranski who always lights up the screen with a presence that is electrifying. However, is life that simple, that easy? You bet your sweet little arse it ain't! Barbara tells her parents that Armand is a cultural attach&eacute; to Greece, whilst Albert is a housewife, and that they divide their time between Greece and Florida. It is only a little white lie really, just as changing their last name from Goldman to Coleman is. The evening of the meeting arrives, the apartment above the drag club is transformed from gay paradise to near austere monastery, Val's real mother, Katherine (Baranski) is held up by traffic and a boat and out pops Albert as a wonderful creation of freakishly good yet awfully bad middle-aged mother. Armand and Val are both horrified at first but have no option to go along with the fa&ccedil;ade, which for some bizarre reason in this movie world works. More jokes, no proper meal and the most amazing china dinner service of naked boys playing leap- frog and still the senator and his wife do not catch on. Until that is at the door arrives Katherine, introducing herself as Val's mother and the whole charade is shot to pieces, just as TV news crews arrive out front How on earth can the senator and his wife leave the drag club without some kind of mass scandal erupting and ending his political career? The answer is simple, drag up and we are treated to the wonderful scene of Gene Hackman in a dress making the late great Bea Arthur look as feminine as a virginal princess. It is a great feel good movie, full of lightness, the jokes and funny situation fire by in rapid succession that you will probably not catch them all on the first viewing. Robin William's is superb as the nightclub owner even if he does sweat profusely at times and almost cracks up completely in the kitchen scene with the houseman come butler. I adore Nathan Lane, with his scene stealing 'Starina' performance and utter camp flamboyant majesty. Gene Hackman is equally good as the chocolate addicted extreme right wing senator with his sour face and dry delivery. As a modern re-make of a seventies classic it is both successful and complimentary, it also stands up on its own, which is a jolly good job, and for I am sure, the vast majority of its audience would not have seen La Cage aux Folles. Sure, it is lightweight, sure, it plays a little to stereotype, but it goes beyond them, reaching in to the human side and honest inner core aspect admirably. It is outrageously camp, unashamedly so, blatantly exotic and wonderfully charming, a great feel good movie. Read more and find out where this film made it in the Top 50 Most Influential Gay Movies of All Time book, search on Amazon for Top 50 Most Influential Gay Movies of All Time, or visit - http://www.amazon.co.uk/dp/B007FU7HPO
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    What a Hoot!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Ron-72
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/4/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I saw the original French film in 1979 - it was good, but not all that memorable. I saw the Broadway musical in 1983 - liked "I Am What I Am" and that was about all. But this version is just wonderful, probably because Mike Nichols and Elaine May who've known each other since forever worked on the script and Nichols can direct anything, especially with the cast he has here. They're all great, but Nathan Lane and Hank Azaria steal the show, and I don't think I've ever seen Gene Hackman as funny...I didn't know he could do comedy. What a collection of award-winners we have here, and thoroughly deserving of their SAG award for ensemble work.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not quite there...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    oceansroar
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/3/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Birdcage is a remake of a French film which i might have seen, but was too young, so i will check it soon. i am almost willing to bet that as usual with remakes of foreign films Hollywood fails. Perhaps they should promote the actual original films to the American audience, but i suppose the average American (not an intentional jab at American, since i have seen it around the world) will not watch a subtitled film. The story is about Armand, a gay man (Robin Williams) that owns a drag nightclub, in which his lover (Nathan Lane) performs as the starring act. The couple raised a son together for 20 years. The 20 year old son is now wanting to get married, but there are some complications, which make for a few hilarious moments, but only a few. i love the cast of this film, especially Robin Williams. When he is left to his own devices he can be brilliant or over the top, so he really needs a great director that allows him more room to fly, but a leash to pull him back to our atmosphere. This director held the leash too tightly, so Robin never quite got there. Nathan Lane steals most of the thunder from Robin, but he is a little over the top at times. Hank Azaria is brilliant as Agador the houseman. The cast is great, except Calista Flockhart seems a little drab in this film. If you have not watched it, then i recommended that you see it once, but keep an open mind, after all it is about a gay family. i gave it 5/10 because it does not hold up as well as it did in 1996 and the film as a whole was just not quite there.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of half a dozen verions of La Cage aux Folles out there, and Nathan Lane is devastating
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    secondtake
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/7/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Birdcage (1996) Well, there is always something great about a Mike Nichols film, and this one, written and directed by Nichols, is no exception. It is however a story that has had better presentations (see below) and I'm not sure why Nichols opted for such an un-original material. The movie really is great in some ways, and has terrific moments, but it doesn't transcend, as the best Nichols films certainly do. Robin Williams, the apparent big name on the marquee, is the weakest link in the cast (not including the two young people, who are fine but routine). But the rest of the main actors, Nathan Lane as the drag queen most of all, but Gene Hackman as a conservative senator and Dianne Wiest as his wife, are an amazing ensemble. Throw in consistently funny and clever writing (a functioanl adaptation), good camera-work, obviously attractive sets (this is South Beach in Miami), and a lively soundtrack and you sort of can't go far wrong. Is it brilliant? No way. It doesn't need to be. It's got jokes that will fade with time, topical references and timely jabs, but overall it's just perky and funny top to bottom. And relentlessly. And yes, it pushes its point hard, about how we're all people and relationships are relationships, and that's where the comedy matters, making sure you don't take the delivery too seriously. If you have doubts that it's a farce with a silver lining, just wait until you see Gene Hackman at the end. You might argue that the social message is all that matters, and of course that's true to some ways of thinking (and in some camps of criticism), but that would limit the point of the whole affair. And as time goes on and people get more used to the idea of gay culture and gay people as just another aspect of life, well, the sensational aspects of the movie will water down. But that's fine. Besides being inevitable, it points to the other parts of the film, the Shakespearean cross-dressing, the play on identities, the constant repartee. It's funny and fun and yet smart, too. The plot, at its core, is an Americanized version of the original French play (from 1973) La Cage aux Folles (which means roughly "Cage of Drag Queens" if you take into account the slang for folles). And there is of course the famous two versions of the Broadway musical version (the 1983 and 2004 versions, not to mention the current one which started in 2010). It's a great story with a long life, clearly. And the playful interaction of the ensemble is perfect for the stage. Yet this isn't the play nor the musical, but the film, with a new name. And the photographic aspects are pretty wonderful, too. Take just the opening shot coming in on a helicopter over the water and seamlessly (almost, there's a frame or two glitch) gliding right into the night club, The Birdcage. And if you don't think the story has legs, there is a 1978 Italian version of the play (not the musical) on film. The advantage of the American version for American audiences is the references are still slightly recognizable (the Bob Dole comments are already seeming like history, however). Anyway, don't see this for Robin Williams. He's fine, but not the crackup fast talker that he's best at. And it isn't him, but Nathan Lane, who gets to cross-dress. Fabulously. You'll see.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Birds of a Feather
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    edwardtjbrown
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/5/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    In his younger days, Armand Goldman (Robin Williams) was a struggling, gay stage actor who decided to have a one night stand with a female friend (Christine Baranski). The result of this brief fling was Val Goldman (Futterman), who, in the present day, is engaged to be married to a lovely woman. Despite some initial misgivings that Val is too young to be married, Val's parents, Armand Goldman and his husband Albert, (Nathan Lane), agree to support the wedding. Yet, Barbra Keeley (Calita Rockhart), the bride-to-be, comes from a prominent political family in the middle of a tough re-election campaign. U.S. Senator Keeley, who thinks Bob Dole is too liberal, is the co-founder of a Christian Coalition-type interest group dedicated enacting laws promoting "moral order". He and his wife also feel that their daughter is too young to be married, and want to 'table' the wedding until after the campaign, especially when the head of the Moral Order Coalition is found dead in the bed of an underage, African American, prostitute. Seeing the writing on the wall, Barbara begins a clever ruse to depict the Goldman family as a traditional, white, Christian, Republican family whose politics are to the right of Patrick Buchanan, Jerry Falwell and Pat Roberston. Val convinces his parents to go to great lengths, changing their house, dress, mannerisms, religion and politics, to pull off this charade as the in-laws meet for dinner. As one might guess, much of the comedy in this film involves a 1990's satire of the right-wing politics, as well as the media's post-OJ Simpson trial (1995) obsession with tabloid and scandal driven news. Robin Williams and Nathan Lane are great together, although they show each other little affection, with Lane playing the more stereotypical gay man/drag queen entertainer, which manages to avoid coming off as mean spirited. Likewise, the Keeley are as stuffy as they are right-wing, but the film allows each of the family members to develop a character and story arch beyond simple card board cut outs. Oddly enough, the film does not really address gay rights, beyond the, often comedic, contrasts between the two families and the assumptions that are made. Armand and Albert are financially successful, owners of a hip nightclub. They live in a trendy, upscale urban neighborhood where discrimination and harassment does not seem to exist. Gays serving open in the military and legal recognition of same-sex marriage are mentioned, but Armand and Albert seem to be a couple that exists just slightly out of reality. They do argue over a palimony agreement and I am not sure how the film could have been anything else, given when it was made. In the early - mid 1990s, Hollywood films were just beginning to depict gay people in a manner that did not involve them being predatory, suicidal, homicidal manics. Yes, the film clearly mocks the stuffy, uptight future in-laws. Yes, it mocks their right-wing politics and prejudices directed at gay people as well as racial, religious and ethnic minorities. As great, witty and funny as this film is, sometimes it cannot hide its age.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Funny!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    nama chakravorty
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/2/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A remake of the 1978 film, La Cage aux Folles, 'The Birdcage' is an amusingly enjoyable film. Mike Nichols continues his magic in this 1996 cult-hit, The legendary filmmaker, along-with a stellar cast and a freaky screenplay, makes a truly funny film about everything gone haywire! 'The Birdcage' is about a gay cabaret owner and his drag queen companion agree to put up a false straight front so that their son can introduce them to his fianc&eacute;'s right-wing moralistic parents. Source taken from IMDb! To be honest, the film begins tepidly and it takes time to grasp each and every character's intentions and further plans. But once you get into the groove, you enter a joyride. The entire last hour, right after Gene Hackman & Co enter Williams house, there is hardly a moment when you don't laugh. Also, watching Gene Hackman as a drag in the climax, is simply hilarious! Mike Nichols directs the film with his usual midas touch. He is amongst the most talented filmmakers ever. The adapted Screenplay is full of absurd, funny, hilarious & strange situations. Cinematography by Emmanuel Lubezki is perfect. Editing could've been sharper. Now to the performances! With such a stellar cast coming under one roof, one expects nothing but exemplary acting. Each and Every Actor delivers in here. Robin Williams, Gene Hackman, Nathan Lane & Dianne Wiest are absolutely flawless. Dan Futterman, Calista Flockhart & Hank Azaria are at par with the seniors! On the whole, A Comedy that needs a watch. An absurd yet lovable experience! Thumbs Up!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Funniest movie I have ever seen
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bluebook-master
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Rarely does a movie cause me to laugh out loud so much as The Birdcage. The cast of characters is extraordinary. The interaction between Gene Hackman and Nathan Lane is priceless. Dan Futterman is not only drop dead gorgeous but his chemistry with Robin Williams is a perfect match. The dinner party reaches a climax with everyone singing "I could have danced all right" with Gene Hackman and Nathan Lane ballroom dancing. The closing scene with Gene Hackman dancing in drag and saying his white dress makes him look fat caused me to cry I was laughing so much. Whoever masterminded this cast of actors knew what they were doing. The film pokes fun at both the absurdity of right wing Republicans and over the top gay men running a nightclub - all humor done very tastefully. For an evening of pure entertainment you've got to see this movies- more than once.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The funniest gay-duo ever, with Robin Williams as the straight-man, so to speak 
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ElMaruecan82
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Traduttore, tradittore" the Italian adage seems to indicate that the transposition of a concept or an artistic creation to another language would inevitably betray its spirit. It's true that most of the times, comedy is the most likely genre to suffer from adaptation and the most eloquent proof can be found in the love-and-hate relationship between French comedies and their much inferior American remakes. Almost every Francis Veber's script for instance, was remade for American audience, and needless to say that some films turns out to be sour disasters, or average entertainments at best. Directed by Mike Nichols, "The Birdcage" is the remake of 'Birds of Feathers' ("La Cage aux Folles"), the greatest Italian-French comedy, starring Ugo Tognazzi and Michel Serrault, and one of the most successful French productions in America. Although it was fair for Nichols to assume that the 1996' audience wouldn't be familiar with the original film, it was risky as well to embrace such a politically incorrect theme, featuring a gay couple with one acting like a hysterical diva, and transpose it in the 90's where the 70's archetypes were no longer held as comedic devices. Needless to say that the performances of the whole cast was crucial, let alone Nathan Lane, who is the highlight of the show. The plot is pure screwball material, Armand (Williams) lives with Albert (Lane) for twenty years, Armand owns a gay burlesque bar in South Florida named "The Birdcage" and directs the very show where Albert stars. Albert acts like a capricious prima donna all the time, always seeming at the edge of a nervous breakdown, praising for attention, he's obviously the "lady" in the couple, and it seems quite fresh to see Williams as the most restrained one, and not let himself carried away by Albert's caprices. The rest of the house also features a Hank Azaria as a Guatemalan butler named Agador, his accent, extraordinary capability to imitate Estefan's "Konga" and some crazy one-liners are really under-appreciated. The routine is broken when Val, Armand's son announces his engagement with the daughter of a republican and notoriously conservative, a Senator named Kevin Keeley (Gene Hackman). Keeley isn't in a better phase because his closest friend and President of the Coalition of Moral Virtues was found dead with an underage black prostitute, a synthesis of every worst- case situation that can undermine a political career. Naturally, his daughter (a pre-McBeal Calista Flockhart) is forced to lie about Armand's profession and Keeley's wife (Dianne Wiest) seize the wedding as an opportunity to clear Keeley from the prejudice caused by the scandal. With these two set-ups, the movie takes off for one of the funniest and most enjoyable recent comedy of errors. Some would naturally get offended by Lane's portrayal of Albert, but the fact is that the film is precisely funny because he's effeminate. It gives its flavor to the scene where he wants to pretend he's Val's uncle, and then learns from Albert how to butter a toast like a man, and not get upset if it gets pierced, and walk like John Wayne. Albert's high pitched screams and overly-gay mannerisms contribute to some of the film's most laugh-out-loud moments and can't take you off totally off-guard, but Lane doesn't overplay them, he finds the right note in an over-the-top personality. And it never shows as well as in the scene where he comes, dressed like a man, only to betray some pink socks, that make even more obvious the fact that he's gay. And that's the basis of the whole comical premise, the more you pretend not to be something, the more it shows. But one thing Lane shows without pretending is how loving and caring he's for Val, and that's what makes his character so endearing and engaging. He's a clown but a sad and funny one, while Williams is the 'straight' man, comically speaking of course, and when a champagne bottle suddenly pops, the effect is immediate, it's pure comedic gold. There are two levels of comedies, where Williams is both the straight man and the clown of a masquerade, no wonder he spent the whole night drinking. Talk about a comical existential nightmare. The secret of "The Birdcage" is to remain faithful to the spirit of the first film, but not without taking some perspective from the original material. The fact that they're Jewish adds another running their name, is it Goldman or Coleman, is the 'd' silent or what? The political undertones are accentuated, maybe because it was before the election campaign, but they seem to be more fitting for the American context, and Gene Hackman is absolutely perfect as the Republican Senator who tries to hide his desperation between a cold facade, he's even more interesting than the original character because the screenplay enriches his personality with his genuine fondness on Albert. And we understand the Senator, Lane plays a drag with such genuine tenderness that we empathize with his desire to help Val. But since we know that it's meant to fail, we can only enjoy the way they keep the Senator believing. And it's indeed funny how Albert touches the Senator's heart when pretending to be Val's mother "they don't make women like that anymore", maybe in a way, Albert fulfilled his all-time dream to be a woman and be treated as well. "The Birdcage" is a film that should have deserved more recognition, less than a remake, it's more of a refreshing and modernization of the 70's version, and it's so lively, so flamboyant, so comical, it seems to reconcile with an idea of the 'gay' culture, that no matter how stereotypical it is, remains more enjoyable than its claim for banality. The style is dated but not the tone. "The Birdcage" deserves all its praises, it's not only one of the few successful American remakes of French comedies, it's more intelligent than what it seems  and it's funny as hell.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    If you don't get this movie, try some more gum
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ironhorse_iv
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I know that look. Hit me, go on. Hit me with why this movie isn't good, because I don't see that face plant of why I should hate this Mike Nichol's film. Yes, it might look like a pale copy of the original La Cage aux Folles, the 1978's French film in itself based on the 1973's play by Jean Poiret, but it's not a drag. Well, it's a drag in another way, but what I like about this remake is how they turns something from French, into a funny American movie. Armand Goldman (Robin Williams) owns a popular drag nightclub in South Miami Beach with his long-time lover Albert Goldman (Nathan Lane). Nathan Lane as Albert is a annoying character with his fits, non-stop complaining and diva like attitude. Some audience members might find the character too irritation to bother with the movie. Some audience members will look past that, due to fact that Albert is so hysterical due to his overreactions to everything. If some people dislike him, they would love the crude humor toward him from Armand. As much as Armand can not stand him, he sticks with Albert. Within the comedy, is a small great speech scene by Armand to Albert. These are two gay men of a certain age, and years of ostracism, threats and taunts would have conditioned them both to avoid any PDAs, no matter how strong the feeling between them. The speech gives the moment enormous poignancy feeling of genuine, heartfelt and caring to Albert. This scene is especially lovely, a great juxtaposition to the rest of the film which is wonderfully silly and comedic. Nathan Lane isn't the only one that nearly steals the movie from Robin Williams, as Armand's maid Agador Spartacus (Hank Azaria) takes a bite of funny throughout the film, with singing and dancing to music, making lousy food, and tripping over his own feet. Watching Agador was a delight, and pans away from Nathan Lane enough times, that we able to rest from his big, brassy yelling and complaining. Soon the Goldman's son Val (Dan Futterman) comes home to announce his engagement to Barbara Keely (Calista Flockhart), daughter of Kevin Keely (Gene Hackman), US Senator, and vice president of the extreme Committee for Moral Order and his wife (Dianne Wiest). First off, the actor Dan Futterman and Calista Flockhart were too old for the role, it felt weird in a way to see Calista play a awkward 18 year old. Both are in later scenes, boozing and smoking. Are we suppose to believe that a conservatism senator would allow his daughter to underage drink? Clearly both are wrong actors for the job. Gene Hackman as Kevin Keely is so extreme right conservatism, it makes the character seem like a political cartoon caricature less than a normal person. Kevin Keely decide to allow Barbara to marry Val only if they meet Val and his family at South Beach and use the marriage to get the media off of the scandal of his co-founder that been focus on him. While in Miami, Val fearing the worst like the Senator will not allow Barbara to marry him. Val tries to convince his father to hide his relationship with Albert and the fact that he is gay and Jewish. At first, Armand stood tall for his right to be open about his sexuality and his religious views, but seeing how much it would mean for him. He allow the dinner to happen, and to make himself seem straight and asking to get rid of Albert for the day was over the line. I just can't stand Dan Futterman's character, for this, what a jerk. First off, Calista's character is clearly old enough to get marry with or without her father permission, and second off, it was the 90's. It wasn't the Leave it to Beaver pre-sexualism freedom 1960's here. I felt it was wrong how Val treats his father to hide who his Father was, ask Albert to leave, all for a girl who only knew for a year. The whole thing was shameful on the part of the character. I know he wasn't in shame of his father's lifestyle, but he knew that Keelys wouldn't understand, and I know without this premise there is no movie, but still he only admit his fault to due to being catch, rather than seeing his wrongs on how he treated his father and Albert the last few days. I also felt the ending was a cop-out, as it's seem like there should had been an extra scene to show how the movie's plot got resolved. Yes it might seem like a bird-brained delight, but you just can't help loving it, and not taking it too serious. The movie acts less like La Cage aux Folles and more like a modern "You can't take it with you", a 1938 film. The music in the film is catchy, love the use of Sister Sledge- We are family, Gloria Estefan- conga, and Alan Lerner- I could have danced all night. It add with the positive good mood of the film. The whole singing scene before dinner was the best. What the movie does well is going beyond the stereotypes to see the character's depth and humanity, and that's why this movie should be check out. Try it, and you will find yourself liking it as much as I do.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not enjoyable
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    WakenPayne
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The main plot of this movie is basically that a gay club owner and his drag queen partner have a son that's getting married. For some reason they pose as being straight (with Nathan Lane in drag posing as his mother) to get the bride's parents approval or giving them the impression that they're straight because the father of the bride has anti-gay political views. I personally found the movie not really that funny at all, full of really bad gay jokes. I don't mind gay jokes (for a fact I have laughed hysterically at a couple over my teenage years) but that is really all this movie has to offer in terms of entertainment. I found the plot to be pointless (but that maybe just who I am). So if you like gay jokes then watch this, but don't really expect anything else.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Delightful Fun
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Jason Shaw
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    ￼ Put simply this is a glitzy, colourful, modern remake of La Cage aux Folles in which Robin Williams stars as the hairy and sweaty Armand, South Beach drag club owner alongside the incomparable Nathan Lane as the star and Armund's lover and partner Albert. Just like the original version, their lives are turned upside down and inside out when Armund's son, Val, comes home to announce he is getting married to an ultra-conservative senator's daughter called Barbara. Everything goes haywire and speeds up to comic high gear when those future in-laws come down to meet their daughters intended and his family. Scandal is what the senator wants to avoid at the great cost, you cannot blame him, and his co-founder of the coalition for moral order partnership has just been found dead in the bed of an underage black prostitute. There are laughs a plenty when first Armund and then Albert try and play it butch, they desperately need a woman and it's so not often you hear a couple of middle aged gay men scream that! In steps the wonderful and delightful Christine Baranski who always lights up the screen with a presence that is electrifying. However, is life that simple, that easy? You bet your sweet little arse it ain't! Barbara tells her parents that Armand is a cultural attach&eacute; to Greece, whilst Albert is a housewife, and that they divide their time between Greece and Florida. It is only a little white lie really, just as changing their last name from Goldman to Coleman is. The evening of the meeting arrives, the apartment above the drag club is transformed from gay paradise to near austere monastery, Val's real mother, Katherine (Baranski) is held up by traffic and a boat and out pops Albert as a wonderful creation of freakishly good yet awfully bad middle-aged mother. Armand and Val are both horrified at first but have no option to go along with the fa&ccedil;ade, which for some bizarre reason in this movie world works. More jokes, no proper meal and the most amazing china dinner service of naked boys playing leap- frog and still the senator and his wife do not catch on. Until that is at the door arrives Katherine, introducing herself as Val's mother and the whole charade is shot to pieces, just as TV news crews arrive out front How on earth can the senator and his wife leave the drag club without some kind of mass scandal erupting and ending his political career? The answer is simple, drag up and we are treated to the wonderful scene of Gene Hackman in a dress making the late great Bea Arthur look as feminine as a virginal princess. It is a great feel good movie, full of lightness, the jokes and funny situation fire by in rapid succession that you will probably not catch them all on the first viewing. Robin William's is superb as the nightclub owner even if he does sweat profusely at times and almost cracks up completely in the kitchen scene with the houseman come butler. I adore Nathan Lane, with his scene stealing 'Starina' performance and utter camp flamboyant majesty. Gene Hackman is equally good as the chocolate addicted extreme right wing senator with his sour face and dry delivery. As a modern re-make of a seventies classic it is both successful and complimentary, it also stands up on its own, which is a jolly good job, and for I am sure, the vast majority of its audience would not have seen La Cage aux Folles. Sure, it is lightweight, sure, it plays a little to stereotype, but it goes beyond them, reaching in to the human side and honest inner core aspect admirably. It is outrageously camp, unashamedly so, blatantly exotic and wonderfully charming, a great feel good movie. Read more and find out where this film made it in the Top 50 Most Influential Gay Movies of All Time book, search on Amazon for Top 50 Most Influential Gay Movies of All Time, or visit - http://www.amazon.co.uk/dp/B007FU7HPO
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    What a Hoot!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Ron-72
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/4/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I saw the original French film in 1979 - it was good, but not all that memorable. I saw the Broadway musical in 1983 - liked "I Am What I Am" and that was about all. But this version is just wonderful, probably because Mike Nichols and Elaine May who've known each other since forever worked on the script and Nichols can direct anything, especially with the cast he has here. They're all great, but Nathan Lane and Hank Azaria steal the show, and I don't think I've ever seen Gene Hackman as funny...I didn't know he could do comedy. What a collection of award-winners we have here, and thoroughly deserving of their SAG award for ensemble work.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not quite there...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    oceansroar
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/3/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Birdcage is a remake of a French film which i might have seen, but was too young, so i will check it soon. i am almost willing to bet that as usual with remakes of foreign films Hollywood fails. Perhaps they should promote the actual original films to the American audience, but i suppose the average American (not an intentional jab at American, since i have seen it around the world) will not watch a subtitled film. The story is about Armand, a gay man (Robin Williams) that owns a drag nightclub, in which his lover (Nathan Lane) performs as the starring act. The couple raised a son together for 20 years. The 20 year old son is now wanting to get married, but there are some complications, which make for a few hilarious moments, but only a few. i love the cast of this film, especially Robin Williams. When he is left to his own devices he can be brilliant or over the top, so he really needs a great director that allows him more room to fly, but a leash to pull him back to our atmosphere. This director held the leash too tightly, so Robin never quite got there. Nathan Lane steals most of the thunder from Robin, but he is a little over the top at times. Hank Azaria is brilliant as Agador the houseman. The cast is great, except Calista Flockhart seems a little drab in this film. If you have not watched it, then i recommended that you see it once, but keep an open mind, after all it is about a gay family. i gave it 5/10 because it does not hold up as well as it did in 1996 and the film as a whole was just not quite there.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of half a dozen verions of La Cage aux Folles out there, and Nathan Lane is devastating
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    secondtake
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/7/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Birdcage (1996) Well, there is always something great about a Mike Nichols film, and this one, written and directed by Nichols, is no exception. It is however a story that has had better presentations (see below) and I'm not sure why Nichols opted for such an un-original material. The movie really is great in some ways, and has terrific moments, but it doesn't transcend, as the best Nichols films certainly do. Robin Williams, the apparent big name on the marquee, is the weakest link in the cast (not including the two young people, who are fine but routine). But the rest of the main actors, Nathan Lane as the drag queen most of all, but Gene Hackman as a conservative senator and Dianne Wiest as his wife, are an amazing ensemble. Throw in consistently funny and clever writing (a functioanl adaptation), good camera-work, obviously attractive sets (this is South Beach in Miami), and a lively soundtrack and you sort of can't go far wrong. Is it brilliant? No way. It doesn't need to be. It's got jokes that will fade with time, topical references and timely jabs, but overall it's just perky and funny top to bottom. And relentlessly. And yes, it pushes its point hard, about how we're all people and relationships are relationships, and that's where the comedy matters, making sure you don't take the delivery too seriously. If you have doubts that it's a farce with a silver lining, just wait until you see Gene Hackman at the end. You might argue that the social message is all that matters, and of course that's true to some ways of thinking (and in some camps of criticism), but that would limit the point of the whole affair. And as time goes on and people get more used to the idea of gay culture and gay people as just another aspect of life, well, the sensational aspects of the movie will water down. But that's fine. Besides being inevitable, it points to the other parts of the film, the Shakespearean cross-dressing, the play on identities, the constant repartee. It's funny and fun and yet smart, too. The plot, at its core, is an Americanized version of the original French play (from 1973) La Cage aux Folles (which means roughly "Cage of Drag Queens" if you take into account the slang for folles). And there is of course the famous two versions of the Broadway musical version (the 1983 and 2004 versions, not to mention the current one which started in 2010). It's a great story with a long life, clearly. And the playful interaction of the ensemble is perfect for the stage. Yet this isn't the play nor the musical, but the film, with a new name. And the photographic aspects are pretty wonderful, too. Take just the opening shot coming in on a helicopter over the water and seamlessly (almost, there's a frame or two glitch) gliding right into the night club, The Birdcage. And if you don't think the story has legs, there is a 1978 Italian version of the play (not the musical) on film. The advantage of the American version for American audiences is the references are still slightly recognizable (the Bob Dole comments are already seeming like history, however). Anyway, don't see this for Robin Williams. He's fine, but not the crackup fast talker that he's best at. And it isn't him, but Nathan Lane, who gets to cross-dress. Fabulously. You'll see.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Birds of a Feather
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    edwardtjbrown
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/5/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    In his younger days, Armand Goldman (Robin Williams) was a struggling, gay stage actor who decided to have a one night stand with a female friend (Christine Baranski). The result of this brief fling was Val Goldman (Futterman), who, in the present day, is engaged to be married to a lovely woman. Despite some initial misgivings that Val is too young to be married, Val's parents, Armand Goldman and his husband Albert, (Nathan Lane), agree to support the wedding. Yet, Barbra Keeley (Calita Rockhart), the bride-to-be, comes from a prominent political family in the middle of a tough re-election campaign. U.S. Senator Keeley, who thinks Bob Dole is too liberal, is the co-founder of a Christian Coalition-type interest group dedicated enacting laws promoting "moral order". He and his wife also feel that their daughter is too young to be married, and want to 'table' the wedding until after the campaign, especially when the head of the Moral Order Coalition is found dead in the bed of an underage, African American, prostitute. Seeing the writing on the wall, Barbara begins a clever ruse to depict the Goldman family as a traditional, white, Christian, Republican family whose politics are to the right of Patrick Buchanan, Jerry Falwell and Pat Roberston. Val convinces his parents to go to great lengths, changing their house, dress, mannerisms, religion and politics, to pull off this charade as the in-laws meet for dinner. As one might guess, much of the comedy in this film involves a 1990's satire of the right-wing politics, as well as the media's post-OJ Simpson trial (1995) obsession with tabloid and scandal driven news. Robin Williams and Nathan Lane are great together, although they show each other little affection, with Lane playing the more stereotypical gay man/drag queen entertainer, which manages to avoid coming off as mean spirited. Likewise, the Keeley are as stuffy as they are right-wing, but the film allows each of the family members to develop a character and story arch beyond simple card board cut outs. Oddly enough, the film does not really address gay rights, beyond the, often comedic, contrasts between the two families and the assumptions that are made. Armand and Albert are financially successful, owners of a hip nightclub. They live in a trendy, upscale urban neighborhood where discrimination and harassment does not seem to exist. Gays serving open in the military and legal recognition of same-sex marriage are mentioned, but Armand and Albert seem to be a couple that exists just slightly out of reality. They do argue over a palimony agreement and I am not sure how the film could have been anything else, given when it was made. In the early - mid 1990s, Hollywood films were just beginning to depict gay people in a manner that did not involve them being predatory, suicidal, homicidal manics. Yes, the film clearly mocks the stuffy, uptight future in-laws. Yes, it mocks their right-wing politics and prejudices directed at gay people as well as racial, religious and ethnic minorities. As great, witty and funny as this film is, sometimes it cannot hide its age.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Funny!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    nama chakravorty
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/2/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A remake of the 1978 film, La Cage aux Folles, 'The Birdcage' is an amusingly enjoyable film. Mike Nichols continues his magic in this 1996 cult-hit, The legendary filmmaker, along-with a stellar cast and a freaky screenplay, makes a truly funny film about everything gone haywire! 'The Birdcage' is about a gay cabaret owner and his drag queen companion agree to put up a false straight front so that their son can introduce them to his fianc&eacute;'s right-wing moralistic parents. Source taken from IMDb! To be honest, the film begins tepidly and it takes time to grasp each and every character's intentions and further plans. But once you get into the groove, you enter a joyride. The entire last hour, right after Gene Hackman & Co enter Williams house, there is hardly a moment when you don't laugh. Also, watching Gene Hackman as a drag in the climax, is simply hilarious! Mike Nichols directs the film with his usual midas touch. He is amongst the most talented filmmakers ever. The adapted Screenplay is full of absurd, funny, hilarious & strange situations. Cinematography by Emmanuel Lubezki is perfect. Editing could've been sharper. Now to the performances! With such a stellar cast coming under one roof, one expects nothing but exemplary acting. Each and Every Actor delivers in here. Robin Williams, Gene Hackman, Nathan Lane & Dianne Wiest are absolutely flawless. Dan Futterman, Calista Flockhart & Hank Azaria are at par with the seniors! On the whole, A Comedy that needs a watch. An absurd yet lovable experience! Thumbs Up!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Funniest movie I have ever seen
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bluebook-master
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Rarely does a movie cause me to laugh out loud so much as The Birdcage. The cast of characters is extraordinary. The interaction between Gene Hackman and Nathan Lane is priceless. Dan Futterman is not only drop dead gorgeous but his chemistry with Robin Williams is a perfect match. The dinner party reaches a climax with everyone singing "I could have danced all right" with Gene Hackman and Nathan Lane ballroom dancing. The closing scene with Gene Hackman dancing in drag and saying his white dress makes him look fat caused me to cry I was laughing so much. Whoever masterminded this cast of actors knew what they were doing. The film pokes fun at both the absurdity of right wing Republicans and over the top gay men running a nightclub - all humor done very tastefully. For an evening of pure entertainment you've got to see this movies- more than once.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The funniest gay-duo ever, with Robin Williams as the straight-man, so to speak 
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ElMaruecan82
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Traduttore, tradittore" the Italian adage seems to indicate that the transposition of a concept or an artistic creation to another language would inevitably betray its spirit. It's true that most of the times, comedy is the most likely genre to suffer from adaptation and the most eloquent proof can be found in the love-and-hate relationship between French comedies and their much inferior American remakes. Almost every Francis Veber's script for instance, was remade for American audience, and needless to say that some films turns out to be sour disasters, or average entertainments at best. Directed by Mike Nichols, "The Birdcage" is the remake of 'Birds of Feathers' ("La Cage aux Folles"), the greatest Italian-French comedy, starring Ugo Tognazzi and Michel Serrault, and one of the most successful French productions in America. Although it was fair for Nichols to assume that the 1996' audience wouldn't be familiar with the original film, it was risky as well to embrace such a politically incorrect theme, featuring a gay couple with one acting like a hysterical diva, and transpose it in the 90's where the 70's archetypes were no longer held as comedic devices. Needless to say that the performances of the whole cast was crucial, let alone Nathan Lane, who is the highlight of the show. The plot is pure screwball material, Armand (Williams) lives with Albert (Lane) for twenty years, Armand owns a gay burlesque bar in South Florida named "The Birdcage" and directs the very show where Albert stars. Albert acts like a capricious prima donna all the time, always seeming at the edge of a nervous breakdown, praising for attention, he's obviously the "lady" in the couple, and it seems quite fresh to see Williams as the most restrained one, and not let himself carried away by Albert's caprices. The rest of the house also features a Hank Azaria as a Guatemalan butler named Agador, his accent, extraordinary capability to imitate Estefan's "Konga" and some crazy one-liners are really under-appreciated. The routine is broken when Val, Armand's son announces his engagement with the daughter of a republican and notoriously conservative, a Senator named Kevin Keeley (Gene Hackman). Keeley isn't in a better phase because his closest friend and President of the Coalition of Moral Virtues was found dead with an underage black prostitute, a synthesis of every worst- case situation that can undermine a political career. Naturally, his daughter (a pre-McBeal Calista Flockhart) is forced to lie about Armand's profession and Keeley's wife (Dianne Wiest) seize the wedding as an opportunity to clear Keeley from the prejudice caused by the scandal. With these two set-ups, the movie takes off for one of the funniest and most enjoyable recent comedy of errors. Some would naturally get offended by Lane's portrayal of Albert, but the fact is that the film is precisely funny because he's effeminate. It gives its flavor to the scene where he wants to pretend he's Val's uncle, and then learns from Albert how to butter a toast like a man, and not get upset if it gets pierced, and walk like John Wayne. Albert's high pitched screams and overly-gay mannerisms contribute to some of the film's most laugh-out-loud moments and can't take you off totally off-guard, but Lane doesn't overplay them, he finds the right note in an over-the-top personality. And it never shows as well as in the scene where he comes, dressed like a man, only to betray some pink socks, that make even more obvious the fact that he's gay. And that's the basis of the whole comical premise, the more you pretend not to be something, the more it shows. But one thing Lane shows without pretending is how loving and caring he's for Val, and that's what makes his character so endearing and engaging. He's a clown but a sad and funny one, while Williams is the 'straight' man, comically speaking of course, and when a champagne bottle suddenly pops, the effect is immediate, it's pure comedic gold. There are two levels of comedies, where Williams is both the straight man and the clown of a masquerade, no wonder he spent the whole night drinking. Talk about a comical existential nightmare. The secret of "The Birdcage" is to remain faithful to the spirit of the first film, but not without taking some perspective from the original material. The fact that they're Jewish adds another running their name, is it Goldman or Coleman, is the 'd' silent or what? The political undertones are accentuated, maybe because it was before the election campaign, but they seem to be more fitting for the American context, and Gene Hackman is absolutely perfect as the Republican Senator who tries to hide his desperation between a cold facade, he's even more interesting than the original character because the screenplay enriches his personality with his genuine fondness on Albert. And we understand the Senator, Lane plays a drag with such genuine tenderness that we empathize with his desire to help Val. But since we know that it's meant to fail, we can only enjoy the way they keep the Senator believing. And it's indeed funny how Albert touches the Senator's heart when pretending to be Val's mother "they don't make women like that anymore", maybe in a way, Albert fulfilled his all-time dream to be a woman and be treated as well. "The Birdcage" is a film that should have deserved more recognition, less than a remake, it's more of a refreshing and modernization of the 70's version, and it's so lively, so flamboyant, so comical, it seems to reconcile with an idea of the 'gay' culture, that no matter how stereotypical it is, remains more enjoyable than its claim for banality. The style is dated but not the tone. "The Birdcage" deserves all its praises, it's not only one of the few successful American remakes of French comedies, it's more intelligent than what it seems  and it's funny as hell.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    If you don't get this movie, try some more gum
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ironhorse_iv
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I know that look. Hit me, go on. Hit me with why this movie isn't good, because I don't see that face plant of why I should hate this Mike Nichol's film. Yes, it might look like a pale copy of the original La Cage aux Folles, the 1978's French film in itself based on the 1973's play by Jean Poiret, but it's not a drag. Well, it's a drag in another way, but what I like about this remake is how they turns something from French, into a funny American movie. Armand Goldman (Robin Williams) owns a popular drag nightclub in South Miami Beach with his long-time lover Albert Goldman (Nathan Lane). Nathan Lane as Albert is a annoying character with his fits, non-stop complaining and diva like attitude. Some audience members might find the character too irritation to bother with the movie. Some audience members will look past that, due to fact that Albert is so hysterical due to his overreactions to everything. If some people dislike him, they would love the crude humor toward him from Armand. As much as Armand can not stand him, he sticks with Albert. Within the comedy, is a small great speech scene by Armand to Albert. These are two gay men of a certain age, and years of ostracism, threats and taunts would have conditioned them both to avoid any PDAs, no matter how strong the feeling between them. The speech gives the moment enormous poignancy feeling of genuine, heartfelt and caring to Albert. This scene is especially lovely, a great juxtaposition to the rest of the film which is wonderfully silly and comedic. Nathan Lane isn't the only one that nearly steals the movie from Robin Williams, as Armand's maid Agador Spartacus (Hank Azaria) takes a bite of funny throughout the film, with singing and dancing to music, making lousy food, and tripping over his own feet. Watching Agador was a delight, and pans away from Nathan Lane enough times, that we able to rest from his big, brassy yelling and complaining. Soon the Goldman's son Val (Dan Futterman) comes home to announce his engagement to Barbara Keely (Calista Flockhart), daughter of Kevin Keely (Gene Hackman), US Senator, and vice president of the extreme Committee for Moral Order and his wife (Dianne Wiest). First off, the actor Dan Futterman and Calista Flockhart were too old for the role, it felt weird in a way to see Calista play a awkward 18 year old. Both are in later scenes, boozing and smoking. Are we suppose to believe that a conservatism senator would allow his daughter to underage drink? Clearly both are wrong actors for the job. Gene Hackman as Kevin Keely is so extreme right conservatism, it makes the character seem like a political cartoon caricature less than a normal person. Kevin Keely decide to allow Barbara to marry Val only if they meet Val and his family at South Beach and use the marriage to get the media off of the scandal of his co-founder that been focus on him. While in Miami, Val fearing the worst like the Senator will not allow Barbara to marry him. Val tries to convince his father to hide his relationship with Albert and the fact that he is gay and Jewish. At first, Armand stood tall for his right to be open about his sexuality and his religious views, but seeing how much it would mean for him. He allow the dinner to happen, and to make himself seem straight and asking to get rid of Albert for the day was over the line. I just can't stand Dan Futterman's character, for this, what a jerk. First off, Calista's character is clearly old enough to get marry with or without her father permission, and second off, it was the 90's. It wasn't the Leave it to Beaver pre-sexualism freedom 1960's here. I felt it was wrong how Val treats his father to hide who his Father was, ask Albert to leave, all for a girl who only knew for a year. The whole thing was shameful on the part of the character. I know he wasn't in shame of his father's lifestyle, but he knew that Keelys wouldn't understand, and I know without this premise there is no movie, but still he only admit his fault to due to being catch, rather than seeing his wrongs on how he treated his father and Albert the last few days. I also felt the ending was a cop-out, as it's seem like there should had been an extra scene to show how the movie's plot got resolved. Yes it might seem like a bird-brained delight, but you just can't help loving it, and not taking it too serious. The movie acts less like La Cage aux Folles and more like a modern "You can't take it with you", a 1938 film. The music in the film is catchy, love the use of Sister Sledge- We are family, Gloria Estefan- conga, and Alan Lerner- I could have danced all night. It add with the positive good mood of the film. The whole singing scene before dinner was the best. What the movie does well is going beyond the stereotypes to see the character's depth and humanity, and that's why this movie should be check out. Try it, and you will find yourself liking it as much as I do.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not enjoyable
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    WakenPayne
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The main plot of this movie is basically that a gay club owner and his drag queen partner have a son that's getting married. For some reason they pose as being straight (with Nathan Lane in drag posing as his mother) to get the bride's parents approval or giving them the impression that they're straight because the father of the bride has anti-gay political views. I personally found the movie not really that funny at all, full of really bad gay jokes. I don't mind gay jokes (for a fact I have laughed hysterically at a couple over my teenage years) but that is really all this movie has to offer in terms of entertainment. I found the plot to be pointless (but that maybe just who I am). So if you like gay jokes then watch this, but don't really expect anything else.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Delightful Fun
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Jason Shaw
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    ￼ Put simply this is a glitzy, colourful, modern remake of La Cage aux Folles in which Robin Williams stars as the hairy and sweaty Armand, South Beach drag club owner alongside the incomparable Nathan Lane as the star and Armund's lover and partner Albert. Just like the original version, their lives are turned upside down and inside out when Armund's son, Val, comes home to announce he is getting married to an ultra-conservative senator's daughter called Barbara. Everything goes haywire and speeds up to comic high gear when those future in-laws come down to meet their daughters intended and his family. Scandal is what the senator wants to avoid at the great cost, you cannot blame him, and his co-founder of the coalition for moral order partnership has just been found dead in the bed of an underage black prostitute. There are laughs a plenty when first Armund and then Albert try and play it butch, they desperately need a woman and it's so not often you hear a couple of middle aged gay men scream that! In steps the wonderful and delightful Christine Baranski who always lights up the screen with a presence that is electrifying. However, is life that simple, that easy? You bet your sweet little arse it ain't! Barbara tells her parents that Armand is a cultural attach&eacute; to Greece, whilst Albert is a housewife, and that they divide their time between Greece and Florida. It is only a little white lie really, just as changing their last name from Goldman to Coleman is. The evening of the meeting arrives, the apartment above the drag club is transformed from gay paradise to near austere monastery, Val's real mother, Katherine (Baranski) is held up by traffic and a boat and out pops Albert as a wonderful creation of freakishly good yet awfully bad middle-aged mother. Armand and Val are both horrified at first but have no option to go along with the fa&ccedil;ade, which for some bizarre reason in this movie world works. More jokes, no proper meal and the most amazing china dinner service of naked boys playing leap- frog and still the senator and his wife do not catch on. Until that is at the door arrives Katherine, introducing herself as Val's mother and the whole charade is shot to pieces, just as TV news crews arrive out front How on earth can the senator and his wife leave the drag club without some kind of mass scandal erupting and ending his political career? The answer is simple, drag up and we are treated to the wonderful scene of Gene Hackman in a dress making the late great Bea Arthur look as feminine as a virginal princess. It is a great feel good movie, full of lightness, the jokes and funny situation fire by in rapid succession that you will probably not catch them all on the first viewing. Robin William's is superb as the nightclub owner even if he does sweat profusely at times and almost cracks up completely in the kitchen scene with the houseman come butler. I adore Nathan Lane, with his scene stealing 'Starina' performance and utter camp flamboyant majesty. Gene Hackman is equally good as the chocolate addicted extreme right wing senator with his sour face and dry delivery. As a modern re-make of a seventies classic it is both successful and complimentary, it also stands up on its own, which is a jolly good job, and for I am sure, the vast majority of its audience would not have seen La Cage aux Folles. Sure, it is lightweight, sure, it plays a little to stereotype, but it goes beyond them, reaching in to the human side and honest inner core aspect admirably. It is outrageously camp, unashamedly so, blatantly exotic and wonderfully charming, a great feel good movie. Read more and find out where this film made it in the Top 50 Most Influential Gay Movies of All Time book, search on Amazon for Top 50 Most Influential Gay Movies of All Time, or visit - http://www.amazon.co.uk/dp/B007FU7HPO
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    What a Hoot!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Ron-72
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/4/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I saw the original French film in 1979 - it was good, but not all that memorable. I saw the Broadway musical in 1983 - liked "I Am What I Am" and that was about all. But this version is just wonderful, probably because Mike Nichols and Elaine May who've known each other since forever worked on the script and Nichols can direct anything, especially with the cast he has here. They're all great, but Nathan Lane and Hank Azaria steal the show, and I don't think I've ever seen Gene Hackman as funny...I didn't know he could do comedy. What a collection of award-winners we have here, and thoroughly deserving of their SAG award for ensemble work.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not quite there...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    oceansroar
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/3/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Birdcage is a remake of a French film which i might have seen, but was too young, so i will check it soon. i am almost willing to bet that as usual with remakes of foreign films Hollywood fails. Perhaps they should promote the actual original films to the American audience, but i suppose the average American (not an intentional jab at American, since i have seen it around the world) will not watch a subtitled film. The story is about Armand, a gay man (Robin Williams) that owns a drag nightclub, in which his lover (Nathan Lane) performs as the starring act. The couple raised a son together for 20 years. The 20 year old son is now wanting to get married, but there are some complications, which make for a few hilarious moments, but only a few. i love the cast of this film, especially Robin Williams. When he is left to his own devices he can be brilliant or over the top, so he really needs a great director that allows him more room to fly, but a leash to pull him back to our atmosphere. This director held the leash too tightly, so Robin never quite got there. Nathan Lane steals most of the thunder from Robin, but he is a little over the top at times. Hank Azaria is brilliant as Agador the houseman. The cast is great, except Calista Flockhart seems a little drab in this film. If you have not watched it, then i recommended that you see it once, but keep an open mind, after all it is about a gay family. i gave it 5/10 because it does not hold up as well as it did in 1996 and the film as a whole was just not quite there.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of half a dozen verions of La Cage aux Folles out there, and Nathan Lane is devastating
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    secondtake
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/7/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Birdcage (1996) Well, there is always something great about a Mike Nichols film, and this one, written and directed by Nichols, is no exception. It is however a story that has had better presentations (see below) and I'm not sure why Nichols opted for such an un-original material. The movie really is great in some ways, and has terrific moments, but it doesn't transcend, as the best Nichols films certainly do. Robin Williams, the apparent big name on the marquee, is the weakest link in the cast (not including the two young people, who are fine but routine). But the rest of the main actors, Nathan Lane as the drag queen most of all, but Gene Hackman as a conservative senator and Dianne Wiest as his wife, are an amazing ensemble. Throw in consistently funny and clever writing (a functioanl adaptation), good camera-work, obviously attractive sets (this is South Beach in Miami), and a lively soundtrack and you sort of can't go far wrong. Is it brilliant? No way. It doesn't need to be. It's got jokes that will fade with time, topical references and timely jabs, but overall it's just perky and funny top to bottom. And relentlessly. And yes, it pushes its point hard, about how we're all people and relationships are relationships, and that's where the comedy matters, making sure you don't take the delivery too seriously. If you have doubts that it's a farce with a silver lining, just wait until you see Gene Hackman at the end. You might argue that the social message is all that matters, and of course that's true to some ways of thinking (and in some camps of criticism), but that would limit the point of the whole affair. And as time goes on and people get more used to the idea of gay culture and gay people as just another aspect of life, well, the sensational aspects of the movie will water down. But that's fine. Besides being inevitable, it points to the other parts of the film, the Shakespearean cross-dressing, the play on identities, the constant repartee. It's funny and fun and yet smart, too. The plot, at its core, is an Americanized version of the original French play (from 1973) La Cage aux Folles (which means roughly "Cage of Drag Queens" if you take into account the slang for folles). And there is of course the famous two versions of the Broadway musical version (the 1983 and 2004 versions, not to mention the current one which started in 2010). It's a great story with a long life, clearly. And the playful interaction of the ensemble is perfect for the stage. Yet this isn't the play nor the musical, but the film, with a new name. And the photographic aspects are pretty wonderful, too. Take just the opening shot coming in on a helicopter over the water and seamlessly (almost, there's a frame or two glitch) gliding right into the night club, The Birdcage. And if you don't think the story has legs, there is a 1978 Italian version of the play (not the musical) on film. The advantage of the American version for American audiences is the references are still slightly recognizable (the Bob Dole comments are already seeming like history, however). Anyway, don't see this for Robin Williams. He's fine, but not the crackup fast talker that he's best at. And it isn't him, but Nathan Lane, who gets to cross-dress. Fabulously. You'll see.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Birds of a Feather
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    edwardtjbrown
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/5/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    In his younger days, Armand Goldman (Robin Williams) was a struggling, gay stage actor who decided to have a one night stand with a female friend (Christine Baranski). The result of this brief fling was Val Goldman (Futterman), who, in the present day, is engaged to be married to a lovely woman. Despite some initial misgivings that Val is too young to be married, Val's parents, Armand Goldman and his husband Albert, (Nathan Lane), agree to support the wedding. Yet, Barbra Keeley (Calita Rockhart), the bride-to-be, comes from a prominent political family in the middle of a tough re-election campaign. U.S. Senator Keeley, who thinks Bob Dole is too liberal, is the co-founder of a Christian Coalition-type interest group dedicated enacting laws promoting "moral order". He and his wife also feel that their daughter is too young to be married, and want to 'table' the wedding until after the campaign, especially when the head of the Moral Order Coalition is found dead in the bed of an underage, African American, prostitute. Seeing the writing on the wall, Barbara begins a clever ruse to depict the Goldman family as a traditional, white, Christian, Republican family whose politics are to the right of Patrick Buchanan, Jerry Falwell and Pat Roberston. Val convinces his parents to go to great lengths, changing their house, dress, mannerisms, religion and politics, to pull off this charade as the in-laws meet for dinner. As one might guess, much of the comedy in this film involves a 1990's satire of the right-wing politics, as well as the media's post-OJ Simpson trial (1995) obsession with tabloid and scandal driven news. Robin Williams and Nathan Lane are great together, although they show each other little affection, with Lane playing the more stereotypical gay man/drag queen entertainer, which manages to avoid coming off as mean spirited. Likewise, the Keeley are as stuffy as they are right-wing, but the film allows each of the family members to develop a character and story arch beyond simple card board cut outs. Oddly enough, the film does not really address gay rights, beyond the, often comedic, contrasts between the two families and the assumptions that are made. Armand and Albert are financially successful, owners of a hip nightclub. They live in a trendy, upscale urban neighborhood where discrimination and harassment does not seem to exist. Gays serving open in the military and legal recognition of same-sex marriage are mentioned, but Armand and Albert seem to be a couple that exists just slightly out of reality. They do argue over a palimony agreement and I am not sure how the film could have been anything else, given when it was made. In the early - mid 1990s, Hollywood films were just beginning to depict gay people in a manner that did not involve them being predatory, suicidal, homicidal manics. Yes, the film clearly mocks the stuffy, uptight future in-laws. Yes, it mocks their right-wing politics and prejudices directed at gay people as well as racial, religious and ethnic minorities. As great, witty and funny as this film is, sometimes it cannot hide its age.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Funny!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    nama chakravorty
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/2/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A remake of the 1978 film, La Cage aux Folles, 'The Birdcage' is an amusingly enjoyable film. Mike Nichols continues his magic in this 1996 cult-hit, The legendary filmmaker, along-with a stellar cast and a freaky screenplay, makes a truly funny film about everything gone haywire! 'The Birdcage' is about a gay cabaret owner and his drag queen companion agree to put up a false straight front so that their son can introduce them to his fianc&eacute;'s right-wing moralistic parents. Source taken from IMDb! To be honest, the film begins tepidly and it takes time to grasp each and every character's intentions and further plans. But once you get into the groove, you enter a joyride. The entire last hour, right after Gene Hackman & Co enter Williams house, there is hardly a moment when you don't laugh. Also, watching Gene Hackman as a drag in the climax, is simply hilarious! Mike Nichols directs the film with his usual midas touch. He is amongst the most talented filmmakers ever. The adapted Screenplay is full of absurd, funny, hilarious & strange situations. Cinematography by Emmanuel Lubezki is perfect. Editing could've been sharper. Now to the performances! With such a stellar cast coming under one roof, one expects nothing but exemplary acting. Each and Every Actor delivers in here. Robin Williams, Gene Hackman, Nathan Lane & Dianne Wiest are absolutely flawless. Dan Futterman, Calista Flockhart & Hank Azaria are at par with the seniors! On the whole, A Comedy that needs a watch. An absurd yet lovable experience! Thumbs Up!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Funniest movie I have ever seen
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bluebook-master
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Rarely does a movie cause me to laugh out loud so much as The Birdcage. The cast of characters is extraordinary. The interaction between Gene Hackman and Nathan Lane is priceless. Dan Futterman is not only drop dead gorgeous but his chemistry with Robin Williams is a perfect match. The dinner party reaches a climax with everyone singing "I could have danced all right" with Gene Hackman and Nathan Lane ballroom dancing. The closing scene with Gene Hackman dancing in drag and saying his white dress makes him look fat caused me to cry I was laughing so much. Whoever masterminded this cast of actors knew what they were doing. The film pokes fun at both the absurdity of right wing Republicans and over the top gay men running a nightclub - all humor done very tastefully. For an evening of pure entertainment you've got to see this movies- more than once.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The funniest gay-duo ever, with Robin Williams as the straight-man, so to speak 
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ElMaruecan82
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Traduttore, tradittore" the Italian adage seems to indicate that the transposition of a concept or an artistic creation to another language would inevitably betray its spirit. It's true that most of the times, comedy is the most likely genre to suffer from adaptation and the most eloquent proof can be found in the love-and-hate relationship between French comedies and their much inferior American remakes. Almost every Francis Veber's script for instance, was remade for American audience, and needless to say that some films turns out to be sour disasters, or average entertainments at best. Directed by Mike Nichols, "The Birdcage" is the remake of 'Birds of Feathers' ("La Cage aux Folles"), the greatest Italian-French comedy, starring Ugo Tognazzi and Michel Serrault, and one of the most successful French productions in America. Although it was fair for Nichols to assume that the 1996' audience wouldn't be familiar with the original film, it was risky as well to embrace such a politically incorrect theme, featuring a gay couple with one acting like a hysterical diva, and transpose it in the 90's where the 70's archetypes were no longer held as comedic devices. Needless to say that the performances of the whole cast was crucial, let alone Nathan Lane, who is the highlight of the show. The plot is pure screwball material, Armand (Williams) lives with Albert (Lane) for twenty years, Armand owns a gay burlesque bar in South Florida named "The Birdcage" and directs the very show where Albert stars. Albert acts like a capricious prima donna all the time, always seeming at the edge of a nervous breakdown, praising for attention, he's obviously the "lady" in the couple, and it seems quite fresh to see Williams as the most restrained one, and not let himself carried away by Albert's caprices. The rest of the house also features a Hank Azaria as a Guatemalan butler named Agador, his accent, extraordinary capability to imitate Estefan's "Konga" and some crazy one-liners are really under-appreciated. The routine is broken when Val, Armand's son announces his engagement with the daughter of a republican and notoriously conservative, a Senator named Kevin Keeley (Gene Hackman). Keeley isn't in a better phase because his closest friend and President of the Coalition of Moral Virtues was found dead with an underage black prostitute, a synthesis of every worst- case situation that can undermine a political career. Naturally, his daughter (a pre-McBeal Calista Flockhart) is forced to lie about Armand's profession and Keeley's wife (Dianne Wiest) seize the wedding as an opportunity to clear Keeley from the prejudice caused by the scandal. With these two set-ups, the movie takes off for one of the funniest and most enjoyable recent comedy of errors. Some would naturally get offended by Lane's portrayal of Albert, but the fact is that the film is precisely funny because he's effeminate. It gives its flavor to the scene where he wants to pretend he's Val's uncle, and then learns from Albert how to butter a toast like a man, and not get upset if it gets pierced, and walk like John Wayne. Albert's high pitched screams and overly-gay mannerisms contribute to some of the film's most laugh-out-loud moments and can't take you off totally off-guard, but Lane doesn't overplay them, he finds the right note in an over-the-top personality. And it never shows as well as in the scene where he comes, dressed like a man, only to betray some pink socks, that make even more obvious the fact that he's gay. And that's the basis of the whole comical premise, the more you pretend not to be something, the more it shows. But one thing Lane shows without pretending is how loving and caring he's for Val, and that's what makes his character so endearing and engaging. He's a clown but a sad and funny one, while Williams is the 'straight' man, comically speaking of course, and when a champagne bottle suddenly pops, the effect is immediate, it's pure comedic gold. There are two levels of comedies, where Williams is both the straight man and the clown of a masquerade, no wonder he spent the whole night drinking. Talk about a comical existential nightmare. The secret of "The Birdcage" is to remain faithful to the spirit of the first film, but not without taking some perspective from the original material. The fact that they're Jewish adds another running their name, is it Goldman or Coleman, is the 'd' silent or what? The political undertones are accentuated, maybe because it was before the election campaign, but they seem to be more fitting for the American context, and Gene Hackman is absolutely perfect as the Republican Senator who tries to hide his desperation between a cold facade, he's even more interesting than the original character because the screenplay enriches his personality with his genuine fondness on Albert. And we understand the Senator, Lane plays a drag with such genuine tenderness that we empathize with his desire to help Val. But since we know that it's meant to fail, we can only enjoy the way they keep the Senator believing. And it's indeed funny how Albert touches the Senator's heart when pretending to be Val's mother "they don't make women like that anymore", maybe in a way, Albert fulfilled his all-time dream to be a woman and be treated as well. "The Birdcage" is a film that should have deserved more recognition, less than a remake, it's more of a refreshing and modernization of the 70's version, and it's so lively, so flamboyant, so comical, it seems to reconcile with an idea of the 'gay' culture, that no matter how stereotypical it is, remains more enjoyable than its claim for banality. The style is dated but not the tone. "The Birdcage" deserves all its praises, it's not only one of the few successful American remakes of French comedies, it's more intelligent than what it seems  and it's funny as hell.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    If you don't get this movie, try some more gum
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ironhorse_iv
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I know that look. Hit me, go on. Hit me with why this movie isn't good, because I don't see that face plant of why I should hate this Mike Nichol's film. Yes, it might look like a pale copy of the original La Cage aux Folles, the 1978's French film in itself based on the 1973's play by Jean Poiret, but it's not a drag. Well, it's a drag in another way, but what I like about this remake is how they turns something from French, into a funny American movie. Armand Goldman (Robin Williams) owns a popular drag nightclub in South Miami Beach with his long-time lover Albert Goldman (Nathan Lane). Nathan Lane as Albert is a annoying character with his fits, non-stop complaining and diva like attitude. Some audience members might find the character too irritation to bother with the movie. Some audience members will look past that, due to fact that Albert is so hysterical due to his overreactions to everything. If some people dislike him, they would love the crude humor toward him from Armand. As much as Armand can not stand him, he sticks with Albert. Within the comedy, is a small great speech scene by Armand to Albert. These are two gay men of a certain age, and years of ostracism, threats and taunts would have conditioned them both to avoid any PDAs, no matter how strong the feeling between them. The speech gives the moment enormous poignancy feeling of genuine, heartfelt and caring to Albert. This scene is especially lovely, a great juxtaposition to the rest of the film which is wonderfully silly and comedic. Nathan Lane isn't the only one that nearly steals the movie from Robin Williams, as Armand's maid Agador Spartacus (Hank Azaria) takes a bite of funny throughout the film, with singing and dancing to music, making lousy food, and tripping over his own feet. Watching Agador was a delight, and pans away from Nathan Lane enough times, that we able to rest from his big, brassy yelling and complaining. Soon the Goldman's son Val (Dan Futterman) comes home to announce his engagement to Barbara Keely (Calista Flockhart), daughter of Kevin Keely (Gene Hackman), US Senator, and vice president of the extreme Committee for Moral Order and his wife (Dianne Wiest). First off, the actor Dan Futterman and Calista Flockhart were too old for the role, it felt weird in a way to see Calista play a awkward 18 year old. Both are in later scenes, boozing and smoking. Are we suppose to believe that a conservatism senator would allow his daughter to underage drink? Clearly both are wrong actors for the job. Gene Hackman as Kevin Keely is so extreme right conservatism, it makes the character seem like a political cartoon caricature less than a normal person. Kevin Keely decide to allow Barbara to marry Val only if they meet Val and his family at South Beach and use the marriage to get the media off of the scandal of his co-founder that been focus on him. While in Miami, Val fearing the worst like the Senator will not allow Barbara to marry him. Val tries to convince his father to hide his relationship with Albert and the fact that he is gay and Jewish. At first, Armand stood tall for his right to be open about his sexuality and his religious views, but seeing how much it would mean for him. He allow the dinner to happen, and to make himself seem straight and asking to get rid of Albert for the day was over the line. I just can't stand Dan Futterman's character, for this, what a jerk. First off, Calista's character is clearly old enough to get marry with or without her father permission, and second off, it was the 90's. It wasn't the Leave it to Beaver pre-sexualism freedom 1960's here. I felt it was wrong how Val treats his father to hide who his Father was, ask Albert to leave, all for a girl who only knew for a year. The whole thing was shameful on the part of the character. I know he wasn't in shame of his father's lifestyle, but he knew that Keelys wouldn't understand, and I know without this premise there is no movie, but still he only admit his fault to due to being catch, rather than seeing his wrongs on how he treated his father and Albert the last few days. I also felt the ending was a cop-out, as it's seem like there should had been an extra scene to show how the movie's plot got resolved. Yes it might seem like a bird-brained delight, but you just can't help loving it, and not taking it too serious. The movie acts less like La Cage aux Folles and more like a modern "You can't take it with you", a 1938 film. The music in the film is catchy, love the use of Sister Sledge- We are family, Gloria Estefan- conga, and Alan Lerner- I could have danced all night. It add with the positive good mood of the film. The whole singing scene before dinner was the best. What the movie does well is going beyond the stereotypes to see the character's depth and humanity, and that's why this movie should be check out. Try it, and you will find yourself liking it as much as I do.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not enjoyable
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    WakenPayne
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The main plot of this movie is basically that a gay club owner and his drag queen partner have a son that's getting married. For some reason they pose as being straight (with Nathan Lane in drag posing as his mother) to get the bride's parents approval or giving them the impression that they're straight because the father of the bride has anti-gay political views. I personally found the movie not really that funny at all, full of really bad gay jokes. I don't mind gay jokes (for a fact I have laughed hysterically at a couple over my teenage years) but that is really all this movie has to offer in terms of entertainment. I found the plot to be pointless (but that maybe just who I am). So if you like gay jokes then watch this, but don't really expect anything else.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Delightful Fun
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Jason Shaw
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    ￼ Put simply this is a glitzy, colourful, modern remake of La Cage aux Folles in which Robin Williams stars as the hairy and sweaty Armand, South Beach drag club owner alongside the incomparable Nathan Lane as the star and Armund's lover and partner Albert. Just like the original version, their lives are turned upside down and inside out when Armund's son, Val, comes home to announce he is getting married to an ultra-conservative senator's daughter called Barbara. Everything goes haywire and speeds up to comic high gear when those future in-laws come down to meet their daughters intended and his family. Scandal is what the senator wants to avoid at the great cost, you cannot blame him, and his co-founder of the coalition for moral order partnership has just been found dead in the bed of an underage black prostitute. There are laughs a plenty when first Armund and then Albert try and play it butch, they desperately need a woman and it's so not often you hear a couple of middle aged gay men scream that! In steps the wonderful and delightful Christine Baranski who always lights up the screen with a presence that is electrifying. However, is life that simple, that easy? You bet your sweet little arse it ain't! Barbara tells her parents that Armand is a cultural attach&eacute; to Greece, whilst Albert is a housewife, and that they divide their time between Greece and Florida. It is only a little white lie really, just as changing their last name from Goldman to Coleman is. The evening of the meeting arrives, the apartment above the drag club is transformed from gay paradise to near austere monastery, Val's real mother, Katherine (Baranski) is held up by traffic and a boat and out pops Albert as a wonderful creation of freakishly good yet awfully bad middle-aged mother. Armand and Val are both horrified at first but have no option to go along with the fa&ccedil;ade, which for some bizarre reason in this movie world works. More jokes, no proper meal and the most amazing china dinner service of naked boys playing leap- frog and still the senator and his wife do not catch on. Until that is at the door arrives Katherine, introducing herself as Val's mother and the whole charade is shot to pieces, just as TV news crews arrive out front How on earth can the senator and his wife leave the drag club without some kind of mass scandal erupting and ending his political career? The answer is simple, drag up and we are treated to the wonderful scene of Gene Hackman in a dress making the late great Bea Arthur look as feminine as a virginal princess. It is a great feel good movie, full of lightness, the jokes and funny situation fire by in rapid succession that you will probably not catch them all on the first viewing. Robin William's is superb as the nightclub owner even if he does sweat profusely at times and almost cracks up completely in the kitchen scene with the houseman come butler. I adore Nathan Lane, with his scene stealing 'Starina' performance and utter camp flamboyant majesty. Gene Hackman is equally good as the chocolate addicted extreme right wing senator with his sour face and dry delivery. As a modern re-make of a seventies classic it is both successful and complimentary, it also stands up on its own, which is a jolly good job, and for I am sure, the vast majority of its audience would not have seen La Cage aux Folles. Sure, it is lightweight, sure, it plays a little to stereotype, but it goes beyond them, reaching in to the human side and honest inner core aspect admirably. It is outrageously camp, unashamedly so, blatantly exotic and wonderfully charming, a great feel good movie. Read more and find out where this film made it in the Top 50 Most Influential Gay Movies of All Time book, search on Amazon for Top 50 Most Influential Gay Movies of All Time, or visit - http://www.amazon.co.uk/dp/B007FU7HPO
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    What a Hoot!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Ron-72
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/4/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I saw the original French film in 1979 - it was good, but not all that memorable. I saw the Broadway musical in 1983 - liked "I Am What I Am" and that was about all. But this version is just wonderful, probably because Mike Nichols and Elaine May who've known each other since forever worked on the script and Nichols can direct anything, especially with the cast he has here. They're all great, but Nathan Lane and Hank Azaria steal the show, and I don't think I've ever seen Gene Hackman as funny...I didn't know he could do comedy. What a collection of award-winners we have here, and thoroughly deserving of their SAG award for ensemble work.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not quite there...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    oceansroar
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/3/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Birdcage is a remake of a French film which i might have seen, but was too young, so i will check it soon. i am almost willing to bet that as usual with remakes of foreign films Hollywood fails. Perhaps they should promote the actual original films to the American audience, but i suppose the average American (not an intentional jab at American, since i have seen it around the world) will not watch a subtitled film. The story is about Armand, a gay man (Robin Williams) that owns a drag nightclub, in which his lover (Nathan Lane) performs as the starring act. The couple raised a son together for 20 years. The 20 year old son is now wanting to get married, but there are some complications, which make for a few hilarious moments, but only a few. i love the cast of this film, especially Robin Williams. When he is left to his own devices he can be brilliant or over the top, so he really needs a great director that allows him more room to fly, but a leash to pull him back to our atmosphere. This director held the leash too tightly, so Robin never quite got there. Nathan Lane steals most of the thunder from Robin, but he is a little over the top at times. Hank Azaria is brilliant as Agador the houseman. The cast is great, except Calista Flockhart seems a little drab in this film. If you have not watched it, then i recommended that you see it once, but keep an open mind, after all it is about a gay family. i gave it 5/10 because it does not hold up as well as it did in 1996 and the film as a whole was just not quite there.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of half a dozen verions of La Cage aux Folles out there, and Nathan Lane is devastating
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    secondtake
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/7/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Birdcage (1996) Well, there is always something great about a Mike Nichols film, and this one, written and directed by Nichols, is no exception. It is however a story that has had better presentations (see below) and I'm not sure why Nichols opted for such an un-original material. The movie really is great in some ways, and has terrific moments, but it doesn't transcend, as the best Nichols films certainly do. Robin Williams, the apparent big name on the marquee, is the weakest link in the cast (not including the two young people, who are fine but routine). But the rest of the main actors, Nathan Lane as the drag queen most of all, but Gene Hackman as a conservative senator and Dianne Wiest as his wife, are an amazing ensemble. Throw in consistently funny and clever writing (a functioanl adaptation), good camera-work, obviously attractive sets (this is South Beach in Miami), and a lively soundtrack and you sort of can't go far wrong. Is it brilliant? No way. It doesn't need to be. It's got jokes that will fade with time, topical references and timely jabs, but overall it's just perky and funny top to bottom. And relentlessly. And yes, it pushes its point hard, about how we're all people and relationships are relationships, and that's where the comedy matters, making sure you don't take the delivery too seriously. If you have doubts that it's a farce with a silver lining, just wait until you see Gene Hackman at the end. You might argue that the social message is all that matters, and of course that's true to some ways of thinking (and in some camps of criticism), but that would limit the point of the whole affair. And as time goes on and people get more used to the idea of gay culture and gay people as just another aspect of life, well, the sensational aspects of the movie will water down. But that's fine. Besides being inevitable, it points to the other parts of the film, the Shakespearean cross-dressing, the play on identities, the constant repartee. It's funny and fun and yet smart, too. The plot, at its core, is an Americanized version of the original French play (from 1973) La Cage aux Folles (which means roughly "Cage of Drag Queens" if you take into account the slang for folles). And there is of course the famous two versions of the Broadway musical version (the 1983 and 2004 versions, not to mention the current one which started in 2010). It's a great story with a long life, clearly. And the playful interaction of the ensemble is perfect for the stage. Yet this isn't the play nor the musical, but the film, with a new name. And the photographic aspects are pretty wonderful, too. Take just the opening shot coming in on a helicopter over the water and seamlessly (almost, there's a frame or two glitch) gliding right into the night club, The Birdcage. And if you don't think the story has legs, there is a 1978 Italian version of the play (not the musical) on film. The advantage of the American version for American audiences is the references are still slightly recognizable (the Bob Dole comments are already seeming like history, however). Anyway, don't see this for Robin Williams. He's fine, but not the crackup fast talker that he's best at. And it isn't him, but Nathan Lane, who gets to cross-dress. Fabulously. You'll see.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Birds of a Feather
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    edwardtjbrown
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/5/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    In his younger days, Armand Goldman (Robin Williams) was a struggling, gay stage actor who decided to have a one night stand with a female friend (Christine Baranski). The result of this brief fling was Val Goldman (Futterman), who, in the present day, is engaged to be married to a lovely woman. Despite some initial misgivings that Val is too young to be married, Val's parents, Armand Goldman and his husband Albert, (Nathan Lane), agree to support the wedding. Yet, Barbra Keeley (Calita Rockhart), the bride-to-be, comes from a prominent political family in the middle of a tough re-election campaign. U.S. Senator Keeley, who thinks Bob Dole is too liberal, is the co-founder of a Christian Coalition-type interest group dedicated enacting laws promoting "moral order". He and his wife also feel that their daughter is too young to be married, and want to 'table' the wedding until after the campaign, especially when the head of the Moral Order Coalition is found dead in the bed of an underage, African American, prostitute. Seeing the writing on the wall, Barbara begins a clever ruse to depict the Goldman family as a traditional, white, Christian, Republican family whose politics are to the right of Patrick Buchanan, Jerry Falwell and Pat Roberston. Val convinces his parents to go to great lengths, changing their house, dress, mannerisms, religion and politics, to pull off this charade as the in-laws meet for dinner. As one might guess, much of the comedy in this film involves a 1990's satire of the right-wing politics, as well as the media's post-OJ Simpson trial (1995) obsession with tabloid and scandal driven news. Robin Williams and Nathan Lane are great together, although they show each other little affection, with Lane playing the more stereotypical gay man/drag queen entertainer, which manages to avoid coming off as mean spirited. Likewise, the Keeley are as stuffy as they are right-wing, but the film allows each of the family members to develop a character and story arch beyond simple card board cut outs. Oddly enough, the film does not really address gay rights, beyond the, often comedic, contrasts between the two families and the assumptions that are made. Armand and Albert are financially successful, owners of a hip nightclub. They live in a trendy, upscale urban neighborhood where discrimination and harassment does not seem to exist. Gays serving open in the military and legal recognition of same-sex marriage are mentioned, but Armand and Albert seem to be a couple that exists just slightly out of reality. They do argue over a palimony agreement and I am not sure how the film could have been anything else, given when it was made. In the early - mid 1990s, Hollywood films were just beginning to depict gay people in a manner that did not involve them being predatory, suicidal, homicidal manics. Yes, the film clearly mocks the stuffy, uptight future in-laws. Yes, it mocks their right-wing politics and prejudices directed at gay people as well as racial, religious and ethnic minorities. As great, witty and funny as this film is, sometimes it cannot hide its age.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Funny!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    nama chakravorty
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/2/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A remake of the 1978 film, La Cage aux Folles, 'The Birdcage' is an amusingly enjoyable film. Mike Nichols continues his magic in this 1996 cult-hit, The legendary filmmaker, along-with a stellar cast and a freaky screenplay, makes a truly funny film about everything gone haywire! 'The Birdcage' is about a gay cabaret owner and his drag queen companion agree to put up a false straight front so that their son can introduce them to his fianc&eacute;'s right-wing moralistic parents. Source taken from IMDb! To be honest, the film begins tepidly and it takes time to grasp each and every character's intentions and further plans. But once you get into the groove, you enter a joyride. The entire last hour, right after Gene Hackman & Co enter Williams house, there is hardly a moment when you don't laugh. Also, watching Gene Hackman as a drag in the climax, is simply hilarious! Mike Nichols directs the film with his usual midas touch. He is amongst the most talented filmmakers ever. The adapted Screenplay is full of absurd, funny, hilarious & strange situations. Cinematography by Emmanuel Lubezki is perfect. Editing could've been sharper. Now to the performances! With such a stellar cast coming under one roof, one expects nothing but exemplary acting. Each and Every Actor delivers in here. Robin Williams, Gene Hackman, Nathan Lane & Dianne Wiest are absolutely flawless. Dan Futterman, Calista Flockhart & Hank Azaria are at par with the seniors! On the whole, A Comedy that needs a watch. An absurd yet lovable experience! Thumbs Up!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Funniest movie I have ever seen
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bluebook-master
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Rarely does a movie cause me to laugh out loud so much as The Birdcage. The cast of characters is extraordinary. The interaction between Gene Hackman and Nathan Lane is priceless. Dan Futterman is not only drop dead gorgeous but his chemistry with Robin Williams is a perfect match. The dinner party reaches a climax with everyone singing "I could have danced all right" with Gene Hackman and Nathan Lane ballroom dancing. The closing scene with Gene Hackman dancing in drag and saying his white dress makes him look fat caused me to cry I was laughing so much. Whoever masterminded this cast of actors knew what they were doing. The film pokes fun at both the absurdity of right wing Republicans and over the top gay men running a nightclub - all humor done very tastefully. For an evening of pure entertainment you've got to see this movies- more than once.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The funniest gay-duo ever, with Robin Williams as the straight-man, so to speak 
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ElMaruecan82
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Traduttore, tradittore" the Italian adage seems to indicate that the transposition of a concept or an artistic creation to another language would inevitably betray its spirit. It's true that most of the times, comedy is the most likely genre to suffer from adaptation and the most eloquent proof can be found in the love-and-hate relationship between French comedies and their much inferior American remakes. Almost every Francis Veber's script for instance, was remade for American audience, and needless to say that some films turns out to be sour disasters, or average entertainments at best. Directed by Mike Nichols, "The Birdcage" is the remake of 'Birds of Feathers' ("La Cage aux Folles"), the greatest Italian-French comedy, starring Ugo Tognazzi and Michel Serrault, and one of the most successful French productions in America. Although it was fair for Nichols to assume that the 1996' audience wouldn't be familiar with the original film, it was risky as well to embrace such a politically incorrect theme, featuring a gay couple with one acting like a hysterical diva, and transpose it in the 90's where the 70's archetypes were no longer held as comedic devices. Needless to say that the performances of the whole cast was crucial, let alone Nathan Lane, who is the highlight of the show. The plot is pure screwball material, Armand (Williams) lives with Albert (Lane) for twenty years, Armand owns a gay burlesque bar in South Florida named "The Birdcage" and directs the very show where Albert stars. Albert acts like a capricious prima donna all the time, always seeming at the edge of a nervous breakdown, praising for attention, he's obviously the "lady" in the couple, and it seems quite fresh to see Williams as the most restrained one, and not let himself carried away by Albert's caprices. The rest of the house also features a Hank Azaria as a Guatemalan butler named Agador, his accent, extraordinary capability to imitate Estefan's "Konga" and some crazy one-liners are really under-appreciated. The routine is broken when Val, Armand's son announces his engagement with the daughter of a republican and notoriously conservative, a Senator named Kevin Keeley (Gene Hackman). Keeley isn't in a better phase because his closest friend and President of the Coalition of Moral Virtues was found dead with an underage black prostitute, a synthesis of every worst- case situation that can undermine a political career. Naturally, his daughter (a pre-McBeal Calista Flockhart) is forced to lie about Armand's profession and Keeley's wife (Dianne Wiest) seize the wedding as an opportunity to clear Keeley from the prejudice caused by the scandal. With these two set-ups, the movie takes off for one of the funniest and most enjoyable recent comedy of errors. Some would naturally get offended by Lane's portrayal of Albert, but the fact is that the film is precisely funny because he's effeminate. It gives its flavor to the scene where he wants to pretend he's Val's uncle, and then learns from Albert how to butter a toast like a man, and not get upset if it gets pierced, and walk like John Wayne. Albert's high pitched screams and overly-gay mannerisms contribute to some of the film's most laugh-out-loud moments and can't take you off totally off-guard, but Lane doesn't overplay them, he finds the right note in an over-the-top personality. And it never shows as well as in the scene where he comes, dressed like a man, only to betray some pink socks, that make even more obvious the fact that he's gay. And that's the basis of the whole comical premise, the more you pretend not to be something, the more it shows. But one thing Lane shows without pretending is how loving and caring he's for Val, and that's what makes his character so endearing and engaging. He's a clown but a sad and funny one, while Williams is the 'straight' man, comically speaking of course, and when a champagne bottle suddenly pops, the effect is immediate, it's pure comedic gold. There are two levels of comedies, where Williams is both the straight man and the clown of a masquerade, no wonder he spent the whole night drinking. Talk about a comical existential nightmare. The secret of "The Birdcage" is to remain faithful to the spirit of the first film, but not without taking some perspective from the original material. The fact that they're Jewish adds another running their name, is it Goldman or Coleman, is the 'd' silent or what? The political undertones are accentuated, maybe because it was before the election campaign, but they seem to be more fitting for the American context, and Gene Hackman is absolutely perfect as the Republican Senator who tries to hide his desperation between a cold facade, he's even more interesting than the original character because the screenplay enriches his personality with his genuine fondness on Albert. And we understand the Senator, Lane plays a drag with such genuine tenderness that we empathize with his desire to help Val. But since we know that it's meant to fail, we can only enjoy the way they keep the Senator believing. And it's indeed funny how Albert touches the Senator's heart when pretending to be Val's mother "they don't make women like that anymore", maybe in a way, Albert fulfilled his all-time dream to be a woman and be treated as well. "The Birdcage" is a film that should have deserved more recognition, less than a remake, it's more of a refreshing and modernization of the 70's version, and it's so lively, so flamboyant, so comical, it seems to reconcile with an idea of the 'gay' culture, that no matter how stereotypical it is, remains more enjoyable than its claim for banality. The style is dated but not the tone. "The Birdcage" deserves all its praises, it's not only one of the few successful American remakes of French comedies, it's more intelligent than what it seems  and it's funny as hell.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    If you don't get this movie, try some more gum
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ironhorse_iv
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I know that look. Hit me, go on. Hit me with why this movie isn't good, because I don't see that face plant of why I should hate this Mike Nichol's film. Yes, it might look like a pale copy of the original La Cage aux Folles, the 1978's French film in itself based on the 1973's play by Jean Poiret, but it's not a drag. Well, it's a drag in another way, but what I like about this remake is how they turns something from French, into a funny American movie. Armand Goldman (Robin Williams) owns a popular drag nightclub in South Miami Beach with his long-time lover Albert Goldman (Nathan Lane). Nathan Lane as Albert is a annoying character with his fits, non-stop complaining and diva like attitude. Some audience members might find the character too irritation to bother with the movie. Some audience members will look past that, due to fact that Albert is so hysterical due to his overreactions to everything. If some people dislike him, they would love the crude humor toward him from Armand. As much as Armand can not stand him, he sticks with Albert. Within the comedy, is a small great speech scene by Armand to Albert. These are two gay men of a certain age, and years of ostracism, threats and taunts would have conditioned them both to avoid any PDAs, no matter how strong the feeling between them. The speech gives the moment enormous poignancy feeling of genuine, heartfelt and caring to Albert. This scene is especially lovely, a great juxtaposition to the rest of the film which is wonderfully silly and comedic. Nathan Lane isn't the only one that nearly steals the movie from Robin Williams, as Armand's maid Agador Spartacus (Hank Azaria) takes a bite of funny throughout the film, with singing and dancing to music, making lousy food, and tripping over his own feet. Watching Agador was a delight, and pans away from Nathan Lane enough times, that we able to rest from his big, brassy yelling and complaining. Soon the Goldman's son Val (Dan Futterman) comes home to announce his engagement to Barbara Keely (Calista Flockhart), daughter of Kevin Keely (Gene Hackman), US Senator, and vice president of the extreme Committee for Moral Order and his wife (Dianne Wiest). First off, the actor Dan Futterman and Calista Flockhart were too old for the role, it felt weird in a way to see Calista play a awkward 18 year old. Both are in later scenes, boozing and smoking. Are we suppose to believe that a conservatism senator would allow his daughter to underage drink? Clearly both are wrong actors for the job. Gene Hackman as Kevin Keely is so extreme right conservatism, it makes the character seem like a political cartoon caricature less than a normal person. Kevin Keely decide to allow Barbara to marry Val only if they meet Val and his family at South Beach and use the marriage to get the media off of the scandal of his co-founder that been focus on him. While in Miami, Val fearing the worst like the Senator will not allow Barbara to marry him. Val tries to convince his father to hide his relationship with Albert and the fact that he is gay and Jewish. At first, Armand stood tall for his right to be open about his sexuality and his religious views, but seeing how much it would mean for him. He allow the dinner to happen, and to make himself seem straight and asking to get rid of Albert for the day was over the line. I just can't stand Dan Futterman's character, for this, what a jerk. First off, Calista's character is clearly old enough to get marry with or without her father permission, and second off, it was the 90's. It wasn't the Leave it to Beaver pre-sexualism freedom 1960's here. I felt it was wrong how Val treats his father to hide who his Father was, ask Albert to leave, all for a girl who only knew for a year. The whole thing was shameful on the part of the character. I know he wasn't in shame of his father's lifestyle, but he knew that Keelys wouldn't understand, and I know without this premise there is no movie, but still he only admit his fault to due to being catch, rather than seeing his wrongs on how he treated his father and Albert the last few days. I also felt the ending was a cop-out, as it's seem like there should had been an extra scene to show how the movie's plot got resolved. Yes it might seem like a bird-brained delight, but you just can't help loving it, and not taking it too serious. The movie acts less like La Cage aux Folles and more like a modern "You can't take it with you", a 1938 film. The music in the film is catchy, love the use of Sister Sledge- We are family, Gloria Estefan- conga, and Alan Lerner- I could have danced all night. It add with the positive good mood of the film. The whole singing scene before dinner was the best. What the movie does well is going beyond the stereotypes to see the character's depth and humanity, and that's why this movie should be check out. Try it, and you will find yourself liking it as much as I do.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not enjoyable
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    WakenPayne
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The main plot of this movie is basically that a gay club owner and his drag queen partner have a son that's getting married. For some reason they pose as being straight (with Nathan Lane in drag posing as his mother) to get the bride's parents approval or giving them the impression that they're straight because the father of the bride has anti-gay political views. I personally found the movie not really that funny at all, full of really bad gay jokes. I don't mind gay jokes (for a fact I have laughed hysterically at a couple over my teenage years) but that is really all this movie has to offer in terms of entertainment. I found the plot to be pointless (but that maybe just who I am). So if you like gay jokes then watch this, but don't really expect anything else.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Delightful Fun
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Jason Shaw
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    ￼ Put simply this is a glitzy, colourful, modern remake of La Cage aux Folles in which Robin Williams stars as the hairy and sweaty Armand, South Beach drag club owner alongside the incomparable Nathan Lane as the star and Armund's lover and partner Albert. Just like the original version, their lives are turned upside down and inside out when Armund's son, Val, comes home to announce he is getting married to an ultra-conservative senator's daughter called Barbara. Everything goes haywire and speeds up to comic high gear when those future in-laws come down to meet their daughters intended and his family. Scandal is what the senator wants to avoid at the great cost, you cannot blame him, and his co-founder of the coalition for moral order partnership has just been found dead in the bed of an underage black prostitute. There are laughs a plenty when first Armund and then Albert try and play it butch, they desperately need a woman and it's so not often you hear a couple of middle aged gay men scream that! In steps the wonderful and delightful Christine Baranski who always lights up the screen with a presence that is electrifying. However, is life that simple, that easy? You bet your sweet little arse it ain't! Barbara tells her parents that Armand is a cultural attach&eacute; to Greece, whilst Albert is a housewife, and that they divide their time between Greece and Florida. It is only a little white lie really, just as changing their last name from Goldman to Coleman is. The evening of the meeting arrives, the apartment above the drag club is transformed from gay paradise to near austere monastery, Val's real mother, Katherine (Baranski) is held up by traffic and a boat and out pops Albert as a wonderful creation of freakishly good yet awfully bad middle-aged mother. Armand and Val are both horrified at first but have no option to go along with the fa&ccedil;ade, which for some bizarre reason in this movie world works. More jokes, no proper meal and the most amazing china dinner service of naked boys playing leap- frog and still the senator and his wife do not catch on. Until that is at the door arrives Katherine, introducing herself as Val's mother and the whole charade is shot to pieces, just as TV news crews arrive out front How on earth can the senator and his wife leave the drag club without some kind of mass scandal erupting and ending his political career? The answer is simple, drag up and we are treated to the wonderful scene of Gene Hackman in a dress making the late great Bea Arthur look as feminine as a virginal princess. It is a great feel good movie, full of lightness, the jokes and funny situation fire by in rapid succession that you will probably not catch them all on the first viewing. Robin William's is superb as the nightclub owner even if he does sweat profusely at times and almost cracks up completely in the kitchen scene with the houseman come butler. I adore Nathan Lane, with his scene stealing 'Starina' performance and utter camp flamboyant majesty. Gene Hackman is equally good as the chocolate addicted extreme right wing senator with his sour face and dry delivery. As a modern re-make of a seventies classic it is both successful and complimentary, it also stands up on its own, which is a jolly good job, and for I am sure, the vast majority of its audience would not have seen La Cage aux Folles. Sure, it is lightweight, sure, it plays a little to stereotype, but it goes beyond them, reaching in to the human side and honest inner core aspect admirably. It is outrageously camp, unashamedly so, blatantly exotic and wonderfully charming, a great feel good movie. Read more and find out where this film made it in the Top 50 Most Influential Gay Movies of All Time book, search on Amazon for Top 50 Most Influential Gay Movies of All Time, or visit - http://www.amazon.co.uk/dp/B007FU7HPO
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    What a Hoot!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Ron-72
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/4/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I saw the original French film in 1979 - it was good, but not all that memorable. I saw the Broadway musical in 1983 - liked "I Am What I Am" and that was about all. But this version is just wonderful, probably because Mike Nichols and Elaine May who've known each other since forever worked on the script and Nichols can direct anything, especially with the cast he has here. They're all great, but Nathan Lane and Hank Azaria steal the show, and I don't think I've ever seen Gene Hackman as funny...I didn't know he could do comedy. What a collection of award-winners we have here, and thoroughly deserving of their SAG award for ensemble work.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not quite there...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    oceansroar
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/3/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Birdcage is a remake of a French film which i might have seen, but was too young, so i will check it soon. i am almost willing to bet that as usual with remakes of foreign films Hollywood fails. Perhaps they should promote the actual original films to the American audience, but i suppose the average American (not an intentional jab at American, since i have seen it around the world) will not watch a subtitled film. The story is about Armand, a gay man (Robin Williams) that owns a drag nightclub, in which his lover (Nathan Lane) performs as the starring act. The couple raised a son together for 20 years. The 20 year old son is now wanting to get married, but there are some complications, which make for a few hilarious moments, but only a few. i love the cast of this film, especially Robin Williams. When he is left to his own devices he can be brilliant or over the top, so he really needs a great director that allows him more room to fly, but a leash to pull him back to our atmosphere. This director held the leash too tightly, so Robin never quite got there. Nathan Lane steals most of the thunder from Robin, but he is a little over the top at times. Hank Azaria is brilliant as Agador the houseman. The cast is great, except Calista Flockhart seems a little drab in this film. If you have not watched it, then i recommended that you see it once, but keep an open mind, after all it is about a gay family. i gave it 5/10 because it does not hold up as well as it did in 1996 and the film as a whole was just not quite there.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of half a dozen verions of La Cage aux Folles out there, and Nathan Lane is devastating
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    secondtake
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/7/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Birdcage (1996) Well, there is always something great about a Mike Nichols film, and this one, written and directed by Nichols, is no exception. It is however a story that has had better presentations (see below) and I'm not sure why Nichols opted for such an un-original material. The movie really is great in some ways, and has terrific moments, but it doesn't transcend, as the best Nichols films certainly do. Robin Williams, the apparent big name on the marquee, is the weakest link in the cast (not including the two young people, who are fine but routine). But the rest of the main actors, Nathan Lane as the drag queen most of all, but Gene Hackman as a conservative senator and Dianne Wiest as his wife, are an amazing ensemble. Throw in consistently funny and clever writing (a functioanl adaptation), good camera-work, obviously attractive sets (this is South Beach in Miami), and a lively soundtrack and you sort of can't go far wrong. Is it brilliant? No way. It doesn't need to be. It's got jokes that will fade with time, topical references and timely jabs, but overall it's just perky and funny top to bottom. And relentlessly. And yes, it pushes its point hard, about how we're all people and relationships are relationships, and that's where the comedy matters, making sure you don't take the delivery too seriously. If you have doubts that it's a farce with a silver lining, just wait until you see Gene Hackman at the end. You might argue that the social message is all that matters, and of course that's true to some ways of thinking (and in some camps of criticism), but that would limit the point of the whole affair. And as time goes on and people get more used to the idea of gay culture and gay people as just another aspect of life, well, the sensational aspects of the movie will water down. But that's fine. Besides being inevitable, it points to the other parts of the film, the Shakespearean cross-dressing, the play on identities, the constant repartee. It's funny and fun and yet smart, too. The plot, at its core, is an Americanized version of the original French play (from 1973) La Cage aux Folles (which means roughly "Cage of Drag Queens" if you take into account the slang for folles). And there is of course the famous two versions of the Broadway musical version (the 1983 and 2004 versions, not to mention the current one which started in 2010). It's a great story with a long life, clearly. And the playful interaction of the ensemble is perfect for the stage. Yet this isn't the play nor the musical, but the film, with a new name. And the photographic aspects are pretty wonderful, too. Take just the opening shot coming in on a helicopter over the water and seamlessly (almost, there's a frame or two glitch) gliding right into the night club, The Birdcage. And if you don't think the story has legs, there is a 1978 Italian version of the play (not the musical) on film. The advantage of the American version for American audiences is the references are still slightly recognizable (the Bob Dole comments are already seeming like history, however). Anyway, don't see this for Robin Williams. He's fine, but not the crackup fast talker that he's best at. And it isn't him, but Nathan Lane, who gets to cross-dress. Fabulously. You'll see.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Birds of a Feather
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    edwardtjbrown
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/5/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    In his younger days, Armand Goldman (Robin Williams) was a struggling, gay stage actor who decided to have a one night stand with a female friend (Christine Baranski). The result of this brief fling was Val Goldman (Futterman), who, in the present day, is engaged to be married to a lovely woman. Despite some initial misgivings that Val is too young to be married, Val's parents, Armand Goldman and his husband Albert, (Nathan Lane), agree to support the wedding. Yet, Barbra Keeley (Calita Rockhart), the bride-to-be, comes from a prominent political family in the middle of a tough re-election campaign. U.S. Senator Keeley, who thinks Bob Dole is too liberal, is the co-founder of a Christian Coalition-type interest group dedicated enacting laws promoting "moral order". He and his wife also feel that their daughter is too young to be married, and want to 'table' the wedding until after the campaign, especially when the head of the Moral Order Coalition is found dead in the bed of an underage, African American, prostitute. Seeing the writing on the wall, Barbara begins a clever ruse to depict the Goldman family as a traditional, white, Christian, Republican family whose politics are to the right of Patrick Buchanan, Jerry Falwell and Pat Roberston. Val convinces his parents to go to great lengths, changing their house, dress, mannerisms, religion and politics, to pull off this charade as the in-laws meet for dinner. As one might guess, much of the comedy in this film involves a 1990's satire of the right-wing politics, as well as the media's post-OJ Simpson trial (1995) obsession with tabloid and scandal driven news. Robin Williams and Nathan Lane are great together, although they show each other little affection, with Lane playing the more stereotypical gay man/drag queen entertainer, which manages to avoid coming off as mean spirited. Likewise, the Keeley are as stuffy as they are right-wing, but the film allows each of the family members to develop a character and story arch beyond simple card board cut outs. Oddly enough, the film does not really address gay rights, beyond the, often comedic, contrasts between the two families and the assumptions that are made. Armand and Albert are financially successful, owners of a hip nightclub. They live in a trendy, upscale urban neighborhood where discrimination and harassment does not seem to exist. Gays serving open in the military and legal recognition of same-sex marriage are mentioned, but Armand and Albert seem to be a couple that exists just slightly out of reality. They do argue over a palimony agreement and I am not sure how the film could have been anything else, given when it was made. In the early - mid 1990s, Hollywood films were just beginning to depict gay people in a manner that did not involve them being predatory, suicidal, homicidal manics. Yes, the film clearly mocks the stuffy, uptight future in-laws. Yes, it mocks their right-wing politics and prejudices directed at gay people as well as racial, religious and ethnic minorities. As great, witty and funny as this film is, sometimes it cannot hide its age.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Funny!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    nama chakravorty
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/2/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A remake of the 1978 film, La Cage aux Folles, 'The Birdcage' is an amusingly enjoyable film. Mike Nichols continues his magic in this 1996 cult-hit, The legendary filmmaker, along-with a stellar cast and a freaky screenplay, makes a truly funny film about everything gone haywire! 'The Birdcage' is about a gay cabaret owner and his drag queen companion agree to put up a false straight front so that their son can introduce them to his fianc&eacute;'s right-wing moralistic parents. Source taken from IMDb! To be honest, the film begins tepidly and it takes time to grasp each and every character's intentions and further plans. But once you get into the groove, you enter a joyride. The entire last hour, right after Gene Hackman & Co enter Williams house, there is hardly a moment when you don't laugh. Also, watching Gene Hackman as a drag in the climax, is simply hilarious! Mike Nichols directs the film with his usual midas touch. He is amongst the most talented filmmakers ever. The adapted Screenplay is full of absurd, funny, hilarious & strange situations. Cinematography by Emmanuel Lubezki is perfect. Editing could've been sharper. Now to the performances! With such a stellar cast coming under one roof, one expects nothing but exemplary acting. Each and Every Actor delivers in here. Robin Williams, Gene Hackman, Nathan Lane & Dianne Wiest are absolutely flawless. Dan Futterman, Calista Flockhart & Hank Azaria are at par with the seniors! On the whole, A Comedy that needs a watch. An absurd yet lovable experience! Thumbs Up!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Funniest movie I have ever seen
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bluebook-master
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Rarely does a movie cause me to laugh out loud so much as The Birdcage. The cast of characters is extraordinary. The interaction between Gene Hackman and Nathan Lane is priceless. Dan Futterman is not only drop dead gorgeous but his chemistry with Robin Williams is a perfect match. The dinner party reaches a climax with everyone singing "I could have danced all right" with Gene Hackman and Nathan Lane ballroom dancing. The closing scene with Gene Hackman dancing in drag and saying his white dress makes him look fat caused me to cry I was laughing so much. Whoever masterminded this cast of actors knew what they were doing. The film pokes fun at both the absurdity of right wing Republicans and over the top gay men running a nightclub - all humor done very tastefully. For an evening of pure entertainment you've got to see this movies- more than once.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The funniest gay-duo ever, with Robin Williams as the straight-man, so to speak 
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ElMaruecan82
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Traduttore, tradittore" the Italian adage seems to indicate that the transposition of a concept or an artistic creation to another language would inevitably betray its spirit. It's true that most of the times, comedy is the most likely genre to suffer from adaptation and the most eloquent proof can be found in the love-and-hate relationship between French comedies and their much inferior American remakes. Almost every Francis Veber's script for instance, was remade for American audience, and needless to say that some films turns out to be sour disasters, or average entertainments at best. Directed by Mike Nichols, "The Birdcage" is the remake of 'Birds of Feathers' ("La Cage aux Folles"), the greatest Italian-French comedy, starring Ugo Tognazzi and Michel Serrault, and one of the most successful French productions in America. Although it was fair for Nichols to assume that the 1996' audience wouldn't be familiar with the original film, it was risky as well to embrace such a politically incorrect theme, featuring a gay couple with one acting like a hysterical diva, and transpose it in the 90's where the 70's archetypes were no longer held as comedic devices. Needless to say that the performances of the whole cast was crucial, let alone Nathan Lane, who is the highlight of the show. The plot is pure screwball material, Armand (Williams) lives with Albert (Lane) for twenty years, Armand owns a gay burlesque bar in South Florida named "The Birdcage" and directs the very show where Albert stars. Albert acts like a capricious prima donna all the time, always seeming at the edge of a nervous breakdown, praising for attention, he's obviously the "lady" in the couple, and it seems quite fresh to see Williams as the most restrained one, and not let himself carried away by Albert's caprices. The rest of the house also features a Hank Azaria as a Guatemalan butler named Agador, his accent, extraordinary capability to imitate Estefan's "Konga" and some crazy one-liners are really under-appreciated. The routine is broken when Val, Armand's son announces his engagement with the daughter of a republican and notoriously conservative, a Senator named Kevin Keeley (Gene Hackman). Keeley isn't in a better phase because his closest friend and President of the Coalition of Moral Virtues was found dead with an underage black prostitute, a synthesis of every worst- case situation that can undermine a political career. Naturally, his daughter (a pre-McBeal Calista Flockhart) is forced to lie about Armand's profession and Keeley's wife (Dianne Wiest) seize the wedding as an opportunity to clear Keeley from the prejudice caused by the scandal. With these two set-ups, the movie takes off for one of the funniest and most enjoyable recent comedy of errors. Some would naturally get offended by Lane's portrayal of Albert, but the fact is that the film is precisely funny because he's effeminate. It gives its flavor to the scene where he wants to pretend he's Val's uncle, and then learns from Albert how to butter a toast like a man, and not get upset if it gets pierced, and walk like John Wayne. Albert's high pitched screams and overly-gay mannerisms contribute to some of the film's most laugh-out-loud moments and can't take you off totally off-guard, but Lane doesn't overplay them, he finds the right note in an over-the-top personality. And it never shows as well as in the scene where he comes, dressed like a man, only to betray some pink socks, that make even more obvious the fact that he's gay. And that's the basis of the whole comical premise, the more you pretend not to be something, the more it shows. But one thing Lane shows without pretending is how loving and caring he's for Val, and that's what makes his character so endearing and engaging. He's a clown but a sad and funny one, while Williams is the 'straight' man, comically speaking of course, and when a champagne bottle suddenly pops, the effect is immediate, it's pure comedic gold. There are two levels of comedies, where Williams is both the straight man and the clown of a masquerade, no wonder he spent the whole night drinking. Talk about a comical existential nightmare. The secret of "The Birdcage" is to remain faithful to the spirit of the first film, but not without taking some perspective from the original material. The fact that they're Jewish adds another running their name, is it Goldman or Coleman, is the 'd' silent or what? The political undertones are accentuated, maybe because it was before the election campaign, but they seem to be more fitting for the American context, and Gene Hackman is absolutely perfect as the Republican Senator who tries to hide his desperation between a cold facade, he's even more interesting than the original character because the screenplay enriches his personality with his genuine fondness on Albert. And we understand the Senator, Lane plays a drag with such genuine tenderness that we empathize with his desire to help Val. But since we know that it's meant to fail, we can only enjoy the way they keep the Senator believing. And it's indeed funny how Albert touches the Senator's heart when pretending to be Val's mother "they don't make women like that anymore", maybe in a way, Albert fulfilled his all-time dream to be a woman and be treated as well. "The Birdcage" is a film that should have deserved more recognition, less than a remake, it's more of a refreshing and modernization of the 70's version, and it's so lively, so flamboyant, so comical, it seems to reconcile with an idea of the 'gay' culture, that no matter how stereotypical it is, remains more enjoyable than its claim for banality. The style is dated but not the tone. "The Birdcage" deserves all its praises, it's not only one of the few successful American remakes of French comedies, it's more intelligent than what it seems  and it's funny as hell.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    If you don't get this movie, try some more gum
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ironhorse_iv
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I know that look. Hit me, go on. Hit me with why this movie isn't good, because I don't see that face plant of why I should hate this Mike Nichol's film. Yes, it might look like a pale copy of the original La Cage aux Folles, the 1978's French film in itself based on the 1973's play by Jean Poiret, but it's not a drag. Well, it's a drag in another way, but what I like about this remake is how they turns something from French, into a funny American movie. Armand Goldman (Robin Williams) owns a popular drag nightclub in South Miami Beach with his long-time lover Albert Goldman (Nathan Lane). Nathan Lane as Albert is a annoying character with his fits, non-stop complaining and diva like attitude. Some audience members might find the character too irritation to bother with the movie. Some audience members will look past that, due to fact that Albert is so hysterical due to his overreactions to everything. If some people dislike him, they would love the crude humor toward him from Armand. As much as Armand can not stand him, he sticks with Albert. Within the comedy, is a small great speech scene by Armand to Albert. These are two gay men of a certain age, and years of ostracism, threats and taunts would have conditioned them both to avoid any PDAs, no matter how strong the feeling between them. The speech gives the moment enormous poignancy feeling of genuine, heartfelt and caring to Albert. This scene is especially lovely, a great juxtaposition to the rest of the film which is wonderfully silly and comedic. Nathan Lane isn't the only one that nearly steals the movie from Robin Williams, as Armand's maid Agador Spartacus (Hank Azaria) takes a bite of funny throughout the film, with singing and dancing to music, making lousy food, and tripping over his own feet. Watching Agador was a delight, and pans away from Nathan Lane enough times, that we able to rest from his big, brassy yelling and complaining. Soon the Goldman's son Val (Dan Futterman) comes home to announce his engagement to Barbara Keely (Calista Flockhart), daughter of Kevin Keely (Gene Hackman), US Senator, and vice president of the extreme Committee for Moral Order and his wife (Dianne Wiest). First off, the actor Dan Futterman and Calista Flockhart were too old for the role, it felt weird in a way to see Calista play a awkward 18 year old. Both are in later scenes, boozing and smoking. Are we suppose to believe that a conservatism senator would allow his daughter to underage drink? Clearly both are wrong actors for the job. Gene Hackman as Kevin Keely is so extreme right conservatism, it makes the character seem like a political cartoon caricature less than a normal person. Kevin Keely decide to allow Barbara to marry Val only if they meet Val and his family at South Beach and use the marriage to get the media off of the scandal of his co-founder that been focus on him. While in Miami, Val fearing the worst like the Senator will not allow Barbara to marry him. Val tries to convince his father to hide his relationship with Albert and the fact that he is gay and Jewish. At first, Armand stood tall for his right to be open about his sexuality and his religious views, but seeing how much it would mean for him. He allow the dinner to happen, and to make himself seem straight and asking to get rid of Albert for the day was over the line. I just can't stand Dan Futterman's character, for this, what a jerk. First off, Calista's character is clearly old enough to get marry with or without her father permission, and second off, it was the 90's. It wasn't the Leave it to Beaver pre-sexualism freedom 1960's here. I felt it was wrong how Val treats his father to hide who his Father was, ask Albert to leave, all for a girl who only knew for a year. The whole thing was shameful on the part of the character. I know he wasn't in shame of his father's lifestyle, but he knew that Keelys wouldn't understand, and I know without this premise there is no movie, but still he only admit his fault to due to being catch, rather than seeing his wrongs on how he treated his father and Albert the last few days. I also felt the ending was a cop-out, as it's seem like there should had been an extra scene to show how the movie's plot got resolved. Yes it might seem like a bird-brained delight, but you just can't help loving it, and not taking it too serious. The movie acts less like La Cage aux Folles and more like a modern "You can't take it with you", a 1938 film. The music in the film is catchy, love the use of Sister Sledge- We are family, Gloria Estefan- conga, and Alan Lerner- I could have danced all night. It add with the positive good mood of the film. The whole singing scene before dinner was the best. What the movie does well is going beyond the stereotypes to see the character's depth and humanity, and that's why this movie should be check out. Try it, and you will find yourself liking it as much as I do.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not enjoyable
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    WakenPayne
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The main plot of this movie is basically that a gay club owner and his drag queen partner have a son that's getting married. For some reason they pose as being straight (with Nathan Lane in drag posing as his mother) to get the bride's parents approval or giving them the impression that they're straight because the father of the bride has anti-gay political views. I personally found the movie not really that funny at all, full of really bad gay jokes. I don't mind gay jokes (for a fact I have laughed hysterically at a couple over my teenage years) but that is really all this movie has to offer in terms of entertainment. I found the plot to be pointless (but that maybe just who I am). So if you like gay jokes then watch this, but don't really expect anything else.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Delightful Fun
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Jason Shaw
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    ￼ Put simply this is a glitzy, colourful, modern remake of La Cage aux Folles in which Robin Williams stars as the hairy and sweaty Armand, South Beach drag club owner alongside the incomparable Nathan Lane as the star and Armund's lover and partner Albert. Just like the original version, their lives are turned upside down and inside out when Armund's son, Val, comes home to announce he is getting married to an ultra-conservative senator's daughter called Barbara. Everything goes haywire and speeds up to comic high gear when those future in-laws come down to meet their daughters intended and his family. Scandal is what the senator wants to avoid at the great cost, you cannot blame him, and his co-founder of the coalition for moral order partnership has just been found dead in the bed of an underage black prostitute. There are laughs a plenty when first Armund and then Albert try and play it butch, they desperately need a woman and it's so not often you hear a couple of middle aged gay men scream that! In steps the wonderful and delightful Christine Baranski who always lights up the screen with a presence that is electrifying. However, is life that simple, that easy? You bet your sweet little arse it ain't! Barbara tells her parents that Armand is a cultural attach&eacute; to Greece, whilst Albert is a housewife, and that they divide their time between Greece and Florida. It is only a little white lie really, just as changing their last name from Goldman to Coleman is. The evening of the meeting arrives, the apartment above the drag club is transformed from gay paradise to near austere monastery, Val's real mother, Katherine (Baranski) is held up by traffic and a boat and out pops Albert as a wonderful creation of freakishly good yet awfully bad middle-aged mother. Armand and Val are both horrified at first but have no option to go along with the fa&ccedil;ade, which for some bizarre reason in this movie world works. More jokes, no proper meal and the most amazing china dinner service of naked boys playing leap- frog and still the senator and his wife do not catch on. Until that is at the door arrives Katherine, introducing herself as Val's mother and the whole charade is shot to pieces, just as TV news crews arrive out front How on earth can the senator and his wife leave the drag club without some kind of mass scandal erupting and ending his political career? The answer is simple, drag up and we are treated to the wonderful scene of Gene Hackman in a dress making the late great Bea Arthur look as feminine as a virginal princess. It is a great feel good movie, full of lightness, the jokes and funny situation fire by in rapid succession that you will probably not catch them all on the first viewing. Robin William's is superb as the nightclub owner even if he does sweat profusely at times and almost cracks up completely in the kitchen scene with the houseman come butler. I adore Nathan Lane, with his scene stealing 'Starina' performance and utter camp flamboyant majesty. Gene Hackman is equally good as the chocolate addicted extreme right wing senator with his sour face and dry delivery. As a modern re-make of a seventies classic it is both successful and complimentary, it also stands up on its own, which is a jolly good job, and for I am sure, the vast majority of its audience would not have seen La Cage aux Folles. Sure, it is lightweight, sure, it plays a little to stereotype, but it goes beyond them, reaching in to the human side and honest inner core aspect admirably. It is outrageously camp, unashamedly so, blatantly exotic and wonderfully charming, a great feel good movie. Read more and find out where this film made it in the Top 50 Most Influential Gay Movies of All Time book, search on Amazon for Top 50 Most Influential Gay Movies of All Time, or visit - http://www.amazon.co.uk/dp/B007FU7HPO
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    What a Hoot!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Ron-72
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/4/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I saw the original French film in 1979 - it was good, but not all that memorable. I saw the Broadway musical in 1983 - liked "I Am What I Am" and that was about all. But this version is just wonderful, probably because Mike Nichols and Elaine May who've known each other since forever worked on the script and Nichols can direct anything, especially with the cast he has here. They're all great, but Nathan Lane and Hank Azaria steal the show, and I don't think I've ever seen Gene Hackman as funny...I didn't know he could do comedy. What a collection of award-winners we have here, and thoroughly deserving of their SAG award for ensemble work.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not quite there...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    oceansroar
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/3/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Birdcage is a remake of a French film which i might have seen, but was too young, so i will check it soon. i am almost willing to bet that as usual with remakes of foreign films Hollywood fails. Perhaps they should promote the actual original films to the American audience, but i suppose the average American (not an intentional jab at American, since i have seen it around the world) will not watch a subtitled film. The story is about Armand, a gay man (Robin Williams) that owns a drag nightclub, in which his lover (Nathan Lane) performs as the starring act. The couple raised a son together for 20 years. The 20 year old son is now wanting to get married, but there are some complications, which make for a few hilarious moments, but only a few. i love the cast of this film, especially Robin Williams. When he is left to his own devices he can be brilliant or over the top, so he really needs a great director that allows him more room to fly, but a leash to pull him back to our atmosphere. This director held the leash too tightly, so Robin never quite got there. Nathan Lane steals most of the thunder from Robin, but he is a little over the top at times. Hank Azaria is brilliant as Agador the houseman. The cast is great, except Calista Flockhart seems a little drab in this film. If you have not watched it, then i recommended that you see it once, but keep an open mind, after all it is about a gay family. i gave it 5/10 because it does not hold up as well as it did in 1996 and the film as a whole was just not quite there.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of half a dozen verions of La Cage aux Folles out there, and Nathan Lane is devastating
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    secondtake
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/7/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Birdcage (1996) Well, there is always something great about a Mike Nichols film, and this one, written and directed by Nichols, is no exception. It is however a story that has had better presentations (see below) and I'm not sure why Nichols opted for such an un-original material. The movie really is great in some ways, and has terrific moments, but it doesn't transcend, as the best Nichols films certainly do. Robin Williams, the apparent big name on the marquee, is the weakest link in the cast (not including the two young people, who are fine but routine). But the rest of the main actors, Nathan Lane as the drag queen most of all, but Gene Hackman as a conservative senator and Dianne Wiest as his wife, are an amazing ensemble. Throw in consistently funny and clever writing (a functioanl adaptation), good camera-work, obviously attractive sets (this is South Beach in Miami), and a lively soundtrack and you sort of can't go far wrong. Is it brilliant? No way. It doesn't need to be. It's got jokes that will fade with time, topical references and timely jabs, but overall it's just perky and funny top to bottom. And relentlessly. And yes, it pushes its point hard, about how we're all people and relationships are relationships, and that's where the comedy matters, making sure you don't take the delivery too seriously. If you have doubts that it's a farce with a silver lining, just wait until you see Gene Hackman at the end. You might argue that the social message is all that matters, and of course that's true to some ways of thinking (and in some camps of criticism), but that would limit the point of the whole affair. And as time goes on and people get more used to the idea of gay culture and gay people as just another aspect of life, well, the sensational aspects of the movie will water down. But that's fine. Besides being inevitable, it points to the other parts of the film, the Shakespearean cross-dressing, the play on identities, the constant repartee. It's funny and fun and yet smart, too. The plot, at its core, is an Americanized version of the original French play (from 1973) La Cage aux Folles (which means roughly "Cage of Drag Queens" if you take into account the slang for folles). And there is of course the famous two versions of the Broadway musical version (the 1983 and 2004 versions, not to mention the current one which started in 2010). It's a great story with a long life, clearly. And the playful interaction of the ensemble is perfect for the stage. Yet this isn't the play nor the musical, but the film, with a new name. And the photographic aspects are pretty wonderful, too. Take just the opening shot coming in on a helicopter over the water and seamlessly (almost, there's a frame or two glitch) gliding right into the night club, The Birdcage. And if you don't think the story has legs, there is a 1978 Italian version of the play (not the musical) on film. The advantage of the American version for American audiences is the references are still slightly recognizable (the Bob Dole comments are already seeming like history, however). Anyway, don't see this for Robin Williams. He's fine, but not the crackup fast talker that he's best at. And it isn't him, but Nathan Lane, who gets to cross-dress. Fabulously. You'll see.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Birds of a Feather
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    edwardtjbrown
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/5/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    In his younger days, Armand Goldman (Robin Williams) was a struggling, gay stage actor who decided to have a one night stand with a female friend (Christine Baranski). The result of this brief fling was Val Goldman (Futterman), who, in the present day, is engaged to be married to a lovely woman. Despite some initial misgivings that Val is too young to be married, Val's parents, Armand Goldman and his husband Albert, (Nathan Lane), agree to support the wedding. Yet, Barbra Keeley (Calita Rockhart), the bride-to-be, comes from a prominent political family in the middle of a tough re-election campaign. U.S. Senator Keeley, who thinks Bob Dole is too liberal, is the co-founder of a Christian Coalition-type interest group dedicated enacting laws promoting "moral order". He and his wife also feel that their daughter is too young to be married, and want to 'table' the wedding until after the campaign, especially when the head of the Moral Order Coalition is found dead in the bed of an underage, African American, prostitute. Seeing the writing on the wall, Barbara begins a clever ruse to depict the Goldman family as a traditional, white, Christian, Republican family whose politics are to the right of Patrick Buchanan, Jerry Falwell and Pat Roberston. Val convinces his parents to go to great lengths, changing their house, dress, mannerisms, religion and politics, to pull off this charade as the in-laws meet for dinner. As one might guess, much of the comedy in this film involves a 1990's satire of the right-wing politics, as well as the media's post-OJ Simpson trial (1995) obsession with tabloid and scandal driven news. Robin Williams and Nathan Lane are great together, although they show each other little affection, with Lane playing the more stereotypical gay man/drag queen entertainer, which manages to avoid coming off as mean spirited. Likewise, the Keeley are as stuffy as they are right-wing, but the film allows each of the family members to develop a character and story arch beyond simple card board cut outs. Oddly enough, the film does not really address gay rights, beyond the, often comedic, contrasts between the two families and the assumptions that are made. Armand and Albert are financially successful, owners of a hip nightclub. They live in a trendy, upscale urban neighborhood where discrimination and harassment does not seem to exist. Gays serving open in the military and legal recognition of same-sex marriage are mentioned, but Armand and Albert seem to be a couple that exists just slightly out of reality. They do argue over a palimony agreement and I am not sure how the film could have been anything else, given when it was made. In the early - mid 1990s, Hollywood films were just beginning to depict gay people in a manner that did not involve them being predatory, suicidal, homicidal manics. Yes, the film clearly mocks the stuffy, uptight future in-laws. Yes, it mocks their right-wing politics and prejudices directed at gay people as well as racial, religious and ethnic minorities. As great, witty and funny as this film is, sometimes it cannot hide its age.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Funny!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    nama chakravorty
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/2/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A remake of the 1978 film, La Cage aux Folles, 'The Birdcage' is an amusingly enjoyable film. Mike Nichols continues his magic in this 1996 cult-hit, The legendary filmmaker, along-with a stellar cast and a freaky screenplay, makes a truly funny film about everything gone haywire! 'The Birdcage' is about a gay cabaret owner and his drag queen companion agree to put up a false straight front so that their son can introduce them to his fianc&eacute;'s right-wing moralistic parents. Source taken from IMDb! To be honest, the film begins tepidly and it takes time to grasp each and every character's intentions and further plans. But once you get into the groove, you enter a joyride. The entire last hour, right after Gene Hackman & Co enter Williams house, there is hardly a moment when you don't laugh. Also, watching Gene Hackman as a drag in the climax, is simply hilarious! Mike Nichols directs the film with his usual midas touch. He is amongst the most talented filmmakers ever. The adapted Screenplay is full of absurd, funny, hilarious & strange situations. Cinematography by Emmanuel Lubezki is perfect. Editing could've been sharper. Now to the performances! With such a stellar cast coming under one roof, one expects nothing but exemplary acting. Each and Every Actor delivers in here. Robin Williams, Gene Hackman, Nathan Lane & Dianne Wiest are absolutely flawless. Dan Futterman, Calista Flockhart & Hank Azaria are at par with the seniors! On the whole, A Comedy that needs a watch. An absurd yet lovable experience! Thumbs Up!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Funniest movie I have ever seen
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bluebook-master
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Rarely does a movie cause me to laugh out loud so much as The Birdcage. The cast of characters is extraordinary. The interaction between Gene Hackman and Nathan Lane is priceless. Dan Futterman is not only drop dead gorgeous but his chemistry with Robin Williams is a perfect match. The dinner party reaches a climax with everyone singing "I could have danced all right" with Gene Hackman and Nathan Lane ballroom dancing. The closing scene with Gene Hackman dancing in drag and saying his white dress makes him look fat caused me to cry I was laughing so much. Whoever masterminded this cast of actors knew what they were doing. The film pokes fun at both the absurdity of right wing Republicans and over the top gay men running a nightclub - all humor done very tastefully. For an evening of pure entertainment you've got to see this movies- more than once.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The funniest gay-duo ever, with Robin Williams as the straight-man, so to speak 
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ElMaruecan82
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Traduttore, tradittore" the Italian adage seems to indicate that the transposition of a concept or an artistic creation to another language would inevitably betray its spirit. It's true that most of the times, comedy is the most likely genre to suffer from adaptation and the most eloquent proof can be found in the love-and-hate relationship between French comedies and their much inferior American remakes. Almost every Francis Veber's script for instance, was remade for American audience, and needless to say that some films turns out to be sour disasters, or average entertainments at best. Directed by Mike Nichols, "The Birdcage" is the remake of 'Birds of Feathers' ("La Cage aux Folles"), the greatest Italian-French comedy, starring Ugo Tognazzi and Michel Serrault, and one of the most successful French productions in America. Although it was fair for Nichols to assume that the 1996' audience wouldn't be familiar with the original film, it was risky as well to embrace such a politically incorrect theme, featuring a gay couple with one acting like a hysterical diva, and transpose it in the 90's where the 70's archetypes were no longer held as comedic devices. Needless to say that the performances of the whole cast was crucial, let alone Nathan Lane, who is the highlight of the show. The plot is pure screwball material, Armand (Williams) lives with Albert (Lane) for twenty years, Armand owns a gay burlesque bar in South Florida named "The Birdcage" and directs the very show where Albert stars. Albert acts like a capricious prima donna all the time, always seeming at the edge of a nervous breakdown, praising for attention, he's obviously the "lady" in the couple, and it seems quite fresh to see Williams as the most restrained one, and not let himself carried away by Albert's caprices. The rest of the house also features a Hank Azaria as a Guatemalan butler named Agador, his accent, extraordinary capability to imitate Estefan's "Konga" and some crazy one-liners are really under-appreciated. The routine is broken when Val, Armand's son announces his engagement with the daughter of a republican and notoriously conservative, a Senator named Kevin Keeley (Gene Hackman). Keeley isn't in a better phase because his closest friend and President of the Coalition of Moral Virtues was found dead with an underage black prostitute, a synthesis of every worst- case situation that can undermine a political career. Naturally, his daughter (a pre-McBeal Calista Flockhart) is forced to lie about Armand's profession and Keeley's wife (Dianne Wiest) seize the wedding as an opportunity to clear Keeley from the prejudice caused by the scandal. With these two set-ups, the movie takes off for one of the funniest and most enjoyable recent comedy of errors. Some would naturally get offended by Lane's portrayal of Albert, but the fact is that the film is precisely funny because he's effeminate. It gives its flavor to the scene where he wants to pretend he's Val's uncle, and then learns from Albert how to butter a toast like a man, and not get upset if it gets pierced, and walk like John Wayne. Albert's high pitched screams and overly-gay mannerisms contribute to some of the film's most laugh-out-loud moments and can't take you off totally off-guard, but Lane doesn't overplay them, he finds the right note in an over-the-top personality. And it never shows as well as in the scene where he comes, dressed like a man, only to betray some pink socks, that make even more obvious the fact that he's gay. And that's the basis of the whole comical premise, the more you pretend not to be something, the more it shows. But one thing Lane shows without pretending is how loving and caring he's for Val, and that's what makes his character so endearing and engaging. He's a clown but a sad and funny one, while Williams is the 'straight' man, comically speaking of course, and when a champagne bottle suddenly pops, the effect is immediate, it's pure comedic gold. There are two levels of comedies, where Williams is both the straight man and the clown of a masquerade, no wonder he spent the whole night drinking. Talk about a comical existential nightmare. The secret of "The Birdcage" is to remain faithful to the spirit of the first film, but not without taking some perspective from the original material. The fact that they're Jewish adds another running their name, is it Goldman or Coleman, is the 'd' silent or what? The political undertones are accentuated, maybe because it was before the election campaign, but they seem to be more fitting for the American context, and Gene Hackman is absolutely perfect as the Republican Senator who tries to hide his desperation between a cold facade, he's even more interesting than the original character because the screenplay enriches his personality with his genuine fondness on Albert. And we understand the Senator, Lane plays a drag with such genuine tenderness that we empathize with his desire to help Val. But since we know that it's meant to fail, we can only enjoy the way they keep the Senator believing. And it's indeed funny how Albert touches the Senator's heart when pretending to be Val's mother "they don't make women like that anymore", maybe in a way, Albert fulfilled his all-time dream to be a woman and be treated as well. "The Birdcage" is a film that should have deserved more recognition, less than a remake, it's more of a refreshing and modernization of the 70's version, and it's so lively, so flamboyant, so comical, it seems to reconcile with an idea of the 'gay' culture, that no matter how stereotypical it is, remains more enjoyable than its claim for banality. The style is dated but not the tone. "The Birdcage" deserves all its praises, it's not only one of the few successful American remakes of French comedies, it's more intelligent than what it seems  and it's funny as hell.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    If you don't get this movie, try some more gum
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ironhorse_iv
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I know that look. Hit me, go on. Hit me with why this movie isn't good, because I don't see that face plant of why I should hate this Mike Nichol's film. Yes, it might look like a pale copy of the original La Cage aux Folles, the 1978's French film in itself based on the 1973's play by Jean Poiret, but it's not a drag. Well, it's a drag in another way, but what I like about this remake is how they turns something from French, into a funny American movie. Armand Goldman (Robin Williams) owns a popular drag nightclub in South Miami Beach with his long-time lover Albert Goldman (Nathan Lane). Nathan Lane as Albert is a annoying character with his fits, non-stop complaining and diva like attitude. Some audience members might find the character too irritation to bother with the movie. Some audience members will look past that, due to fact that Albert is so hysterical due to his overreactions to everything. If some people dislike him, they would love the crude humor toward him from Armand. As much as Armand can not stand him, he sticks with Albert. Within the comedy, is a small great speech scene by Armand to Albert. These are two gay men of a certain age, and years of ostracism, threats and taunts would have conditioned them both to avoid any PDAs, no matter how strong the feeling between them. The speech gives the moment enormous poignancy feeling of genuine, heartfelt and caring to Albert. This scene is especially lovely, a great juxtaposition to the rest of the film which is wonderfully silly and comedic. Nathan Lane isn't the only one that nearly steals the movie from Robin Williams, as Armand's maid Agador Spartacus (Hank Azaria) takes a bite of funny throughout the film, with singing and dancing to music, making lousy food, and tripping over his own feet. Watching Agador was a delight, and pans away from Nathan Lane enough times, that we able to rest from his big, brassy yelling and complaining. Soon the Goldman's son Val (Dan Futterman) comes home to announce his engagement to Barbara Keely (Calista Flockhart), daughter of Kevin Keely (Gene Hackman), US Senator, and vice president of the extreme Committee for Moral Order and his wife (Dianne Wiest). First off, the actor Dan Futterman and Calista Flockhart were too old for the role, it felt weird in a way to see Calista play a awkward 18 year old. Both are in later scenes, boozing and smoking. Are we suppose to believe that a conservatism senator would allow his daughter to underage drink? Clearly both are wrong actors for the job. Gene Hackman as Kevin Keely is so extreme right conservatism, it makes the character seem like a political cartoon caricature less than a normal person. Kevin Keely decide to allow Barbara to marry Val only if they meet Val and his family at South Beach and use the marriage to get the media off of the scandal of his co-founder that been focus on him. While in Miami, Val fearing the worst like the Senator will not allow Barbara to marry him. Val tries to convince his father to hide his relationship with Albert and the fact that he is gay and Jewish. At first, Armand stood tall for his right to be open about his sexuality and his religious views, but seeing how much it would mean for him. He allow the dinner to happen, and to make himself seem straight and asking to get rid of Albert for the day was over the line. I just can't stand Dan Futterman's character, for this, what a jerk. First off, Calista's character is clearly old enough to get marry with or without her father permission, and second off, it was the 90's. It wasn't the Leave it to Beaver pre-sexualism freedom 1960's here. I felt it was wrong how Val treats his father to hide who his Father was, ask Albert to leave, all for a girl who only knew for a year. The whole thing was shameful on the part of the character. I know he wasn't in shame of his father's lifestyle, but he knew that Keelys wouldn't understand, and I know without this premise there is no movie, but still he only admit his fault to due to being catch, rather than seeing his wrongs on how he treated his father and Albert the last few days. I also felt the ending was a cop-out, as it's seem like there should had been an extra scene to show how the movie's plot got resolved. Yes it might seem like a bird-brained delight, but you just can't help loving it, and not taking it too serious. The movie acts less like La Cage aux Folles and more like a modern "You can't take it with you", a 1938 film. The music in the film is catchy, love the use of Sister Sledge- We are family, Gloria Estefan- conga, and Alan Lerner- I could have danced all night. It add with the positive good mood of the film. The whole singing scene before dinner was the best. What the movie does well is going beyond the stereotypes to see the character's depth and humanity, and that's why this movie should be check out. Try it, and you will find yourself liking it as much as I do.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not enjoyable
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    WakenPayne
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The main plot of this movie is basically that a gay club owner and his drag queen partner have a son that's getting married. For some reason they pose as being straight (with Nathan Lane in drag posing as his mother) to get the bride's parents approval or giving them the impression that they're straight because the father of the bride has anti-gay political views. I personally found the movie not really that funny at all, full of really bad gay jokes. I don't mind gay jokes (for a fact I have laughed hysterically at a couple over my teenage years) but that is really all this movie has to offer in terms of entertainment. I found the plot to be pointless (but that maybe just who I am). So if you like gay jokes then watch this, but don't really expect anything else.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Delightful Fun
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Jason Shaw
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    ￼ Put simply this is a glitzy, colourful, modern remake of La Cage aux Folles in which Robin Williams stars as the hairy and sweaty Armand, South Beach drag club owner alongside the incomparable Nathan Lane as the star and Armund's lover and partner Albert. Just like the original version, their lives are turned upside down and inside out when Armund's son, Val, comes home to announce he is getting married to an ultra-conservative senator's daughter called Barbara. Everything goes haywire and speeds up to comic high gear when those future in-laws come down to meet their daughters intended and his family. Scandal is what the senator wants to avoid at the great cost, you cannot blame him, and his co-founder of the coalition for moral order partnership has just been found dead in the bed of an underage black prostitute. There are laughs a plenty when first Armund and then Albert try and play it butch, they desperately need a woman and it's so not often you hear a couple of middle aged gay men scream that! In steps the wonderful and delightful Christine Baranski who always lights up the screen with a presence that is electrifying. However, is life that simple, that easy? You bet your sweet little arse it ain't! Barbara tells her parents that Armand is a cultural attach&eacute; to Greece, whilst Albert is a housewife, and that they divide their time between Greece and Florida. It is only a little white lie really, just as changing their last name from Goldman to Coleman is. The evening of the meeting arrives, the apartment above the drag club is transformed from gay paradise to near austere monastery, Val's real mother, Katherine (Baranski) is held up by traffic and a boat and out pops Albert as a wonderful creation of freakishly good yet awfully bad middle-aged mother. Armand and Val are both horrified at first but have no option to go along with the fa&ccedil;ade, which for some bizarre reason in this movie world works. More jokes, no proper meal and the most amazing china dinner service of naked boys playing leap- frog and still the senator and his wife do not catch on. Until that is at the door arrives Katherine, introducing herself as Val's mother and the whole charade is shot to pieces, just as TV news crews arrive out front How on earth can the senator and his wife leave the drag club without some kind of mass scandal erupting and ending his political career? The answer is simple, drag up and we are treated to the wonderful scene of Gene Hackman in a dress making the late great Bea Arthur look as feminine as a virginal princess. It is a great feel good movie, full of lightness, the jokes and funny situation fire by in rapid succession that you will probably not catch them all on the first viewing. Robin William's is superb as the nightclub owner even if he does sweat profusely at times and almost cracks up completely in the kitchen scene with the houseman come butler. I adore Nathan Lane, with his scene stealing 'Starina' performance and utter camp flamboyant majesty. Gene Hackman is equally good as the chocolate addicted extreme right wing senator with his sour face and dry delivery. As a modern re-make of a seventies classic it is both successful and complimentary, it also stands up on its own, which is a jolly good job, and for I am sure, the vast majority of its audience would not have seen La Cage aux Folles. Sure, it is lightweight, sure, it plays a little to stereotype, but it goes beyond them, reaching in to the human side and honest inner core aspect admirably. It is outrageously camp, unashamedly so, blatantly exotic and wonderfully charming, a great feel good movie. Read more and find out where this film made it in the Top 50 Most Influential Gay Movies of All Time book, search on Amazon for Top 50 Most Influential Gay Movies of All Time, or visit - http://www.amazon.co.uk/dp/B007FU7HPO
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    What a Hoot!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Ron-72
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/4/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I saw the original French film in 1979 - it was good, but not all that memorable. I saw the Broadway musical in 1983 - liked "I Am What I Am" and that was about all. But this version is just wonderful, probably because Mike Nichols and Elaine May who've known each other since forever worked on the script and Nichols can direct anything, especially with the cast he has here. They're all great, but Nathan Lane and Hank Azaria steal the show, and I don't think I've ever seen Gene Hackman as funny...I didn't know he could do comedy. What a collection of award-winners we have here, and thoroughly deserving of their SAG award for ensemble work.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not quite there...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    oceansroar
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/3/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Birdcage is a remake of a French film which i might have seen, but was too young, so i will check it soon. i am almost willing to bet that as usual with remakes of foreign films Hollywood fails. Perhaps they should promote the actual original films to the American audience, but i suppose the average American (not an intentional jab at American, since i have seen it around the world) will not watch a subtitled film. The story is about Armand, a gay man (Robin Williams) that owns a drag nightclub, in which his lover (Nathan Lane) performs as the starring act. The couple raised a son together for 20 years. The 20 year old son is now wanting to get married, but there are some complications, which make for a few hilarious moments, but only a few. i love the cast of this film, especially Robin Williams. When he is left to his own devices he can be brilliant or over the top, so he really needs a great director that allows him more room to fly, but a leash to pull him back to our atmosphere. This director held the leash too tightly, so Robin never quite got there. Nathan Lane steals most of the thunder from Robin, but he is a little over the top at times. Hank Azaria is brilliant as Agador the houseman. The cast is great, except Calista Flockhart seems a little drab in this film. If you have not watched it, then i recommended that you see it once, but keep an open mind, after all it is about a gay family. i gave it 5/10 because it does not hold up as well as it did in 1996 and the film as a whole was just not quite there.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of half a dozen verions of La Cage aux Folles out there, and Nathan Lane is devastating
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    secondtake
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/7/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Birdcage (1996) Well, there is always something great about a Mike Nichols film, and this one, written and directed by Nichols, is no exception. It is however a story that has had better presentations (see below) and I'm not sure why Nichols opted for such an un-original material. The movie really is great in some ways, and has terrific moments, but it doesn't transcend, as the best Nichols films certainly do. Robin Williams, the apparent big name on the marquee, is the weakest link in the cast (not including the two young people, who are fine but routine). But the rest of the main actors, Nathan Lane as the drag queen most of all, but Gene Hackman as a conservative senator and Dianne Wiest as his wife, are an amazing ensemble. Throw in consistently funny and clever writing (a functioanl adaptation), good camera-work, obviously attractive sets (this is South Beach in Miami), and a lively soundtrack and you sort of can't go far wrong. Is it brilliant? No way. It doesn't need to be. It's got jokes that will fade with time, topical references and timely jabs, but overall it's just perky and funny top to bottom. And relentlessly. And yes, it pushes its point hard, about how we're all people and relationships are relationships, and that's where the comedy matters, making sure you don't take the delivery too seriously. If you have doubts that it's a farce with a silver lining, just wait until you see Gene Hackman at the end. You might argue that the social message is all that matters, and of course that's true to some ways of thinking (and in some camps of criticism), but that would limit the point of the whole affair. And as time goes on and people get more used to the idea of gay culture and gay people as just another aspect of life, well, the sensational aspects of the movie will water down. But that's fine. Besides being inevitable, it points to the other parts of the film, the Shakespearean cross-dressing, the play on identities, the constant repartee. It's funny and fun and yet smart, too. The plot, at its core, is an Americanized version of the original French play (from 1973) La Cage aux Folles (which means roughly "Cage of Drag Queens" if you take into account the slang for folles). And there is of course the famous two versions of the Broadway musical version (the 1983 and 2004 versions, not to mention the current one which started in 2010). It's a great story with a long life, clearly. And the playful interaction of the ensemble is perfect for the stage. Yet this isn't the play nor the musical, but the film, with a new name. And the photographic aspects are pretty wonderful, too. Take just the opening shot coming in on a helicopter over the water and seamlessly (almost, there's a frame or two glitch) gliding right into the night club, The Birdcage. And if you don't think the story has legs, there is a 1978 Italian version of the play (not the musical) on film. The advantage of the American version for American audiences is the references are still slightly recognizable (the Bob Dole comments are already seeming like history, however). Anyway, don't see this for Robin Williams. He's fine, but not the crackup fast talker that he's best at. And it isn't him, but Nathan Lane, who gets to cross-dress. Fabulously. You'll see.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Birds of a Feather
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    edwardtjbrown
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/5/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    In his younger days, Armand Goldman (Robin Williams) was a struggling, gay stage actor who decided to have a one night stand with a female friend (Christine Baranski). The result of this brief fling was Val Goldman (Futterman), who, in the present day, is engaged to be married to a lovely woman. Despite some initial misgivings that Val is too young to be married, Val's parents, Armand Goldman and his husband Albert, (Nathan Lane), agree to support the wedding. Yet, Barbra Keeley (Calita Rockhart), the bride-to-be, comes from a prominent political family in the middle of a tough re-election campaign. U.S. Senator Keeley, who thinks Bob Dole is too liberal, is the co-founder of a Christian Coalition-type interest group dedicated enacting laws promoting "moral order". He and his wife also feel that their daughter is too young to be married, and want to 'table' the wedding until after the campaign, especially when the head of the Moral Order Coalition is found dead in the bed of an underage, African American, prostitute. Seeing the writing on the wall, Barbara begins a clever ruse to depict the Goldman family as a traditional, white, Christian, Republican family whose politics are to the right of Patrick Buchanan, Jerry Falwell and Pat Roberston. Val convinces his parents to go to great lengths, changing their house, dress, mannerisms, religion and politics, to pull off this charade as the in-laws meet for dinner. As one might guess, much of the comedy in this film involves a 1990's satire of the right-wing politics, as well as the media's post-OJ Simpson trial (1995) obsession with tabloid and scandal driven news. Robin Williams and Nathan Lane are great together, although they show each other little affection, with Lane playing the more stereotypical gay man/drag queen entertainer, which manages to avoid coming off as mean spirited. Likewise, the Keeley are as stuffy as they are right-wing, but the film allows each of the family members to develop a character and story arch beyond simple card board cut outs. Oddly enough, the film does not really address gay rights, beyond the, often comedic, contrasts between the two families and the assumptions that are made. Armand and Albert are financially successful, owners of a hip nightclub. They live in a trendy, upscale urban neighborhood where discrimination and harassment does not seem to exist. Gays serving open in the military and legal recognition of same-sex marriage are mentioned, but Armand and Albert seem to be a couple that exists just slightly out of reality. They do argue over a palimony agreement and I am not sure how the film could have been anything else, given when it was made. In the early - mid 1990s, Hollywood films were just beginning to depict gay people in a manner that did not involve them being predatory, suicidal, homicidal manics. Yes, the film clearly mocks the stuffy, uptight future in-laws. Yes, it mocks their right-wing politics and prejudices directed at gay people as well as racial, religious and ethnic minorities. As great, witty and funny as this film is, sometimes it cannot hide its age.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Funny!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    nama chakravorty
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/2/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A remake of the 1978 film, La Cage aux Folles, 'The Birdcage' is an amusingly enjoyable film. Mike Nichols continues his magic in this 1996 cult-hit, The legendary filmmaker, along-with a stellar cast and a freaky screenplay, makes a truly funny film about everything gone haywire! 'The Birdcage' is about a gay cabaret owner and his drag queen companion agree to put up a false straight front so that their son can introduce them to his fianc&eacute;'s right-wing moralistic parents. Source taken from IMDb! To be honest, the film begins tepidly and it takes time to grasp each and every character's intentions and further plans. But once you get into the groove, you enter a joyride. The entire last hour, right after Gene Hackman & Co enter Williams house, there is hardly a moment when you don't laugh. Also, watching Gene Hackman as a drag in the climax, is simply hilarious! Mike Nichols directs the film with his usual midas touch. He is amongst the most talented filmmakers ever. The adapted Screenplay is full of absurd, funny, hilarious & strange situations. Cinematography by Emmanuel Lubezki is perfect. Editing could've been sharper. Now to the performances! With such a stellar cast coming under one roof, one expects nothing but exemplary acting. Each and Every Actor delivers in here. Robin Williams, Gene Hackman, Nathan Lane & Dianne Wiest are absolutely flawless. Dan Futterman, Calista Flockhart & Hank Azaria are at par with the seniors! On the whole, A Comedy that needs a watch. An absurd yet lovable experience! Thumbs Up!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Funniest movie I have ever seen
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bluebook-master
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Rarely does a movie cause me to laugh out loud so much as The Birdcage. The cast of characters is extraordinary. The interaction between Gene Hackman and Nathan Lane is priceless. Dan Futterman is not only drop dead gorgeous but his chemistry with Robin Williams is a perfect match. The dinner party reaches a climax with everyone singing "I could have danced all right" with Gene Hackman and Nathan Lane ballroom dancing. The closing scene with Gene Hackman dancing in drag and saying his white dress makes him look fat caused me to cry I was laughing so much. Whoever masterminded this cast of actors knew what they were doing. The film pokes fun at both the absurdity of right wing Republicans and over the top gay men running a nightclub - all humor done very tastefully. For an evening of pure entertainment you've got to see this movies- more than once.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The funniest gay-duo ever, with Robin Williams as the straight-man, so to speak 
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ElMaruecan82
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Traduttore, tradittore" the Italian adage seems to indicate that the transposition of a concept or an artistic creation to another language would inevitably betray its spirit. It's true that most of the times, comedy is the most likely genre to suffer from adaptation and the most eloquent proof can be found in the love-and-hate relationship between French comedies and their much inferior American remakes. Almost every Francis Veber's script for instance, was remade for American audience, and needless to say that some films turns out to be sour disasters, or average entertainments at best. Directed by Mike Nichols, "The Birdcage" is the remake of 'Birds of Feathers' ("La Cage aux Folles"), the greatest Italian-French comedy, starring Ugo Tognazzi and Michel Serrault, and one of the most successful French productions in America. Although it was fair for Nichols to assume that the 1996' audience wouldn't be familiar with the original film, it was risky as well to embrace such a politically incorrect theme, featuring a gay couple with one acting like a hysterical diva, and transpose it in the 90's where the 70's archetypes were no longer held as comedic devices. Needless to say that the performances of the whole cast was crucial, let alone Nathan Lane, who is the highlight of the show. The plot is pure screwball material, Armand (Williams) lives with Albert (Lane) for twenty years, Armand owns a gay burlesque bar in South Florida named "The Birdcage" and directs the very show where Albert stars. Albert acts like a capricious prima donna all the time, always seeming at the edge of a nervous breakdown, praising for attention, he's obviously the "lady" in the couple, and it seems quite fresh to see Williams as the most restrained one, and not let himself carried away by Albert's caprices. The rest of the house also features a Hank Azaria as a Guatemalan butler named Agador, his accent, extraordinary capability to imitate Estefan's "Konga" and some crazy one-liners are really under-appreciated. The routine is broken when Val, Armand's son announces his engagement with the daughter of a republican and notoriously conservative, a Senator named Kevin Keeley (Gene Hackman). Keeley isn't in a better phase because his closest friend and President of the Coalition of Moral Virtues was found dead with an underage black prostitute, a synthesis of every worst- case situation that can undermine a political career. Naturally, his daughter (a pre-McBeal Calista Flockhart) is forced to lie about Armand's profession and Keeley's wife (Dianne Wiest) seize the wedding as an opportunity to clear Keeley from the prejudice caused by the scandal. With these two set-ups, the movie takes off for one of the funniest and most enjoyable recent comedy of errors. Some would naturally get offended by Lane's portrayal of Albert, but the fact is that the film is precisely funny because he's effeminate. It gives its flavor to the scene where he wants to pretend he's Val's uncle, and then learns from Albert how to butter a toast like a man, and not get upset if it gets pierced, and walk like John Wayne. Albert's high pitched screams and overly-gay mannerisms contribute to some of the film's most laugh-out-loud moments and can't take you off totally off-guard, but Lane doesn't overplay them, he finds the right note in an over-the-top personality. And it never shows as well as in the scene where he comes, dressed like a man, only to betray some pink socks, that make even more obvious the fact that he's gay. And that's the basis of the whole comical premise, the more you pretend not to be something, the more it shows. But one thing Lane shows without pretending is how loving and caring he's for Val, and that's what makes his character so endearing and engaging. He's a clown but a sad and funny one, while Williams is the 'straight' man, comically speaking of course, and when a champagne bottle suddenly pops, the effect is immediate, it's pure comedic gold. There are two levels of comedies, where Williams is both the straight man and the clown of a masquerade, no wonder he spent the whole night drinking. Talk about a comical existential nightmare. The secret of "The Birdcage" is to remain faithful to the spirit of the first film, but not without taking some perspective from the original material. The fact that they're Jewish adds another running their name, is it Goldman or Coleman, is the 'd' silent or what? The political undertones are accentuated, maybe because it was before the election campaign, but they seem to be more fitting for the American context, and Gene Hackman is absolutely perfect as the Republican Senator who tries to hide his desperation between a cold facade, he's even more interesting than the original character because the screenplay enriches his personality with his genuine fondness on Albert. And we understand the Senator, Lane plays a drag with such genuine tenderness that we empathize with his desire to help Val. But since we know that it's meant to fail, we can only enjoy the way they keep the Senator believing. And it's indeed funny how Albert touches the Senator's heart when pretending to be Val's mother "they don't make women like that anymore", maybe in a way, Albert fulfilled his all-time dream to be a woman and be treated as well. "The Birdcage" is a film that should have deserved more recognition, less than a remake, it's more of a refreshing and modernization of the 70's version, and it's so lively, so flamboyant, so comical, it seems to reconcile with an idea of the 'gay' culture, that no matter how stereotypical it is, remains more enjoyable than its claim for banality. The style is dated but not the tone. "The Birdcage" deserves all its praises, it's not only one of the few successful American remakes of French comedies, it's more intelligent than what it seems  and it's funny as hell.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    If you don't get this movie, try some more gum
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ironhorse_iv
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I know that look. Hit me, go on. Hit me with why this movie isn't good, because I don't see that face plant of why I should hate this Mike Nichol's film. Yes, it might look like a pale copy of the original La Cage aux Folles, the 1978's French film in itself based on the 1973's play by Jean Poiret, but it's not a drag. Well, it's a drag in another way, but what I like about this remake is how they turns something from French, into a funny American movie. Armand Goldman (Robin Williams) owns a popular drag nightclub in South Miami Beach with his long-time lover Albert Goldman (Nathan Lane). Nathan Lane as Albert is a annoying character with his fits, non-stop complaining and diva like attitude. Some audience members might find the character too irritation to bother with the movie. Some audience members will look past that, due to fact that Albert is so hysterical due to his overreactions to everything. If some people dislike him, they would love the crude humor toward him from Armand. As much as Armand can not stand him, he sticks with Albert. Within the comedy, is a small great speech scene by Armand to Albert. These are two gay men of a certain age, and years of ostracism, threats and taunts would have conditioned them both to avoid any PDAs, no matter how strong the feeling between them. The speech gives the moment enormous poignancy feeling of genuine, heartfelt and caring to Albert. This scene is especially lovely, a great juxtaposition to the rest of the film which is wonderfully silly and comedic. Nathan Lane isn't the only one that nearly steals the movie from Robin Williams, as Armand's maid Agador Spartacus (Hank Azaria) takes a bite of funny throughout the film, with singing and dancing to music, making lousy food, and tripping over his own feet. Watching Agador was a delight, and pans away from Nathan Lane enough times, that we able to rest from his big, brassy yelling and complaining. Soon the Goldman's son Val (Dan Futterman) comes home to announce his engagement to Barbara Keely (Calista Flockhart), daughter of Kevin Keely (Gene Hackman), US Senator, and vice president of the extreme Committee for Moral Order and his wife (Dianne Wiest). First off, the actor Dan Futterman and Calista Flockhart were too old for the role, it felt weird in a way to see Calista play a awkward 18 year old. Both are in later scenes, boozing and smoking. Are we suppose to believe that a conservatism senator would allow his daughter to underage drink? Clearly both are wrong actors for the job. Gene Hackman as Kevin Keely is so extreme right conservatism, it makes the character seem like a political cartoon caricature less than a normal person. Kevin Keely decide to allow Barbara to marry Val only if they meet Val and his family at South Beach and use the marriage to get the media off of the scandal of his co-founder that been focus on him. While in Miami, Val fearing the worst like the Senator will not allow Barbara to marry him. Val tries to convince his father to hide his relationship with Albert and the fact that he is gay and Jewish. At first, Armand stood tall for his right to be open about his sexuality and his religious views, but seeing how much it would mean for him. He allow the dinner to happen, and to make himself seem straight and asking to get rid of Albert for the day was over the line. I just can't stand Dan Futterman's character, for this, what a jerk. First off, Calista's character is clearly old enough to get marry with or without her father permission, and second off, it was the 90's. It wasn't the Leave it to Beaver pre-sexualism freedom 1960's here. I felt it was wrong how Val treats his father to hide who his Father was, ask Albert to leave, all for a girl who only knew for a year. The whole thing was shameful on the part of the character. I know he wasn't in shame of his father's lifestyle, but he knew that Keelys wouldn't understand, and I know without this premise there is no movie, but still he only admit his fault to due to being catch, rather than seeing his wrongs on how he treated his father and Albert the last few days. I also felt the ending was a cop-out, as it's seem like there should had been an extra scene to show how the movie's plot got resolved. Yes it might seem like a bird-brained delight, but you just can't help loving it, and not taking it too serious. The movie acts less like La Cage aux Folles and more like a modern "You can't take it with you", a 1938 film. The music in the film is catchy, love the use of Sister Sledge- We are family, Gloria Estefan- conga, and Alan Lerner- I could have danced all night. It add with the positive good mood of the film. The whole singing scene before dinner was the best. What the movie does well is going beyond the stereotypes to see the character's depth and humanity, and that's why this movie should be check out. Try it, and you will find yourself liking it as much as I do.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not enjoyable
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    WakenPayne
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The main plot of this movie is basically that a gay club owner and his drag queen partner have a son that's getting married. For some reason they pose as being straight (with Nathan Lane in drag posing as his mother) to get the bride's parents approval or giving them the impression that they're straight because the father of the bride has anti-gay political views. I personally found the movie not really that funny at all, full of really bad gay jokes. I don't mind gay jokes (for a fact I have laughed hysterically at a couple over my teenage years) but that is really all this movie has to offer in terms of entertainment. I found the plot to be pointless (but that maybe just who I am). So if you like gay jokes then watch this, but don't really expect anything else.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Delightful Fun
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Jason Shaw
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    ￼ Put simply this is a glitzy, colourful, modern remake of La Cage aux Folles in which Robin Williams stars as the hairy and sweaty Armand, South Beach drag club owner alongside the incomparable Nathan Lane as the star and Armund's lover and partner Albert. Just like the original version, their lives are turned upside down and inside out when Armund's son, Val, comes home to announce he is getting married to an ultra-conservative senator's daughter called Barbara. Everything goes haywire and speeds up to comic high gear when those future in-laws come down to meet their daughters intended and his family. Scandal is what the senator wants to avoid at the great cost, you cannot blame him, and his co-founder of the coalition for moral order partnership has just been found dead in the bed of an underage black prostitute. There are laughs a plenty when first Armund and then Albert try and play it butch, they desperately need a woman and it's so not often you hear a couple of middle aged gay men scream that! In steps the wonderful and delightful Christine Baranski who always lights up the screen with a presence that is electrifying. However, is life that simple, that easy? You bet your sweet little arse it ain't! Barbara tells her parents that Armand is a cultural attach&eacute; to Greece, whilst Albert is a housewife, and that they divide their time between Greece and Florida. It is only a little white lie really, just as changing their last name from Goldman to Coleman is. The evening of the meeting arrives, the apartment above the drag club is transformed from gay paradise to near austere monastery, Val's real mother, Katherine (Baranski) is held up by traffic and a boat and out pops Albert as a wonderful creation of freakishly good yet awfully bad middle-aged mother. Armand and Val are both horrified at first but have no option to go along with the fa&ccedil;ade, which for some bizarre reason in this movie world works. More jokes, no proper meal and the most amazing china dinner service of naked boys playing leap- frog and still the senator and his wife do not catch on. Until that is at the door arrives Katherine, introducing herself as Val's mother and the whole charade is shot to pieces, just as TV news crews arrive out front How on earth can the senator and his wife leave the drag club without some kind of mass scandal erupting and ending his political career? The answer is simple, drag up and we are treated to the wonderful scene of Gene Hackman in a dress making the late great Bea Arthur look as feminine as a virginal princess. It is a great feel good movie, full of lightness, the jokes and funny situation fire by in rapid succession that you will probably not catch them all on the first viewing. Robin William's is superb as the nightclub owner even if he does sweat profusely at times and almost cracks up completely in the kitchen scene with the houseman come butler. I adore Nathan Lane, with his scene stealing 'Starina' performance and utter camp flamboyant majesty. Gene Hackman is equally good as the chocolate addicted extreme right wing senator with his sour face and dry delivery. As a modern re-make of a seventies classic it is both successful and complimentary, it also stands up on its own, which is a jolly good job, and for I am sure, the vast majority of its audience would not have seen La Cage aux Folles. Sure, it is lightweight, sure, it plays a little to stereotype, but it goes beyond them, reaching in to the human side and honest inner core aspect admirably. It is outrageously camp, unashamedly so, blatantly exotic and wonderfully charming, a great feel good movie. Read more and find out where this film made it in the Top 50 Most Influential Gay Movies of All Time book, search on Amazon for Top 50 Most Influential Gay Movies of All Time, or visit - http://www.amazon.co.uk/dp/B007FU7HPO
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    What a Hoot!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Ron-72
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/4/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I saw the original French film in 1979 - it was good, but not all that memorable. I saw the Broadway musical in 1983 - liked "I Am What I Am" and that was about all. But this version is just wonderful, probably because Mike Nichols and Elaine May who've known each other since forever worked on the script and Nichols can direct anything, especially with the cast he has here. They're all great, but Nathan Lane and Hank Azaria steal the show, and I don't think I've ever seen Gene Hackman as funny...I didn't know he could do comedy. What a collection of award-winners we have here, and thoroughly deserving of their SAG award for ensemble work.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not quite there...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    oceansroar
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/3/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Birdcage is a remake of a French film which i might have seen, but was too young, so i will check it soon. i am almost willing to bet that as usual with remakes of foreign films Hollywood fails. Perhaps they should promote the actual original films to the American audience, but i suppose the average American (not an intentional jab at American, since i have seen it around the world) will not watch a subtitled film. The story is about Armand, a gay man (Robin Williams) that owns a drag nightclub, in which his lover (Nathan Lane) performs as the starring act. The couple raised a son together for 20 years. The 20 year old son is now wanting to get married, but there are some complications, which make for a few hilarious moments, but only a few. i love the cast of this film, especially Robin Williams. When he is left to his own devices he can be brilliant or over the top, so he really needs a great director that allows him more room to fly, but a leash to pull him back to our atmosphere. This director held the leash too tightly, so Robin never quite got there. Nathan Lane steals most of the thunder from Robin, but he is a little over the top at times. Hank Azaria is brilliant as Agador the houseman. The cast is great, except Calista Flockhart seems a little drab in this film. If you have not watched it, then i recommended that you see it once, but keep an open mind, after all it is about a gay family. i gave it 5/10 because it does not hold up as well as it did in 1996 and the film as a whole was just not quite there.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of half a dozen verions of La Cage aux Folles out there, and Nathan Lane is devastating
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    secondtake
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/7/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Birdcage (1996) Well, there is always something great about a Mike Nichols film, and this one, written and directed by Nichols, is no exception. It is however a story that has had better presentations (see below) and I'm not sure why Nichols opted for such an un-original material. The movie really is great in some ways, and has terrific moments, but it doesn't transcend, as the best Nichols films certainly do. Robin Williams, the apparent big name on the marquee, is the weakest link in the cast (not including the two young people, who are fine but routine). But the rest of the main actors, Nathan Lane as the drag queen most of all, but Gene Hackman as a conservative senator and Dianne Wiest as his wife, are an amazing ensemble. Throw in consistently funny and clever writing (a functioanl adaptation), good camera-work, obviously attractive sets (this is South Beach in Miami), and a lively soundtrack and you sort of can't go far wrong. Is it brilliant? No way. It doesn't need to be. It's got jokes that will fade with time, topical references and timely jabs, but overall it's just perky and funny top to bottom. And relentlessly. And yes, it pushes its point hard, about how we're all people and relationships are relationships, and that's where the comedy matters, making sure you don't take the delivery too seriously. If you have doubts that it's a farce with a silver lining, just wait until you see Gene Hackman at the end. You might argue that the social message is all that matters, and of course that's true to some ways of thinking (and in some camps of criticism), but that would limit the point of the whole affair. And as time goes on and people get more used to the idea of gay culture and gay people as just another aspect of life, well, the sensational aspects of the movie will water down. But that's fine. Besides being inevitable, it points to the other parts of the film, the Shakespearean cross-dressing, the play on identities, the constant repartee. It's funny and fun and yet smart, too. The plot, at its core, is an Americanized version of the original French play (from 1973) La Cage aux Folles (which means roughly "Cage of Drag Queens" if you take into account the slang for folles). And there is of course the famous two versions of the Broadway musical version (the 1983 and 2004 versions, not to mention the current one which started in 2010). It's a great story with a long life, clearly. And the playful interaction of the ensemble is perfect for the stage. Yet this isn't the play nor the musical, but the film, with a new name. And the photographic aspects are pretty wonderful, too. Take just the opening shot coming in on a helicopter over the water and seamlessly (almost, there's a frame or two glitch) gliding right into the night club, The Birdcage. And if you don't think the story has legs, there is a 1978 Italian version of the play (not the musical) on film. The advantage of the American version for American audiences is the references are still slightly recognizable (the Bob Dole comments are already seeming like history, however). Anyway, don't see this for Robin Williams. He's fine, but not the crackup fast talker that he's best at. And it isn't him, but Nathan Lane, who gets to cross-dress. Fabulously. You'll see.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Birds of a Feather
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    edwardtjbrown
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/5/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    In his younger days, Armand Goldman (Robin Williams) was a struggling, gay stage actor who decided to have a one night stand with a female friend (Christine Baranski). The result of this brief fling was Val Goldman (Futterman), who, in the present day, is engaged to be married to a lovely woman. Despite some initial misgivings that Val is too young to be married, Val's parents, Armand Goldman and his husband Albert, (Nathan Lane), agree to support the wedding. Yet, Barbra Keeley (Calita Rockhart), the bride-to-be, comes from a prominent political family in the middle of a tough re-election campaign. U.S. Senator Keeley, who thinks Bob Dole is too liberal, is the co-founder of a Christian Coalition-type interest group dedicated enacting laws promoting "moral order". He and his wife also feel that their daughter is too young to be married, and want to 'table' the wedding until after the campaign, especially when the head of the Moral Order Coalition is found dead in the bed of an underage, African American, prostitute. Seeing the writing on the wall, Barbara begins a clever ruse to depict the Goldman family as a traditional, white, Christian, Republican family whose politics are to the right of Patrick Buchanan, Jerry Falwell and Pat Roberston. Val convinces his parents to go to great lengths, changing their house, dress, mannerisms, religion and politics, to pull off this charade as the in-laws meet for dinner. As one might guess, much of the comedy in this film involves a 1990's satire of the right-wing politics, as well as the media's post-OJ Simpson trial (1995) obsession with tabloid and scandal driven news. Robin Williams and Nathan Lane are great together, although they show each other little affection, with Lane playing the more stereotypical gay man/drag queen entertainer, which manages to avoid coming off as mean spirited. Likewise, the Keeley are as stuffy as they are right-wing, but the film allows each of the family members to develop a character and story arch beyond simple card board cut outs. Oddly enough, the film does not really address gay rights, beyond the, often comedic, contrasts between the two families and the assumptions that are made. Armand and Albert are financially successful, owners of a hip nightclub. They live in a trendy, upscale urban neighborhood where discrimination and harassment does not seem to exist. Gays serving open in the military and legal recognition of same-sex marriage are mentioned, but Armand and Albert seem to be a couple that exists just slightly out of reality. They do argue over a palimony agreement and I am not sure how the film could have been anything else, given when it was made. In the early - mid 1990s, Hollywood films were just beginning to depict gay people in a manner that did not involve them being predatory, suicidal, homicidal manics. Yes, the film clearly mocks the stuffy, uptight future in-laws. Yes, it mocks their right-wing politics and prejudices directed at gay people as well as racial, religious and ethnic minorities. As great, witty and funny as this film is, sometimes it cannot hide its age.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Funny!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    nama chakravorty
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/2/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A remake of the 1978 film, La Cage aux Folles, 'The Birdcage' is an amusingly enjoyable film. Mike Nichols continues his magic in this 1996 cult-hit, The legendary filmmaker, along-with a stellar cast and a freaky screenplay, makes a truly funny film about everything gone haywire! 'The Birdcage' is about a gay cabaret owner and his drag queen companion agree to put up a false straight front so that their son can introduce them to his fianc&eacute;'s right-wing moralistic parents. Source taken from IMDb! To be honest, the film begins tepidly and it takes time to grasp each and every character's intentions and further plans. But once you get into the groove, you enter a joyride. The entire last hour, right after Gene Hackman & Co enter Williams house, there is hardly a moment when you don't laugh. Also, watching Gene Hackman as a drag in the climax, is simply hilarious! Mike Nichols directs the film with his usual midas touch. He is amongst the most talented filmmakers ever. The adapted Screenplay is full of absurd, funny, hilarious & strange situations. Cinematography by Emmanuel Lubezki is perfect. Editing could've been sharper. Now to the performances! With such a stellar cast coming under one roof, one expects nothing but exemplary acting. Each and Every Actor delivers in here. Robin Williams, Gene Hackman, Nathan Lane & Dianne Wiest are absolutely flawless. Dan Futterman, Calista Flockhart & Hank Azaria are at par with the seniors! On the whole, A Comedy that needs a watch. An absurd yet lovable experience! Thumbs Up!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Funniest movie I have ever seen
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bluebook-master
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Rarely does a movie cause me to laugh out loud so much as The Birdcage. The cast of characters is extraordinary. The interaction between Gene Hackman and Nathan Lane is priceless. Dan Futterman is not only drop dead gorgeous but his chemistry with Robin Williams is a perfect match. The dinner party reaches a climax with everyone singing "I could have danced all right" with Gene Hackman and Nathan Lane ballroom dancing. The closing scene with Gene Hackman dancing in drag and saying his white dress makes him look fat caused me to cry I was laughing so much. Whoever masterminded this cast of actors knew what they were doing. The film pokes fun at both the absurdity of right wing Republicans and over the top gay men running a nightclub - all humor done very tastefully. For an evening of pure entertainment you've got to see this movies- more than once.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The funniest gay-duo ever, with Robin Williams as the straight-man, so to speak 
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ElMaruecan82
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Traduttore, tradittore" the Italian adage seems to indicate that the transposition of a concept or an artistic creation to another language would inevitably betray its spirit. It's true that most of the times, comedy is the most likely genre to suffer from adaptation and the most eloquent proof can be found in the love-and-hate relationship between French comedies and their much inferior American remakes. Almost every Francis Veber's script for instance, was remade for American audience, and needless to say that some films turns out to be sour disasters, or average entertainments at best. Directed by Mike Nichols, "The Birdcage" is the remake of 'Birds of Feathers' ("La Cage aux Folles"), the greatest Italian-French comedy, starring Ugo Tognazzi and Michel Serrault, and one of the most successful French productions in America. Although it was fair for Nichols to assume that the 1996' audience wouldn't be familiar with the original film, it was risky as well to embrace such a politically incorrect theme, featuring a gay couple with one acting like a hysterical diva, and transpose it in the 90's where the 70's archetypes were no longer held as comedic devices. Needless to say that the performances of the whole cast was crucial, let alone Nathan Lane, who is the highlight of the show. The plot is pure screwball material, Armand (Williams) lives with Albert (Lane) for twenty years, Armand owns a gay burlesque bar in South Florida named "The Birdcage" and directs the very show where Albert stars. Albert acts like a capricious prima donna all the time, always seeming at the edge of a nervous breakdown, praising for attention, he's obviously the "lady" in the couple, and it seems quite fresh to see Williams as the most restrained one, and not let himself carried away by Albert's caprices. The rest of the house also features a Hank Azaria as a Guatemalan butler named Agador, his accent, extraordinary capability to imitate Estefan's "Konga" and some crazy one-liners are really under-appreciated. The routine is broken when Val, Armand's son announces his engagement with the daughter of a republican and notoriously conservative, a Senator named Kevin Keeley (Gene Hackman). Keeley isn't in a better phase because his closest friend and President of the Coalition of Moral Virtues was found dead with an underage black prostitute, a synthesis of every worst- case situation that can undermine a political career. Naturally, his daughter (a pre-McBeal Calista Flockhart) is forced to lie about Armand's profession and Keeley's wife (Dianne Wiest) seize the wedding as an opportunity to clear Keeley from the prejudice caused by the scandal. With these two set-ups, the movie takes off for one of the funniest and most enjoyable recent comedy of errors. Some would naturally get offended by Lane's portrayal of Albert, but the fact is that the film is precisely funny because he's effeminate. It gives its flavor to the scene where he wants to pretend he's Val's uncle, and then learns from Albert how to butter a toast like a man, and not get upset if it gets pierced, and walk like John Wayne. Albert's high pitched screams and overly-gay mannerisms contribute to some of the film's most laugh-out-loud moments and can't take you off totally off-guard, but Lane doesn't overplay them, he finds the right note in an over-the-top personality. And it never shows as well as in the scene where he comes, dressed like a man, only to betray some pink socks, that make even more obvious the fact that he's gay. And that's the basis of the whole comical premise, the more you pretend not to be something, the more it shows. But one thing Lane shows without pretending is how loving and caring he's for Val, and that's what makes his character so endearing and engaging. He's a clown but a sad and funny one, while Williams is the 'straight' man, comically speaking of course, and when a champagne bottle suddenly pops, the effect is immediate, it's pure comedic gold. There are two levels of comedies, where Williams is both the straight man and the clown of a masquerade, no wonder he spent the whole night drinking. Talk about a comical existential nightmare. The secret of "The Birdcage" is to remain faithful to the spirit of the first film, but not without taking some perspective from the original material. The fact that they're Jewish adds another running their name, is it Goldman or Coleman, is the 'd' silent or what? The political undertones are accentuated, maybe because it was before the election campaign, but they seem to be more fitting for the American context, and Gene Hackman is absolutely perfect as the Republican Senator who tries to hide his desperation between a cold facade, he's even more interesting than the original character because the screenplay enriches his personality with his genuine fondness on Albert. And we understand the Senator, Lane plays a drag with such genuine tenderness that we empathize with his desire to help Val. But since we know that it's meant to fail, we can only enjoy the way they keep the Senator believing. And it's indeed funny how Albert touches the Senator's heart when pretending to be Val's mother "they don't make women like that anymore", maybe in a way, Albert fulfilled his all-time dream to be a woman and be treated as well. "The Birdcage" is a film that should have deserved more recognition, less than a remake, it's more of a refreshing and modernization of the 70's version, and it's so lively, so flamboyant, so comical, it seems to reconcile with an idea of the 'gay' culture, that no matter how stereotypical it is, remains more enjoyable than its claim for banality. The style is dated but not the tone. "The Birdcage" deserves all its praises, it's not only one of the few successful American remakes of French comedies, it's more intelligent than what it seems  and it's funny as hell.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    If you don't get this movie, try some more gum
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ironhorse_iv
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I know that look. Hit me, go on. Hit me with why this movie isn't good, because I don't see that face plant of why I should hate this Mike Nichol's film. Yes, it might look like a pale copy of the original La Cage aux Folles, the 1978's French film in itself based on the 1973's play by Jean Poiret, but it's not a drag. Well, it's a drag in another way, but what I like about this remake is how they turns something from French, into a funny American movie. Armand Goldman (Robin Williams) owns a popular drag nightclub in South Miami Beach with his long-time lover Albert Goldman (Nathan Lane). Nathan Lane as Albert is a annoying character with his fits, non-stop complaining and diva like attitude. Some audience members might find the character too irritation to bother with the movie. Some audience members will look past that, due to fact that Albert is so hysterical due to his overreactions to everything. If some people dislike him, they would love the crude humor toward him from Armand. As much as Armand can not stand him, he sticks with Albert. Within the comedy, is a small great speech scene by Armand to Albert. These are two gay men of a certain age, and years of ostracism, threats and taunts would have conditioned them both to avoid any PDAs, no matter how strong the feeling between them. The speech gives the moment enormous poignancy feeling of genuine, heartfelt and caring to Albert. This scene is especially lovely, a great juxtaposition to the rest of the film which is wonderfully silly and comedic. Nathan Lane isn't the only one that nearly steals the movie from Robin Williams, as Armand's maid Agador Spartacus (Hank Azaria) takes a bite of funny throughout the film, with singing and dancing to music, making lousy food, and tripping over his own feet. Watching Agador was a delight, and pans away from Nathan Lane enough times, that we able to rest from his big, brassy yelling and complaining. Soon the Goldman's son Val (Dan Futterman) comes home to announce his engagement to Barbara Keely (Calista Flockhart), daughter of Kevin Keely (Gene Hackman), US Senator, and vice president of the extreme Committee for Moral Order and his wife (Dianne Wiest). First off, the actor Dan Futterman and Calista Flockhart were too old for the role, it felt weird in a way to see Calista play a awkward 18 year old. Both are in later scenes, boozing and smoking. Are we suppose to believe that a conservatism senator would allow his daughter to underage drink? Clearly both are wrong actors for the job. Gene Hackman as Kevin Keely is so extreme right conservatism, it makes the character seem like a political cartoon caricature less than a normal person. Kevin Keely decide to allow Barbara to marry Val only if they meet Val and his family at South Beach and use the marriage to get the media off of the scandal of his co-founder that been focus on him. While in Miami, Val fearing the worst like the Senator will not allow Barbara to marry him. Val tries to convince his father to hide his relationship with Albert and the fact that he is gay and Jewish. At first, Armand stood tall for his right to be open about his sexuality and his religious views, but seeing how much it would mean for him. He allow the dinner to happen, and to make himself seem straight and asking to get rid of Albert for the day was over the line. I just can't stand Dan Futterman's character, for this, what a jerk. First off, Calista's character is clearly old enough to get marry with or without her father permission, and second off, it was the 90's. It wasn't the Leave it to Beaver pre-sexualism freedom 1960's here. I felt it was wrong how Val treats his father to hide who his Father was, ask Albert to leave, all for a girl who only knew for a year. The whole thing was shameful on the part of the character. I know he wasn't in shame of his father's lifestyle, but he knew that Keelys wouldn't understand, and I know without this premise there is no movie, but still he only admit his fault to due to being catch, rather than seeing his wrongs on how he treated his father and Albert the last few days. I also felt the ending was a cop-out, as it's seem like there should had been an extra scene to show how the movie's plot got resolved. Yes it might seem like a bird-brained delight, but you just can't help loving it, and not taking it too serious. The movie acts less like La Cage aux Folles and more like a modern "You can't take it with you", a 1938 film. The music in the film is catchy, love the use of Sister Sledge- We are family, Gloria Estefan- conga, and Alan Lerner- I could have danced all night. It add with the positive good mood of the film. The whole singing scene before dinner was the best. What the movie does well is going beyond the stereotypes to see the character's depth and humanity, and that's why this movie should be check out. Try it, and you will find yourself liking it as much as I do.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not enjoyable
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    WakenPayne
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The main plot of this movie is basically that a gay club owner and his drag queen partner have a son that's getting married. For some reason they pose as being straight (with Nathan Lane in drag posing as his mother) to get the bride's parents approval or giving them the impression that they're straight because the father of the bride has anti-gay political views. I personally found the movie not really that funny at all, full of really bad gay jokes. I don't mind gay jokes (for a fact I have laughed hysterically at a couple over my teenage years) but that is really all this movie has to offer in terms of entertainment. I found the plot to be pointless (but that maybe just who I am). So if you like gay jokes then watch this, but don't really expect anything else.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Delightful Fun
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Jason Shaw
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    ￼ Put simply this is a glitzy, colourful, modern remake of La Cage aux Folles in which Robin Williams stars as the hairy and sweaty Armand, South Beach drag club owner alongside the incomparable Nathan Lane as the star and Armund's lover and partner Albert. Just like the original version, their lives are turned upside down and inside out when Armund's son, Val, comes home to announce he is getting married to an ultra-conservative senator's daughter called Barbara. Everything goes haywire and speeds up to comic high gear when those future in-laws come down to meet their daughters intended and his family. Scandal is what the senator wants to avoid at the great cost, you cannot blame him, and his co-founder of the coalition for moral order partnership has just been found dead in the bed of an underage black prostitute. There are laughs a plenty when first Armund and then Albert try and play it butch, they desperately need a woman and it's so not often you hear a couple of middle aged gay men scream that! In steps the wonderful and delightful Christine Baranski who always lights up the screen with a presence that is electrifying. However, is life that simple, that easy? You bet your sweet little arse it ain't! Barbara tells her parents that Armand is a cultural attach&eacute; to Greece, whilst Albert is a housewife, and that they divide their time between Greece and Florida. It is only a little white lie really, just as changing their last name from Goldman to Coleman is. The evening of the meeting arrives, the apartment above the drag club is transformed from gay paradise to near austere monastery, Val's real mother, Katherine (Baranski) is held up by traffic and a boat and out pops Albert as a wonderful creation of freakishly good yet awfully bad middle-aged mother. Armand and Val are both horrified at first but have no option to go along with the fa&ccedil;ade, which for some bizarre reason in this movie world works. More jokes, no proper meal and the most amazing china dinner service of naked boys playing leap- frog and still the senator and his wife do not catch on. Until that is at the door arrives Katherine, introducing herself as Val's mother and the whole charade is shot to pieces, just as TV news crews arrive out front How on earth can the senator and his wife leave the drag club without some kind of mass scandal erupting and ending his political career? The answer is simple, drag up and we are treated to the wonderful scene of Gene Hackman in a dress making the late great Bea Arthur look as feminine as a virginal princess. It is a great feel good movie, full of lightness, the jokes and funny situation fire by in rapid succession that you will probably not catch them all on the first viewing. Robin William's is superb as the nightclub owner even if he does sweat profusely at times and almost cracks up completely in the kitchen scene with the houseman come butler. I adore Nathan Lane, with his scene stealing 'Starina' performance and utter camp flamboyant majesty. Gene Hackman is equally good as the chocolate addicted extreme right wing senator with his sour face and dry delivery. As a modern re-make of a seventies classic it is both successful and complimentary, it also stands up on its own, which is a jolly good job, and for I am sure, the vast majority of its audience would not have seen La Cage aux Folles. Sure, it is lightweight, sure, it plays a little to stereotype, but it goes beyond them, reaching in to the human side and honest inner core aspect admirably. It is outrageously camp, unashamedly so, blatantly exotic and wonderfully charming, a great feel good movie. Read more and find out where this film made it in the Top 50 Most Influential Gay Movies of All Time book, search on Amazon for Top 50 Most Influential Gay Movies of All Time, or visit - http://www.amazon.co.uk/dp/B007FU7HPO
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    What a Hoot!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Ron-72
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/4/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I saw the original French film in 1979 - it was good, but not all that memorable. I saw the Broadway musical in 1983 - liked "I Am What I Am" and that was about all. But this version is just wonderful, probably because Mike Nichols and Elaine May who've known each other since forever worked on the script and Nichols can direct anything, especially with the cast he has here. They're all great, but Nathan Lane and Hank Azaria steal the show, and I don't think I've ever seen Gene Hackman as funny...I didn't know he could do comedy. What a collection of award-winners we have here, and thoroughly deserving of their SAG award for ensemble work.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not quite there...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    oceansroar
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/3/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Birdcage is a remake of a French film which i might have seen, but was too young, so i will check it soon. i am almost willing to bet that as usual with remakes of foreign films Hollywood fails. Perhaps they should promote the actual original films to the American audience, but i suppose the average American (not an intentional jab at American, since i have seen it around the world) will not watch a subtitled film. The story is about Armand, a gay man (Robin Williams) that owns a drag nightclub, in which his lover (Nathan Lane) performs as the starring act. The couple raised a son together for 20 years. The 20 year old son is now wanting to get married, but there are some complications, which make for a few hilarious moments, but only a few. i love the cast of this film, especially Robin Williams. When he is left to his own devices he can be brilliant or over the top, so he really needs a great director that allows him more room to fly, but a leash to pull him back to our atmosphere. This director held the leash too tightly, so Robin never quite got there. Nathan Lane steals most of the thunder from Robin, but he is a little over the top at times. Hank Azaria is brilliant as Agador the houseman. The cast is great, except Calista Flockhart seems a little drab in this film. If you have not watched it, then i recommended that you see it once, but keep an open mind, after all it is about a gay family. i gave it 5/10 because it does not hold up as well as it did in 1996 and the film as a whole was just not quite there.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of half a dozen verions of La Cage aux Folles out there, and Nathan Lane is devastating
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    secondtake
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/7/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Birdcage (1996) Well, there is always something great about a Mike Nichols film, and this one, written and directed by Nichols, is no exception. It is however a story that has had better presentations (see below) and I'm not sure why Nichols opted for such an un-original material. The movie really is great in some ways, and has terrific moments, but it doesn't transcend, as the best Nichols films certainly do. Robin Williams, the apparent big name on the marquee, is the weakest link in the cast (not including the two young people, who are fine but routine). But the rest of the main actors, Nathan Lane as the drag queen most of all, but Gene Hackman as a conservative senator and Dianne Wiest as his wife, are an amazing ensemble. Throw in consistently funny and clever writing (a functioanl adaptation), good camera-work, obviously attractive sets (this is South Beach in Miami), and a lively soundtrack and you sort of can't go far wrong. Is it brilliant? No way. It doesn't need to be. It's got jokes that will fade with time, topical references and timely jabs, but overall it's just perky and funny top to bottom. And relentlessly. And yes, it pushes its point hard, about how we're all people and relationships are relationships, and that's where the comedy matters, making sure you don't take the delivery too seriously. If you have doubts that it's a farce with a silver lining, just wait until you see Gene Hackman at the end. You might argue that the social message is all that matters, and of course that's true to some ways of thinking (and in some camps of criticism), but that would limit the point of the whole affair. And as time goes on and people get more used to the idea of gay culture and gay people as just another aspect of life, well, the sensational aspects of the movie will water down. But that's fine. Besides being inevitable, it points to the other parts of the film, the Shakespearean cross-dressing, the play on identities, the constant repartee. It's funny and fun and yet smart, too. The plot, at its core, is an Americanized version of the original French play (from 1973) La Cage aux Folles (which means roughly "Cage of Drag Queens" if you take into account the slang for folles). And there is of course the famous two versions of the Broadway musical version (the 1983 and 2004 versions, not to mention the current one which started in 2010). It's a great story with a long life, clearly. And the playful interaction of the ensemble is perfect for the stage. Yet this isn't the play nor the musical, but the film, with a new name. And the photographic aspects are pretty wonderful, too. Take just the opening shot coming in on a helicopter over the water and seamlessly (almost, there's a frame or two glitch) gliding right into the night club, The Birdcage. And if you don't think the story has legs, there is a 1978 Italian version of the play (not the musical) on film. The advantage of the American version for American audiences is the references are still slightly recognizable (the Bob Dole comments are already seeming like history, however). Anyway, don't see this for Robin Williams. He's fine, but not the crackup fast talker that he's best at. And it isn't him, but Nathan Lane, who gets to cross-dress. Fabulously. You'll see.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Birds of a Feather
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    edwardtjbrown
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/5/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    In his younger days, Armand Goldman (Robin Williams) was a struggling, gay stage actor who decided to have a one night stand with a female friend (Christine Baranski). The result of this brief fling was Val Goldman (Futterman), who, in the present day, is engaged to be married to a lovely woman. Despite some initial misgivings that Val is too young to be married, Val's parents, Armand Goldman and his husband Albert, (Nathan Lane), agree to support the wedding. Yet, Barbra Keeley (Calita Rockhart), the bride-to-be, comes from a prominent political family in the middle of a tough re-election campaign. U.S. Senator Keeley, who thinks Bob Dole is too liberal, is the co-founder of a Christian Coalition-type interest group dedicated enacting laws promoting "moral order". He and his wife also feel that their daughter is too young to be married, and want to 'table' the wedding until after the campaign, especially when the head of the Moral Order Coalition is found dead in the bed of an underage, African American, prostitute. Seeing the writing on the wall, Barbara begins a clever ruse to depict the Goldman family as a traditional, white, Christian, Republican family whose politics are to the right of Patrick Buchanan, Jerry Falwell and Pat Roberston. Val convinces his parents to go to great lengths, changing their house, dress, mannerisms, religion and politics, to pull off this charade as the in-laws meet for dinner. As one might guess, much of the comedy in this film involves a 1990's satire of the right-wing politics, as well as the media's post-OJ Simpson trial (1995) obsession with tabloid and scandal driven news. Robin Williams and Nathan Lane are great together, although they show each other little affection, with Lane playing the more stereotypical gay man/drag queen entertainer, which manages to avoid coming off as mean spirited. Likewise, the Keeley are as stuffy as they are right-wing, but the film allows each of the family members to develop a character and story arch beyond simple card board cut outs. Oddly enough, the film does not really address gay rights, beyond the, often comedic, contrasts between the two families and the assumptions that are made. Armand and Albert are financially successful, owners of a hip nightclub. They live in a trendy, upscale urban neighborhood where discrimination and harassment does not seem to exist. Gays serving open in the military and legal recognition of same-sex marriage are mentioned, but Armand and Albert seem to be a couple that exists just slightly out of reality. They do argue over a palimony agreement and I am not sure how the film could have been anything else, given when it was made. In the early - mid 1990s, Hollywood films were just beginning to depict gay people in a manner that did not involve them being predatory, suicidal, homicidal manics. Yes, the film clearly mocks the stuffy, uptight future in-laws. Yes, it mocks their right-wing politics and prejudices directed at gay people as well as racial, religious and ethnic minorities. As great, witty and funny as this film is, sometimes it cannot hide its age.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Funny!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    nama chakravorty
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/2/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A remake of the 1978 film, La Cage aux Folles, 'The Birdcage' is an amusingly enjoyable film. Mike Nichols continues his magic in this 1996 cult-hit, The legendary filmmaker, along-with a stellar cast and a freaky screenplay, makes a truly funny film about everything gone haywire! 'The Birdcage' is about a gay cabaret owner and his drag queen companion agree to put up a false straight front so that their son can introduce them to his fianc&eacute;'s right-wing moralistic parents. Source taken from IMDb! To be honest, the film begins tepidly and it takes time to grasp each and every character's intentions and further plans. But once you get into the groove, you enter a joyride. The entire last hour, right after Gene Hackman & Co enter Williams house, there is hardly a moment when you don't laugh. Also, watching Gene Hackman as a drag in the climax, is simply hilarious! Mike Nichols directs the film with his usual midas touch. He is amongst the most talented filmmakers ever. The adapted Screenplay is full of absurd, funny, hilarious & strange situations. Cinematography by Emmanuel Lubezki is perfect. Editing could've been sharper. Now to the performances! With such a stellar cast coming under one roof, one expects nothing but exemplary acting. Each and Every Actor delivers in here. Robin Williams, Gene Hackman, Nathan Lane & Dianne Wiest are absolutely flawless. Dan Futterman, Calista Flockhart & Hank Azaria are at par with the seniors! On the whole, A Comedy that needs a watch. An absurd yet lovable experience! Thumbs Up!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
 </reviews>
</filme>
