<filme>
 <id>
  254
 </id>
 <imdburl>
  http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0118688
 </imdburl>
 <ano>
  1997
 </ano>
 <titulo>
  Batman & Robin
 </titulo>
 <rating>
  3.6
 </rating>
 <sinopse>
  Batman & Robin try to keep their relationship together even as they must stop Mr. Freeze and Poison Ivy from freezing Gotham City.
 </sinopse>
 <storyline>
  Batman and Robin are back working side-by-side to stop the villains of Gotham City, but is there tension appearing between them, especially when one villainess who calls herself Poison Ivy can make anyone fall in love with her...literally. Along with Poison Ivy, the icy Mr. Freeze is freezing anything which gets in his way from achieving his goal.
 </storyline>
 <generos>
  <genero>
   Action
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Crime
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Fantasy
  </genero>
 </generos>
 <keywords>
  <keyword>
   freeze
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   gotham
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   disease
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   sidekick
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   death
  </keyword>
 </keywords>
 <diretores>
  <diretor>
   Joel Schumacher
  </diretor>
 </diretores>
 <escritores>
  <escritor>
   Bob Kane
  </escritor>
  <escritor>
   Akiva Goldsman
  </escritor>
 </escritores>
 <atores>
  <ator>
   Arnold Schwarzenegger
  </ator>
  <ator>
   George Clooney
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Chris O'Donnell
  </ator>
 </atores>
 <reviews>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Some touching scenes completely overshadowed by ridiculous rubbish!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    powerkrust
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Batman & Robin, world famous franchise killer and the best example of why studios should not interfere with the movie making process. Batman Forever was a roaring success at the box office but this success was largely due to the reputation of the first two Burton films and zero to do with the actual quality of the movie. Batman & Robin was released to an audience now wise to what was going on and now the studios saw what the world thought of their family pandering and dumbed down plot. Batman & Robin was universally panned by just about everyone, including Director Joel Schumacher who walked out of the premier in embarrassment, but really....was it all that bad? The answer is both yes and no but the negative vastly outweighs any positives the film has to offer. The films script, if you can call it that is nothing more than a collection of one liners. In fact almost all of Arnie's dialogue as Mr Freeze is one liners and the jokey too and fro of Batman & Robin is cringeworthy. It's not even so bad it's good funny it's just bad, like a low budget under 5's kids TV program except this film cost a lot of money to make. The inaccuracies to the source material really ticked off the comic book community. It's true that Burton didn't stick entirely to the source either but he captured a lot of what the comic was about. Schumacher doesn't have a clue and seems content with quick flashes of Batman's arse to carry the film and zero sense of character depth anywhere to be seen. Amazingly enough the film DOES in fact have some good points. The best of the bunch being the wonderful Michael Gough having probably the most screen time of all the Batman films. The sub-story of his illness and the scenes that tell this are actually very moving and it's great to see Michael have a chance to do something a bit more in depth. It must be said also that George Cloony is an almost perfect fit for the role of Bruce Wayne with his suave look and manner and his scenes with Gough really have a lot of warmth but he is severely let down with the film he is in. Other good points include some very nice sets, props and some great designs for the look of Gotham City, though these too are marred by garish lighting and wobbly fake looking ice. Uma Thurman clearly is performing tongue in cheek and as such get's a way with it but even she cannot save the terrible surroundings she is in. Somewhere deep in Batman & Robin there was a good film that was wanting to get out and it could very well have been pulled off with the cast, but campy humour and cheap laughs which weren't even funny completely rob the film of anything it was trying to achieve in any of the more serious scenes and unfortunately that's all people remember. Let this film be remembered as a lesson to studios, don't interfere with the creative process of film making. Batman could have gone on for many films but you killed it stone dead with this one and it should never be repeated again.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Some touching scenes completely overshadowed by ridiculous rubbish!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    powerkrust
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Batman & Robin, world famous franchise killer and the best example of why studios should not interfere with the movie making process. Batman Forever was a roaring success at the box office but this success was largely due to the reputation of the first two Burton films and zero to do with the actual quality of the movie. Batman & Robin was released to an audience now wise to what was going on and now the studios saw what the world thought of their family pandering and dumbed down plot. Batman & Robin was universally panned by just about everyone, including Director Joel Schumacher who walked out of the premier in embarrassment, but really....was it all that bad? The answer is both yes and no but the negative vastly outweighs any positives the film has to offer. The films script, if you can call it that is nothing more than a collection of one liners. In fact almost all of Arnie's dialogue as Mr Freeze is one liners and the jokey too and fro of Batman & Robin is cringeworthy. It's not even so bad it's good funny it's just bad, like a low budget under 5's kids TV program except this film cost a lot of money to make. The inaccuracies to the source material really ticked off the comic book community. It's true that Burton didn't stick entirely to the source either but he captured a lot of what the comic was about. Schumacher doesn't have a clue and seems content with quick flashes of Batman's arse to carry the film and zero sense of character depth anywhere to be seen. Amazingly enough the film DOES in fact have some good points. The best of the bunch being the wonderful Michael Gough having probably the most screen time of all the Batman films. The sub-story of his illness and the scenes that tell this are actually very moving and it's great to see Michael have a chance to do something a bit more in depth. It must be said also that George Cloony is an almost perfect fit for the role of Bruce Wayne with his suave look and manner and his scenes with Gough really have a lot of warmth but he is severely let down with the film he is in. Other good points include some very nice sets, props and some great designs for the look of Gotham City, though these too are marred by garish lighting and wobbly fake looking ice. Uma Thurman clearly is performing tongue in cheek and as such get's a way with it but even she cannot save the terrible surroundings she is in. Somewhere deep in Batman & Robin there was a good film that was wanting to get out and it could very well have been pulled off with the cast, but campy humour and cheap laughs which weren't even funny completely rob the film of anything it was trying to achieve in any of the more serious scenes and unfortunately that's all people remember. Let this film be remembered as a lesson to studios, don't interfere with the creative process of film making. Batman could have gone on for many films but you killed it stone dead with this one and it should never be repeated again.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    This is the worst movie I have ever saw in my entire life.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    hansonevan14
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie sucks. The casting sucks, the acting sucks, the action sucks, the effect sucks, everything about this movie is a mess. I spend one Thanksgiving night watch this shitty movie. I hate this movie so much. The first line of this movie is that Robin said "I want a car, chicks dig to car" and then Batman said "this is why Superman works alone". It gets worse and worse by the minute. Batman is play by George Clooney, which makes Val Kilmer's batman look like Michael Keaton's batman. Look I like George Clooney he's a good actor, but was he good in this, not at all. He doesn't have the right Batman voice, he just crashed through the window and was like "hi freeze I'm Batman". Really, is that the best you could do. Overall, George Clooney is a terrible Batman. Robin is play by Chris O' Donnell. All he does in this entire movie is just complain about stupid stuff. And that's all I have to say about his performance in this movie. Mr.Freeze is play by Arnold Schwarzenegger. One of the worst casting decisions ever. He only said one liners in this movie that consists of puns. And that pun is ice. "Allow me to break the ice", "Okay everyone, chill" "Hell, freeze is over", "Let's kick some ice", "What kill the dinosaurs, the ice age". Poison Ivy is play by Uma Thurman. She was actually nominated for an Oscar before this movie came out. Terrible performance from her in this movie, worst Poison Ivy. Batgirl is play by Alicia Silverstone. Worst performance in this movie. That's all I have to say. In the end, never see this movie, ever. This is the worst movie I have ever saw in my entire life. I'll never see it again. Oh yeah, who could ever forget the Bat-Nipples and Bat-Asses. Who's idea was that in the first place to put those things in? I hate this movie so much, makes me cringe every time I think about it. This movie is so horrible!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I Fell Asleep During The Movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bigverybadtom
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    My girlfriend got this as a gift, and we watched it together one evening. I fell asleep while watching it, and though my girlfriend presumably did not, she indicated not liking this either. What was wrong with it? Everything. "Batman" may supposed to be dark, but there was too much darkness in this one. Contrast does help keep one's interest, and Batman doesn't absolutely require darkness to be successful, as you might guess if you've seen the other movies, comics, etc. The heroes are bad. The interaction between the title characters doesn't come off properly. The villains are worse. The police tell Batman about the new villain, Mr. Freeze. (Huh? Batman is supposed to be the great detective who knows everything before anyone else does!) And Arnold Schwarzenegger was as suitable for the character as Danny DeVito would be to play Marilyn Monroe. The female villain stinks too. It's hard to describe more; I fell asleep because everything was done so badly. I wouldn't be surprised if everyone wasn't sleeping themselves when they were making this movie.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Awesome movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    blade1634989
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I for one loved this movie I've seen all live action batman's(excluding the horrible horrible fan made crap) yes The new batman's with christen bale are awesome but nothing beat a classic this movie is amazing and right up to pare with the first 3 it truly gives you The DC Comic feel witch i thought was great and BANE let me tell you if you watched the new dark knight the Bane in this movie would eat that guy for dinner BANE IS BIG HES BAD AND HE KICKS ASS witch is how banes suppose to be hes and x-con and a big dumb brute Never once was bane a criminal mastermind in the comics he was always there to pummel bats wile the real master mind killed stole and made his escape. This movie like the first 3 were all great comic based movies fun to watch with the kids and stuck true to the dc comic yes maybe clooney wasn't the best choice for batman i personally liked val kilmer better but that's just me. SO ignore all the shitty reviews and watch it for yours self keeping in mind not to compare it to the Dark-knight Trilogy but to the DC Comics we all know and love
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Worst Case of Groupthink Criticism Ever
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Clark Ho
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie was a hell of a lot of fun. I was fortunate enough to see it without hearing all the "let's all pan this" baloney and both my then GF and I thought it was great. I remember Clooney as a perfectly charming and intense Batman and Arnold at his self- deprecating silliest, portraying a wonderfully funny supervillain. The professional critimob just held hands and jumped on it per their usual thoughtless whim and the general audience just woke up on the wrong side of the collective bed that weekend. If you haven't seen it yet, go ahead and check it out and see how wrong conventional wisdom can be.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    what in the name of all that is holy is this?!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    movie critic
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It is to bad I can't give this movie minus one. Batman and Robin is hated by everyone blessed with the gift of sight. You have to be blind or even deaf to like this movie, or both! It is the worst representation of who Batman is. A comic book is better than this. Mr. Freeze wasn't a cool villain to start with and they made him worse with his stupid cheesy lines and his plastic chrome costume. Poison Ivy is supposed to be sexy but they managed to make her look like green alien, she wears a cheap cotton costume and blows some sort of essence into men's faces one to many times. George Clooney is a cool and calm Bruce Wayne but he is not so great at being batman. Robin is not so bad and bat girl is totally useless. Joel is a very bad director and he ruined batman. Please do not watch this movie. I personally think it is the work of Satan. Only he could have thought of something like that. But nevertheless, it is the worst movie that mankind has ever created. It is possibly the worst thing mankind has ever created.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Most Over-hated Movie In History
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    zduvvian
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    When I see reviews for the movie 'Batman and Robin', people always seem to say that it is an awful movie and one of the worst films ever made. I have seen it, and to be honest, I really like it. It is campy and a little stupid, but it really doesn't deserve to be given the same title given to other horrible movies like 'The Garbage Pail Kids Movie' or 'Jaws: The Revenge'. I'm not saying that people should stop hating on this movie (because I can see what people have against it) but I do think that people need to calm down about it. There are far worse superhero movies out there like 'Superman IV' and 'Catwoman'. Onto the film itself, like I said, I can see what people have against it: "The acting is awful, the story is campy and the movie overall isn't well directed". I don't think the acting is that bad. There are a few characters who are terrible (like Batgirl, who was meant to be British but it is obvious that the actress is American), but some characters do pretty good performances. George Clooney does a good job as Batman, Michael Gough does a great job as Alfred, Uma Thurman is a convincing Poison Ivy and Arnold Schwarzenegger is a pretty funny Mr Freeze (although I do agree that most of his ice puns are painful). The rest of the characters are pretty mediocre, but not terrible. The story is no Oscar-winning masterpiece, but it is still a good story that flows well. The (very) basic plot synopsis is that Batman and Robin are trying to stop Mr Freeze and Poison Ivy from freezing Gotham City and taking over the world. (Of course!) That may sound like a boring and clich&eacute;d story, but it is actually quite good. The sub-plots fit into the story perfectly, especially one about Alfred dying of MacGregor's Syndrome. Overall, I feel that Batman and Robin is one of the most over-hated movies of all time and should really be given a chance. Like I said, it isn't perfect, but it really isn't as awful as everybody says. If you watch the movie with the knowledge that is a campy flick, you'll have a good time, just don't listen to the people who say that it is a horrible abomination to cinema, because it really isn't. 7/10 P.S. - If you want to know what I think of Bane, I think he is closer to the comics than Bane in 'The Dark Knight Rises' because the inclusion of the Venom drug that gives Bane his strength.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    so bad it hurts
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    dbenitez25
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    the thing is that there isn't much to say, is just not worth it... is a really bad movie... the script is crap, the customs are crap, the special effects are crap, the roles are crap, the time-line is crap, there isn't a single thing to point out as positive. I am sorry but is a real bummer. And another thing, at last but not least... Really? Nipples?? nipples in a Batman suit??? is just a disgrace...
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Joel, you where possessed when you made this film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    natebridgeman
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie SUCKS!!!!!! The entire film is just one two and a half hour toy commercial. It's possibly the worst film of all time with over the top action sequences, ridiculous costumes and make-up, effect that were obviously drawn on paper, just plain terrible acting, everyone wanting to punch robin in the face 700 times, and most of all, 65% of the entire movie is just plain one-liners. There is just plain nothing I love about about this movie. It makes every other bad movie look like a masterpiece. Don't even waste your time like I did. If you want to live a happy life on earth. This movie not only killed the Batman franchise for 8 years, but it also killed superhero movies for 4 years. George Clooney is the worst batman ever!!!!!!! Joel Schumaucher, if you are looking at this review you killed one of my favorite superheros. At least, thank the Lord God Almighty that he created Christopher Nolan. Why did Warner Bros. release this garbage. Don't see it at all!!!!!!!!!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Some touching scenes completely overshadowed by ridiculous rubbish!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    powerkrust
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Batman & Robin, world famous franchise killer and the best example of why studios should not interfere with the movie making process. Batman Forever was a roaring success at the box office but this success was largely due to the reputation of the first two Burton films and zero to do with the actual quality of the movie. Batman & Robin was released to an audience now wise to what was going on and now the studios saw what the world thought of their family pandering and dumbed down plot. Batman & Robin was universally panned by just about everyone, including Director Joel Schumacher who walked out of the premier in embarrassment, but really....was it all that bad? The answer is both yes and no but the negative vastly outweighs any positives the film has to offer. The films script, if you can call it that is nothing more than a collection of one liners. In fact almost all of Arnie's dialogue as Mr Freeze is one liners and the jokey too and fro of Batman & Robin is cringeworthy. It's not even so bad it's good funny it's just bad, like a low budget under 5's kids TV program except this film cost a lot of money to make. The inaccuracies to the source material really ticked off the comic book community. It's true that Burton didn't stick entirely to the source either but he captured a lot of what the comic was about. Schumacher doesn't have a clue and seems content with quick flashes of Batman's arse to carry the film and zero sense of character depth anywhere to be seen. Amazingly enough the film DOES in fact have some good points. The best of the bunch being the wonderful Michael Gough having probably the most screen time of all the Batman films. The sub-story of his illness and the scenes that tell this are actually very moving and it's great to see Michael have a chance to do something a bit more in depth. It must be said also that George Cloony is an almost perfect fit for the role of Bruce Wayne with his suave look and manner and his scenes with Gough really have a lot of warmth but he is severely let down with the film he is in. Other good points include some very nice sets, props and some great designs for the look of Gotham City, though these too are marred by garish lighting and wobbly fake looking ice. Uma Thurman clearly is performing tongue in cheek and as such get's a way with it but even she cannot save the terrible surroundings she is in. Somewhere deep in Batman & Robin there was a good film that was wanting to get out and it could very well have been pulled off with the cast, but campy humour and cheap laughs which weren't even funny completely rob the film of anything it was trying to achieve in any of the more serious scenes and unfortunately that's all people remember. Let this film be remembered as a lesson to studios, don't interfere with the creative process of film making. Batman could have gone on for many films but you killed it stone dead with this one and it should never be repeated again.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Some touching scenes completely overshadowed by ridiculous rubbish!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    powerkrust
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Batman & Robin, world famous franchise killer and the best example of why studios should not interfere with the movie making process. Batman Forever was a roaring success at the box office but this success was largely due to the reputation of the first two Burton films and zero to do with the actual quality of the movie. Batman & Robin was released to an audience now wise to what was going on and now the studios saw what the world thought of their family pandering and dumbed down plot. Batman & Robin was universally panned by just about everyone, including Director Joel Schumacher who walked out of the premier in embarrassment, but really....was it all that bad? The answer is both yes and no but the negative vastly outweighs any positives the film has to offer. The films script, if you can call it that is nothing more than a collection of one liners. In fact almost all of Arnie's dialogue as Mr Freeze is one liners and the jokey too and fro of Batman & Robin is cringeworthy. It's not even so bad it's good funny it's just bad, like a low budget under 5's kids TV program except this film cost a lot of money to make. The inaccuracies to the source material really ticked off the comic book community. It's true that Burton didn't stick entirely to the source either but he captured a lot of what the comic was about. Schumacher doesn't have a clue and seems content with quick flashes of Batman's arse to carry the film and zero sense of character depth anywhere to be seen. Amazingly enough the film DOES in fact have some good points. The best of the bunch being the wonderful Michael Gough having probably the most screen time of all the Batman films. The sub-story of his illness and the scenes that tell this are actually very moving and it's great to see Michael have a chance to do something a bit more in depth. It must be said also that George Cloony is an almost perfect fit for the role of Bruce Wayne with his suave look and manner and his scenes with Gough really have a lot of warmth but he is severely let down with the film he is in. Other good points include some very nice sets, props and some great designs for the look of Gotham City, though these too are marred by garish lighting and wobbly fake looking ice. Uma Thurman clearly is performing tongue in cheek and as such get's a way with it but even she cannot save the terrible surroundings she is in. Somewhere deep in Batman & Robin there was a good film that was wanting to get out and it could very well have been pulled off with the cast, but campy humour and cheap laughs which weren't even funny completely rob the film of anything it was trying to achieve in any of the more serious scenes and unfortunately that's all people remember. Let this film be remembered as a lesson to studios, don't interfere with the creative process of film making. Batman could have gone on for many films but you killed it stone dead with this one and it should never be repeated again.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    This is the worst movie I have ever saw in my entire life.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    hansonevan14
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie sucks. The casting sucks, the acting sucks, the action sucks, the effect sucks, everything about this movie is a mess. I spend one Thanksgiving night watch this shitty movie. I hate this movie so much. The first line of this movie is that Robin said "I want a car, chicks dig to car" and then Batman said "this is why Superman works alone". It gets worse and worse by the minute. Batman is play by George Clooney, which makes Val Kilmer's batman look like Michael Keaton's batman. Look I like George Clooney he's a good actor, but was he good in this, not at all. He doesn't have the right Batman voice, he just crashed through the window and was like "hi freeze I'm Batman". Really, is that the best you could do. Overall, George Clooney is a terrible Batman. Robin is play by Chris O' Donnell. All he does in this entire movie is just complain about stupid stuff. And that's all I have to say about his performance in this movie. Mr.Freeze is play by Arnold Schwarzenegger. One of the worst casting decisions ever. He only said one liners in this movie that consists of puns. And that pun is ice. "Allow me to break the ice", "Okay everyone, chill" "Hell, freeze is over", "Let's kick some ice", "What kill the dinosaurs, the ice age". Poison Ivy is play by Uma Thurman. She was actually nominated for an Oscar before this movie came out. Terrible performance from her in this movie, worst Poison Ivy. Batgirl is play by Alicia Silverstone. Worst performance in this movie. That's all I have to say. In the end, never see this movie, ever. This is the worst movie I have ever saw in my entire life. I'll never see it again. Oh yeah, who could ever forget the Bat-Nipples and Bat-Asses. Who's idea was that in the first place to put those things in? I hate this movie so much, makes me cringe every time I think about it. This movie is so horrible!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I Fell Asleep During The Movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bigverybadtom
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    My girlfriend got this as a gift, and we watched it together one evening. I fell asleep while watching it, and though my girlfriend presumably did not, she indicated not liking this either. What was wrong with it? Everything. "Batman" may supposed to be dark, but there was too much darkness in this one. Contrast does help keep one's interest, and Batman doesn't absolutely require darkness to be successful, as you might guess if you've seen the other movies, comics, etc. The heroes are bad. The interaction between the title characters doesn't come off properly. The villains are worse. The police tell Batman about the new villain, Mr. Freeze. (Huh? Batman is supposed to be the great detective who knows everything before anyone else does!) And Arnold Schwarzenegger was as suitable for the character as Danny DeVito would be to play Marilyn Monroe. The female villain stinks too. It's hard to describe more; I fell asleep because everything was done so badly. I wouldn't be surprised if everyone wasn't sleeping themselves when they were making this movie.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Awesome movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    blade1634989
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I for one loved this movie I've seen all live action batman's(excluding the horrible horrible fan made crap) yes The new batman's with christen bale are awesome but nothing beat a classic this movie is amazing and right up to pare with the first 3 it truly gives you The DC Comic feel witch i thought was great and BANE let me tell you if you watched the new dark knight the Bane in this movie would eat that guy for dinner BANE IS BIG HES BAD AND HE KICKS ASS witch is how banes suppose to be hes and x-con and a big dumb brute Never once was bane a criminal mastermind in the comics he was always there to pummel bats wile the real master mind killed stole and made his escape. This movie like the first 3 were all great comic based movies fun to watch with the kids and stuck true to the dc comic yes maybe clooney wasn't the best choice for batman i personally liked val kilmer better but that's just me. SO ignore all the shitty reviews and watch it for yours self keeping in mind not to compare it to the Dark-knight Trilogy but to the DC Comics we all know and love
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Worst Case of Groupthink Criticism Ever
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Clark Ho
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie was a hell of a lot of fun. I was fortunate enough to see it without hearing all the "let's all pan this" baloney and both my then GF and I thought it was great. I remember Clooney as a perfectly charming and intense Batman and Arnold at his self- deprecating silliest, portraying a wonderfully funny supervillain. The professional critimob just held hands and jumped on it per their usual thoughtless whim and the general audience just woke up on the wrong side of the collective bed that weekend. If you haven't seen it yet, go ahead and check it out and see how wrong conventional wisdom can be.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    what in the name of all that is holy is this?!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    movie critic
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It is to bad I can't give this movie minus one. Batman and Robin is hated by everyone blessed with the gift of sight. You have to be blind or even deaf to like this movie, or both! It is the worst representation of who Batman is. A comic book is better than this. Mr. Freeze wasn't a cool villain to start with and they made him worse with his stupid cheesy lines and his plastic chrome costume. Poison Ivy is supposed to be sexy but they managed to make her look like green alien, she wears a cheap cotton costume and blows some sort of essence into men's faces one to many times. George Clooney is a cool and calm Bruce Wayne but he is not so great at being batman. Robin is not so bad and bat girl is totally useless. Joel is a very bad director and he ruined batman. Please do not watch this movie. I personally think it is the work of Satan. Only he could have thought of something like that. But nevertheless, it is the worst movie that mankind has ever created. It is possibly the worst thing mankind has ever created.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Most Over-hated Movie In History
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    zduvvian
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    When I see reviews for the movie 'Batman and Robin', people always seem to say that it is an awful movie and one of the worst films ever made. I have seen it, and to be honest, I really like it. It is campy and a little stupid, but it really doesn't deserve to be given the same title given to other horrible movies like 'The Garbage Pail Kids Movie' or 'Jaws: The Revenge'. I'm not saying that people should stop hating on this movie (because I can see what people have against it) but I do think that people need to calm down about it. There are far worse superhero movies out there like 'Superman IV' and 'Catwoman'. Onto the film itself, like I said, I can see what people have against it: "The acting is awful, the story is campy and the movie overall isn't well directed". I don't think the acting is that bad. There are a few characters who are terrible (like Batgirl, who was meant to be British but it is obvious that the actress is American), but some characters do pretty good performances. George Clooney does a good job as Batman, Michael Gough does a great job as Alfred, Uma Thurman is a convincing Poison Ivy and Arnold Schwarzenegger is a pretty funny Mr Freeze (although I do agree that most of his ice puns are painful). The rest of the characters are pretty mediocre, but not terrible. The story is no Oscar-winning masterpiece, but it is still a good story that flows well. The (very) basic plot synopsis is that Batman and Robin are trying to stop Mr Freeze and Poison Ivy from freezing Gotham City and taking over the world. (Of course!) That may sound like a boring and clich&eacute;d story, but it is actually quite good. The sub-plots fit into the story perfectly, especially one about Alfred dying of MacGregor's Syndrome. Overall, I feel that Batman and Robin is one of the most over-hated movies of all time and should really be given a chance. Like I said, it isn't perfect, but it really isn't as awful as everybody says. If you watch the movie with the knowledge that is a campy flick, you'll have a good time, just don't listen to the people who say that it is a horrible abomination to cinema, because it really isn't. 7/10 P.S. - If you want to know what I think of Bane, I think he is closer to the comics than Bane in 'The Dark Knight Rises' because the inclusion of the Venom drug that gives Bane his strength.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    so bad it hurts
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    dbenitez25
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    the thing is that there isn't much to say, is just not worth it... is a really bad movie... the script is crap, the customs are crap, the special effects are crap, the roles are crap, the time-line is crap, there isn't a single thing to point out as positive. I am sorry but is a real bummer. And another thing, at last but not least... Really? Nipples?? nipples in a Batman suit??? is just a disgrace...
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Joel, you where possessed when you made this film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    natebridgeman
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie SUCKS!!!!!! The entire film is just one two and a half hour toy commercial. It's possibly the worst film of all time with over the top action sequences, ridiculous costumes and make-up, effect that were obviously drawn on paper, just plain terrible acting, everyone wanting to punch robin in the face 700 times, and most of all, 65% of the entire movie is just plain one-liners. There is just plain nothing I love about about this movie. It makes every other bad movie look like a masterpiece. Don't even waste your time like I did. If you want to live a happy life on earth. This movie not only killed the Batman franchise for 8 years, but it also killed superhero movies for 4 years. George Clooney is the worst batman ever!!!!!!! Joel Schumaucher, if you are looking at this review you killed one of my favorite superheros. At least, thank the Lord God Almighty that he created Christopher Nolan. Why did Warner Bros. release this garbage. Don't see it at all!!!!!!!!!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Some touching scenes completely overshadowed by ridiculous rubbish!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    powerkrust
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Batman & Robin, world famous franchise killer and the best example of why studios should not interfere with the movie making process. Batman Forever was a roaring success at the box office but this success was largely due to the reputation of the first two Burton films and zero to do with the actual quality of the movie. Batman & Robin was released to an audience now wise to what was going on and now the studios saw what the world thought of their family pandering and dumbed down plot. Batman & Robin was universally panned by just about everyone, including Director Joel Schumacher who walked out of the premier in embarrassment, but really....was it all that bad? The answer is both yes and no but the negative vastly outweighs any positives the film has to offer. The films script, if you can call it that is nothing more than a collection of one liners. In fact almost all of Arnie's dialogue as Mr Freeze is one liners and the jokey too and fro of Batman & Robin is cringeworthy. It's not even so bad it's good funny it's just bad, like a low budget under 5's kids TV program except this film cost a lot of money to make. The inaccuracies to the source material really ticked off the comic book community. It's true that Burton didn't stick entirely to the source either but he captured a lot of what the comic was about. Schumacher doesn't have a clue and seems content with quick flashes of Batman's arse to carry the film and zero sense of character depth anywhere to be seen. Amazingly enough the film DOES in fact have some good points. The best of the bunch being the wonderful Michael Gough having probably the most screen time of all the Batman films. The sub-story of his illness and the scenes that tell this are actually very moving and it's great to see Michael have a chance to do something a bit more in depth. It must be said also that George Cloony is an almost perfect fit for the role of Bruce Wayne with his suave look and manner and his scenes with Gough really have a lot of warmth but he is severely let down with the film he is in. Other good points include some very nice sets, props and some great designs for the look of Gotham City, though these too are marred by garish lighting and wobbly fake looking ice. Uma Thurman clearly is performing tongue in cheek and as such get's a way with it but even she cannot save the terrible surroundings she is in. Somewhere deep in Batman & Robin there was a good film that was wanting to get out and it could very well have been pulled off with the cast, but campy humour and cheap laughs which weren't even funny completely rob the film of anything it was trying to achieve in any of the more serious scenes and unfortunately that's all people remember. Let this film be remembered as a lesson to studios, don't interfere with the creative process of film making. Batman could have gone on for many films but you killed it stone dead with this one and it should never be repeated again.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Some touching scenes completely overshadowed by ridiculous rubbish!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    powerkrust
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Batman & Robin, world famous franchise killer and the best example of why studios should not interfere with the movie making process. Batman Forever was a roaring success at the box office but this success was largely due to the reputation of the first two Burton films and zero to do with the actual quality of the movie. Batman & Robin was released to an audience now wise to what was going on and now the studios saw what the world thought of their family pandering and dumbed down plot. Batman & Robin was universally panned by just about everyone, including Director Joel Schumacher who walked out of the premier in embarrassment, but really....was it all that bad? The answer is both yes and no but the negative vastly outweighs any positives the film has to offer. The films script, if you can call it that is nothing more than a collection of one liners. In fact almost all of Arnie's dialogue as Mr Freeze is one liners and the jokey too and fro of Batman & Robin is cringeworthy. It's not even so bad it's good funny it's just bad, like a low budget under 5's kids TV program except this film cost a lot of money to make. The inaccuracies to the source material really ticked off the comic book community. It's true that Burton didn't stick entirely to the source either but he captured a lot of what the comic was about. Schumacher doesn't have a clue and seems content with quick flashes of Batman's arse to carry the film and zero sense of character depth anywhere to be seen. Amazingly enough the film DOES in fact have some good points. The best of the bunch being the wonderful Michael Gough having probably the most screen time of all the Batman films. The sub-story of his illness and the scenes that tell this are actually very moving and it's great to see Michael have a chance to do something a bit more in depth. It must be said also that George Cloony is an almost perfect fit for the role of Bruce Wayne with his suave look and manner and his scenes with Gough really have a lot of warmth but he is severely let down with the film he is in. Other good points include some very nice sets, props and some great designs for the look of Gotham City, though these too are marred by garish lighting and wobbly fake looking ice. Uma Thurman clearly is performing tongue in cheek and as such get's a way with it but even she cannot save the terrible surroundings she is in. Somewhere deep in Batman & Robin there was a good film that was wanting to get out and it could very well have been pulled off with the cast, but campy humour and cheap laughs which weren't even funny completely rob the film of anything it was trying to achieve in any of the more serious scenes and unfortunately that's all people remember. Let this film be remembered as a lesson to studios, don't interfere with the creative process of film making. Batman could have gone on for many films but you killed it stone dead with this one and it should never be repeated again.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    This is the worst movie I have ever saw in my entire life.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    hansonevan14
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie sucks. The casting sucks, the acting sucks, the action sucks, the effect sucks, everything about this movie is a mess. I spend one Thanksgiving night watch this shitty movie. I hate this movie so much. The first line of this movie is that Robin said "I want a car, chicks dig to car" and then Batman said "this is why Superman works alone". It gets worse and worse by the minute. Batman is play by George Clooney, which makes Val Kilmer's batman look like Michael Keaton's batman. Look I like George Clooney he's a good actor, but was he good in this, not at all. He doesn't have the right Batman voice, he just crashed through the window and was like "hi freeze I'm Batman". Really, is that the best you could do. Overall, George Clooney is a terrible Batman. Robin is play by Chris O' Donnell. All he does in this entire movie is just complain about stupid stuff. And that's all I have to say about his performance in this movie. Mr.Freeze is play by Arnold Schwarzenegger. One of the worst casting decisions ever. He only said one liners in this movie that consists of puns. And that pun is ice. "Allow me to break the ice", "Okay everyone, chill" "Hell, freeze is over", "Let's kick some ice", "What kill the dinosaurs, the ice age". Poison Ivy is play by Uma Thurman. She was actually nominated for an Oscar before this movie came out. Terrible performance from her in this movie, worst Poison Ivy. Batgirl is play by Alicia Silverstone. Worst performance in this movie. That's all I have to say. In the end, never see this movie, ever. This is the worst movie I have ever saw in my entire life. I'll never see it again. Oh yeah, who could ever forget the Bat-Nipples and Bat-Asses. Who's idea was that in the first place to put those things in? I hate this movie so much, makes me cringe every time I think about it. This movie is so horrible!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I Fell Asleep During The Movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bigverybadtom
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    My girlfriend got this as a gift, and we watched it together one evening. I fell asleep while watching it, and though my girlfriend presumably did not, she indicated not liking this either. What was wrong with it? Everything. "Batman" may supposed to be dark, but there was too much darkness in this one. Contrast does help keep one's interest, and Batman doesn't absolutely require darkness to be successful, as you might guess if you've seen the other movies, comics, etc. The heroes are bad. The interaction between the title characters doesn't come off properly. The villains are worse. The police tell Batman about the new villain, Mr. Freeze. (Huh? Batman is supposed to be the great detective who knows everything before anyone else does!) And Arnold Schwarzenegger was as suitable for the character as Danny DeVito would be to play Marilyn Monroe. The female villain stinks too. It's hard to describe more; I fell asleep because everything was done so badly. I wouldn't be surprised if everyone wasn't sleeping themselves when they were making this movie.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Awesome movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    blade1634989
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I for one loved this movie I've seen all live action batman's(excluding the horrible horrible fan made crap) yes The new batman's with christen bale are awesome but nothing beat a classic this movie is amazing and right up to pare with the first 3 it truly gives you The DC Comic feel witch i thought was great and BANE let me tell you if you watched the new dark knight the Bane in this movie would eat that guy for dinner BANE IS BIG HES BAD AND HE KICKS ASS witch is how banes suppose to be hes and x-con and a big dumb brute Never once was bane a criminal mastermind in the comics he was always there to pummel bats wile the real master mind killed stole and made his escape. This movie like the first 3 were all great comic based movies fun to watch with the kids and stuck true to the dc comic yes maybe clooney wasn't the best choice for batman i personally liked val kilmer better but that's just me. SO ignore all the shitty reviews and watch it for yours self keeping in mind not to compare it to the Dark-knight Trilogy but to the DC Comics we all know and love
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Worst Case of Groupthink Criticism Ever
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Clark Ho
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie was a hell of a lot of fun. I was fortunate enough to see it without hearing all the "let's all pan this" baloney and both my then GF and I thought it was great. I remember Clooney as a perfectly charming and intense Batman and Arnold at his self- deprecating silliest, portraying a wonderfully funny supervillain. The professional critimob just held hands and jumped on it per their usual thoughtless whim and the general audience just woke up on the wrong side of the collective bed that weekend. If you haven't seen it yet, go ahead and check it out and see how wrong conventional wisdom can be.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    what in the name of all that is holy is this?!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    movie critic
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It is to bad I can't give this movie minus one. Batman and Robin is hated by everyone blessed with the gift of sight. You have to be blind or even deaf to like this movie, or both! It is the worst representation of who Batman is. A comic book is better than this. Mr. Freeze wasn't a cool villain to start with and they made him worse with his stupid cheesy lines and his plastic chrome costume. Poison Ivy is supposed to be sexy but they managed to make her look like green alien, she wears a cheap cotton costume and blows some sort of essence into men's faces one to many times. George Clooney is a cool and calm Bruce Wayne but he is not so great at being batman. Robin is not so bad and bat girl is totally useless. Joel is a very bad director and he ruined batman. Please do not watch this movie. I personally think it is the work of Satan. Only he could have thought of something like that. But nevertheless, it is the worst movie that mankind has ever created. It is possibly the worst thing mankind has ever created.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Most Over-hated Movie In History
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    zduvvian
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    When I see reviews for the movie 'Batman and Robin', people always seem to say that it is an awful movie and one of the worst films ever made. I have seen it, and to be honest, I really like it. It is campy and a little stupid, but it really doesn't deserve to be given the same title given to other horrible movies like 'The Garbage Pail Kids Movie' or 'Jaws: The Revenge'. I'm not saying that people should stop hating on this movie (because I can see what people have against it) but I do think that people need to calm down about it. There are far worse superhero movies out there like 'Superman IV' and 'Catwoman'. Onto the film itself, like I said, I can see what people have against it: "The acting is awful, the story is campy and the movie overall isn't well directed". I don't think the acting is that bad. There are a few characters who are terrible (like Batgirl, who was meant to be British but it is obvious that the actress is American), but some characters do pretty good performances. George Clooney does a good job as Batman, Michael Gough does a great job as Alfred, Uma Thurman is a convincing Poison Ivy and Arnold Schwarzenegger is a pretty funny Mr Freeze (although I do agree that most of his ice puns are painful). The rest of the characters are pretty mediocre, but not terrible. The story is no Oscar-winning masterpiece, but it is still a good story that flows well. The (very) basic plot synopsis is that Batman and Robin are trying to stop Mr Freeze and Poison Ivy from freezing Gotham City and taking over the world. (Of course!) That may sound like a boring and clich&eacute;d story, but it is actually quite good. The sub-plots fit into the story perfectly, especially one about Alfred dying of MacGregor's Syndrome. Overall, I feel that Batman and Robin is one of the most over-hated movies of all time and should really be given a chance. Like I said, it isn't perfect, but it really isn't as awful as everybody says. If you watch the movie with the knowledge that is a campy flick, you'll have a good time, just don't listen to the people who say that it is a horrible abomination to cinema, because it really isn't. 7/10 P.S. - If you want to know what I think of Bane, I think he is closer to the comics than Bane in 'The Dark Knight Rises' because the inclusion of the Venom drug that gives Bane his strength.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    so bad it hurts
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    dbenitez25
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    the thing is that there isn't much to say, is just not worth it... is a really bad movie... the script is crap, the customs are crap, the special effects are crap, the roles are crap, the time-line is crap, there isn't a single thing to point out as positive. I am sorry but is a real bummer. And another thing, at last but not least... Really? Nipples?? nipples in a Batman suit??? is just a disgrace...
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Joel, you where possessed when you made this film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    natebridgeman
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie SUCKS!!!!!! The entire film is just one two and a half hour toy commercial. It's possibly the worst film of all time with over the top action sequences, ridiculous costumes and make-up, effect that were obviously drawn on paper, just plain terrible acting, everyone wanting to punch robin in the face 700 times, and most of all, 65% of the entire movie is just plain one-liners. There is just plain nothing I love about about this movie. It makes every other bad movie look like a masterpiece. Don't even waste your time like I did. If you want to live a happy life on earth. This movie not only killed the Batman franchise for 8 years, but it also killed superhero movies for 4 years. George Clooney is the worst batman ever!!!!!!! Joel Schumaucher, if you are looking at this review you killed one of my favorite superheros. At least, thank the Lord God Almighty that he created Christopher Nolan. Why did Warner Bros. release this garbage. Don't see it at all!!!!!!!!!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Some touching scenes completely overshadowed by ridiculous rubbish!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    powerkrust
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Batman & Robin, world famous franchise killer and the best example of why studios should not interfere with the movie making process. Batman Forever was a roaring success at the box office but this success was largely due to the reputation of the first two Burton films and zero to do with the actual quality of the movie. Batman & Robin was released to an audience now wise to what was going on and now the studios saw what the world thought of their family pandering and dumbed down plot. Batman & Robin was universally panned by just about everyone, including Director Joel Schumacher who walked out of the premier in embarrassment, but really....was it all that bad? The answer is both yes and no but the negative vastly outweighs any positives the film has to offer. The films script, if you can call it that is nothing more than a collection of one liners. In fact almost all of Arnie's dialogue as Mr Freeze is one liners and the jokey too and fro of Batman & Robin is cringeworthy. It's not even so bad it's good funny it's just bad, like a low budget under 5's kids TV program except this film cost a lot of money to make. The inaccuracies to the source material really ticked off the comic book community. It's true that Burton didn't stick entirely to the source either but he captured a lot of what the comic was about. Schumacher doesn't have a clue and seems content with quick flashes of Batman's arse to carry the film and zero sense of character depth anywhere to be seen. Amazingly enough the film DOES in fact have some good points. The best of the bunch being the wonderful Michael Gough having probably the most screen time of all the Batman films. The sub-story of his illness and the scenes that tell this are actually very moving and it's great to see Michael have a chance to do something a bit more in depth. It must be said also that George Cloony is an almost perfect fit for the role of Bruce Wayne with his suave look and manner and his scenes with Gough really have a lot of warmth but he is severely let down with the film he is in. Other good points include some very nice sets, props and some great designs for the look of Gotham City, though these too are marred by garish lighting and wobbly fake looking ice. Uma Thurman clearly is performing tongue in cheek and as such get's a way with it but even she cannot save the terrible surroundings she is in. Somewhere deep in Batman & Robin there was a good film that was wanting to get out and it could very well have been pulled off with the cast, but campy humour and cheap laughs which weren't even funny completely rob the film of anything it was trying to achieve in any of the more serious scenes and unfortunately that's all people remember. Let this film be remembered as a lesson to studios, don't interfere with the creative process of film making. Batman could have gone on for many films but you killed it stone dead with this one and it should never be repeated again.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Some touching scenes completely overshadowed by ridiculous rubbish!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    powerkrust
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Batman & Robin, world famous franchise killer and the best example of why studios should not interfere with the movie making process. Batman Forever was a roaring success at the box office but this success was largely due to the reputation of the first two Burton films and zero to do with the actual quality of the movie. Batman & Robin was released to an audience now wise to what was going on and now the studios saw what the world thought of their family pandering and dumbed down plot. Batman & Robin was universally panned by just about everyone, including Director Joel Schumacher who walked out of the premier in embarrassment, but really....was it all that bad? The answer is both yes and no but the negative vastly outweighs any positives the film has to offer. The films script, if you can call it that is nothing more than a collection of one liners. In fact almost all of Arnie's dialogue as Mr Freeze is one liners and the jokey too and fro of Batman & Robin is cringeworthy. It's not even so bad it's good funny it's just bad, like a low budget under 5's kids TV program except this film cost a lot of money to make. The inaccuracies to the source material really ticked off the comic book community. It's true that Burton didn't stick entirely to the source either but he captured a lot of what the comic was about. Schumacher doesn't have a clue and seems content with quick flashes of Batman's arse to carry the film and zero sense of character depth anywhere to be seen. Amazingly enough the film DOES in fact have some good points. The best of the bunch being the wonderful Michael Gough having probably the most screen time of all the Batman films. The sub-story of his illness and the scenes that tell this are actually very moving and it's great to see Michael have a chance to do something a bit more in depth. It must be said also that George Cloony is an almost perfect fit for the role of Bruce Wayne with his suave look and manner and his scenes with Gough really have a lot of warmth but he is severely let down with the film he is in. Other good points include some very nice sets, props and some great designs for the look of Gotham City, though these too are marred by garish lighting and wobbly fake looking ice. Uma Thurman clearly is performing tongue in cheek and as such get's a way with it but even she cannot save the terrible surroundings she is in. Somewhere deep in Batman & Robin there was a good film that was wanting to get out and it could very well have been pulled off with the cast, but campy humour and cheap laughs which weren't even funny completely rob the film of anything it was trying to achieve in any of the more serious scenes and unfortunately that's all people remember. Let this film be remembered as a lesson to studios, don't interfere with the creative process of film making. Batman could have gone on for many films but you killed it stone dead with this one and it should never be repeated again.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    This is the worst movie I have ever saw in my entire life.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    hansonevan14
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie sucks. The casting sucks, the acting sucks, the action sucks, the effect sucks, everything about this movie is a mess. I spend one Thanksgiving night watch this shitty movie. I hate this movie so much. The first line of this movie is that Robin said "I want a car, chicks dig to car" and then Batman said "this is why Superman works alone". It gets worse and worse by the minute. Batman is play by George Clooney, which makes Val Kilmer's batman look like Michael Keaton's batman. Look I like George Clooney he's a good actor, but was he good in this, not at all. He doesn't have the right Batman voice, he just crashed through the window and was like "hi freeze I'm Batman". Really, is that the best you could do. Overall, George Clooney is a terrible Batman. Robin is play by Chris O' Donnell. All he does in this entire movie is just complain about stupid stuff. And that's all I have to say about his performance in this movie. Mr.Freeze is play by Arnold Schwarzenegger. One of the worst casting decisions ever. He only said one liners in this movie that consists of puns. And that pun is ice. "Allow me to break the ice", "Okay everyone, chill" "Hell, freeze is over", "Let's kick some ice", "What kill the dinosaurs, the ice age". Poison Ivy is play by Uma Thurman. She was actually nominated for an Oscar before this movie came out. Terrible performance from her in this movie, worst Poison Ivy. Batgirl is play by Alicia Silverstone. Worst performance in this movie. That's all I have to say. In the end, never see this movie, ever. This is the worst movie I have ever saw in my entire life. I'll never see it again. Oh yeah, who could ever forget the Bat-Nipples and Bat-Asses. Who's idea was that in the first place to put those things in? I hate this movie so much, makes me cringe every time I think about it. This movie is so horrible!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I Fell Asleep During The Movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bigverybadtom
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    My girlfriend got this as a gift, and we watched it together one evening. I fell asleep while watching it, and though my girlfriend presumably did not, she indicated not liking this either. What was wrong with it? Everything. "Batman" may supposed to be dark, but there was too much darkness in this one. Contrast does help keep one's interest, and Batman doesn't absolutely require darkness to be successful, as you might guess if you've seen the other movies, comics, etc. The heroes are bad. The interaction between the title characters doesn't come off properly. The villains are worse. The police tell Batman about the new villain, Mr. Freeze. (Huh? Batman is supposed to be the great detective who knows everything before anyone else does!) And Arnold Schwarzenegger was as suitable for the character as Danny DeVito would be to play Marilyn Monroe. The female villain stinks too. It's hard to describe more; I fell asleep because everything was done so badly. I wouldn't be surprised if everyone wasn't sleeping themselves when they were making this movie.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Awesome movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    blade1634989
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I for one loved this movie I've seen all live action batman's(excluding the horrible horrible fan made crap) yes The new batman's with christen bale are awesome but nothing beat a classic this movie is amazing and right up to pare with the first 3 it truly gives you The DC Comic feel witch i thought was great and BANE let me tell you if you watched the new dark knight the Bane in this movie would eat that guy for dinner BANE IS BIG HES BAD AND HE KICKS ASS witch is how banes suppose to be hes and x-con and a big dumb brute Never once was bane a criminal mastermind in the comics he was always there to pummel bats wile the real master mind killed stole and made his escape. This movie like the first 3 were all great comic based movies fun to watch with the kids and stuck true to the dc comic yes maybe clooney wasn't the best choice for batman i personally liked val kilmer better but that's just me. SO ignore all the shitty reviews and watch it for yours self keeping in mind not to compare it to the Dark-knight Trilogy but to the DC Comics we all know and love
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Worst Case of Groupthink Criticism Ever
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Clark Ho
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie was a hell of a lot of fun. I was fortunate enough to see it without hearing all the "let's all pan this" baloney and both my then GF and I thought it was great. I remember Clooney as a perfectly charming and intense Batman and Arnold at his self- deprecating silliest, portraying a wonderfully funny supervillain. The professional critimob just held hands and jumped on it per their usual thoughtless whim and the general audience just woke up on the wrong side of the collective bed that weekend. If you haven't seen it yet, go ahead and check it out and see how wrong conventional wisdom can be.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    what in the name of all that is holy is this?!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    movie critic
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It is to bad I can't give this movie minus one. Batman and Robin is hated by everyone blessed with the gift of sight. You have to be blind or even deaf to like this movie, or both! It is the worst representation of who Batman is. A comic book is better than this. Mr. Freeze wasn't a cool villain to start with and they made him worse with his stupid cheesy lines and his plastic chrome costume. Poison Ivy is supposed to be sexy but they managed to make her look like green alien, she wears a cheap cotton costume and blows some sort of essence into men's faces one to many times. George Clooney is a cool and calm Bruce Wayne but he is not so great at being batman. Robin is not so bad and bat girl is totally useless. Joel is a very bad director and he ruined batman. Please do not watch this movie. I personally think it is the work of Satan. Only he could have thought of something like that. But nevertheless, it is the worst movie that mankind has ever created. It is possibly the worst thing mankind has ever created.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Most Over-hated Movie In History
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    zduvvian
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    When I see reviews for the movie 'Batman and Robin', people always seem to say that it is an awful movie and one of the worst films ever made. I have seen it, and to be honest, I really like it. It is campy and a little stupid, but it really doesn't deserve to be given the same title given to other horrible movies like 'The Garbage Pail Kids Movie' or 'Jaws: The Revenge'. I'm not saying that people should stop hating on this movie (because I can see what people have against it) but I do think that people need to calm down about it. There are far worse superhero movies out there like 'Superman IV' and 'Catwoman'. Onto the film itself, like I said, I can see what people have against it: "The acting is awful, the story is campy and the movie overall isn't well directed". I don't think the acting is that bad. There are a few characters who are terrible (like Batgirl, who was meant to be British but it is obvious that the actress is American), but some characters do pretty good performances. George Clooney does a good job as Batman, Michael Gough does a great job as Alfred, Uma Thurman is a convincing Poison Ivy and Arnold Schwarzenegger is a pretty funny Mr Freeze (although I do agree that most of his ice puns are painful). The rest of the characters are pretty mediocre, but not terrible. The story is no Oscar-winning masterpiece, but it is still a good story that flows well. The (very) basic plot synopsis is that Batman and Robin are trying to stop Mr Freeze and Poison Ivy from freezing Gotham City and taking over the world. (Of course!) That may sound like a boring and clich&eacute;d story, but it is actually quite good. The sub-plots fit into the story perfectly, especially one about Alfred dying of MacGregor's Syndrome. Overall, I feel that Batman and Robin is one of the most over-hated movies of all time and should really be given a chance. Like I said, it isn't perfect, but it really isn't as awful as everybody says. If you watch the movie with the knowledge that is a campy flick, you'll have a good time, just don't listen to the people who say that it is a horrible abomination to cinema, because it really isn't. 7/10 P.S. - If you want to know what I think of Bane, I think he is closer to the comics than Bane in 'The Dark Knight Rises' because the inclusion of the Venom drug that gives Bane his strength.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    so bad it hurts
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    dbenitez25
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    the thing is that there isn't much to say, is just not worth it... is a really bad movie... the script is crap, the customs are crap, the special effects are crap, the roles are crap, the time-line is crap, there isn't a single thing to point out as positive. I am sorry but is a real bummer. And another thing, at last but not least... Really? Nipples?? nipples in a Batman suit??? is just a disgrace...
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Joel, you where possessed when you made this film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    natebridgeman
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie SUCKS!!!!!! The entire film is just one two and a half hour toy commercial. It's possibly the worst film of all time with over the top action sequences, ridiculous costumes and make-up, effect that were obviously drawn on paper, just plain terrible acting, everyone wanting to punch robin in the face 700 times, and most of all, 65% of the entire movie is just plain one-liners. There is just plain nothing I love about about this movie. It makes every other bad movie look like a masterpiece. Don't even waste your time like I did. If you want to live a happy life on earth. This movie not only killed the Batman franchise for 8 years, but it also killed superhero movies for 4 years. George Clooney is the worst batman ever!!!!!!! Joel Schumaucher, if you are looking at this review you killed one of my favorite superheros. At least, thank the Lord God Almighty that he created Christopher Nolan. Why did Warner Bros. release this garbage. Don't see it at all!!!!!!!!!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Some touching scenes completely overshadowed by ridiculous rubbish!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    powerkrust
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Batman & Robin, world famous franchise killer and the best example of why studios should not interfere with the movie making process. Batman Forever was a roaring success at the box office but this success was largely due to the reputation of the first two Burton films and zero to do with the actual quality of the movie. Batman & Robin was released to an audience now wise to what was going on and now the studios saw what the world thought of their family pandering and dumbed down plot. Batman & Robin was universally panned by just about everyone, including Director Joel Schumacher who walked out of the premier in embarrassment, but really....was it all that bad? The answer is both yes and no but the negative vastly outweighs any positives the film has to offer. The films script, if you can call it that is nothing more than a collection of one liners. In fact almost all of Arnie's dialogue as Mr Freeze is one liners and the jokey too and fro of Batman & Robin is cringeworthy. It's not even so bad it's good funny it's just bad, like a low budget under 5's kids TV program except this film cost a lot of money to make. The inaccuracies to the source material really ticked off the comic book community. It's true that Burton didn't stick entirely to the source either but he captured a lot of what the comic was about. Schumacher doesn't have a clue and seems content with quick flashes of Batman's arse to carry the film and zero sense of character depth anywhere to be seen. Amazingly enough the film DOES in fact have some good points. The best of the bunch being the wonderful Michael Gough having probably the most screen time of all the Batman films. The sub-story of his illness and the scenes that tell this are actually very moving and it's great to see Michael have a chance to do something a bit more in depth. It must be said also that George Cloony is an almost perfect fit for the role of Bruce Wayne with his suave look and manner and his scenes with Gough really have a lot of warmth but he is severely let down with the film he is in. Other good points include some very nice sets, props and some great designs for the look of Gotham City, though these too are marred by garish lighting and wobbly fake looking ice. Uma Thurman clearly is performing tongue in cheek and as such get's a way with it but even she cannot save the terrible surroundings she is in. Somewhere deep in Batman & Robin there was a good film that was wanting to get out and it could very well have been pulled off with the cast, but campy humour and cheap laughs which weren't even funny completely rob the film of anything it was trying to achieve in any of the more serious scenes and unfortunately that's all people remember. Let this film be remembered as a lesson to studios, don't interfere with the creative process of film making. Batman could have gone on for many films but you killed it stone dead with this one and it should never be repeated again.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Some touching scenes completely overshadowed by ridiculous rubbish!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    powerkrust
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Batman & Robin, world famous franchise killer and the best example of why studios should not interfere with the movie making process. Batman Forever was a roaring success at the box office but this success was largely due to the reputation of the first two Burton films and zero to do with the actual quality of the movie. Batman & Robin was released to an audience now wise to what was going on and now the studios saw what the world thought of their family pandering and dumbed down plot. Batman & Robin was universally panned by just about everyone, including Director Joel Schumacher who walked out of the premier in embarrassment, but really....was it all that bad? The answer is both yes and no but the negative vastly outweighs any positives the film has to offer. The films script, if you can call it that is nothing more than a collection of one liners. In fact almost all of Arnie's dialogue as Mr Freeze is one liners and the jokey too and fro of Batman & Robin is cringeworthy. It's not even so bad it's good funny it's just bad, like a low budget under 5's kids TV program except this film cost a lot of money to make. The inaccuracies to the source material really ticked off the comic book community. It's true that Burton didn't stick entirely to the source either but he captured a lot of what the comic was about. Schumacher doesn't have a clue and seems content with quick flashes of Batman's arse to carry the film and zero sense of character depth anywhere to be seen. Amazingly enough the film DOES in fact have some good points. The best of the bunch being the wonderful Michael Gough having probably the most screen time of all the Batman films. The sub-story of his illness and the scenes that tell this are actually very moving and it's great to see Michael have a chance to do something a bit more in depth. It must be said also that George Cloony is an almost perfect fit for the role of Bruce Wayne with his suave look and manner and his scenes with Gough really have a lot of warmth but he is severely let down with the film he is in. Other good points include some very nice sets, props and some great designs for the look of Gotham City, though these too are marred by garish lighting and wobbly fake looking ice. Uma Thurman clearly is performing tongue in cheek and as such get's a way with it but even she cannot save the terrible surroundings she is in. Somewhere deep in Batman & Robin there was a good film that was wanting to get out and it could very well have been pulled off with the cast, but campy humour and cheap laughs which weren't even funny completely rob the film of anything it was trying to achieve in any of the more serious scenes and unfortunately that's all people remember. Let this film be remembered as a lesson to studios, don't interfere with the creative process of film making. Batman could have gone on for many films but you killed it stone dead with this one and it should never be repeated again.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    This is the worst movie I have ever saw in my entire life.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    hansonevan14
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie sucks. The casting sucks, the acting sucks, the action sucks, the effect sucks, everything about this movie is a mess. I spend one Thanksgiving night watch this shitty movie. I hate this movie so much. The first line of this movie is that Robin said "I want a car, chicks dig to car" and then Batman said "this is why Superman works alone". It gets worse and worse by the minute. Batman is play by George Clooney, which makes Val Kilmer's batman look like Michael Keaton's batman. Look I like George Clooney he's a good actor, but was he good in this, not at all. He doesn't have the right Batman voice, he just crashed through the window and was like "hi freeze I'm Batman". Really, is that the best you could do. Overall, George Clooney is a terrible Batman. Robin is play by Chris O' Donnell. All he does in this entire movie is just complain about stupid stuff. And that's all I have to say about his performance in this movie. Mr.Freeze is play by Arnold Schwarzenegger. One of the worst casting decisions ever. He only said one liners in this movie that consists of puns. And that pun is ice. "Allow me to break the ice", "Okay everyone, chill" "Hell, freeze is over", "Let's kick some ice", "What kill the dinosaurs, the ice age". Poison Ivy is play by Uma Thurman. She was actually nominated for an Oscar before this movie came out. Terrible performance from her in this movie, worst Poison Ivy. Batgirl is play by Alicia Silverstone. Worst performance in this movie. That's all I have to say. In the end, never see this movie, ever. This is the worst movie I have ever saw in my entire life. I'll never see it again. Oh yeah, who could ever forget the Bat-Nipples and Bat-Asses. Who's idea was that in the first place to put those things in? I hate this movie so much, makes me cringe every time I think about it. This movie is so horrible!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I Fell Asleep During The Movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bigverybadtom
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    My girlfriend got this as a gift, and we watched it together one evening. I fell asleep while watching it, and though my girlfriend presumably did not, she indicated not liking this either. What was wrong with it? Everything. "Batman" may supposed to be dark, but there was too much darkness in this one. Contrast does help keep one's interest, and Batman doesn't absolutely require darkness to be successful, as you might guess if you've seen the other movies, comics, etc. The heroes are bad. The interaction between the title characters doesn't come off properly. The villains are worse. The police tell Batman about the new villain, Mr. Freeze. (Huh? Batman is supposed to be the great detective who knows everything before anyone else does!) And Arnold Schwarzenegger was as suitable for the character as Danny DeVito would be to play Marilyn Monroe. The female villain stinks too. It's hard to describe more; I fell asleep because everything was done so badly. I wouldn't be surprised if everyone wasn't sleeping themselves when they were making this movie.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Awesome movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    blade1634989
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I for one loved this movie I've seen all live action batman's(excluding the horrible horrible fan made crap) yes The new batman's with christen bale are awesome but nothing beat a classic this movie is amazing and right up to pare with the first 3 it truly gives you The DC Comic feel witch i thought was great and BANE let me tell you if you watched the new dark knight the Bane in this movie would eat that guy for dinner BANE IS BIG HES BAD AND HE KICKS ASS witch is how banes suppose to be hes and x-con and a big dumb brute Never once was bane a criminal mastermind in the comics he was always there to pummel bats wile the real master mind killed stole and made his escape. This movie like the first 3 were all great comic based movies fun to watch with the kids and stuck true to the dc comic yes maybe clooney wasn't the best choice for batman i personally liked val kilmer better but that's just me. SO ignore all the shitty reviews and watch it for yours self keeping in mind not to compare it to the Dark-knight Trilogy but to the DC Comics we all know and love
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Worst Case of Groupthink Criticism Ever
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Clark Ho
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie was a hell of a lot of fun. I was fortunate enough to see it without hearing all the "let's all pan this" baloney and both my then GF and I thought it was great. I remember Clooney as a perfectly charming and intense Batman and Arnold at his self- deprecating silliest, portraying a wonderfully funny supervillain. The professional critimob just held hands and jumped on it per their usual thoughtless whim and the general audience just woke up on the wrong side of the collective bed that weekend. If you haven't seen it yet, go ahead and check it out and see how wrong conventional wisdom can be.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    what in the name of all that is holy is this?!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    movie critic
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It is to bad I can't give this movie minus one. Batman and Robin is hated by everyone blessed with the gift of sight. You have to be blind or even deaf to like this movie, or both! It is the worst representation of who Batman is. A comic book is better than this. Mr. Freeze wasn't a cool villain to start with and they made him worse with his stupid cheesy lines and his plastic chrome costume. Poison Ivy is supposed to be sexy but they managed to make her look like green alien, she wears a cheap cotton costume and blows some sort of essence into men's faces one to many times. George Clooney is a cool and calm Bruce Wayne but he is not so great at being batman. Robin is not so bad and bat girl is totally useless. Joel is a very bad director and he ruined batman. Please do not watch this movie. I personally think it is the work of Satan. Only he could have thought of something like that. But nevertheless, it is the worst movie that mankind has ever created. It is possibly the worst thing mankind has ever created.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Most Over-hated Movie In History
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    zduvvian
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    When I see reviews for the movie 'Batman and Robin', people always seem to say that it is an awful movie and one of the worst films ever made. I have seen it, and to be honest, I really like it. It is campy and a little stupid, but it really doesn't deserve to be given the same title given to other horrible movies like 'The Garbage Pail Kids Movie' or 'Jaws: The Revenge'. I'm not saying that people should stop hating on this movie (because I can see what people have against it) but I do think that people need to calm down about it. There are far worse superhero movies out there like 'Superman IV' and 'Catwoman'. Onto the film itself, like I said, I can see what people have against it: "The acting is awful, the story is campy and the movie overall isn't well directed". I don't think the acting is that bad. There are a few characters who are terrible (like Batgirl, who was meant to be British but it is obvious that the actress is American), but some characters do pretty good performances. George Clooney does a good job as Batman, Michael Gough does a great job as Alfred, Uma Thurman is a convincing Poison Ivy and Arnold Schwarzenegger is a pretty funny Mr Freeze (although I do agree that most of his ice puns are painful). The rest of the characters are pretty mediocre, but not terrible. The story is no Oscar-winning masterpiece, but it is still a good story that flows well. The (very) basic plot synopsis is that Batman and Robin are trying to stop Mr Freeze and Poison Ivy from freezing Gotham City and taking over the world. (Of course!) That may sound like a boring and clich&eacute;d story, but it is actually quite good. The sub-plots fit into the story perfectly, especially one about Alfred dying of MacGregor's Syndrome. Overall, I feel that Batman and Robin is one of the most over-hated movies of all time and should really be given a chance. Like I said, it isn't perfect, but it really isn't as awful as everybody says. If you watch the movie with the knowledge that is a campy flick, you'll have a good time, just don't listen to the people who say that it is a horrible abomination to cinema, because it really isn't. 7/10 P.S. - If you want to know what I think of Bane, I think he is closer to the comics than Bane in 'The Dark Knight Rises' because the inclusion of the Venom drug that gives Bane his strength.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    so bad it hurts
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    dbenitez25
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    the thing is that there isn't much to say, is just not worth it... is a really bad movie... the script is crap, the customs are crap, the special effects are crap, the roles are crap, the time-line is crap, there isn't a single thing to point out as positive. I am sorry but is a real bummer. And another thing, at last but not least... Really? Nipples?? nipples in a Batman suit??? is just a disgrace...
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Joel, you where possessed when you made this film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    natebridgeman
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie SUCKS!!!!!! The entire film is just one two and a half hour toy commercial. It's possibly the worst film of all time with over the top action sequences, ridiculous costumes and make-up, effect that were obviously drawn on paper, just plain terrible acting, everyone wanting to punch robin in the face 700 times, and most of all, 65% of the entire movie is just plain one-liners. There is just plain nothing I love about about this movie. It makes every other bad movie look like a masterpiece. Don't even waste your time like I did. If you want to live a happy life on earth. This movie not only killed the Batman franchise for 8 years, but it also killed superhero movies for 4 years. George Clooney is the worst batman ever!!!!!!! Joel Schumaucher, if you are looking at this review you killed one of my favorite superheros. At least, thank the Lord God Almighty that he created Christopher Nolan. Why did Warner Bros. release this garbage. Don't see it at all!!!!!!!!!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Some touching scenes completely overshadowed by ridiculous rubbish!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    powerkrust
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Batman & Robin, world famous franchise killer and the best example of why studios should not interfere with the movie making process. Batman Forever was a roaring success at the box office but this success was largely due to the reputation of the first two Burton films and zero to do with the actual quality of the movie. Batman & Robin was released to an audience now wise to what was going on and now the studios saw what the world thought of their family pandering and dumbed down plot. Batman & Robin was universally panned by just about everyone, including Director Joel Schumacher who walked out of the premier in embarrassment, but really....was it all that bad? The answer is both yes and no but the negative vastly outweighs any positives the film has to offer. The films script, if you can call it that is nothing more than a collection of one liners. In fact almost all of Arnie's dialogue as Mr Freeze is one liners and the jokey too and fro of Batman & Robin is cringeworthy. It's not even so bad it's good funny it's just bad, like a low budget under 5's kids TV program except this film cost a lot of money to make. The inaccuracies to the source material really ticked off the comic book community. It's true that Burton didn't stick entirely to the source either but he captured a lot of what the comic was about. Schumacher doesn't have a clue and seems content with quick flashes of Batman's arse to carry the film and zero sense of character depth anywhere to be seen. Amazingly enough the film DOES in fact have some good points. The best of the bunch being the wonderful Michael Gough having probably the most screen time of all the Batman films. The sub-story of his illness and the scenes that tell this are actually very moving and it's great to see Michael have a chance to do something a bit more in depth. It must be said also that George Cloony is an almost perfect fit for the role of Bruce Wayne with his suave look and manner and his scenes with Gough really have a lot of warmth but he is severely let down with the film he is in. Other good points include some very nice sets, props and some great designs for the look of Gotham City, though these too are marred by garish lighting and wobbly fake looking ice. Uma Thurman clearly is performing tongue in cheek and as such get's a way with it but even she cannot save the terrible surroundings she is in. Somewhere deep in Batman & Robin there was a good film that was wanting to get out and it could very well have been pulled off with the cast, but campy humour and cheap laughs which weren't even funny completely rob the film of anything it was trying to achieve in any of the more serious scenes and unfortunately that's all people remember. Let this film be remembered as a lesson to studios, don't interfere with the creative process of film making. Batman could have gone on for many films but you killed it stone dead with this one and it should never be repeated again.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Some touching scenes completely overshadowed by ridiculous rubbish!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    powerkrust
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Batman & Robin, world famous franchise killer and the best example of why studios should not interfere with the movie making process. Batman Forever was a roaring success at the box office but this success was largely due to the reputation of the first two Burton films and zero to do with the actual quality of the movie. Batman & Robin was released to an audience now wise to what was going on and now the studios saw what the world thought of their family pandering and dumbed down plot. Batman & Robin was universally panned by just about everyone, including Director Joel Schumacher who walked out of the premier in embarrassment, but really....was it all that bad? The answer is both yes and no but the negative vastly outweighs any positives the film has to offer. The films script, if you can call it that is nothing more than a collection of one liners. In fact almost all of Arnie's dialogue as Mr Freeze is one liners and the jokey too and fro of Batman & Robin is cringeworthy. It's not even so bad it's good funny it's just bad, like a low budget under 5's kids TV program except this film cost a lot of money to make. The inaccuracies to the source material really ticked off the comic book community. It's true that Burton didn't stick entirely to the source either but he captured a lot of what the comic was about. Schumacher doesn't have a clue and seems content with quick flashes of Batman's arse to carry the film and zero sense of character depth anywhere to be seen. Amazingly enough the film DOES in fact have some good points. The best of the bunch being the wonderful Michael Gough having probably the most screen time of all the Batman films. The sub-story of his illness and the scenes that tell this are actually very moving and it's great to see Michael have a chance to do something a bit more in depth. It must be said also that George Cloony is an almost perfect fit for the role of Bruce Wayne with his suave look and manner and his scenes with Gough really have a lot of warmth but he is severely let down with the film he is in. Other good points include some very nice sets, props and some great designs for the look of Gotham City, though these too are marred by garish lighting and wobbly fake looking ice. Uma Thurman clearly is performing tongue in cheek and as such get's a way with it but even she cannot save the terrible surroundings she is in. Somewhere deep in Batman & Robin there was a good film that was wanting to get out and it could very well have been pulled off with the cast, but campy humour and cheap laughs which weren't even funny completely rob the film of anything it was trying to achieve in any of the more serious scenes and unfortunately that's all people remember. Let this film be remembered as a lesson to studios, don't interfere with the creative process of film making. Batman could have gone on for many films but you killed it stone dead with this one and it should never be repeated again.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    This is the worst movie I have ever saw in my entire life.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    hansonevan14
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie sucks. The casting sucks, the acting sucks, the action sucks, the effect sucks, everything about this movie is a mess. I spend one Thanksgiving night watch this shitty movie. I hate this movie so much. The first line of this movie is that Robin said "I want a car, chicks dig to car" and then Batman said "this is why Superman works alone". It gets worse and worse by the minute. Batman is play by George Clooney, which makes Val Kilmer's batman look like Michael Keaton's batman. Look I like George Clooney he's a good actor, but was he good in this, not at all. He doesn't have the right Batman voice, he just crashed through the window and was like "hi freeze I'm Batman". Really, is that the best you could do. Overall, George Clooney is a terrible Batman. Robin is play by Chris O' Donnell. All he does in this entire movie is just complain about stupid stuff. And that's all I have to say about his performance in this movie. Mr.Freeze is play by Arnold Schwarzenegger. One of the worst casting decisions ever. He only said one liners in this movie that consists of puns. And that pun is ice. "Allow me to break the ice", "Okay everyone, chill" "Hell, freeze is over", "Let's kick some ice", "What kill the dinosaurs, the ice age". Poison Ivy is play by Uma Thurman. She was actually nominated for an Oscar before this movie came out. Terrible performance from her in this movie, worst Poison Ivy. Batgirl is play by Alicia Silverstone. Worst performance in this movie. That's all I have to say. In the end, never see this movie, ever. This is the worst movie I have ever saw in my entire life. I'll never see it again. Oh yeah, who could ever forget the Bat-Nipples and Bat-Asses. Who's idea was that in the first place to put those things in? I hate this movie so much, makes me cringe every time I think about it. This movie is so horrible!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I Fell Asleep During The Movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bigverybadtom
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    My girlfriend got this as a gift, and we watched it together one evening. I fell asleep while watching it, and though my girlfriend presumably did not, she indicated not liking this either. What was wrong with it? Everything. "Batman" may supposed to be dark, but there was too much darkness in this one. Contrast does help keep one's interest, and Batman doesn't absolutely require darkness to be successful, as you might guess if you've seen the other movies, comics, etc. The heroes are bad. The interaction between the title characters doesn't come off properly. The villains are worse. The police tell Batman about the new villain, Mr. Freeze. (Huh? Batman is supposed to be the great detective who knows everything before anyone else does!) And Arnold Schwarzenegger was as suitable for the character as Danny DeVito would be to play Marilyn Monroe. The female villain stinks too. It's hard to describe more; I fell asleep because everything was done so badly. I wouldn't be surprised if everyone wasn't sleeping themselves when they were making this movie.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Awesome movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    blade1634989
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I for one loved this movie I've seen all live action batman's(excluding the horrible horrible fan made crap) yes The new batman's with christen bale are awesome but nothing beat a classic this movie is amazing and right up to pare with the first 3 it truly gives you The DC Comic feel witch i thought was great and BANE let me tell you if you watched the new dark knight the Bane in this movie would eat that guy for dinner BANE IS BIG HES BAD AND HE KICKS ASS witch is how banes suppose to be hes and x-con and a big dumb brute Never once was bane a criminal mastermind in the comics he was always there to pummel bats wile the real master mind killed stole and made his escape. This movie like the first 3 were all great comic based movies fun to watch with the kids and stuck true to the dc comic yes maybe clooney wasn't the best choice for batman i personally liked val kilmer better but that's just me. SO ignore all the shitty reviews and watch it for yours self keeping in mind not to compare it to the Dark-knight Trilogy but to the DC Comics we all know and love
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Worst Case of Groupthink Criticism Ever
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Clark Ho
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie was a hell of a lot of fun. I was fortunate enough to see it without hearing all the "let's all pan this" baloney and both my then GF and I thought it was great. I remember Clooney as a perfectly charming and intense Batman and Arnold at his self- deprecating silliest, portraying a wonderfully funny supervillain. The professional critimob just held hands and jumped on it per their usual thoughtless whim and the general audience just woke up on the wrong side of the collective bed that weekend. If you haven't seen it yet, go ahead and check it out and see how wrong conventional wisdom can be.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    what in the name of all that is holy is this?!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    movie critic
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It is to bad I can't give this movie minus one. Batman and Robin is hated by everyone blessed with the gift of sight. You have to be blind or even deaf to like this movie, or both! It is the worst representation of who Batman is. A comic book is better than this. Mr. Freeze wasn't a cool villain to start with and they made him worse with his stupid cheesy lines and his plastic chrome costume. Poison Ivy is supposed to be sexy but they managed to make her look like green alien, she wears a cheap cotton costume and blows some sort of essence into men's faces one to many times. George Clooney is a cool and calm Bruce Wayne but he is not so great at being batman. Robin is not so bad and bat girl is totally useless. Joel is a very bad director and he ruined batman. Please do not watch this movie. I personally think it is the work of Satan. Only he could have thought of something like that. But nevertheless, it is the worst movie that mankind has ever created. It is possibly the worst thing mankind has ever created.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Most Over-hated Movie In History
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    zduvvian
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    When I see reviews for the movie 'Batman and Robin', people always seem to say that it is an awful movie and one of the worst films ever made. I have seen it, and to be honest, I really like it. It is campy and a little stupid, but it really doesn't deserve to be given the same title given to other horrible movies like 'The Garbage Pail Kids Movie' or 'Jaws: The Revenge'. I'm not saying that people should stop hating on this movie (because I can see what people have against it) but I do think that people need to calm down about it. There are far worse superhero movies out there like 'Superman IV' and 'Catwoman'. Onto the film itself, like I said, I can see what people have against it: "The acting is awful, the story is campy and the movie overall isn't well directed". I don't think the acting is that bad. There are a few characters who are terrible (like Batgirl, who was meant to be British but it is obvious that the actress is American), but some characters do pretty good performances. George Clooney does a good job as Batman, Michael Gough does a great job as Alfred, Uma Thurman is a convincing Poison Ivy and Arnold Schwarzenegger is a pretty funny Mr Freeze (although I do agree that most of his ice puns are painful). The rest of the characters are pretty mediocre, but not terrible. The story is no Oscar-winning masterpiece, but it is still a good story that flows well. The (very) basic plot synopsis is that Batman and Robin are trying to stop Mr Freeze and Poison Ivy from freezing Gotham City and taking over the world. (Of course!) That may sound like a boring and clich&eacute;d story, but it is actually quite good. The sub-plots fit into the story perfectly, especially one about Alfred dying of MacGregor's Syndrome. Overall, I feel that Batman and Robin is one of the most over-hated movies of all time and should really be given a chance. Like I said, it isn't perfect, but it really isn't as awful as everybody says. If you watch the movie with the knowledge that is a campy flick, you'll have a good time, just don't listen to the people who say that it is a horrible abomination to cinema, because it really isn't. 7/10 P.S. - If you want to know what I think of Bane, I think he is closer to the comics than Bane in 'The Dark Knight Rises' because the inclusion of the Venom drug that gives Bane his strength.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    so bad it hurts
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    dbenitez25
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    the thing is that there isn't much to say, is just not worth it... is a really bad movie... the script is crap, the customs are crap, the special effects are crap, the roles are crap, the time-line is crap, there isn't a single thing to point out as positive. I am sorry but is a real bummer. And another thing, at last but not least... Really? Nipples?? nipples in a Batman suit??? is just a disgrace...
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Joel, you where possessed when you made this film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    natebridgeman
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie SUCKS!!!!!! The entire film is just one two and a half hour toy commercial. It's possibly the worst film of all time with over the top action sequences, ridiculous costumes and make-up, effect that were obviously drawn on paper, just plain terrible acting, everyone wanting to punch robin in the face 700 times, and most of all, 65% of the entire movie is just plain one-liners. There is just plain nothing I love about about this movie. It makes every other bad movie look like a masterpiece. Don't even waste your time like I did. If you want to live a happy life on earth. This movie not only killed the Batman franchise for 8 years, but it also killed superhero movies for 4 years. George Clooney is the worst batman ever!!!!!!! Joel Schumaucher, if you are looking at this review you killed one of my favorite superheros. At least, thank the Lord God Almighty that he created Christopher Nolan. Why did Warner Bros. release this garbage. Don't see it at all!!!!!!!!!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Some touching scenes completely overshadowed by ridiculous rubbish!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    powerkrust
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Batman & Robin, world famous franchise killer and the best example of why studios should not interfere with the movie making process. Batman Forever was a roaring success at the box office but this success was largely due to the reputation of the first two Burton films and zero to do with the actual quality of the movie. Batman & Robin was released to an audience now wise to what was going on and now the studios saw what the world thought of their family pandering and dumbed down plot. Batman & Robin was universally panned by just about everyone, including Director Joel Schumacher who walked out of the premier in embarrassment, but really....was it all that bad? The answer is both yes and no but the negative vastly outweighs any positives the film has to offer. The films script, if you can call it that is nothing more than a collection of one liners. In fact almost all of Arnie's dialogue as Mr Freeze is one liners and the jokey too and fro of Batman & Robin is cringeworthy. It's not even so bad it's good funny it's just bad, like a low budget under 5's kids TV program except this film cost a lot of money to make. The inaccuracies to the source material really ticked off the comic book community. It's true that Burton didn't stick entirely to the source either but he captured a lot of what the comic was about. Schumacher doesn't have a clue and seems content with quick flashes of Batman's arse to carry the film and zero sense of character depth anywhere to be seen. Amazingly enough the film DOES in fact have some good points. The best of the bunch being the wonderful Michael Gough having probably the most screen time of all the Batman films. The sub-story of his illness and the scenes that tell this are actually very moving and it's great to see Michael have a chance to do something a bit more in depth. It must be said also that George Cloony is an almost perfect fit for the role of Bruce Wayne with his suave look and manner and his scenes with Gough really have a lot of warmth but he is severely let down with the film he is in. Other good points include some very nice sets, props and some great designs for the look of Gotham City, though these too are marred by garish lighting and wobbly fake looking ice. Uma Thurman clearly is performing tongue in cheek and as such get's a way with it but even she cannot save the terrible surroundings she is in. Somewhere deep in Batman & Robin there was a good film that was wanting to get out and it could very well have been pulled off with the cast, but campy humour and cheap laughs which weren't even funny completely rob the film of anything it was trying to achieve in any of the more serious scenes and unfortunately that's all people remember. Let this film be remembered as a lesson to studios, don't interfere with the creative process of film making. Batman could have gone on for many films but you killed it stone dead with this one and it should never be repeated again.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Some touching scenes completely overshadowed by ridiculous rubbish!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    powerkrust
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Batman & Robin, world famous franchise killer and the best example of why studios should not interfere with the movie making process. Batman Forever was a roaring success at the box office but this success was largely due to the reputation of the first two Burton films and zero to do with the actual quality of the movie. Batman & Robin was released to an audience now wise to what was going on and now the studios saw what the world thought of their family pandering and dumbed down plot. Batman & Robin was universally panned by just about everyone, including Director Joel Schumacher who walked out of the premier in embarrassment, but really....was it all that bad? The answer is both yes and no but the negative vastly outweighs any positives the film has to offer. The films script, if you can call it that is nothing more than a collection of one liners. In fact almost all of Arnie's dialogue as Mr Freeze is one liners and the jokey too and fro of Batman & Robin is cringeworthy. It's not even so bad it's good funny it's just bad, like a low budget under 5's kids TV program except this film cost a lot of money to make. The inaccuracies to the source material really ticked off the comic book community. It's true that Burton didn't stick entirely to the source either but he captured a lot of what the comic was about. Schumacher doesn't have a clue and seems content with quick flashes of Batman's arse to carry the film and zero sense of character depth anywhere to be seen. Amazingly enough the film DOES in fact have some good points. The best of the bunch being the wonderful Michael Gough having probably the most screen time of all the Batman films. The sub-story of his illness and the scenes that tell this are actually very moving and it's great to see Michael have a chance to do something a bit more in depth. It must be said also that George Cloony is an almost perfect fit for the role of Bruce Wayne with his suave look and manner and his scenes with Gough really have a lot of warmth but he is severely let down with the film he is in. Other good points include some very nice sets, props and some great designs for the look of Gotham City, though these too are marred by garish lighting and wobbly fake looking ice. Uma Thurman clearly is performing tongue in cheek and as such get's a way with it but even she cannot save the terrible surroundings she is in. Somewhere deep in Batman & Robin there was a good film that was wanting to get out and it could very well have been pulled off with the cast, but campy humour and cheap laughs which weren't even funny completely rob the film of anything it was trying to achieve in any of the more serious scenes and unfortunately that's all people remember. Let this film be remembered as a lesson to studios, don't interfere with the creative process of film making. Batman could have gone on for many films but you killed it stone dead with this one and it should never be repeated again.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    This is the worst movie I have ever saw in my entire life.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    hansonevan14
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie sucks. The casting sucks, the acting sucks, the action sucks, the effect sucks, everything about this movie is a mess. I spend one Thanksgiving night watch this shitty movie. I hate this movie so much. The first line of this movie is that Robin said "I want a car, chicks dig to car" and then Batman said "this is why Superman works alone". It gets worse and worse by the minute. Batman is play by George Clooney, which makes Val Kilmer's batman look like Michael Keaton's batman. Look I like George Clooney he's a good actor, but was he good in this, not at all. He doesn't have the right Batman voice, he just crashed through the window and was like "hi freeze I'm Batman". Really, is that the best you could do. Overall, George Clooney is a terrible Batman. Robin is play by Chris O' Donnell. All he does in this entire movie is just complain about stupid stuff. And that's all I have to say about his performance in this movie. Mr.Freeze is play by Arnold Schwarzenegger. One of the worst casting decisions ever. He only said one liners in this movie that consists of puns. And that pun is ice. "Allow me to break the ice", "Okay everyone, chill" "Hell, freeze is over", "Let's kick some ice", "What kill the dinosaurs, the ice age". Poison Ivy is play by Uma Thurman. She was actually nominated for an Oscar before this movie came out. Terrible performance from her in this movie, worst Poison Ivy. Batgirl is play by Alicia Silverstone. Worst performance in this movie. That's all I have to say. In the end, never see this movie, ever. This is the worst movie I have ever saw in my entire life. I'll never see it again. Oh yeah, who could ever forget the Bat-Nipples and Bat-Asses. Who's idea was that in the first place to put those things in? I hate this movie so much, makes me cringe every time I think about it. This movie is so horrible!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I Fell Asleep During The Movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bigverybadtom
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    My girlfriend got this as a gift, and we watched it together one evening. I fell asleep while watching it, and though my girlfriend presumably did not, she indicated not liking this either. What was wrong with it? Everything. "Batman" may supposed to be dark, but there was too much darkness in this one. Contrast does help keep one's interest, and Batman doesn't absolutely require darkness to be successful, as you might guess if you've seen the other movies, comics, etc. The heroes are bad. The interaction between the title characters doesn't come off properly. The villains are worse. The police tell Batman about the new villain, Mr. Freeze. (Huh? Batman is supposed to be the great detective who knows everything before anyone else does!) And Arnold Schwarzenegger was as suitable for the character as Danny DeVito would be to play Marilyn Monroe. The female villain stinks too. It's hard to describe more; I fell asleep because everything was done so badly. I wouldn't be surprised if everyone wasn't sleeping themselves when they were making this movie.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Awesome movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    blade1634989
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I for one loved this movie I've seen all live action batman's(excluding the horrible horrible fan made crap) yes The new batman's with christen bale are awesome but nothing beat a classic this movie is amazing and right up to pare with the first 3 it truly gives you The DC Comic feel witch i thought was great and BANE let me tell you if you watched the new dark knight the Bane in this movie would eat that guy for dinner BANE IS BIG HES BAD AND HE KICKS ASS witch is how banes suppose to be hes and x-con and a big dumb brute Never once was bane a criminal mastermind in the comics he was always there to pummel bats wile the real master mind killed stole and made his escape. This movie like the first 3 were all great comic based movies fun to watch with the kids and stuck true to the dc comic yes maybe clooney wasn't the best choice for batman i personally liked val kilmer better but that's just me. SO ignore all the shitty reviews and watch it for yours self keeping in mind not to compare it to the Dark-knight Trilogy but to the DC Comics we all know and love
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Worst Case of Groupthink Criticism Ever
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Clark Ho
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie was a hell of a lot of fun. I was fortunate enough to see it without hearing all the "let's all pan this" baloney and both my then GF and I thought it was great. I remember Clooney as a perfectly charming and intense Batman and Arnold at his self- deprecating silliest, portraying a wonderfully funny supervillain. The professional critimob just held hands and jumped on it per their usual thoughtless whim and the general audience just woke up on the wrong side of the collective bed that weekend. If you haven't seen it yet, go ahead and check it out and see how wrong conventional wisdom can be.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    what in the name of all that is holy is this?!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    movie critic
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It is to bad I can't give this movie minus one. Batman and Robin is hated by everyone blessed with the gift of sight. You have to be blind or even deaf to like this movie, or both! It is the worst representation of who Batman is. A comic book is better than this. Mr. Freeze wasn't a cool villain to start with and they made him worse with his stupid cheesy lines and his plastic chrome costume. Poison Ivy is supposed to be sexy but they managed to make her look like green alien, she wears a cheap cotton costume and blows some sort of essence into men's faces one to many times. George Clooney is a cool and calm Bruce Wayne but he is not so great at being batman. Robin is not so bad and bat girl is totally useless. Joel is a very bad director and he ruined batman. Please do not watch this movie. I personally think it is the work of Satan. Only he could have thought of something like that. But nevertheless, it is the worst movie that mankind has ever created. It is possibly the worst thing mankind has ever created.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Most Over-hated Movie In History
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    zduvvian
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    When I see reviews for the movie 'Batman and Robin', people always seem to say that it is an awful movie and one of the worst films ever made. I have seen it, and to be honest, I really like it. It is campy and a little stupid, but it really doesn't deserve to be given the same title given to other horrible movies like 'The Garbage Pail Kids Movie' or 'Jaws: The Revenge'. I'm not saying that people should stop hating on this movie (because I can see what people have against it) but I do think that people need to calm down about it. There are far worse superhero movies out there like 'Superman IV' and 'Catwoman'. Onto the film itself, like I said, I can see what people have against it: "The acting is awful, the story is campy and the movie overall isn't well directed". I don't think the acting is that bad. There are a few characters who are terrible (like Batgirl, who was meant to be British but it is obvious that the actress is American), but some characters do pretty good performances. George Clooney does a good job as Batman, Michael Gough does a great job as Alfred, Uma Thurman is a convincing Poison Ivy and Arnold Schwarzenegger is a pretty funny Mr Freeze (although I do agree that most of his ice puns are painful). The rest of the characters are pretty mediocre, but not terrible. The story is no Oscar-winning masterpiece, but it is still a good story that flows well. The (very) basic plot synopsis is that Batman and Robin are trying to stop Mr Freeze and Poison Ivy from freezing Gotham City and taking over the world. (Of course!) That may sound like a boring and clich&eacute;d story, but it is actually quite good. The sub-plots fit into the story perfectly, especially one about Alfred dying of MacGregor's Syndrome. Overall, I feel that Batman and Robin is one of the most over-hated movies of all time and should really be given a chance. Like I said, it isn't perfect, but it really isn't as awful as everybody says. If you watch the movie with the knowledge that is a campy flick, you'll have a good time, just don't listen to the people who say that it is a horrible abomination to cinema, because it really isn't. 7/10 P.S. - If you want to know what I think of Bane, I think he is closer to the comics than Bane in 'The Dark Knight Rises' because the inclusion of the Venom drug that gives Bane his strength.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    so bad it hurts
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    dbenitez25
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    the thing is that there isn't much to say, is just not worth it... is a really bad movie... the script is crap, the customs are crap, the special effects are crap, the roles are crap, the time-line is crap, there isn't a single thing to point out as positive. I am sorry but is a real bummer. And another thing, at last but not least... Really? Nipples?? nipples in a Batman suit??? is just a disgrace...
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Joel, you where possessed when you made this film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    natebridgeman
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie SUCKS!!!!!! The entire film is just one two and a half hour toy commercial. It's possibly the worst film of all time with over the top action sequences, ridiculous costumes and make-up, effect that were obviously drawn on paper, just plain terrible acting, everyone wanting to punch robin in the face 700 times, and most of all, 65% of the entire movie is just plain one-liners. There is just plain nothing I love about about this movie. It makes every other bad movie look like a masterpiece. Don't even waste your time like I did. If you want to live a happy life on earth. This movie not only killed the Batman franchise for 8 years, but it also killed superhero movies for 4 years. George Clooney is the worst batman ever!!!!!!! Joel Schumaucher, if you are looking at this review you killed one of my favorite superheros. At least, thank the Lord God Almighty that he created Christopher Nolan. Why did Warner Bros. release this garbage. Don't see it at all!!!!!!!!!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Some touching scenes completely overshadowed by ridiculous rubbish!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    powerkrust
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Batman & Robin, world famous franchise killer and the best example of why studios should not interfere with the movie making process. Batman Forever was a roaring success at the box office but this success was largely due to the reputation of the first two Burton films and zero to do with the actual quality of the movie. Batman & Robin was released to an audience now wise to what was going on and now the studios saw what the world thought of their family pandering and dumbed down plot. Batman & Robin was universally panned by just about everyone, including Director Joel Schumacher who walked out of the premier in embarrassment, but really....was it all that bad? The answer is both yes and no but the negative vastly outweighs any positives the film has to offer. The films script, if you can call it that is nothing more than a collection of one liners. In fact almost all of Arnie's dialogue as Mr Freeze is one liners and the jokey too and fro of Batman & Robin is cringeworthy. It's not even so bad it's good funny it's just bad, like a low budget under 5's kids TV program except this film cost a lot of money to make. The inaccuracies to the source material really ticked off the comic book community. It's true that Burton didn't stick entirely to the source either but he captured a lot of what the comic was about. Schumacher doesn't have a clue and seems content with quick flashes of Batman's arse to carry the film and zero sense of character depth anywhere to be seen. Amazingly enough the film DOES in fact have some good points. The best of the bunch being the wonderful Michael Gough having probably the most screen time of all the Batman films. The sub-story of his illness and the scenes that tell this are actually very moving and it's great to see Michael have a chance to do something a bit more in depth. It must be said also that George Cloony is an almost perfect fit for the role of Bruce Wayne with his suave look and manner and his scenes with Gough really have a lot of warmth but he is severely let down with the film he is in. Other good points include some very nice sets, props and some great designs for the look of Gotham City, though these too are marred by garish lighting and wobbly fake looking ice. Uma Thurman clearly is performing tongue in cheek and as such get's a way with it but even she cannot save the terrible surroundings she is in. Somewhere deep in Batman & Robin there was a good film that was wanting to get out and it could very well have been pulled off with the cast, but campy humour and cheap laughs which weren't even funny completely rob the film of anything it was trying to achieve in any of the more serious scenes and unfortunately that's all people remember. Let this film be remembered as a lesson to studios, don't interfere with the creative process of film making. Batman could have gone on for many films but you killed it stone dead with this one and it should never be repeated again.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Some touching scenes completely overshadowed by ridiculous rubbish!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    powerkrust
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Batman & Robin, world famous franchise killer and the best example of why studios should not interfere with the movie making process. Batman Forever was a roaring success at the box office but this success was largely due to the reputation of the first two Burton films and zero to do with the actual quality of the movie. Batman & Robin was released to an audience now wise to what was going on and now the studios saw what the world thought of their family pandering and dumbed down plot. Batman & Robin was universally panned by just about everyone, including Director Joel Schumacher who walked out of the premier in embarrassment, but really....was it all that bad? The answer is both yes and no but the negative vastly outweighs any positives the film has to offer. The films script, if you can call it that is nothing more than a collection of one liners. In fact almost all of Arnie's dialogue as Mr Freeze is one liners and the jokey too and fro of Batman & Robin is cringeworthy. It's not even so bad it's good funny it's just bad, like a low budget under 5's kids TV program except this film cost a lot of money to make. The inaccuracies to the source material really ticked off the comic book community. It's true that Burton didn't stick entirely to the source either but he captured a lot of what the comic was about. Schumacher doesn't have a clue and seems content with quick flashes of Batman's arse to carry the film and zero sense of character depth anywhere to be seen. Amazingly enough the film DOES in fact have some good points. The best of the bunch being the wonderful Michael Gough having probably the most screen time of all the Batman films. The sub-story of his illness and the scenes that tell this are actually very moving and it's great to see Michael have a chance to do something a bit more in depth. It must be said also that George Cloony is an almost perfect fit for the role of Bruce Wayne with his suave look and manner and his scenes with Gough really have a lot of warmth but he is severely let down with the film he is in. Other good points include some very nice sets, props and some great designs for the look of Gotham City, though these too are marred by garish lighting and wobbly fake looking ice. Uma Thurman clearly is performing tongue in cheek and as such get's a way with it but even she cannot save the terrible surroundings she is in. Somewhere deep in Batman & Robin there was a good film that was wanting to get out and it could very well have been pulled off with the cast, but campy humour and cheap laughs which weren't even funny completely rob the film of anything it was trying to achieve in any of the more serious scenes and unfortunately that's all people remember. Let this film be remembered as a lesson to studios, don't interfere with the creative process of film making. Batman could have gone on for many films but you killed it stone dead with this one and it should never be repeated again.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    This is the worst movie I have ever saw in my entire life.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    hansonevan14
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie sucks. The casting sucks, the acting sucks, the action sucks, the effect sucks, everything about this movie is a mess. I spend one Thanksgiving night watch this shitty movie. I hate this movie so much. The first line of this movie is that Robin said "I want a car, chicks dig to car" and then Batman said "this is why Superman works alone". It gets worse and worse by the minute. Batman is play by George Clooney, which makes Val Kilmer's batman look like Michael Keaton's batman. Look I like George Clooney he's a good actor, but was he good in this, not at all. He doesn't have the right Batman voice, he just crashed through the window and was like "hi freeze I'm Batman". Really, is that the best you could do. Overall, George Clooney is a terrible Batman. Robin is play by Chris O' Donnell. All he does in this entire movie is just complain about stupid stuff. And that's all I have to say about his performance in this movie. Mr.Freeze is play by Arnold Schwarzenegger. One of the worst casting decisions ever. He only said one liners in this movie that consists of puns. And that pun is ice. "Allow me to break the ice", "Okay everyone, chill" "Hell, freeze is over", "Let's kick some ice", "What kill the dinosaurs, the ice age". Poison Ivy is play by Uma Thurman. She was actually nominated for an Oscar before this movie came out. Terrible performance from her in this movie, worst Poison Ivy. Batgirl is play by Alicia Silverstone. Worst performance in this movie. That's all I have to say. In the end, never see this movie, ever. This is the worst movie I have ever saw in my entire life. I'll never see it again. Oh yeah, who could ever forget the Bat-Nipples and Bat-Asses. Who's idea was that in the first place to put those things in? I hate this movie so much, makes me cringe every time I think about it. This movie is so horrible!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I Fell Asleep During The Movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bigverybadtom
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    My girlfriend got this as a gift, and we watched it together one evening. I fell asleep while watching it, and though my girlfriend presumably did not, she indicated not liking this either. What was wrong with it? Everything. "Batman" may supposed to be dark, but there was too much darkness in this one. Contrast does help keep one's interest, and Batman doesn't absolutely require darkness to be successful, as you might guess if you've seen the other movies, comics, etc. The heroes are bad. The interaction between the title characters doesn't come off properly. The villains are worse. The police tell Batman about the new villain, Mr. Freeze. (Huh? Batman is supposed to be the great detective who knows everything before anyone else does!) And Arnold Schwarzenegger was as suitable for the character as Danny DeVito would be to play Marilyn Monroe. The female villain stinks too. It's hard to describe more; I fell asleep because everything was done so badly. I wouldn't be surprised if everyone wasn't sleeping themselves when they were making this movie.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Awesome movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    blade1634989
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I for one loved this movie I've seen all live action batman's(excluding the horrible horrible fan made crap) yes The new batman's with christen bale are awesome but nothing beat a classic this movie is amazing and right up to pare with the first 3 it truly gives you The DC Comic feel witch i thought was great and BANE let me tell you if you watched the new dark knight the Bane in this movie would eat that guy for dinner BANE IS BIG HES BAD AND HE KICKS ASS witch is how banes suppose to be hes and x-con and a big dumb brute Never once was bane a criminal mastermind in the comics he was always there to pummel bats wile the real master mind killed stole and made his escape. This movie like the first 3 were all great comic based movies fun to watch with the kids and stuck true to the dc comic yes maybe clooney wasn't the best choice for batman i personally liked val kilmer better but that's just me. SO ignore all the shitty reviews and watch it for yours self keeping in mind not to compare it to the Dark-knight Trilogy but to the DC Comics we all know and love
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Worst Case of Groupthink Criticism Ever
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Clark Ho
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie was a hell of a lot of fun. I was fortunate enough to see it without hearing all the "let's all pan this" baloney and both my then GF and I thought it was great. I remember Clooney as a perfectly charming and intense Batman and Arnold at his self- deprecating silliest, portraying a wonderfully funny supervillain. The professional critimob just held hands and jumped on it per their usual thoughtless whim and the general audience just woke up on the wrong side of the collective bed that weekend. If you haven't seen it yet, go ahead and check it out and see how wrong conventional wisdom can be.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    what in the name of all that is holy is this?!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    movie critic
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It is to bad I can't give this movie minus one. Batman and Robin is hated by everyone blessed with the gift of sight. You have to be blind or even deaf to like this movie, or both! It is the worst representation of who Batman is. A comic book is better than this. Mr. Freeze wasn't a cool villain to start with and they made him worse with his stupid cheesy lines and his plastic chrome costume. Poison Ivy is supposed to be sexy but they managed to make her look like green alien, she wears a cheap cotton costume and blows some sort of essence into men's faces one to many times. George Clooney is a cool and calm Bruce Wayne but he is not so great at being batman. Robin is not so bad and bat girl is totally useless. Joel is a very bad director and he ruined batman. Please do not watch this movie. I personally think it is the work of Satan. Only he could have thought of something like that. But nevertheless, it is the worst movie that mankind has ever created. It is possibly the worst thing mankind has ever created.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Most Over-hated Movie In History
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    zduvvian
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    When I see reviews for the movie 'Batman and Robin', people always seem to say that it is an awful movie and one of the worst films ever made. I have seen it, and to be honest, I really like it. It is campy and a little stupid, but it really doesn't deserve to be given the same title given to other horrible movies like 'The Garbage Pail Kids Movie' or 'Jaws: The Revenge'. I'm not saying that people should stop hating on this movie (because I can see what people have against it) but I do think that people need to calm down about it. There are far worse superhero movies out there like 'Superman IV' and 'Catwoman'. Onto the film itself, like I said, I can see what people have against it: "The acting is awful, the story is campy and the movie overall isn't well directed". I don't think the acting is that bad. There are a few characters who are terrible (like Batgirl, who was meant to be British but it is obvious that the actress is American), but some characters do pretty good performances. George Clooney does a good job as Batman, Michael Gough does a great job as Alfred, Uma Thurman is a convincing Poison Ivy and Arnold Schwarzenegger is a pretty funny Mr Freeze (although I do agree that most of his ice puns are painful). The rest of the characters are pretty mediocre, but not terrible. The story is no Oscar-winning masterpiece, but it is still a good story that flows well. The (very) basic plot synopsis is that Batman and Robin are trying to stop Mr Freeze and Poison Ivy from freezing Gotham City and taking over the world. (Of course!) That may sound like a boring and clich&eacute;d story, but it is actually quite good. The sub-plots fit into the story perfectly, especially one about Alfred dying of MacGregor's Syndrome. Overall, I feel that Batman and Robin is one of the most over-hated movies of all time and should really be given a chance. Like I said, it isn't perfect, but it really isn't as awful as everybody says. If you watch the movie with the knowledge that is a campy flick, you'll have a good time, just don't listen to the people who say that it is a horrible abomination to cinema, because it really isn't. 7/10 P.S. - If you want to know what I think of Bane, I think he is closer to the comics than Bane in 'The Dark Knight Rises' because the inclusion of the Venom drug that gives Bane his strength.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    so bad it hurts
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    dbenitez25
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    the thing is that there isn't much to say, is just not worth it... is a really bad movie... the script is crap, the customs are crap, the special effects are crap, the roles are crap, the time-line is crap, there isn't a single thing to point out as positive. I am sorry but is a real bummer. And another thing, at last but not least... Really? Nipples?? nipples in a Batman suit??? is just a disgrace...
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Joel, you where possessed when you made this film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    natebridgeman
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie SUCKS!!!!!! The entire film is just one two and a half hour toy commercial. It's possibly the worst film of all time with over the top action sequences, ridiculous costumes and make-up, effect that were obviously drawn on paper, just plain terrible acting, everyone wanting to punch robin in the face 700 times, and most of all, 65% of the entire movie is just plain one-liners. There is just plain nothing I love about about this movie. It makes every other bad movie look like a masterpiece. Don't even waste your time like I did. If you want to live a happy life on earth. This movie not only killed the Batman franchise for 8 years, but it also killed superhero movies for 4 years. George Clooney is the worst batman ever!!!!!!! Joel Schumaucher, if you are looking at this review you killed one of my favorite superheros. At least, thank the Lord God Almighty that he created Christopher Nolan. Why did Warner Bros. release this garbage. Don't see it at all!!!!!!!!!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Some touching scenes completely overshadowed by ridiculous rubbish!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    powerkrust
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Batman & Robin, world famous franchise killer and the best example of why studios should not interfere with the movie making process. Batman Forever was a roaring success at the box office but this success was largely due to the reputation of the first two Burton films and zero to do with the actual quality of the movie. Batman & Robin was released to an audience now wise to what was going on and now the studios saw what the world thought of their family pandering and dumbed down plot. Batman & Robin was universally panned by just about everyone, including Director Joel Schumacher who walked out of the premier in embarrassment, but really....was it all that bad? The answer is both yes and no but the negative vastly outweighs any positives the film has to offer. The films script, if you can call it that is nothing more than a collection of one liners. In fact almost all of Arnie's dialogue as Mr Freeze is one liners and the jokey too and fro of Batman & Robin is cringeworthy. It's not even so bad it's good funny it's just bad, like a low budget under 5's kids TV program except this film cost a lot of money to make. The inaccuracies to the source material really ticked off the comic book community. It's true that Burton didn't stick entirely to the source either but he captured a lot of what the comic was about. Schumacher doesn't have a clue and seems content with quick flashes of Batman's arse to carry the film and zero sense of character depth anywhere to be seen. Amazingly enough the film DOES in fact have some good points. The best of the bunch being the wonderful Michael Gough having probably the most screen time of all the Batman films. The sub-story of his illness and the scenes that tell this are actually very moving and it's great to see Michael have a chance to do something a bit more in depth. It must be said also that George Cloony is an almost perfect fit for the role of Bruce Wayne with his suave look and manner and his scenes with Gough really have a lot of warmth but he is severely let down with the film he is in. Other good points include some very nice sets, props and some great designs for the look of Gotham City, though these too are marred by garish lighting and wobbly fake looking ice. Uma Thurman clearly is performing tongue in cheek and as such get's a way with it but even she cannot save the terrible surroundings she is in. Somewhere deep in Batman & Robin there was a good film that was wanting to get out and it could very well have been pulled off with the cast, but campy humour and cheap laughs which weren't even funny completely rob the film of anything it was trying to achieve in any of the more serious scenes and unfortunately that's all people remember. Let this film be remembered as a lesson to studios, don't interfere with the creative process of film making. Batman could have gone on for many films but you killed it stone dead with this one and it should never be repeated again.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Some touching scenes completely overshadowed by ridiculous rubbish!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    powerkrust
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Batman & Robin, world famous franchise killer and the best example of why studios should not interfere with the movie making process. Batman Forever was a roaring success at the box office but this success was largely due to the reputation of the first two Burton films and zero to do with the actual quality of the movie. Batman & Robin was released to an audience now wise to what was going on and now the studios saw what the world thought of their family pandering and dumbed down plot. Batman & Robin was universally panned by just about everyone, including Director Joel Schumacher who walked out of the premier in embarrassment, but really....was it all that bad? The answer is both yes and no but the negative vastly outweighs any positives the film has to offer. The films script, if you can call it that is nothing more than a collection of one liners. In fact almost all of Arnie's dialogue as Mr Freeze is one liners and the jokey too and fro of Batman & Robin is cringeworthy. It's not even so bad it's good funny it's just bad, like a low budget under 5's kids TV program except this film cost a lot of money to make. The inaccuracies to the source material really ticked off the comic book community. It's true that Burton didn't stick entirely to the source either but he captured a lot of what the comic was about. Schumacher doesn't have a clue and seems content with quick flashes of Batman's arse to carry the film and zero sense of character depth anywhere to be seen. Amazingly enough the film DOES in fact have some good points. The best of the bunch being the wonderful Michael Gough having probably the most screen time of all the Batman films. The sub-story of his illness and the scenes that tell this are actually very moving and it's great to see Michael have a chance to do something a bit more in depth. It must be said also that George Cloony is an almost perfect fit for the role of Bruce Wayne with his suave look and manner and his scenes with Gough really have a lot of warmth but he is severely let down with the film he is in. Other good points include some very nice sets, props and some great designs for the look of Gotham City, though these too are marred by garish lighting and wobbly fake looking ice. Uma Thurman clearly is performing tongue in cheek and as such get's a way with it but even she cannot save the terrible surroundings she is in. Somewhere deep in Batman & Robin there was a good film that was wanting to get out and it could very well have been pulled off with the cast, but campy humour and cheap laughs which weren't even funny completely rob the film of anything it was trying to achieve in any of the more serious scenes and unfortunately that's all people remember. Let this film be remembered as a lesson to studios, don't interfere with the creative process of film making. Batman could have gone on for many films but you killed it stone dead with this one and it should never be repeated again.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    This is the worst movie I have ever saw in my entire life.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    hansonevan14
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie sucks. The casting sucks, the acting sucks, the action sucks, the effect sucks, everything about this movie is a mess. I spend one Thanksgiving night watch this shitty movie. I hate this movie so much. The first line of this movie is that Robin said "I want a car, chicks dig to car" and then Batman said "this is why Superman works alone". It gets worse and worse by the minute. Batman is play by George Clooney, which makes Val Kilmer's batman look like Michael Keaton's batman. Look I like George Clooney he's a good actor, but was he good in this, not at all. He doesn't have the right Batman voice, he just crashed through the window and was like "hi freeze I'm Batman". Really, is that the best you could do. Overall, George Clooney is a terrible Batman. Robin is play by Chris O' Donnell. All he does in this entire movie is just complain about stupid stuff. And that's all I have to say about his performance in this movie. Mr.Freeze is play by Arnold Schwarzenegger. One of the worst casting decisions ever. He only said one liners in this movie that consists of puns. And that pun is ice. "Allow me to break the ice", "Okay everyone, chill" "Hell, freeze is over", "Let's kick some ice", "What kill the dinosaurs, the ice age". Poison Ivy is play by Uma Thurman. She was actually nominated for an Oscar before this movie came out. Terrible performance from her in this movie, worst Poison Ivy. Batgirl is play by Alicia Silverstone. Worst performance in this movie. That's all I have to say. In the end, never see this movie, ever. This is the worst movie I have ever saw in my entire life. I'll never see it again. Oh yeah, who could ever forget the Bat-Nipples and Bat-Asses. Who's idea was that in the first place to put those things in? I hate this movie so much, makes me cringe every time I think about it. This movie is so horrible!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I Fell Asleep During The Movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bigverybadtom
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    My girlfriend got this as a gift, and we watched it together one evening. I fell asleep while watching it, and though my girlfriend presumably did not, she indicated not liking this either. What was wrong with it? Everything. "Batman" may supposed to be dark, but there was too much darkness in this one. Contrast does help keep one's interest, and Batman doesn't absolutely require darkness to be successful, as you might guess if you've seen the other movies, comics, etc. The heroes are bad. The interaction between the title characters doesn't come off properly. The villains are worse. The police tell Batman about the new villain, Mr. Freeze. (Huh? Batman is supposed to be the great detective who knows everything before anyone else does!) And Arnold Schwarzenegger was as suitable for the character as Danny DeVito would be to play Marilyn Monroe. The female villain stinks too. It's hard to describe more; I fell asleep because everything was done so badly. I wouldn't be surprised if everyone wasn't sleeping themselves when they were making this movie.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Awesome movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    blade1634989
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I for one loved this movie I've seen all live action batman's(excluding the horrible horrible fan made crap) yes The new batman's with christen bale are awesome but nothing beat a classic this movie is amazing and right up to pare with the first 3 it truly gives you The DC Comic feel witch i thought was great and BANE let me tell you if you watched the new dark knight the Bane in this movie would eat that guy for dinner BANE IS BIG HES BAD AND HE KICKS ASS witch is how banes suppose to be hes and x-con and a big dumb brute Never once was bane a criminal mastermind in the comics he was always there to pummel bats wile the real master mind killed stole and made his escape. This movie like the first 3 were all great comic based movies fun to watch with the kids and stuck true to the dc comic yes maybe clooney wasn't the best choice for batman i personally liked val kilmer better but that's just me. SO ignore all the shitty reviews and watch it for yours self keeping in mind not to compare it to the Dark-knight Trilogy but to the DC Comics we all know and love
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Worst Case of Groupthink Criticism Ever
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Clark Ho
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie was a hell of a lot of fun. I was fortunate enough to see it without hearing all the "let's all pan this" baloney and both my then GF and I thought it was great. I remember Clooney as a perfectly charming and intense Batman and Arnold at his self- deprecating silliest, portraying a wonderfully funny supervillain. The professional critimob just held hands and jumped on it per their usual thoughtless whim and the general audience just woke up on the wrong side of the collective bed that weekend. If you haven't seen it yet, go ahead and check it out and see how wrong conventional wisdom can be.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    what in the name of all that is holy is this?!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    movie critic
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It is to bad I can't give this movie minus one. Batman and Robin is hated by everyone blessed with the gift of sight. You have to be blind or even deaf to like this movie, or both! It is the worst representation of who Batman is. A comic book is better than this. Mr. Freeze wasn't a cool villain to start with and they made him worse with his stupid cheesy lines and his plastic chrome costume. Poison Ivy is supposed to be sexy but they managed to make her look like green alien, she wears a cheap cotton costume and blows some sort of essence into men's faces one to many times. George Clooney is a cool and calm Bruce Wayne but he is not so great at being batman. Robin is not so bad and bat girl is totally useless. Joel is a very bad director and he ruined batman. Please do not watch this movie. I personally think it is the work of Satan. Only he could have thought of something like that. But nevertheless, it is the worst movie that mankind has ever created. It is possibly the worst thing mankind has ever created.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Most Over-hated Movie In History
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    zduvvian
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    When I see reviews for the movie 'Batman and Robin', people always seem to say that it is an awful movie and one of the worst films ever made. I have seen it, and to be honest, I really like it. It is campy and a little stupid, but it really doesn't deserve to be given the same title given to other horrible movies like 'The Garbage Pail Kids Movie' or 'Jaws: The Revenge'. I'm not saying that people should stop hating on this movie (because I can see what people have against it) but I do think that people need to calm down about it. There are far worse superhero movies out there like 'Superman IV' and 'Catwoman'. Onto the film itself, like I said, I can see what people have against it: "The acting is awful, the story is campy and the movie overall isn't well directed". I don't think the acting is that bad. There are a few characters who are terrible (like Batgirl, who was meant to be British but it is obvious that the actress is American), but some characters do pretty good performances. George Clooney does a good job as Batman, Michael Gough does a great job as Alfred, Uma Thurman is a convincing Poison Ivy and Arnold Schwarzenegger is a pretty funny Mr Freeze (although I do agree that most of his ice puns are painful). The rest of the characters are pretty mediocre, but not terrible. The story is no Oscar-winning masterpiece, but it is still a good story that flows well. The (very) basic plot synopsis is that Batman and Robin are trying to stop Mr Freeze and Poison Ivy from freezing Gotham City and taking over the world. (Of course!) That may sound like a boring and clich&eacute;d story, but it is actually quite good. The sub-plots fit into the story perfectly, especially one about Alfred dying of MacGregor's Syndrome. Overall, I feel that Batman and Robin is one of the most over-hated movies of all time and should really be given a chance. Like I said, it isn't perfect, but it really isn't as awful as everybody says. If you watch the movie with the knowledge that is a campy flick, you'll have a good time, just don't listen to the people who say that it is a horrible abomination to cinema, because it really isn't. 7/10 P.S. - If you want to know what I think of Bane, I think he is closer to the comics than Bane in 'The Dark Knight Rises' because the inclusion of the Venom drug that gives Bane his strength.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    so bad it hurts
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    dbenitez25
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    the thing is that there isn't much to say, is just not worth it... is a really bad movie... the script is crap, the customs are crap, the special effects are crap, the roles are crap, the time-line is crap, there isn't a single thing to point out as positive. I am sorry but is a real bummer. And another thing, at last but not least... Really? Nipples?? nipples in a Batman suit??? is just a disgrace...
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Joel, you where possessed when you made this film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    natebridgeman
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie SUCKS!!!!!! The entire film is just one two and a half hour toy commercial. It's possibly the worst film of all time with over the top action sequences, ridiculous costumes and make-up, effect that were obviously drawn on paper, just plain terrible acting, everyone wanting to punch robin in the face 700 times, and most of all, 65% of the entire movie is just plain one-liners. There is just plain nothing I love about about this movie. It makes every other bad movie look like a masterpiece. Don't even waste your time like I did. If you want to live a happy life on earth. This movie not only killed the Batman franchise for 8 years, but it also killed superhero movies for 4 years. George Clooney is the worst batman ever!!!!!!! Joel Schumaucher, if you are looking at this review you killed one of my favorite superheros. At least, thank the Lord God Almighty that he created Christopher Nolan. Why did Warner Bros. release this garbage. Don't see it at all!!!!!!!!!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Some touching scenes completely overshadowed by ridiculous rubbish!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    powerkrust
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Batman & Robin, world famous franchise killer and the best example of why studios should not interfere with the movie making process. Batman Forever was a roaring success at the box office but this success was largely due to the reputation of the first two Burton films and zero to do with the actual quality of the movie. Batman & Robin was released to an audience now wise to what was going on and now the studios saw what the world thought of their family pandering and dumbed down plot. Batman & Robin was universally panned by just about everyone, including Director Joel Schumacher who walked out of the premier in embarrassment, but really....was it all that bad? The answer is both yes and no but the negative vastly outweighs any positives the film has to offer. The films script, if you can call it that is nothing more than a collection of one liners. In fact almost all of Arnie's dialogue as Mr Freeze is one liners and the jokey too and fro of Batman & Robin is cringeworthy. It's not even so bad it's good funny it's just bad, like a low budget under 5's kids TV program except this film cost a lot of money to make. The inaccuracies to the source material really ticked off the comic book community. It's true that Burton didn't stick entirely to the source either but he captured a lot of what the comic was about. Schumacher doesn't have a clue and seems content with quick flashes of Batman's arse to carry the film and zero sense of character depth anywhere to be seen. Amazingly enough the film DOES in fact have some good points. The best of the bunch being the wonderful Michael Gough having probably the most screen time of all the Batman films. The sub-story of his illness and the scenes that tell this are actually very moving and it's great to see Michael have a chance to do something a bit more in depth. It must be said also that George Cloony is an almost perfect fit for the role of Bruce Wayne with his suave look and manner and his scenes with Gough really have a lot of warmth but he is severely let down with the film he is in. Other good points include some very nice sets, props and some great designs for the look of Gotham City, though these too are marred by garish lighting and wobbly fake looking ice. Uma Thurman clearly is performing tongue in cheek and as such get's a way with it but even she cannot save the terrible surroundings she is in. Somewhere deep in Batman & Robin there was a good film that was wanting to get out and it could very well have been pulled off with the cast, but campy humour and cheap laughs which weren't even funny completely rob the film of anything it was trying to achieve in any of the more serious scenes and unfortunately that's all people remember. Let this film be remembered as a lesson to studios, don't interfere with the creative process of film making. Batman could have gone on for many films but you killed it stone dead with this one and it should never be repeated again.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Some touching scenes completely overshadowed by ridiculous rubbish!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    powerkrust
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Batman & Robin, world famous franchise killer and the best example of why studios should not interfere with the movie making process. Batman Forever was a roaring success at the box office but this success was largely due to the reputation of the first two Burton films and zero to do with the actual quality of the movie. Batman & Robin was released to an audience now wise to what was going on and now the studios saw what the world thought of their family pandering and dumbed down plot. Batman & Robin was universally panned by just about everyone, including Director Joel Schumacher who walked out of the premier in embarrassment, but really....was it all that bad? The answer is both yes and no but the negative vastly outweighs any positives the film has to offer. The films script, if you can call it that is nothing more than a collection of one liners. In fact almost all of Arnie's dialogue as Mr Freeze is one liners and the jokey too and fro of Batman & Robin is cringeworthy. It's not even so bad it's good funny it's just bad, like a low budget under 5's kids TV program except this film cost a lot of money to make. The inaccuracies to the source material really ticked off the comic book community. It's true that Burton didn't stick entirely to the source either but he captured a lot of what the comic was about. Schumacher doesn't have a clue and seems content with quick flashes of Batman's arse to carry the film and zero sense of character depth anywhere to be seen. Amazingly enough the film DOES in fact have some good points. The best of the bunch being the wonderful Michael Gough having probably the most screen time of all the Batman films. The sub-story of his illness and the scenes that tell this are actually very moving and it's great to see Michael have a chance to do something a bit more in depth. It must be said also that George Cloony is an almost perfect fit for the role of Bruce Wayne with his suave look and manner and his scenes with Gough really have a lot of warmth but he is severely let down with the film he is in. Other good points include some very nice sets, props and some great designs for the look of Gotham City, though these too are marred by garish lighting and wobbly fake looking ice. Uma Thurman clearly is performing tongue in cheek and as such get's a way with it but even she cannot save the terrible surroundings she is in. Somewhere deep in Batman & Robin there was a good film that was wanting to get out and it could very well have been pulled off with the cast, but campy humour and cheap laughs which weren't even funny completely rob the film of anything it was trying to achieve in any of the more serious scenes and unfortunately that's all people remember. Let this film be remembered as a lesson to studios, don't interfere with the creative process of film making. Batman could have gone on for many films but you killed it stone dead with this one and it should never be repeated again.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    This is the worst movie I have ever saw in my entire life.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    hansonevan14
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie sucks. The casting sucks, the acting sucks, the action sucks, the effect sucks, everything about this movie is a mess. I spend one Thanksgiving night watch this shitty movie. I hate this movie so much. The first line of this movie is that Robin said "I want a car, chicks dig to car" and then Batman said "this is why Superman works alone". It gets worse and worse by the minute. Batman is play by George Clooney, which makes Val Kilmer's batman look like Michael Keaton's batman. Look I like George Clooney he's a good actor, but was he good in this, not at all. He doesn't have the right Batman voice, he just crashed through the window and was like "hi freeze I'm Batman". Really, is that the best you could do. Overall, George Clooney is a terrible Batman. Robin is play by Chris O' Donnell. All he does in this entire movie is just complain about stupid stuff. And that's all I have to say about his performance in this movie. Mr.Freeze is play by Arnold Schwarzenegger. One of the worst casting decisions ever. He only said one liners in this movie that consists of puns. And that pun is ice. "Allow me to break the ice", "Okay everyone, chill" "Hell, freeze is over", "Let's kick some ice", "What kill the dinosaurs, the ice age". Poison Ivy is play by Uma Thurman. She was actually nominated for an Oscar before this movie came out. Terrible performance from her in this movie, worst Poison Ivy. Batgirl is play by Alicia Silverstone. Worst performance in this movie. That's all I have to say. In the end, never see this movie, ever. This is the worst movie I have ever saw in my entire life. I'll never see it again. Oh yeah, who could ever forget the Bat-Nipples and Bat-Asses. Who's idea was that in the first place to put those things in? I hate this movie so much, makes me cringe every time I think about it. This movie is so horrible!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I Fell Asleep During The Movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bigverybadtom
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    My girlfriend got this as a gift, and we watched it together one evening. I fell asleep while watching it, and though my girlfriend presumably did not, she indicated not liking this either. What was wrong with it? Everything. "Batman" may supposed to be dark, but there was too much darkness in this one. Contrast does help keep one's interest, and Batman doesn't absolutely require darkness to be successful, as you might guess if you've seen the other movies, comics, etc. The heroes are bad. The interaction between the title characters doesn't come off properly. The villains are worse. The police tell Batman about the new villain, Mr. Freeze. (Huh? Batman is supposed to be the great detective who knows everything before anyone else does!) And Arnold Schwarzenegger was as suitable for the character as Danny DeVito would be to play Marilyn Monroe. The female villain stinks too. It's hard to describe more; I fell asleep because everything was done so badly. I wouldn't be surprised if everyone wasn't sleeping themselves when they were making this movie.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Awesome movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    blade1634989
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I for one loved this movie I've seen all live action batman's(excluding the horrible horrible fan made crap) yes The new batman's with christen bale are awesome but nothing beat a classic this movie is amazing and right up to pare with the first 3 it truly gives you The DC Comic feel witch i thought was great and BANE let me tell you if you watched the new dark knight the Bane in this movie would eat that guy for dinner BANE IS BIG HES BAD AND HE KICKS ASS witch is how banes suppose to be hes and x-con and a big dumb brute Never once was bane a criminal mastermind in the comics he was always there to pummel bats wile the real master mind killed stole and made his escape. This movie like the first 3 were all great comic based movies fun to watch with the kids and stuck true to the dc comic yes maybe clooney wasn't the best choice for batman i personally liked val kilmer better but that's just me. SO ignore all the shitty reviews and watch it for yours self keeping in mind not to compare it to the Dark-knight Trilogy but to the DC Comics we all know and love
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Worst Case of Groupthink Criticism Ever
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Clark Ho
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie was a hell of a lot of fun. I was fortunate enough to see it without hearing all the "let's all pan this" baloney and both my then GF and I thought it was great. I remember Clooney as a perfectly charming and intense Batman and Arnold at his self- deprecating silliest, portraying a wonderfully funny supervillain. The professional critimob just held hands and jumped on it per their usual thoughtless whim and the general audience just woke up on the wrong side of the collective bed that weekend. If you haven't seen it yet, go ahead and check it out and see how wrong conventional wisdom can be.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    what in the name of all that is holy is this?!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    movie critic
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It is to bad I can't give this movie minus one. Batman and Robin is hated by everyone blessed with the gift of sight. You have to be blind or even deaf to like this movie, or both! It is the worst representation of who Batman is. A comic book is better than this. Mr. Freeze wasn't a cool villain to start with and they made him worse with his stupid cheesy lines and his plastic chrome costume. Poison Ivy is supposed to be sexy but they managed to make her look like green alien, she wears a cheap cotton costume and blows some sort of essence into men's faces one to many times. George Clooney is a cool and calm Bruce Wayne but he is not so great at being batman. Robin is not so bad and bat girl is totally useless. Joel is a very bad director and he ruined batman. Please do not watch this movie. I personally think it is the work of Satan. Only he could have thought of something like that. But nevertheless, it is the worst movie that mankind has ever created. It is possibly the worst thing mankind has ever created.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Most Over-hated Movie In History
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    zduvvian
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    When I see reviews for the movie 'Batman and Robin', people always seem to say that it is an awful movie and one of the worst films ever made. I have seen it, and to be honest, I really like it. It is campy and a little stupid, but it really doesn't deserve to be given the same title given to other horrible movies like 'The Garbage Pail Kids Movie' or 'Jaws: The Revenge'. I'm not saying that people should stop hating on this movie (because I can see what people have against it) but I do think that people need to calm down about it. There are far worse superhero movies out there like 'Superman IV' and 'Catwoman'. Onto the film itself, like I said, I can see what people have against it: "The acting is awful, the story is campy and the movie overall isn't well directed". I don't think the acting is that bad. There are a few characters who are terrible (like Batgirl, who was meant to be British but it is obvious that the actress is American), but some characters do pretty good performances. George Clooney does a good job as Batman, Michael Gough does a great job as Alfred, Uma Thurman is a convincing Poison Ivy and Arnold Schwarzenegger is a pretty funny Mr Freeze (although I do agree that most of his ice puns are painful). The rest of the characters are pretty mediocre, but not terrible. The story is no Oscar-winning masterpiece, but it is still a good story that flows well. The (very) basic plot synopsis is that Batman and Robin are trying to stop Mr Freeze and Poison Ivy from freezing Gotham City and taking over the world. (Of course!) That may sound like a boring and clich&eacute;d story, but it is actually quite good. The sub-plots fit into the story perfectly, especially one about Alfred dying of MacGregor's Syndrome. Overall, I feel that Batman and Robin is one of the most over-hated movies of all time and should really be given a chance. Like I said, it isn't perfect, but it really isn't as awful as everybody says. If you watch the movie with the knowledge that is a campy flick, you'll have a good time, just don't listen to the people who say that it is a horrible abomination to cinema, because it really isn't. 7/10 P.S. - If you want to know what I think of Bane, I think he is closer to the comics than Bane in 'The Dark Knight Rises' because the inclusion of the Venom drug that gives Bane his strength.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    so bad it hurts
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    dbenitez25
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    the thing is that there isn't much to say, is just not worth it... is a really bad movie... the script is crap, the customs are crap, the special effects are crap, the roles are crap, the time-line is crap, there isn't a single thing to point out as positive. I am sorry but is a real bummer. And another thing, at last but not least... Really? Nipples?? nipples in a Batman suit??? is just a disgrace...
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Joel, you where possessed when you made this film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    natebridgeman
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie SUCKS!!!!!! The entire film is just one two and a half hour toy commercial. It's possibly the worst film of all time with over the top action sequences, ridiculous costumes and make-up, effect that were obviously drawn on paper, just plain terrible acting, everyone wanting to punch robin in the face 700 times, and most of all, 65% of the entire movie is just plain one-liners. There is just plain nothing I love about about this movie. It makes every other bad movie look like a masterpiece. Don't even waste your time like I did. If you want to live a happy life on earth. This movie not only killed the Batman franchise for 8 years, but it also killed superhero movies for 4 years. George Clooney is the worst batman ever!!!!!!! Joel Schumaucher, if you are looking at this review you killed one of my favorite superheros. At least, thank the Lord God Almighty that he created Christopher Nolan. Why did Warner Bros. release this garbage. Don't see it at all!!!!!!!!!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
 </reviews>
</filme>
