<filme>
 <id>
  256
 </id>
 <imdburl>
  http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0115856
 </imdburl>
 <ano>
  1996
 </ano>
 <titulo>
  O Gato Sumiu
 </titulo>
 <rating>
  6.8
 </rating>
 <sinopse>
  Chloe, a young woman, is going on holidays. She entrusts her beloved cat to Madame Ren&eacute;e's care. But one day Madame Ren&eacute;e (an old lady of the neighborhood) can not find the cat. Chloe ... &nbsp;&raquo;
 </sinopse>
 <storyline>
  Chloe, a young woman, is going on holidays. She entrusts her beloved cat to Madame Ren&eacute;e's care. But one day Madame Ren&eacute;e (an old lady of the neighborhood) can not find the cat. Chloe starts searching the neighborhood... This is the pretext for the exploration of a quarter of Paris and his inhabitants.
 </storyline>
 <generos>
  <genero>
   Comedy
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Romance
  </genero>
 </generos>
 <keywords>
  <keyword>
   cat
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   neighborhood
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   drums
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   salsa
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   reference to vincent van gogh
  </keyword>
 </keywords>
 <diretores>
  <diretor>
   C&eacute;dric Klapisch
  </diretor>
 </diretores>
 <escritores>
  <escritor>
   C&eacute;dric Klapisch
  </escritor>
 </escritores>
 <atores>
  <ator>
   Garance Clavel
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Zinedine Soualem
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Ren&eacute;e Le Calm
  </ator>
 </atores>
 <reviews>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Study of people and Paris, and both
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gcd70
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/3/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    As a character study or a study of Paris, Cedric Klapisch's "When the Cat's Away" works well. After some time to warm up, the film becomes an affecting tale of a lonely Parisian girl who is searching desperately for companionship. We follow young Chloe in her quest for her lost Love (Gris Gris the cat) and her first love, a a man in whom she can put her trust. Ironically like Gris Gris, the man who truly deserves her affections is right in front of her nose. Delightful performances from the three main actors really give the show an edge. Garance Clavel's natural turn helps the audience relate to her, while Zinedine Soualem is touching as the simple Djamel. Adding humour is the lovable Madame Renee, a widow whose love of cats is the beginning of Cloe's trouble. Madame Renee heads up an amazing sub-culture of lonely old women. You have to give credit to Klapisch's basic screenplay and simple direction, as well as Benoit Delhomme's revealing cinematography. Monday, November 30, 1998 - Hoyts Croydon
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Going after your cat and finding yourself
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    rebeccastelea
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/1/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A peculiar depiction of Paris. The more ambiguous, the more interesting. No Eiffel Tower, No 'Mus&eacute;e Du Louvre', no 'lost in translation' tourists. Just life, life at its fullest. In a controversial neighbourhood of the 20th 'arrondissement' there is more to life than commercial Paris. Life lies here in graffiti, in demolition of buildings, in bars, in the inevitable gossip. Chlo&eacute; is our vehicle of discovering that exploring life leads to identity. The camera follows her around and illustrates the most banal daily routines. The film doesn't need special effects to captivate you; it replaces them with people dealing with absurdly normal situations. From recurring scenes of amnesic old ladies being brought back by the police to characters running after cats on the roof of a building, C&eacute;dric Klapisch transforms the trivial into something exciting. All characters are expected to develop their identity and reach a common ground with the society and with themselves. Just as lost things are frequently lying in front of us, their search is ephemeral.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Delightful Tour of a Gentrifying Paris Neighborhood
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    noralee
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/12/2005
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The last time I saw Paris was in Eric Rohmer's "Rendez-Vous." Now I've revisited in "While the Cat's Away (Chacun cherche son chat)." It's "Seinfeld"-ian in that nothing really happens (and sometimes its 95 minutes do drag) but it's a wonderful slice of urban life in a gentrifying neighborhood as residents occupy different eco-systems in the same locality. It could easily be re-made on the Upper West Side of NYC, or other city neighborhoods. It is quite a lovely little movie. Many of the actors are non-professionals that really are their neighborhood's local color characters. However, at last night's showing someone brought their kids thinking because it had an animal in the title it was appropriate. I did not think so - there are visuals and discussion of explicit sex (hetero- and homosexual) as well as sexual harassment threats that I do not think are appropriate for children. (originally written 7/24/1997)
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    when the cat's away, Chlo&eacute; learns more about herself...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    dbdumonteil
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/2/2005
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    1996 was the year during which C&eacute;dric Klapisch definitely imposed his talent in the landscape of French cinema thanks to two feature movies: "un air de famille" and "chacun cherche son chat". The ones who have been enthralled by these two flicks won't contradict me. Written day-to-day on account of the evolution of the story, shot with a shoestring budget, acted by only 2 or 3 professional comedians and virtually non-professional actors, "chacun cherche son chat" confirms all the hopes placed in Klapisch. One thing I noticed with him is that he has the gift to entitle his movies with catchy and funny titles (which can only be understood by French-speaking people; here "chacun cherche son chat" was translated abroad by :"when the cat's away" whereas the original title in French is "everyone's looking for his/her cat"). "Chacun cherche son chat" clearly obeys to this trend. The main character is a teenage girl, Chlo&eacute; who's looking for her cat in a popular neighborhood in Paris. We find again in this film, a few themes and features peculiar to Klapisch which he will develop and improve in his future movies like the initiatory voyage "l'auberge Espagnole" (2002). About it, for Klapisch the loss of Chlo&eacute;'s cat "Grisgris" mainly serves as a pretext to confront her heroin with the exterior world, in the street. She will gradually leave her naive and egocentric world to get interested in the people who surround her and to strike up friendships with several people. In a way, the director tries to communicate us a nearly identical message to the one in "Groundhog Day" (1993): you have to open yourselves to others which enables to see the world under another (and better) angle. Then, I previously mentioned Klapisch's features. I won't linger on them. I will just say that two of them shine. The director knows how to associate an ironic and tender look in the portrait of his characters and he seems very close to them. In another hand, he just has to proceed by little touches to make a situation intense (I think of the moment when Chlo&eacute; meets Michel's latest lover). But if there's a more admirable thing in Klapisch's opus, it's the directing of actors. Each one of them is perfectly used. Garence Clavel is a real revelation whereas some of her partners see their talent evolving (Zinedine Soualem and Romain Duris, two actors from Klapisch's gang). And this dear Mrs Ren&eacute;e! Very far from the commonplaces and stereotypes commonly attributed to old people, she's also the opposite of Etienne Chatiliez's "tatie Danielle". The director also grants a great attention to the non-professional actors, even to those who have a minor role. Most of them appear for a few minutes on the screen but their presences remain in the memories. Moreover, the solidarity which strongly links its inhabitants (no matter their age) clashes with the place of the action and the dramatic changes which occur in it: a dying popular neighborhood. We can often see in the film, shots of buildings razed or half razed to the ground. "Chacun cherche son chat" is beneficial cinema like we would like to watch it more often and this one, "Le p&eacute;ril jeune" (1994), "un air de famille" and "l'auberge Espagnole" can secure Klapisch's place in the limited circle of the greatest French film-makers of these last years. And by the way, thank you Mr Klapisch for making movies that make me happy.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An interesting, arty exploration of the search to find oneself in the midst of the rapidly changing modern day Paris
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mars_to_marla
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/12/2004
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This was a thoroughly enjoyable film, with a very interesting use of editing in parts... The film's main character, Chloe, lives with her gay flatmate, Michel, has few friends, and definitely no love life to speak of. She works as a make up artist, a job which she hates. One day, Chloe goes away on holiday, and leaves her cat with the local cat lady, Mme Renoir. Upon returning home, Chloe's cat, Gris-Gris, has disappeared. So starts a search for Gris-Gris that the whole neighbourhood is involved in. We are taken on a journey through a district of Paris quite distinct from any glamorised Hollywood image you'll ever see. This is the real, working, living Paris, with real people living in it, and this particular area is in a phase of 'urban development', with a lot of the traditional, working class aspects of the community being pushed aside to make way for the progress of bourgeois trends. We meet a whole host of this area's inhabitants along the way, each with their own eccentricities and foibles; characters that soon become part of Chloe's life. The disappearance of the cat instigates Chloe's search into her own life, to fill the gaps that are missing. This film centres around the hopes and desires of one character in particular (Chloe), but the backdrop is a vessel for expressing changes that are affecting real people in Paris. An interesting, arty approach to a film about the search to find oneself, and come to terms with an ever changing world that one may feel at odds with.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Cat's Pajamas
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    writers_reign
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/1/2004
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    If it's true that Kaplishe's best film remains 'un air de famille', where all he had to do was join the dots of Agnes Jaoui's and Jean-Pierre Bacri's peerless screenplay, he does also have a quirkiness all his own which comes out in 'Little Nothings' and in this entry. I don't know what school these translators go to to learn how to screw up titles - one recent gem was 'The Girl From Paris' from the French, One Swallow Does Not Make A Summer. Weird. Kaplishe's own 'L'Auberge Espanol' underwent a similar bizarre translation which I asked him about personally and he was just as baffled as the rest of us. Chacun cherche son chat translates as Each searches for his own cat, with cat, of course, being a metaphor for happiness, and so it is here. Chloe is really looking for Mr Right but a missing cat is a convenient metaphor. As in other Kaplish entries we get the whole nine yards in terms of off-the-wall characters and the whole schmeer is set against the transformations taking place around North-East Paris between Bastille and Nation. Not a lot happens and it happens all at once. A charmer. 8/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Gris Gris rules!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jbels
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/7/2003
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    When the woman tries to take a vacation and leaves her beloved cat Gris Gris with an old neighbor, the cat gets lost and all heck breaks loose in France. Funny movie shows the love that humans have for their pets and the importance they play in our lives. Also, one of the funniest endings I have ever seen!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A wonderful simple movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    comiis8
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/12/2002
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is a very well done movie. The ending seems a little unfair, but such is life. Too bad this is not on DVD, a good one to own.. A cat is lost and a whole group of people are searching for it. We go thru each one's life as it all comes together at the very end..
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    So tired of being alone
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    boris (boris_peeters@hotmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/9/2002
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The superb Al Green moaning one of his greatest songs : I'm so tired of being alone. That about sums it up. Klapish is quickly becoming one of my favourite directors, making great movies with small budgets like l'auberge espanol. I don't fall in love with actresses every time I see a movie but Garance Clavel will certainly haunt my daydreams for a few days... Credits to the other actors, especially Zinedine Soualem and Ren&eacute;e le Calm. This is a warm, sparkling and very true movie about real persons and real emotions, (and therefore) sometimes funny, sometimes tragic. A movie that makes one run out the door and ...
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    French cinema still has bite...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Jonah (SixofSwords)
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/7/2002
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    What starts out initially as a rather dull drama, quickly picks up pace and sparkles. A lovely little movie that hopefully will never be given a Hollywood remake this movie is a treat.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Study of people and Paris, and both
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gcd70
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/3/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    As a character study or a study of Paris, Cedric Klapisch's "When the Cat's Away" works well. After some time to warm up, the film becomes an affecting tale of a lonely Parisian girl who is searching desperately for companionship. We follow young Chloe in her quest for her lost Love (Gris Gris the cat) and her first love, a a man in whom she can put her trust. Ironically like Gris Gris, the man who truly deserves her affections is right in front of her nose. Delightful performances from the three main actors really give the show an edge. Garance Clavel's natural turn helps the audience relate to her, while Zinedine Soualem is touching as the simple Djamel. Adding humour is the lovable Madame Renee, a widow whose love of cats is the beginning of Cloe's trouble. Madame Renee heads up an amazing sub-culture of lonely old women. You have to give credit to Klapisch's basic screenplay and simple direction, as well as Benoit Delhomme's revealing cinematography. Monday, November 30, 1998 - Hoyts Croydon
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Going after your cat and finding yourself
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    rebeccastelea
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/1/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A peculiar depiction of Paris. The more ambiguous, the more interesting. No Eiffel Tower, No 'Mus&eacute;e Du Louvre', no 'lost in translation' tourists. Just life, life at its fullest. In a controversial neighbourhood of the 20th 'arrondissement' there is more to life than commercial Paris. Life lies here in graffiti, in demolition of buildings, in bars, in the inevitable gossip. Chlo&eacute; is our vehicle of discovering that exploring life leads to identity. The camera follows her around and illustrates the most banal daily routines. The film doesn't need special effects to captivate you; it replaces them with people dealing with absurdly normal situations. From recurring scenes of amnesic old ladies being brought back by the police to characters running after cats on the roof of a building, C&eacute;dric Klapisch transforms the trivial into something exciting. All characters are expected to develop their identity and reach a common ground with the society and with themselves. Just as lost things are frequently lying in front of us, their search is ephemeral.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Delightful Tour of a Gentrifying Paris Neighborhood
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    noralee
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/12/2005
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The last time I saw Paris was in Eric Rohmer's "Rendez-Vous." Now I've revisited in "While the Cat's Away (Chacun cherche son chat)." It's "Seinfeld"-ian in that nothing really happens (and sometimes its 95 minutes do drag) but it's a wonderful slice of urban life in a gentrifying neighborhood as residents occupy different eco-systems in the same locality. It could easily be re-made on the Upper West Side of NYC, or other city neighborhoods. It is quite a lovely little movie. Many of the actors are non-professionals that really are their neighborhood's local color characters. However, at last night's showing someone brought their kids thinking because it had an animal in the title it was appropriate. I did not think so - there are visuals and discussion of explicit sex (hetero- and homosexual) as well as sexual harassment threats that I do not think are appropriate for children. (originally written 7/24/1997)
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    when the cat's away, Chlo&eacute; learns more about herself...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    dbdumonteil
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/2/2005
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    1996 was the year during which C&eacute;dric Klapisch definitely imposed his talent in the landscape of French cinema thanks to two feature movies: "un air de famille" and "chacun cherche son chat". The ones who have been enthralled by these two flicks won't contradict me. Written day-to-day on account of the evolution of the story, shot with a shoestring budget, acted by only 2 or 3 professional comedians and virtually non-professional actors, "chacun cherche son chat" confirms all the hopes placed in Klapisch. One thing I noticed with him is that he has the gift to entitle his movies with catchy and funny titles (which can only be understood by French-speaking people; here "chacun cherche son chat" was translated abroad by :"when the cat's away" whereas the original title in French is "everyone's looking for his/her cat"). "Chacun cherche son chat" clearly obeys to this trend. The main character is a teenage girl, Chlo&eacute; who's looking for her cat in a popular neighborhood in Paris. We find again in this film, a few themes and features peculiar to Klapisch which he will develop and improve in his future movies like the initiatory voyage "l'auberge Espagnole" (2002). About it, for Klapisch the loss of Chlo&eacute;'s cat "Grisgris" mainly serves as a pretext to confront her heroin with the exterior world, in the street. She will gradually leave her naive and egocentric world to get interested in the people who surround her and to strike up friendships with several people. In a way, the director tries to communicate us a nearly identical message to the one in "Groundhog Day" (1993): you have to open yourselves to others which enables to see the world under another (and better) angle. Then, I previously mentioned Klapisch's features. I won't linger on them. I will just say that two of them shine. The director knows how to associate an ironic and tender look in the portrait of his characters and he seems very close to them. In another hand, he just has to proceed by little touches to make a situation intense (I think of the moment when Chlo&eacute; meets Michel's latest lover). But if there's a more admirable thing in Klapisch's opus, it's the directing of actors. Each one of them is perfectly used. Garence Clavel is a real revelation whereas some of her partners see their talent evolving (Zinedine Soualem and Romain Duris, two actors from Klapisch's gang). And this dear Mrs Ren&eacute;e! Very far from the commonplaces and stereotypes commonly attributed to old people, she's also the opposite of Etienne Chatiliez's "tatie Danielle". The director also grants a great attention to the non-professional actors, even to those who have a minor role. Most of them appear for a few minutes on the screen but their presences remain in the memories. Moreover, the solidarity which strongly links its inhabitants (no matter their age) clashes with the place of the action and the dramatic changes which occur in it: a dying popular neighborhood. We can often see in the film, shots of buildings razed or half razed to the ground. "Chacun cherche son chat" is beneficial cinema like we would like to watch it more often and this one, "Le p&eacute;ril jeune" (1994), "un air de famille" and "l'auberge Espagnole" can secure Klapisch's place in the limited circle of the greatest French film-makers of these last years. And by the way, thank you Mr Klapisch for making movies that make me happy.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An interesting, arty exploration of the search to find oneself in the midst of the rapidly changing modern day Paris
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mars_to_marla
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/12/2004
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This was a thoroughly enjoyable film, with a very interesting use of editing in parts... The film's main character, Chloe, lives with her gay flatmate, Michel, has few friends, and definitely no love life to speak of. She works as a make up artist, a job which she hates. One day, Chloe goes away on holiday, and leaves her cat with the local cat lady, Mme Renoir. Upon returning home, Chloe's cat, Gris-Gris, has disappeared. So starts a search for Gris-Gris that the whole neighbourhood is involved in. We are taken on a journey through a district of Paris quite distinct from any glamorised Hollywood image you'll ever see. This is the real, working, living Paris, with real people living in it, and this particular area is in a phase of 'urban development', with a lot of the traditional, working class aspects of the community being pushed aside to make way for the progress of bourgeois trends. We meet a whole host of this area's inhabitants along the way, each with their own eccentricities and foibles; characters that soon become part of Chloe's life. The disappearance of the cat instigates Chloe's search into her own life, to fill the gaps that are missing. This film centres around the hopes and desires of one character in particular (Chloe), but the backdrop is a vessel for expressing changes that are affecting real people in Paris. An interesting, arty approach to a film about the search to find oneself, and come to terms with an ever changing world that one may feel at odds with.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Cat's Pajamas
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    writers_reign
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/1/2004
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    If it's true that Kaplishe's best film remains 'un air de famille', where all he had to do was join the dots of Agnes Jaoui's and Jean-Pierre Bacri's peerless screenplay, he does also have a quirkiness all his own which comes out in 'Little Nothings' and in this entry. I don't know what school these translators go to to learn how to screw up titles - one recent gem was 'The Girl From Paris' from the French, One Swallow Does Not Make A Summer. Weird. Kaplishe's own 'L'Auberge Espanol' underwent a similar bizarre translation which I asked him about personally and he was just as baffled as the rest of us. Chacun cherche son chat translates as Each searches for his own cat, with cat, of course, being a metaphor for happiness, and so it is here. Chloe is really looking for Mr Right but a missing cat is a convenient metaphor. As in other Kaplish entries we get the whole nine yards in terms of off-the-wall characters and the whole schmeer is set against the transformations taking place around North-East Paris between Bastille and Nation. Not a lot happens and it happens all at once. A charmer. 8/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Gris Gris rules!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jbels
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/7/2003
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    When the woman tries to take a vacation and leaves her beloved cat Gris Gris with an old neighbor, the cat gets lost and all heck breaks loose in France. Funny movie shows the love that humans have for their pets and the importance they play in our lives. Also, one of the funniest endings I have ever seen!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A wonderful simple movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    comiis8
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/12/2002
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is a very well done movie. The ending seems a little unfair, but such is life. Too bad this is not on DVD, a good one to own.. A cat is lost and a whole group of people are searching for it. We go thru each one's life as it all comes together at the very end..
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    So tired of being alone
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    boris (boris_peeters@hotmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/9/2002
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The superb Al Green moaning one of his greatest songs : I'm so tired of being alone. That about sums it up. Klapish is quickly becoming one of my favourite directors, making great movies with small budgets like l'auberge espanol. I don't fall in love with actresses every time I see a movie but Garance Clavel will certainly haunt my daydreams for a few days... Credits to the other actors, especially Zinedine Soualem and Ren&eacute;e le Calm. This is a warm, sparkling and very true movie about real persons and real emotions, (and therefore) sometimes funny, sometimes tragic. A movie that makes one run out the door and ...
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    French cinema still has bite...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Jonah (SixofSwords)
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/7/2002
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    What starts out initially as a rather dull drama, quickly picks up pace and sparkles. A lovely little movie that hopefully will never be given a Hollywood remake this movie is a treat.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Study of people and Paris, and both
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gcd70
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/3/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    As a character study or a study of Paris, Cedric Klapisch's "When the Cat's Away" works well. After some time to warm up, the film becomes an affecting tale of a lonely Parisian girl who is searching desperately for companionship. We follow young Chloe in her quest for her lost Love (Gris Gris the cat) and her first love, a a man in whom she can put her trust. Ironically like Gris Gris, the man who truly deserves her affections is right in front of her nose. Delightful performances from the three main actors really give the show an edge. Garance Clavel's natural turn helps the audience relate to her, while Zinedine Soualem is touching as the simple Djamel. Adding humour is the lovable Madame Renee, a widow whose love of cats is the beginning of Cloe's trouble. Madame Renee heads up an amazing sub-culture of lonely old women. You have to give credit to Klapisch's basic screenplay and simple direction, as well as Benoit Delhomme's revealing cinematography. Monday, November 30, 1998 - Hoyts Croydon
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Going after your cat and finding yourself
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    rebeccastelea
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/1/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A peculiar depiction of Paris. The more ambiguous, the more interesting. No Eiffel Tower, No 'Mus&eacute;e Du Louvre', no 'lost in translation' tourists. Just life, life at its fullest. In a controversial neighbourhood of the 20th 'arrondissement' there is more to life than commercial Paris. Life lies here in graffiti, in demolition of buildings, in bars, in the inevitable gossip. Chlo&eacute; is our vehicle of discovering that exploring life leads to identity. The camera follows her around and illustrates the most banal daily routines. The film doesn't need special effects to captivate you; it replaces them with people dealing with absurdly normal situations. From recurring scenes of amnesic old ladies being brought back by the police to characters running after cats on the roof of a building, C&eacute;dric Klapisch transforms the trivial into something exciting. All characters are expected to develop their identity and reach a common ground with the society and with themselves. Just as lost things are frequently lying in front of us, their search is ephemeral.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Delightful Tour of a Gentrifying Paris Neighborhood
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    noralee
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/12/2005
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The last time I saw Paris was in Eric Rohmer's "Rendez-Vous." Now I've revisited in "While the Cat's Away (Chacun cherche son chat)." It's "Seinfeld"-ian in that nothing really happens (and sometimes its 95 minutes do drag) but it's a wonderful slice of urban life in a gentrifying neighborhood as residents occupy different eco-systems in the same locality. It could easily be re-made on the Upper West Side of NYC, or other city neighborhoods. It is quite a lovely little movie. Many of the actors are non-professionals that really are their neighborhood's local color characters. However, at last night's showing someone brought their kids thinking because it had an animal in the title it was appropriate. I did not think so - there are visuals and discussion of explicit sex (hetero- and homosexual) as well as sexual harassment threats that I do not think are appropriate for children. (originally written 7/24/1997)
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    when the cat's away, Chlo&eacute; learns more about herself...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    dbdumonteil
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/2/2005
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    1996 was the year during which C&eacute;dric Klapisch definitely imposed his talent in the landscape of French cinema thanks to two feature movies: "un air de famille" and "chacun cherche son chat". The ones who have been enthralled by these two flicks won't contradict me. Written day-to-day on account of the evolution of the story, shot with a shoestring budget, acted by only 2 or 3 professional comedians and virtually non-professional actors, "chacun cherche son chat" confirms all the hopes placed in Klapisch. One thing I noticed with him is that he has the gift to entitle his movies with catchy and funny titles (which can only be understood by French-speaking people; here "chacun cherche son chat" was translated abroad by :"when the cat's away" whereas the original title in French is "everyone's looking for his/her cat"). "Chacun cherche son chat" clearly obeys to this trend. The main character is a teenage girl, Chlo&eacute; who's looking for her cat in a popular neighborhood in Paris. We find again in this film, a few themes and features peculiar to Klapisch which he will develop and improve in his future movies like the initiatory voyage "l'auberge Espagnole" (2002). About it, for Klapisch the loss of Chlo&eacute;'s cat "Grisgris" mainly serves as a pretext to confront her heroin with the exterior world, in the street. She will gradually leave her naive and egocentric world to get interested in the people who surround her and to strike up friendships with several people. In a way, the director tries to communicate us a nearly identical message to the one in "Groundhog Day" (1993): you have to open yourselves to others which enables to see the world under another (and better) angle. Then, I previously mentioned Klapisch's features. I won't linger on them. I will just say that two of them shine. The director knows how to associate an ironic and tender look in the portrait of his characters and he seems very close to them. In another hand, he just has to proceed by little touches to make a situation intense (I think of the moment when Chlo&eacute; meets Michel's latest lover). But if there's a more admirable thing in Klapisch's opus, it's the directing of actors. Each one of them is perfectly used. Garence Clavel is a real revelation whereas some of her partners see their talent evolving (Zinedine Soualem and Romain Duris, two actors from Klapisch's gang). And this dear Mrs Ren&eacute;e! Very far from the commonplaces and stereotypes commonly attributed to old people, she's also the opposite of Etienne Chatiliez's "tatie Danielle". The director also grants a great attention to the non-professional actors, even to those who have a minor role. Most of them appear for a few minutes on the screen but their presences remain in the memories. Moreover, the solidarity which strongly links its inhabitants (no matter their age) clashes with the place of the action and the dramatic changes which occur in it: a dying popular neighborhood. We can often see in the film, shots of buildings razed or half razed to the ground. "Chacun cherche son chat" is beneficial cinema like we would like to watch it more often and this one, "Le p&eacute;ril jeune" (1994), "un air de famille" and "l'auberge Espagnole" can secure Klapisch's place in the limited circle of the greatest French film-makers of these last years. And by the way, thank you Mr Klapisch for making movies that make me happy.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An interesting, arty exploration of the search to find oneself in the midst of the rapidly changing modern day Paris
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mars_to_marla
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/12/2004
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This was a thoroughly enjoyable film, with a very interesting use of editing in parts... The film's main character, Chloe, lives with her gay flatmate, Michel, has few friends, and definitely no love life to speak of. She works as a make up artist, a job which she hates. One day, Chloe goes away on holiday, and leaves her cat with the local cat lady, Mme Renoir. Upon returning home, Chloe's cat, Gris-Gris, has disappeared. So starts a search for Gris-Gris that the whole neighbourhood is involved in. We are taken on a journey through a district of Paris quite distinct from any glamorised Hollywood image you'll ever see. This is the real, working, living Paris, with real people living in it, and this particular area is in a phase of 'urban development', with a lot of the traditional, working class aspects of the community being pushed aside to make way for the progress of bourgeois trends. We meet a whole host of this area's inhabitants along the way, each with their own eccentricities and foibles; characters that soon become part of Chloe's life. The disappearance of the cat instigates Chloe's search into her own life, to fill the gaps that are missing. This film centres around the hopes and desires of one character in particular (Chloe), but the backdrop is a vessel for expressing changes that are affecting real people in Paris. An interesting, arty approach to a film about the search to find oneself, and come to terms with an ever changing world that one may feel at odds with.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Cat's Pajamas
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    writers_reign
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/1/2004
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    If it's true that Kaplishe's best film remains 'un air de famille', where all he had to do was join the dots of Agnes Jaoui's and Jean-Pierre Bacri's peerless screenplay, he does also have a quirkiness all his own which comes out in 'Little Nothings' and in this entry. I don't know what school these translators go to to learn how to screw up titles - one recent gem was 'The Girl From Paris' from the French, One Swallow Does Not Make A Summer. Weird. Kaplishe's own 'L'Auberge Espanol' underwent a similar bizarre translation which I asked him about personally and he was just as baffled as the rest of us. Chacun cherche son chat translates as Each searches for his own cat, with cat, of course, being a metaphor for happiness, and so it is here. Chloe is really looking for Mr Right but a missing cat is a convenient metaphor. As in other Kaplish entries we get the whole nine yards in terms of off-the-wall characters and the whole schmeer is set against the transformations taking place around North-East Paris between Bastille and Nation. Not a lot happens and it happens all at once. A charmer. 8/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Gris Gris rules!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jbels
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/7/2003
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    When the woman tries to take a vacation and leaves her beloved cat Gris Gris with an old neighbor, the cat gets lost and all heck breaks loose in France. Funny movie shows the love that humans have for their pets and the importance they play in our lives. Also, one of the funniest endings I have ever seen!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A wonderful simple movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    comiis8
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/12/2002
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is a very well done movie. The ending seems a little unfair, but such is life. Too bad this is not on DVD, a good one to own.. A cat is lost and a whole group of people are searching for it. We go thru each one's life as it all comes together at the very end..
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    So tired of being alone
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    boris (boris_peeters@hotmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/9/2002
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The superb Al Green moaning one of his greatest songs : I'm so tired of being alone. That about sums it up. Klapish is quickly becoming one of my favourite directors, making great movies with small budgets like l'auberge espanol. I don't fall in love with actresses every time I see a movie but Garance Clavel will certainly haunt my daydreams for a few days... Credits to the other actors, especially Zinedine Soualem and Ren&eacute;e le Calm. This is a warm, sparkling and very true movie about real persons and real emotions, (and therefore) sometimes funny, sometimes tragic. A movie that makes one run out the door and ...
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    French cinema still has bite...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Jonah (SixofSwords)
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/7/2002
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    What starts out initially as a rather dull drama, quickly picks up pace and sparkles. A lovely little movie that hopefully will never be given a Hollywood remake this movie is a treat.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
 </reviews>
</filme>
