<filme>
 <id>
  260
 </id>
 <imdburl>
  http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0119081
 </imdburl>
 <ano>
  1997
 </ano>
 <titulo>
  O Enigma do Horizonte
 </titulo>
 <rating>
  6.6
 </rating>
 <sinopse>
  A rescue crew investigates a spaceship that disappeared into a black hole and has now returned...with someone or something new on-board.
 </sinopse>
 <storyline>
  In the year 2047 a group of astronauts are sent to investigate and salvage the long lost starship "Event Horizon". The ship disappeared mysteriously 7 years before on its maiden voyage and with its return comes even more mystery as the crew of the "Lewis and Clark" discover the real truth behind its disappearance and something even more terrifying.
 </storyline>
 <generos>
  <genero>
   Horror
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Sci-Fi
  </genero>
 </generos>
 <keywords>
  <keyword>
   black hole
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   madness
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   mother son relationship
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   box office flop
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   reverse footage
  </keyword>
 </keywords>
 <diretores>
  <diretor>
   Paul W.S. Anderson
  </diretor>
 </diretores>
 <escritores>
  <escritor>
   Philip Eisner
  </escritor>
 </escritores>
 <atores>
  <ator>
   Laurence Fishburne
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Sam Neill
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Kathleen Quinlan
  </ator>
 </atores>
 <reviews>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    a waste of space-time
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Sven Jolly
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Another dump of cinematic excrement, this drivel is a disjointed mish mash of several other, greatly superior sci-fi movies, cribbed together in a random fashion to achieve nothing but boredom in the hapless viewer. One part Alien, one part Apollo 13, a "rotating magnetic field" gizmo that looks suspiciously like "Contact" this movie meanders all over the place. The story is stupid, with time travel, hallucinations, time/space monsters - it's as if they just tossed everything they could think of in a cut-up process to derive some semblance of a story line. Every character is pure stereotype, the dialogue is inane, seemingly composed by a group of high school boys, or perhaps one thousand monkey's typing randomly. After one hour of viewing you will have no idea what is going on, and neither do the characters or the writers. I couldn't finish watching this rubbish, one hour was all I could stand. MINUS -10 out of 10 for wasting my time. Strongly suggest you don't waste yours.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Creepy at times.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Scott LeBrun (Hey_Sweden)
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Right from the beginning, it may be clear that "Event Horizon" owes a pretty big debt to "Alien" (but then, so do many other post-1979 films) but it does have a fairly interesting story and it does live up to the word "horror". It gets substantially unnerving and creates some wonderfully horrific imagery. In fact, as films of this type go, it's a pleasure in terms of the visuals - special effects, sets, cinematography. Devotees of these genres should find it to be solid if not exceptional entertainment. They may find the "science" ludicrous, but still be amused. In the year 2047, an exploratory spaceship, the "Event Horizon" of the title, has reappeared after having been lost for seven years. A U.S.A.C. team is launched to find out what happened, and rescue any possible survivors. They do this in the company of the ships' designer, William Weir (Sam Neill), who has a tragedy in his past, and members of the team bring their own baggage to the situation, with no-nonsense Captain Miller (Laurence Fishburne) in charge of the mission. What they learn is that the ship now seems to be "alive", and aware of what has happened in the teams' pasts. The script by Philip Eisner is not without humour, but it mostly plays things straight, and the cast performs it with real gravity. Fishburne is good as a rock-solid type of man, while Neill gets a chance to tear into the scenery as Weir becomes more and more deranged. Kathleen Quinlan is affecting as Peters, who is having to deal with child custody issues in her personal life. Joely Richardson is good as efficient team member Starck, and Richard T. Jones, Jack Noseworthy, Jason Isaacs, and Sean Pertwee round out the cast. Things get off to a nice start with Paramount putting a fun spin on their standard logo sequence, and director Paul Anderson guides everything with style. "Event Horizon" may be derivative in some ways, but it moves along well and is never dull. Seven out of 10.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The ship's name held promise but the film fell short
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    A.N.
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I watched this after reading a Stephen Hawking book in which "event horizon" was described in terms of general relativity and black hole physics. But the hammering soundtrack in the opening credits warned me that this film probably wouldn't rise to the elegance of that concept. It had too many standard plot devices and was never really scary to me. Here are some issues, starting with most annoying first: 1) You'd think that an advanced spaceship crew would be educated like today's astronauts, not blue collar types easily bored by the scientist's explanation of a "singularity" and other aspects of black hole travel. They'd send the best of the best on such a critical mission, not jive talkers and impatient drones. "Say it in plain English!" is ridiculously overused in movies and insults an intelligent audience. A real crew of that caliber would understand black holes well beyond his folded paper demo. I know it was done for the audience's sake, but still. 2) The steam-punk gravity drive and the general interior of the ship seemed deliberately designed to convey malice, not functionality. It's almost as if the ship was built as a haunted house. Why all the spikes in the doors that humans pass through? OSHA wouldn't allow such a ship to be built. The gravity drive seemed more like a medieval torture device than something modern engineering would come up with. I suppose all the spikes could be related to magnetism but it wasn't explained. 3) The blood in the ship's structure had no scientific context. It played like a ripoff of "The Shining." This movie was too big on "fi" and too small on "sci." They should have toned down the gore. 4) Technical aspects, like the guy in the airlock spewing that much blood and living, or the astronaut being propelled back toward the planet with his breathing pack seemed ludicrous. The electronics damage to the rescue ship seemed impossible to fix. It needed a lot more than skin patches. Why do so many movies show sparks flying from sophisticated instruments which are miraculously repaired in hours? 5) The premise that we'd already colonized the Moon by 2015 was ridiculously optimistic, even in 1997. Still, it kept me entertained enough to see it through, so I gave it a neutral 5. I'd recommend "Solaris" (2002) for a much better depiction of mentally conjured people, etc. The elements of that in "Event Horizon" were done in sledgehammer style, though the eyeless wife did give me a jolt.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Repulsive movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    verna-a
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    You'll hate yourself for watching this and hate what the producers/directors of this film did to decent actors. I like sci-fi films and was attracted to the story outline. Unfortunately it soon became evident no-one had any faith in the power of storytelling and characterization to engage the audience. Instead they had to exaggerate every interaction between members of the crew to be as abrasive as possible, and introduce every cheesy and over-the-top horror film trick they could think of to progress the film. I nearly wrote "to maintain interest" but in fact it's a big turn off and you soon regard the whole affair with total contempt. Here's an example of the wit and character development in the film: black male crew member to female crew member while offering a cup of coffee "How'd you like something hot and black inside you?" (leers). Just when you think it can't get any worse with exaggerated gory special effects, it does. I see some people like this film, honestly I shudder to imagine the sort of person that would. It's quite repulsive, and the only reason I'm giving it a 2 is that I did watch it to the end to see who they could extricate from the general mayhem. I think I caught a line of dialogue "In this situation, some self-control is an advantage". Are they kidding! I hope the people responsible for this film have found employment in some other industry.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not impressed
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    (mikedennett-664-275394)
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie was far weaker than I expected. It is full of tired stereotypical character profiles (the gruff captain, the odd doctor, the yucking-it-up Chris Rock/Eddie Murphy wanna-be, the eccentric scientist who speaks in mysterious scientific mumbo-jumbo, the hardened let's-get- the-heck-out-of-here pilot, etc ad nauseum), weak acting, and an endless series of predictable disasters. I did not find it clever, inspiring, or original. Even the CGI was weak in many spots. The average rating surprises the heck out of me, are people's standards really that low? There were a few surprises, but you can make people jump out of their seats with an orchestra hit even if the screen shows a kitten licking its paw. I tend to automatically lower my expectations anytime a move starts with a teletype history line leading up to the opening scenes.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of two films i rarely watch because they are just to good
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Ark 7754
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Don't be perplexed by my summary.. This film and the ring are truly great horrors. I literally go to bed after a bit unnerved. This is probably my all time favourite horror. The shining is disturbing but i can watch it,I've watched it 5 times i think..event horizon i have watched twice. once when i was young,the second with my wife because she needed to watch it at my request lol Needless to say she caked it as well. just watch the film..yeah okay like some reviews some of its predictable..but the majority isn't and its pretty damn scary. When the scene with the footage arrives is when you know bad times ahead lol..thats not a spoiler you'll know what i mean yeah but regardless..stop reading this..go watch it
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Dark and Rather Brave Film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Michael_Elliott
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Event Horizon (1997) *** (out of 4) Dark and sometimes disturbing mix of sci-fi and horror about the spaceship Event Horizon, which went missing shortly after its mission. Seven years later it reemerges so a rescue crew goes after it trying to figure out where it's been the entire time. I saw EVENT HORIZON when it was first released and really couldn't understand why it gained so many negative reviews. There's no question that the film contains some flaws but it's also a rather ambitious film that relies just as much on its story than just the special effects. I thought director Paul Anderson did a fantastic job early on really making the viewer feel uneasy. There's a brief line where a crew member talks about how far they are from safety and this scene perfectly builds up a rather dark tension because you realize that these people really are on their own with no one to help them. The entire atmosphere of the film is incredibly dark and while I'm not going to give anything away, what the story attempts to do with where the ship has gone was rather unique and I think that for the most part it works. Now, if you've ever heard of this film then you know about the various issues it ran into during the test screenings. There's been talk of a director's cut, which I think might help out many of the flaws. The story takes us to a rather dark direction but it just seems as if something is missing. There are a few questions that need to be answered and there are a few things that don't make much sense but perhaps these were forced to be left on the cutting room floor. If so, hopefully we can see the complete version at some point. Another thing that works here are the extremely strong performances with Laurence Fishburne, Sam Neill, Kathleen Quinlan and Joely Richardson delivering great work. The special effects are also another major plus including an incredibly beautiful opening sequence as well as the effects really making you feel as if you're in space the entire time. Some have been critical of some of the graphic and bloody violence but I thought it actually played well into the story and didn't take away from anything. As it stands, EVENT HORIZON is a rather brave but flawed film but hopefully a complete version will give us a better look at what it was really trying to do.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Fun sci fi, not real scary
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ahorn88
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Just watched this movie as per the suggestion of this post. What I expected? Shocking, gory imagery. Mind bending, unsettling theories of what could be possible in this world over the next 100 years. What The movie delivered? A middling sci-fi thriller with a pretty great cast; not particularly scary. The premise is great - the human race, "flying too close to the sun," rips a hole in the fabric of space time, opening a portal to a chaotic, evil dimension. The spacecraft itself is transformed into an evil being, devouring any well-intentioned rescue crew that happens to cross its path. This is one of those movies that on paper and in my head seem incredible - limitless potential - but unfortunately the execution just did not match up. The hype I had built up based on comments people had made and a review or two that I had read prior to viewing made me expect a mind f*** to compete with other creepy sci fi flicks like The Cube or The Cell crossed with the horror and gore of Candyman. At the end of the day, I recommend checking out Event Horizon as a fun sci-fi movie that requires a bit of imagination and the suspension of disbelief thanks to the mid 90's special effects. Expect a 5/10, discover an 8/10. And that's my 2 cents.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The most frightening,effective and disturbing horror movie I have ever seen
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    yasenkiranov
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I had extremely low expectations for "Event Horizon".The film was made in a period where a lot of filmmakers thought that when you have enough money to use and abuse CGI your movie doesn't need a decent script.With that in mind I thought "Event Horizon" was going to be a clich&eacute; horror film that makes no effort to build suspense and just throws CG blood and gore in your face.I was wrong.Dead wrong. "Event Horizon" is the creepiest and most suspenseful horror movie I have ever seen.It manages to create a feeling of dread and foreboding like no other film I have ever seen before.This is due to a combination of great camera-work,appropriate music and(believe it or not) CG.Yes,the CGI is actually used appropriately here,not just added for the sake of it being there.That said,the special effects are top-notch(for 1997). Another thing I liked was that the ship itself wasn't the main threat.It was the characters.They become obsessed with their past mistakes(things they had locked away in their minds and didn't want to remember) and that begins to drive them insane.True,the ship is the catalyst for this,but the focus is more on the characters themselves.This reminds me of "Cube"-one of my favorite movies. The characters themselves are a bit underdeveloped,but they aren't cannon fodder like in many other horror films.Each of them has their the distinct personality and background information is given about some of them.I think this was alright for the purpose of this film.In my opinion ,if they did add more character development it would have ruined the pacing. "Event Horizon" is a very well made,but sadly underrated, horror movie.I strongly recommend it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I wasn't amazed by this movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jklimentowski
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A horror science-fiction movie. When I think of this genre I always have "Alien" on my mind. I think this is a perfect example. Unfortunately "Event Horizon" lacks both in the horror and science-fiction parts. As for the science fiction - well it is just not realistic enough. Of course not all movies should be as realistic as "2010: Space Odyssey", but still when you compare it to "Alien" it turns out quite poor. Actually there is not much realism or physics in it at all. OK - the idea of time-space folding is nice, but the idea itself is at least as old as The Dune movie, or perhaps even older. I liked the scene of transition from zero gravity to artificial-earth gravity with fluids and bodies instantly dropping. The decompression sequence tries to be more horror like than scientific... and that is all I think. The rest is just pure fantasy. So forget about science-fiction - is it a good horror? This might be a difficult question for me as most horrors make me laugh rather than scare mostly due to their stupidity and lack of realism. There are of course exceptions like Alien or The Thing. What makes the difference? I think it is the realism of the situation. I really can't be scared by ghosts which can do anything. It is just too unreal - I can not place myself in such a world and my imagination fails. Unfortunately Event Horizon is a movie it this ghost type. Anything can happen therefore I do not feel like one of the terrified crew members, rather I wonder what could the director think of next. Of course there are some more or less scary moments, but these are just typical horror tricks - sudden action with a proper sound effect. There is no feel of terror while watching the movie. Another thing at which the movie fails is the plot. While the beginning sequences are quite interesting with every minute the plot becomes more and more chaotic. At some stage one really gets bored as it seems that there is no real goal or solution of the plot. One by one some things happen which try to scare you, but there is no logic in them. I can imagine that such a movie could last for a long time with random scary adventures happening to the characters until all of them are dead. But what is the point of watching that? Unfortunately the ending is also quite predictable and gives you no satisfaction of discovering something interesting or an unexpected solution. It is just as plain as that. OK - so is the movie really so bad? Well it is not a perfect movie, but not a terrible one either. One can watch it and have some fun but it is not a movie that you would like to come back to after years. Just see once, have fun and forget. It is worth to mention that the move has it's own style. While placed in future all the ships and equipment sometimes look like designed in the past. I can't describe it exactly but sometimes I had a feel of watching a sci-fiction movie from the fifties. Why did the director decide to chose such a scenography instead of pure futuristic one? No idea but I think it works fine.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    a waste of space-time
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Sven Jolly
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Another dump of cinematic excrement, this drivel is a disjointed mish mash of several other, greatly superior sci-fi movies, cribbed together in a random fashion to achieve nothing but boredom in the hapless viewer. One part Alien, one part Apollo 13, a "rotating magnetic field" gizmo that looks suspiciously like "Contact" this movie meanders all over the place. The story is stupid, with time travel, hallucinations, time/space monsters - it's as if they just tossed everything they could think of in a cut-up process to derive some semblance of a story line. Every character is pure stereotype, the dialogue is inane, seemingly composed by a group of high school boys, or perhaps one thousand monkey's typing randomly. After one hour of viewing you will have no idea what is going on, and neither do the characters or the writers. I couldn't finish watching this rubbish, one hour was all I could stand. MINUS -10 out of 10 for wasting my time. Strongly suggest you don't waste yours.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Creepy at times.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Scott LeBrun (Hey_Sweden)
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Right from the beginning, it may be clear that "Event Horizon" owes a pretty big debt to "Alien" (but then, so do many other post-1979 films) but it does have a fairly interesting story and it does live up to the word "horror". It gets substantially unnerving and creates some wonderfully horrific imagery. In fact, as films of this type go, it's a pleasure in terms of the visuals - special effects, sets, cinematography. Devotees of these genres should find it to be solid if not exceptional entertainment. They may find the "science" ludicrous, but still be amused. In the year 2047, an exploratory spaceship, the "Event Horizon" of the title, has reappeared after having been lost for seven years. A U.S.A.C. team is launched to find out what happened, and rescue any possible survivors. They do this in the company of the ships' designer, William Weir (Sam Neill), who has a tragedy in his past, and members of the team bring their own baggage to the situation, with no-nonsense Captain Miller (Laurence Fishburne) in charge of the mission. What they learn is that the ship now seems to be "alive", and aware of what has happened in the teams' pasts. The script by Philip Eisner is not without humour, but it mostly plays things straight, and the cast performs it with real gravity. Fishburne is good as a rock-solid type of man, while Neill gets a chance to tear into the scenery as Weir becomes more and more deranged. Kathleen Quinlan is affecting as Peters, who is having to deal with child custody issues in her personal life. Joely Richardson is good as efficient team member Starck, and Richard T. Jones, Jack Noseworthy, Jason Isaacs, and Sean Pertwee round out the cast. Things get off to a nice start with Paramount putting a fun spin on their standard logo sequence, and director Paul Anderson guides everything with style. "Event Horizon" may be derivative in some ways, but it moves along well and is never dull. Seven out of 10.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The ship's name held promise but the film fell short
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    A.N.
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I watched this after reading a Stephen Hawking book in which "event horizon" was described in terms of general relativity and black hole physics. But the hammering soundtrack in the opening credits warned me that this film probably wouldn't rise to the elegance of that concept. It had too many standard plot devices and was never really scary to me. Here are some issues, starting with most annoying first: 1) You'd think that an advanced spaceship crew would be educated like today's astronauts, not blue collar types easily bored by the scientist's explanation of a "singularity" and other aspects of black hole travel. They'd send the best of the best on such a critical mission, not jive talkers and impatient drones. "Say it in plain English!" is ridiculously overused in movies and insults an intelligent audience. A real crew of that caliber would understand black holes well beyond his folded paper demo. I know it was done for the audience's sake, but still. 2) The steam-punk gravity drive and the general interior of the ship seemed deliberately designed to convey malice, not functionality. It's almost as if the ship was built as a haunted house. Why all the spikes in the doors that humans pass through? OSHA wouldn't allow such a ship to be built. The gravity drive seemed more like a medieval torture device than something modern engineering would come up with. I suppose all the spikes could be related to magnetism but it wasn't explained. 3) The blood in the ship's structure had no scientific context. It played like a ripoff of "The Shining." This movie was too big on "fi" and too small on "sci." They should have toned down the gore. 4) Technical aspects, like the guy in the airlock spewing that much blood and living, or the astronaut being propelled back toward the planet with his breathing pack seemed ludicrous. The electronics damage to the rescue ship seemed impossible to fix. It needed a lot more than skin patches. Why do so many movies show sparks flying from sophisticated instruments which are miraculously repaired in hours? 5) The premise that we'd already colonized the Moon by 2015 was ridiculously optimistic, even in 1997. Still, it kept me entertained enough to see it through, so I gave it a neutral 5. I'd recommend "Solaris" (2002) for a much better depiction of mentally conjured people, etc. The elements of that in "Event Horizon" were done in sledgehammer style, though the eyeless wife did give me a jolt.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Repulsive movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    verna-a
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    You'll hate yourself for watching this and hate what the producers/directors of this film did to decent actors. I like sci-fi films and was attracted to the story outline. Unfortunately it soon became evident no-one had any faith in the power of storytelling and characterization to engage the audience. Instead they had to exaggerate every interaction between members of the crew to be as abrasive as possible, and introduce every cheesy and over-the-top horror film trick they could think of to progress the film. I nearly wrote "to maintain interest" but in fact it's a big turn off and you soon regard the whole affair with total contempt. Here's an example of the wit and character development in the film: black male crew member to female crew member while offering a cup of coffee "How'd you like something hot and black inside you?" (leers). Just when you think it can't get any worse with exaggerated gory special effects, it does. I see some people like this film, honestly I shudder to imagine the sort of person that would. It's quite repulsive, and the only reason I'm giving it a 2 is that I did watch it to the end to see who they could extricate from the general mayhem. I think I caught a line of dialogue "In this situation, some self-control is an advantage". Are they kidding! I hope the people responsible for this film have found employment in some other industry.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not impressed
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    (mikedennett-664-275394)
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie was far weaker than I expected. It is full of tired stereotypical character profiles (the gruff captain, the odd doctor, the yucking-it-up Chris Rock/Eddie Murphy wanna-be, the eccentric scientist who speaks in mysterious scientific mumbo-jumbo, the hardened let's-get- the-heck-out-of-here pilot, etc ad nauseum), weak acting, and an endless series of predictable disasters. I did not find it clever, inspiring, or original. Even the CGI was weak in many spots. The average rating surprises the heck out of me, are people's standards really that low? There were a few surprises, but you can make people jump out of their seats with an orchestra hit even if the screen shows a kitten licking its paw. I tend to automatically lower my expectations anytime a move starts with a teletype history line leading up to the opening scenes.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of two films i rarely watch because they are just to good
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Ark 7754
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Don't be perplexed by my summary.. This film and the ring are truly great horrors. I literally go to bed after a bit unnerved. This is probably my all time favourite horror. The shining is disturbing but i can watch it,I've watched it 5 times i think..event horizon i have watched twice. once when i was young,the second with my wife because she needed to watch it at my request lol Needless to say she caked it as well. just watch the film..yeah okay like some reviews some of its predictable..but the majority isn't and its pretty damn scary. When the scene with the footage arrives is when you know bad times ahead lol..thats not a spoiler you'll know what i mean yeah but regardless..stop reading this..go watch it
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Dark and Rather Brave Film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Michael_Elliott
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Event Horizon (1997) *** (out of 4) Dark and sometimes disturbing mix of sci-fi and horror about the spaceship Event Horizon, which went missing shortly after its mission. Seven years later it reemerges so a rescue crew goes after it trying to figure out where it's been the entire time. I saw EVENT HORIZON when it was first released and really couldn't understand why it gained so many negative reviews. There's no question that the film contains some flaws but it's also a rather ambitious film that relies just as much on its story than just the special effects. I thought director Paul Anderson did a fantastic job early on really making the viewer feel uneasy. There's a brief line where a crew member talks about how far they are from safety and this scene perfectly builds up a rather dark tension because you realize that these people really are on their own with no one to help them. The entire atmosphere of the film is incredibly dark and while I'm not going to give anything away, what the story attempts to do with where the ship has gone was rather unique and I think that for the most part it works. Now, if you've ever heard of this film then you know about the various issues it ran into during the test screenings. There's been talk of a director's cut, which I think might help out many of the flaws. The story takes us to a rather dark direction but it just seems as if something is missing. There are a few questions that need to be answered and there are a few things that don't make much sense but perhaps these were forced to be left on the cutting room floor. If so, hopefully we can see the complete version at some point. Another thing that works here are the extremely strong performances with Laurence Fishburne, Sam Neill, Kathleen Quinlan and Joely Richardson delivering great work. The special effects are also another major plus including an incredibly beautiful opening sequence as well as the effects really making you feel as if you're in space the entire time. Some have been critical of some of the graphic and bloody violence but I thought it actually played well into the story and didn't take away from anything. As it stands, EVENT HORIZON is a rather brave but flawed film but hopefully a complete version will give us a better look at what it was really trying to do.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Fun sci fi, not real scary
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ahorn88
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Just watched this movie as per the suggestion of this post. What I expected? Shocking, gory imagery. Mind bending, unsettling theories of what could be possible in this world over the next 100 years. What The movie delivered? A middling sci-fi thriller with a pretty great cast; not particularly scary. The premise is great - the human race, "flying too close to the sun," rips a hole in the fabric of space time, opening a portal to a chaotic, evil dimension. The spacecraft itself is transformed into an evil being, devouring any well-intentioned rescue crew that happens to cross its path. This is one of those movies that on paper and in my head seem incredible - limitless potential - but unfortunately the execution just did not match up. The hype I had built up based on comments people had made and a review or two that I had read prior to viewing made me expect a mind f*** to compete with other creepy sci fi flicks like The Cube or The Cell crossed with the horror and gore of Candyman. At the end of the day, I recommend checking out Event Horizon as a fun sci-fi movie that requires a bit of imagination and the suspension of disbelief thanks to the mid 90's special effects. Expect a 5/10, discover an 8/10. And that's my 2 cents.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The most frightening,effective and disturbing horror movie I have ever seen
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    yasenkiranov
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I had extremely low expectations for "Event Horizon".The film was made in a period where a lot of filmmakers thought that when you have enough money to use and abuse CGI your movie doesn't need a decent script.With that in mind I thought "Event Horizon" was going to be a clich&eacute; horror film that makes no effort to build suspense and just throws CG blood and gore in your face.I was wrong.Dead wrong. "Event Horizon" is the creepiest and most suspenseful horror movie I have ever seen.It manages to create a feeling of dread and foreboding like no other film I have ever seen before.This is due to a combination of great camera-work,appropriate music and(believe it or not) CG.Yes,the CGI is actually used appropriately here,not just added for the sake of it being there.That said,the special effects are top-notch(for 1997). Another thing I liked was that the ship itself wasn't the main threat.It was the characters.They become obsessed with their past mistakes(things they had locked away in their minds and didn't want to remember) and that begins to drive them insane.True,the ship is the catalyst for this,but the focus is more on the characters themselves.This reminds me of "Cube"-one of my favorite movies. The characters themselves are a bit underdeveloped,but they aren't cannon fodder like in many other horror films.Each of them has their the distinct personality and background information is given about some of them.I think this was alright for the purpose of this film.In my opinion ,if they did add more character development it would have ruined the pacing. "Event Horizon" is a very well made,but sadly underrated, horror movie.I strongly recommend it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I wasn't amazed by this movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jklimentowski
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A horror science-fiction movie. When I think of this genre I always have "Alien" on my mind. I think this is a perfect example. Unfortunately "Event Horizon" lacks both in the horror and science-fiction parts. As for the science fiction - well it is just not realistic enough. Of course not all movies should be as realistic as "2010: Space Odyssey", but still when you compare it to "Alien" it turns out quite poor. Actually there is not much realism or physics in it at all. OK - the idea of time-space folding is nice, but the idea itself is at least as old as The Dune movie, or perhaps even older. I liked the scene of transition from zero gravity to artificial-earth gravity with fluids and bodies instantly dropping. The decompression sequence tries to be more horror like than scientific... and that is all I think. The rest is just pure fantasy. So forget about science-fiction - is it a good horror? This might be a difficult question for me as most horrors make me laugh rather than scare mostly due to their stupidity and lack of realism. There are of course exceptions like Alien or The Thing. What makes the difference? I think it is the realism of the situation. I really can't be scared by ghosts which can do anything. It is just too unreal - I can not place myself in such a world and my imagination fails. Unfortunately Event Horizon is a movie it this ghost type. Anything can happen therefore I do not feel like one of the terrified crew members, rather I wonder what could the director think of next. Of course there are some more or less scary moments, but these are just typical horror tricks - sudden action with a proper sound effect. There is no feel of terror while watching the movie. Another thing at which the movie fails is the plot. While the beginning sequences are quite interesting with every minute the plot becomes more and more chaotic. At some stage one really gets bored as it seems that there is no real goal or solution of the plot. One by one some things happen which try to scare you, but there is no logic in them. I can imagine that such a movie could last for a long time with random scary adventures happening to the characters until all of them are dead. But what is the point of watching that? Unfortunately the ending is also quite predictable and gives you no satisfaction of discovering something interesting or an unexpected solution. It is just as plain as that. OK - so is the movie really so bad? Well it is not a perfect movie, but not a terrible one either. One can watch it and have some fun but it is not a movie that you would like to come back to after years. Just see once, have fun and forget. It is worth to mention that the move has it's own style. While placed in future all the ships and equipment sometimes look like designed in the past. I can't describe it exactly but sometimes I had a feel of watching a sci-fiction movie from the fifties. Why did the director decide to chose such a scenography instead of pure futuristic one? No idea but I think it works fine.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    a waste of space-time
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Sven Jolly
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Another dump of cinematic excrement, this drivel is a disjointed mish mash of several other, greatly superior sci-fi movies, cribbed together in a random fashion to achieve nothing but boredom in the hapless viewer. One part Alien, one part Apollo 13, a "rotating magnetic field" gizmo that looks suspiciously like "Contact" this movie meanders all over the place. The story is stupid, with time travel, hallucinations, time/space monsters - it's as if they just tossed everything they could think of in a cut-up process to derive some semblance of a story line. Every character is pure stereotype, the dialogue is inane, seemingly composed by a group of high school boys, or perhaps one thousand monkey's typing randomly. After one hour of viewing you will have no idea what is going on, and neither do the characters or the writers. I couldn't finish watching this rubbish, one hour was all I could stand. MINUS -10 out of 10 for wasting my time. Strongly suggest you don't waste yours.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Creepy at times.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Scott LeBrun (Hey_Sweden)
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Right from the beginning, it may be clear that "Event Horizon" owes a pretty big debt to "Alien" (but then, so do many other post-1979 films) but it does have a fairly interesting story and it does live up to the word "horror". It gets substantially unnerving and creates some wonderfully horrific imagery. In fact, as films of this type go, it's a pleasure in terms of the visuals - special effects, sets, cinematography. Devotees of these genres should find it to be solid if not exceptional entertainment. They may find the "science" ludicrous, but still be amused. In the year 2047, an exploratory spaceship, the "Event Horizon" of the title, has reappeared after having been lost for seven years. A U.S.A.C. team is launched to find out what happened, and rescue any possible survivors. They do this in the company of the ships' designer, William Weir (Sam Neill), who has a tragedy in his past, and members of the team bring their own baggage to the situation, with no-nonsense Captain Miller (Laurence Fishburne) in charge of the mission. What they learn is that the ship now seems to be "alive", and aware of what has happened in the teams' pasts. The script by Philip Eisner is not without humour, but it mostly plays things straight, and the cast performs it with real gravity. Fishburne is good as a rock-solid type of man, while Neill gets a chance to tear into the scenery as Weir becomes more and more deranged. Kathleen Quinlan is affecting as Peters, who is having to deal with child custody issues in her personal life. Joely Richardson is good as efficient team member Starck, and Richard T. Jones, Jack Noseworthy, Jason Isaacs, and Sean Pertwee round out the cast. Things get off to a nice start with Paramount putting a fun spin on their standard logo sequence, and director Paul Anderson guides everything with style. "Event Horizon" may be derivative in some ways, but it moves along well and is never dull. Seven out of 10.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The ship's name held promise but the film fell short
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    A.N.
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I watched this after reading a Stephen Hawking book in which "event horizon" was described in terms of general relativity and black hole physics. But the hammering soundtrack in the opening credits warned me that this film probably wouldn't rise to the elegance of that concept. It had too many standard plot devices and was never really scary to me. Here are some issues, starting with most annoying first: 1) You'd think that an advanced spaceship crew would be educated like today's astronauts, not blue collar types easily bored by the scientist's explanation of a "singularity" and other aspects of black hole travel. They'd send the best of the best on such a critical mission, not jive talkers and impatient drones. "Say it in plain English!" is ridiculously overused in movies and insults an intelligent audience. A real crew of that caliber would understand black holes well beyond his folded paper demo. I know it was done for the audience's sake, but still. 2) The steam-punk gravity drive and the general interior of the ship seemed deliberately designed to convey malice, not functionality. It's almost as if the ship was built as a haunted house. Why all the spikes in the doors that humans pass through? OSHA wouldn't allow such a ship to be built. The gravity drive seemed more like a medieval torture device than something modern engineering would come up with. I suppose all the spikes could be related to magnetism but it wasn't explained. 3) The blood in the ship's structure had no scientific context. It played like a ripoff of "The Shining." This movie was too big on "fi" and too small on "sci." They should have toned down the gore. 4) Technical aspects, like the guy in the airlock spewing that much blood and living, or the astronaut being propelled back toward the planet with his breathing pack seemed ludicrous. The electronics damage to the rescue ship seemed impossible to fix. It needed a lot more than skin patches. Why do so many movies show sparks flying from sophisticated instruments which are miraculously repaired in hours? 5) The premise that we'd already colonized the Moon by 2015 was ridiculously optimistic, even in 1997. Still, it kept me entertained enough to see it through, so I gave it a neutral 5. I'd recommend "Solaris" (2002) for a much better depiction of mentally conjured people, etc. The elements of that in "Event Horizon" were done in sledgehammer style, though the eyeless wife did give me a jolt.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Repulsive movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    verna-a
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    You'll hate yourself for watching this and hate what the producers/directors of this film did to decent actors. I like sci-fi films and was attracted to the story outline. Unfortunately it soon became evident no-one had any faith in the power of storytelling and characterization to engage the audience. Instead they had to exaggerate every interaction between members of the crew to be as abrasive as possible, and introduce every cheesy and over-the-top horror film trick they could think of to progress the film. I nearly wrote "to maintain interest" but in fact it's a big turn off and you soon regard the whole affair with total contempt. Here's an example of the wit and character development in the film: black male crew member to female crew member while offering a cup of coffee "How'd you like something hot and black inside you?" (leers). Just when you think it can't get any worse with exaggerated gory special effects, it does. I see some people like this film, honestly I shudder to imagine the sort of person that would. It's quite repulsive, and the only reason I'm giving it a 2 is that I did watch it to the end to see who they could extricate from the general mayhem. I think I caught a line of dialogue "In this situation, some self-control is an advantage". Are they kidding! I hope the people responsible for this film have found employment in some other industry.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not impressed
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    (mikedennett-664-275394)
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie was far weaker than I expected. It is full of tired stereotypical character profiles (the gruff captain, the odd doctor, the yucking-it-up Chris Rock/Eddie Murphy wanna-be, the eccentric scientist who speaks in mysterious scientific mumbo-jumbo, the hardened let's-get- the-heck-out-of-here pilot, etc ad nauseum), weak acting, and an endless series of predictable disasters. I did not find it clever, inspiring, or original. Even the CGI was weak in many spots. The average rating surprises the heck out of me, are people's standards really that low? There were a few surprises, but you can make people jump out of their seats with an orchestra hit even if the screen shows a kitten licking its paw. I tend to automatically lower my expectations anytime a move starts with a teletype history line leading up to the opening scenes.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of two films i rarely watch because they are just to good
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Ark 7754
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Don't be perplexed by my summary.. This film and the ring are truly great horrors. I literally go to bed after a bit unnerved. This is probably my all time favourite horror. The shining is disturbing but i can watch it,I've watched it 5 times i think..event horizon i have watched twice. once when i was young,the second with my wife because she needed to watch it at my request lol Needless to say she caked it as well. just watch the film..yeah okay like some reviews some of its predictable..but the majority isn't and its pretty damn scary. When the scene with the footage arrives is when you know bad times ahead lol..thats not a spoiler you'll know what i mean yeah but regardless..stop reading this..go watch it
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Dark and Rather Brave Film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Michael_Elliott
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Event Horizon (1997) *** (out of 4) Dark and sometimes disturbing mix of sci-fi and horror about the spaceship Event Horizon, which went missing shortly after its mission. Seven years later it reemerges so a rescue crew goes after it trying to figure out where it's been the entire time. I saw EVENT HORIZON when it was first released and really couldn't understand why it gained so many negative reviews. There's no question that the film contains some flaws but it's also a rather ambitious film that relies just as much on its story than just the special effects. I thought director Paul Anderson did a fantastic job early on really making the viewer feel uneasy. There's a brief line where a crew member talks about how far they are from safety and this scene perfectly builds up a rather dark tension because you realize that these people really are on their own with no one to help them. The entire atmosphere of the film is incredibly dark and while I'm not going to give anything away, what the story attempts to do with where the ship has gone was rather unique and I think that for the most part it works. Now, if you've ever heard of this film then you know about the various issues it ran into during the test screenings. There's been talk of a director's cut, which I think might help out many of the flaws. The story takes us to a rather dark direction but it just seems as if something is missing. There are a few questions that need to be answered and there are a few things that don't make much sense but perhaps these were forced to be left on the cutting room floor. If so, hopefully we can see the complete version at some point. Another thing that works here are the extremely strong performances with Laurence Fishburne, Sam Neill, Kathleen Quinlan and Joely Richardson delivering great work. The special effects are also another major plus including an incredibly beautiful opening sequence as well as the effects really making you feel as if you're in space the entire time. Some have been critical of some of the graphic and bloody violence but I thought it actually played well into the story and didn't take away from anything. As it stands, EVENT HORIZON is a rather brave but flawed film but hopefully a complete version will give us a better look at what it was really trying to do.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Fun sci fi, not real scary
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ahorn88
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Just watched this movie as per the suggestion of this post. What I expected? Shocking, gory imagery. Mind bending, unsettling theories of what could be possible in this world over the next 100 years. What The movie delivered? A middling sci-fi thriller with a pretty great cast; not particularly scary. The premise is great - the human race, "flying too close to the sun," rips a hole in the fabric of space time, opening a portal to a chaotic, evil dimension. The spacecraft itself is transformed into an evil being, devouring any well-intentioned rescue crew that happens to cross its path. This is one of those movies that on paper and in my head seem incredible - limitless potential - but unfortunately the execution just did not match up. The hype I had built up based on comments people had made and a review or two that I had read prior to viewing made me expect a mind f*** to compete with other creepy sci fi flicks like The Cube or The Cell crossed with the horror and gore of Candyman. At the end of the day, I recommend checking out Event Horizon as a fun sci-fi movie that requires a bit of imagination and the suspension of disbelief thanks to the mid 90's special effects. Expect a 5/10, discover an 8/10. And that's my 2 cents.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The most frightening,effective and disturbing horror movie I have ever seen
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    yasenkiranov
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I had extremely low expectations for "Event Horizon".The film was made in a period where a lot of filmmakers thought that when you have enough money to use and abuse CGI your movie doesn't need a decent script.With that in mind I thought "Event Horizon" was going to be a clich&eacute; horror film that makes no effort to build suspense and just throws CG blood and gore in your face.I was wrong.Dead wrong. "Event Horizon" is the creepiest and most suspenseful horror movie I have ever seen.It manages to create a feeling of dread and foreboding like no other film I have ever seen before.This is due to a combination of great camera-work,appropriate music and(believe it or not) CG.Yes,the CGI is actually used appropriately here,not just added for the sake of it being there.That said,the special effects are top-notch(for 1997). Another thing I liked was that the ship itself wasn't the main threat.It was the characters.They become obsessed with their past mistakes(things they had locked away in their minds and didn't want to remember) and that begins to drive them insane.True,the ship is the catalyst for this,but the focus is more on the characters themselves.This reminds me of "Cube"-one of my favorite movies. The characters themselves are a bit underdeveloped,but they aren't cannon fodder like in many other horror films.Each of them has their the distinct personality and background information is given about some of them.I think this was alright for the purpose of this film.In my opinion ,if they did add more character development it would have ruined the pacing. "Event Horizon" is a very well made,but sadly underrated, horror movie.I strongly recommend it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I wasn't amazed by this movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jklimentowski
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A horror science-fiction movie. When I think of this genre I always have "Alien" on my mind. I think this is a perfect example. Unfortunately "Event Horizon" lacks both in the horror and science-fiction parts. As for the science fiction - well it is just not realistic enough. Of course not all movies should be as realistic as "2010: Space Odyssey", but still when you compare it to "Alien" it turns out quite poor. Actually there is not much realism or physics in it at all. OK - the idea of time-space folding is nice, but the idea itself is at least as old as The Dune movie, or perhaps even older. I liked the scene of transition from zero gravity to artificial-earth gravity with fluids and bodies instantly dropping. The decompression sequence tries to be more horror like than scientific... and that is all I think. The rest is just pure fantasy. So forget about science-fiction - is it a good horror? This might be a difficult question for me as most horrors make me laugh rather than scare mostly due to their stupidity and lack of realism. There are of course exceptions like Alien or The Thing. What makes the difference? I think it is the realism of the situation. I really can't be scared by ghosts which can do anything. It is just too unreal - I can not place myself in such a world and my imagination fails. Unfortunately Event Horizon is a movie it this ghost type. Anything can happen therefore I do not feel like one of the terrified crew members, rather I wonder what could the director think of next. Of course there are some more or less scary moments, but these are just typical horror tricks - sudden action with a proper sound effect. There is no feel of terror while watching the movie. Another thing at which the movie fails is the plot. While the beginning sequences are quite interesting with every minute the plot becomes more and more chaotic. At some stage one really gets bored as it seems that there is no real goal or solution of the plot. One by one some things happen which try to scare you, but there is no logic in them. I can imagine that such a movie could last for a long time with random scary adventures happening to the characters until all of them are dead. But what is the point of watching that? Unfortunately the ending is also quite predictable and gives you no satisfaction of discovering something interesting or an unexpected solution. It is just as plain as that. OK - so is the movie really so bad? Well it is not a perfect movie, but not a terrible one either. One can watch it and have some fun but it is not a movie that you would like to come back to after years. Just see once, have fun and forget. It is worth to mention that the move has it's own style. While placed in future all the ships and equipment sometimes look like designed in the past. I can't describe it exactly but sometimes I had a feel of watching a sci-fiction movie from the fifties. Why did the director decide to chose such a scenography instead of pure futuristic one? No idea but I think it works fine.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    a waste of space-time
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Sven Jolly
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Another dump of cinematic excrement, this drivel is a disjointed mish mash of several other, greatly superior sci-fi movies, cribbed together in a random fashion to achieve nothing but boredom in the hapless viewer. One part Alien, one part Apollo 13, a "rotating magnetic field" gizmo that looks suspiciously like "Contact" this movie meanders all over the place. The story is stupid, with time travel, hallucinations, time/space monsters - it's as if they just tossed everything they could think of in a cut-up process to derive some semblance of a story line. Every character is pure stereotype, the dialogue is inane, seemingly composed by a group of high school boys, or perhaps one thousand monkey's typing randomly. After one hour of viewing you will have no idea what is going on, and neither do the characters or the writers. I couldn't finish watching this rubbish, one hour was all I could stand. MINUS -10 out of 10 for wasting my time. Strongly suggest you don't waste yours.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Creepy at times.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Scott LeBrun (Hey_Sweden)
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Right from the beginning, it may be clear that "Event Horizon" owes a pretty big debt to "Alien" (but then, so do many other post-1979 films) but it does have a fairly interesting story and it does live up to the word "horror". It gets substantially unnerving and creates some wonderfully horrific imagery. In fact, as films of this type go, it's a pleasure in terms of the visuals - special effects, sets, cinematography. Devotees of these genres should find it to be solid if not exceptional entertainment. They may find the "science" ludicrous, but still be amused. In the year 2047, an exploratory spaceship, the "Event Horizon" of the title, has reappeared after having been lost for seven years. A U.S.A.C. team is launched to find out what happened, and rescue any possible survivors. They do this in the company of the ships' designer, William Weir (Sam Neill), who has a tragedy in his past, and members of the team bring their own baggage to the situation, with no-nonsense Captain Miller (Laurence Fishburne) in charge of the mission. What they learn is that the ship now seems to be "alive", and aware of what has happened in the teams' pasts. The script by Philip Eisner is not without humour, but it mostly plays things straight, and the cast performs it with real gravity. Fishburne is good as a rock-solid type of man, while Neill gets a chance to tear into the scenery as Weir becomes more and more deranged. Kathleen Quinlan is affecting as Peters, who is having to deal with child custody issues in her personal life. Joely Richardson is good as efficient team member Starck, and Richard T. Jones, Jack Noseworthy, Jason Isaacs, and Sean Pertwee round out the cast. Things get off to a nice start with Paramount putting a fun spin on their standard logo sequence, and director Paul Anderson guides everything with style. "Event Horizon" may be derivative in some ways, but it moves along well and is never dull. Seven out of 10.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The ship's name held promise but the film fell short
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    A.N.
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I watched this after reading a Stephen Hawking book in which "event horizon" was described in terms of general relativity and black hole physics. But the hammering soundtrack in the opening credits warned me that this film probably wouldn't rise to the elegance of that concept. It had too many standard plot devices and was never really scary to me. Here are some issues, starting with most annoying first: 1) You'd think that an advanced spaceship crew would be educated like today's astronauts, not blue collar types easily bored by the scientist's explanation of a "singularity" and other aspects of black hole travel. They'd send the best of the best on such a critical mission, not jive talkers and impatient drones. "Say it in plain English!" is ridiculously overused in movies and insults an intelligent audience. A real crew of that caliber would understand black holes well beyond his folded paper demo. I know it was done for the audience's sake, but still. 2) The steam-punk gravity drive and the general interior of the ship seemed deliberately designed to convey malice, not functionality. It's almost as if the ship was built as a haunted house. Why all the spikes in the doors that humans pass through? OSHA wouldn't allow such a ship to be built. The gravity drive seemed more like a medieval torture device than something modern engineering would come up with. I suppose all the spikes could be related to magnetism but it wasn't explained. 3) The blood in the ship's structure had no scientific context. It played like a ripoff of "The Shining." This movie was too big on "fi" and too small on "sci." They should have toned down the gore. 4) Technical aspects, like the guy in the airlock spewing that much blood and living, or the astronaut being propelled back toward the planet with his breathing pack seemed ludicrous. The electronics damage to the rescue ship seemed impossible to fix. It needed a lot more than skin patches. Why do so many movies show sparks flying from sophisticated instruments which are miraculously repaired in hours? 5) The premise that we'd already colonized the Moon by 2015 was ridiculously optimistic, even in 1997. Still, it kept me entertained enough to see it through, so I gave it a neutral 5. I'd recommend "Solaris" (2002) for a much better depiction of mentally conjured people, etc. The elements of that in "Event Horizon" were done in sledgehammer style, though the eyeless wife did give me a jolt.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Repulsive movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    verna-a
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    You'll hate yourself for watching this and hate what the producers/directors of this film did to decent actors. I like sci-fi films and was attracted to the story outline. Unfortunately it soon became evident no-one had any faith in the power of storytelling and characterization to engage the audience. Instead they had to exaggerate every interaction between members of the crew to be as abrasive as possible, and introduce every cheesy and over-the-top horror film trick they could think of to progress the film. I nearly wrote "to maintain interest" but in fact it's a big turn off and you soon regard the whole affair with total contempt. Here's an example of the wit and character development in the film: black male crew member to female crew member while offering a cup of coffee "How'd you like something hot and black inside you?" (leers). Just when you think it can't get any worse with exaggerated gory special effects, it does. I see some people like this film, honestly I shudder to imagine the sort of person that would. It's quite repulsive, and the only reason I'm giving it a 2 is that I did watch it to the end to see who they could extricate from the general mayhem. I think I caught a line of dialogue "In this situation, some self-control is an advantage". Are they kidding! I hope the people responsible for this film have found employment in some other industry.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not impressed
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    (mikedennett-664-275394)
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie was far weaker than I expected. It is full of tired stereotypical character profiles (the gruff captain, the odd doctor, the yucking-it-up Chris Rock/Eddie Murphy wanna-be, the eccentric scientist who speaks in mysterious scientific mumbo-jumbo, the hardened let's-get- the-heck-out-of-here pilot, etc ad nauseum), weak acting, and an endless series of predictable disasters. I did not find it clever, inspiring, or original. Even the CGI was weak in many spots. The average rating surprises the heck out of me, are people's standards really that low? There were a few surprises, but you can make people jump out of their seats with an orchestra hit even if the screen shows a kitten licking its paw. I tend to automatically lower my expectations anytime a move starts with a teletype history line leading up to the opening scenes.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of two films i rarely watch because they are just to good
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Ark 7754
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Don't be perplexed by my summary.. This film and the ring are truly great horrors. I literally go to bed after a bit unnerved. This is probably my all time favourite horror. The shining is disturbing but i can watch it,I've watched it 5 times i think..event horizon i have watched twice. once when i was young,the second with my wife because she needed to watch it at my request lol Needless to say she caked it as well. just watch the film..yeah okay like some reviews some of its predictable..but the majority isn't and its pretty damn scary. When the scene with the footage arrives is when you know bad times ahead lol..thats not a spoiler you'll know what i mean yeah but regardless..stop reading this..go watch it
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Dark and Rather Brave Film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Michael_Elliott
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Event Horizon (1997) *** (out of 4) Dark and sometimes disturbing mix of sci-fi and horror about the spaceship Event Horizon, which went missing shortly after its mission. Seven years later it reemerges so a rescue crew goes after it trying to figure out where it's been the entire time. I saw EVENT HORIZON when it was first released and really couldn't understand why it gained so many negative reviews. There's no question that the film contains some flaws but it's also a rather ambitious film that relies just as much on its story than just the special effects. I thought director Paul Anderson did a fantastic job early on really making the viewer feel uneasy. There's a brief line where a crew member talks about how far they are from safety and this scene perfectly builds up a rather dark tension because you realize that these people really are on their own with no one to help them. The entire atmosphere of the film is incredibly dark and while I'm not going to give anything away, what the story attempts to do with where the ship has gone was rather unique and I think that for the most part it works. Now, if you've ever heard of this film then you know about the various issues it ran into during the test screenings. There's been talk of a director's cut, which I think might help out many of the flaws. The story takes us to a rather dark direction but it just seems as if something is missing. There are a few questions that need to be answered and there are a few things that don't make much sense but perhaps these were forced to be left on the cutting room floor. If so, hopefully we can see the complete version at some point. Another thing that works here are the extremely strong performances with Laurence Fishburne, Sam Neill, Kathleen Quinlan and Joely Richardson delivering great work. The special effects are also another major plus including an incredibly beautiful opening sequence as well as the effects really making you feel as if you're in space the entire time. Some have been critical of some of the graphic and bloody violence but I thought it actually played well into the story and didn't take away from anything. As it stands, EVENT HORIZON is a rather brave but flawed film but hopefully a complete version will give us a better look at what it was really trying to do.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Fun sci fi, not real scary
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ahorn88
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Just watched this movie as per the suggestion of this post. What I expected? Shocking, gory imagery. Mind bending, unsettling theories of what could be possible in this world over the next 100 years. What The movie delivered? A middling sci-fi thriller with a pretty great cast; not particularly scary. The premise is great - the human race, "flying too close to the sun," rips a hole in the fabric of space time, opening a portal to a chaotic, evil dimension. The spacecraft itself is transformed into an evil being, devouring any well-intentioned rescue crew that happens to cross its path. This is one of those movies that on paper and in my head seem incredible - limitless potential - but unfortunately the execution just did not match up. The hype I had built up based on comments people had made and a review or two that I had read prior to viewing made me expect a mind f*** to compete with other creepy sci fi flicks like The Cube or The Cell crossed with the horror and gore of Candyman. At the end of the day, I recommend checking out Event Horizon as a fun sci-fi movie that requires a bit of imagination and the suspension of disbelief thanks to the mid 90's special effects. Expect a 5/10, discover an 8/10. And that's my 2 cents.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The most frightening,effective and disturbing horror movie I have ever seen
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    yasenkiranov
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I had extremely low expectations for "Event Horizon".The film was made in a period where a lot of filmmakers thought that when you have enough money to use and abuse CGI your movie doesn't need a decent script.With that in mind I thought "Event Horizon" was going to be a clich&eacute; horror film that makes no effort to build suspense and just throws CG blood and gore in your face.I was wrong.Dead wrong. "Event Horizon" is the creepiest and most suspenseful horror movie I have ever seen.It manages to create a feeling of dread and foreboding like no other film I have ever seen before.This is due to a combination of great camera-work,appropriate music and(believe it or not) CG.Yes,the CGI is actually used appropriately here,not just added for the sake of it being there.That said,the special effects are top-notch(for 1997). Another thing I liked was that the ship itself wasn't the main threat.It was the characters.They become obsessed with their past mistakes(things they had locked away in their minds and didn't want to remember) and that begins to drive them insane.True,the ship is the catalyst for this,but the focus is more on the characters themselves.This reminds me of "Cube"-one of my favorite movies. The characters themselves are a bit underdeveloped,but they aren't cannon fodder like in many other horror films.Each of them has their the distinct personality and background information is given about some of them.I think this was alright for the purpose of this film.In my opinion ,if they did add more character development it would have ruined the pacing. "Event Horizon" is a very well made,but sadly underrated, horror movie.I strongly recommend it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I wasn't amazed by this movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jklimentowski
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A horror science-fiction movie. When I think of this genre I always have "Alien" on my mind. I think this is a perfect example. Unfortunately "Event Horizon" lacks both in the horror and science-fiction parts. As for the science fiction - well it is just not realistic enough. Of course not all movies should be as realistic as "2010: Space Odyssey", but still when you compare it to "Alien" it turns out quite poor. Actually there is not much realism or physics in it at all. OK - the idea of time-space folding is nice, but the idea itself is at least as old as The Dune movie, or perhaps even older. I liked the scene of transition from zero gravity to artificial-earth gravity with fluids and bodies instantly dropping. The decompression sequence tries to be more horror like than scientific... and that is all I think. The rest is just pure fantasy. So forget about science-fiction - is it a good horror? This might be a difficult question for me as most horrors make me laugh rather than scare mostly due to their stupidity and lack of realism. There are of course exceptions like Alien or The Thing. What makes the difference? I think it is the realism of the situation. I really can't be scared by ghosts which can do anything. It is just too unreal - I can not place myself in such a world and my imagination fails. Unfortunately Event Horizon is a movie it this ghost type. Anything can happen therefore I do not feel like one of the terrified crew members, rather I wonder what could the director think of next. Of course there are some more or less scary moments, but these are just typical horror tricks - sudden action with a proper sound effect. There is no feel of terror while watching the movie. Another thing at which the movie fails is the plot. While the beginning sequences are quite interesting with every minute the plot becomes more and more chaotic. At some stage one really gets bored as it seems that there is no real goal or solution of the plot. One by one some things happen which try to scare you, but there is no logic in them. I can imagine that such a movie could last for a long time with random scary adventures happening to the characters until all of them are dead. But what is the point of watching that? Unfortunately the ending is also quite predictable and gives you no satisfaction of discovering something interesting or an unexpected solution. It is just as plain as that. OK - so is the movie really so bad? Well it is not a perfect movie, but not a terrible one either. One can watch it and have some fun but it is not a movie that you would like to come back to after years. Just see once, have fun and forget. It is worth to mention that the move has it's own style. While placed in future all the ships and equipment sometimes look like designed in the past. I can't describe it exactly but sometimes I had a feel of watching a sci-fiction movie from the fifties. Why did the director decide to chose such a scenography instead of pure futuristic one? No idea but I think it works fine.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    a waste of space-time
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Sven Jolly
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Another dump of cinematic excrement, this drivel is a disjointed mish mash of several other, greatly superior sci-fi movies, cribbed together in a random fashion to achieve nothing but boredom in the hapless viewer. One part Alien, one part Apollo 13, a "rotating magnetic field" gizmo that looks suspiciously like "Contact" this movie meanders all over the place. The story is stupid, with time travel, hallucinations, time/space monsters - it's as if they just tossed everything they could think of in a cut-up process to derive some semblance of a story line. Every character is pure stereotype, the dialogue is inane, seemingly composed by a group of high school boys, or perhaps one thousand monkey's typing randomly. After one hour of viewing you will have no idea what is going on, and neither do the characters or the writers. I couldn't finish watching this rubbish, one hour was all I could stand. MINUS -10 out of 10 for wasting my time. Strongly suggest you don't waste yours.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Creepy at times.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Scott LeBrun (Hey_Sweden)
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Right from the beginning, it may be clear that "Event Horizon" owes a pretty big debt to "Alien" (but then, so do many other post-1979 films) but it does have a fairly interesting story and it does live up to the word "horror". It gets substantially unnerving and creates some wonderfully horrific imagery. In fact, as films of this type go, it's a pleasure in terms of the visuals - special effects, sets, cinematography. Devotees of these genres should find it to be solid if not exceptional entertainment. They may find the "science" ludicrous, but still be amused. In the year 2047, an exploratory spaceship, the "Event Horizon" of the title, has reappeared after having been lost for seven years. A U.S.A.C. team is launched to find out what happened, and rescue any possible survivors. They do this in the company of the ships' designer, William Weir (Sam Neill), who has a tragedy in his past, and members of the team bring their own baggage to the situation, with no-nonsense Captain Miller (Laurence Fishburne) in charge of the mission. What they learn is that the ship now seems to be "alive", and aware of what has happened in the teams' pasts. The script by Philip Eisner is not without humour, but it mostly plays things straight, and the cast performs it with real gravity. Fishburne is good as a rock-solid type of man, while Neill gets a chance to tear into the scenery as Weir becomes more and more deranged. Kathleen Quinlan is affecting as Peters, who is having to deal with child custody issues in her personal life. Joely Richardson is good as efficient team member Starck, and Richard T. Jones, Jack Noseworthy, Jason Isaacs, and Sean Pertwee round out the cast. Things get off to a nice start with Paramount putting a fun spin on their standard logo sequence, and director Paul Anderson guides everything with style. "Event Horizon" may be derivative in some ways, but it moves along well and is never dull. Seven out of 10.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The ship's name held promise but the film fell short
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    A.N.
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I watched this after reading a Stephen Hawking book in which "event horizon" was described in terms of general relativity and black hole physics. But the hammering soundtrack in the opening credits warned me that this film probably wouldn't rise to the elegance of that concept. It had too many standard plot devices and was never really scary to me. Here are some issues, starting with most annoying first: 1) You'd think that an advanced spaceship crew would be educated like today's astronauts, not blue collar types easily bored by the scientist's explanation of a "singularity" and other aspects of black hole travel. They'd send the best of the best on such a critical mission, not jive talkers and impatient drones. "Say it in plain English!" is ridiculously overused in movies and insults an intelligent audience. A real crew of that caliber would understand black holes well beyond his folded paper demo. I know it was done for the audience's sake, but still. 2) The steam-punk gravity drive and the general interior of the ship seemed deliberately designed to convey malice, not functionality. It's almost as if the ship was built as a haunted house. Why all the spikes in the doors that humans pass through? OSHA wouldn't allow such a ship to be built. The gravity drive seemed more like a medieval torture device than something modern engineering would come up with. I suppose all the spikes could be related to magnetism but it wasn't explained. 3) The blood in the ship's structure had no scientific context. It played like a ripoff of "The Shining." This movie was too big on "fi" and too small on "sci." They should have toned down the gore. 4) Technical aspects, like the guy in the airlock spewing that much blood and living, or the astronaut being propelled back toward the planet with his breathing pack seemed ludicrous. The electronics damage to the rescue ship seemed impossible to fix. It needed a lot more than skin patches. Why do so many movies show sparks flying from sophisticated instruments which are miraculously repaired in hours? 5) The premise that we'd already colonized the Moon by 2015 was ridiculously optimistic, even in 1997. Still, it kept me entertained enough to see it through, so I gave it a neutral 5. I'd recommend "Solaris" (2002) for a much better depiction of mentally conjured people, etc. The elements of that in "Event Horizon" were done in sledgehammer style, though the eyeless wife did give me a jolt.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Repulsive movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    verna-a
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    You'll hate yourself for watching this and hate what the producers/directors of this film did to decent actors. I like sci-fi films and was attracted to the story outline. Unfortunately it soon became evident no-one had any faith in the power of storytelling and characterization to engage the audience. Instead they had to exaggerate every interaction between members of the crew to be as abrasive as possible, and introduce every cheesy and over-the-top horror film trick they could think of to progress the film. I nearly wrote "to maintain interest" but in fact it's a big turn off and you soon regard the whole affair with total contempt. Here's an example of the wit and character development in the film: black male crew member to female crew member while offering a cup of coffee "How'd you like something hot and black inside you?" (leers). Just when you think it can't get any worse with exaggerated gory special effects, it does. I see some people like this film, honestly I shudder to imagine the sort of person that would. It's quite repulsive, and the only reason I'm giving it a 2 is that I did watch it to the end to see who they could extricate from the general mayhem. I think I caught a line of dialogue "In this situation, some self-control is an advantage". Are they kidding! I hope the people responsible for this film have found employment in some other industry.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not impressed
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    (mikedennett-664-275394)
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie was far weaker than I expected. It is full of tired stereotypical character profiles (the gruff captain, the odd doctor, the yucking-it-up Chris Rock/Eddie Murphy wanna-be, the eccentric scientist who speaks in mysterious scientific mumbo-jumbo, the hardened let's-get- the-heck-out-of-here pilot, etc ad nauseum), weak acting, and an endless series of predictable disasters. I did not find it clever, inspiring, or original. Even the CGI was weak in many spots. The average rating surprises the heck out of me, are people's standards really that low? There were a few surprises, but you can make people jump out of their seats with an orchestra hit even if the screen shows a kitten licking its paw. I tend to automatically lower my expectations anytime a move starts with a teletype history line leading up to the opening scenes.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of two films i rarely watch because they are just to good
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Ark 7754
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Don't be perplexed by my summary.. This film and the ring are truly great horrors. I literally go to bed after a bit unnerved. This is probably my all time favourite horror. The shining is disturbing but i can watch it,I've watched it 5 times i think..event horizon i have watched twice. once when i was young,the second with my wife because she needed to watch it at my request lol Needless to say she caked it as well. just watch the film..yeah okay like some reviews some of its predictable..but the majority isn't and its pretty damn scary. When the scene with the footage arrives is when you know bad times ahead lol..thats not a spoiler you'll know what i mean yeah but regardless..stop reading this..go watch it
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Dark and Rather Brave Film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Michael_Elliott
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Event Horizon (1997) *** (out of 4) Dark and sometimes disturbing mix of sci-fi and horror about the spaceship Event Horizon, which went missing shortly after its mission. Seven years later it reemerges so a rescue crew goes after it trying to figure out where it's been the entire time. I saw EVENT HORIZON when it was first released and really couldn't understand why it gained so many negative reviews. There's no question that the film contains some flaws but it's also a rather ambitious film that relies just as much on its story than just the special effects. I thought director Paul Anderson did a fantastic job early on really making the viewer feel uneasy. There's a brief line where a crew member talks about how far they are from safety and this scene perfectly builds up a rather dark tension because you realize that these people really are on their own with no one to help them. The entire atmosphere of the film is incredibly dark and while I'm not going to give anything away, what the story attempts to do with where the ship has gone was rather unique and I think that for the most part it works. Now, if you've ever heard of this film then you know about the various issues it ran into during the test screenings. There's been talk of a director's cut, which I think might help out many of the flaws. The story takes us to a rather dark direction but it just seems as if something is missing. There are a few questions that need to be answered and there are a few things that don't make much sense but perhaps these were forced to be left on the cutting room floor. If so, hopefully we can see the complete version at some point. Another thing that works here are the extremely strong performances with Laurence Fishburne, Sam Neill, Kathleen Quinlan and Joely Richardson delivering great work. The special effects are also another major plus including an incredibly beautiful opening sequence as well as the effects really making you feel as if you're in space the entire time. Some have been critical of some of the graphic and bloody violence but I thought it actually played well into the story and didn't take away from anything. As it stands, EVENT HORIZON is a rather brave but flawed film but hopefully a complete version will give us a better look at what it was really trying to do.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Fun sci fi, not real scary
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ahorn88
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Just watched this movie as per the suggestion of this post. What I expected? Shocking, gory imagery. Mind bending, unsettling theories of what could be possible in this world over the next 100 years. What The movie delivered? A middling sci-fi thriller with a pretty great cast; not particularly scary. The premise is great - the human race, "flying too close to the sun," rips a hole in the fabric of space time, opening a portal to a chaotic, evil dimension. The spacecraft itself is transformed into an evil being, devouring any well-intentioned rescue crew that happens to cross its path. This is one of those movies that on paper and in my head seem incredible - limitless potential - but unfortunately the execution just did not match up. The hype I had built up based on comments people had made and a review or two that I had read prior to viewing made me expect a mind f*** to compete with other creepy sci fi flicks like The Cube or The Cell crossed with the horror and gore of Candyman. At the end of the day, I recommend checking out Event Horizon as a fun sci-fi movie that requires a bit of imagination and the suspension of disbelief thanks to the mid 90's special effects. Expect a 5/10, discover an 8/10. And that's my 2 cents.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The most frightening,effective and disturbing horror movie I have ever seen
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    yasenkiranov
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I had extremely low expectations for "Event Horizon".The film was made in a period where a lot of filmmakers thought that when you have enough money to use and abuse CGI your movie doesn't need a decent script.With that in mind I thought "Event Horizon" was going to be a clich&eacute; horror film that makes no effort to build suspense and just throws CG blood and gore in your face.I was wrong.Dead wrong. "Event Horizon" is the creepiest and most suspenseful horror movie I have ever seen.It manages to create a feeling of dread and foreboding like no other film I have ever seen before.This is due to a combination of great camera-work,appropriate music and(believe it or not) CG.Yes,the CGI is actually used appropriately here,not just added for the sake of it being there.That said,the special effects are top-notch(for 1997). Another thing I liked was that the ship itself wasn't the main threat.It was the characters.They become obsessed with their past mistakes(things they had locked away in their minds and didn't want to remember) and that begins to drive them insane.True,the ship is the catalyst for this,but the focus is more on the characters themselves.This reminds me of "Cube"-one of my favorite movies. The characters themselves are a bit underdeveloped,but they aren't cannon fodder like in many other horror films.Each of them has their the distinct personality and background information is given about some of them.I think this was alright for the purpose of this film.In my opinion ,if they did add more character development it would have ruined the pacing. "Event Horizon" is a very well made,but sadly underrated, horror movie.I strongly recommend it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I wasn't amazed by this movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jklimentowski
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A horror science-fiction movie. When I think of this genre I always have "Alien" on my mind. I think this is a perfect example. Unfortunately "Event Horizon" lacks both in the horror and science-fiction parts. As for the science fiction - well it is just not realistic enough. Of course not all movies should be as realistic as "2010: Space Odyssey", but still when you compare it to "Alien" it turns out quite poor. Actually there is not much realism or physics in it at all. OK - the idea of time-space folding is nice, but the idea itself is at least as old as The Dune movie, or perhaps even older. I liked the scene of transition from zero gravity to artificial-earth gravity with fluids and bodies instantly dropping. The decompression sequence tries to be more horror like than scientific... and that is all I think. The rest is just pure fantasy. So forget about science-fiction - is it a good horror? This might be a difficult question for me as most horrors make me laugh rather than scare mostly due to their stupidity and lack of realism. There are of course exceptions like Alien or The Thing. What makes the difference? I think it is the realism of the situation. I really can't be scared by ghosts which can do anything. It is just too unreal - I can not place myself in such a world and my imagination fails. Unfortunately Event Horizon is a movie it this ghost type. Anything can happen therefore I do not feel like one of the terrified crew members, rather I wonder what could the director think of next. Of course there are some more or less scary moments, but these are just typical horror tricks - sudden action with a proper sound effect. There is no feel of terror while watching the movie. Another thing at which the movie fails is the plot. While the beginning sequences are quite interesting with every minute the plot becomes more and more chaotic. At some stage one really gets bored as it seems that there is no real goal or solution of the plot. One by one some things happen which try to scare you, but there is no logic in them. I can imagine that such a movie could last for a long time with random scary adventures happening to the characters until all of them are dead. But what is the point of watching that? Unfortunately the ending is also quite predictable and gives you no satisfaction of discovering something interesting or an unexpected solution. It is just as plain as that. OK - so is the movie really so bad? Well it is not a perfect movie, but not a terrible one either. One can watch it and have some fun but it is not a movie that you would like to come back to after years. Just see once, have fun and forget. It is worth to mention that the move has it's own style. While placed in future all the ships and equipment sometimes look like designed in the past. I can't describe it exactly but sometimes I had a feel of watching a sci-fiction movie from the fifties. Why did the director decide to chose such a scenography instead of pure futuristic one? No idea but I think it works fine.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    a waste of space-time
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Sven Jolly
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Another dump of cinematic excrement, this drivel is a disjointed mish mash of several other, greatly superior sci-fi movies, cribbed together in a random fashion to achieve nothing but boredom in the hapless viewer. One part Alien, one part Apollo 13, a "rotating magnetic field" gizmo that looks suspiciously like "Contact" this movie meanders all over the place. The story is stupid, with time travel, hallucinations, time/space monsters - it's as if they just tossed everything they could think of in a cut-up process to derive some semblance of a story line. Every character is pure stereotype, the dialogue is inane, seemingly composed by a group of high school boys, or perhaps one thousand monkey's typing randomly. After one hour of viewing you will have no idea what is going on, and neither do the characters or the writers. I couldn't finish watching this rubbish, one hour was all I could stand. MINUS -10 out of 10 for wasting my time. Strongly suggest you don't waste yours.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Creepy at times.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Scott LeBrun (Hey_Sweden)
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Right from the beginning, it may be clear that "Event Horizon" owes a pretty big debt to "Alien" (but then, so do many other post-1979 films) but it does have a fairly interesting story and it does live up to the word "horror". It gets substantially unnerving and creates some wonderfully horrific imagery. In fact, as films of this type go, it's a pleasure in terms of the visuals - special effects, sets, cinematography. Devotees of these genres should find it to be solid if not exceptional entertainment. They may find the "science" ludicrous, but still be amused. In the year 2047, an exploratory spaceship, the "Event Horizon" of the title, has reappeared after having been lost for seven years. A U.S.A.C. team is launched to find out what happened, and rescue any possible survivors. They do this in the company of the ships' designer, William Weir (Sam Neill), who has a tragedy in his past, and members of the team bring their own baggage to the situation, with no-nonsense Captain Miller (Laurence Fishburne) in charge of the mission. What they learn is that the ship now seems to be "alive", and aware of what has happened in the teams' pasts. The script by Philip Eisner is not without humour, but it mostly plays things straight, and the cast performs it with real gravity. Fishburne is good as a rock-solid type of man, while Neill gets a chance to tear into the scenery as Weir becomes more and more deranged. Kathleen Quinlan is affecting as Peters, who is having to deal with child custody issues in her personal life. Joely Richardson is good as efficient team member Starck, and Richard T. Jones, Jack Noseworthy, Jason Isaacs, and Sean Pertwee round out the cast. Things get off to a nice start with Paramount putting a fun spin on their standard logo sequence, and director Paul Anderson guides everything with style. "Event Horizon" may be derivative in some ways, but it moves along well and is never dull. Seven out of 10.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The ship's name held promise but the film fell short
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    A.N.
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I watched this after reading a Stephen Hawking book in which "event horizon" was described in terms of general relativity and black hole physics. But the hammering soundtrack in the opening credits warned me that this film probably wouldn't rise to the elegance of that concept. It had too many standard plot devices and was never really scary to me. Here are some issues, starting with most annoying first: 1) You'd think that an advanced spaceship crew would be educated like today's astronauts, not blue collar types easily bored by the scientist's explanation of a "singularity" and other aspects of black hole travel. They'd send the best of the best on such a critical mission, not jive talkers and impatient drones. "Say it in plain English!" is ridiculously overused in movies and insults an intelligent audience. A real crew of that caliber would understand black holes well beyond his folded paper demo. I know it was done for the audience's sake, but still. 2) The steam-punk gravity drive and the general interior of the ship seemed deliberately designed to convey malice, not functionality. It's almost as if the ship was built as a haunted house. Why all the spikes in the doors that humans pass through? OSHA wouldn't allow such a ship to be built. The gravity drive seemed more like a medieval torture device than something modern engineering would come up with. I suppose all the spikes could be related to magnetism but it wasn't explained. 3) The blood in the ship's structure had no scientific context. It played like a ripoff of "The Shining." This movie was too big on "fi" and too small on "sci." They should have toned down the gore. 4) Technical aspects, like the guy in the airlock spewing that much blood and living, or the astronaut being propelled back toward the planet with his breathing pack seemed ludicrous. The electronics damage to the rescue ship seemed impossible to fix. It needed a lot more than skin patches. Why do so many movies show sparks flying from sophisticated instruments which are miraculously repaired in hours? 5) The premise that we'd already colonized the Moon by 2015 was ridiculously optimistic, even in 1997. Still, it kept me entertained enough to see it through, so I gave it a neutral 5. I'd recommend "Solaris" (2002) for a much better depiction of mentally conjured people, etc. The elements of that in "Event Horizon" were done in sledgehammer style, though the eyeless wife did give me a jolt.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Repulsive movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    verna-a
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    You'll hate yourself for watching this and hate what the producers/directors of this film did to decent actors. I like sci-fi films and was attracted to the story outline. Unfortunately it soon became evident no-one had any faith in the power of storytelling and characterization to engage the audience. Instead they had to exaggerate every interaction between members of the crew to be as abrasive as possible, and introduce every cheesy and over-the-top horror film trick they could think of to progress the film. I nearly wrote "to maintain interest" but in fact it's a big turn off and you soon regard the whole affair with total contempt. Here's an example of the wit and character development in the film: black male crew member to female crew member while offering a cup of coffee "How'd you like something hot and black inside you?" (leers). Just when you think it can't get any worse with exaggerated gory special effects, it does. I see some people like this film, honestly I shudder to imagine the sort of person that would. It's quite repulsive, and the only reason I'm giving it a 2 is that I did watch it to the end to see who they could extricate from the general mayhem. I think I caught a line of dialogue "In this situation, some self-control is an advantage". Are they kidding! I hope the people responsible for this film have found employment in some other industry.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not impressed
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    (mikedennett-664-275394)
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie was far weaker than I expected. It is full of tired stereotypical character profiles (the gruff captain, the odd doctor, the yucking-it-up Chris Rock/Eddie Murphy wanna-be, the eccentric scientist who speaks in mysterious scientific mumbo-jumbo, the hardened let's-get- the-heck-out-of-here pilot, etc ad nauseum), weak acting, and an endless series of predictable disasters. I did not find it clever, inspiring, or original. Even the CGI was weak in many spots. The average rating surprises the heck out of me, are people's standards really that low? There were a few surprises, but you can make people jump out of their seats with an orchestra hit even if the screen shows a kitten licking its paw. I tend to automatically lower my expectations anytime a move starts with a teletype history line leading up to the opening scenes.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of two films i rarely watch because they are just to good
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Ark 7754
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Don't be perplexed by my summary.. This film and the ring are truly great horrors. I literally go to bed after a bit unnerved. This is probably my all time favourite horror. The shining is disturbing but i can watch it,I've watched it 5 times i think..event horizon i have watched twice. once when i was young,the second with my wife because she needed to watch it at my request lol Needless to say she caked it as well. just watch the film..yeah okay like some reviews some of its predictable..but the majority isn't and its pretty damn scary. When the scene with the footage arrives is when you know bad times ahead lol..thats not a spoiler you'll know what i mean yeah but regardless..stop reading this..go watch it
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Dark and Rather Brave Film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Michael_Elliott
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Event Horizon (1997) *** (out of 4) Dark and sometimes disturbing mix of sci-fi and horror about the spaceship Event Horizon, which went missing shortly after its mission. Seven years later it reemerges so a rescue crew goes after it trying to figure out where it's been the entire time. I saw EVENT HORIZON when it was first released and really couldn't understand why it gained so many negative reviews. There's no question that the film contains some flaws but it's also a rather ambitious film that relies just as much on its story than just the special effects. I thought director Paul Anderson did a fantastic job early on really making the viewer feel uneasy. There's a brief line where a crew member talks about how far they are from safety and this scene perfectly builds up a rather dark tension because you realize that these people really are on their own with no one to help them. The entire atmosphere of the film is incredibly dark and while I'm not going to give anything away, what the story attempts to do with where the ship has gone was rather unique and I think that for the most part it works. Now, if you've ever heard of this film then you know about the various issues it ran into during the test screenings. There's been talk of a director's cut, which I think might help out many of the flaws. The story takes us to a rather dark direction but it just seems as if something is missing. There are a few questions that need to be answered and there are a few things that don't make much sense but perhaps these were forced to be left on the cutting room floor. If so, hopefully we can see the complete version at some point. Another thing that works here are the extremely strong performances with Laurence Fishburne, Sam Neill, Kathleen Quinlan and Joely Richardson delivering great work. The special effects are also another major plus including an incredibly beautiful opening sequence as well as the effects really making you feel as if you're in space the entire time. Some have been critical of some of the graphic and bloody violence but I thought it actually played well into the story and didn't take away from anything. As it stands, EVENT HORIZON is a rather brave but flawed film but hopefully a complete version will give us a better look at what it was really trying to do.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Fun sci fi, not real scary
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ahorn88
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Just watched this movie as per the suggestion of this post. What I expected? Shocking, gory imagery. Mind bending, unsettling theories of what could be possible in this world over the next 100 years. What The movie delivered? A middling sci-fi thriller with a pretty great cast; not particularly scary. The premise is great - the human race, "flying too close to the sun," rips a hole in the fabric of space time, opening a portal to a chaotic, evil dimension. The spacecraft itself is transformed into an evil being, devouring any well-intentioned rescue crew that happens to cross its path. This is one of those movies that on paper and in my head seem incredible - limitless potential - but unfortunately the execution just did not match up. The hype I had built up based on comments people had made and a review or two that I had read prior to viewing made me expect a mind f*** to compete with other creepy sci fi flicks like The Cube or The Cell crossed with the horror and gore of Candyman. At the end of the day, I recommend checking out Event Horizon as a fun sci-fi movie that requires a bit of imagination and the suspension of disbelief thanks to the mid 90's special effects. Expect a 5/10, discover an 8/10. And that's my 2 cents.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The most frightening,effective and disturbing horror movie I have ever seen
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    yasenkiranov
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I had extremely low expectations for "Event Horizon".The film was made in a period where a lot of filmmakers thought that when you have enough money to use and abuse CGI your movie doesn't need a decent script.With that in mind I thought "Event Horizon" was going to be a clich&eacute; horror film that makes no effort to build suspense and just throws CG blood and gore in your face.I was wrong.Dead wrong. "Event Horizon" is the creepiest and most suspenseful horror movie I have ever seen.It manages to create a feeling of dread and foreboding like no other film I have ever seen before.This is due to a combination of great camera-work,appropriate music and(believe it or not) CG.Yes,the CGI is actually used appropriately here,not just added for the sake of it being there.That said,the special effects are top-notch(for 1997). Another thing I liked was that the ship itself wasn't the main threat.It was the characters.They become obsessed with their past mistakes(things they had locked away in their minds and didn't want to remember) and that begins to drive them insane.True,the ship is the catalyst for this,but the focus is more on the characters themselves.This reminds me of "Cube"-one of my favorite movies. The characters themselves are a bit underdeveloped,but they aren't cannon fodder like in many other horror films.Each of them has their the distinct personality and background information is given about some of them.I think this was alright for the purpose of this film.In my opinion ,if they did add more character development it would have ruined the pacing. "Event Horizon" is a very well made,but sadly underrated, horror movie.I strongly recommend it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I wasn't amazed by this movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jklimentowski
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A horror science-fiction movie. When I think of this genre I always have "Alien" on my mind. I think this is a perfect example. Unfortunately "Event Horizon" lacks both in the horror and science-fiction parts. As for the science fiction - well it is just not realistic enough. Of course not all movies should be as realistic as "2010: Space Odyssey", but still when you compare it to "Alien" it turns out quite poor. Actually there is not much realism or physics in it at all. OK - the idea of time-space folding is nice, but the idea itself is at least as old as The Dune movie, or perhaps even older. I liked the scene of transition from zero gravity to artificial-earth gravity with fluids and bodies instantly dropping. The decompression sequence tries to be more horror like than scientific... and that is all I think. The rest is just pure fantasy. So forget about science-fiction - is it a good horror? This might be a difficult question for me as most horrors make me laugh rather than scare mostly due to their stupidity and lack of realism. There are of course exceptions like Alien or The Thing. What makes the difference? I think it is the realism of the situation. I really can't be scared by ghosts which can do anything. It is just too unreal - I can not place myself in such a world and my imagination fails. Unfortunately Event Horizon is a movie it this ghost type. Anything can happen therefore I do not feel like one of the terrified crew members, rather I wonder what could the director think of next. Of course there are some more or less scary moments, but these are just typical horror tricks - sudden action with a proper sound effect. There is no feel of terror while watching the movie. Another thing at which the movie fails is the plot. While the beginning sequences are quite interesting with every minute the plot becomes more and more chaotic. At some stage one really gets bored as it seems that there is no real goal or solution of the plot. One by one some things happen which try to scare you, but there is no logic in them. I can imagine that such a movie could last for a long time with random scary adventures happening to the characters until all of them are dead. But what is the point of watching that? Unfortunately the ending is also quite predictable and gives you no satisfaction of discovering something interesting or an unexpected solution. It is just as plain as that. OK - so is the movie really so bad? Well it is not a perfect movie, but not a terrible one either. One can watch it and have some fun but it is not a movie that you would like to come back to after years. Just see once, have fun and forget. It is worth to mention that the move has it's own style. While placed in future all the ships and equipment sometimes look like designed in the past. I can't describe it exactly but sometimes I had a feel of watching a sci-fiction movie from the fifties. Why did the director decide to chose such a scenography instead of pure futuristic one? No idea but I think it works fine.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    a waste of space-time
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Sven Jolly
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Another dump of cinematic excrement, this drivel is a disjointed mish mash of several other, greatly superior sci-fi movies, cribbed together in a random fashion to achieve nothing but boredom in the hapless viewer. One part Alien, one part Apollo 13, a "rotating magnetic field" gizmo that looks suspiciously like "Contact" this movie meanders all over the place. The story is stupid, with time travel, hallucinations, time/space monsters - it's as if they just tossed everything they could think of in a cut-up process to derive some semblance of a story line. Every character is pure stereotype, the dialogue is inane, seemingly composed by a group of high school boys, or perhaps one thousand monkey's typing randomly. After one hour of viewing you will have no idea what is going on, and neither do the characters or the writers. I couldn't finish watching this rubbish, one hour was all I could stand. MINUS -10 out of 10 for wasting my time. Strongly suggest you don't waste yours.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Creepy at times.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Scott LeBrun (Hey_Sweden)
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Right from the beginning, it may be clear that "Event Horizon" owes a pretty big debt to "Alien" (but then, so do many other post-1979 films) but it does have a fairly interesting story and it does live up to the word "horror". It gets substantially unnerving and creates some wonderfully horrific imagery. In fact, as films of this type go, it's a pleasure in terms of the visuals - special effects, sets, cinematography. Devotees of these genres should find it to be solid if not exceptional entertainment. They may find the "science" ludicrous, but still be amused. In the year 2047, an exploratory spaceship, the "Event Horizon" of the title, has reappeared after having been lost for seven years. A U.S.A.C. team is launched to find out what happened, and rescue any possible survivors. They do this in the company of the ships' designer, William Weir (Sam Neill), who has a tragedy in his past, and members of the team bring their own baggage to the situation, with no-nonsense Captain Miller (Laurence Fishburne) in charge of the mission. What they learn is that the ship now seems to be "alive", and aware of what has happened in the teams' pasts. The script by Philip Eisner is not without humour, but it mostly plays things straight, and the cast performs it with real gravity. Fishburne is good as a rock-solid type of man, while Neill gets a chance to tear into the scenery as Weir becomes more and more deranged. Kathleen Quinlan is affecting as Peters, who is having to deal with child custody issues in her personal life. Joely Richardson is good as efficient team member Starck, and Richard T. Jones, Jack Noseworthy, Jason Isaacs, and Sean Pertwee round out the cast. Things get off to a nice start with Paramount putting a fun spin on their standard logo sequence, and director Paul Anderson guides everything with style. "Event Horizon" may be derivative in some ways, but it moves along well and is never dull. Seven out of 10.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The ship's name held promise but the film fell short
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    A.N.
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I watched this after reading a Stephen Hawking book in which "event horizon" was described in terms of general relativity and black hole physics. But the hammering soundtrack in the opening credits warned me that this film probably wouldn't rise to the elegance of that concept. It had too many standard plot devices and was never really scary to me. Here are some issues, starting with most annoying first: 1) You'd think that an advanced spaceship crew would be educated like today's astronauts, not blue collar types easily bored by the scientist's explanation of a "singularity" and other aspects of black hole travel. They'd send the best of the best on such a critical mission, not jive talkers and impatient drones. "Say it in plain English!" is ridiculously overused in movies and insults an intelligent audience. A real crew of that caliber would understand black holes well beyond his folded paper demo. I know it was done for the audience's sake, but still. 2) The steam-punk gravity drive and the general interior of the ship seemed deliberately designed to convey malice, not functionality. It's almost as if the ship was built as a haunted house. Why all the spikes in the doors that humans pass through? OSHA wouldn't allow such a ship to be built. The gravity drive seemed more like a medieval torture device than something modern engineering would come up with. I suppose all the spikes could be related to magnetism but it wasn't explained. 3) The blood in the ship's structure had no scientific context. It played like a ripoff of "The Shining." This movie was too big on "fi" and too small on "sci." They should have toned down the gore. 4) Technical aspects, like the guy in the airlock spewing that much blood and living, or the astronaut being propelled back toward the planet with his breathing pack seemed ludicrous. The electronics damage to the rescue ship seemed impossible to fix. It needed a lot more than skin patches. Why do so many movies show sparks flying from sophisticated instruments which are miraculously repaired in hours? 5) The premise that we'd already colonized the Moon by 2015 was ridiculously optimistic, even in 1997. Still, it kept me entertained enough to see it through, so I gave it a neutral 5. I'd recommend "Solaris" (2002) for a much better depiction of mentally conjured people, etc. The elements of that in "Event Horizon" were done in sledgehammer style, though the eyeless wife did give me a jolt.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Repulsive movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    verna-a
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    You'll hate yourself for watching this and hate what the producers/directors of this film did to decent actors. I like sci-fi films and was attracted to the story outline. Unfortunately it soon became evident no-one had any faith in the power of storytelling and characterization to engage the audience. Instead they had to exaggerate every interaction between members of the crew to be as abrasive as possible, and introduce every cheesy and over-the-top horror film trick they could think of to progress the film. I nearly wrote "to maintain interest" but in fact it's a big turn off and you soon regard the whole affair with total contempt. Here's an example of the wit and character development in the film: black male crew member to female crew member while offering a cup of coffee "How'd you like something hot and black inside you?" (leers). Just when you think it can't get any worse with exaggerated gory special effects, it does. I see some people like this film, honestly I shudder to imagine the sort of person that would. It's quite repulsive, and the only reason I'm giving it a 2 is that I did watch it to the end to see who they could extricate from the general mayhem. I think I caught a line of dialogue "In this situation, some self-control is an advantage". Are they kidding! I hope the people responsible for this film have found employment in some other industry.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not impressed
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    (mikedennett-664-275394)
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie was far weaker than I expected. It is full of tired stereotypical character profiles (the gruff captain, the odd doctor, the yucking-it-up Chris Rock/Eddie Murphy wanna-be, the eccentric scientist who speaks in mysterious scientific mumbo-jumbo, the hardened let's-get- the-heck-out-of-here pilot, etc ad nauseum), weak acting, and an endless series of predictable disasters. I did not find it clever, inspiring, or original. Even the CGI was weak in many spots. The average rating surprises the heck out of me, are people's standards really that low? There were a few surprises, but you can make people jump out of their seats with an orchestra hit even if the screen shows a kitten licking its paw. I tend to automatically lower my expectations anytime a move starts with a teletype history line leading up to the opening scenes.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of two films i rarely watch because they are just to good
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Ark 7754
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Don't be perplexed by my summary.. This film and the ring are truly great horrors. I literally go to bed after a bit unnerved. This is probably my all time favourite horror. The shining is disturbing but i can watch it,I've watched it 5 times i think..event horizon i have watched twice. once when i was young,the second with my wife because she needed to watch it at my request lol Needless to say she caked it as well. just watch the film..yeah okay like some reviews some of its predictable..but the majority isn't and its pretty damn scary. When the scene with the footage arrives is when you know bad times ahead lol..thats not a spoiler you'll know what i mean yeah but regardless..stop reading this..go watch it
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Dark and Rather Brave Film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Michael_Elliott
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Event Horizon (1997) *** (out of 4) Dark and sometimes disturbing mix of sci-fi and horror about the spaceship Event Horizon, which went missing shortly after its mission. Seven years later it reemerges so a rescue crew goes after it trying to figure out where it's been the entire time. I saw EVENT HORIZON when it was first released and really couldn't understand why it gained so many negative reviews. There's no question that the film contains some flaws but it's also a rather ambitious film that relies just as much on its story than just the special effects. I thought director Paul Anderson did a fantastic job early on really making the viewer feel uneasy. There's a brief line where a crew member talks about how far they are from safety and this scene perfectly builds up a rather dark tension because you realize that these people really are on their own with no one to help them. The entire atmosphere of the film is incredibly dark and while I'm not going to give anything away, what the story attempts to do with where the ship has gone was rather unique and I think that for the most part it works. Now, if you've ever heard of this film then you know about the various issues it ran into during the test screenings. There's been talk of a director's cut, which I think might help out many of the flaws. The story takes us to a rather dark direction but it just seems as if something is missing. There are a few questions that need to be answered and there are a few things that don't make much sense but perhaps these were forced to be left on the cutting room floor. If so, hopefully we can see the complete version at some point. Another thing that works here are the extremely strong performances with Laurence Fishburne, Sam Neill, Kathleen Quinlan and Joely Richardson delivering great work. The special effects are also another major plus including an incredibly beautiful opening sequence as well as the effects really making you feel as if you're in space the entire time. Some have been critical of some of the graphic and bloody violence but I thought it actually played well into the story and didn't take away from anything. As it stands, EVENT HORIZON is a rather brave but flawed film but hopefully a complete version will give us a better look at what it was really trying to do.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Fun sci fi, not real scary
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ahorn88
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Just watched this movie as per the suggestion of this post. What I expected? Shocking, gory imagery. Mind bending, unsettling theories of what could be possible in this world over the next 100 years. What The movie delivered? A middling sci-fi thriller with a pretty great cast; not particularly scary. The premise is great - the human race, "flying too close to the sun," rips a hole in the fabric of space time, opening a portal to a chaotic, evil dimension. The spacecraft itself is transformed into an evil being, devouring any well-intentioned rescue crew that happens to cross its path. This is one of those movies that on paper and in my head seem incredible - limitless potential - but unfortunately the execution just did not match up. The hype I had built up based on comments people had made and a review or two that I had read prior to viewing made me expect a mind f*** to compete with other creepy sci fi flicks like The Cube or The Cell crossed with the horror and gore of Candyman. At the end of the day, I recommend checking out Event Horizon as a fun sci-fi movie that requires a bit of imagination and the suspension of disbelief thanks to the mid 90's special effects. Expect a 5/10, discover an 8/10. And that's my 2 cents.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The most frightening,effective and disturbing horror movie I have ever seen
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    yasenkiranov
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I had extremely low expectations for "Event Horizon".The film was made in a period where a lot of filmmakers thought that when you have enough money to use and abuse CGI your movie doesn't need a decent script.With that in mind I thought "Event Horizon" was going to be a clich&eacute; horror film that makes no effort to build suspense and just throws CG blood and gore in your face.I was wrong.Dead wrong. "Event Horizon" is the creepiest and most suspenseful horror movie I have ever seen.It manages to create a feeling of dread and foreboding like no other film I have ever seen before.This is due to a combination of great camera-work,appropriate music and(believe it or not) CG.Yes,the CGI is actually used appropriately here,not just added for the sake of it being there.That said,the special effects are top-notch(for 1997). Another thing I liked was that the ship itself wasn't the main threat.It was the characters.They become obsessed with their past mistakes(things they had locked away in their minds and didn't want to remember) and that begins to drive them insane.True,the ship is the catalyst for this,but the focus is more on the characters themselves.This reminds me of "Cube"-one of my favorite movies. The characters themselves are a bit underdeveloped,but they aren't cannon fodder like in many other horror films.Each of them has their the distinct personality and background information is given about some of them.I think this was alright for the purpose of this film.In my opinion ,if they did add more character development it would have ruined the pacing. "Event Horizon" is a very well made,but sadly underrated, horror movie.I strongly recommend it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I wasn't amazed by this movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jklimentowski
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A horror science-fiction movie. When I think of this genre I always have "Alien" on my mind. I think this is a perfect example. Unfortunately "Event Horizon" lacks both in the horror and science-fiction parts. As for the science fiction - well it is just not realistic enough. Of course not all movies should be as realistic as "2010: Space Odyssey", but still when you compare it to "Alien" it turns out quite poor. Actually there is not much realism or physics in it at all. OK - the idea of time-space folding is nice, but the idea itself is at least as old as The Dune movie, or perhaps even older. I liked the scene of transition from zero gravity to artificial-earth gravity with fluids and bodies instantly dropping. The decompression sequence tries to be more horror like than scientific... and that is all I think. The rest is just pure fantasy. So forget about science-fiction - is it a good horror? This might be a difficult question for me as most horrors make me laugh rather than scare mostly due to their stupidity and lack of realism. There are of course exceptions like Alien or The Thing. What makes the difference? I think it is the realism of the situation. I really can't be scared by ghosts which can do anything. It is just too unreal - I can not place myself in such a world and my imagination fails. Unfortunately Event Horizon is a movie it this ghost type. Anything can happen therefore I do not feel like one of the terrified crew members, rather I wonder what could the director think of next. Of course there are some more or less scary moments, but these are just typical horror tricks - sudden action with a proper sound effect. There is no feel of terror while watching the movie. Another thing at which the movie fails is the plot. While the beginning sequences are quite interesting with every minute the plot becomes more and more chaotic. At some stage one really gets bored as it seems that there is no real goal or solution of the plot. One by one some things happen which try to scare you, but there is no logic in them. I can imagine that such a movie could last for a long time with random scary adventures happening to the characters until all of them are dead. But what is the point of watching that? Unfortunately the ending is also quite predictable and gives you no satisfaction of discovering something interesting or an unexpected solution. It is just as plain as that. OK - so is the movie really so bad? Well it is not a perfect movie, but not a terrible one either. One can watch it and have some fun but it is not a movie that you would like to come back to after years. Just see once, have fun and forget. It is worth to mention that the move has it's own style. While placed in future all the ships and equipment sometimes look like designed in the past. I can't describe it exactly but sometimes I had a feel of watching a sci-fiction movie from the fifties. Why did the director decide to chose such a scenography instead of pure futuristic one? No idea but I think it works fine.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    a waste of space-time
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Sven Jolly
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Another dump of cinematic excrement, this drivel is a disjointed mish mash of several other, greatly superior sci-fi movies, cribbed together in a random fashion to achieve nothing but boredom in the hapless viewer. One part Alien, one part Apollo 13, a "rotating magnetic field" gizmo that looks suspiciously like "Contact" this movie meanders all over the place. The story is stupid, with time travel, hallucinations, time/space monsters - it's as if they just tossed everything they could think of in a cut-up process to derive some semblance of a story line. Every character is pure stereotype, the dialogue is inane, seemingly composed by a group of high school boys, or perhaps one thousand monkey's typing randomly. After one hour of viewing you will have no idea what is going on, and neither do the characters or the writers. I couldn't finish watching this rubbish, one hour was all I could stand. MINUS -10 out of 10 for wasting my time. Strongly suggest you don't waste yours.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Creepy at times.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Scott LeBrun (Hey_Sweden)
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Right from the beginning, it may be clear that "Event Horizon" owes a pretty big debt to "Alien" (but then, so do many other post-1979 films) but it does have a fairly interesting story and it does live up to the word "horror". It gets substantially unnerving and creates some wonderfully horrific imagery. In fact, as films of this type go, it's a pleasure in terms of the visuals - special effects, sets, cinematography. Devotees of these genres should find it to be solid if not exceptional entertainment. They may find the "science" ludicrous, but still be amused. In the year 2047, an exploratory spaceship, the "Event Horizon" of the title, has reappeared after having been lost for seven years. A U.S.A.C. team is launched to find out what happened, and rescue any possible survivors. They do this in the company of the ships' designer, William Weir (Sam Neill), who has a tragedy in his past, and members of the team bring their own baggage to the situation, with no-nonsense Captain Miller (Laurence Fishburne) in charge of the mission. What they learn is that the ship now seems to be "alive", and aware of what has happened in the teams' pasts. The script by Philip Eisner is not without humour, but it mostly plays things straight, and the cast performs it with real gravity. Fishburne is good as a rock-solid type of man, while Neill gets a chance to tear into the scenery as Weir becomes more and more deranged. Kathleen Quinlan is affecting as Peters, who is having to deal with child custody issues in her personal life. Joely Richardson is good as efficient team member Starck, and Richard T. Jones, Jack Noseworthy, Jason Isaacs, and Sean Pertwee round out the cast. Things get off to a nice start with Paramount putting a fun spin on their standard logo sequence, and director Paul Anderson guides everything with style. "Event Horizon" may be derivative in some ways, but it moves along well and is never dull. Seven out of 10.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The ship's name held promise but the film fell short
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    A.N.
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I watched this after reading a Stephen Hawking book in which "event horizon" was described in terms of general relativity and black hole physics. But the hammering soundtrack in the opening credits warned me that this film probably wouldn't rise to the elegance of that concept. It had too many standard plot devices and was never really scary to me. Here are some issues, starting with most annoying first: 1) You'd think that an advanced spaceship crew would be educated like today's astronauts, not blue collar types easily bored by the scientist's explanation of a "singularity" and other aspects of black hole travel. They'd send the best of the best on such a critical mission, not jive talkers and impatient drones. "Say it in plain English!" is ridiculously overused in movies and insults an intelligent audience. A real crew of that caliber would understand black holes well beyond his folded paper demo. I know it was done for the audience's sake, but still. 2) The steam-punk gravity drive and the general interior of the ship seemed deliberately designed to convey malice, not functionality. It's almost as if the ship was built as a haunted house. Why all the spikes in the doors that humans pass through? OSHA wouldn't allow such a ship to be built. The gravity drive seemed more like a medieval torture device than something modern engineering would come up with. I suppose all the spikes could be related to magnetism but it wasn't explained. 3) The blood in the ship's structure had no scientific context. It played like a ripoff of "The Shining." This movie was too big on "fi" and too small on "sci." They should have toned down the gore. 4) Technical aspects, like the guy in the airlock spewing that much blood and living, or the astronaut being propelled back toward the planet with his breathing pack seemed ludicrous. The electronics damage to the rescue ship seemed impossible to fix. It needed a lot more than skin patches. Why do so many movies show sparks flying from sophisticated instruments which are miraculously repaired in hours? 5) The premise that we'd already colonized the Moon by 2015 was ridiculously optimistic, even in 1997. Still, it kept me entertained enough to see it through, so I gave it a neutral 5. I'd recommend "Solaris" (2002) for a much better depiction of mentally conjured people, etc. The elements of that in "Event Horizon" were done in sledgehammer style, though the eyeless wife did give me a jolt.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Repulsive movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    verna-a
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    You'll hate yourself for watching this and hate what the producers/directors of this film did to decent actors. I like sci-fi films and was attracted to the story outline. Unfortunately it soon became evident no-one had any faith in the power of storytelling and characterization to engage the audience. Instead they had to exaggerate every interaction between members of the crew to be as abrasive as possible, and introduce every cheesy and over-the-top horror film trick they could think of to progress the film. I nearly wrote "to maintain interest" but in fact it's a big turn off and you soon regard the whole affair with total contempt. Here's an example of the wit and character development in the film: black male crew member to female crew member while offering a cup of coffee "How'd you like something hot and black inside you?" (leers). Just when you think it can't get any worse with exaggerated gory special effects, it does. I see some people like this film, honestly I shudder to imagine the sort of person that would. It's quite repulsive, and the only reason I'm giving it a 2 is that I did watch it to the end to see who they could extricate from the general mayhem. I think I caught a line of dialogue "In this situation, some self-control is an advantage". Are they kidding! I hope the people responsible for this film have found employment in some other industry.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not impressed
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    (mikedennett-664-275394)
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie was far weaker than I expected. It is full of tired stereotypical character profiles (the gruff captain, the odd doctor, the yucking-it-up Chris Rock/Eddie Murphy wanna-be, the eccentric scientist who speaks in mysterious scientific mumbo-jumbo, the hardened let's-get- the-heck-out-of-here pilot, etc ad nauseum), weak acting, and an endless series of predictable disasters. I did not find it clever, inspiring, or original. Even the CGI was weak in many spots. The average rating surprises the heck out of me, are people's standards really that low? There were a few surprises, but you can make people jump out of their seats with an orchestra hit even if the screen shows a kitten licking its paw. I tend to automatically lower my expectations anytime a move starts with a teletype history line leading up to the opening scenes.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of two films i rarely watch because they are just to good
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Ark 7754
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Don't be perplexed by my summary.. This film and the ring are truly great horrors. I literally go to bed after a bit unnerved. This is probably my all time favourite horror. The shining is disturbing but i can watch it,I've watched it 5 times i think..event horizon i have watched twice. once when i was young,the second with my wife because she needed to watch it at my request lol Needless to say she caked it as well. just watch the film..yeah okay like some reviews some of its predictable..but the majority isn't and its pretty damn scary. When the scene with the footage arrives is when you know bad times ahead lol..thats not a spoiler you'll know what i mean yeah but regardless..stop reading this..go watch it
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Dark and Rather Brave Film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Michael_Elliott
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Event Horizon (1997) *** (out of 4) Dark and sometimes disturbing mix of sci-fi and horror about the spaceship Event Horizon, which went missing shortly after its mission. Seven years later it reemerges so a rescue crew goes after it trying to figure out where it's been the entire time. I saw EVENT HORIZON when it was first released and really couldn't understand why it gained so many negative reviews. There's no question that the film contains some flaws but it's also a rather ambitious film that relies just as much on its story than just the special effects. I thought director Paul Anderson did a fantastic job early on really making the viewer feel uneasy. There's a brief line where a crew member talks about how far they are from safety and this scene perfectly builds up a rather dark tension because you realize that these people really are on their own with no one to help them. The entire atmosphere of the film is incredibly dark and while I'm not going to give anything away, what the story attempts to do with where the ship has gone was rather unique and I think that for the most part it works. Now, if you've ever heard of this film then you know about the various issues it ran into during the test screenings. There's been talk of a director's cut, which I think might help out many of the flaws. The story takes us to a rather dark direction but it just seems as if something is missing. There are a few questions that need to be answered and there are a few things that don't make much sense but perhaps these were forced to be left on the cutting room floor. If so, hopefully we can see the complete version at some point. Another thing that works here are the extremely strong performances with Laurence Fishburne, Sam Neill, Kathleen Quinlan and Joely Richardson delivering great work. The special effects are also another major plus including an incredibly beautiful opening sequence as well as the effects really making you feel as if you're in space the entire time. Some have been critical of some of the graphic and bloody violence but I thought it actually played well into the story and didn't take away from anything. As it stands, EVENT HORIZON is a rather brave but flawed film but hopefully a complete version will give us a better look at what it was really trying to do.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Fun sci fi, not real scary
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ahorn88
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Just watched this movie as per the suggestion of this post. What I expected? Shocking, gory imagery. Mind bending, unsettling theories of what could be possible in this world over the next 100 years. What The movie delivered? A middling sci-fi thriller with a pretty great cast; not particularly scary. The premise is great - the human race, "flying too close to the sun," rips a hole in the fabric of space time, opening a portal to a chaotic, evil dimension. The spacecraft itself is transformed into an evil being, devouring any well-intentioned rescue crew that happens to cross its path. This is one of those movies that on paper and in my head seem incredible - limitless potential - but unfortunately the execution just did not match up. The hype I had built up based on comments people had made and a review or two that I had read prior to viewing made me expect a mind f*** to compete with other creepy sci fi flicks like The Cube or The Cell crossed with the horror and gore of Candyman. At the end of the day, I recommend checking out Event Horizon as a fun sci-fi movie that requires a bit of imagination and the suspension of disbelief thanks to the mid 90's special effects. Expect a 5/10, discover an 8/10. And that's my 2 cents.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The most frightening,effective and disturbing horror movie I have ever seen
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    yasenkiranov
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I had extremely low expectations for "Event Horizon".The film was made in a period where a lot of filmmakers thought that when you have enough money to use and abuse CGI your movie doesn't need a decent script.With that in mind I thought "Event Horizon" was going to be a clich&eacute; horror film that makes no effort to build suspense and just throws CG blood and gore in your face.I was wrong.Dead wrong. "Event Horizon" is the creepiest and most suspenseful horror movie I have ever seen.It manages to create a feeling of dread and foreboding like no other film I have ever seen before.This is due to a combination of great camera-work,appropriate music and(believe it or not) CG.Yes,the CGI is actually used appropriately here,not just added for the sake of it being there.That said,the special effects are top-notch(for 1997). Another thing I liked was that the ship itself wasn't the main threat.It was the characters.They become obsessed with their past mistakes(things they had locked away in their minds and didn't want to remember) and that begins to drive them insane.True,the ship is the catalyst for this,but the focus is more on the characters themselves.This reminds me of "Cube"-one of my favorite movies. The characters themselves are a bit underdeveloped,but they aren't cannon fodder like in many other horror films.Each of them has their the distinct personality and background information is given about some of them.I think this was alright for the purpose of this film.In my opinion ,if they did add more character development it would have ruined the pacing. "Event Horizon" is a very well made,but sadly underrated, horror movie.I strongly recommend it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I wasn't amazed by this movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jklimentowski
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A horror science-fiction movie. When I think of this genre I always have "Alien" on my mind. I think this is a perfect example. Unfortunately "Event Horizon" lacks both in the horror and science-fiction parts. As for the science fiction - well it is just not realistic enough. Of course not all movies should be as realistic as "2010: Space Odyssey", but still when you compare it to "Alien" it turns out quite poor. Actually there is not much realism or physics in it at all. OK - the idea of time-space folding is nice, but the idea itself is at least as old as The Dune movie, or perhaps even older. I liked the scene of transition from zero gravity to artificial-earth gravity with fluids and bodies instantly dropping. The decompression sequence tries to be more horror like than scientific... and that is all I think. The rest is just pure fantasy. So forget about science-fiction - is it a good horror? This might be a difficult question for me as most horrors make me laugh rather than scare mostly due to their stupidity and lack of realism. There are of course exceptions like Alien or The Thing. What makes the difference? I think it is the realism of the situation. I really can't be scared by ghosts which can do anything. It is just too unreal - I can not place myself in such a world and my imagination fails. Unfortunately Event Horizon is a movie it this ghost type. Anything can happen therefore I do not feel like one of the terrified crew members, rather I wonder what could the director think of next. Of course there are some more or less scary moments, but these are just typical horror tricks - sudden action with a proper sound effect. There is no feel of terror while watching the movie. Another thing at which the movie fails is the plot. While the beginning sequences are quite interesting with every minute the plot becomes more and more chaotic. At some stage one really gets bored as it seems that there is no real goal or solution of the plot. One by one some things happen which try to scare you, but there is no logic in them. I can imagine that such a movie could last for a long time with random scary adventures happening to the characters until all of them are dead. But what is the point of watching that? Unfortunately the ending is also quite predictable and gives you no satisfaction of discovering something interesting or an unexpected solution. It is just as plain as that. OK - so is the movie really so bad? Well it is not a perfect movie, but not a terrible one either. One can watch it and have some fun but it is not a movie that you would like to come back to after years. Just see once, have fun and forget. It is worth to mention that the move has it's own style. While placed in future all the ships and equipment sometimes look like designed in the past. I can't describe it exactly but sometimes I had a feel of watching a sci-fiction movie from the fifties. Why did the director decide to chose such a scenography instead of pure futuristic one? No idea but I think it works fine.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    a waste of space-time
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Sven Jolly
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Another dump of cinematic excrement, this drivel is a disjointed mish mash of several other, greatly superior sci-fi movies, cribbed together in a random fashion to achieve nothing but boredom in the hapless viewer. One part Alien, one part Apollo 13, a "rotating magnetic field" gizmo that looks suspiciously like "Contact" this movie meanders all over the place. The story is stupid, with time travel, hallucinations, time/space monsters - it's as if they just tossed everything they could think of in a cut-up process to derive some semblance of a story line. Every character is pure stereotype, the dialogue is inane, seemingly composed by a group of high school boys, or perhaps one thousand monkey's typing randomly. After one hour of viewing you will have no idea what is going on, and neither do the characters or the writers. I couldn't finish watching this rubbish, one hour was all I could stand. MINUS -10 out of 10 for wasting my time. Strongly suggest you don't waste yours.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Creepy at times.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Scott LeBrun (Hey_Sweden)
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Right from the beginning, it may be clear that "Event Horizon" owes a pretty big debt to "Alien" (but then, so do many other post-1979 films) but it does have a fairly interesting story and it does live up to the word "horror". It gets substantially unnerving and creates some wonderfully horrific imagery. In fact, as films of this type go, it's a pleasure in terms of the visuals - special effects, sets, cinematography. Devotees of these genres should find it to be solid if not exceptional entertainment. They may find the "science" ludicrous, but still be amused. In the year 2047, an exploratory spaceship, the "Event Horizon" of the title, has reappeared after having been lost for seven years. A U.S.A.C. team is launched to find out what happened, and rescue any possible survivors. They do this in the company of the ships' designer, William Weir (Sam Neill), who has a tragedy in his past, and members of the team bring their own baggage to the situation, with no-nonsense Captain Miller (Laurence Fishburne) in charge of the mission. What they learn is that the ship now seems to be "alive", and aware of what has happened in the teams' pasts. The script by Philip Eisner is not without humour, but it mostly plays things straight, and the cast performs it with real gravity. Fishburne is good as a rock-solid type of man, while Neill gets a chance to tear into the scenery as Weir becomes more and more deranged. Kathleen Quinlan is affecting as Peters, who is having to deal with child custody issues in her personal life. Joely Richardson is good as efficient team member Starck, and Richard T. Jones, Jack Noseworthy, Jason Isaacs, and Sean Pertwee round out the cast. Things get off to a nice start with Paramount putting a fun spin on their standard logo sequence, and director Paul Anderson guides everything with style. "Event Horizon" may be derivative in some ways, but it moves along well and is never dull. Seven out of 10.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The ship's name held promise but the film fell short
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    A.N.
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I watched this after reading a Stephen Hawking book in which "event horizon" was described in terms of general relativity and black hole physics. But the hammering soundtrack in the opening credits warned me that this film probably wouldn't rise to the elegance of that concept. It had too many standard plot devices and was never really scary to me. Here are some issues, starting with most annoying first: 1) You'd think that an advanced spaceship crew would be educated like today's astronauts, not blue collar types easily bored by the scientist's explanation of a "singularity" and other aspects of black hole travel. They'd send the best of the best on such a critical mission, not jive talkers and impatient drones. "Say it in plain English!" is ridiculously overused in movies and insults an intelligent audience. A real crew of that caliber would understand black holes well beyond his folded paper demo. I know it was done for the audience's sake, but still. 2) The steam-punk gravity drive and the general interior of the ship seemed deliberately designed to convey malice, not functionality. It's almost as if the ship was built as a haunted house. Why all the spikes in the doors that humans pass through? OSHA wouldn't allow such a ship to be built. The gravity drive seemed more like a medieval torture device than something modern engineering would come up with. I suppose all the spikes could be related to magnetism but it wasn't explained. 3) The blood in the ship's structure had no scientific context. It played like a ripoff of "The Shining." This movie was too big on "fi" and too small on "sci." They should have toned down the gore. 4) Technical aspects, like the guy in the airlock spewing that much blood and living, or the astronaut being propelled back toward the planet with his breathing pack seemed ludicrous. The electronics damage to the rescue ship seemed impossible to fix. It needed a lot more than skin patches. Why do so many movies show sparks flying from sophisticated instruments which are miraculously repaired in hours? 5) The premise that we'd already colonized the Moon by 2015 was ridiculously optimistic, even in 1997. Still, it kept me entertained enough to see it through, so I gave it a neutral 5. I'd recommend "Solaris" (2002) for a much better depiction of mentally conjured people, etc. The elements of that in "Event Horizon" were done in sledgehammer style, though the eyeless wife did give me a jolt.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Repulsive movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    verna-a
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    You'll hate yourself for watching this and hate what the producers/directors of this film did to decent actors. I like sci-fi films and was attracted to the story outline. Unfortunately it soon became evident no-one had any faith in the power of storytelling and characterization to engage the audience. Instead they had to exaggerate every interaction between members of the crew to be as abrasive as possible, and introduce every cheesy and over-the-top horror film trick they could think of to progress the film. I nearly wrote "to maintain interest" but in fact it's a big turn off and you soon regard the whole affair with total contempt. Here's an example of the wit and character development in the film: black male crew member to female crew member while offering a cup of coffee "How'd you like something hot and black inside you?" (leers). Just when you think it can't get any worse with exaggerated gory special effects, it does. I see some people like this film, honestly I shudder to imagine the sort of person that would. It's quite repulsive, and the only reason I'm giving it a 2 is that I did watch it to the end to see who they could extricate from the general mayhem. I think I caught a line of dialogue "In this situation, some self-control is an advantage". Are they kidding! I hope the people responsible for this film have found employment in some other industry.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not impressed
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    (mikedennett-664-275394)
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie was far weaker than I expected. It is full of tired stereotypical character profiles (the gruff captain, the odd doctor, the yucking-it-up Chris Rock/Eddie Murphy wanna-be, the eccentric scientist who speaks in mysterious scientific mumbo-jumbo, the hardened let's-get- the-heck-out-of-here pilot, etc ad nauseum), weak acting, and an endless series of predictable disasters. I did not find it clever, inspiring, or original. Even the CGI was weak in many spots. The average rating surprises the heck out of me, are people's standards really that low? There were a few surprises, but you can make people jump out of their seats with an orchestra hit even if the screen shows a kitten licking its paw. I tend to automatically lower my expectations anytime a move starts with a teletype history line leading up to the opening scenes.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of two films i rarely watch because they are just to good
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Ark 7754
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Don't be perplexed by my summary.. This film and the ring are truly great horrors. I literally go to bed after a bit unnerved. This is probably my all time favourite horror. The shining is disturbing but i can watch it,I've watched it 5 times i think..event horizon i have watched twice. once when i was young,the second with my wife because she needed to watch it at my request lol Needless to say she caked it as well. just watch the film..yeah okay like some reviews some of its predictable..but the majority isn't and its pretty damn scary. When the scene with the footage arrives is when you know bad times ahead lol..thats not a spoiler you'll know what i mean yeah but regardless..stop reading this..go watch it
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Dark and Rather Brave Film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Michael_Elliott
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Event Horizon (1997) *** (out of 4) Dark and sometimes disturbing mix of sci-fi and horror about the spaceship Event Horizon, which went missing shortly after its mission. Seven years later it reemerges so a rescue crew goes after it trying to figure out where it's been the entire time. I saw EVENT HORIZON when it was first released and really couldn't understand why it gained so many negative reviews. There's no question that the film contains some flaws but it's also a rather ambitious film that relies just as much on its story than just the special effects. I thought director Paul Anderson did a fantastic job early on really making the viewer feel uneasy. There's a brief line where a crew member talks about how far they are from safety and this scene perfectly builds up a rather dark tension because you realize that these people really are on their own with no one to help them. The entire atmosphere of the film is incredibly dark and while I'm not going to give anything away, what the story attempts to do with where the ship has gone was rather unique and I think that for the most part it works. Now, if you've ever heard of this film then you know about the various issues it ran into during the test screenings. There's been talk of a director's cut, which I think might help out many of the flaws. The story takes us to a rather dark direction but it just seems as if something is missing. There are a few questions that need to be answered and there are a few things that don't make much sense but perhaps these were forced to be left on the cutting room floor. If so, hopefully we can see the complete version at some point. Another thing that works here are the extremely strong performances with Laurence Fishburne, Sam Neill, Kathleen Quinlan and Joely Richardson delivering great work. The special effects are also another major plus including an incredibly beautiful opening sequence as well as the effects really making you feel as if you're in space the entire time. Some have been critical of some of the graphic and bloody violence but I thought it actually played well into the story and didn't take away from anything. As it stands, EVENT HORIZON is a rather brave but flawed film but hopefully a complete version will give us a better look at what it was really trying to do.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Fun sci fi, not real scary
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ahorn88
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Just watched this movie as per the suggestion of this post. What I expected? Shocking, gory imagery. Mind bending, unsettling theories of what could be possible in this world over the next 100 years. What The movie delivered? A middling sci-fi thriller with a pretty great cast; not particularly scary. The premise is great - the human race, "flying too close to the sun," rips a hole in the fabric of space time, opening a portal to a chaotic, evil dimension. The spacecraft itself is transformed into an evil being, devouring any well-intentioned rescue crew that happens to cross its path. This is one of those movies that on paper and in my head seem incredible - limitless potential - but unfortunately the execution just did not match up. The hype I had built up based on comments people had made and a review or two that I had read prior to viewing made me expect a mind f*** to compete with other creepy sci fi flicks like The Cube or The Cell crossed with the horror and gore of Candyman. At the end of the day, I recommend checking out Event Horizon as a fun sci-fi movie that requires a bit of imagination and the suspension of disbelief thanks to the mid 90's special effects. Expect a 5/10, discover an 8/10. And that's my 2 cents.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The most frightening,effective and disturbing horror movie I have ever seen
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    yasenkiranov
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I had extremely low expectations for "Event Horizon".The film was made in a period where a lot of filmmakers thought that when you have enough money to use and abuse CGI your movie doesn't need a decent script.With that in mind I thought "Event Horizon" was going to be a clich&eacute; horror film that makes no effort to build suspense and just throws CG blood and gore in your face.I was wrong.Dead wrong. "Event Horizon" is the creepiest and most suspenseful horror movie I have ever seen.It manages to create a feeling of dread and foreboding like no other film I have ever seen before.This is due to a combination of great camera-work,appropriate music and(believe it or not) CG.Yes,the CGI is actually used appropriately here,not just added for the sake of it being there.That said,the special effects are top-notch(for 1997). Another thing I liked was that the ship itself wasn't the main threat.It was the characters.They become obsessed with their past mistakes(things they had locked away in their minds and didn't want to remember) and that begins to drive them insane.True,the ship is the catalyst for this,but the focus is more on the characters themselves.This reminds me of "Cube"-one of my favorite movies. The characters themselves are a bit underdeveloped,but they aren't cannon fodder like in many other horror films.Each of them has their the distinct personality and background information is given about some of them.I think this was alright for the purpose of this film.In my opinion ,if they did add more character development it would have ruined the pacing. "Event Horizon" is a very well made,but sadly underrated, horror movie.I strongly recommend it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I wasn't amazed by this movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jklimentowski
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A horror science-fiction movie. When I think of this genre I always have "Alien" on my mind. I think this is a perfect example. Unfortunately "Event Horizon" lacks both in the horror and science-fiction parts. As for the science fiction - well it is just not realistic enough. Of course not all movies should be as realistic as "2010: Space Odyssey", but still when you compare it to "Alien" it turns out quite poor. Actually there is not much realism or physics in it at all. OK - the idea of time-space folding is nice, but the idea itself is at least as old as The Dune movie, or perhaps even older. I liked the scene of transition from zero gravity to artificial-earth gravity with fluids and bodies instantly dropping. The decompression sequence tries to be more horror like than scientific... and that is all I think. The rest is just pure fantasy. So forget about science-fiction - is it a good horror? This might be a difficult question for me as most horrors make me laugh rather than scare mostly due to their stupidity and lack of realism. There are of course exceptions like Alien or The Thing. What makes the difference? I think it is the realism of the situation. I really can't be scared by ghosts which can do anything. It is just too unreal - I can not place myself in such a world and my imagination fails. Unfortunately Event Horizon is a movie it this ghost type. Anything can happen therefore I do not feel like one of the terrified crew members, rather I wonder what could the director think of next. Of course there are some more or less scary moments, but these are just typical horror tricks - sudden action with a proper sound effect. There is no feel of terror while watching the movie. Another thing at which the movie fails is the plot. While the beginning sequences are quite interesting with every minute the plot becomes more and more chaotic. At some stage one really gets bored as it seems that there is no real goal or solution of the plot. One by one some things happen which try to scare you, but there is no logic in them. I can imagine that such a movie could last for a long time with random scary adventures happening to the characters until all of them are dead. But what is the point of watching that? Unfortunately the ending is also quite predictable and gives you no satisfaction of discovering something interesting or an unexpected solution. It is just as plain as that. OK - so is the movie really so bad? Well it is not a perfect movie, but not a terrible one either. One can watch it and have some fun but it is not a movie that you would like to come back to after years. Just see once, have fun and forget. It is worth to mention that the move has it's own style. While placed in future all the ships and equipment sometimes look like designed in the past. I can't describe it exactly but sometimes I had a feel of watching a sci-fiction movie from the fifties. Why did the director decide to chose such a scenography instead of pure futuristic one? No idea but I think it works fine.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    a waste of space-time
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Sven Jolly
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Another dump of cinematic excrement, this drivel is a disjointed mish mash of several other, greatly superior sci-fi movies, cribbed together in a random fashion to achieve nothing but boredom in the hapless viewer. One part Alien, one part Apollo 13, a "rotating magnetic field" gizmo that looks suspiciously like "Contact" this movie meanders all over the place. The story is stupid, with time travel, hallucinations, time/space monsters - it's as if they just tossed everything they could think of in a cut-up process to derive some semblance of a story line. Every character is pure stereotype, the dialogue is inane, seemingly composed by a group of high school boys, or perhaps one thousand monkey's typing randomly. After one hour of viewing you will have no idea what is going on, and neither do the characters or the writers. I couldn't finish watching this rubbish, one hour was all I could stand. MINUS -10 out of 10 for wasting my time. Strongly suggest you don't waste yours.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Creepy at times.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Scott LeBrun (Hey_Sweden)
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Right from the beginning, it may be clear that "Event Horizon" owes a pretty big debt to "Alien" (but then, so do many other post-1979 films) but it does have a fairly interesting story and it does live up to the word "horror". It gets substantially unnerving and creates some wonderfully horrific imagery. In fact, as films of this type go, it's a pleasure in terms of the visuals - special effects, sets, cinematography. Devotees of these genres should find it to be solid if not exceptional entertainment. They may find the "science" ludicrous, but still be amused. In the year 2047, an exploratory spaceship, the "Event Horizon" of the title, has reappeared after having been lost for seven years. A U.S.A.C. team is launched to find out what happened, and rescue any possible survivors. They do this in the company of the ships' designer, William Weir (Sam Neill), who has a tragedy in his past, and members of the team bring their own baggage to the situation, with no-nonsense Captain Miller (Laurence Fishburne) in charge of the mission. What they learn is that the ship now seems to be "alive", and aware of what has happened in the teams' pasts. The script by Philip Eisner is not without humour, but it mostly plays things straight, and the cast performs it with real gravity. Fishburne is good as a rock-solid type of man, while Neill gets a chance to tear into the scenery as Weir becomes more and more deranged. Kathleen Quinlan is affecting as Peters, who is having to deal with child custody issues in her personal life. Joely Richardson is good as efficient team member Starck, and Richard T. Jones, Jack Noseworthy, Jason Isaacs, and Sean Pertwee round out the cast. Things get off to a nice start with Paramount putting a fun spin on their standard logo sequence, and director Paul Anderson guides everything with style. "Event Horizon" may be derivative in some ways, but it moves along well and is never dull. Seven out of 10.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The ship's name held promise but the film fell short
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    A.N.
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I watched this after reading a Stephen Hawking book in which "event horizon" was described in terms of general relativity and black hole physics. But the hammering soundtrack in the opening credits warned me that this film probably wouldn't rise to the elegance of that concept. It had too many standard plot devices and was never really scary to me. Here are some issues, starting with most annoying first: 1) You'd think that an advanced spaceship crew would be educated like today's astronauts, not blue collar types easily bored by the scientist's explanation of a "singularity" and other aspects of black hole travel. They'd send the best of the best on such a critical mission, not jive talkers and impatient drones. "Say it in plain English!" is ridiculously overused in movies and insults an intelligent audience. A real crew of that caliber would understand black holes well beyond his folded paper demo. I know it was done for the audience's sake, but still. 2) The steam-punk gravity drive and the general interior of the ship seemed deliberately designed to convey malice, not functionality. It's almost as if the ship was built as a haunted house. Why all the spikes in the doors that humans pass through? OSHA wouldn't allow such a ship to be built. The gravity drive seemed more like a medieval torture device than something modern engineering would come up with. I suppose all the spikes could be related to magnetism but it wasn't explained. 3) The blood in the ship's structure had no scientific context. It played like a ripoff of "The Shining." This movie was too big on "fi" and too small on "sci." They should have toned down the gore. 4) Technical aspects, like the guy in the airlock spewing that much blood and living, or the astronaut being propelled back toward the planet with his breathing pack seemed ludicrous. The electronics damage to the rescue ship seemed impossible to fix. It needed a lot more than skin patches. Why do so many movies show sparks flying from sophisticated instruments which are miraculously repaired in hours? 5) The premise that we'd already colonized the Moon by 2015 was ridiculously optimistic, even in 1997. Still, it kept me entertained enough to see it through, so I gave it a neutral 5. I'd recommend "Solaris" (2002) for a much better depiction of mentally conjured people, etc. The elements of that in "Event Horizon" were done in sledgehammer style, though the eyeless wife did give me a jolt.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Repulsive movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    verna-a
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    You'll hate yourself for watching this and hate what the producers/directors of this film did to decent actors. I like sci-fi films and was attracted to the story outline. Unfortunately it soon became evident no-one had any faith in the power of storytelling and characterization to engage the audience. Instead they had to exaggerate every interaction between members of the crew to be as abrasive as possible, and introduce every cheesy and over-the-top horror film trick they could think of to progress the film. I nearly wrote "to maintain interest" but in fact it's a big turn off and you soon regard the whole affair with total contempt. Here's an example of the wit and character development in the film: black male crew member to female crew member while offering a cup of coffee "How'd you like something hot and black inside you?" (leers). Just when you think it can't get any worse with exaggerated gory special effects, it does. I see some people like this film, honestly I shudder to imagine the sort of person that would. It's quite repulsive, and the only reason I'm giving it a 2 is that I did watch it to the end to see who they could extricate from the general mayhem. I think I caught a line of dialogue "In this situation, some self-control is an advantage". Are they kidding! I hope the people responsible for this film have found employment in some other industry.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not impressed
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    (mikedennett-664-275394)
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie was far weaker than I expected. It is full of tired stereotypical character profiles (the gruff captain, the odd doctor, the yucking-it-up Chris Rock/Eddie Murphy wanna-be, the eccentric scientist who speaks in mysterious scientific mumbo-jumbo, the hardened let's-get- the-heck-out-of-here pilot, etc ad nauseum), weak acting, and an endless series of predictable disasters. I did not find it clever, inspiring, or original. Even the CGI was weak in many spots. The average rating surprises the heck out of me, are people's standards really that low? There were a few surprises, but you can make people jump out of their seats with an orchestra hit even if the screen shows a kitten licking its paw. I tend to automatically lower my expectations anytime a move starts with a teletype history line leading up to the opening scenes.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of two films i rarely watch because they are just to good
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Ark 7754
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Don't be perplexed by my summary.. This film and the ring are truly great horrors. I literally go to bed after a bit unnerved. This is probably my all time favourite horror. The shining is disturbing but i can watch it,I've watched it 5 times i think..event horizon i have watched twice. once when i was young,the second with my wife because she needed to watch it at my request lol Needless to say she caked it as well. just watch the film..yeah okay like some reviews some of its predictable..but the majority isn't and its pretty damn scary. When the scene with the footage arrives is when you know bad times ahead lol..thats not a spoiler you'll know what i mean yeah but regardless..stop reading this..go watch it
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Dark and Rather Brave Film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Michael_Elliott
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Event Horizon (1997) *** (out of 4) Dark and sometimes disturbing mix of sci-fi and horror about the spaceship Event Horizon, which went missing shortly after its mission. Seven years later it reemerges so a rescue crew goes after it trying to figure out where it's been the entire time. I saw EVENT HORIZON when it was first released and really couldn't understand why it gained so many negative reviews. There's no question that the film contains some flaws but it's also a rather ambitious film that relies just as much on its story than just the special effects. I thought director Paul Anderson did a fantastic job early on really making the viewer feel uneasy. There's a brief line where a crew member talks about how far they are from safety and this scene perfectly builds up a rather dark tension because you realize that these people really are on their own with no one to help them. The entire atmosphere of the film is incredibly dark and while I'm not going to give anything away, what the story attempts to do with where the ship has gone was rather unique and I think that for the most part it works. Now, if you've ever heard of this film then you know about the various issues it ran into during the test screenings. There's been talk of a director's cut, which I think might help out many of the flaws. The story takes us to a rather dark direction but it just seems as if something is missing. There are a few questions that need to be answered and there are a few things that don't make much sense but perhaps these were forced to be left on the cutting room floor. If so, hopefully we can see the complete version at some point. Another thing that works here are the extremely strong performances with Laurence Fishburne, Sam Neill, Kathleen Quinlan and Joely Richardson delivering great work. The special effects are also another major plus including an incredibly beautiful opening sequence as well as the effects really making you feel as if you're in space the entire time. Some have been critical of some of the graphic and bloody violence but I thought it actually played well into the story and didn't take away from anything. As it stands, EVENT HORIZON is a rather brave but flawed film but hopefully a complete version will give us a better look at what it was really trying to do.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Fun sci fi, not real scary
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ahorn88
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Just watched this movie as per the suggestion of this post. What I expected? Shocking, gory imagery. Mind bending, unsettling theories of what could be possible in this world over the next 100 years. What The movie delivered? A middling sci-fi thriller with a pretty great cast; not particularly scary. The premise is great - the human race, "flying too close to the sun," rips a hole in the fabric of space time, opening a portal to a chaotic, evil dimension. The spacecraft itself is transformed into an evil being, devouring any well-intentioned rescue crew that happens to cross its path. This is one of those movies that on paper and in my head seem incredible - limitless potential - but unfortunately the execution just did not match up. The hype I had built up based on comments people had made and a review or two that I had read prior to viewing made me expect a mind f*** to compete with other creepy sci fi flicks like The Cube or The Cell crossed with the horror and gore of Candyman. At the end of the day, I recommend checking out Event Horizon as a fun sci-fi movie that requires a bit of imagination and the suspension of disbelief thanks to the mid 90's special effects. Expect a 5/10, discover an 8/10. And that's my 2 cents.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The most frightening,effective and disturbing horror movie I have ever seen
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    yasenkiranov
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I had extremely low expectations for "Event Horizon".The film was made in a period where a lot of filmmakers thought that when you have enough money to use and abuse CGI your movie doesn't need a decent script.With that in mind I thought "Event Horizon" was going to be a clich&eacute; horror film that makes no effort to build suspense and just throws CG blood and gore in your face.I was wrong.Dead wrong. "Event Horizon" is the creepiest and most suspenseful horror movie I have ever seen.It manages to create a feeling of dread and foreboding like no other film I have ever seen before.This is due to a combination of great camera-work,appropriate music and(believe it or not) CG.Yes,the CGI is actually used appropriately here,not just added for the sake of it being there.That said,the special effects are top-notch(for 1997). Another thing I liked was that the ship itself wasn't the main threat.It was the characters.They become obsessed with their past mistakes(things they had locked away in their minds and didn't want to remember) and that begins to drive them insane.True,the ship is the catalyst for this,but the focus is more on the characters themselves.This reminds me of "Cube"-one of my favorite movies. The characters themselves are a bit underdeveloped,but they aren't cannon fodder like in many other horror films.Each of them has their the distinct personality and background information is given about some of them.I think this was alright for the purpose of this film.In my opinion ,if they did add more character development it would have ruined the pacing. "Event Horizon" is a very well made,but sadly underrated, horror movie.I strongly recommend it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I wasn't amazed by this movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jklimentowski
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A horror science-fiction movie. When I think of this genre I always have "Alien" on my mind. I think this is a perfect example. Unfortunately "Event Horizon" lacks both in the horror and science-fiction parts. As for the science fiction - well it is just not realistic enough. Of course not all movies should be as realistic as "2010: Space Odyssey", but still when you compare it to "Alien" it turns out quite poor. Actually there is not much realism or physics in it at all. OK - the idea of time-space folding is nice, but the idea itself is at least as old as The Dune movie, or perhaps even older. I liked the scene of transition from zero gravity to artificial-earth gravity with fluids and bodies instantly dropping. The decompression sequence tries to be more horror like than scientific... and that is all I think. The rest is just pure fantasy. So forget about science-fiction - is it a good horror? This might be a difficult question for me as most horrors make me laugh rather than scare mostly due to their stupidity and lack of realism. There are of course exceptions like Alien or The Thing. What makes the difference? I think it is the realism of the situation. I really can't be scared by ghosts which can do anything. It is just too unreal - I can not place myself in such a world and my imagination fails. Unfortunately Event Horizon is a movie it this ghost type. Anything can happen therefore I do not feel like one of the terrified crew members, rather I wonder what could the director think of next. Of course there are some more or less scary moments, but these are just typical horror tricks - sudden action with a proper sound effect. There is no feel of terror while watching the movie. Another thing at which the movie fails is the plot. While the beginning sequences are quite interesting with every minute the plot becomes more and more chaotic. At some stage one really gets bored as it seems that there is no real goal or solution of the plot. One by one some things happen which try to scare you, but there is no logic in them. I can imagine that such a movie could last for a long time with random scary adventures happening to the characters until all of them are dead. But what is the point of watching that? Unfortunately the ending is also quite predictable and gives you no satisfaction of discovering something interesting or an unexpected solution. It is just as plain as that. OK - so is the movie really so bad? Well it is not a perfect movie, but not a terrible one either. One can watch it and have some fun but it is not a movie that you would like to come back to after years. Just see once, have fun and forget. It is worth to mention that the move has it's own style. While placed in future all the ships and equipment sometimes look like designed in the past. I can't describe it exactly but sometimes I had a feel of watching a sci-fiction movie from the fifties. Why did the director decide to chose such a scenography instead of pure futuristic one? No idea but I think it works fine.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
 </reviews>
</filme>
