<filme>
 <id>
  263
 </id>
 <imdburl>
  http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0120207
 </imdburl>
 <ano>
  1997
 </ano>
 <titulo>
  A&ccedil;o
 </titulo>
 <rating>
  2.7
 </rating>
 <sinopse>
  John Henry Irons designs weapons for the military. When his project to create weapons that harmlessly neutralize soldiers is sabotaged, he leaves in disgust. When he sees gangs are using ... &nbsp;&raquo;
 </sinopse>
 <storyline>
  John Henry Irons designs weapons for the military. When his project to create weapons that harmlessly neutralize soldiers is sabotaged, he leaves in disgust. When he sees gangs are using his weapons on the street, he uses his brains and his Uncle Joe's junkyard know-how to fight back, becoming a real man of "steel."
 </storyline>
 <generos>
  <genero>
   Action
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Crime
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Sci-Fi
  </genero>
 </generos>
 <keywords>
  <keyword>
   gang
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   soldier
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   military
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   fight
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   junkyard
  </keyword>
 </keywords>
 <diretores>
  <diretor>
   Kenneth Johnson
  </diretor>
 </diretores>
 <escritores>
  <escritor>
   Louise Simonson
  </escritor>
  <escritor>
   Jon Bogdanove
  </escritor>
 </escritores>
 <atores>
  <ator>
   Shaquille O'Neal
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Annabeth Gish
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Judd Nelson
  </ator>
 </atores>
 <reviews>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Worst Superhero Movie ever.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Khalid Rafi
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Wow, this movie is unbelievably terrible. Why? Shaquille O'Neal. That's why. Shaq stars as John Henry Irons a special weapon designer for the military who quits after seeing the damage they do after the weapon reaches the hands of the street gangs he uses his brains and his Uncle Joe's junkyard know-how to fight back by becoming a guy who wears metal Shaq gives an unbelievably terrible performance trying to be Superman. The I guess you're probably wondering why i gave it a 1, I guess he had a cool costume. In conclusion, A low budget, horribly acted movie that just goes to show us how low the bar for acting can go. So if you're in the mood to watch an old Superman movie, don't because this isn't Suuperman.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Shaq Can't Act
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    zardoz-13
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Shaquille O'Neal was a better basketball star than he was an actor. Cast as the eponymous hero in scif-fi writer & director Kenneth Johnson's costumed crime fighter saga, he looks absurd with his sappy expressions. Nevertheless, "Steel" isn't a bad movie. Despite Shaq's lackluster performance, this 97-minute adaptation of a DC Comics character features some fine performances from Judd Nelson, Annabeth Gish, and Richard Roundtree. Johnson makes several references to the superheroes in the DC Comics Universe, but Superman never makes a cameo. In the comics, Superman saved John Henry Steel's life and advised him to make something of himself. As far as this movie goes, Superman doesn't exist and John Henry Steel Shaquille O'Neal) has never made contact with him. Shaq is in the military when the action unfolds and he is testing experimental weapons. Nathaniel Burke (Judd Nelson) is a fellow officer. Unscrupulous to the core, he is always willing to push the envelope on any project. When Senator Nolan hints that he can expect a promotion to captain if he pushes things along on a weapons testing program, Burke resets the mechanism on one of John Henry's laser weapons. John Henry builds weapons that don't kill so much as neutralize enemy troops. The blast misfires and knocks on a concrete wall. Susan "Sparky" Sparks (Annabeth Gish of "Mystic Pizza") is pinned under a giant fragment. Our seven foot one hero frees her, but she spends the rest of her life in a wheelchair. Incredibly, a military tribunal is held, and Burke run out of the service. Despondent over the condition of Sparky, John Henry resigns from the Army. What he doesn't know is that Burke has taken the gun designs and plans to produce versions of it to sell. He captures attention not long afterward when he arms a gang of hoodlums and they rob a bank. John Henry sets up a secret factory in his Uncle's junkyard. He pulls Sparky out of a depressing V.A. Hospital and makes him the brain of his operation. He creates a steel suit and is given a special sledgehammer. Meanwhile, Burke lets every scumbag in the world know that he can provide them with the ultimate weapon. "Steel" is formulaic but entertaining. The hand grenade scene is unforgivable.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    ShaqFu In an iron suit
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Tommy Bolden
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    You ever wonder what it would feel like to be raped by 7 football tall black man and then him steal 10 bucks from you? Well watch this movie and you will find out.What makes shaq think he can act? He cant make video games, music , and can barely play basketball. So why did he think he could do this? He might as well called this Shaqfu the live action movie, because that is exactly what this movie is, its a big Fu from shaq. That is right folks shaq is screwing you hard and there is nothing you can do about it.So if you watch this grit your teeth bare the load and get ready for a full on anal invasion from the master him self in this torture porn of a movie.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    It's good for a rainy day, I'd say...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    dee.reid
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/5/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    With all this madness about superheroes going on right now ("The Avengers" just opened today), I decided to go back in time to 1997, to the poorly received box office flop "Steel." I was 12 back in 1997, but I have to admit that I liked "Steel" then (I also liked the big-budget adaptation of another favorite superhero of mine, "Spawn"). 15 years later, a lot has changed. For one, I've grown up. I now realize that "Steel" is not a very good movie. I remember around that time, my cousin saw "Steel" in the theaters and told us that it was not a very good movie. The critics and most sensible audience members seemed to agree. But I digress; "Steel" is good for one thing and one thing only: a rainy day, like today. Since I'm not daring brave the over-crowded theaters for fear of being over-run by Avengers fan-boys (and fan-girls), I decided to pop in my 14-year-old VHS copy of "Steel" and relive 1997 like it was just 15 years ago (which, in fact, it was). "Steel" is the live-action adaptation of the second-tier DC Comics character co-created by Louise Simonson and Jon Bogdanove, with NBA star Shaquille O'Neal playing the titular steel-armored, non-super-powered superhero whose real name is John Henry Irons in his civilian identity. I'm not really a fan of the movie anymore (most readers will remember that I'm largely a Marvel Comics reader), but I find the history of the original comic book character to be quite fascinating: as yet another proud, positive black-American superhero in comics, John Henry Irons is a brilliant former weapons designer for a private arms-manufacturing company whose life is saved, both literally and metaphorically, by the mighty Man of Steel himself, Superman. Ironically, a later incident with the powerful super-villain Doomsday costs Superman his life, and Irons's life is changed forever when he decides to don a powered suit of armor of his own making - much like Marvel Comics' Tony Stark/Iron Man - and fight crime himself as Steel (with Superman's logo blazoned mightily on his chest as a reminder of his inspiration) and wielding a powerful sledgehammer, too. The 1997 live-action adaptation removes any mention of Superman (or his apparent death), except for a tattoo O'Neal has on his arm, and goes forward with its own origin story. Certain aspects of the movie are faithful to the comics, but the rest of it is pretty campy and just bloody awful. This time out, Irons is a weapons designer for the U.S. Army and when an ambitious rival, Nathaniel Burke (Judd Nelson), is involved in an accident that kills a U.S. senator and leaves his best friend Susan "Sparky" Sparks (Annabeth Gish) a paraplegic, Irons resigns from the military in disgust. Irons (whose name is reportedly inspired by the legendary black-American folk hero John Henry) returns to his home in Los Angeles, only to discover that street gangs are out committing brazen bank robberies using the exact same, albeit heavily modified, weapons he designed. With Sparky and Uncle Joe (Richard Roundtree) by his side, Irons dons a custom-made suit of armor as the armored superhero Steel. As he dives deeper into his investigation, he discovers that his old rival Nathaniel Burke (who has since recruited young neighborhood street kids to do his bidding) is behind the robberies and the deadly new weapons out on the street. "Steel" is pretty cheesy and campy, and I don't mean that in a good way. Unlike most people, I don't think Shaquille O'Neal is that lousy an actor. I think that if he were given the right material, he would manage out OK. At least here, I think he seems perfect for the part of John Henry Irons/Steel; it's just a shame that the rest of the movie, as written and directed by Kenneth Johnson ("V"), is just not very good. In other words, Shaq just needed a better movie. The special effects, the hokey street dialogue, and the performances don't help matters much either. Richard Roundtree and Irma P. Hall do what they can, but aren't given a whole lot to do beyond offering elder-generation advice to the younger folks. Judd Nelson relishes his role as a stereotypical villain, but it's really Annabeth Gish as the physically handicapped yet resilient gadgeteer Susan Sparks who really seems to shine the most in what could have been a very limiting part. I sense that a remake/reboot is, or soon probably will be, in the works sometime in the near future, and that is one "Steel" I just "may" (italicized) fork over $7.50 at my local movie theater to see. Until then, "Steel" will continue to mightily serve its purpose for rainy days (and some late-'90s nostalgia)... 4/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    For 97 it's pretty good, unless you have anything else to watch.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Gregory
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/10/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I have no interest in basketball, I stink at it, and the only big names I know are Michael Jordan, Shaquille O'Neal and the Harlem Globetrotters. I have no idea why everyone likes to criticize Shaq, nor do I really care - he had to be good at something in order to be ridiculed so much. Quoting others, for 1997 it's pretty good, unless you have anything else to watch. It's not a masterpiece, but rather one of those pictures that requires you to set aside your pre-conceived notions about good film-making and just enjoy the ride. Do that, and Steel is a surprisingly amusing little adventure comedy. On top of all that, it has a memorable theme and subtle special effects. John Henry Irons was a harmless weapons designer until his project crippled his partner Sparks. After quitting his job, his weapons are mass-produced for criminals, and in order to stop it Irons and Sparks create a suit of armor that leads Irons to become the superhero vigilante Steel. He is the blue collar Iron Man of the DC universe. Overall, it's an average superhero film plot. The original story of Steel was based on the comic book Death of Superman. Irons wanted to go after Doomsday, the killer of Superman, himself, thus creating a mechanical super suit. But the film was in development for so long, that it lost all meaning. Instead, we got a cheesier independent film without the long drama. Given the way others cashed on the Death of Superman, the film could have been far worse. The reason why its one of my favorite movies is Steels realistic, cheap and simple armor. The hand-forged work-in-progress suit with chain mail and occasional glitches was made in a junkyard out of regular iron and steel. That's as good as any of us can get without using advanced industrial facilities. Some may argue it looks like someone decided to pour glue all over their body and go rolling around in a junkyard, but it's well thought through, even though parts sometimes just fall off in action. The 34kg armored suit is not only bulletproof, but also well padded, able to absorb most kinetic energy. Steel takes on a clip of ammo, some stun impulses, and a sonic blast that throws him back about 6m. He even falls of a building about 24m into a dumpster. It's virtually impregnable to known weaponry. I really like how they made the waist area. It's simultaneously flexible and incredibly strong. There is no such tech on the market even a decade later. The chain mail is almost indistinguishable from plate armor creating an impression that he is almost completely covered in steel plates. The electric support is a basic video/audio 31km earpiece transceiver, with an extra camera for rear view, an inbuilt GPS for fast navigation around the city, and a basic body monitoring system with body ventilation. The left arm houses a nail gun and a grappling hook (slow, but supports about 181kg for a short time). The shoulders are nice, but don't protect from above dangers, exposing the chain mail, and gloves are just regular surface chain mail, with no palm protection. The weakest part of the suit is the helmet. Not only does look like it's made of rubber, but it also leaves the face exposed. Steel was shot in the head several times throughout the film, but the biggest injury he sustained was a scratched chin from falling on pavement. Well, it is a superhero movie and emotionless faces with chin guards are for villains. The main weapon of Steel is his sledgehammer, pimped with a sonic gun, stun gun, short focus laser, a grenade launcher and high-powered magnet. The long-range capabilities come equipped with a sniper scope. Since the suit is mostly iron, it amplifies the magnetic field of the hammer, enabling to attract anything iron around him, like enemy weapons and trashcan lids. Sadly, jet boots and super strength, along with other over the top features, were left out from the 97-minute film about a guy building power armor in a 97s junkyard. However, there were also improvements. There is no red cape, or a gigantic "S" on his chest. Later DC versions of Steel retained this, setting him apart from Superman. The resulting "armor" satisfied both the look of the character and the filming physical requirements. After completion, with all its pieces and layering, it took 3 costumers an hour to transform John Henry into Steel. Shaq had to do all of his own stunts because the producers were unable to find a 2.16m stunt double for him. Other movie features include a customized humvee, van, motorbike and wheelchair. As far as superhero movies go, this one didn't fall as flat as more popular hero films that altered the original story. Steel costume may look like a cheap Robocop mockup, but at least you can RUN in it without CGI. Let's see you make a better suit without CGI! I dare you! I double dare you!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Movie That Killed Comic Book Movies for Nearly a Decade
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Eric Smith
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/7/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is one of the most horrifyingly awful films of all time. It would an embarrassment to your local dump to find this movie wallowing in there. It's not even worthy of that! Shaquille O'Neal delivers a performance that (gasp!) is worse than his awful performance in Kazaam! Apparently, after the mild success and small critical praise of Shaq's performance in Blue Chips, he thought he had a chance at a real acting career. I would like to know who it was that encouraged him to go forth with two more lead roles in his career?! The only reason he did so well in Blue Chips was because he was basically playing himself! Casting Shaq in this big, lumbering idiot of a role is so bad, it actually makes us laugh...hard. The costuming is a joke. It's all too obvious that Shaq is wearing a rubber helmet when its supposed to be made of steel! He also looks just plain ridiculous in that suit. He looks like an over-sized kid ready for Halloween, as he has to strain to peer through the eye holes. He just looks like a metallic turd. The special effects are mediocre at best, and the rest of the cast is bland. Judd Nelson, who's career said bye-bye back in the '80s, is among the worst villains in movie history, and certainly didn't help his career any. The story is ludicrous and often makes no sense...that is, when there is an actual story to follow, and the dialogue is so bad, that they have to resort to stealing lines from other, far better, action movies!! After this, its plain to see why you didn't see another comic-book based movie for a while (excluding Batman & Robin, which was a joke in itself). This movie literally killed the comic book movie for almost a decade.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I found Superman's kryptonite.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    YellowJacketYJ
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/4/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Steel is one of those movies that you hear how bad it is, but, in your mind, believe that it can't be that bad. This time, it is that bad. Steel is the equivalent of going to a PETA meeting wearing a fur coat with snakeskin boots, with deer blood dried onto your pants, while holding a platter of ham, chicken, turkey, and other "animal cruelty" foods in one hand, and a deer head in the other. To make it easier to understand, it feels out of place and doomed to fail (and possibly pelted with tomatoes). Shaq, as the movie poster refers to him as, plays John Henry Irons, a weapons designer for the military. After a tragic accident occurs (not the board meeting to green-light this movie), Irons retires his position and returns to the safety of his home. Within a few days back, he takes notice that his dangerous guns are running amok in the streets, thanks to Nathaniel Burke, a former sergeant (I'm probably wrong about his position, but who cares) relieved from his position for attempted destruction (and no, he wasn't the man who green-lit this movie. Okay, I'll stop). I want to stop right there and delve into the stupidity that this situation is. I'm still laughing at the fact that, instead of criminal punishment via jail time, a man bent on human destruction is just released from his military duties. What the hell?!? Did they honestly think he wasn't going to cause destruction once he got home? What if they did this in real life. For instance, when they found Saddam Huessin, instead of hanging him, they just spanked him on the ass! I'm sure that would've worked. Anyway, back to the plot (or as much of a plot there is). Once ahold of these guns, Nathaniel uses them to destroy Irons' hometown, and Irons himself. Of course, this doesn't keep Irons down, as he gets back up, renames himself Shaquille O'Neal, joins the NBA, and becomes a huge star. Okay, so this didn't happen in the movie. But I'm pretty positive this is how Shaq's career came about. My ramblings aside, Irons picks himself back up, grabs an old army buddy and Shaft (not kidding), makes himself the absolute worst looking superhero attire ever (it makes the Bat Nipples look like the Mona Lisa), dons himself Steel, and comes back to save the day, equipped with a huge sledgehammer (Triple H's inspiration), magnetic shield, and advice (once again, not kidding). The sheer stupidity that is Steel is unprecedented. Yes, I've seen worse COUGH*Batman & Robin*COUGH. But, that doesn't do justice for the man of Steel (and insults the true man of Steel, Superman, which this story is based off of a side character after the death of Superman). Steel is so bad, that I was actually yearning for Kazaam shortly into the movie. Do yourself a favor, and shoot yourself in the foot. It's a lot less painful.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Quite Possibly the Worst Movie Ever Made
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Michael Margetis (pmargetis@cox.net)
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/11/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Uncle Joe: Well dip me in sh__t and roll me in breadcrumbs. Without question, 'Steel' is in the running for worst film ever made. However, it is a fun movie to watch to make fun of. You'll be laughing hysterically, but not as the filmmakers intended. Shaquille O'Neal's acting skills are kind of like Adolf Hitler's morals. They're seriously lacking. This movie does have some classic one liners like "Y'all stay cool now." a line Shaq delivers to a couple of old people he returns a stolen purse to, and my personal favorite, "Well, dip me in sh__t and roll me in breadcrumbs!". I highly recommend 'Steel' if you need a good laugh. I think I laughed harder during this than I did during 'Borat'. Grade: F
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Jumbo-Sized Hero
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jonathon_naylor
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/11/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Let's get the worst facets of STEEL out of the way first. Yes, Shaquille O'Neal is a dreadful actor. Yes, he looks like the world's biggest sardine can in his Steel armor. Yes, the dialog is bargain basement. Yes, Judd Nelson makes for the worst comic book villain this side of Mark Hamill as The Trickster in THE FLASH television series. And yes, the film embarrasses itself even further by clumsily trying to deliver a we-must-stop-using-weapons-to-settle-our-differences message. Happy? STEEL is not a masterpiece in any sense of the word, but that doesn't mean it should be completely written off. It's one of those pictures that requires you to set aside your pre-conceived notions about good film-making and just enjoy the ride. Do that, and STEEL is a surprisingly amusing little adventure. O'Neal is fun, if not unspectacular, as our jumbo-sized hero, a do-gooder vigilante cleanin' up the streets with a big ol' hammer and souped-up motorbike. He's aided by wheelchair-bound hottie Annabeth Gish and an aged Richard Roundtree as his off-the-wall Uncle Joe. Our hero's climactic showdown with the one-dimensionally evil Nelson is incredibly cheesy, as are many scenes, but the film has its heart so firmly in the right place you'll be more than a little lenient. As usual, what Shaq lacks in talent he makes up for in charm and a deep likability that seeps right through the screen. STEEL is an uncomplicated film that seems custom-made for little boys, who will absolutely adore it. If you're in the right mood, you'll like it, too.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Poor action stuff that will only appeal to children and undemanding adults
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bob the moo
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/11/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    John Henry Irons is a weapons designer for the military who has been key in the development of a range of experimental weapons that immobilise enemy troops without any fatalities. However when Nat Burke tries to increase the power of the weapon during the test, the result sees a Senator dead and one of his colleagues disabled. The court martial sees Burke kicked out of the military and John decides his days of weapon design are over  returning to LA to work in a small steel mill. However when his weapons somehow make it into the hands of LA's criminal underworld, John decides that it is "on" and takes steps to counter the threat. Universally derided ever since it was even green lit for production, this film does have little to recommend it but still produces very basic distraction if that is what you want. The plot is obvious and goes just where you expect it to and it offers little for the discerning adult viewer (or to be honest the undemanding ones too). The action will please children but it is the wider delivery where it all falls down and, contrary to opinion, it is not all Shaq's fault. The script is clunky for the most part and has lots of injokes, most of which are embarrassing basketball references although, that said, the "Shaft" joke drew a laugh from me simply because it was so unexpected and so disrespectful to the film! This is very basic stuff though and nobody seems that interested in trying to make it more than that. Johnson is happy to deliver a kiddie-friendly superhero movie for the most part and this is all it seems to be. The cast have potential but too few of them have any decent material to work with. O'Neal can't act and that's the truth. He can play basketball and, given the riches this has given him we should not feel too sorry for him here. He says his lines and he stands where they tell him to stand but that is not the same as producing a character and being engaging  neither of which applies in this situation. Gish has little to do and Roundtree seems happy just to be a walking reference. Nelson hams it up in an obvious baddie while Harper, Hall and Ray J (!) are not the ones to address the lack of quality. The only person that I actually noted with interest was Kevin Grevioux, not because of his performance here but more because he is an interesting man who has built a small but varied career. Overall then this is a poor superhero movie but one that has had just about enough money spent on it to make it distract children and undemanding adults. The backlash against has been a bit overly cruel but it is still not any good with basic acting, basic script, basic plotting and action that only aspires to be colourful and noisy.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Worst Superhero Movie ever.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Khalid Rafi
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Wow, this movie is unbelievably terrible. Why? Shaquille O'Neal. That's why. Shaq stars as John Henry Irons a special weapon designer for the military who quits after seeing the damage they do after the weapon reaches the hands of the street gangs he uses his brains and his Uncle Joe's junkyard know-how to fight back by becoming a guy who wears metal Shaq gives an unbelievably terrible performance trying to be Superman. The I guess you're probably wondering why i gave it a 1, I guess he had a cool costume. In conclusion, A low budget, horribly acted movie that just goes to show us how low the bar for acting can go. So if you're in the mood to watch an old Superman movie, don't because this isn't Suuperman.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Shaq Can't Act
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    zardoz-13
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Shaquille O'Neal was a better basketball star than he was an actor. Cast as the eponymous hero in scif-fi writer & director Kenneth Johnson's costumed crime fighter saga, he looks absurd with his sappy expressions. Nevertheless, "Steel" isn't a bad movie. Despite Shaq's lackluster performance, this 97-minute adaptation of a DC Comics character features some fine performances from Judd Nelson, Annabeth Gish, and Richard Roundtree. Johnson makes several references to the superheroes in the DC Comics Universe, but Superman never makes a cameo. In the comics, Superman saved John Henry Steel's life and advised him to make something of himself. As far as this movie goes, Superman doesn't exist and John Henry Steel Shaquille O'Neal) has never made contact with him. Shaq is in the military when the action unfolds and he is testing experimental weapons. Nathaniel Burke (Judd Nelson) is a fellow officer. Unscrupulous to the core, he is always willing to push the envelope on any project. When Senator Nolan hints that he can expect a promotion to captain if he pushes things along on a weapons testing program, Burke resets the mechanism on one of John Henry's laser weapons. John Henry builds weapons that don't kill so much as neutralize enemy troops. The blast misfires and knocks on a concrete wall. Susan "Sparky" Sparks (Annabeth Gish of "Mystic Pizza") is pinned under a giant fragment. Our seven foot one hero frees her, but she spends the rest of her life in a wheelchair. Incredibly, a military tribunal is held, and Burke run out of the service. Despondent over the condition of Sparky, John Henry resigns from the Army. What he doesn't know is that Burke has taken the gun designs and plans to produce versions of it to sell. He captures attention not long afterward when he arms a gang of hoodlums and they rob a bank. John Henry sets up a secret factory in his Uncle's junkyard. He pulls Sparky out of a depressing V.A. Hospital and makes him the brain of his operation. He creates a steel suit and is given a special sledgehammer. Meanwhile, Burke lets every scumbag in the world know that he can provide them with the ultimate weapon. "Steel" is formulaic but entertaining. The hand grenade scene is unforgivable.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    ShaqFu In an iron suit
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Tommy Bolden
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    You ever wonder what it would feel like to be raped by 7 football tall black man and then him steal 10 bucks from you? Well watch this movie and you will find out.What makes shaq think he can act? He cant make video games, music , and can barely play basketball. So why did he think he could do this? He might as well called this Shaqfu the live action movie, because that is exactly what this movie is, its a big Fu from shaq. That is right folks shaq is screwing you hard and there is nothing you can do about it.So if you watch this grit your teeth bare the load and get ready for a full on anal invasion from the master him self in this torture porn of a movie.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    It's good for a rainy day, I'd say...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    dee.reid
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/5/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    With all this madness about superheroes going on right now ("The Avengers" just opened today), I decided to go back in time to 1997, to the poorly received box office flop "Steel." I was 12 back in 1997, but I have to admit that I liked "Steel" then (I also liked the big-budget adaptation of another favorite superhero of mine, "Spawn"). 15 years later, a lot has changed. For one, I've grown up. I now realize that "Steel" is not a very good movie. I remember around that time, my cousin saw "Steel" in the theaters and told us that it was not a very good movie. The critics and most sensible audience members seemed to agree. But I digress; "Steel" is good for one thing and one thing only: a rainy day, like today. Since I'm not daring brave the over-crowded theaters for fear of being over-run by Avengers fan-boys (and fan-girls), I decided to pop in my 14-year-old VHS copy of "Steel" and relive 1997 like it was just 15 years ago (which, in fact, it was). "Steel" is the live-action adaptation of the second-tier DC Comics character co-created by Louise Simonson and Jon Bogdanove, with NBA star Shaquille O'Neal playing the titular steel-armored, non-super-powered superhero whose real name is John Henry Irons in his civilian identity. I'm not really a fan of the movie anymore (most readers will remember that I'm largely a Marvel Comics reader), but I find the history of the original comic book character to be quite fascinating: as yet another proud, positive black-American superhero in comics, John Henry Irons is a brilliant former weapons designer for a private arms-manufacturing company whose life is saved, both literally and metaphorically, by the mighty Man of Steel himself, Superman. Ironically, a later incident with the powerful super-villain Doomsday costs Superman his life, and Irons's life is changed forever when he decides to don a powered suit of armor of his own making - much like Marvel Comics' Tony Stark/Iron Man - and fight crime himself as Steel (with Superman's logo blazoned mightily on his chest as a reminder of his inspiration) and wielding a powerful sledgehammer, too. The 1997 live-action adaptation removes any mention of Superman (or his apparent death), except for a tattoo O'Neal has on his arm, and goes forward with its own origin story. Certain aspects of the movie are faithful to the comics, but the rest of it is pretty campy and just bloody awful. This time out, Irons is a weapons designer for the U.S. Army and when an ambitious rival, Nathaniel Burke (Judd Nelson), is involved in an accident that kills a U.S. senator and leaves his best friend Susan "Sparky" Sparks (Annabeth Gish) a paraplegic, Irons resigns from the military in disgust. Irons (whose name is reportedly inspired by the legendary black-American folk hero John Henry) returns to his home in Los Angeles, only to discover that street gangs are out committing brazen bank robberies using the exact same, albeit heavily modified, weapons he designed. With Sparky and Uncle Joe (Richard Roundtree) by his side, Irons dons a custom-made suit of armor as the armored superhero Steel. As he dives deeper into his investigation, he discovers that his old rival Nathaniel Burke (who has since recruited young neighborhood street kids to do his bidding) is behind the robberies and the deadly new weapons out on the street. "Steel" is pretty cheesy and campy, and I don't mean that in a good way. Unlike most people, I don't think Shaquille O'Neal is that lousy an actor. I think that if he were given the right material, he would manage out OK. At least here, I think he seems perfect for the part of John Henry Irons/Steel; it's just a shame that the rest of the movie, as written and directed by Kenneth Johnson ("V"), is just not very good. In other words, Shaq just needed a better movie. The special effects, the hokey street dialogue, and the performances don't help matters much either. Richard Roundtree and Irma P. Hall do what they can, but aren't given a whole lot to do beyond offering elder-generation advice to the younger folks. Judd Nelson relishes his role as a stereotypical villain, but it's really Annabeth Gish as the physically handicapped yet resilient gadgeteer Susan Sparks who really seems to shine the most in what could have been a very limiting part. I sense that a remake/reboot is, or soon probably will be, in the works sometime in the near future, and that is one "Steel" I just "may" (italicized) fork over $7.50 at my local movie theater to see. Until then, "Steel" will continue to mightily serve its purpose for rainy days (and some late-'90s nostalgia)... 4/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    For 97 it's pretty good, unless you have anything else to watch.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Gregory
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/10/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I have no interest in basketball, I stink at it, and the only big names I know are Michael Jordan, Shaquille O'Neal and the Harlem Globetrotters. I have no idea why everyone likes to criticize Shaq, nor do I really care - he had to be good at something in order to be ridiculed so much. Quoting others, for 1997 it's pretty good, unless you have anything else to watch. It's not a masterpiece, but rather one of those pictures that requires you to set aside your pre-conceived notions about good film-making and just enjoy the ride. Do that, and Steel is a surprisingly amusing little adventure comedy. On top of all that, it has a memorable theme and subtle special effects. John Henry Irons was a harmless weapons designer until his project crippled his partner Sparks. After quitting his job, his weapons are mass-produced for criminals, and in order to stop it Irons and Sparks create a suit of armor that leads Irons to become the superhero vigilante Steel. He is the blue collar Iron Man of the DC universe. Overall, it's an average superhero film plot. The original story of Steel was based on the comic book Death of Superman. Irons wanted to go after Doomsday, the killer of Superman, himself, thus creating a mechanical super suit. But the film was in development for so long, that it lost all meaning. Instead, we got a cheesier independent film without the long drama. Given the way others cashed on the Death of Superman, the film could have been far worse. The reason why its one of my favorite movies is Steels realistic, cheap and simple armor. The hand-forged work-in-progress suit with chain mail and occasional glitches was made in a junkyard out of regular iron and steel. That's as good as any of us can get without using advanced industrial facilities. Some may argue it looks like someone decided to pour glue all over their body and go rolling around in a junkyard, but it's well thought through, even though parts sometimes just fall off in action. The 34kg armored suit is not only bulletproof, but also well padded, able to absorb most kinetic energy. Steel takes on a clip of ammo, some stun impulses, and a sonic blast that throws him back about 6m. He even falls of a building about 24m into a dumpster. It's virtually impregnable to known weaponry. I really like how they made the waist area. It's simultaneously flexible and incredibly strong. There is no such tech on the market even a decade later. The chain mail is almost indistinguishable from plate armor creating an impression that he is almost completely covered in steel plates. The electric support is a basic video/audio 31km earpiece transceiver, with an extra camera for rear view, an inbuilt GPS for fast navigation around the city, and a basic body monitoring system with body ventilation. The left arm houses a nail gun and a grappling hook (slow, but supports about 181kg for a short time). The shoulders are nice, but don't protect from above dangers, exposing the chain mail, and gloves are just regular surface chain mail, with no palm protection. The weakest part of the suit is the helmet. Not only does look like it's made of rubber, but it also leaves the face exposed. Steel was shot in the head several times throughout the film, but the biggest injury he sustained was a scratched chin from falling on pavement. Well, it is a superhero movie and emotionless faces with chin guards are for villains. The main weapon of Steel is his sledgehammer, pimped with a sonic gun, stun gun, short focus laser, a grenade launcher and high-powered magnet. The long-range capabilities come equipped with a sniper scope. Since the suit is mostly iron, it amplifies the magnetic field of the hammer, enabling to attract anything iron around him, like enemy weapons and trashcan lids. Sadly, jet boots and super strength, along with other over the top features, were left out from the 97-minute film about a guy building power armor in a 97s junkyard. However, there were also improvements. There is no red cape, or a gigantic "S" on his chest. Later DC versions of Steel retained this, setting him apart from Superman. The resulting "armor" satisfied both the look of the character and the filming physical requirements. After completion, with all its pieces and layering, it took 3 costumers an hour to transform John Henry into Steel. Shaq had to do all of his own stunts because the producers were unable to find a 2.16m stunt double for him. Other movie features include a customized humvee, van, motorbike and wheelchair. As far as superhero movies go, this one didn't fall as flat as more popular hero films that altered the original story. Steel costume may look like a cheap Robocop mockup, but at least you can RUN in it without CGI. Let's see you make a better suit without CGI! I dare you! I double dare you!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Movie That Killed Comic Book Movies for Nearly a Decade
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Eric Smith
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/7/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is one of the most horrifyingly awful films of all time. It would an embarrassment to your local dump to find this movie wallowing in there. It's not even worthy of that! Shaquille O'Neal delivers a performance that (gasp!) is worse than his awful performance in Kazaam! Apparently, after the mild success and small critical praise of Shaq's performance in Blue Chips, he thought he had a chance at a real acting career. I would like to know who it was that encouraged him to go forth with two more lead roles in his career?! The only reason he did so well in Blue Chips was because he was basically playing himself! Casting Shaq in this big, lumbering idiot of a role is so bad, it actually makes us laugh...hard. The costuming is a joke. It's all too obvious that Shaq is wearing a rubber helmet when its supposed to be made of steel! He also looks just plain ridiculous in that suit. He looks like an over-sized kid ready for Halloween, as he has to strain to peer through the eye holes. He just looks like a metallic turd. The special effects are mediocre at best, and the rest of the cast is bland. Judd Nelson, who's career said bye-bye back in the '80s, is among the worst villains in movie history, and certainly didn't help his career any. The story is ludicrous and often makes no sense...that is, when there is an actual story to follow, and the dialogue is so bad, that they have to resort to stealing lines from other, far better, action movies!! After this, its plain to see why you didn't see another comic-book based movie for a while (excluding Batman & Robin, which was a joke in itself). This movie literally killed the comic book movie for almost a decade.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I found Superman's kryptonite.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    YellowJacketYJ
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/4/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Steel is one of those movies that you hear how bad it is, but, in your mind, believe that it can't be that bad. This time, it is that bad. Steel is the equivalent of going to a PETA meeting wearing a fur coat with snakeskin boots, with deer blood dried onto your pants, while holding a platter of ham, chicken, turkey, and other "animal cruelty" foods in one hand, and a deer head in the other. To make it easier to understand, it feels out of place and doomed to fail (and possibly pelted with tomatoes). Shaq, as the movie poster refers to him as, plays John Henry Irons, a weapons designer for the military. After a tragic accident occurs (not the board meeting to green-light this movie), Irons retires his position and returns to the safety of his home. Within a few days back, he takes notice that his dangerous guns are running amok in the streets, thanks to Nathaniel Burke, a former sergeant (I'm probably wrong about his position, but who cares) relieved from his position for attempted destruction (and no, he wasn't the man who green-lit this movie. Okay, I'll stop). I want to stop right there and delve into the stupidity that this situation is. I'm still laughing at the fact that, instead of criminal punishment via jail time, a man bent on human destruction is just released from his military duties. What the hell?!? Did they honestly think he wasn't going to cause destruction once he got home? What if they did this in real life. For instance, when they found Saddam Huessin, instead of hanging him, they just spanked him on the ass! I'm sure that would've worked. Anyway, back to the plot (or as much of a plot there is). Once ahold of these guns, Nathaniel uses them to destroy Irons' hometown, and Irons himself. Of course, this doesn't keep Irons down, as he gets back up, renames himself Shaquille O'Neal, joins the NBA, and becomes a huge star. Okay, so this didn't happen in the movie. But I'm pretty positive this is how Shaq's career came about. My ramblings aside, Irons picks himself back up, grabs an old army buddy and Shaft (not kidding), makes himself the absolute worst looking superhero attire ever (it makes the Bat Nipples look like the Mona Lisa), dons himself Steel, and comes back to save the day, equipped with a huge sledgehammer (Triple H's inspiration), magnetic shield, and advice (once again, not kidding). The sheer stupidity that is Steel is unprecedented. Yes, I've seen worse COUGH*Batman & Robin*COUGH. But, that doesn't do justice for the man of Steel (and insults the true man of Steel, Superman, which this story is based off of a side character after the death of Superman). Steel is so bad, that I was actually yearning for Kazaam shortly into the movie. Do yourself a favor, and shoot yourself in the foot. It's a lot less painful.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Quite Possibly the Worst Movie Ever Made
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Michael Margetis (pmargetis@cox.net)
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/11/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Uncle Joe: Well dip me in sh__t and roll me in breadcrumbs. Without question, 'Steel' is in the running for worst film ever made. However, it is a fun movie to watch to make fun of. You'll be laughing hysterically, but not as the filmmakers intended. Shaquille O'Neal's acting skills are kind of like Adolf Hitler's morals. They're seriously lacking. This movie does have some classic one liners like "Y'all stay cool now." a line Shaq delivers to a couple of old people he returns a stolen purse to, and my personal favorite, "Well, dip me in sh__t and roll me in breadcrumbs!". I highly recommend 'Steel' if you need a good laugh. I think I laughed harder during this than I did during 'Borat'. Grade: F
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Jumbo-Sized Hero
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jonathon_naylor
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/11/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Let's get the worst facets of STEEL out of the way first. Yes, Shaquille O'Neal is a dreadful actor. Yes, he looks like the world's biggest sardine can in his Steel armor. Yes, the dialog is bargain basement. Yes, Judd Nelson makes for the worst comic book villain this side of Mark Hamill as The Trickster in THE FLASH television series. And yes, the film embarrasses itself even further by clumsily trying to deliver a we-must-stop-using-weapons-to-settle-our-differences message. Happy? STEEL is not a masterpiece in any sense of the word, but that doesn't mean it should be completely written off. It's one of those pictures that requires you to set aside your pre-conceived notions about good film-making and just enjoy the ride. Do that, and STEEL is a surprisingly amusing little adventure. O'Neal is fun, if not unspectacular, as our jumbo-sized hero, a do-gooder vigilante cleanin' up the streets with a big ol' hammer and souped-up motorbike. He's aided by wheelchair-bound hottie Annabeth Gish and an aged Richard Roundtree as his off-the-wall Uncle Joe. Our hero's climactic showdown with the one-dimensionally evil Nelson is incredibly cheesy, as are many scenes, but the film has its heart so firmly in the right place you'll be more than a little lenient. As usual, what Shaq lacks in talent he makes up for in charm and a deep likability that seeps right through the screen. STEEL is an uncomplicated film that seems custom-made for little boys, who will absolutely adore it. If you're in the right mood, you'll like it, too.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Poor action stuff that will only appeal to children and undemanding adults
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bob the moo
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/11/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    John Henry Irons is a weapons designer for the military who has been key in the development of a range of experimental weapons that immobilise enemy troops without any fatalities. However when Nat Burke tries to increase the power of the weapon during the test, the result sees a Senator dead and one of his colleagues disabled. The court martial sees Burke kicked out of the military and John decides his days of weapon design are over  returning to LA to work in a small steel mill. However when his weapons somehow make it into the hands of LA's criminal underworld, John decides that it is "on" and takes steps to counter the threat. Universally derided ever since it was even green lit for production, this film does have little to recommend it but still produces very basic distraction if that is what you want. The plot is obvious and goes just where you expect it to and it offers little for the discerning adult viewer (or to be honest the undemanding ones too). The action will please children but it is the wider delivery where it all falls down and, contrary to opinion, it is not all Shaq's fault. The script is clunky for the most part and has lots of injokes, most of which are embarrassing basketball references although, that said, the "Shaft" joke drew a laugh from me simply because it was so unexpected and so disrespectful to the film! This is very basic stuff though and nobody seems that interested in trying to make it more than that. Johnson is happy to deliver a kiddie-friendly superhero movie for the most part and this is all it seems to be. The cast have potential but too few of them have any decent material to work with. O'Neal can't act and that's the truth. He can play basketball and, given the riches this has given him we should not feel too sorry for him here. He says his lines and he stands where they tell him to stand but that is not the same as producing a character and being engaging  neither of which applies in this situation. Gish has little to do and Roundtree seems happy just to be a walking reference. Nelson hams it up in an obvious baddie while Harper, Hall and Ray J (!) are not the ones to address the lack of quality. The only person that I actually noted with interest was Kevin Grevioux, not because of his performance here but more because he is an interesting man who has built a small but varied career. Overall then this is a poor superhero movie but one that has had just about enough money spent on it to make it distract children and undemanding adults. The backlash against has been a bit overly cruel but it is still not any good with basic acting, basic script, basic plotting and action that only aspires to be colourful and noisy.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Worst Superhero Movie ever.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Khalid Rafi
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Wow, this movie is unbelievably terrible. Why? Shaquille O'Neal. That's why. Shaq stars as John Henry Irons a special weapon designer for the military who quits after seeing the damage they do after the weapon reaches the hands of the street gangs he uses his brains and his Uncle Joe's junkyard know-how to fight back by becoming a guy who wears metal Shaq gives an unbelievably terrible performance trying to be Superman. The I guess you're probably wondering why i gave it a 1, I guess he had a cool costume. In conclusion, A low budget, horribly acted movie that just goes to show us how low the bar for acting can go. So if you're in the mood to watch an old Superman movie, don't because this isn't Suuperman.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Shaq Can't Act
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    zardoz-13
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Shaquille O'Neal was a better basketball star than he was an actor. Cast as the eponymous hero in scif-fi writer & director Kenneth Johnson's costumed crime fighter saga, he looks absurd with his sappy expressions. Nevertheless, "Steel" isn't a bad movie. Despite Shaq's lackluster performance, this 97-minute adaptation of a DC Comics character features some fine performances from Judd Nelson, Annabeth Gish, and Richard Roundtree. Johnson makes several references to the superheroes in the DC Comics Universe, but Superman never makes a cameo. In the comics, Superman saved John Henry Steel's life and advised him to make something of himself. As far as this movie goes, Superman doesn't exist and John Henry Steel Shaquille O'Neal) has never made contact with him. Shaq is in the military when the action unfolds and he is testing experimental weapons. Nathaniel Burke (Judd Nelson) is a fellow officer. Unscrupulous to the core, he is always willing to push the envelope on any project. When Senator Nolan hints that he can expect a promotion to captain if he pushes things along on a weapons testing program, Burke resets the mechanism on one of John Henry's laser weapons. John Henry builds weapons that don't kill so much as neutralize enemy troops. The blast misfires and knocks on a concrete wall. Susan "Sparky" Sparks (Annabeth Gish of "Mystic Pizza") is pinned under a giant fragment. Our seven foot one hero frees her, but she spends the rest of her life in a wheelchair. Incredibly, a military tribunal is held, and Burke run out of the service. Despondent over the condition of Sparky, John Henry resigns from the Army. What he doesn't know is that Burke has taken the gun designs and plans to produce versions of it to sell. He captures attention not long afterward when he arms a gang of hoodlums and they rob a bank. John Henry sets up a secret factory in his Uncle's junkyard. He pulls Sparky out of a depressing V.A. Hospital and makes him the brain of his operation. He creates a steel suit and is given a special sledgehammer. Meanwhile, Burke lets every scumbag in the world know that he can provide them with the ultimate weapon. "Steel" is formulaic but entertaining. The hand grenade scene is unforgivable.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    ShaqFu In an iron suit
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Tommy Bolden
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    You ever wonder what it would feel like to be raped by 7 football tall black man and then him steal 10 bucks from you? Well watch this movie and you will find out.What makes shaq think he can act? He cant make video games, music , and can barely play basketball. So why did he think he could do this? He might as well called this Shaqfu the live action movie, because that is exactly what this movie is, its a big Fu from shaq. That is right folks shaq is screwing you hard and there is nothing you can do about it.So if you watch this grit your teeth bare the load and get ready for a full on anal invasion from the master him self in this torture porn of a movie.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    It's good for a rainy day, I'd say...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    dee.reid
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/5/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    With all this madness about superheroes going on right now ("The Avengers" just opened today), I decided to go back in time to 1997, to the poorly received box office flop "Steel." I was 12 back in 1997, but I have to admit that I liked "Steel" then (I also liked the big-budget adaptation of another favorite superhero of mine, "Spawn"). 15 years later, a lot has changed. For one, I've grown up. I now realize that "Steel" is not a very good movie. I remember around that time, my cousin saw "Steel" in the theaters and told us that it was not a very good movie. The critics and most sensible audience members seemed to agree. But I digress; "Steel" is good for one thing and one thing only: a rainy day, like today. Since I'm not daring brave the over-crowded theaters for fear of being over-run by Avengers fan-boys (and fan-girls), I decided to pop in my 14-year-old VHS copy of "Steel" and relive 1997 like it was just 15 years ago (which, in fact, it was). "Steel" is the live-action adaptation of the second-tier DC Comics character co-created by Louise Simonson and Jon Bogdanove, with NBA star Shaquille O'Neal playing the titular steel-armored, non-super-powered superhero whose real name is John Henry Irons in his civilian identity. I'm not really a fan of the movie anymore (most readers will remember that I'm largely a Marvel Comics reader), but I find the history of the original comic book character to be quite fascinating: as yet another proud, positive black-American superhero in comics, John Henry Irons is a brilliant former weapons designer for a private arms-manufacturing company whose life is saved, both literally and metaphorically, by the mighty Man of Steel himself, Superman. Ironically, a later incident with the powerful super-villain Doomsday costs Superman his life, and Irons's life is changed forever when he decides to don a powered suit of armor of his own making - much like Marvel Comics' Tony Stark/Iron Man - and fight crime himself as Steel (with Superman's logo blazoned mightily on his chest as a reminder of his inspiration) and wielding a powerful sledgehammer, too. The 1997 live-action adaptation removes any mention of Superman (or his apparent death), except for a tattoo O'Neal has on his arm, and goes forward with its own origin story. Certain aspects of the movie are faithful to the comics, but the rest of it is pretty campy and just bloody awful. This time out, Irons is a weapons designer for the U.S. Army and when an ambitious rival, Nathaniel Burke (Judd Nelson), is involved in an accident that kills a U.S. senator and leaves his best friend Susan "Sparky" Sparks (Annabeth Gish) a paraplegic, Irons resigns from the military in disgust. Irons (whose name is reportedly inspired by the legendary black-American folk hero John Henry) returns to his home in Los Angeles, only to discover that street gangs are out committing brazen bank robberies using the exact same, albeit heavily modified, weapons he designed. With Sparky and Uncle Joe (Richard Roundtree) by his side, Irons dons a custom-made suit of armor as the armored superhero Steel. As he dives deeper into his investigation, he discovers that his old rival Nathaniel Burke (who has since recruited young neighborhood street kids to do his bidding) is behind the robberies and the deadly new weapons out on the street. "Steel" is pretty cheesy and campy, and I don't mean that in a good way. Unlike most people, I don't think Shaquille O'Neal is that lousy an actor. I think that if he were given the right material, he would manage out OK. At least here, I think he seems perfect for the part of John Henry Irons/Steel; it's just a shame that the rest of the movie, as written and directed by Kenneth Johnson ("V"), is just not very good. In other words, Shaq just needed a better movie. The special effects, the hokey street dialogue, and the performances don't help matters much either. Richard Roundtree and Irma P. Hall do what they can, but aren't given a whole lot to do beyond offering elder-generation advice to the younger folks. Judd Nelson relishes his role as a stereotypical villain, but it's really Annabeth Gish as the physically handicapped yet resilient gadgeteer Susan Sparks who really seems to shine the most in what could have been a very limiting part. I sense that a remake/reboot is, or soon probably will be, in the works sometime in the near future, and that is one "Steel" I just "may" (italicized) fork over $7.50 at my local movie theater to see. Until then, "Steel" will continue to mightily serve its purpose for rainy days (and some late-'90s nostalgia)... 4/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    For 97 it's pretty good, unless you have anything else to watch.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Gregory
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/10/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I have no interest in basketball, I stink at it, and the only big names I know are Michael Jordan, Shaquille O'Neal and the Harlem Globetrotters. I have no idea why everyone likes to criticize Shaq, nor do I really care - he had to be good at something in order to be ridiculed so much. Quoting others, for 1997 it's pretty good, unless you have anything else to watch. It's not a masterpiece, but rather one of those pictures that requires you to set aside your pre-conceived notions about good film-making and just enjoy the ride. Do that, and Steel is a surprisingly amusing little adventure comedy. On top of all that, it has a memorable theme and subtle special effects. John Henry Irons was a harmless weapons designer until his project crippled his partner Sparks. After quitting his job, his weapons are mass-produced for criminals, and in order to stop it Irons and Sparks create a suit of armor that leads Irons to become the superhero vigilante Steel. He is the blue collar Iron Man of the DC universe. Overall, it's an average superhero film plot. The original story of Steel was based on the comic book Death of Superman. Irons wanted to go after Doomsday, the killer of Superman, himself, thus creating a mechanical super suit. But the film was in development for so long, that it lost all meaning. Instead, we got a cheesier independent film without the long drama. Given the way others cashed on the Death of Superman, the film could have been far worse. The reason why its one of my favorite movies is Steels realistic, cheap and simple armor. The hand-forged work-in-progress suit with chain mail and occasional glitches was made in a junkyard out of regular iron and steel. That's as good as any of us can get without using advanced industrial facilities. Some may argue it looks like someone decided to pour glue all over their body and go rolling around in a junkyard, but it's well thought through, even though parts sometimes just fall off in action. The 34kg armored suit is not only bulletproof, but also well padded, able to absorb most kinetic energy. Steel takes on a clip of ammo, some stun impulses, and a sonic blast that throws him back about 6m. He even falls of a building about 24m into a dumpster. It's virtually impregnable to known weaponry. I really like how they made the waist area. It's simultaneously flexible and incredibly strong. There is no such tech on the market even a decade later. The chain mail is almost indistinguishable from plate armor creating an impression that he is almost completely covered in steel plates. The electric support is a basic video/audio 31km earpiece transceiver, with an extra camera for rear view, an inbuilt GPS for fast navigation around the city, and a basic body monitoring system with body ventilation. The left arm houses a nail gun and a grappling hook (slow, but supports about 181kg for a short time). The shoulders are nice, but don't protect from above dangers, exposing the chain mail, and gloves are just regular surface chain mail, with no palm protection. The weakest part of the suit is the helmet. Not only does look like it's made of rubber, but it also leaves the face exposed. Steel was shot in the head several times throughout the film, but the biggest injury he sustained was a scratched chin from falling on pavement. Well, it is a superhero movie and emotionless faces with chin guards are for villains. The main weapon of Steel is his sledgehammer, pimped with a sonic gun, stun gun, short focus laser, a grenade launcher and high-powered magnet. The long-range capabilities come equipped with a sniper scope. Since the suit is mostly iron, it amplifies the magnetic field of the hammer, enabling to attract anything iron around him, like enemy weapons and trashcan lids. Sadly, jet boots and super strength, along with other over the top features, were left out from the 97-minute film about a guy building power armor in a 97s junkyard. However, there were also improvements. There is no red cape, or a gigantic "S" on his chest. Later DC versions of Steel retained this, setting him apart from Superman. The resulting "armor" satisfied both the look of the character and the filming physical requirements. After completion, with all its pieces and layering, it took 3 costumers an hour to transform John Henry into Steel. Shaq had to do all of his own stunts because the producers were unable to find a 2.16m stunt double for him. Other movie features include a customized humvee, van, motorbike and wheelchair. As far as superhero movies go, this one didn't fall as flat as more popular hero films that altered the original story. Steel costume may look like a cheap Robocop mockup, but at least you can RUN in it without CGI. Let's see you make a better suit without CGI! I dare you! I double dare you!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Movie That Killed Comic Book Movies for Nearly a Decade
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Eric Smith
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/7/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is one of the most horrifyingly awful films of all time. It would an embarrassment to your local dump to find this movie wallowing in there. It's not even worthy of that! Shaquille O'Neal delivers a performance that (gasp!) is worse than his awful performance in Kazaam! Apparently, after the mild success and small critical praise of Shaq's performance in Blue Chips, he thought he had a chance at a real acting career. I would like to know who it was that encouraged him to go forth with two more lead roles in his career?! The only reason he did so well in Blue Chips was because he was basically playing himself! Casting Shaq in this big, lumbering idiot of a role is so bad, it actually makes us laugh...hard. The costuming is a joke. It's all too obvious that Shaq is wearing a rubber helmet when its supposed to be made of steel! He also looks just plain ridiculous in that suit. He looks like an over-sized kid ready for Halloween, as he has to strain to peer through the eye holes. He just looks like a metallic turd. The special effects are mediocre at best, and the rest of the cast is bland. Judd Nelson, who's career said bye-bye back in the '80s, is among the worst villains in movie history, and certainly didn't help his career any. The story is ludicrous and often makes no sense...that is, when there is an actual story to follow, and the dialogue is so bad, that they have to resort to stealing lines from other, far better, action movies!! After this, its plain to see why you didn't see another comic-book based movie for a while (excluding Batman & Robin, which was a joke in itself). This movie literally killed the comic book movie for almost a decade.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I found Superman's kryptonite.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    YellowJacketYJ
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/4/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Steel is one of those movies that you hear how bad it is, but, in your mind, believe that it can't be that bad. This time, it is that bad. Steel is the equivalent of going to a PETA meeting wearing a fur coat with snakeskin boots, with deer blood dried onto your pants, while holding a platter of ham, chicken, turkey, and other "animal cruelty" foods in one hand, and a deer head in the other. To make it easier to understand, it feels out of place and doomed to fail (and possibly pelted with tomatoes). Shaq, as the movie poster refers to him as, plays John Henry Irons, a weapons designer for the military. After a tragic accident occurs (not the board meeting to green-light this movie), Irons retires his position and returns to the safety of his home. Within a few days back, he takes notice that his dangerous guns are running amok in the streets, thanks to Nathaniel Burke, a former sergeant (I'm probably wrong about his position, but who cares) relieved from his position for attempted destruction (and no, he wasn't the man who green-lit this movie. Okay, I'll stop). I want to stop right there and delve into the stupidity that this situation is. I'm still laughing at the fact that, instead of criminal punishment via jail time, a man bent on human destruction is just released from his military duties. What the hell?!? Did they honestly think he wasn't going to cause destruction once he got home? What if they did this in real life. For instance, when they found Saddam Huessin, instead of hanging him, they just spanked him on the ass! I'm sure that would've worked. Anyway, back to the plot (or as much of a plot there is). Once ahold of these guns, Nathaniel uses them to destroy Irons' hometown, and Irons himself. Of course, this doesn't keep Irons down, as he gets back up, renames himself Shaquille O'Neal, joins the NBA, and becomes a huge star. Okay, so this didn't happen in the movie. But I'm pretty positive this is how Shaq's career came about. My ramblings aside, Irons picks himself back up, grabs an old army buddy and Shaft (not kidding), makes himself the absolute worst looking superhero attire ever (it makes the Bat Nipples look like the Mona Lisa), dons himself Steel, and comes back to save the day, equipped with a huge sledgehammer (Triple H's inspiration), magnetic shield, and advice (once again, not kidding). The sheer stupidity that is Steel is unprecedented. Yes, I've seen worse COUGH*Batman & Robin*COUGH. But, that doesn't do justice for the man of Steel (and insults the true man of Steel, Superman, which this story is based off of a side character after the death of Superman). Steel is so bad, that I was actually yearning for Kazaam shortly into the movie. Do yourself a favor, and shoot yourself in the foot. It's a lot less painful.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Quite Possibly the Worst Movie Ever Made
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Michael Margetis (pmargetis@cox.net)
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/11/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Uncle Joe: Well dip me in sh__t and roll me in breadcrumbs. Without question, 'Steel' is in the running for worst film ever made. However, it is a fun movie to watch to make fun of. You'll be laughing hysterically, but not as the filmmakers intended. Shaquille O'Neal's acting skills are kind of like Adolf Hitler's morals. They're seriously lacking. This movie does have some classic one liners like "Y'all stay cool now." a line Shaq delivers to a couple of old people he returns a stolen purse to, and my personal favorite, "Well, dip me in sh__t and roll me in breadcrumbs!". I highly recommend 'Steel' if you need a good laugh. I think I laughed harder during this than I did during 'Borat'. Grade: F
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Jumbo-Sized Hero
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jonathon_naylor
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/11/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Let's get the worst facets of STEEL out of the way first. Yes, Shaquille O'Neal is a dreadful actor. Yes, he looks like the world's biggest sardine can in his Steel armor. Yes, the dialog is bargain basement. Yes, Judd Nelson makes for the worst comic book villain this side of Mark Hamill as The Trickster in THE FLASH television series. And yes, the film embarrasses itself even further by clumsily trying to deliver a we-must-stop-using-weapons-to-settle-our-differences message. Happy? STEEL is not a masterpiece in any sense of the word, but that doesn't mean it should be completely written off. It's one of those pictures that requires you to set aside your pre-conceived notions about good film-making and just enjoy the ride. Do that, and STEEL is a surprisingly amusing little adventure. O'Neal is fun, if not unspectacular, as our jumbo-sized hero, a do-gooder vigilante cleanin' up the streets with a big ol' hammer and souped-up motorbike. He's aided by wheelchair-bound hottie Annabeth Gish and an aged Richard Roundtree as his off-the-wall Uncle Joe. Our hero's climactic showdown with the one-dimensionally evil Nelson is incredibly cheesy, as are many scenes, but the film has its heart so firmly in the right place you'll be more than a little lenient. As usual, what Shaq lacks in talent he makes up for in charm and a deep likability that seeps right through the screen. STEEL is an uncomplicated film that seems custom-made for little boys, who will absolutely adore it. If you're in the right mood, you'll like it, too.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Poor action stuff that will only appeal to children and undemanding adults
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bob the moo
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/11/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    John Henry Irons is a weapons designer for the military who has been key in the development of a range of experimental weapons that immobilise enemy troops without any fatalities. However when Nat Burke tries to increase the power of the weapon during the test, the result sees a Senator dead and one of his colleagues disabled. The court martial sees Burke kicked out of the military and John decides his days of weapon design are over  returning to LA to work in a small steel mill. However when his weapons somehow make it into the hands of LA's criminal underworld, John decides that it is "on" and takes steps to counter the threat. Universally derided ever since it was even green lit for production, this film does have little to recommend it but still produces very basic distraction if that is what you want. The plot is obvious and goes just where you expect it to and it offers little for the discerning adult viewer (or to be honest the undemanding ones too). The action will please children but it is the wider delivery where it all falls down and, contrary to opinion, it is not all Shaq's fault. The script is clunky for the most part and has lots of injokes, most of which are embarrassing basketball references although, that said, the "Shaft" joke drew a laugh from me simply because it was so unexpected and so disrespectful to the film! This is very basic stuff though and nobody seems that interested in trying to make it more than that. Johnson is happy to deliver a kiddie-friendly superhero movie for the most part and this is all it seems to be. The cast have potential but too few of them have any decent material to work with. O'Neal can't act and that's the truth. He can play basketball and, given the riches this has given him we should not feel too sorry for him here. He says his lines and he stands where they tell him to stand but that is not the same as producing a character and being engaging  neither of which applies in this situation. Gish has little to do and Roundtree seems happy just to be a walking reference. Nelson hams it up in an obvious baddie while Harper, Hall and Ray J (!) are not the ones to address the lack of quality. The only person that I actually noted with interest was Kevin Grevioux, not because of his performance here but more because he is an interesting man who has built a small but varied career. Overall then this is a poor superhero movie but one that has had just about enough money spent on it to make it distract children and undemanding adults. The backlash against has been a bit overly cruel but it is still not any good with basic acting, basic script, basic plotting and action that only aspires to be colourful and noisy.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Worst Superhero Movie ever.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Khalid Rafi
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Wow, this movie is unbelievably terrible. Why? Shaquille O'Neal. That's why. Shaq stars as John Henry Irons a special weapon designer for the military who quits after seeing the damage they do after the weapon reaches the hands of the street gangs he uses his brains and his Uncle Joe's junkyard know-how to fight back by becoming a guy who wears metal Shaq gives an unbelievably terrible performance trying to be Superman. The I guess you're probably wondering why i gave it a 1, I guess he had a cool costume. In conclusion, A low budget, horribly acted movie that just goes to show us how low the bar for acting can go. So if you're in the mood to watch an old Superman movie, don't because this isn't Suuperman.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Shaq Can't Act
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    zardoz-13
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Shaquille O'Neal was a better basketball star than he was an actor. Cast as the eponymous hero in scif-fi writer & director Kenneth Johnson's costumed crime fighter saga, he looks absurd with his sappy expressions. Nevertheless, "Steel" isn't a bad movie. Despite Shaq's lackluster performance, this 97-minute adaptation of a DC Comics character features some fine performances from Judd Nelson, Annabeth Gish, and Richard Roundtree. Johnson makes several references to the superheroes in the DC Comics Universe, but Superman never makes a cameo. In the comics, Superman saved John Henry Steel's life and advised him to make something of himself. As far as this movie goes, Superman doesn't exist and John Henry Steel Shaquille O'Neal) has never made contact with him. Shaq is in the military when the action unfolds and he is testing experimental weapons. Nathaniel Burke (Judd Nelson) is a fellow officer. Unscrupulous to the core, he is always willing to push the envelope on any project. When Senator Nolan hints that he can expect a promotion to captain if he pushes things along on a weapons testing program, Burke resets the mechanism on one of John Henry's laser weapons. John Henry builds weapons that don't kill so much as neutralize enemy troops. The blast misfires and knocks on a concrete wall. Susan "Sparky" Sparks (Annabeth Gish of "Mystic Pizza") is pinned under a giant fragment. Our seven foot one hero frees her, but she spends the rest of her life in a wheelchair. Incredibly, a military tribunal is held, and Burke run out of the service. Despondent over the condition of Sparky, John Henry resigns from the Army. What he doesn't know is that Burke has taken the gun designs and plans to produce versions of it to sell. He captures attention not long afterward when he arms a gang of hoodlums and they rob a bank. John Henry sets up a secret factory in his Uncle's junkyard. He pulls Sparky out of a depressing V.A. Hospital and makes him the brain of his operation. He creates a steel suit and is given a special sledgehammer. Meanwhile, Burke lets every scumbag in the world know that he can provide them with the ultimate weapon. "Steel" is formulaic but entertaining. The hand grenade scene is unforgivable.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    ShaqFu In an iron suit
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Tommy Bolden
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    You ever wonder what it would feel like to be raped by 7 football tall black man and then him steal 10 bucks from you? Well watch this movie and you will find out.What makes shaq think he can act? He cant make video games, music , and can barely play basketball. So why did he think he could do this? He might as well called this Shaqfu the live action movie, because that is exactly what this movie is, its a big Fu from shaq. That is right folks shaq is screwing you hard and there is nothing you can do about it.So if you watch this grit your teeth bare the load and get ready for a full on anal invasion from the master him self in this torture porn of a movie.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    It's good for a rainy day, I'd say...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    dee.reid
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/5/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    With all this madness about superheroes going on right now ("The Avengers" just opened today), I decided to go back in time to 1997, to the poorly received box office flop "Steel." I was 12 back in 1997, but I have to admit that I liked "Steel" then (I also liked the big-budget adaptation of another favorite superhero of mine, "Spawn"). 15 years later, a lot has changed. For one, I've grown up. I now realize that "Steel" is not a very good movie. I remember around that time, my cousin saw "Steel" in the theaters and told us that it was not a very good movie. The critics and most sensible audience members seemed to agree. But I digress; "Steel" is good for one thing and one thing only: a rainy day, like today. Since I'm not daring brave the over-crowded theaters for fear of being over-run by Avengers fan-boys (and fan-girls), I decided to pop in my 14-year-old VHS copy of "Steel" and relive 1997 like it was just 15 years ago (which, in fact, it was). "Steel" is the live-action adaptation of the second-tier DC Comics character co-created by Louise Simonson and Jon Bogdanove, with NBA star Shaquille O'Neal playing the titular steel-armored, non-super-powered superhero whose real name is John Henry Irons in his civilian identity. I'm not really a fan of the movie anymore (most readers will remember that I'm largely a Marvel Comics reader), but I find the history of the original comic book character to be quite fascinating: as yet another proud, positive black-American superhero in comics, John Henry Irons is a brilliant former weapons designer for a private arms-manufacturing company whose life is saved, both literally and metaphorically, by the mighty Man of Steel himself, Superman. Ironically, a later incident with the powerful super-villain Doomsday costs Superman his life, and Irons's life is changed forever when he decides to don a powered suit of armor of his own making - much like Marvel Comics' Tony Stark/Iron Man - and fight crime himself as Steel (with Superman's logo blazoned mightily on his chest as a reminder of his inspiration) and wielding a powerful sledgehammer, too. The 1997 live-action adaptation removes any mention of Superman (or his apparent death), except for a tattoo O'Neal has on his arm, and goes forward with its own origin story. Certain aspects of the movie are faithful to the comics, but the rest of it is pretty campy and just bloody awful. This time out, Irons is a weapons designer for the U.S. Army and when an ambitious rival, Nathaniel Burke (Judd Nelson), is involved in an accident that kills a U.S. senator and leaves his best friend Susan "Sparky" Sparks (Annabeth Gish) a paraplegic, Irons resigns from the military in disgust. Irons (whose name is reportedly inspired by the legendary black-American folk hero John Henry) returns to his home in Los Angeles, only to discover that street gangs are out committing brazen bank robberies using the exact same, albeit heavily modified, weapons he designed. With Sparky and Uncle Joe (Richard Roundtree) by his side, Irons dons a custom-made suit of armor as the armored superhero Steel. As he dives deeper into his investigation, he discovers that his old rival Nathaniel Burke (who has since recruited young neighborhood street kids to do his bidding) is behind the robberies and the deadly new weapons out on the street. "Steel" is pretty cheesy and campy, and I don't mean that in a good way. Unlike most people, I don't think Shaquille O'Neal is that lousy an actor. I think that if he were given the right material, he would manage out OK. At least here, I think he seems perfect for the part of John Henry Irons/Steel; it's just a shame that the rest of the movie, as written and directed by Kenneth Johnson ("V"), is just not very good. In other words, Shaq just needed a better movie. The special effects, the hokey street dialogue, and the performances don't help matters much either. Richard Roundtree and Irma P. Hall do what they can, but aren't given a whole lot to do beyond offering elder-generation advice to the younger folks. Judd Nelson relishes his role as a stereotypical villain, but it's really Annabeth Gish as the physically handicapped yet resilient gadgeteer Susan Sparks who really seems to shine the most in what could have been a very limiting part. I sense that a remake/reboot is, or soon probably will be, in the works sometime in the near future, and that is one "Steel" I just "may" (italicized) fork over $7.50 at my local movie theater to see. Until then, "Steel" will continue to mightily serve its purpose for rainy days (and some late-'90s nostalgia)... 4/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    For 97 it's pretty good, unless you have anything else to watch.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Gregory
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/10/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I have no interest in basketball, I stink at it, and the only big names I know are Michael Jordan, Shaquille O'Neal and the Harlem Globetrotters. I have no idea why everyone likes to criticize Shaq, nor do I really care - he had to be good at something in order to be ridiculed so much. Quoting others, for 1997 it's pretty good, unless you have anything else to watch. It's not a masterpiece, but rather one of those pictures that requires you to set aside your pre-conceived notions about good film-making and just enjoy the ride. Do that, and Steel is a surprisingly amusing little adventure comedy. On top of all that, it has a memorable theme and subtle special effects. John Henry Irons was a harmless weapons designer until his project crippled his partner Sparks. After quitting his job, his weapons are mass-produced for criminals, and in order to stop it Irons and Sparks create a suit of armor that leads Irons to become the superhero vigilante Steel. He is the blue collar Iron Man of the DC universe. Overall, it's an average superhero film plot. The original story of Steel was based on the comic book Death of Superman. Irons wanted to go after Doomsday, the killer of Superman, himself, thus creating a mechanical super suit. But the film was in development for so long, that it lost all meaning. Instead, we got a cheesier independent film without the long drama. Given the way others cashed on the Death of Superman, the film could have been far worse. The reason why its one of my favorite movies is Steels realistic, cheap and simple armor. The hand-forged work-in-progress suit with chain mail and occasional glitches was made in a junkyard out of regular iron and steel. That's as good as any of us can get without using advanced industrial facilities. Some may argue it looks like someone decided to pour glue all over their body and go rolling around in a junkyard, but it's well thought through, even though parts sometimes just fall off in action. The 34kg armored suit is not only bulletproof, but also well padded, able to absorb most kinetic energy. Steel takes on a clip of ammo, some stun impulses, and a sonic blast that throws him back about 6m. He even falls of a building about 24m into a dumpster. It's virtually impregnable to known weaponry. I really like how they made the waist area. It's simultaneously flexible and incredibly strong. There is no such tech on the market even a decade later. The chain mail is almost indistinguishable from plate armor creating an impression that he is almost completely covered in steel plates. The electric support is a basic video/audio 31km earpiece transceiver, with an extra camera for rear view, an inbuilt GPS for fast navigation around the city, and a basic body monitoring system with body ventilation. The left arm houses a nail gun and a grappling hook (slow, but supports about 181kg for a short time). The shoulders are nice, but don't protect from above dangers, exposing the chain mail, and gloves are just regular surface chain mail, with no palm protection. The weakest part of the suit is the helmet. Not only does look like it's made of rubber, but it also leaves the face exposed. Steel was shot in the head several times throughout the film, but the biggest injury he sustained was a scratched chin from falling on pavement. Well, it is a superhero movie and emotionless faces with chin guards are for villains. The main weapon of Steel is his sledgehammer, pimped with a sonic gun, stun gun, short focus laser, a grenade launcher and high-powered magnet. The long-range capabilities come equipped with a sniper scope. Since the suit is mostly iron, it amplifies the magnetic field of the hammer, enabling to attract anything iron around him, like enemy weapons and trashcan lids. Sadly, jet boots and super strength, along with other over the top features, were left out from the 97-minute film about a guy building power armor in a 97s junkyard. However, there were also improvements. There is no red cape, or a gigantic "S" on his chest. Later DC versions of Steel retained this, setting him apart from Superman. The resulting "armor" satisfied both the look of the character and the filming physical requirements. After completion, with all its pieces and layering, it took 3 costumers an hour to transform John Henry into Steel. Shaq had to do all of his own stunts because the producers were unable to find a 2.16m stunt double for him. Other movie features include a customized humvee, van, motorbike and wheelchair. As far as superhero movies go, this one didn't fall as flat as more popular hero films that altered the original story. Steel costume may look like a cheap Robocop mockup, but at least you can RUN in it without CGI. Let's see you make a better suit without CGI! I dare you! I double dare you!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Movie That Killed Comic Book Movies for Nearly a Decade
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Eric Smith
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/7/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is one of the most horrifyingly awful films of all time. It would an embarrassment to your local dump to find this movie wallowing in there. It's not even worthy of that! Shaquille O'Neal delivers a performance that (gasp!) is worse than his awful performance in Kazaam! Apparently, after the mild success and small critical praise of Shaq's performance in Blue Chips, he thought he had a chance at a real acting career. I would like to know who it was that encouraged him to go forth with two more lead roles in his career?! The only reason he did so well in Blue Chips was because he was basically playing himself! Casting Shaq in this big, lumbering idiot of a role is so bad, it actually makes us laugh...hard. The costuming is a joke. It's all too obvious that Shaq is wearing a rubber helmet when its supposed to be made of steel! He also looks just plain ridiculous in that suit. He looks like an over-sized kid ready for Halloween, as he has to strain to peer through the eye holes. He just looks like a metallic turd. The special effects are mediocre at best, and the rest of the cast is bland. Judd Nelson, who's career said bye-bye back in the '80s, is among the worst villains in movie history, and certainly didn't help his career any. The story is ludicrous and often makes no sense...that is, when there is an actual story to follow, and the dialogue is so bad, that they have to resort to stealing lines from other, far better, action movies!! After this, its plain to see why you didn't see another comic-book based movie for a while (excluding Batman & Robin, which was a joke in itself). This movie literally killed the comic book movie for almost a decade.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I found Superman's kryptonite.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    YellowJacketYJ
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/4/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Steel is one of those movies that you hear how bad it is, but, in your mind, believe that it can't be that bad. This time, it is that bad. Steel is the equivalent of going to a PETA meeting wearing a fur coat with snakeskin boots, with deer blood dried onto your pants, while holding a platter of ham, chicken, turkey, and other "animal cruelty" foods in one hand, and a deer head in the other. To make it easier to understand, it feels out of place and doomed to fail (and possibly pelted with tomatoes). Shaq, as the movie poster refers to him as, plays John Henry Irons, a weapons designer for the military. After a tragic accident occurs (not the board meeting to green-light this movie), Irons retires his position and returns to the safety of his home. Within a few days back, he takes notice that his dangerous guns are running amok in the streets, thanks to Nathaniel Burke, a former sergeant (I'm probably wrong about his position, but who cares) relieved from his position for attempted destruction (and no, he wasn't the man who green-lit this movie. Okay, I'll stop). I want to stop right there and delve into the stupidity that this situation is. I'm still laughing at the fact that, instead of criminal punishment via jail time, a man bent on human destruction is just released from his military duties. What the hell?!? Did they honestly think he wasn't going to cause destruction once he got home? What if they did this in real life. For instance, when they found Saddam Huessin, instead of hanging him, they just spanked him on the ass! I'm sure that would've worked. Anyway, back to the plot (or as much of a plot there is). Once ahold of these guns, Nathaniel uses them to destroy Irons' hometown, and Irons himself. Of course, this doesn't keep Irons down, as he gets back up, renames himself Shaquille O'Neal, joins the NBA, and becomes a huge star. Okay, so this didn't happen in the movie. But I'm pretty positive this is how Shaq's career came about. My ramblings aside, Irons picks himself back up, grabs an old army buddy and Shaft (not kidding), makes himself the absolute worst looking superhero attire ever (it makes the Bat Nipples look like the Mona Lisa), dons himself Steel, and comes back to save the day, equipped with a huge sledgehammer (Triple H's inspiration), magnetic shield, and advice (once again, not kidding). The sheer stupidity that is Steel is unprecedented. Yes, I've seen worse COUGH*Batman & Robin*COUGH. But, that doesn't do justice for the man of Steel (and insults the true man of Steel, Superman, which this story is based off of a side character after the death of Superman). Steel is so bad, that I was actually yearning for Kazaam shortly into the movie. Do yourself a favor, and shoot yourself in the foot. It's a lot less painful.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Quite Possibly the Worst Movie Ever Made
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Michael Margetis (pmargetis@cox.net)
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/11/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Uncle Joe: Well dip me in sh__t and roll me in breadcrumbs. Without question, 'Steel' is in the running for worst film ever made. However, it is a fun movie to watch to make fun of. You'll be laughing hysterically, but not as the filmmakers intended. Shaquille O'Neal's acting skills are kind of like Adolf Hitler's morals. They're seriously lacking. This movie does have some classic one liners like "Y'all stay cool now." a line Shaq delivers to a couple of old people he returns a stolen purse to, and my personal favorite, "Well, dip me in sh__t and roll me in breadcrumbs!". I highly recommend 'Steel' if you need a good laugh. I think I laughed harder during this than I did during 'Borat'. Grade: F
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Jumbo-Sized Hero
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jonathon_naylor
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/11/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Let's get the worst facets of STEEL out of the way first. Yes, Shaquille O'Neal is a dreadful actor. Yes, he looks like the world's biggest sardine can in his Steel armor. Yes, the dialog is bargain basement. Yes, Judd Nelson makes for the worst comic book villain this side of Mark Hamill as The Trickster in THE FLASH television series. And yes, the film embarrasses itself even further by clumsily trying to deliver a we-must-stop-using-weapons-to-settle-our-differences message. Happy? STEEL is not a masterpiece in any sense of the word, but that doesn't mean it should be completely written off. It's one of those pictures that requires you to set aside your pre-conceived notions about good film-making and just enjoy the ride. Do that, and STEEL is a surprisingly amusing little adventure. O'Neal is fun, if not unspectacular, as our jumbo-sized hero, a do-gooder vigilante cleanin' up the streets with a big ol' hammer and souped-up motorbike. He's aided by wheelchair-bound hottie Annabeth Gish and an aged Richard Roundtree as his off-the-wall Uncle Joe. Our hero's climactic showdown with the one-dimensionally evil Nelson is incredibly cheesy, as are many scenes, but the film has its heart so firmly in the right place you'll be more than a little lenient. As usual, what Shaq lacks in talent he makes up for in charm and a deep likability that seeps right through the screen. STEEL is an uncomplicated film that seems custom-made for little boys, who will absolutely adore it. If you're in the right mood, you'll like it, too.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Poor action stuff that will only appeal to children and undemanding adults
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bob the moo
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/11/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    John Henry Irons is a weapons designer for the military who has been key in the development of a range of experimental weapons that immobilise enemy troops without any fatalities. However when Nat Burke tries to increase the power of the weapon during the test, the result sees a Senator dead and one of his colleagues disabled. The court martial sees Burke kicked out of the military and John decides his days of weapon design are over  returning to LA to work in a small steel mill. However when his weapons somehow make it into the hands of LA's criminal underworld, John decides that it is "on" and takes steps to counter the threat. Universally derided ever since it was even green lit for production, this film does have little to recommend it but still produces very basic distraction if that is what you want. The plot is obvious and goes just where you expect it to and it offers little for the discerning adult viewer (or to be honest the undemanding ones too). The action will please children but it is the wider delivery where it all falls down and, contrary to opinion, it is not all Shaq's fault. The script is clunky for the most part and has lots of injokes, most of which are embarrassing basketball references although, that said, the "Shaft" joke drew a laugh from me simply because it was so unexpected and so disrespectful to the film! This is very basic stuff though and nobody seems that interested in trying to make it more than that. Johnson is happy to deliver a kiddie-friendly superhero movie for the most part and this is all it seems to be. The cast have potential but too few of them have any decent material to work with. O'Neal can't act and that's the truth. He can play basketball and, given the riches this has given him we should not feel too sorry for him here. He says his lines and he stands where they tell him to stand but that is not the same as producing a character and being engaging  neither of which applies in this situation. Gish has little to do and Roundtree seems happy just to be a walking reference. Nelson hams it up in an obvious baddie while Harper, Hall and Ray J (!) are not the ones to address the lack of quality. The only person that I actually noted with interest was Kevin Grevioux, not because of his performance here but more because he is an interesting man who has built a small but varied career. Overall then this is a poor superhero movie but one that has had just about enough money spent on it to make it distract children and undemanding adults. The backlash against has been a bit overly cruel but it is still not any good with basic acting, basic script, basic plotting and action that only aspires to be colourful and noisy.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Worst Superhero Movie ever.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Khalid Rafi
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Wow, this movie is unbelievably terrible. Why? Shaquille O'Neal. That's why. Shaq stars as John Henry Irons a special weapon designer for the military who quits after seeing the damage they do after the weapon reaches the hands of the street gangs he uses his brains and his Uncle Joe's junkyard know-how to fight back by becoming a guy who wears metal Shaq gives an unbelievably terrible performance trying to be Superman. The I guess you're probably wondering why i gave it a 1, I guess he had a cool costume. In conclusion, A low budget, horribly acted movie that just goes to show us how low the bar for acting can go. So if you're in the mood to watch an old Superman movie, don't because this isn't Suuperman.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Shaq Can't Act
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    zardoz-13
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Shaquille O'Neal was a better basketball star than he was an actor. Cast as the eponymous hero in scif-fi writer & director Kenneth Johnson's costumed crime fighter saga, he looks absurd with his sappy expressions. Nevertheless, "Steel" isn't a bad movie. Despite Shaq's lackluster performance, this 97-minute adaptation of a DC Comics character features some fine performances from Judd Nelson, Annabeth Gish, and Richard Roundtree. Johnson makes several references to the superheroes in the DC Comics Universe, but Superman never makes a cameo. In the comics, Superman saved John Henry Steel's life and advised him to make something of himself. As far as this movie goes, Superman doesn't exist and John Henry Steel Shaquille O'Neal) has never made contact with him. Shaq is in the military when the action unfolds and he is testing experimental weapons. Nathaniel Burke (Judd Nelson) is a fellow officer. Unscrupulous to the core, he is always willing to push the envelope on any project. When Senator Nolan hints that he can expect a promotion to captain if he pushes things along on a weapons testing program, Burke resets the mechanism on one of John Henry's laser weapons. John Henry builds weapons that don't kill so much as neutralize enemy troops. The blast misfires and knocks on a concrete wall. Susan "Sparky" Sparks (Annabeth Gish of "Mystic Pizza") is pinned under a giant fragment. Our seven foot one hero frees her, but she spends the rest of her life in a wheelchair. Incredibly, a military tribunal is held, and Burke run out of the service. Despondent over the condition of Sparky, John Henry resigns from the Army. What he doesn't know is that Burke has taken the gun designs and plans to produce versions of it to sell. He captures attention not long afterward when he arms a gang of hoodlums and they rob a bank. John Henry sets up a secret factory in his Uncle's junkyard. He pulls Sparky out of a depressing V.A. Hospital and makes him the brain of his operation. He creates a steel suit and is given a special sledgehammer. Meanwhile, Burke lets every scumbag in the world know that he can provide them with the ultimate weapon. "Steel" is formulaic but entertaining. The hand grenade scene is unforgivable.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    ShaqFu In an iron suit
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Tommy Bolden
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    You ever wonder what it would feel like to be raped by 7 football tall black man and then him steal 10 bucks from you? Well watch this movie and you will find out.What makes shaq think he can act? He cant make video games, music , and can barely play basketball. So why did he think he could do this? He might as well called this Shaqfu the live action movie, because that is exactly what this movie is, its a big Fu from shaq. That is right folks shaq is screwing you hard and there is nothing you can do about it.So if you watch this grit your teeth bare the load and get ready for a full on anal invasion from the master him self in this torture porn of a movie.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    It's good for a rainy day, I'd say...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    dee.reid
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/5/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    With all this madness about superheroes going on right now ("The Avengers" just opened today), I decided to go back in time to 1997, to the poorly received box office flop "Steel." I was 12 back in 1997, but I have to admit that I liked "Steel" then (I also liked the big-budget adaptation of another favorite superhero of mine, "Spawn"). 15 years later, a lot has changed. For one, I've grown up. I now realize that "Steel" is not a very good movie. I remember around that time, my cousin saw "Steel" in the theaters and told us that it was not a very good movie. The critics and most sensible audience members seemed to agree. But I digress; "Steel" is good for one thing and one thing only: a rainy day, like today. Since I'm not daring brave the over-crowded theaters for fear of being over-run by Avengers fan-boys (and fan-girls), I decided to pop in my 14-year-old VHS copy of "Steel" and relive 1997 like it was just 15 years ago (which, in fact, it was). "Steel" is the live-action adaptation of the second-tier DC Comics character co-created by Louise Simonson and Jon Bogdanove, with NBA star Shaquille O'Neal playing the titular steel-armored, non-super-powered superhero whose real name is John Henry Irons in his civilian identity. I'm not really a fan of the movie anymore (most readers will remember that I'm largely a Marvel Comics reader), but I find the history of the original comic book character to be quite fascinating: as yet another proud, positive black-American superhero in comics, John Henry Irons is a brilliant former weapons designer for a private arms-manufacturing company whose life is saved, both literally and metaphorically, by the mighty Man of Steel himself, Superman. Ironically, a later incident with the powerful super-villain Doomsday costs Superman his life, and Irons's life is changed forever when he decides to don a powered suit of armor of his own making - much like Marvel Comics' Tony Stark/Iron Man - and fight crime himself as Steel (with Superman's logo blazoned mightily on his chest as a reminder of his inspiration) and wielding a powerful sledgehammer, too. The 1997 live-action adaptation removes any mention of Superman (or his apparent death), except for a tattoo O'Neal has on his arm, and goes forward with its own origin story. Certain aspects of the movie are faithful to the comics, but the rest of it is pretty campy and just bloody awful. This time out, Irons is a weapons designer for the U.S. Army and when an ambitious rival, Nathaniel Burke (Judd Nelson), is involved in an accident that kills a U.S. senator and leaves his best friend Susan "Sparky" Sparks (Annabeth Gish) a paraplegic, Irons resigns from the military in disgust. Irons (whose name is reportedly inspired by the legendary black-American folk hero John Henry) returns to his home in Los Angeles, only to discover that street gangs are out committing brazen bank robberies using the exact same, albeit heavily modified, weapons he designed. With Sparky and Uncle Joe (Richard Roundtree) by his side, Irons dons a custom-made suit of armor as the armored superhero Steel. As he dives deeper into his investigation, he discovers that his old rival Nathaniel Burke (who has since recruited young neighborhood street kids to do his bidding) is behind the robberies and the deadly new weapons out on the street. "Steel" is pretty cheesy and campy, and I don't mean that in a good way. Unlike most people, I don't think Shaquille O'Neal is that lousy an actor. I think that if he were given the right material, he would manage out OK. At least here, I think he seems perfect for the part of John Henry Irons/Steel; it's just a shame that the rest of the movie, as written and directed by Kenneth Johnson ("V"), is just not very good. In other words, Shaq just needed a better movie. The special effects, the hokey street dialogue, and the performances don't help matters much either. Richard Roundtree and Irma P. Hall do what they can, but aren't given a whole lot to do beyond offering elder-generation advice to the younger folks. Judd Nelson relishes his role as a stereotypical villain, but it's really Annabeth Gish as the physically handicapped yet resilient gadgeteer Susan Sparks who really seems to shine the most in what could have been a very limiting part. I sense that a remake/reboot is, or soon probably will be, in the works sometime in the near future, and that is one "Steel" I just "may" (italicized) fork over $7.50 at my local movie theater to see. Until then, "Steel" will continue to mightily serve its purpose for rainy days (and some late-'90s nostalgia)... 4/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    For 97 it's pretty good, unless you have anything else to watch.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Gregory
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/10/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I have no interest in basketball, I stink at it, and the only big names I know are Michael Jordan, Shaquille O'Neal and the Harlem Globetrotters. I have no idea why everyone likes to criticize Shaq, nor do I really care - he had to be good at something in order to be ridiculed so much. Quoting others, for 1997 it's pretty good, unless you have anything else to watch. It's not a masterpiece, but rather one of those pictures that requires you to set aside your pre-conceived notions about good film-making and just enjoy the ride. Do that, and Steel is a surprisingly amusing little adventure comedy. On top of all that, it has a memorable theme and subtle special effects. John Henry Irons was a harmless weapons designer until his project crippled his partner Sparks. After quitting his job, his weapons are mass-produced for criminals, and in order to stop it Irons and Sparks create a suit of armor that leads Irons to become the superhero vigilante Steel. He is the blue collar Iron Man of the DC universe. Overall, it's an average superhero film plot. The original story of Steel was based on the comic book Death of Superman. Irons wanted to go after Doomsday, the killer of Superman, himself, thus creating a mechanical super suit. But the film was in development for so long, that it lost all meaning. Instead, we got a cheesier independent film without the long drama. Given the way others cashed on the Death of Superman, the film could have been far worse. The reason why its one of my favorite movies is Steels realistic, cheap and simple armor. The hand-forged work-in-progress suit with chain mail and occasional glitches was made in a junkyard out of regular iron and steel. That's as good as any of us can get without using advanced industrial facilities. Some may argue it looks like someone decided to pour glue all over their body and go rolling around in a junkyard, but it's well thought through, even though parts sometimes just fall off in action. The 34kg armored suit is not only bulletproof, but also well padded, able to absorb most kinetic energy. Steel takes on a clip of ammo, some stun impulses, and a sonic blast that throws him back about 6m. He even falls of a building about 24m into a dumpster. It's virtually impregnable to known weaponry. I really like how they made the waist area. It's simultaneously flexible and incredibly strong. There is no such tech on the market even a decade later. The chain mail is almost indistinguishable from plate armor creating an impression that he is almost completely covered in steel plates. The electric support is a basic video/audio 31km earpiece transceiver, with an extra camera for rear view, an inbuilt GPS for fast navigation around the city, and a basic body monitoring system with body ventilation. The left arm houses a nail gun and a grappling hook (slow, but supports about 181kg for a short time). The shoulders are nice, but don't protect from above dangers, exposing the chain mail, and gloves are just regular surface chain mail, with no palm protection. The weakest part of the suit is the helmet. Not only does look like it's made of rubber, but it also leaves the face exposed. Steel was shot in the head several times throughout the film, but the biggest injury he sustained was a scratched chin from falling on pavement. Well, it is a superhero movie and emotionless faces with chin guards are for villains. The main weapon of Steel is his sledgehammer, pimped with a sonic gun, stun gun, short focus laser, a grenade launcher and high-powered magnet. The long-range capabilities come equipped with a sniper scope. Since the suit is mostly iron, it amplifies the magnetic field of the hammer, enabling to attract anything iron around him, like enemy weapons and trashcan lids. Sadly, jet boots and super strength, along with other over the top features, were left out from the 97-minute film about a guy building power armor in a 97s junkyard. However, there were also improvements. There is no red cape, or a gigantic "S" on his chest. Later DC versions of Steel retained this, setting him apart from Superman. The resulting "armor" satisfied both the look of the character and the filming physical requirements. After completion, with all its pieces and layering, it took 3 costumers an hour to transform John Henry into Steel. Shaq had to do all of his own stunts because the producers were unable to find a 2.16m stunt double for him. Other movie features include a customized humvee, van, motorbike and wheelchair. As far as superhero movies go, this one didn't fall as flat as more popular hero films that altered the original story. Steel costume may look like a cheap Robocop mockup, but at least you can RUN in it without CGI. Let's see you make a better suit without CGI! I dare you! I double dare you!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Movie That Killed Comic Book Movies for Nearly a Decade
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Eric Smith
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/7/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is one of the most horrifyingly awful films of all time. It would an embarrassment to your local dump to find this movie wallowing in there. It's not even worthy of that! Shaquille O'Neal delivers a performance that (gasp!) is worse than his awful performance in Kazaam! Apparently, after the mild success and small critical praise of Shaq's performance in Blue Chips, he thought he had a chance at a real acting career. I would like to know who it was that encouraged him to go forth with two more lead roles in his career?! The only reason he did so well in Blue Chips was because he was basically playing himself! Casting Shaq in this big, lumbering idiot of a role is so bad, it actually makes us laugh...hard. The costuming is a joke. It's all too obvious that Shaq is wearing a rubber helmet when its supposed to be made of steel! He also looks just plain ridiculous in that suit. He looks like an over-sized kid ready for Halloween, as he has to strain to peer through the eye holes. He just looks like a metallic turd. The special effects are mediocre at best, and the rest of the cast is bland. Judd Nelson, who's career said bye-bye back in the '80s, is among the worst villains in movie history, and certainly didn't help his career any. The story is ludicrous and often makes no sense...that is, when there is an actual story to follow, and the dialogue is so bad, that they have to resort to stealing lines from other, far better, action movies!! After this, its plain to see why you didn't see another comic-book based movie for a while (excluding Batman & Robin, which was a joke in itself). This movie literally killed the comic book movie for almost a decade.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I found Superman's kryptonite.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    YellowJacketYJ
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/4/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Steel is one of those movies that you hear how bad it is, but, in your mind, believe that it can't be that bad. This time, it is that bad. Steel is the equivalent of going to a PETA meeting wearing a fur coat with snakeskin boots, with deer blood dried onto your pants, while holding a platter of ham, chicken, turkey, and other "animal cruelty" foods in one hand, and a deer head in the other. To make it easier to understand, it feels out of place and doomed to fail (and possibly pelted with tomatoes). Shaq, as the movie poster refers to him as, plays John Henry Irons, a weapons designer for the military. After a tragic accident occurs (not the board meeting to green-light this movie), Irons retires his position and returns to the safety of his home. Within a few days back, he takes notice that his dangerous guns are running amok in the streets, thanks to Nathaniel Burke, a former sergeant (I'm probably wrong about his position, but who cares) relieved from his position for attempted destruction (and no, he wasn't the man who green-lit this movie. Okay, I'll stop). I want to stop right there and delve into the stupidity that this situation is. I'm still laughing at the fact that, instead of criminal punishment via jail time, a man bent on human destruction is just released from his military duties. What the hell?!? Did they honestly think he wasn't going to cause destruction once he got home? What if they did this in real life. For instance, when they found Saddam Huessin, instead of hanging him, they just spanked him on the ass! I'm sure that would've worked. Anyway, back to the plot (or as much of a plot there is). Once ahold of these guns, Nathaniel uses them to destroy Irons' hometown, and Irons himself. Of course, this doesn't keep Irons down, as he gets back up, renames himself Shaquille O'Neal, joins the NBA, and becomes a huge star. Okay, so this didn't happen in the movie. But I'm pretty positive this is how Shaq's career came about. My ramblings aside, Irons picks himself back up, grabs an old army buddy and Shaft (not kidding), makes himself the absolute worst looking superhero attire ever (it makes the Bat Nipples look like the Mona Lisa), dons himself Steel, and comes back to save the day, equipped with a huge sledgehammer (Triple H's inspiration), magnetic shield, and advice (once again, not kidding). The sheer stupidity that is Steel is unprecedented. Yes, I've seen worse COUGH*Batman & Robin*COUGH. But, that doesn't do justice for the man of Steel (and insults the true man of Steel, Superman, which this story is based off of a side character after the death of Superman). Steel is so bad, that I was actually yearning for Kazaam shortly into the movie. Do yourself a favor, and shoot yourself in the foot. It's a lot less painful.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Quite Possibly the Worst Movie Ever Made
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Michael Margetis (pmargetis@cox.net)
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/11/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Uncle Joe: Well dip me in sh__t and roll me in breadcrumbs. Without question, 'Steel' is in the running for worst film ever made. However, it is a fun movie to watch to make fun of. You'll be laughing hysterically, but not as the filmmakers intended. Shaquille O'Neal's acting skills are kind of like Adolf Hitler's morals. They're seriously lacking. This movie does have some classic one liners like "Y'all stay cool now." a line Shaq delivers to a couple of old people he returns a stolen purse to, and my personal favorite, "Well, dip me in sh__t and roll me in breadcrumbs!". I highly recommend 'Steel' if you need a good laugh. I think I laughed harder during this than I did during 'Borat'. Grade: F
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Jumbo-Sized Hero
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jonathon_naylor
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/11/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Let's get the worst facets of STEEL out of the way first. Yes, Shaquille O'Neal is a dreadful actor. Yes, he looks like the world's biggest sardine can in his Steel armor. Yes, the dialog is bargain basement. Yes, Judd Nelson makes for the worst comic book villain this side of Mark Hamill as The Trickster in THE FLASH television series. And yes, the film embarrasses itself even further by clumsily trying to deliver a we-must-stop-using-weapons-to-settle-our-differences message. Happy? STEEL is not a masterpiece in any sense of the word, but that doesn't mean it should be completely written off. It's one of those pictures that requires you to set aside your pre-conceived notions about good film-making and just enjoy the ride. Do that, and STEEL is a surprisingly amusing little adventure. O'Neal is fun, if not unspectacular, as our jumbo-sized hero, a do-gooder vigilante cleanin' up the streets with a big ol' hammer and souped-up motorbike. He's aided by wheelchair-bound hottie Annabeth Gish and an aged Richard Roundtree as his off-the-wall Uncle Joe. Our hero's climactic showdown with the one-dimensionally evil Nelson is incredibly cheesy, as are many scenes, but the film has its heart so firmly in the right place you'll be more than a little lenient. As usual, what Shaq lacks in talent he makes up for in charm and a deep likability that seeps right through the screen. STEEL is an uncomplicated film that seems custom-made for little boys, who will absolutely adore it. If you're in the right mood, you'll like it, too.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Poor action stuff that will only appeal to children and undemanding adults
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bob the moo
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/11/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    John Henry Irons is a weapons designer for the military who has been key in the development of a range of experimental weapons that immobilise enemy troops without any fatalities. However when Nat Burke tries to increase the power of the weapon during the test, the result sees a Senator dead and one of his colleagues disabled. The court martial sees Burke kicked out of the military and John decides his days of weapon design are over  returning to LA to work in a small steel mill. However when his weapons somehow make it into the hands of LA's criminal underworld, John decides that it is "on" and takes steps to counter the threat. Universally derided ever since it was even green lit for production, this film does have little to recommend it but still produces very basic distraction if that is what you want. The plot is obvious and goes just where you expect it to and it offers little for the discerning adult viewer (or to be honest the undemanding ones too). The action will please children but it is the wider delivery where it all falls down and, contrary to opinion, it is not all Shaq's fault. The script is clunky for the most part and has lots of injokes, most of which are embarrassing basketball references although, that said, the "Shaft" joke drew a laugh from me simply because it was so unexpected and so disrespectful to the film! This is very basic stuff though and nobody seems that interested in trying to make it more than that. Johnson is happy to deliver a kiddie-friendly superhero movie for the most part and this is all it seems to be. The cast have potential but too few of them have any decent material to work with. O'Neal can't act and that's the truth. He can play basketball and, given the riches this has given him we should not feel too sorry for him here. He says his lines and he stands where they tell him to stand but that is not the same as producing a character and being engaging  neither of which applies in this situation. Gish has little to do and Roundtree seems happy just to be a walking reference. Nelson hams it up in an obvious baddie while Harper, Hall and Ray J (!) are not the ones to address the lack of quality. The only person that I actually noted with interest was Kevin Grevioux, not because of his performance here but more because he is an interesting man who has built a small but varied career. Overall then this is a poor superhero movie but one that has had just about enough money spent on it to make it distract children and undemanding adults. The backlash against has been a bit overly cruel but it is still not any good with basic acting, basic script, basic plotting and action that only aspires to be colourful and noisy.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Worst Superhero Movie ever.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Khalid Rafi
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Wow, this movie is unbelievably terrible. Why? Shaquille O'Neal. That's why. Shaq stars as John Henry Irons a special weapon designer for the military who quits after seeing the damage they do after the weapon reaches the hands of the street gangs he uses his brains and his Uncle Joe's junkyard know-how to fight back by becoming a guy who wears metal Shaq gives an unbelievably terrible performance trying to be Superman. The I guess you're probably wondering why i gave it a 1, I guess he had a cool costume. In conclusion, A low budget, horribly acted movie that just goes to show us how low the bar for acting can go. So if you're in the mood to watch an old Superman movie, don't because this isn't Suuperman.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Shaq Can't Act
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    zardoz-13
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Shaquille O'Neal was a better basketball star than he was an actor. Cast as the eponymous hero in scif-fi writer & director Kenneth Johnson's costumed crime fighter saga, he looks absurd with his sappy expressions. Nevertheless, "Steel" isn't a bad movie. Despite Shaq's lackluster performance, this 97-minute adaptation of a DC Comics character features some fine performances from Judd Nelson, Annabeth Gish, and Richard Roundtree. Johnson makes several references to the superheroes in the DC Comics Universe, but Superman never makes a cameo. In the comics, Superman saved John Henry Steel's life and advised him to make something of himself. As far as this movie goes, Superman doesn't exist and John Henry Steel Shaquille O'Neal) has never made contact with him. Shaq is in the military when the action unfolds and he is testing experimental weapons. Nathaniel Burke (Judd Nelson) is a fellow officer. Unscrupulous to the core, he is always willing to push the envelope on any project. When Senator Nolan hints that he can expect a promotion to captain if he pushes things along on a weapons testing program, Burke resets the mechanism on one of John Henry's laser weapons. John Henry builds weapons that don't kill so much as neutralize enemy troops. The blast misfires and knocks on a concrete wall. Susan "Sparky" Sparks (Annabeth Gish of "Mystic Pizza") is pinned under a giant fragment. Our seven foot one hero frees her, but she spends the rest of her life in a wheelchair. Incredibly, a military tribunal is held, and Burke run out of the service. Despondent over the condition of Sparky, John Henry resigns from the Army. What he doesn't know is that Burke has taken the gun designs and plans to produce versions of it to sell. He captures attention not long afterward when he arms a gang of hoodlums and they rob a bank. John Henry sets up a secret factory in his Uncle's junkyard. He pulls Sparky out of a depressing V.A. Hospital and makes him the brain of his operation. He creates a steel suit and is given a special sledgehammer. Meanwhile, Burke lets every scumbag in the world know that he can provide them with the ultimate weapon. "Steel" is formulaic but entertaining. The hand grenade scene is unforgivable.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    ShaqFu In an iron suit
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Tommy Bolden
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    You ever wonder what it would feel like to be raped by 7 football tall black man and then him steal 10 bucks from you? Well watch this movie and you will find out.What makes shaq think he can act? He cant make video games, music , and can barely play basketball. So why did he think he could do this? He might as well called this Shaqfu the live action movie, because that is exactly what this movie is, its a big Fu from shaq. That is right folks shaq is screwing you hard and there is nothing you can do about it.So if you watch this grit your teeth bare the load and get ready for a full on anal invasion from the master him self in this torture porn of a movie.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    It's good for a rainy day, I'd say...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    dee.reid
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/5/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    With all this madness about superheroes going on right now ("The Avengers" just opened today), I decided to go back in time to 1997, to the poorly received box office flop "Steel." I was 12 back in 1997, but I have to admit that I liked "Steel" then (I also liked the big-budget adaptation of another favorite superhero of mine, "Spawn"). 15 years later, a lot has changed. For one, I've grown up. I now realize that "Steel" is not a very good movie. I remember around that time, my cousin saw "Steel" in the theaters and told us that it was not a very good movie. The critics and most sensible audience members seemed to agree. But I digress; "Steel" is good for one thing and one thing only: a rainy day, like today. Since I'm not daring brave the over-crowded theaters for fear of being over-run by Avengers fan-boys (and fan-girls), I decided to pop in my 14-year-old VHS copy of "Steel" and relive 1997 like it was just 15 years ago (which, in fact, it was). "Steel" is the live-action adaptation of the second-tier DC Comics character co-created by Louise Simonson and Jon Bogdanove, with NBA star Shaquille O'Neal playing the titular steel-armored, non-super-powered superhero whose real name is John Henry Irons in his civilian identity. I'm not really a fan of the movie anymore (most readers will remember that I'm largely a Marvel Comics reader), but I find the history of the original comic book character to be quite fascinating: as yet another proud, positive black-American superhero in comics, John Henry Irons is a brilliant former weapons designer for a private arms-manufacturing company whose life is saved, both literally and metaphorically, by the mighty Man of Steel himself, Superman. Ironically, a later incident with the powerful super-villain Doomsday costs Superman his life, and Irons's life is changed forever when he decides to don a powered suit of armor of his own making - much like Marvel Comics' Tony Stark/Iron Man - and fight crime himself as Steel (with Superman's logo blazoned mightily on his chest as a reminder of his inspiration) and wielding a powerful sledgehammer, too. The 1997 live-action adaptation removes any mention of Superman (or his apparent death), except for a tattoo O'Neal has on his arm, and goes forward with its own origin story. Certain aspects of the movie are faithful to the comics, but the rest of it is pretty campy and just bloody awful. This time out, Irons is a weapons designer for the U.S. Army and when an ambitious rival, Nathaniel Burke (Judd Nelson), is involved in an accident that kills a U.S. senator and leaves his best friend Susan "Sparky" Sparks (Annabeth Gish) a paraplegic, Irons resigns from the military in disgust. Irons (whose name is reportedly inspired by the legendary black-American folk hero John Henry) returns to his home in Los Angeles, only to discover that street gangs are out committing brazen bank robberies using the exact same, albeit heavily modified, weapons he designed. With Sparky and Uncle Joe (Richard Roundtree) by his side, Irons dons a custom-made suit of armor as the armored superhero Steel. As he dives deeper into his investigation, he discovers that his old rival Nathaniel Burke (who has since recruited young neighborhood street kids to do his bidding) is behind the robberies and the deadly new weapons out on the street. "Steel" is pretty cheesy and campy, and I don't mean that in a good way. Unlike most people, I don't think Shaquille O'Neal is that lousy an actor. I think that if he were given the right material, he would manage out OK. At least here, I think he seems perfect for the part of John Henry Irons/Steel; it's just a shame that the rest of the movie, as written and directed by Kenneth Johnson ("V"), is just not very good. In other words, Shaq just needed a better movie. The special effects, the hokey street dialogue, and the performances don't help matters much either. Richard Roundtree and Irma P. Hall do what they can, but aren't given a whole lot to do beyond offering elder-generation advice to the younger folks. Judd Nelson relishes his role as a stereotypical villain, but it's really Annabeth Gish as the physically handicapped yet resilient gadgeteer Susan Sparks who really seems to shine the most in what could have been a very limiting part. I sense that a remake/reboot is, or soon probably will be, in the works sometime in the near future, and that is one "Steel" I just "may" (italicized) fork over $7.50 at my local movie theater to see. Until then, "Steel" will continue to mightily serve its purpose for rainy days (and some late-'90s nostalgia)... 4/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    For 97 it's pretty good, unless you have anything else to watch.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Gregory
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/10/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I have no interest in basketball, I stink at it, and the only big names I know are Michael Jordan, Shaquille O'Neal and the Harlem Globetrotters. I have no idea why everyone likes to criticize Shaq, nor do I really care - he had to be good at something in order to be ridiculed so much. Quoting others, for 1997 it's pretty good, unless you have anything else to watch. It's not a masterpiece, but rather one of those pictures that requires you to set aside your pre-conceived notions about good film-making and just enjoy the ride. Do that, and Steel is a surprisingly amusing little adventure comedy. On top of all that, it has a memorable theme and subtle special effects. John Henry Irons was a harmless weapons designer until his project crippled his partner Sparks. After quitting his job, his weapons are mass-produced for criminals, and in order to stop it Irons and Sparks create a suit of armor that leads Irons to become the superhero vigilante Steel. He is the blue collar Iron Man of the DC universe. Overall, it's an average superhero film plot. The original story of Steel was based on the comic book Death of Superman. Irons wanted to go after Doomsday, the killer of Superman, himself, thus creating a mechanical super suit. But the film was in development for so long, that it lost all meaning. Instead, we got a cheesier independent film without the long drama. Given the way others cashed on the Death of Superman, the film could have been far worse. The reason why its one of my favorite movies is Steels realistic, cheap and simple armor. The hand-forged work-in-progress suit with chain mail and occasional glitches was made in a junkyard out of regular iron and steel. That's as good as any of us can get without using advanced industrial facilities. Some may argue it looks like someone decided to pour glue all over their body and go rolling around in a junkyard, but it's well thought through, even though parts sometimes just fall off in action. The 34kg armored suit is not only bulletproof, but also well padded, able to absorb most kinetic energy. Steel takes on a clip of ammo, some stun impulses, and a sonic blast that throws him back about 6m. He even falls of a building about 24m into a dumpster. It's virtually impregnable to known weaponry. I really like how they made the waist area. It's simultaneously flexible and incredibly strong. There is no such tech on the market even a decade later. The chain mail is almost indistinguishable from plate armor creating an impression that he is almost completely covered in steel plates. The electric support is a basic video/audio 31km earpiece transceiver, with an extra camera for rear view, an inbuilt GPS for fast navigation around the city, and a basic body monitoring system with body ventilation. The left arm houses a nail gun and a grappling hook (slow, but supports about 181kg for a short time). The shoulders are nice, but don't protect from above dangers, exposing the chain mail, and gloves are just regular surface chain mail, with no palm protection. The weakest part of the suit is the helmet. Not only does look like it's made of rubber, but it also leaves the face exposed. Steel was shot in the head several times throughout the film, but the biggest injury he sustained was a scratched chin from falling on pavement. Well, it is a superhero movie and emotionless faces with chin guards are for villains. The main weapon of Steel is his sledgehammer, pimped with a sonic gun, stun gun, short focus laser, a grenade launcher and high-powered magnet. The long-range capabilities come equipped with a sniper scope. Since the suit is mostly iron, it amplifies the magnetic field of the hammer, enabling to attract anything iron around him, like enemy weapons and trashcan lids. Sadly, jet boots and super strength, along with other over the top features, were left out from the 97-minute film about a guy building power armor in a 97s junkyard. However, there were also improvements. There is no red cape, or a gigantic "S" on his chest. Later DC versions of Steel retained this, setting him apart from Superman. The resulting "armor" satisfied both the look of the character and the filming physical requirements. After completion, with all its pieces and layering, it took 3 costumers an hour to transform John Henry into Steel. Shaq had to do all of his own stunts because the producers were unable to find a 2.16m stunt double for him. Other movie features include a customized humvee, van, motorbike and wheelchair. As far as superhero movies go, this one didn't fall as flat as more popular hero films that altered the original story. Steel costume may look like a cheap Robocop mockup, but at least you can RUN in it without CGI. Let's see you make a better suit without CGI! I dare you! I double dare you!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Movie That Killed Comic Book Movies for Nearly a Decade
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Eric Smith
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/7/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is one of the most horrifyingly awful films of all time. It would an embarrassment to your local dump to find this movie wallowing in there. It's not even worthy of that! Shaquille O'Neal delivers a performance that (gasp!) is worse than his awful performance in Kazaam! Apparently, after the mild success and small critical praise of Shaq's performance in Blue Chips, he thought he had a chance at a real acting career. I would like to know who it was that encouraged him to go forth with two more lead roles in his career?! The only reason he did so well in Blue Chips was because he was basically playing himself! Casting Shaq in this big, lumbering idiot of a role is so bad, it actually makes us laugh...hard. The costuming is a joke. It's all too obvious that Shaq is wearing a rubber helmet when its supposed to be made of steel! He also looks just plain ridiculous in that suit. He looks like an over-sized kid ready for Halloween, as he has to strain to peer through the eye holes. He just looks like a metallic turd. The special effects are mediocre at best, and the rest of the cast is bland. Judd Nelson, who's career said bye-bye back in the '80s, is among the worst villains in movie history, and certainly didn't help his career any. The story is ludicrous and often makes no sense...that is, when there is an actual story to follow, and the dialogue is so bad, that they have to resort to stealing lines from other, far better, action movies!! After this, its plain to see why you didn't see another comic-book based movie for a while (excluding Batman & Robin, which was a joke in itself). This movie literally killed the comic book movie for almost a decade.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I found Superman's kryptonite.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    YellowJacketYJ
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/4/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Steel is one of those movies that you hear how bad it is, but, in your mind, believe that it can't be that bad. This time, it is that bad. Steel is the equivalent of going to a PETA meeting wearing a fur coat with snakeskin boots, with deer blood dried onto your pants, while holding a platter of ham, chicken, turkey, and other "animal cruelty" foods in one hand, and a deer head in the other. To make it easier to understand, it feels out of place and doomed to fail (and possibly pelted with tomatoes). Shaq, as the movie poster refers to him as, plays John Henry Irons, a weapons designer for the military. After a tragic accident occurs (not the board meeting to green-light this movie), Irons retires his position and returns to the safety of his home. Within a few days back, he takes notice that his dangerous guns are running amok in the streets, thanks to Nathaniel Burke, a former sergeant (I'm probably wrong about his position, but who cares) relieved from his position for attempted destruction (and no, he wasn't the man who green-lit this movie. Okay, I'll stop). I want to stop right there and delve into the stupidity that this situation is. I'm still laughing at the fact that, instead of criminal punishment via jail time, a man bent on human destruction is just released from his military duties. What the hell?!? Did they honestly think he wasn't going to cause destruction once he got home? What if they did this in real life. For instance, when they found Saddam Huessin, instead of hanging him, they just spanked him on the ass! I'm sure that would've worked. Anyway, back to the plot (or as much of a plot there is). Once ahold of these guns, Nathaniel uses them to destroy Irons' hometown, and Irons himself. Of course, this doesn't keep Irons down, as he gets back up, renames himself Shaquille O'Neal, joins the NBA, and becomes a huge star. Okay, so this didn't happen in the movie. But I'm pretty positive this is how Shaq's career came about. My ramblings aside, Irons picks himself back up, grabs an old army buddy and Shaft (not kidding), makes himself the absolute worst looking superhero attire ever (it makes the Bat Nipples look like the Mona Lisa), dons himself Steel, and comes back to save the day, equipped with a huge sledgehammer (Triple H's inspiration), magnetic shield, and advice (once again, not kidding). The sheer stupidity that is Steel is unprecedented. Yes, I've seen worse COUGH*Batman & Robin*COUGH. But, that doesn't do justice for the man of Steel (and insults the true man of Steel, Superman, which this story is based off of a side character after the death of Superman). Steel is so bad, that I was actually yearning for Kazaam shortly into the movie. Do yourself a favor, and shoot yourself in the foot. It's a lot less painful.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Quite Possibly the Worst Movie Ever Made
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Michael Margetis (pmargetis@cox.net)
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/11/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Uncle Joe: Well dip me in sh__t and roll me in breadcrumbs. Without question, 'Steel' is in the running for worst film ever made. However, it is a fun movie to watch to make fun of. You'll be laughing hysterically, but not as the filmmakers intended. Shaquille O'Neal's acting skills are kind of like Adolf Hitler's morals. They're seriously lacking. This movie does have some classic one liners like "Y'all stay cool now." a line Shaq delivers to a couple of old people he returns a stolen purse to, and my personal favorite, "Well, dip me in sh__t and roll me in breadcrumbs!". I highly recommend 'Steel' if you need a good laugh. I think I laughed harder during this than I did during 'Borat'. Grade: F
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Jumbo-Sized Hero
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jonathon_naylor
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/11/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Let's get the worst facets of STEEL out of the way first. Yes, Shaquille O'Neal is a dreadful actor. Yes, he looks like the world's biggest sardine can in his Steel armor. Yes, the dialog is bargain basement. Yes, Judd Nelson makes for the worst comic book villain this side of Mark Hamill as The Trickster in THE FLASH television series. And yes, the film embarrasses itself even further by clumsily trying to deliver a we-must-stop-using-weapons-to-settle-our-differences message. Happy? STEEL is not a masterpiece in any sense of the word, but that doesn't mean it should be completely written off. It's one of those pictures that requires you to set aside your pre-conceived notions about good film-making and just enjoy the ride. Do that, and STEEL is a surprisingly amusing little adventure. O'Neal is fun, if not unspectacular, as our jumbo-sized hero, a do-gooder vigilante cleanin' up the streets with a big ol' hammer and souped-up motorbike. He's aided by wheelchair-bound hottie Annabeth Gish and an aged Richard Roundtree as his off-the-wall Uncle Joe. Our hero's climactic showdown with the one-dimensionally evil Nelson is incredibly cheesy, as are many scenes, but the film has its heart so firmly in the right place you'll be more than a little lenient. As usual, what Shaq lacks in talent he makes up for in charm and a deep likability that seeps right through the screen. STEEL is an uncomplicated film that seems custom-made for little boys, who will absolutely adore it. If you're in the right mood, you'll like it, too.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Poor action stuff that will only appeal to children and undemanding adults
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bob the moo
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/11/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    John Henry Irons is a weapons designer for the military who has been key in the development of a range of experimental weapons that immobilise enemy troops without any fatalities. However when Nat Burke tries to increase the power of the weapon during the test, the result sees a Senator dead and one of his colleagues disabled. The court martial sees Burke kicked out of the military and John decides his days of weapon design are over  returning to LA to work in a small steel mill. However when his weapons somehow make it into the hands of LA's criminal underworld, John decides that it is "on" and takes steps to counter the threat. Universally derided ever since it was even green lit for production, this film does have little to recommend it but still produces very basic distraction if that is what you want. The plot is obvious and goes just where you expect it to and it offers little for the discerning adult viewer (or to be honest the undemanding ones too). The action will please children but it is the wider delivery where it all falls down and, contrary to opinion, it is not all Shaq's fault. The script is clunky for the most part and has lots of injokes, most of which are embarrassing basketball references although, that said, the "Shaft" joke drew a laugh from me simply because it was so unexpected and so disrespectful to the film! This is very basic stuff though and nobody seems that interested in trying to make it more than that. Johnson is happy to deliver a kiddie-friendly superhero movie for the most part and this is all it seems to be. The cast have potential but too few of them have any decent material to work with. O'Neal can't act and that's the truth. He can play basketball and, given the riches this has given him we should not feel too sorry for him here. He says his lines and he stands where they tell him to stand but that is not the same as producing a character and being engaging  neither of which applies in this situation. Gish has little to do and Roundtree seems happy just to be a walking reference. Nelson hams it up in an obvious baddie while Harper, Hall and Ray J (!) are not the ones to address the lack of quality. The only person that I actually noted with interest was Kevin Grevioux, not because of his performance here but more because he is an interesting man who has built a small but varied career. Overall then this is a poor superhero movie but one that has had just about enough money spent on it to make it distract children and undemanding adults. The backlash against has been a bit overly cruel but it is still not any good with basic acting, basic script, basic plotting and action that only aspires to be colourful and noisy.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
 </reviews>
</filme>
