<filme>
 <id>
  270
 </id>
 <imdburl>
  http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0119177
 </imdburl>
 <ano>
  1997
 </ano>
 <titulo>
  Gattaca - Experi&ecirc;ncia Gen&eacute;tica
 </titulo>
 <rating>
  7.8
 </rating>
 <sinopse>
  A genetically inferior man assumes the identity of a superior one in order to pursue his lifelong dream of space travel.
 </sinopse>
 <storyline>
  In the not-too-distant future, a less-than-perfect man wants to travel to the stars. Society has categorized Vincent Freeman as less than suitable given his genetic make-up and he has become one of the underclass of humans that are only useful for menial jobs. To move ahead, he assumes the identity of Jerome Morrow, a perfect genetic specimen who is a paraplegic as a result of a car accident. With professional advice, Vincent learns to deceive DNA and urine sample testing. Just when he is finally scheduled for a space mission, his program director is killed and the police begin an investigation, jeopardizing his secret.
 </storyline>
 <generos>
  <genero>
   Drama
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Romance
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Sci-Fi
  </genero>
 </generos>
 <keywords>
  <keyword>
   dream
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   police
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   genetics
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   accident
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   space travel
  </keyword>
 </keywords>
 <diretores>
  <diretor>
   Andrew Niccol
  </diretor>
 </diretores>
 <escritores>
  <escritor>
   Andrew Niccol
  </escritor>
 </escritores>
 <atores>
  <ator>
   Ethan Hawke
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Uma Thurman
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Jude Law
  </ator>
 </atores>
 <reviews>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Great film, even with the ambiguity.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Peter Hill
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I love this film, I think its one of the most thought-provoking and stylish sci-fi films of the past few decades. Rather than just repeat all the praise/comments that previous reviewers have posted, I will get straight to what struck me about this film is the retro-feel of much of it's design. This film is set in an imaginary future yet the film is as much a homage to the styles and sheens of 1950s/60s sci-fi. The elites dress like the early Beatles, everyone seems to drive Cadillacs, the detectives wear film noir hats & overcoats, even the space rockets seem to have lifted straight from a 50s sci-fi comic. As well as a thought-provoking study on what it means to be human and how limitations are often imposed by others, the film seems to be a love-letter to both classic and B-grade sci-fi, from the shiny design of 'Logan's Run' to the cheesy, lovable awfulness of 'Mars Needs Women'. Having said that, this is one of my favourite films of the 1990s. Even the few baffling parts of the film don't bother me (like they bother a friend of mine who always complains about the final scenes where Ethan Hawke is boarding the space ship- 'he's still wearing his ordinary clothes, where's the space suit? And why hasn't he done any astronaut training? And why didn't he even bother to say goodbye to Uma Thurman?'), I like films that leave you wondering and thinking.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Going against the odds to achieve something
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    omasir02
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Gattaca a space-age (futuristic) city has a research center that specializes in aerospace research that embodies specific characteristics which allow people with perfection to be employed. Only those with perfect genes have access to better jobs. But children who carry natural genes, which are designed without the help of science, are known as natural or invalid inevitably are in turn rejected, isolated, and nevertheless pushed into poverty, with a prospective for a low job ranking. Parents have to define ways of helping their children in attaining an ideal life. This is where we meet Vincent (Ethan Hawke), supposedly a natural child with less perfect genes, with big dreams of one day going to space engages the help from Jerome Morrow (Jude Law) a paralyzed former swimming star. To beat all odds, both men enable one another the opportunity to achieve something desired and stump the laws that run Gattaca. In order for Vincent to thrive in Gattaca, Jerome provides him with his biological samples, hair, urine and blood that qualify Vincent in passing the DNA test requirement. Hence Vincent then enrolls the facade of being Jerome after undergoing psychological and physical changes. Then there is Irene Cassini (Uma Thurman) a charming young woman who in spite of her perfect design suffers from heart issues and seems to be falling for Vincent but at the same time is trying to find out who he really is. One other film that has the appropriateness to the theme is Elysium which shows the determination of certain individuals embattled to reach the space paradise habitat Elysium for state-of-the-art health-care and citizenship. The scene where as children and yet again as adults, Vincent and his brother Anton (Loren Dean) are competitively swimming seems to be the motif that shows determination can help in overcoming genetic shortcomings because Vincent sees his brother Anton and society rejecting him for his imperfections. There is a high angle shot for the swimming scenario because we are able to view Vincent and his brother from an aerial view. Overall the film is brilliant with cast displaying a composed mannerism while playing their parts in a way that goes to show that each is determined to achieve their desired goals by all means possible. The actors' performance is sterling because they make their characters to be believable. The theme shows that science can be manipulated to fit the interests of the protagonist.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Gattaca (or How To Succeed In A Corrupt Scociety
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    lagondapaolini-778-957250
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Imagine a society where corruption is so rampant that all the good careers are reserved for the elite and their offspring. Now imagine a making a perfect analogy for that problem in a movie. The result is Gattaca. The main character's problem is being considered 'Less Than Perfect' by his society, and thus unfit to lead the career of his choice, and which suits his skills, because such career is reserved for those who earned the right to it by birth. Those who were 'born lucky'. It could work as a great symbol of racism, but on deeper level it actually dissects all the aspects of a corrupt society where your career is determined by your family ties (genetic composition) and not at all by your skills. The main character did not only train himself to earn the skills needed for the career he wanted, but he also done the extra effort of designing a perfect lie. Which is how to win in life if you are not born a fortunate son :) Think about it. For delivering that message in such a and beautiful and touching manner, the movie, and everyone in its cast, deserves a big Kudos.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Gattaca
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    myystery-773-599626
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Gattaca is a beautiful film. It touches on themes of discrimination, prejudice, possible dangers of technological progress and the life of those who are left behind. The film's yellow tone accompanies the melancholic nature of the film. The ending of the film is very beautiful in the way that it allows the main character to escape from hostile earth and probably achieve a good life for himself somewhere else. It's plot seems a bit contrived and unoriginal, though. Another problem is that Uma Thurman's character never manages to become important. 8 stars.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Hit and miss for me.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Sergeant_Tibbs
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Gattaca had always been one of those cult favourites which I'd never seen but was always intrigued by. It has some great science fiction concepts, which can be expected from the writer of The Truman Show, here writing and directing, but Gattaca doesn't have the emotion that Truman was able to conjure. It's a highly engrossing film yet subtle, with rich set decoration, photography, score and a devotion to detail. I really enjoyed the simple goal of the protagonist, Vincent played by Ethan Hawke, and his simple desire to go to space. How he overcame the initial obstacle of his predicted fate was fascinating, but other obstacles were convoluted and not as engaging. However, I wasn't convinced by the scenes of him socialising with Uma Thurman or Jude Law's characters as it came off as awkward or not well developed. It didn't seem like the character had a way written in him to pull off those scenes. However, I loved the sci-fi ideas of how the future can be predicted through DNA. I've always wanted to see them explored in film. The first act was the best scene, with the prologue and then the growing up montage, although it's a shame that the film's climax returned to a homage to the montage which seemed really immature with a predictable twist. There's a great short film in here somewhere, with a bit too much excess to pad it out to a feature. 7/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    This fantastic movie humbled me a lot
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    lisaofshades
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Just watch it. As a kid I wanted to become a scientist specialized in genetics... I wanted to mess with the human DNA... create monsters, but also super humans... but that movie isn't about that... merely perfecting people to make them less likely to have diseases, violent impulses and have good looks, better endurance, intelligence... perfect for a normal human... This really appeals to me... I know deep down that it's evil and Hitler like... but I always believed it was for the best and a fantastic idea... Until I saw this movie. It showed someone who was born naturally... fight against his own discarded fate... to reach his dream. He turned out to be more resourceful and a better person than a killer whose DNA would have never been suspected... surpassing even the DNA of someone who was born with the utmost perfect fate, but with a tragic accident, saw it all go down in the garbage in an instant... It shows how that values such as passion, determination and resourcefulness are forgotten but shouldn't be... that we shouldn't just assume that someone has no future, no matter how unprivileged and even handicapped his start might be... the heart and will can have a tremendous weight in the balance... and that very power, which allowed the most humble to surpass the most gifted became more powerful by being trained by the very hardship and flaws that we thought made him inferior... That movie really made me think... and help me see that the people that we dismiss have tales to tell, values that we are clueless about, wisdom that we can't even suspect... all thanks to the hardship they went through... and that's what made them better people... not a ton of money. I was born with the greatest brain, I could have done anything... I thought that I could do anything alone, but it's meaningless if no one wants to believe and hire you... meaningless if you're too sick to even move... fate isn't everything... The music, the actors, everything was perfect in this movie. It's one of the few that actually showed me that some people are even more clever and wiser than me... I really respect the creators of this movie for being able to show me why my idea of perfection was wrong so brilliantly and in an entertaining manner; but don't expect explosions all over the place... it has a sort of nostalgic pace... I just plain love this movie. I feel a sorrowful fondness every time I see the name. Jude Law said this about it (see his biography): It was the first time I felt I was making a script I believed in, and that I'd see something on screen close to what I'd hoped, rather than this vaguely confusing wilderness my jobs had been to this point. It was my first project with quality minds behind it, Jersey Films, Andrew Niccol and Ethan Hawke, who was a joy to work with. I felt we had a real meeting of the minds. (On making Gattaca (1997)). Thank you for this movie. I want more of this.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A complex and heavy duty film.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    oscar-35
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    *Spoiler/plot- Gattaca, 1997. The future world is obsessed with good genes and genetic engineering of their offspring. The world has become a Gestapo-like in it's enforcement of social strata based on tightly enforced class matters. A young man finds a way to 'pass' as someone else and upsets the social establishment for his own goals. *Special Stars- Ethan Hawke, Uma Thurman, Jude Law, Alan Arkin, Ernest Borgine. *Theme- Being yourself instead of others is the best truth. *Trivia/location/goofs- Locations: Marin County Civic Center, Sepulveda Spillway. Look for the ripped shoulder jacket seam when the policeman gets attacked and then it magically repairs itself. *Emotion- A complex and heavy duty film plot tackling some major questions of our modern era. Interesting to see and understand the lesson that the director wanted the viewer to think about after seeing this film. This is an important film theme and could be more than more can handle, but worth seeing to open you own mind on these societal issues.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not my cup of tea
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Ken Potocki
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    So, in Honors Biology, my teacher announced we we're going to watch this movie. (Since we are in the DNA unit) Teacher said: "This movie was a flop at the box office"....already I was worried. What the movie basically plays off as, is a romance-drama slash murder mystery. I do not sense an entire lot of "sci-fi" within the movie. The movie opens with an un-needed 35 minute flashback/life story of our main character. To me, I like how they based the movie around his backstory, however, it was dragged out for too long. Other than that, when the murder-mystery subplot enters the movie, to me, it lags, and doesn't keep up a fast pace, and is pretty slow moving. At certain points, Uma Thurmann even seemed like a character just added for time, it could have done without random romance scenes between her and Ethan Hawke. Towards the end, the movie offers decent twists and turns with characters, Ernest Borgnine does a solid job as the mission director (Sadly, his screen time does not amount to a lot). Overall, I was expecting more of a science fiction movie, and basically what it is, is a romance/drama. Only go into this if you're a fan of romance and/or drama movies. Sci-fi is pretty lackluster here. 5/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Slow Paced but Deep and in Touch with the Human Spirit
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    kchang511
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    First of all, I would like to state that the musical score in this film was incredible and I still remember the musical motif to this day. I believe this movie was a great story about the strength of the human spirit and how it can more than fully augment deficiencies in genetics. I don't believe the stark portrait of the future depicted in this film will actually come true, as I don't have such pessimism about the humanity of humanity. But, I believe in certain group think circumstances, it might come true. Whatever the case, I think the movie gave a great portrayal of what it is like to be deemed genetically inferior. The main character's hard work and endurance to reach his dreams gave a universal meaning and message without coming off as too corny. Also, I didn't think his plight and efforts for greatness detracted anything from the message. Often movies try too hard at pushing their universal message that the story ends up being horrible and the message ends up being overly done. This movie can help inspire all to believe in hard work and dedication while showing that the spirit is the strongest thing a human can have. The only one flaw I felt in this movie was the swimming competition with his brother. After already beating him once, beating him again was useless. They should have saved him beating his brother for the second time, having him lose the first time in his youth. This would have made it more powerful. While the swimming part was a bit corny, I couldn't think of any better way it could have been done. Finally, I believe Jerome's suicide at the end really solidified the meaning of spirit. He has felt his chance at greatness passed and has lived on through the main character, thus completing his life.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    We now have discrimination down to a science.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    JohnRouseMerriottChard
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Gattaca is written and directed by Andrew Niccol. It stars Ethan Hawke, Uma Thurman, Jude Law, Gore Vidal, Loren Dean, Xander Berkeley and Alan Arkin. Music is by Michael Nyman and cinematography by Slawomir Idziak. It's the near future and eugenics dominate a society where children are either "valids" (reproductive through eugenics) or "in-valids" (naturally birthed with inherent genetic flaws). One such "in-valid" is Vincent Anton Freeman (Hawke), who plots an intricate scheme to assume a "valid" person's identification so as to reach his dreams of being an astronaut. There is no gene for fate. Biopunk future meets tech-noir in this thought provoking and intelligent piece of sci-fi. There is a decent argument to suggest that Gattaca is more style over character substance, especially given that visually Niccol's movie is stunning. It's a near future world of genetic engineering where although discrimination is illegal, perfection rules the day and the "in-valids" are passed over for high grade employment. Identity, inferiority and bigotry are fused together to offer up moral quandaries and ethical conundrums, all set to an oppressive tech-noir backdrop painted by Idziak's deft choice of colour filters. There's a striking difference between the look of the Gattaca corporation compared to the rest of the outside world, this helps to keep the thematics at work rich and potent. As a thriller it barely raises the pulse, but this is deliberate, as is the pacing by Niccol. This is an emotionally stunted world and the ethereal atmosphere hovers continually over proceedings. There's a romance in the mix between Hawke and Thurman, which on the surface seems a token sub-plot and devoid of passion, but again this feels deliberate, lack of passion is actually the order of the day. Cast performances are well up to scratch, with Law stealing the film as a one time "valid" ironically invalidated by an incident. And while we could have done with more from top performers Arkin (as a copper attired like a classical film noir gumshoe) and Elias Koteas (as Vincent's father), it rounds out as an impressively constructed picture. Provocative and brainy, with visual pleasures unbound, Gattaca has many attributes that reward still further on repeat viewings. 8/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Great film, even with the ambiguity.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Peter Hill
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I love this film, I think its one of the most thought-provoking and stylish sci-fi films of the past few decades. Rather than just repeat all the praise/comments that previous reviewers have posted, I will get straight to what struck me about this film is the retro-feel of much of it's design. This film is set in an imaginary future yet the film is as much a homage to the styles and sheens of 1950s/60s sci-fi. The elites dress like the early Beatles, everyone seems to drive Cadillacs, the detectives wear film noir hats & overcoats, even the space rockets seem to have lifted straight from a 50s sci-fi comic. As well as a thought-provoking study on what it means to be human and how limitations are often imposed by others, the film seems to be a love-letter to both classic and B-grade sci-fi, from the shiny design of 'Logan's Run' to the cheesy, lovable awfulness of 'Mars Needs Women'. Having said that, this is one of my favourite films of the 1990s. Even the few baffling parts of the film don't bother me (like they bother a friend of mine who always complains about the final scenes where Ethan Hawke is boarding the space ship- 'he's still wearing his ordinary clothes, where's the space suit? And why hasn't he done any astronaut training? And why didn't he even bother to say goodbye to Uma Thurman?'), I like films that leave you wondering and thinking.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Going against the odds to achieve something
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    omasir02
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Gattaca a space-age (futuristic) city has a research center that specializes in aerospace research that embodies specific characteristics which allow people with perfection to be employed. Only those with perfect genes have access to better jobs. But children who carry natural genes, which are designed without the help of science, are known as natural or invalid inevitably are in turn rejected, isolated, and nevertheless pushed into poverty, with a prospective for a low job ranking. Parents have to define ways of helping their children in attaining an ideal life. This is where we meet Vincent (Ethan Hawke), supposedly a natural child with less perfect genes, with big dreams of one day going to space engages the help from Jerome Morrow (Jude Law) a paralyzed former swimming star. To beat all odds, both men enable one another the opportunity to achieve something desired and stump the laws that run Gattaca. In order for Vincent to thrive in Gattaca, Jerome provides him with his biological samples, hair, urine and blood that qualify Vincent in passing the DNA test requirement. Hence Vincent then enrolls the facade of being Jerome after undergoing psychological and physical changes. Then there is Irene Cassini (Uma Thurman) a charming young woman who in spite of her perfect design suffers from heart issues and seems to be falling for Vincent but at the same time is trying to find out who he really is. One other film that has the appropriateness to the theme is Elysium which shows the determination of certain individuals embattled to reach the space paradise habitat Elysium for state-of-the-art health-care and citizenship. The scene where as children and yet again as adults, Vincent and his brother Anton (Loren Dean) are competitively swimming seems to be the motif that shows determination can help in overcoming genetic shortcomings because Vincent sees his brother Anton and society rejecting him for his imperfections. There is a high angle shot for the swimming scenario because we are able to view Vincent and his brother from an aerial view. Overall the film is brilliant with cast displaying a composed mannerism while playing their parts in a way that goes to show that each is determined to achieve their desired goals by all means possible. The actors' performance is sterling because they make their characters to be believable. The theme shows that science can be manipulated to fit the interests of the protagonist.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Gattaca (or How To Succeed In A Corrupt Scociety
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    lagondapaolini-778-957250
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Imagine a society where corruption is so rampant that all the good careers are reserved for the elite and their offspring. Now imagine a making a perfect analogy for that problem in a movie. The result is Gattaca. The main character's problem is being considered 'Less Than Perfect' by his society, and thus unfit to lead the career of his choice, and which suits his skills, because such career is reserved for those who earned the right to it by birth. Those who were 'born lucky'. It could work as a great symbol of racism, but on deeper level it actually dissects all the aspects of a corrupt society where your career is determined by your family ties (genetic composition) and not at all by your skills. The main character did not only train himself to earn the skills needed for the career he wanted, but he also done the extra effort of designing a perfect lie. Which is how to win in life if you are not born a fortunate son :) Think about it. For delivering that message in such a and beautiful and touching manner, the movie, and everyone in its cast, deserves a big Kudos.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Gattaca
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    myystery-773-599626
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Gattaca is a beautiful film. It touches on themes of discrimination, prejudice, possible dangers of technological progress and the life of those who are left behind. The film's yellow tone accompanies the melancholic nature of the film. The ending of the film is very beautiful in the way that it allows the main character to escape from hostile earth and probably achieve a good life for himself somewhere else. It's plot seems a bit contrived and unoriginal, though. Another problem is that Uma Thurman's character never manages to become important. 8 stars.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Hit and miss for me.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Sergeant_Tibbs
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Gattaca had always been one of those cult favourites which I'd never seen but was always intrigued by. It has some great science fiction concepts, which can be expected from the writer of The Truman Show, here writing and directing, but Gattaca doesn't have the emotion that Truman was able to conjure. It's a highly engrossing film yet subtle, with rich set decoration, photography, score and a devotion to detail. I really enjoyed the simple goal of the protagonist, Vincent played by Ethan Hawke, and his simple desire to go to space. How he overcame the initial obstacle of his predicted fate was fascinating, but other obstacles were convoluted and not as engaging. However, I wasn't convinced by the scenes of him socialising with Uma Thurman or Jude Law's characters as it came off as awkward or not well developed. It didn't seem like the character had a way written in him to pull off those scenes. However, I loved the sci-fi ideas of how the future can be predicted through DNA. I've always wanted to see them explored in film. The first act was the best scene, with the prologue and then the growing up montage, although it's a shame that the film's climax returned to a homage to the montage which seemed really immature with a predictable twist. There's a great short film in here somewhere, with a bit too much excess to pad it out to a feature. 7/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    This fantastic movie humbled me a lot
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    lisaofshades
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Just watch it. As a kid I wanted to become a scientist specialized in genetics... I wanted to mess with the human DNA... create monsters, but also super humans... but that movie isn't about that... merely perfecting people to make them less likely to have diseases, violent impulses and have good looks, better endurance, intelligence... perfect for a normal human... This really appeals to me... I know deep down that it's evil and Hitler like... but I always believed it was for the best and a fantastic idea... Until I saw this movie. It showed someone who was born naturally... fight against his own discarded fate... to reach his dream. He turned out to be more resourceful and a better person than a killer whose DNA would have never been suspected... surpassing even the DNA of someone who was born with the utmost perfect fate, but with a tragic accident, saw it all go down in the garbage in an instant... It shows how that values such as passion, determination and resourcefulness are forgotten but shouldn't be... that we shouldn't just assume that someone has no future, no matter how unprivileged and even handicapped his start might be... the heart and will can have a tremendous weight in the balance... and that very power, which allowed the most humble to surpass the most gifted became more powerful by being trained by the very hardship and flaws that we thought made him inferior... That movie really made me think... and help me see that the people that we dismiss have tales to tell, values that we are clueless about, wisdom that we can't even suspect... all thanks to the hardship they went through... and that's what made them better people... not a ton of money. I was born with the greatest brain, I could have done anything... I thought that I could do anything alone, but it's meaningless if no one wants to believe and hire you... meaningless if you're too sick to even move... fate isn't everything... The music, the actors, everything was perfect in this movie. It's one of the few that actually showed me that some people are even more clever and wiser than me... I really respect the creators of this movie for being able to show me why my idea of perfection was wrong so brilliantly and in an entertaining manner; but don't expect explosions all over the place... it has a sort of nostalgic pace... I just plain love this movie. I feel a sorrowful fondness every time I see the name. Jude Law said this about it (see his biography): It was the first time I felt I was making a script I believed in, and that I'd see something on screen close to what I'd hoped, rather than this vaguely confusing wilderness my jobs had been to this point. It was my first project with quality minds behind it, Jersey Films, Andrew Niccol and Ethan Hawke, who was a joy to work with. I felt we had a real meeting of the minds. (On making Gattaca (1997)). Thank you for this movie. I want more of this.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A complex and heavy duty film.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    oscar-35
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    *Spoiler/plot- Gattaca, 1997. The future world is obsessed with good genes and genetic engineering of their offspring. The world has become a Gestapo-like in it's enforcement of social strata based on tightly enforced class matters. A young man finds a way to 'pass' as someone else and upsets the social establishment for his own goals. *Special Stars- Ethan Hawke, Uma Thurman, Jude Law, Alan Arkin, Ernest Borgine. *Theme- Being yourself instead of others is the best truth. *Trivia/location/goofs- Locations: Marin County Civic Center, Sepulveda Spillway. Look for the ripped shoulder jacket seam when the policeman gets attacked and then it magically repairs itself. *Emotion- A complex and heavy duty film plot tackling some major questions of our modern era. Interesting to see and understand the lesson that the director wanted the viewer to think about after seeing this film. This is an important film theme and could be more than more can handle, but worth seeing to open you own mind on these societal issues.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not my cup of tea
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Ken Potocki
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    So, in Honors Biology, my teacher announced we we're going to watch this movie. (Since we are in the DNA unit) Teacher said: "This movie was a flop at the box office"....already I was worried. What the movie basically plays off as, is a romance-drama slash murder mystery. I do not sense an entire lot of "sci-fi" within the movie. The movie opens with an un-needed 35 minute flashback/life story of our main character. To me, I like how they based the movie around his backstory, however, it was dragged out for too long. Other than that, when the murder-mystery subplot enters the movie, to me, it lags, and doesn't keep up a fast pace, and is pretty slow moving. At certain points, Uma Thurmann even seemed like a character just added for time, it could have done without random romance scenes between her and Ethan Hawke. Towards the end, the movie offers decent twists and turns with characters, Ernest Borgnine does a solid job as the mission director (Sadly, his screen time does not amount to a lot). Overall, I was expecting more of a science fiction movie, and basically what it is, is a romance/drama. Only go into this if you're a fan of romance and/or drama movies. Sci-fi is pretty lackluster here. 5/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Slow Paced but Deep and in Touch with the Human Spirit
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    kchang511
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    First of all, I would like to state that the musical score in this film was incredible and I still remember the musical motif to this day. I believe this movie was a great story about the strength of the human spirit and how it can more than fully augment deficiencies in genetics. I don't believe the stark portrait of the future depicted in this film will actually come true, as I don't have such pessimism about the humanity of humanity. But, I believe in certain group think circumstances, it might come true. Whatever the case, I think the movie gave a great portrayal of what it is like to be deemed genetically inferior. The main character's hard work and endurance to reach his dreams gave a universal meaning and message without coming off as too corny. Also, I didn't think his plight and efforts for greatness detracted anything from the message. Often movies try too hard at pushing their universal message that the story ends up being horrible and the message ends up being overly done. This movie can help inspire all to believe in hard work and dedication while showing that the spirit is the strongest thing a human can have. The only one flaw I felt in this movie was the swimming competition with his brother. After already beating him once, beating him again was useless. They should have saved him beating his brother for the second time, having him lose the first time in his youth. This would have made it more powerful. While the swimming part was a bit corny, I couldn't think of any better way it could have been done. Finally, I believe Jerome's suicide at the end really solidified the meaning of spirit. He has felt his chance at greatness passed and has lived on through the main character, thus completing his life.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    We now have discrimination down to a science.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    JohnRouseMerriottChard
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Gattaca is written and directed by Andrew Niccol. It stars Ethan Hawke, Uma Thurman, Jude Law, Gore Vidal, Loren Dean, Xander Berkeley and Alan Arkin. Music is by Michael Nyman and cinematography by Slawomir Idziak. It's the near future and eugenics dominate a society where children are either "valids" (reproductive through eugenics) or "in-valids" (naturally birthed with inherent genetic flaws). One such "in-valid" is Vincent Anton Freeman (Hawke), who plots an intricate scheme to assume a "valid" person's identification so as to reach his dreams of being an astronaut. There is no gene for fate. Biopunk future meets tech-noir in this thought provoking and intelligent piece of sci-fi. There is a decent argument to suggest that Gattaca is more style over character substance, especially given that visually Niccol's movie is stunning. It's a near future world of genetic engineering where although discrimination is illegal, perfection rules the day and the "in-valids" are passed over for high grade employment. Identity, inferiority and bigotry are fused together to offer up moral quandaries and ethical conundrums, all set to an oppressive tech-noir backdrop painted by Idziak's deft choice of colour filters. There's a striking difference between the look of the Gattaca corporation compared to the rest of the outside world, this helps to keep the thematics at work rich and potent. As a thriller it barely raises the pulse, but this is deliberate, as is the pacing by Niccol. This is an emotionally stunted world and the ethereal atmosphere hovers continually over proceedings. There's a romance in the mix between Hawke and Thurman, which on the surface seems a token sub-plot and devoid of passion, but again this feels deliberate, lack of passion is actually the order of the day. Cast performances are well up to scratch, with Law stealing the film as a one time "valid" ironically invalidated by an incident. And while we could have done with more from top performers Arkin (as a copper attired like a classical film noir gumshoe) and Elias Koteas (as Vincent's father), it rounds out as an impressively constructed picture. Provocative and brainy, with visual pleasures unbound, Gattaca has many attributes that reward still further on repeat viewings. 8/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Great film, even with the ambiguity.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Peter Hill
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I love this film, I think its one of the most thought-provoking and stylish sci-fi films of the past few decades. Rather than just repeat all the praise/comments that previous reviewers have posted, I will get straight to what struck me about this film is the retro-feel of much of it's design. This film is set in an imaginary future yet the film is as much a homage to the styles and sheens of 1950s/60s sci-fi. The elites dress like the early Beatles, everyone seems to drive Cadillacs, the detectives wear film noir hats & overcoats, even the space rockets seem to have lifted straight from a 50s sci-fi comic. As well as a thought-provoking study on what it means to be human and how limitations are often imposed by others, the film seems to be a love-letter to both classic and B-grade sci-fi, from the shiny design of 'Logan's Run' to the cheesy, lovable awfulness of 'Mars Needs Women'. Having said that, this is one of my favourite films of the 1990s. Even the few baffling parts of the film don't bother me (like they bother a friend of mine who always complains about the final scenes where Ethan Hawke is boarding the space ship- 'he's still wearing his ordinary clothes, where's the space suit? And why hasn't he done any astronaut training? And why didn't he even bother to say goodbye to Uma Thurman?'), I like films that leave you wondering and thinking.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Going against the odds to achieve something
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    omasir02
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Gattaca a space-age (futuristic) city has a research center that specializes in aerospace research that embodies specific characteristics which allow people with perfection to be employed. Only those with perfect genes have access to better jobs. But children who carry natural genes, which are designed without the help of science, are known as natural or invalid inevitably are in turn rejected, isolated, and nevertheless pushed into poverty, with a prospective for a low job ranking. Parents have to define ways of helping their children in attaining an ideal life. This is where we meet Vincent (Ethan Hawke), supposedly a natural child with less perfect genes, with big dreams of one day going to space engages the help from Jerome Morrow (Jude Law) a paralyzed former swimming star. To beat all odds, both men enable one another the opportunity to achieve something desired and stump the laws that run Gattaca. In order for Vincent to thrive in Gattaca, Jerome provides him with his biological samples, hair, urine and blood that qualify Vincent in passing the DNA test requirement. Hence Vincent then enrolls the facade of being Jerome after undergoing psychological and physical changes. Then there is Irene Cassini (Uma Thurman) a charming young woman who in spite of her perfect design suffers from heart issues and seems to be falling for Vincent but at the same time is trying to find out who he really is. One other film that has the appropriateness to the theme is Elysium which shows the determination of certain individuals embattled to reach the space paradise habitat Elysium for state-of-the-art health-care and citizenship. The scene where as children and yet again as adults, Vincent and his brother Anton (Loren Dean) are competitively swimming seems to be the motif that shows determination can help in overcoming genetic shortcomings because Vincent sees his brother Anton and society rejecting him for his imperfections. There is a high angle shot for the swimming scenario because we are able to view Vincent and his brother from an aerial view. Overall the film is brilliant with cast displaying a composed mannerism while playing their parts in a way that goes to show that each is determined to achieve their desired goals by all means possible. The actors' performance is sterling because they make their characters to be believable. The theme shows that science can be manipulated to fit the interests of the protagonist.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Gattaca (or How To Succeed In A Corrupt Scociety
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    lagondapaolini-778-957250
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Imagine a society where corruption is so rampant that all the good careers are reserved for the elite and their offspring. Now imagine a making a perfect analogy for that problem in a movie. The result is Gattaca. The main character's problem is being considered 'Less Than Perfect' by his society, and thus unfit to lead the career of his choice, and which suits his skills, because such career is reserved for those who earned the right to it by birth. Those who were 'born lucky'. It could work as a great symbol of racism, but on deeper level it actually dissects all the aspects of a corrupt society where your career is determined by your family ties (genetic composition) and not at all by your skills. The main character did not only train himself to earn the skills needed for the career he wanted, but he also done the extra effort of designing a perfect lie. Which is how to win in life if you are not born a fortunate son :) Think about it. For delivering that message in such a and beautiful and touching manner, the movie, and everyone in its cast, deserves a big Kudos.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Gattaca
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    myystery-773-599626
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Gattaca is a beautiful film. It touches on themes of discrimination, prejudice, possible dangers of technological progress and the life of those who are left behind. The film's yellow tone accompanies the melancholic nature of the film. The ending of the film is very beautiful in the way that it allows the main character to escape from hostile earth and probably achieve a good life for himself somewhere else. It's plot seems a bit contrived and unoriginal, though. Another problem is that Uma Thurman's character never manages to become important. 8 stars.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Hit and miss for me.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Sergeant_Tibbs
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Gattaca had always been one of those cult favourites which I'd never seen but was always intrigued by. It has some great science fiction concepts, which can be expected from the writer of The Truman Show, here writing and directing, but Gattaca doesn't have the emotion that Truman was able to conjure. It's a highly engrossing film yet subtle, with rich set decoration, photography, score and a devotion to detail. I really enjoyed the simple goal of the protagonist, Vincent played by Ethan Hawke, and his simple desire to go to space. How he overcame the initial obstacle of his predicted fate was fascinating, but other obstacles were convoluted and not as engaging. However, I wasn't convinced by the scenes of him socialising with Uma Thurman or Jude Law's characters as it came off as awkward or not well developed. It didn't seem like the character had a way written in him to pull off those scenes. However, I loved the sci-fi ideas of how the future can be predicted through DNA. I've always wanted to see them explored in film. The first act was the best scene, with the prologue and then the growing up montage, although it's a shame that the film's climax returned to a homage to the montage which seemed really immature with a predictable twist. There's a great short film in here somewhere, with a bit too much excess to pad it out to a feature. 7/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    This fantastic movie humbled me a lot
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    lisaofshades
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Just watch it. As a kid I wanted to become a scientist specialized in genetics... I wanted to mess with the human DNA... create monsters, but also super humans... but that movie isn't about that... merely perfecting people to make them less likely to have diseases, violent impulses and have good looks, better endurance, intelligence... perfect for a normal human... This really appeals to me... I know deep down that it's evil and Hitler like... but I always believed it was for the best and a fantastic idea... Until I saw this movie. It showed someone who was born naturally... fight against his own discarded fate... to reach his dream. He turned out to be more resourceful and a better person than a killer whose DNA would have never been suspected... surpassing even the DNA of someone who was born with the utmost perfect fate, but with a tragic accident, saw it all go down in the garbage in an instant... It shows how that values such as passion, determination and resourcefulness are forgotten but shouldn't be... that we shouldn't just assume that someone has no future, no matter how unprivileged and even handicapped his start might be... the heart and will can have a tremendous weight in the balance... and that very power, which allowed the most humble to surpass the most gifted became more powerful by being trained by the very hardship and flaws that we thought made him inferior... That movie really made me think... and help me see that the people that we dismiss have tales to tell, values that we are clueless about, wisdom that we can't even suspect... all thanks to the hardship they went through... and that's what made them better people... not a ton of money. I was born with the greatest brain, I could have done anything... I thought that I could do anything alone, but it's meaningless if no one wants to believe and hire you... meaningless if you're too sick to even move... fate isn't everything... The music, the actors, everything was perfect in this movie. It's one of the few that actually showed me that some people are even more clever and wiser than me... I really respect the creators of this movie for being able to show me why my idea of perfection was wrong so brilliantly and in an entertaining manner; but don't expect explosions all over the place... it has a sort of nostalgic pace... I just plain love this movie. I feel a sorrowful fondness every time I see the name. Jude Law said this about it (see his biography): It was the first time I felt I was making a script I believed in, and that I'd see something on screen close to what I'd hoped, rather than this vaguely confusing wilderness my jobs had been to this point. It was my first project with quality minds behind it, Jersey Films, Andrew Niccol and Ethan Hawke, who was a joy to work with. I felt we had a real meeting of the minds. (On making Gattaca (1997)). Thank you for this movie. I want more of this.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A complex and heavy duty film.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    oscar-35
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    *Spoiler/plot- Gattaca, 1997. The future world is obsessed with good genes and genetic engineering of their offspring. The world has become a Gestapo-like in it's enforcement of social strata based on tightly enforced class matters. A young man finds a way to 'pass' as someone else and upsets the social establishment for his own goals. *Special Stars- Ethan Hawke, Uma Thurman, Jude Law, Alan Arkin, Ernest Borgine. *Theme- Being yourself instead of others is the best truth. *Trivia/location/goofs- Locations: Marin County Civic Center, Sepulveda Spillway. Look for the ripped shoulder jacket seam when the policeman gets attacked and then it magically repairs itself. *Emotion- A complex and heavy duty film plot tackling some major questions of our modern era. Interesting to see and understand the lesson that the director wanted the viewer to think about after seeing this film. This is an important film theme and could be more than more can handle, but worth seeing to open you own mind on these societal issues.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not my cup of tea
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Ken Potocki
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    So, in Honors Biology, my teacher announced we we're going to watch this movie. (Since we are in the DNA unit) Teacher said: "This movie was a flop at the box office"....already I was worried. What the movie basically plays off as, is a romance-drama slash murder mystery. I do not sense an entire lot of "sci-fi" within the movie. The movie opens with an un-needed 35 minute flashback/life story of our main character. To me, I like how they based the movie around his backstory, however, it was dragged out for too long. Other than that, when the murder-mystery subplot enters the movie, to me, it lags, and doesn't keep up a fast pace, and is pretty slow moving. At certain points, Uma Thurmann even seemed like a character just added for time, it could have done without random romance scenes between her and Ethan Hawke. Towards the end, the movie offers decent twists and turns with characters, Ernest Borgnine does a solid job as the mission director (Sadly, his screen time does not amount to a lot). Overall, I was expecting more of a science fiction movie, and basically what it is, is a romance/drama. Only go into this if you're a fan of romance and/or drama movies. Sci-fi is pretty lackluster here. 5/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Slow Paced but Deep and in Touch with the Human Spirit
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    kchang511
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    First of all, I would like to state that the musical score in this film was incredible and I still remember the musical motif to this day. I believe this movie was a great story about the strength of the human spirit and how it can more than fully augment deficiencies in genetics. I don't believe the stark portrait of the future depicted in this film will actually come true, as I don't have such pessimism about the humanity of humanity. But, I believe in certain group think circumstances, it might come true. Whatever the case, I think the movie gave a great portrayal of what it is like to be deemed genetically inferior. The main character's hard work and endurance to reach his dreams gave a universal meaning and message without coming off as too corny. Also, I didn't think his plight and efforts for greatness detracted anything from the message. Often movies try too hard at pushing their universal message that the story ends up being horrible and the message ends up being overly done. This movie can help inspire all to believe in hard work and dedication while showing that the spirit is the strongest thing a human can have. The only one flaw I felt in this movie was the swimming competition with his brother. After already beating him once, beating him again was useless. They should have saved him beating his brother for the second time, having him lose the first time in his youth. This would have made it more powerful. While the swimming part was a bit corny, I couldn't think of any better way it could have been done. Finally, I believe Jerome's suicide at the end really solidified the meaning of spirit. He has felt his chance at greatness passed and has lived on through the main character, thus completing his life.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    We now have discrimination down to a science.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    JohnRouseMerriottChard
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Gattaca is written and directed by Andrew Niccol. It stars Ethan Hawke, Uma Thurman, Jude Law, Gore Vidal, Loren Dean, Xander Berkeley and Alan Arkin. Music is by Michael Nyman and cinematography by Slawomir Idziak. It's the near future and eugenics dominate a society where children are either "valids" (reproductive through eugenics) or "in-valids" (naturally birthed with inherent genetic flaws). One such "in-valid" is Vincent Anton Freeman (Hawke), who plots an intricate scheme to assume a "valid" person's identification so as to reach his dreams of being an astronaut. There is no gene for fate. Biopunk future meets tech-noir in this thought provoking and intelligent piece of sci-fi. There is a decent argument to suggest that Gattaca is more style over character substance, especially given that visually Niccol's movie is stunning. It's a near future world of genetic engineering where although discrimination is illegal, perfection rules the day and the "in-valids" are passed over for high grade employment. Identity, inferiority and bigotry are fused together to offer up moral quandaries and ethical conundrums, all set to an oppressive tech-noir backdrop painted by Idziak's deft choice of colour filters. There's a striking difference between the look of the Gattaca corporation compared to the rest of the outside world, this helps to keep the thematics at work rich and potent. As a thriller it barely raises the pulse, but this is deliberate, as is the pacing by Niccol. This is an emotionally stunted world and the ethereal atmosphere hovers continually over proceedings. There's a romance in the mix between Hawke and Thurman, which on the surface seems a token sub-plot and devoid of passion, but again this feels deliberate, lack of passion is actually the order of the day. Cast performances are well up to scratch, with Law stealing the film as a one time "valid" ironically invalidated by an incident. And while we could have done with more from top performers Arkin (as a copper attired like a classical film noir gumshoe) and Elias Koteas (as Vincent's father), it rounds out as an impressively constructed picture. Provocative and brainy, with visual pleasures unbound, Gattaca has many attributes that reward still further on repeat viewings. 8/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Great film, even with the ambiguity.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Peter Hill
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I love this film, I think its one of the most thought-provoking and stylish sci-fi films of the past few decades. Rather than just repeat all the praise/comments that previous reviewers have posted, I will get straight to what struck me about this film is the retro-feel of much of it's design. This film is set in an imaginary future yet the film is as much a homage to the styles and sheens of 1950s/60s sci-fi. The elites dress like the early Beatles, everyone seems to drive Cadillacs, the detectives wear film noir hats & overcoats, even the space rockets seem to have lifted straight from a 50s sci-fi comic. As well as a thought-provoking study on what it means to be human and how limitations are often imposed by others, the film seems to be a love-letter to both classic and B-grade sci-fi, from the shiny design of 'Logan's Run' to the cheesy, lovable awfulness of 'Mars Needs Women'. Having said that, this is one of my favourite films of the 1990s. Even the few baffling parts of the film don't bother me (like they bother a friend of mine who always complains about the final scenes where Ethan Hawke is boarding the space ship- 'he's still wearing his ordinary clothes, where's the space suit? And why hasn't he done any astronaut training? And why didn't he even bother to say goodbye to Uma Thurman?'), I like films that leave you wondering and thinking.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Going against the odds to achieve something
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    omasir02
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Gattaca a space-age (futuristic) city has a research center that specializes in aerospace research that embodies specific characteristics which allow people with perfection to be employed. Only those with perfect genes have access to better jobs. But children who carry natural genes, which are designed without the help of science, are known as natural or invalid inevitably are in turn rejected, isolated, and nevertheless pushed into poverty, with a prospective for a low job ranking. Parents have to define ways of helping their children in attaining an ideal life. This is where we meet Vincent (Ethan Hawke), supposedly a natural child with less perfect genes, with big dreams of one day going to space engages the help from Jerome Morrow (Jude Law) a paralyzed former swimming star. To beat all odds, both men enable one another the opportunity to achieve something desired and stump the laws that run Gattaca. In order for Vincent to thrive in Gattaca, Jerome provides him with his biological samples, hair, urine and blood that qualify Vincent in passing the DNA test requirement. Hence Vincent then enrolls the facade of being Jerome after undergoing psychological and physical changes. Then there is Irene Cassini (Uma Thurman) a charming young woman who in spite of her perfect design suffers from heart issues and seems to be falling for Vincent but at the same time is trying to find out who he really is. One other film that has the appropriateness to the theme is Elysium which shows the determination of certain individuals embattled to reach the space paradise habitat Elysium for state-of-the-art health-care and citizenship. The scene where as children and yet again as adults, Vincent and his brother Anton (Loren Dean) are competitively swimming seems to be the motif that shows determination can help in overcoming genetic shortcomings because Vincent sees his brother Anton and society rejecting him for his imperfections. There is a high angle shot for the swimming scenario because we are able to view Vincent and his brother from an aerial view. Overall the film is brilliant with cast displaying a composed mannerism while playing their parts in a way that goes to show that each is determined to achieve their desired goals by all means possible. The actors' performance is sterling because they make their characters to be believable. The theme shows that science can be manipulated to fit the interests of the protagonist.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Gattaca (or How To Succeed In A Corrupt Scociety
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    lagondapaolini-778-957250
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Imagine a society where corruption is so rampant that all the good careers are reserved for the elite and their offspring. Now imagine a making a perfect analogy for that problem in a movie. The result is Gattaca. The main character's problem is being considered 'Less Than Perfect' by his society, and thus unfit to lead the career of his choice, and which suits his skills, because such career is reserved for those who earned the right to it by birth. Those who were 'born lucky'. It could work as a great symbol of racism, but on deeper level it actually dissects all the aspects of a corrupt society where your career is determined by your family ties (genetic composition) and not at all by your skills. The main character did not only train himself to earn the skills needed for the career he wanted, but he also done the extra effort of designing a perfect lie. Which is how to win in life if you are not born a fortunate son :) Think about it. For delivering that message in such a and beautiful and touching manner, the movie, and everyone in its cast, deserves a big Kudos.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Gattaca
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    myystery-773-599626
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Gattaca is a beautiful film. It touches on themes of discrimination, prejudice, possible dangers of technological progress and the life of those who are left behind. The film's yellow tone accompanies the melancholic nature of the film. The ending of the film is very beautiful in the way that it allows the main character to escape from hostile earth and probably achieve a good life for himself somewhere else. It's plot seems a bit contrived and unoriginal, though. Another problem is that Uma Thurman's character never manages to become important. 8 stars.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Hit and miss for me.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Sergeant_Tibbs
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Gattaca had always been one of those cult favourites which I'd never seen but was always intrigued by. It has some great science fiction concepts, which can be expected from the writer of The Truman Show, here writing and directing, but Gattaca doesn't have the emotion that Truman was able to conjure. It's a highly engrossing film yet subtle, with rich set decoration, photography, score and a devotion to detail. I really enjoyed the simple goal of the protagonist, Vincent played by Ethan Hawke, and his simple desire to go to space. How he overcame the initial obstacle of his predicted fate was fascinating, but other obstacles were convoluted and not as engaging. However, I wasn't convinced by the scenes of him socialising with Uma Thurman or Jude Law's characters as it came off as awkward or not well developed. It didn't seem like the character had a way written in him to pull off those scenes. However, I loved the sci-fi ideas of how the future can be predicted through DNA. I've always wanted to see them explored in film. The first act was the best scene, with the prologue and then the growing up montage, although it's a shame that the film's climax returned to a homage to the montage which seemed really immature with a predictable twist. There's a great short film in here somewhere, with a bit too much excess to pad it out to a feature. 7/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    This fantastic movie humbled me a lot
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    lisaofshades
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Just watch it. As a kid I wanted to become a scientist specialized in genetics... I wanted to mess with the human DNA... create monsters, but also super humans... but that movie isn't about that... merely perfecting people to make them less likely to have diseases, violent impulses and have good looks, better endurance, intelligence... perfect for a normal human... This really appeals to me... I know deep down that it's evil and Hitler like... but I always believed it was for the best and a fantastic idea... Until I saw this movie. It showed someone who was born naturally... fight against his own discarded fate... to reach his dream. He turned out to be more resourceful and a better person than a killer whose DNA would have never been suspected... surpassing even the DNA of someone who was born with the utmost perfect fate, but with a tragic accident, saw it all go down in the garbage in an instant... It shows how that values such as passion, determination and resourcefulness are forgotten but shouldn't be... that we shouldn't just assume that someone has no future, no matter how unprivileged and even handicapped his start might be... the heart and will can have a tremendous weight in the balance... and that very power, which allowed the most humble to surpass the most gifted became more powerful by being trained by the very hardship and flaws that we thought made him inferior... That movie really made me think... and help me see that the people that we dismiss have tales to tell, values that we are clueless about, wisdom that we can't even suspect... all thanks to the hardship they went through... and that's what made them better people... not a ton of money. I was born with the greatest brain, I could have done anything... I thought that I could do anything alone, but it's meaningless if no one wants to believe and hire you... meaningless if you're too sick to even move... fate isn't everything... The music, the actors, everything was perfect in this movie. It's one of the few that actually showed me that some people are even more clever and wiser than me... I really respect the creators of this movie for being able to show me why my idea of perfection was wrong so brilliantly and in an entertaining manner; but don't expect explosions all over the place... it has a sort of nostalgic pace... I just plain love this movie. I feel a sorrowful fondness every time I see the name. Jude Law said this about it (see his biography): It was the first time I felt I was making a script I believed in, and that I'd see something on screen close to what I'd hoped, rather than this vaguely confusing wilderness my jobs had been to this point. It was my first project with quality minds behind it, Jersey Films, Andrew Niccol and Ethan Hawke, who was a joy to work with. I felt we had a real meeting of the minds. (On making Gattaca (1997)). Thank you for this movie. I want more of this.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A complex and heavy duty film.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    oscar-35
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    *Spoiler/plot- Gattaca, 1997. The future world is obsessed with good genes and genetic engineering of their offspring. The world has become a Gestapo-like in it's enforcement of social strata based on tightly enforced class matters. A young man finds a way to 'pass' as someone else and upsets the social establishment for his own goals. *Special Stars- Ethan Hawke, Uma Thurman, Jude Law, Alan Arkin, Ernest Borgine. *Theme- Being yourself instead of others is the best truth. *Trivia/location/goofs- Locations: Marin County Civic Center, Sepulveda Spillway. Look for the ripped shoulder jacket seam when the policeman gets attacked and then it magically repairs itself. *Emotion- A complex and heavy duty film plot tackling some major questions of our modern era. Interesting to see and understand the lesson that the director wanted the viewer to think about after seeing this film. This is an important film theme and could be more than more can handle, but worth seeing to open you own mind on these societal issues.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not my cup of tea
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Ken Potocki
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    So, in Honors Biology, my teacher announced we we're going to watch this movie. (Since we are in the DNA unit) Teacher said: "This movie was a flop at the box office"....already I was worried. What the movie basically plays off as, is a romance-drama slash murder mystery. I do not sense an entire lot of "sci-fi" within the movie. The movie opens with an un-needed 35 minute flashback/life story of our main character. To me, I like how they based the movie around his backstory, however, it was dragged out for too long. Other than that, when the murder-mystery subplot enters the movie, to me, it lags, and doesn't keep up a fast pace, and is pretty slow moving. At certain points, Uma Thurmann even seemed like a character just added for time, it could have done without random romance scenes between her and Ethan Hawke. Towards the end, the movie offers decent twists and turns with characters, Ernest Borgnine does a solid job as the mission director (Sadly, his screen time does not amount to a lot). Overall, I was expecting more of a science fiction movie, and basically what it is, is a romance/drama. Only go into this if you're a fan of romance and/or drama movies. Sci-fi is pretty lackluster here. 5/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Slow Paced but Deep and in Touch with the Human Spirit
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    kchang511
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    First of all, I would like to state that the musical score in this film was incredible and I still remember the musical motif to this day. I believe this movie was a great story about the strength of the human spirit and how it can more than fully augment deficiencies in genetics. I don't believe the stark portrait of the future depicted in this film will actually come true, as I don't have such pessimism about the humanity of humanity. But, I believe in certain group think circumstances, it might come true. Whatever the case, I think the movie gave a great portrayal of what it is like to be deemed genetically inferior. The main character's hard work and endurance to reach his dreams gave a universal meaning and message without coming off as too corny. Also, I didn't think his plight and efforts for greatness detracted anything from the message. Often movies try too hard at pushing their universal message that the story ends up being horrible and the message ends up being overly done. This movie can help inspire all to believe in hard work and dedication while showing that the spirit is the strongest thing a human can have. The only one flaw I felt in this movie was the swimming competition with his brother. After already beating him once, beating him again was useless. They should have saved him beating his brother for the second time, having him lose the first time in his youth. This would have made it more powerful. While the swimming part was a bit corny, I couldn't think of any better way it could have been done. Finally, I believe Jerome's suicide at the end really solidified the meaning of spirit. He has felt his chance at greatness passed and has lived on through the main character, thus completing his life.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    We now have discrimination down to a science.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    JohnRouseMerriottChard
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Gattaca is written and directed by Andrew Niccol. It stars Ethan Hawke, Uma Thurman, Jude Law, Gore Vidal, Loren Dean, Xander Berkeley and Alan Arkin. Music is by Michael Nyman and cinematography by Slawomir Idziak. It's the near future and eugenics dominate a society where children are either "valids" (reproductive through eugenics) or "in-valids" (naturally birthed with inherent genetic flaws). One such "in-valid" is Vincent Anton Freeman (Hawke), who plots an intricate scheme to assume a "valid" person's identification so as to reach his dreams of being an astronaut. There is no gene for fate. Biopunk future meets tech-noir in this thought provoking and intelligent piece of sci-fi. There is a decent argument to suggest that Gattaca is more style over character substance, especially given that visually Niccol's movie is stunning. It's a near future world of genetic engineering where although discrimination is illegal, perfection rules the day and the "in-valids" are passed over for high grade employment. Identity, inferiority and bigotry are fused together to offer up moral quandaries and ethical conundrums, all set to an oppressive tech-noir backdrop painted by Idziak's deft choice of colour filters. There's a striking difference between the look of the Gattaca corporation compared to the rest of the outside world, this helps to keep the thematics at work rich and potent. As a thriller it barely raises the pulse, but this is deliberate, as is the pacing by Niccol. This is an emotionally stunted world and the ethereal atmosphere hovers continually over proceedings. There's a romance in the mix between Hawke and Thurman, which on the surface seems a token sub-plot and devoid of passion, but again this feels deliberate, lack of passion is actually the order of the day. Cast performances are well up to scratch, with Law stealing the film as a one time "valid" ironically invalidated by an incident. And while we could have done with more from top performers Arkin (as a copper attired like a classical film noir gumshoe) and Elias Koteas (as Vincent's father), it rounds out as an impressively constructed picture. Provocative and brainy, with visual pleasures unbound, Gattaca has many attributes that reward still further on repeat viewings. 8/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Great film, even with the ambiguity.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Peter Hill
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I love this film, I think its one of the most thought-provoking and stylish sci-fi films of the past few decades. Rather than just repeat all the praise/comments that previous reviewers have posted, I will get straight to what struck me about this film is the retro-feel of much of it's design. This film is set in an imaginary future yet the film is as much a homage to the styles and sheens of 1950s/60s sci-fi. The elites dress like the early Beatles, everyone seems to drive Cadillacs, the detectives wear film noir hats & overcoats, even the space rockets seem to have lifted straight from a 50s sci-fi comic. As well as a thought-provoking study on what it means to be human and how limitations are often imposed by others, the film seems to be a love-letter to both classic and B-grade sci-fi, from the shiny design of 'Logan's Run' to the cheesy, lovable awfulness of 'Mars Needs Women'. Having said that, this is one of my favourite films of the 1990s. Even the few baffling parts of the film don't bother me (like they bother a friend of mine who always complains about the final scenes where Ethan Hawke is boarding the space ship- 'he's still wearing his ordinary clothes, where's the space suit? And why hasn't he done any astronaut training? And why didn't he even bother to say goodbye to Uma Thurman?'), I like films that leave you wondering and thinking.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Going against the odds to achieve something
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    omasir02
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Gattaca a space-age (futuristic) city has a research center that specializes in aerospace research that embodies specific characteristics which allow people with perfection to be employed. Only those with perfect genes have access to better jobs. But children who carry natural genes, which are designed without the help of science, are known as natural or invalid inevitably are in turn rejected, isolated, and nevertheless pushed into poverty, with a prospective for a low job ranking. Parents have to define ways of helping their children in attaining an ideal life. This is where we meet Vincent (Ethan Hawke), supposedly a natural child with less perfect genes, with big dreams of one day going to space engages the help from Jerome Morrow (Jude Law) a paralyzed former swimming star. To beat all odds, both men enable one another the opportunity to achieve something desired and stump the laws that run Gattaca. In order for Vincent to thrive in Gattaca, Jerome provides him with his biological samples, hair, urine and blood that qualify Vincent in passing the DNA test requirement. Hence Vincent then enrolls the facade of being Jerome after undergoing psychological and physical changes. Then there is Irene Cassini (Uma Thurman) a charming young woman who in spite of her perfect design suffers from heart issues and seems to be falling for Vincent but at the same time is trying to find out who he really is. One other film that has the appropriateness to the theme is Elysium which shows the determination of certain individuals embattled to reach the space paradise habitat Elysium for state-of-the-art health-care and citizenship. The scene where as children and yet again as adults, Vincent and his brother Anton (Loren Dean) are competitively swimming seems to be the motif that shows determination can help in overcoming genetic shortcomings because Vincent sees his brother Anton and society rejecting him for his imperfections. There is a high angle shot for the swimming scenario because we are able to view Vincent and his brother from an aerial view. Overall the film is brilliant with cast displaying a composed mannerism while playing their parts in a way that goes to show that each is determined to achieve their desired goals by all means possible. The actors' performance is sterling because they make their characters to be believable. The theme shows that science can be manipulated to fit the interests of the protagonist.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Gattaca (or How To Succeed In A Corrupt Scociety
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    lagondapaolini-778-957250
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Imagine a society where corruption is so rampant that all the good careers are reserved for the elite and their offspring. Now imagine a making a perfect analogy for that problem in a movie. The result is Gattaca. The main character's problem is being considered 'Less Than Perfect' by his society, and thus unfit to lead the career of his choice, and which suits his skills, because such career is reserved for those who earned the right to it by birth. Those who were 'born lucky'. It could work as a great symbol of racism, but on deeper level it actually dissects all the aspects of a corrupt society where your career is determined by your family ties (genetic composition) and not at all by your skills. The main character did not only train himself to earn the skills needed for the career he wanted, but he also done the extra effort of designing a perfect lie. Which is how to win in life if you are not born a fortunate son :) Think about it. For delivering that message in such a and beautiful and touching manner, the movie, and everyone in its cast, deserves a big Kudos.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Gattaca
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    myystery-773-599626
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Gattaca is a beautiful film. It touches on themes of discrimination, prejudice, possible dangers of technological progress and the life of those who are left behind. The film's yellow tone accompanies the melancholic nature of the film. The ending of the film is very beautiful in the way that it allows the main character to escape from hostile earth and probably achieve a good life for himself somewhere else. It's plot seems a bit contrived and unoriginal, though. Another problem is that Uma Thurman's character never manages to become important. 8 stars.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Hit and miss for me.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Sergeant_Tibbs
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Gattaca had always been one of those cult favourites which I'd never seen but was always intrigued by. It has some great science fiction concepts, which can be expected from the writer of The Truman Show, here writing and directing, but Gattaca doesn't have the emotion that Truman was able to conjure. It's a highly engrossing film yet subtle, with rich set decoration, photography, score and a devotion to detail. I really enjoyed the simple goal of the protagonist, Vincent played by Ethan Hawke, and his simple desire to go to space. How he overcame the initial obstacle of his predicted fate was fascinating, but other obstacles were convoluted and not as engaging. However, I wasn't convinced by the scenes of him socialising with Uma Thurman or Jude Law's characters as it came off as awkward or not well developed. It didn't seem like the character had a way written in him to pull off those scenes. However, I loved the sci-fi ideas of how the future can be predicted through DNA. I've always wanted to see them explored in film. The first act was the best scene, with the prologue and then the growing up montage, although it's a shame that the film's climax returned to a homage to the montage which seemed really immature with a predictable twist. There's a great short film in here somewhere, with a bit too much excess to pad it out to a feature. 7/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    This fantastic movie humbled me a lot
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    lisaofshades
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Just watch it. As a kid I wanted to become a scientist specialized in genetics... I wanted to mess with the human DNA... create monsters, but also super humans... but that movie isn't about that... merely perfecting people to make them less likely to have diseases, violent impulses and have good looks, better endurance, intelligence... perfect for a normal human... This really appeals to me... I know deep down that it's evil and Hitler like... but I always believed it was for the best and a fantastic idea... Until I saw this movie. It showed someone who was born naturally... fight against his own discarded fate... to reach his dream. He turned out to be more resourceful and a better person than a killer whose DNA would have never been suspected... surpassing even the DNA of someone who was born with the utmost perfect fate, but with a tragic accident, saw it all go down in the garbage in an instant... It shows how that values such as passion, determination and resourcefulness are forgotten but shouldn't be... that we shouldn't just assume that someone has no future, no matter how unprivileged and even handicapped his start might be... the heart and will can have a tremendous weight in the balance... and that very power, which allowed the most humble to surpass the most gifted became more powerful by being trained by the very hardship and flaws that we thought made him inferior... That movie really made me think... and help me see that the people that we dismiss have tales to tell, values that we are clueless about, wisdom that we can't even suspect... all thanks to the hardship they went through... and that's what made them better people... not a ton of money. I was born with the greatest brain, I could have done anything... I thought that I could do anything alone, but it's meaningless if no one wants to believe and hire you... meaningless if you're too sick to even move... fate isn't everything... The music, the actors, everything was perfect in this movie. It's one of the few that actually showed me that some people are even more clever and wiser than me... I really respect the creators of this movie for being able to show me why my idea of perfection was wrong so brilliantly and in an entertaining manner; but don't expect explosions all over the place... it has a sort of nostalgic pace... I just plain love this movie. I feel a sorrowful fondness every time I see the name. Jude Law said this about it (see his biography): It was the first time I felt I was making a script I believed in, and that I'd see something on screen close to what I'd hoped, rather than this vaguely confusing wilderness my jobs had been to this point. It was my first project with quality minds behind it, Jersey Films, Andrew Niccol and Ethan Hawke, who was a joy to work with. I felt we had a real meeting of the minds. (On making Gattaca (1997)). Thank you for this movie. I want more of this.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A complex and heavy duty film.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    oscar-35
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    *Spoiler/plot- Gattaca, 1997. The future world is obsessed with good genes and genetic engineering of their offspring. The world has become a Gestapo-like in it's enforcement of social strata based on tightly enforced class matters. A young man finds a way to 'pass' as someone else and upsets the social establishment for his own goals. *Special Stars- Ethan Hawke, Uma Thurman, Jude Law, Alan Arkin, Ernest Borgine. *Theme- Being yourself instead of others is the best truth. *Trivia/location/goofs- Locations: Marin County Civic Center, Sepulveda Spillway. Look for the ripped shoulder jacket seam when the policeman gets attacked and then it magically repairs itself. *Emotion- A complex and heavy duty film plot tackling some major questions of our modern era. Interesting to see and understand the lesson that the director wanted the viewer to think about after seeing this film. This is an important film theme and could be more than more can handle, but worth seeing to open you own mind on these societal issues.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not my cup of tea
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Ken Potocki
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    So, in Honors Biology, my teacher announced we we're going to watch this movie. (Since we are in the DNA unit) Teacher said: "This movie was a flop at the box office"....already I was worried. What the movie basically plays off as, is a romance-drama slash murder mystery. I do not sense an entire lot of "sci-fi" within the movie. The movie opens with an un-needed 35 minute flashback/life story of our main character. To me, I like how they based the movie around his backstory, however, it was dragged out for too long. Other than that, when the murder-mystery subplot enters the movie, to me, it lags, and doesn't keep up a fast pace, and is pretty slow moving. At certain points, Uma Thurmann even seemed like a character just added for time, it could have done without random romance scenes between her and Ethan Hawke. Towards the end, the movie offers decent twists and turns with characters, Ernest Borgnine does a solid job as the mission director (Sadly, his screen time does not amount to a lot). Overall, I was expecting more of a science fiction movie, and basically what it is, is a romance/drama. Only go into this if you're a fan of romance and/or drama movies. Sci-fi is pretty lackluster here. 5/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Slow Paced but Deep and in Touch with the Human Spirit
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    kchang511
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    First of all, I would like to state that the musical score in this film was incredible and I still remember the musical motif to this day. I believe this movie was a great story about the strength of the human spirit and how it can more than fully augment deficiencies in genetics. I don't believe the stark portrait of the future depicted in this film will actually come true, as I don't have such pessimism about the humanity of humanity. But, I believe in certain group think circumstances, it might come true. Whatever the case, I think the movie gave a great portrayal of what it is like to be deemed genetically inferior. The main character's hard work and endurance to reach his dreams gave a universal meaning and message without coming off as too corny. Also, I didn't think his plight and efforts for greatness detracted anything from the message. Often movies try too hard at pushing their universal message that the story ends up being horrible and the message ends up being overly done. This movie can help inspire all to believe in hard work and dedication while showing that the spirit is the strongest thing a human can have. The only one flaw I felt in this movie was the swimming competition with his brother. After already beating him once, beating him again was useless. They should have saved him beating his brother for the second time, having him lose the first time in his youth. This would have made it more powerful. While the swimming part was a bit corny, I couldn't think of any better way it could have been done. Finally, I believe Jerome's suicide at the end really solidified the meaning of spirit. He has felt his chance at greatness passed and has lived on through the main character, thus completing his life.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    We now have discrimination down to a science.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    JohnRouseMerriottChard
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Gattaca is written and directed by Andrew Niccol. It stars Ethan Hawke, Uma Thurman, Jude Law, Gore Vidal, Loren Dean, Xander Berkeley and Alan Arkin. Music is by Michael Nyman and cinematography by Slawomir Idziak. It's the near future and eugenics dominate a society where children are either "valids" (reproductive through eugenics) or "in-valids" (naturally birthed with inherent genetic flaws). One such "in-valid" is Vincent Anton Freeman (Hawke), who plots an intricate scheme to assume a "valid" person's identification so as to reach his dreams of being an astronaut. There is no gene for fate. Biopunk future meets tech-noir in this thought provoking and intelligent piece of sci-fi. There is a decent argument to suggest that Gattaca is more style over character substance, especially given that visually Niccol's movie is stunning. It's a near future world of genetic engineering where although discrimination is illegal, perfection rules the day and the "in-valids" are passed over for high grade employment. Identity, inferiority and bigotry are fused together to offer up moral quandaries and ethical conundrums, all set to an oppressive tech-noir backdrop painted by Idziak's deft choice of colour filters. There's a striking difference between the look of the Gattaca corporation compared to the rest of the outside world, this helps to keep the thematics at work rich and potent. As a thriller it barely raises the pulse, but this is deliberate, as is the pacing by Niccol. This is an emotionally stunted world and the ethereal atmosphere hovers continually over proceedings. There's a romance in the mix between Hawke and Thurman, which on the surface seems a token sub-plot and devoid of passion, but again this feels deliberate, lack of passion is actually the order of the day. Cast performances are well up to scratch, with Law stealing the film as a one time "valid" ironically invalidated by an incident. And while we could have done with more from top performers Arkin (as a copper attired like a classical film noir gumshoe) and Elias Koteas (as Vincent's father), it rounds out as an impressively constructed picture. Provocative and brainy, with visual pleasures unbound, Gattaca has many attributes that reward still further on repeat viewings. 8/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Great film, even with the ambiguity.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Peter Hill
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I love this film, I think its one of the most thought-provoking and stylish sci-fi films of the past few decades. Rather than just repeat all the praise/comments that previous reviewers have posted, I will get straight to what struck me about this film is the retro-feel of much of it's design. This film is set in an imaginary future yet the film is as much a homage to the styles and sheens of 1950s/60s sci-fi. The elites dress like the early Beatles, everyone seems to drive Cadillacs, the detectives wear film noir hats & overcoats, even the space rockets seem to have lifted straight from a 50s sci-fi comic. As well as a thought-provoking study on what it means to be human and how limitations are often imposed by others, the film seems to be a love-letter to both classic and B-grade sci-fi, from the shiny design of 'Logan's Run' to the cheesy, lovable awfulness of 'Mars Needs Women'. Having said that, this is one of my favourite films of the 1990s. Even the few baffling parts of the film don't bother me (like they bother a friend of mine who always complains about the final scenes where Ethan Hawke is boarding the space ship- 'he's still wearing his ordinary clothes, where's the space suit? And why hasn't he done any astronaut training? And why didn't he even bother to say goodbye to Uma Thurman?'), I like films that leave you wondering and thinking.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Going against the odds to achieve something
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    omasir02
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Gattaca a space-age (futuristic) city has a research center that specializes in aerospace research that embodies specific characteristics which allow people with perfection to be employed. Only those with perfect genes have access to better jobs. But children who carry natural genes, which are designed without the help of science, are known as natural or invalid inevitably are in turn rejected, isolated, and nevertheless pushed into poverty, with a prospective for a low job ranking. Parents have to define ways of helping their children in attaining an ideal life. This is where we meet Vincent (Ethan Hawke), supposedly a natural child with less perfect genes, with big dreams of one day going to space engages the help from Jerome Morrow (Jude Law) a paralyzed former swimming star. To beat all odds, both men enable one another the opportunity to achieve something desired and stump the laws that run Gattaca. In order for Vincent to thrive in Gattaca, Jerome provides him with his biological samples, hair, urine and blood that qualify Vincent in passing the DNA test requirement. Hence Vincent then enrolls the facade of being Jerome after undergoing psychological and physical changes. Then there is Irene Cassini (Uma Thurman) a charming young woman who in spite of her perfect design suffers from heart issues and seems to be falling for Vincent but at the same time is trying to find out who he really is. One other film that has the appropriateness to the theme is Elysium which shows the determination of certain individuals embattled to reach the space paradise habitat Elysium for state-of-the-art health-care and citizenship. The scene where as children and yet again as adults, Vincent and his brother Anton (Loren Dean) are competitively swimming seems to be the motif that shows determination can help in overcoming genetic shortcomings because Vincent sees his brother Anton and society rejecting him for his imperfections. There is a high angle shot for the swimming scenario because we are able to view Vincent and his brother from an aerial view. Overall the film is brilliant with cast displaying a composed mannerism while playing their parts in a way that goes to show that each is determined to achieve their desired goals by all means possible. The actors' performance is sterling because they make their characters to be believable. The theme shows that science can be manipulated to fit the interests of the protagonist.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Gattaca (or How To Succeed In A Corrupt Scociety
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    lagondapaolini-778-957250
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Imagine a society where corruption is so rampant that all the good careers are reserved for the elite and their offspring. Now imagine a making a perfect analogy for that problem in a movie. The result is Gattaca. The main character's problem is being considered 'Less Than Perfect' by his society, and thus unfit to lead the career of his choice, and which suits his skills, because such career is reserved for those who earned the right to it by birth. Those who were 'born lucky'. It could work as a great symbol of racism, but on deeper level it actually dissects all the aspects of a corrupt society where your career is determined by your family ties (genetic composition) and not at all by your skills. The main character did not only train himself to earn the skills needed for the career he wanted, but he also done the extra effort of designing a perfect lie. Which is how to win in life if you are not born a fortunate son :) Think about it. For delivering that message in such a and beautiful and touching manner, the movie, and everyone in its cast, deserves a big Kudos.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Gattaca
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    myystery-773-599626
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Gattaca is a beautiful film. It touches on themes of discrimination, prejudice, possible dangers of technological progress and the life of those who are left behind. The film's yellow tone accompanies the melancholic nature of the film. The ending of the film is very beautiful in the way that it allows the main character to escape from hostile earth and probably achieve a good life for himself somewhere else. It's plot seems a bit contrived and unoriginal, though. Another problem is that Uma Thurman's character never manages to become important. 8 stars.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Hit and miss for me.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Sergeant_Tibbs
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Gattaca had always been one of those cult favourites which I'd never seen but was always intrigued by. It has some great science fiction concepts, which can be expected from the writer of The Truman Show, here writing and directing, but Gattaca doesn't have the emotion that Truman was able to conjure. It's a highly engrossing film yet subtle, with rich set decoration, photography, score and a devotion to detail. I really enjoyed the simple goal of the protagonist, Vincent played by Ethan Hawke, and his simple desire to go to space. How he overcame the initial obstacle of his predicted fate was fascinating, but other obstacles were convoluted and not as engaging. However, I wasn't convinced by the scenes of him socialising with Uma Thurman or Jude Law's characters as it came off as awkward or not well developed. It didn't seem like the character had a way written in him to pull off those scenes. However, I loved the sci-fi ideas of how the future can be predicted through DNA. I've always wanted to see them explored in film. The first act was the best scene, with the prologue and then the growing up montage, although it's a shame that the film's climax returned to a homage to the montage which seemed really immature with a predictable twist. There's a great short film in here somewhere, with a bit too much excess to pad it out to a feature. 7/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    This fantastic movie humbled me a lot
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    lisaofshades
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Just watch it. As a kid I wanted to become a scientist specialized in genetics... I wanted to mess with the human DNA... create monsters, but also super humans... but that movie isn't about that... merely perfecting people to make them less likely to have diseases, violent impulses and have good looks, better endurance, intelligence... perfect for a normal human... This really appeals to me... I know deep down that it's evil and Hitler like... but I always believed it was for the best and a fantastic idea... Until I saw this movie. It showed someone who was born naturally... fight against his own discarded fate... to reach his dream. He turned out to be more resourceful and a better person than a killer whose DNA would have never been suspected... surpassing even the DNA of someone who was born with the utmost perfect fate, but with a tragic accident, saw it all go down in the garbage in an instant... It shows how that values such as passion, determination and resourcefulness are forgotten but shouldn't be... that we shouldn't just assume that someone has no future, no matter how unprivileged and even handicapped his start might be... the heart and will can have a tremendous weight in the balance... and that very power, which allowed the most humble to surpass the most gifted became more powerful by being trained by the very hardship and flaws that we thought made him inferior... That movie really made me think... and help me see that the people that we dismiss have tales to tell, values that we are clueless about, wisdom that we can't even suspect... all thanks to the hardship they went through... and that's what made them better people... not a ton of money. I was born with the greatest brain, I could have done anything... I thought that I could do anything alone, but it's meaningless if no one wants to believe and hire you... meaningless if you're too sick to even move... fate isn't everything... The music, the actors, everything was perfect in this movie. It's one of the few that actually showed me that some people are even more clever and wiser than me... I really respect the creators of this movie for being able to show me why my idea of perfection was wrong so brilliantly and in an entertaining manner; but don't expect explosions all over the place... it has a sort of nostalgic pace... I just plain love this movie. I feel a sorrowful fondness every time I see the name. Jude Law said this about it (see his biography): It was the first time I felt I was making a script I believed in, and that I'd see something on screen close to what I'd hoped, rather than this vaguely confusing wilderness my jobs had been to this point. It was my first project with quality minds behind it, Jersey Films, Andrew Niccol and Ethan Hawke, who was a joy to work with. I felt we had a real meeting of the minds. (On making Gattaca (1997)). Thank you for this movie. I want more of this.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A complex and heavy duty film.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    oscar-35
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    *Spoiler/plot- Gattaca, 1997. The future world is obsessed with good genes and genetic engineering of their offspring. The world has become a Gestapo-like in it's enforcement of social strata based on tightly enforced class matters. A young man finds a way to 'pass' as someone else and upsets the social establishment for his own goals. *Special Stars- Ethan Hawke, Uma Thurman, Jude Law, Alan Arkin, Ernest Borgine. *Theme- Being yourself instead of others is the best truth. *Trivia/location/goofs- Locations: Marin County Civic Center, Sepulveda Spillway. Look for the ripped shoulder jacket seam when the policeman gets attacked and then it magically repairs itself. *Emotion- A complex and heavy duty film plot tackling some major questions of our modern era. Interesting to see and understand the lesson that the director wanted the viewer to think about after seeing this film. This is an important film theme and could be more than more can handle, but worth seeing to open you own mind on these societal issues.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not my cup of tea
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Ken Potocki
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    So, in Honors Biology, my teacher announced we we're going to watch this movie. (Since we are in the DNA unit) Teacher said: "This movie was a flop at the box office"....already I was worried. What the movie basically plays off as, is a romance-drama slash murder mystery. I do not sense an entire lot of "sci-fi" within the movie. The movie opens with an un-needed 35 minute flashback/life story of our main character. To me, I like how they based the movie around his backstory, however, it was dragged out for too long. Other than that, when the murder-mystery subplot enters the movie, to me, it lags, and doesn't keep up a fast pace, and is pretty slow moving. At certain points, Uma Thurmann even seemed like a character just added for time, it could have done without random romance scenes between her and Ethan Hawke. Towards the end, the movie offers decent twists and turns with characters, Ernest Borgnine does a solid job as the mission director (Sadly, his screen time does not amount to a lot). Overall, I was expecting more of a science fiction movie, and basically what it is, is a romance/drama. Only go into this if you're a fan of romance and/or drama movies. Sci-fi is pretty lackluster here. 5/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Slow Paced but Deep and in Touch with the Human Spirit
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    kchang511
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    First of all, I would like to state that the musical score in this film was incredible and I still remember the musical motif to this day. I believe this movie was a great story about the strength of the human spirit and how it can more than fully augment deficiencies in genetics. I don't believe the stark portrait of the future depicted in this film will actually come true, as I don't have such pessimism about the humanity of humanity. But, I believe in certain group think circumstances, it might come true. Whatever the case, I think the movie gave a great portrayal of what it is like to be deemed genetically inferior. The main character's hard work and endurance to reach his dreams gave a universal meaning and message without coming off as too corny. Also, I didn't think his plight and efforts for greatness detracted anything from the message. Often movies try too hard at pushing their universal message that the story ends up being horrible and the message ends up being overly done. This movie can help inspire all to believe in hard work and dedication while showing that the spirit is the strongest thing a human can have. The only one flaw I felt in this movie was the swimming competition with his brother. After already beating him once, beating him again was useless. They should have saved him beating his brother for the second time, having him lose the first time in his youth. This would have made it more powerful. While the swimming part was a bit corny, I couldn't think of any better way it could have been done. Finally, I believe Jerome's suicide at the end really solidified the meaning of spirit. He has felt his chance at greatness passed and has lived on through the main character, thus completing his life.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    We now have discrimination down to a science.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    JohnRouseMerriottChard
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Gattaca is written and directed by Andrew Niccol. It stars Ethan Hawke, Uma Thurman, Jude Law, Gore Vidal, Loren Dean, Xander Berkeley and Alan Arkin. Music is by Michael Nyman and cinematography by Slawomir Idziak. It's the near future and eugenics dominate a society where children are either "valids" (reproductive through eugenics) or "in-valids" (naturally birthed with inherent genetic flaws). One such "in-valid" is Vincent Anton Freeman (Hawke), who plots an intricate scheme to assume a "valid" person's identification so as to reach his dreams of being an astronaut. There is no gene for fate. Biopunk future meets tech-noir in this thought provoking and intelligent piece of sci-fi. There is a decent argument to suggest that Gattaca is more style over character substance, especially given that visually Niccol's movie is stunning. It's a near future world of genetic engineering where although discrimination is illegal, perfection rules the day and the "in-valids" are passed over for high grade employment. Identity, inferiority and bigotry are fused together to offer up moral quandaries and ethical conundrums, all set to an oppressive tech-noir backdrop painted by Idziak's deft choice of colour filters. There's a striking difference between the look of the Gattaca corporation compared to the rest of the outside world, this helps to keep the thematics at work rich and potent. As a thriller it barely raises the pulse, but this is deliberate, as is the pacing by Niccol. This is an emotionally stunted world and the ethereal atmosphere hovers continually over proceedings. There's a romance in the mix between Hawke and Thurman, which on the surface seems a token sub-plot and devoid of passion, but again this feels deliberate, lack of passion is actually the order of the day. Cast performances are well up to scratch, with Law stealing the film as a one time "valid" ironically invalidated by an incident. And while we could have done with more from top performers Arkin (as a copper attired like a classical film noir gumshoe) and Elias Koteas (as Vincent's father), it rounds out as an impressively constructed picture. Provocative and brainy, with visual pleasures unbound, Gattaca has many attributes that reward still further on repeat viewings. 8/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Great film, even with the ambiguity.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Peter Hill
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I love this film, I think its one of the most thought-provoking and stylish sci-fi films of the past few decades. Rather than just repeat all the praise/comments that previous reviewers have posted, I will get straight to what struck me about this film is the retro-feel of much of it's design. This film is set in an imaginary future yet the film is as much a homage to the styles and sheens of 1950s/60s sci-fi. The elites dress like the early Beatles, everyone seems to drive Cadillacs, the detectives wear film noir hats & overcoats, even the space rockets seem to have lifted straight from a 50s sci-fi comic. As well as a thought-provoking study on what it means to be human and how limitations are often imposed by others, the film seems to be a love-letter to both classic and B-grade sci-fi, from the shiny design of 'Logan's Run' to the cheesy, lovable awfulness of 'Mars Needs Women'. Having said that, this is one of my favourite films of the 1990s. Even the few baffling parts of the film don't bother me (like they bother a friend of mine who always complains about the final scenes where Ethan Hawke is boarding the space ship- 'he's still wearing his ordinary clothes, where's the space suit? And why hasn't he done any astronaut training? And why didn't he even bother to say goodbye to Uma Thurman?'), I like films that leave you wondering and thinking.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Going against the odds to achieve something
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    omasir02
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Gattaca a space-age (futuristic) city has a research center that specializes in aerospace research that embodies specific characteristics which allow people with perfection to be employed. Only those with perfect genes have access to better jobs. But children who carry natural genes, which are designed without the help of science, are known as natural or invalid inevitably are in turn rejected, isolated, and nevertheless pushed into poverty, with a prospective for a low job ranking. Parents have to define ways of helping their children in attaining an ideal life. This is where we meet Vincent (Ethan Hawke), supposedly a natural child with less perfect genes, with big dreams of one day going to space engages the help from Jerome Morrow (Jude Law) a paralyzed former swimming star. To beat all odds, both men enable one another the opportunity to achieve something desired and stump the laws that run Gattaca. In order for Vincent to thrive in Gattaca, Jerome provides him with his biological samples, hair, urine and blood that qualify Vincent in passing the DNA test requirement. Hence Vincent then enrolls the facade of being Jerome after undergoing psychological and physical changes. Then there is Irene Cassini (Uma Thurman) a charming young woman who in spite of her perfect design suffers from heart issues and seems to be falling for Vincent but at the same time is trying to find out who he really is. One other film that has the appropriateness to the theme is Elysium which shows the determination of certain individuals embattled to reach the space paradise habitat Elysium for state-of-the-art health-care and citizenship. The scene where as children and yet again as adults, Vincent and his brother Anton (Loren Dean) are competitively swimming seems to be the motif that shows determination can help in overcoming genetic shortcomings because Vincent sees his brother Anton and society rejecting him for his imperfections. There is a high angle shot for the swimming scenario because we are able to view Vincent and his brother from an aerial view. Overall the film is brilliant with cast displaying a composed mannerism while playing their parts in a way that goes to show that each is determined to achieve their desired goals by all means possible. The actors' performance is sterling because they make their characters to be believable. The theme shows that science can be manipulated to fit the interests of the protagonist.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Gattaca (or How To Succeed In A Corrupt Scociety
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    lagondapaolini-778-957250
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Imagine a society where corruption is so rampant that all the good careers are reserved for the elite and their offspring. Now imagine a making a perfect analogy for that problem in a movie. The result is Gattaca. The main character's problem is being considered 'Less Than Perfect' by his society, and thus unfit to lead the career of his choice, and which suits his skills, because such career is reserved for those who earned the right to it by birth. Those who were 'born lucky'. It could work as a great symbol of racism, but on deeper level it actually dissects all the aspects of a corrupt society where your career is determined by your family ties (genetic composition) and not at all by your skills. The main character did not only train himself to earn the skills needed for the career he wanted, but he also done the extra effort of designing a perfect lie. Which is how to win in life if you are not born a fortunate son :) Think about it. For delivering that message in such a and beautiful and touching manner, the movie, and everyone in its cast, deserves a big Kudos.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Gattaca
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    myystery-773-599626
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Gattaca is a beautiful film. It touches on themes of discrimination, prejudice, possible dangers of technological progress and the life of those who are left behind. The film's yellow tone accompanies the melancholic nature of the film. The ending of the film is very beautiful in the way that it allows the main character to escape from hostile earth and probably achieve a good life for himself somewhere else. It's plot seems a bit contrived and unoriginal, though. Another problem is that Uma Thurman's character never manages to become important. 8 stars.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Hit and miss for me.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Sergeant_Tibbs
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Gattaca had always been one of those cult favourites which I'd never seen but was always intrigued by. It has some great science fiction concepts, which can be expected from the writer of The Truman Show, here writing and directing, but Gattaca doesn't have the emotion that Truman was able to conjure. It's a highly engrossing film yet subtle, with rich set decoration, photography, score and a devotion to detail. I really enjoyed the simple goal of the protagonist, Vincent played by Ethan Hawke, and his simple desire to go to space. How he overcame the initial obstacle of his predicted fate was fascinating, but other obstacles were convoluted and not as engaging. However, I wasn't convinced by the scenes of him socialising with Uma Thurman or Jude Law's characters as it came off as awkward or not well developed. It didn't seem like the character had a way written in him to pull off those scenes. However, I loved the sci-fi ideas of how the future can be predicted through DNA. I've always wanted to see them explored in film. The first act was the best scene, with the prologue and then the growing up montage, although it's a shame that the film's climax returned to a homage to the montage which seemed really immature with a predictable twist. There's a great short film in here somewhere, with a bit too much excess to pad it out to a feature. 7/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    This fantastic movie humbled me a lot
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    lisaofshades
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Just watch it. As a kid I wanted to become a scientist specialized in genetics... I wanted to mess with the human DNA... create monsters, but also super humans... but that movie isn't about that... merely perfecting people to make them less likely to have diseases, violent impulses and have good looks, better endurance, intelligence... perfect for a normal human... This really appeals to me... I know deep down that it's evil and Hitler like... but I always believed it was for the best and a fantastic idea... Until I saw this movie. It showed someone who was born naturally... fight against his own discarded fate... to reach his dream. He turned out to be more resourceful and a better person than a killer whose DNA would have never been suspected... surpassing even the DNA of someone who was born with the utmost perfect fate, but with a tragic accident, saw it all go down in the garbage in an instant... It shows how that values such as passion, determination and resourcefulness are forgotten but shouldn't be... that we shouldn't just assume that someone has no future, no matter how unprivileged and even handicapped his start might be... the heart and will can have a tremendous weight in the balance... and that very power, which allowed the most humble to surpass the most gifted became more powerful by being trained by the very hardship and flaws that we thought made him inferior... That movie really made me think... and help me see that the people that we dismiss have tales to tell, values that we are clueless about, wisdom that we can't even suspect... all thanks to the hardship they went through... and that's what made them better people... not a ton of money. I was born with the greatest brain, I could have done anything... I thought that I could do anything alone, but it's meaningless if no one wants to believe and hire you... meaningless if you're too sick to even move... fate isn't everything... The music, the actors, everything was perfect in this movie. It's one of the few that actually showed me that some people are even more clever and wiser than me... I really respect the creators of this movie for being able to show me why my idea of perfection was wrong so brilliantly and in an entertaining manner; but don't expect explosions all over the place... it has a sort of nostalgic pace... I just plain love this movie. I feel a sorrowful fondness every time I see the name. Jude Law said this about it (see his biography): It was the first time I felt I was making a script I believed in, and that I'd see something on screen close to what I'd hoped, rather than this vaguely confusing wilderness my jobs had been to this point. It was my first project with quality minds behind it, Jersey Films, Andrew Niccol and Ethan Hawke, who was a joy to work with. I felt we had a real meeting of the minds. (On making Gattaca (1997)). Thank you for this movie. I want more of this.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A complex and heavy duty film.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    oscar-35
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    *Spoiler/plot- Gattaca, 1997. The future world is obsessed with good genes and genetic engineering of their offspring. The world has become a Gestapo-like in it's enforcement of social strata based on tightly enforced class matters. A young man finds a way to 'pass' as someone else and upsets the social establishment for his own goals. *Special Stars- Ethan Hawke, Uma Thurman, Jude Law, Alan Arkin, Ernest Borgine. *Theme- Being yourself instead of others is the best truth. *Trivia/location/goofs- Locations: Marin County Civic Center, Sepulveda Spillway. Look for the ripped shoulder jacket seam when the policeman gets attacked and then it magically repairs itself. *Emotion- A complex and heavy duty film plot tackling some major questions of our modern era. Interesting to see and understand the lesson that the director wanted the viewer to think about after seeing this film. This is an important film theme and could be more than more can handle, but worth seeing to open you own mind on these societal issues.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not my cup of tea
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Ken Potocki
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    So, in Honors Biology, my teacher announced we we're going to watch this movie. (Since we are in the DNA unit) Teacher said: "This movie was a flop at the box office"....already I was worried. What the movie basically plays off as, is a romance-drama slash murder mystery. I do not sense an entire lot of "sci-fi" within the movie. The movie opens with an un-needed 35 minute flashback/life story of our main character. To me, I like how they based the movie around his backstory, however, it was dragged out for too long. Other than that, when the murder-mystery subplot enters the movie, to me, it lags, and doesn't keep up a fast pace, and is pretty slow moving. At certain points, Uma Thurmann even seemed like a character just added for time, it could have done without random romance scenes between her and Ethan Hawke. Towards the end, the movie offers decent twists and turns with characters, Ernest Borgnine does a solid job as the mission director (Sadly, his screen time does not amount to a lot). Overall, I was expecting more of a science fiction movie, and basically what it is, is a romance/drama. Only go into this if you're a fan of romance and/or drama movies. Sci-fi is pretty lackluster here. 5/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Slow Paced but Deep and in Touch with the Human Spirit
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    kchang511
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    First of all, I would like to state that the musical score in this film was incredible and I still remember the musical motif to this day. I believe this movie was a great story about the strength of the human spirit and how it can more than fully augment deficiencies in genetics. I don't believe the stark portrait of the future depicted in this film will actually come true, as I don't have such pessimism about the humanity of humanity. But, I believe in certain group think circumstances, it might come true. Whatever the case, I think the movie gave a great portrayal of what it is like to be deemed genetically inferior. The main character's hard work and endurance to reach his dreams gave a universal meaning and message without coming off as too corny. Also, I didn't think his plight and efforts for greatness detracted anything from the message. Often movies try too hard at pushing their universal message that the story ends up being horrible and the message ends up being overly done. This movie can help inspire all to believe in hard work and dedication while showing that the spirit is the strongest thing a human can have. The only one flaw I felt in this movie was the swimming competition with his brother. After already beating him once, beating him again was useless. They should have saved him beating his brother for the second time, having him lose the first time in his youth. This would have made it more powerful. While the swimming part was a bit corny, I couldn't think of any better way it could have been done. Finally, I believe Jerome's suicide at the end really solidified the meaning of spirit. He has felt his chance at greatness passed and has lived on through the main character, thus completing his life.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    We now have discrimination down to a science.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    JohnRouseMerriottChard
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Gattaca is written and directed by Andrew Niccol. It stars Ethan Hawke, Uma Thurman, Jude Law, Gore Vidal, Loren Dean, Xander Berkeley and Alan Arkin. Music is by Michael Nyman and cinematography by Slawomir Idziak. It's the near future and eugenics dominate a society where children are either "valids" (reproductive through eugenics) or "in-valids" (naturally birthed with inherent genetic flaws). One such "in-valid" is Vincent Anton Freeman (Hawke), who plots an intricate scheme to assume a "valid" person's identification so as to reach his dreams of being an astronaut. There is no gene for fate. Biopunk future meets tech-noir in this thought provoking and intelligent piece of sci-fi. There is a decent argument to suggest that Gattaca is more style over character substance, especially given that visually Niccol's movie is stunning. It's a near future world of genetic engineering where although discrimination is illegal, perfection rules the day and the "in-valids" are passed over for high grade employment. Identity, inferiority and bigotry are fused together to offer up moral quandaries and ethical conundrums, all set to an oppressive tech-noir backdrop painted by Idziak's deft choice of colour filters. There's a striking difference between the look of the Gattaca corporation compared to the rest of the outside world, this helps to keep the thematics at work rich and potent. As a thriller it barely raises the pulse, but this is deliberate, as is the pacing by Niccol. This is an emotionally stunted world and the ethereal atmosphere hovers continually over proceedings. There's a romance in the mix between Hawke and Thurman, which on the surface seems a token sub-plot and devoid of passion, but again this feels deliberate, lack of passion is actually the order of the day. Cast performances are well up to scratch, with Law stealing the film as a one time "valid" ironically invalidated by an incident. And while we could have done with more from top performers Arkin (as a copper attired like a classical film noir gumshoe) and Elias Koteas (as Vincent's father), it rounds out as an impressively constructed picture. Provocative and brainy, with visual pleasures unbound, Gattaca has many attributes that reward still further on repeat viewings. 8/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Great film, even with the ambiguity.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Peter Hill
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I love this film, I think its one of the most thought-provoking and stylish sci-fi films of the past few decades. Rather than just repeat all the praise/comments that previous reviewers have posted, I will get straight to what struck me about this film is the retro-feel of much of it's design. This film is set in an imaginary future yet the film is as much a homage to the styles and sheens of 1950s/60s sci-fi. The elites dress like the early Beatles, everyone seems to drive Cadillacs, the detectives wear film noir hats & overcoats, even the space rockets seem to have lifted straight from a 50s sci-fi comic. As well as a thought-provoking study on what it means to be human and how limitations are often imposed by others, the film seems to be a love-letter to both classic and B-grade sci-fi, from the shiny design of 'Logan's Run' to the cheesy, lovable awfulness of 'Mars Needs Women'. Having said that, this is one of my favourite films of the 1990s. Even the few baffling parts of the film don't bother me (like they bother a friend of mine who always complains about the final scenes where Ethan Hawke is boarding the space ship- 'he's still wearing his ordinary clothes, where's the space suit? And why hasn't he done any astronaut training? And why didn't he even bother to say goodbye to Uma Thurman?'), I like films that leave you wondering and thinking.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Going against the odds to achieve something
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    omasir02
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Gattaca a space-age (futuristic) city has a research center that specializes in aerospace research that embodies specific characteristics which allow people with perfection to be employed. Only those with perfect genes have access to better jobs. But children who carry natural genes, which are designed without the help of science, are known as natural or invalid inevitably are in turn rejected, isolated, and nevertheless pushed into poverty, with a prospective for a low job ranking. Parents have to define ways of helping their children in attaining an ideal life. This is where we meet Vincent (Ethan Hawke), supposedly a natural child with less perfect genes, with big dreams of one day going to space engages the help from Jerome Morrow (Jude Law) a paralyzed former swimming star. To beat all odds, both men enable one another the opportunity to achieve something desired and stump the laws that run Gattaca. In order for Vincent to thrive in Gattaca, Jerome provides him with his biological samples, hair, urine and blood that qualify Vincent in passing the DNA test requirement. Hence Vincent then enrolls the facade of being Jerome after undergoing psychological and physical changes. Then there is Irene Cassini (Uma Thurman) a charming young woman who in spite of her perfect design suffers from heart issues and seems to be falling for Vincent but at the same time is trying to find out who he really is. One other film that has the appropriateness to the theme is Elysium which shows the determination of certain individuals embattled to reach the space paradise habitat Elysium for state-of-the-art health-care and citizenship. The scene where as children and yet again as adults, Vincent and his brother Anton (Loren Dean) are competitively swimming seems to be the motif that shows determination can help in overcoming genetic shortcomings because Vincent sees his brother Anton and society rejecting him for his imperfections. There is a high angle shot for the swimming scenario because we are able to view Vincent and his brother from an aerial view. Overall the film is brilliant with cast displaying a composed mannerism while playing their parts in a way that goes to show that each is determined to achieve their desired goals by all means possible. The actors' performance is sterling because they make their characters to be believable. The theme shows that science can be manipulated to fit the interests of the protagonist.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Gattaca (or How To Succeed In A Corrupt Scociety
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    lagondapaolini-778-957250
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Imagine a society where corruption is so rampant that all the good careers are reserved for the elite and their offspring. Now imagine a making a perfect analogy for that problem in a movie. The result is Gattaca. The main character's problem is being considered 'Less Than Perfect' by his society, and thus unfit to lead the career of his choice, and which suits his skills, because such career is reserved for those who earned the right to it by birth. Those who were 'born lucky'. It could work as a great symbol of racism, but on deeper level it actually dissects all the aspects of a corrupt society where your career is determined by your family ties (genetic composition) and not at all by your skills. The main character did not only train himself to earn the skills needed for the career he wanted, but he also done the extra effort of designing a perfect lie. Which is how to win in life if you are not born a fortunate son :) Think about it. For delivering that message in such a and beautiful and touching manner, the movie, and everyone in its cast, deserves a big Kudos.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Gattaca
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    myystery-773-599626
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Gattaca is a beautiful film. It touches on themes of discrimination, prejudice, possible dangers of technological progress and the life of those who are left behind. The film's yellow tone accompanies the melancholic nature of the film. The ending of the film is very beautiful in the way that it allows the main character to escape from hostile earth and probably achieve a good life for himself somewhere else. It's plot seems a bit contrived and unoriginal, though. Another problem is that Uma Thurman's character never manages to become important. 8 stars.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Hit and miss for me.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Sergeant_Tibbs
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Gattaca had always been one of those cult favourites which I'd never seen but was always intrigued by. It has some great science fiction concepts, which can be expected from the writer of The Truman Show, here writing and directing, but Gattaca doesn't have the emotion that Truman was able to conjure. It's a highly engrossing film yet subtle, with rich set decoration, photography, score and a devotion to detail. I really enjoyed the simple goal of the protagonist, Vincent played by Ethan Hawke, and his simple desire to go to space. How he overcame the initial obstacle of his predicted fate was fascinating, but other obstacles were convoluted and not as engaging. However, I wasn't convinced by the scenes of him socialising with Uma Thurman or Jude Law's characters as it came off as awkward or not well developed. It didn't seem like the character had a way written in him to pull off those scenes. However, I loved the sci-fi ideas of how the future can be predicted through DNA. I've always wanted to see them explored in film. The first act was the best scene, with the prologue and then the growing up montage, although it's a shame that the film's climax returned to a homage to the montage which seemed really immature with a predictable twist. There's a great short film in here somewhere, with a bit too much excess to pad it out to a feature. 7/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    This fantastic movie humbled me a lot
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    lisaofshades
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Just watch it. As a kid I wanted to become a scientist specialized in genetics... I wanted to mess with the human DNA... create monsters, but also super humans... but that movie isn't about that... merely perfecting people to make them less likely to have diseases, violent impulses and have good looks, better endurance, intelligence... perfect for a normal human... This really appeals to me... I know deep down that it's evil and Hitler like... but I always believed it was for the best and a fantastic idea... Until I saw this movie. It showed someone who was born naturally... fight against his own discarded fate... to reach his dream. He turned out to be more resourceful and a better person than a killer whose DNA would have never been suspected... surpassing even the DNA of someone who was born with the utmost perfect fate, but with a tragic accident, saw it all go down in the garbage in an instant... It shows how that values such as passion, determination and resourcefulness are forgotten but shouldn't be... that we shouldn't just assume that someone has no future, no matter how unprivileged and even handicapped his start might be... the heart and will can have a tremendous weight in the balance... and that very power, which allowed the most humble to surpass the most gifted became more powerful by being trained by the very hardship and flaws that we thought made him inferior... That movie really made me think... and help me see that the people that we dismiss have tales to tell, values that we are clueless about, wisdom that we can't even suspect... all thanks to the hardship they went through... and that's what made them better people... not a ton of money. I was born with the greatest brain, I could have done anything... I thought that I could do anything alone, but it's meaningless if no one wants to believe and hire you... meaningless if you're too sick to even move... fate isn't everything... The music, the actors, everything was perfect in this movie. It's one of the few that actually showed me that some people are even more clever and wiser than me... I really respect the creators of this movie for being able to show me why my idea of perfection was wrong so brilliantly and in an entertaining manner; but don't expect explosions all over the place... it has a sort of nostalgic pace... I just plain love this movie. I feel a sorrowful fondness every time I see the name. Jude Law said this about it (see his biography): It was the first time I felt I was making a script I believed in, and that I'd see something on screen close to what I'd hoped, rather than this vaguely confusing wilderness my jobs had been to this point. It was my first project with quality minds behind it, Jersey Films, Andrew Niccol and Ethan Hawke, who was a joy to work with. I felt we had a real meeting of the minds. (On making Gattaca (1997)). Thank you for this movie. I want more of this.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A complex and heavy duty film.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    oscar-35
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    *Spoiler/plot- Gattaca, 1997. The future world is obsessed with good genes and genetic engineering of their offspring. The world has become a Gestapo-like in it's enforcement of social strata based on tightly enforced class matters. A young man finds a way to 'pass' as someone else and upsets the social establishment for his own goals. *Special Stars- Ethan Hawke, Uma Thurman, Jude Law, Alan Arkin, Ernest Borgine. *Theme- Being yourself instead of others is the best truth. *Trivia/location/goofs- Locations: Marin County Civic Center, Sepulveda Spillway. Look for the ripped shoulder jacket seam when the policeman gets attacked and then it magically repairs itself. *Emotion- A complex and heavy duty film plot tackling some major questions of our modern era. Interesting to see and understand the lesson that the director wanted the viewer to think about after seeing this film. This is an important film theme and could be more than more can handle, but worth seeing to open you own mind on these societal issues.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not my cup of tea
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Ken Potocki
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    So, in Honors Biology, my teacher announced we we're going to watch this movie. (Since we are in the DNA unit) Teacher said: "This movie was a flop at the box office"....already I was worried. What the movie basically plays off as, is a romance-drama slash murder mystery. I do not sense an entire lot of "sci-fi" within the movie. The movie opens with an un-needed 35 minute flashback/life story of our main character. To me, I like how they based the movie around his backstory, however, it was dragged out for too long. Other than that, when the murder-mystery subplot enters the movie, to me, it lags, and doesn't keep up a fast pace, and is pretty slow moving. At certain points, Uma Thurmann even seemed like a character just added for time, it could have done without random romance scenes between her and Ethan Hawke. Towards the end, the movie offers decent twists and turns with characters, Ernest Borgnine does a solid job as the mission director (Sadly, his screen time does not amount to a lot). Overall, I was expecting more of a science fiction movie, and basically what it is, is a romance/drama. Only go into this if you're a fan of romance and/or drama movies. Sci-fi is pretty lackluster here. 5/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Slow Paced but Deep and in Touch with the Human Spirit
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    kchang511
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    First of all, I would like to state that the musical score in this film was incredible and I still remember the musical motif to this day. I believe this movie was a great story about the strength of the human spirit and how it can more than fully augment deficiencies in genetics. I don't believe the stark portrait of the future depicted in this film will actually come true, as I don't have such pessimism about the humanity of humanity. But, I believe in certain group think circumstances, it might come true. Whatever the case, I think the movie gave a great portrayal of what it is like to be deemed genetically inferior. The main character's hard work and endurance to reach his dreams gave a universal meaning and message without coming off as too corny. Also, I didn't think his plight and efforts for greatness detracted anything from the message. Often movies try too hard at pushing their universal message that the story ends up being horrible and the message ends up being overly done. This movie can help inspire all to believe in hard work and dedication while showing that the spirit is the strongest thing a human can have. The only one flaw I felt in this movie was the swimming competition with his brother. After already beating him once, beating him again was useless. They should have saved him beating his brother for the second time, having him lose the first time in his youth. This would have made it more powerful. While the swimming part was a bit corny, I couldn't think of any better way it could have been done. Finally, I believe Jerome's suicide at the end really solidified the meaning of spirit. He has felt his chance at greatness passed and has lived on through the main character, thus completing his life.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    We now have discrimination down to a science.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    JohnRouseMerriottChard
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Gattaca is written and directed by Andrew Niccol. It stars Ethan Hawke, Uma Thurman, Jude Law, Gore Vidal, Loren Dean, Xander Berkeley and Alan Arkin. Music is by Michael Nyman and cinematography by Slawomir Idziak. It's the near future and eugenics dominate a society where children are either "valids" (reproductive through eugenics) or "in-valids" (naturally birthed with inherent genetic flaws). One such "in-valid" is Vincent Anton Freeman (Hawke), who plots an intricate scheme to assume a "valid" person's identification so as to reach his dreams of being an astronaut. There is no gene for fate. Biopunk future meets tech-noir in this thought provoking and intelligent piece of sci-fi. There is a decent argument to suggest that Gattaca is more style over character substance, especially given that visually Niccol's movie is stunning. It's a near future world of genetic engineering where although discrimination is illegal, perfection rules the day and the "in-valids" are passed over for high grade employment. Identity, inferiority and bigotry are fused together to offer up moral quandaries and ethical conundrums, all set to an oppressive tech-noir backdrop painted by Idziak's deft choice of colour filters. There's a striking difference between the look of the Gattaca corporation compared to the rest of the outside world, this helps to keep the thematics at work rich and potent. As a thriller it barely raises the pulse, but this is deliberate, as is the pacing by Niccol. This is an emotionally stunted world and the ethereal atmosphere hovers continually over proceedings. There's a romance in the mix between Hawke and Thurman, which on the surface seems a token sub-plot and devoid of passion, but again this feels deliberate, lack of passion is actually the order of the day. Cast performances are well up to scratch, with Law stealing the film as a one time "valid" ironically invalidated by an incident. And while we could have done with more from top performers Arkin (as a copper attired like a classical film noir gumshoe) and Elias Koteas (as Vincent's father), it rounds out as an impressively constructed picture. Provocative and brainy, with visual pleasures unbound, Gattaca has many attributes that reward still further on repeat viewings. 8/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Great film, even with the ambiguity.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Peter Hill
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I love this film, I think its one of the most thought-provoking and stylish sci-fi films of the past few decades. Rather than just repeat all the praise/comments that previous reviewers have posted, I will get straight to what struck me about this film is the retro-feel of much of it's design. This film is set in an imaginary future yet the film is as much a homage to the styles and sheens of 1950s/60s sci-fi. The elites dress like the early Beatles, everyone seems to drive Cadillacs, the detectives wear film noir hats & overcoats, even the space rockets seem to have lifted straight from a 50s sci-fi comic. As well as a thought-provoking study on what it means to be human and how limitations are often imposed by others, the film seems to be a love-letter to both classic and B-grade sci-fi, from the shiny design of 'Logan's Run' to the cheesy, lovable awfulness of 'Mars Needs Women'. Having said that, this is one of my favourite films of the 1990s. Even the few baffling parts of the film don't bother me (like they bother a friend of mine who always complains about the final scenes where Ethan Hawke is boarding the space ship- 'he's still wearing his ordinary clothes, where's the space suit? And why hasn't he done any astronaut training? And why didn't he even bother to say goodbye to Uma Thurman?'), I like films that leave you wondering and thinking.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Going against the odds to achieve something
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    omasir02
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Gattaca a space-age (futuristic) city has a research center that specializes in aerospace research that embodies specific characteristics which allow people with perfection to be employed. Only those with perfect genes have access to better jobs. But children who carry natural genes, which are designed without the help of science, are known as natural or invalid inevitably are in turn rejected, isolated, and nevertheless pushed into poverty, with a prospective for a low job ranking. Parents have to define ways of helping their children in attaining an ideal life. This is where we meet Vincent (Ethan Hawke), supposedly a natural child with less perfect genes, with big dreams of one day going to space engages the help from Jerome Morrow (Jude Law) a paralyzed former swimming star. To beat all odds, both men enable one another the opportunity to achieve something desired and stump the laws that run Gattaca. In order for Vincent to thrive in Gattaca, Jerome provides him with his biological samples, hair, urine and blood that qualify Vincent in passing the DNA test requirement. Hence Vincent then enrolls the facade of being Jerome after undergoing psychological and physical changes. Then there is Irene Cassini (Uma Thurman) a charming young woman who in spite of her perfect design suffers from heart issues and seems to be falling for Vincent but at the same time is trying to find out who he really is. One other film that has the appropriateness to the theme is Elysium which shows the determination of certain individuals embattled to reach the space paradise habitat Elysium for state-of-the-art health-care and citizenship. The scene where as children and yet again as adults, Vincent and his brother Anton (Loren Dean) are competitively swimming seems to be the motif that shows determination can help in overcoming genetic shortcomings because Vincent sees his brother Anton and society rejecting him for his imperfections. There is a high angle shot for the swimming scenario because we are able to view Vincent and his brother from an aerial view. Overall the film is brilliant with cast displaying a composed mannerism while playing their parts in a way that goes to show that each is determined to achieve their desired goals by all means possible. The actors' performance is sterling because they make their characters to be believable. The theme shows that science can be manipulated to fit the interests of the protagonist.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Gattaca (or How To Succeed In A Corrupt Scociety
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    lagondapaolini-778-957250
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Imagine a society where corruption is so rampant that all the good careers are reserved for the elite and their offspring. Now imagine a making a perfect analogy for that problem in a movie. The result is Gattaca. The main character's problem is being considered 'Less Than Perfect' by his society, and thus unfit to lead the career of his choice, and which suits his skills, because such career is reserved for those who earned the right to it by birth. Those who were 'born lucky'. It could work as a great symbol of racism, but on deeper level it actually dissects all the aspects of a corrupt society where your career is determined by your family ties (genetic composition) and not at all by your skills. The main character did not only train himself to earn the skills needed for the career he wanted, but he also done the extra effort of designing a perfect lie. Which is how to win in life if you are not born a fortunate son :) Think about it. For delivering that message in such a and beautiful and touching manner, the movie, and everyone in its cast, deserves a big Kudos.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Gattaca
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    myystery-773-599626
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Gattaca is a beautiful film. It touches on themes of discrimination, prejudice, possible dangers of technological progress and the life of those who are left behind. The film's yellow tone accompanies the melancholic nature of the film. The ending of the film is very beautiful in the way that it allows the main character to escape from hostile earth and probably achieve a good life for himself somewhere else. It's plot seems a bit contrived and unoriginal, though. Another problem is that Uma Thurman's character never manages to become important. 8 stars.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Hit and miss for me.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Sergeant_Tibbs
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Gattaca had always been one of those cult favourites which I'd never seen but was always intrigued by. It has some great science fiction concepts, which can be expected from the writer of The Truman Show, here writing and directing, but Gattaca doesn't have the emotion that Truman was able to conjure. It's a highly engrossing film yet subtle, with rich set decoration, photography, score and a devotion to detail. I really enjoyed the simple goal of the protagonist, Vincent played by Ethan Hawke, and his simple desire to go to space. How he overcame the initial obstacle of his predicted fate was fascinating, but other obstacles were convoluted and not as engaging. However, I wasn't convinced by the scenes of him socialising with Uma Thurman or Jude Law's characters as it came off as awkward or not well developed. It didn't seem like the character had a way written in him to pull off those scenes. However, I loved the sci-fi ideas of how the future can be predicted through DNA. I've always wanted to see them explored in film. The first act was the best scene, with the prologue and then the growing up montage, although it's a shame that the film's climax returned to a homage to the montage which seemed really immature with a predictable twist. There's a great short film in here somewhere, with a bit too much excess to pad it out to a feature. 7/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    This fantastic movie humbled me a lot
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    lisaofshades
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Just watch it. As a kid I wanted to become a scientist specialized in genetics... I wanted to mess with the human DNA... create monsters, but also super humans... but that movie isn't about that... merely perfecting people to make them less likely to have diseases, violent impulses and have good looks, better endurance, intelligence... perfect for a normal human... This really appeals to me... I know deep down that it's evil and Hitler like... but I always believed it was for the best and a fantastic idea... Until I saw this movie. It showed someone who was born naturally... fight against his own discarded fate... to reach his dream. He turned out to be more resourceful and a better person than a killer whose DNA would have never been suspected... surpassing even the DNA of someone who was born with the utmost perfect fate, but with a tragic accident, saw it all go down in the garbage in an instant... It shows how that values such as passion, determination and resourcefulness are forgotten but shouldn't be... that we shouldn't just assume that someone has no future, no matter how unprivileged and even handicapped his start might be... the heart and will can have a tremendous weight in the balance... and that very power, which allowed the most humble to surpass the most gifted became more powerful by being trained by the very hardship and flaws that we thought made him inferior... That movie really made me think... and help me see that the people that we dismiss have tales to tell, values that we are clueless about, wisdom that we can't even suspect... all thanks to the hardship they went through... and that's what made them better people... not a ton of money. I was born with the greatest brain, I could have done anything... I thought that I could do anything alone, but it's meaningless if no one wants to believe and hire you... meaningless if you're too sick to even move... fate isn't everything... The music, the actors, everything was perfect in this movie. It's one of the few that actually showed me that some people are even more clever and wiser than me... I really respect the creators of this movie for being able to show me why my idea of perfection was wrong so brilliantly and in an entertaining manner; but don't expect explosions all over the place... it has a sort of nostalgic pace... I just plain love this movie. I feel a sorrowful fondness every time I see the name. Jude Law said this about it (see his biography): It was the first time I felt I was making a script I believed in, and that I'd see something on screen close to what I'd hoped, rather than this vaguely confusing wilderness my jobs had been to this point. It was my first project with quality minds behind it, Jersey Films, Andrew Niccol and Ethan Hawke, who was a joy to work with. I felt we had a real meeting of the minds. (On making Gattaca (1997)). Thank you for this movie. I want more of this.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A complex and heavy duty film.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    oscar-35
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    *Spoiler/plot- Gattaca, 1997. The future world is obsessed with good genes and genetic engineering of their offspring. The world has become a Gestapo-like in it's enforcement of social strata based on tightly enforced class matters. A young man finds a way to 'pass' as someone else and upsets the social establishment for his own goals. *Special Stars- Ethan Hawke, Uma Thurman, Jude Law, Alan Arkin, Ernest Borgine. *Theme- Being yourself instead of others is the best truth. *Trivia/location/goofs- Locations: Marin County Civic Center, Sepulveda Spillway. Look for the ripped shoulder jacket seam when the policeman gets attacked and then it magically repairs itself. *Emotion- A complex and heavy duty film plot tackling some major questions of our modern era. Interesting to see and understand the lesson that the director wanted the viewer to think about after seeing this film. This is an important film theme and could be more than more can handle, but worth seeing to open you own mind on these societal issues.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not my cup of tea
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Ken Potocki
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    So, in Honors Biology, my teacher announced we we're going to watch this movie. (Since we are in the DNA unit) Teacher said: "This movie was a flop at the box office"....already I was worried. What the movie basically plays off as, is a romance-drama slash murder mystery. I do not sense an entire lot of "sci-fi" within the movie. The movie opens with an un-needed 35 minute flashback/life story of our main character. To me, I like how they based the movie around his backstory, however, it was dragged out for too long. Other than that, when the murder-mystery subplot enters the movie, to me, it lags, and doesn't keep up a fast pace, and is pretty slow moving. At certain points, Uma Thurmann even seemed like a character just added for time, it could have done without random romance scenes between her and Ethan Hawke. Towards the end, the movie offers decent twists and turns with characters, Ernest Borgnine does a solid job as the mission director (Sadly, his screen time does not amount to a lot). Overall, I was expecting more of a science fiction movie, and basically what it is, is a romance/drama. Only go into this if you're a fan of romance and/or drama movies. Sci-fi is pretty lackluster here. 5/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Slow Paced but Deep and in Touch with the Human Spirit
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    kchang511
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    First of all, I would like to state that the musical score in this film was incredible and I still remember the musical motif to this day. I believe this movie was a great story about the strength of the human spirit and how it can more than fully augment deficiencies in genetics. I don't believe the stark portrait of the future depicted in this film will actually come true, as I don't have such pessimism about the humanity of humanity. But, I believe in certain group think circumstances, it might come true. Whatever the case, I think the movie gave a great portrayal of what it is like to be deemed genetically inferior. The main character's hard work and endurance to reach his dreams gave a universal meaning and message without coming off as too corny. Also, I didn't think his plight and efforts for greatness detracted anything from the message. Often movies try too hard at pushing their universal message that the story ends up being horrible and the message ends up being overly done. This movie can help inspire all to believe in hard work and dedication while showing that the spirit is the strongest thing a human can have. The only one flaw I felt in this movie was the swimming competition with his brother. After already beating him once, beating him again was useless. They should have saved him beating his brother for the second time, having him lose the first time in his youth. This would have made it more powerful. While the swimming part was a bit corny, I couldn't think of any better way it could have been done. Finally, I believe Jerome's suicide at the end really solidified the meaning of spirit. He has felt his chance at greatness passed and has lived on through the main character, thus completing his life.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    We now have discrimination down to a science.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    JohnRouseMerriottChard
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Gattaca is written and directed by Andrew Niccol. It stars Ethan Hawke, Uma Thurman, Jude Law, Gore Vidal, Loren Dean, Xander Berkeley and Alan Arkin. Music is by Michael Nyman and cinematography by Slawomir Idziak. It's the near future and eugenics dominate a society where children are either "valids" (reproductive through eugenics) or "in-valids" (naturally birthed with inherent genetic flaws). One such "in-valid" is Vincent Anton Freeman (Hawke), who plots an intricate scheme to assume a "valid" person's identification so as to reach his dreams of being an astronaut. There is no gene for fate. Biopunk future meets tech-noir in this thought provoking and intelligent piece of sci-fi. There is a decent argument to suggest that Gattaca is more style over character substance, especially given that visually Niccol's movie is stunning. It's a near future world of genetic engineering where although discrimination is illegal, perfection rules the day and the "in-valids" are passed over for high grade employment. Identity, inferiority and bigotry are fused together to offer up moral quandaries and ethical conundrums, all set to an oppressive tech-noir backdrop painted by Idziak's deft choice of colour filters. There's a striking difference between the look of the Gattaca corporation compared to the rest of the outside world, this helps to keep the thematics at work rich and potent. As a thriller it barely raises the pulse, but this is deliberate, as is the pacing by Niccol. This is an emotionally stunted world and the ethereal atmosphere hovers continually over proceedings. There's a romance in the mix between Hawke and Thurman, which on the surface seems a token sub-plot and devoid of passion, but again this feels deliberate, lack of passion is actually the order of the day. Cast performances are well up to scratch, with Law stealing the film as a one time "valid" ironically invalidated by an incident. And while we could have done with more from top performers Arkin (as a copper attired like a classical film noir gumshoe) and Elias Koteas (as Vincent's father), it rounds out as an impressively constructed picture. Provocative and brainy, with visual pleasures unbound, Gattaca has many attributes that reward still further on repeat viewings. 8/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Great film, even with the ambiguity.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Peter Hill
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I love this film, I think its one of the most thought-provoking and stylish sci-fi films of the past few decades. Rather than just repeat all the praise/comments that previous reviewers have posted, I will get straight to what struck me about this film is the retro-feel of much of it's design. This film is set in an imaginary future yet the film is as much a homage to the styles and sheens of 1950s/60s sci-fi. The elites dress like the early Beatles, everyone seems to drive Cadillacs, the detectives wear film noir hats & overcoats, even the space rockets seem to have lifted straight from a 50s sci-fi comic. As well as a thought-provoking study on what it means to be human and how limitations are often imposed by others, the film seems to be a love-letter to both classic and B-grade sci-fi, from the shiny design of 'Logan's Run' to the cheesy, lovable awfulness of 'Mars Needs Women'. Having said that, this is one of my favourite films of the 1990s. Even the few baffling parts of the film don't bother me (like they bother a friend of mine who always complains about the final scenes where Ethan Hawke is boarding the space ship- 'he's still wearing his ordinary clothes, where's the space suit? And why hasn't he done any astronaut training? And why didn't he even bother to say goodbye to Uma Thurman?'), I like films that leave you wondering and thinking.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Going against the odds to achieve something
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    omasir02
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Gattaca a space-age (futuristic) city has a research center that specializes in aerospace research that embodies specific characteristics which allow people with perfection to be employed. Only those with perfect genes have access to better jobs. But children who carry natural genes, which are designed without the help of science, are known as natural or invalid inevitably are in turn rejected, isolated, and nevertheless pushed into poverty, with a prospective for a low job ranking. Parents have to define ways of helping their children in attaining an ideal life. This is where we meet Vincent (Ethan Hawke), supposedly a natural child with less perfect genes, with big dreams of one day going to space engages the help from Jerome Morrow (Jude Law) a paralyzed former swimming star. To beat all odds, both men enable one another the opportunity to achieve something desired and stump the laws that run Gattaca. In order for Vincent to thrive in Gattaca, Jerome provides him with his biological samples, hair, urine and blood that qualify Vincent in passing the DNA test requirement. Hence Vincent then enrolls the facade of being Jerome after undergoing psychological and physical changes. Then there is Irene Cassini (Uma Thurman) a charming young woman who in spite of her perfect design suffers from heart issues and seems to be falling for Vincent but at the same time is trying to find out who he really is. One other film that has the appropriateness to the theme is Elysium which shows the determination of certain individuals embattled to reach the space paradise habitat Elysium for state-of-the-art health-care and citizenship. The scene where as children and yet again as adults, Vincent and his brother Anton (Loren Dean) are competitively swimming seems to be the motif that shows determination can help in overcoming genetic shortcomings because Vincent sees his brother Anton and society rejecting him for his imperfections. There is a high angle shot for the swimming scenario because we are able to view Vincent and his brother from an aerial view. Overall the film is brilliant with cast displaying a composed mannerism while playing their parts in a way that goes to show that each is determined to achieve their desired goals by all means possible. The actors' performance is sterling because they make their characters to be believable. The theme shows that science can be manipulated to fit the interests of the protagonist.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Gattaca (or How To Succeed In A Corrupt Scociety
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    lagondapaolini-778-957250
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Imagine a society where corruption is so rampant that all the good careers are reserved for the elite and their offspring. Now imagine a making a perfect analogy for that problem in a movie. The result is Gattaca. The main character's problem is being considered 'Less Than Perfect' by his society, and thus unfit to lead the career of his choice, and which suits his skills, because such career is reserved for those who earned the right to it by birth. Those who were 'born lucky'. It could work as a great symbol of racism, but on deeper level it actually dissects all the aspects of a corrupt society where your career is determined by your family ties (genetic composition) and not at all by your skills. The main character did not only train himself to earn the skills needed for the career he wanted, but he also done the extra effort of designing a perfect lie. Which is how to win in life if you are not born a fortunate son :) Think about it. For delivering that message in such a and beautiful and touching manner, the movie, and everyone in its cast, deserves a big Kudos.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Gattaca
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    myystery-773-599626
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Gattaca is a beautiful film. It touches on themes of discrimination, prejudice, possible dangers of technological progress and the life of those who are left behind. The film's yellow tone accompanies the melancholic nature of the film. The ending of the film is very beautiful in the way that it allows the main character to escape from hostile earth and probably achieve a good life for himself somewhere else. It's plot seems a bit contrived and unoriginal, though. Another problem is that Uma Thurman's character never manages to become important. 8 stars.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Hit and miss for me.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Sergeant_Tibbs
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Gattaca had always been one of those cult favourites which I'd never seen but was always intrigued by. It has some great science fiction concepts, which can be expected from the writer of The Truman Show, here writing and directing, but Gattaca doesn't have the emotion that Truman was able to conjure. It's a highly engrossing film yet subtle, with rich set decoration, photography, score and a devotion to detail. I really enjoyed the simple goal of the protagonist, Vincent played by Ethan Hawke, and his simple desire to go to space. How he overcame the initial obstacle of his predicted fate was fascinating, but other obstacles were convoluted and not as engaging. However, I wasn't convinced by the scenes of him socialising with Uma Thurman or Jude Law's characters as it came off as awkward or not well developed. It didn't seem like the character had a way written in him to pull off those scenes. However, I loved the sci-fi ideas of how the future can be predicted through DNA. I've always wanted to see them explored in film. The first act was the best scene, with the prologue and then the growing up montage, although it's a shame that the film's climax returned to a homage to the montage which seemed really immature with a predictable twist. There's a great short film in here somewhere, with a bit too much excess to pad it out to a feature. 7/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    This fantastic movie humbled me a lot
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    lisaofshades
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Just watch it. As a kid I wanted to become a scientist specialized in genetics... I wanted to mess with the human DNA... create monsters, but also super humans... but that movie isn't about that... merely perfecting people to make them less likely to have diseases, violent impulses and have good looks, better endurance, intelligence... perfect for a normal human... This really appeals to me... I know deep down that it's evil and Hitler like... but I always believed it was for the best and a fantastic idea... Until I saw this movie. It showed someone who was born naturally... fight against his own discarded fate... to reach his dream. He turned out to be more resourceful and a better person than a killer whose DNA would have never been suspected... surpassing even the DNA of someone who was born with the utmost perfect fate, but with a tragic accident, saw it all go down in the garbage in an instant... It shows how that values such as passion, determination and resourcefulness are forgotten but shouldn't be... that we shouldn't just assume that someone has no future, no matter how unprivileged and even handicapped his start might be... the heart and will can have a tremendous weight in the balance... and that very power, which allowed the most humble to surpass the most gifted became more powerful by being trained by the very hardship and flaws that we thought made him inferior... That movie really made me think... and help me see that the people that we dismiss have tales to tell, values that we are clueless about, wisdom that we can't even suspect... all thanks to the hardship they went through... and that's what made them better people... not a ton of money. I was born with the greatest brain, I could have done anything... I thought that I could do anything alone, but it's meaningless if no one wants to believe and hire you... meaningless if you're too sick to even move... fate isn't everything... The music, the actors, everything was perfect in this movie. It's one of the few that actually showed me that some people are even more clever and wiser than me... I really respect the creators of this movie for being able to show me why my idea of perfection was wrong so brilliantly and in an entertaining manner; but don't expect explosions all over the place... it has a sort of nostalgic pace... I just plain love this movie. I feel a sorrowful fondness every time I see the name. Jude Law said this about it (see his biography): It was the first time I felt I was making a script I believed in, and that I'd see something on screen close to what I'd hoped, rather than this vaguely confusing wilderness my jobs had been to this point. It was my first project with quality minds behind it, Jersey Films, Andrew Niccol and Ethan Hawke, who was a joy to work with. I felt we had a real meeting of the minds. (On making Gattaca (1997)). Thank you for this movie. I want more of this.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A complex and heavy duty film.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    oscar-35
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    *Spoiler/plot- Gattaca, 1997. The future world is obsessed with good genes and genetic engineering of their offspring. The world has become a Gestapo-like in it's enforcement of social strata based on tightly enforced class matters. A young man finds a way to 'pass' as someone else and upsets the social establishment for his own goals. *Special Stars- Ethan Hawke, Uma Thurman, Jude Law, Alan Arkin, Ernest Borgine. *Theme- Being yourself instead of others is the best truth. *Trivia/location/goofs- Locations: Marin County Civic Center, Sepulveda Spillway. Look for the ripped shoulder jacket seam when the policeman gets attacked and then it magically repairs itself. *Emotion- A complex and heavy duty film plot tackling some major questions of our modern era. Interesting to see and understand the lesson that the director wanted the viewer to think about after seeing this film. This is an important film theme and could be more than more can handle, but worth seeing to open you own mind on these societal issues.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not my cup of tea
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Ken Potocki
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    So, in Honors Biology, my teacher announced we we're going to watch this movie. (Since we are in the DNA unit) Teacher said: "This movie was a flop at the box office"....already I was worried. What the movie basically plays off as, is a romance-drama slash murder mystery. I do not sense an entire lot of "sci-fi" within the movie. The movie opens with an un-needed 35 minute flashback/life story of our main character. To me, I like how they based the movie around his backstory, however, it was dragged out for too long. Other than that, when the murder-mystery subplot enters the movie, to me, it lags, and doesn't keep up a fast pace, and is pretty slow moving. At certain points, Uma Thurmann even seemed like a character just added for time, it could have done without random romance scenes between her and Ethan Hawke. Towards the end, the movie offers decent twists and turns with characters, Ernest Borgnine does a solid job as the mission director (Sadly, his screen time does not amount to a lot). Overall, I was expecting more of a science fiction movie, and basically what it is, is a romance/drama. Only go into this if you're a fan of romance and/or drama movies. Sci-fi is pretty lackluster here. 5/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Slow Paced but Deep and in Touch with the Human Spirit
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    kchang511
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    First of all, I would like to state that the musical score in this film was incredible and I still remember the musical motif to this day. I believe this movie was a great story about the strength of the human spirit and how it can more than fully augment deficiencies in genetics. I don't believe the stark portrait of the future depicted in this film will actually come true, as I don't have such pessimism about the humanity of humanity. But, I believe in certain group think circumstances, it might come true. Whatever the case, I think the movie gave a great portrayal of what it is like to be deemed genetically inferior. The main character's hard work and endurance to reach his dreams gave a universal meaning and message without coming off as too corny. Also, I didn't think his plight and efforts for greatness detracted anything from the message. Often movies try too hard at pushing their universal message that the story ends up being horrible and the message ends up being overly done. This movie can help inspire all to believe in hard work and dedication while showing that the spirit is the strongest thing a human can have. The only one flaw I felt in this movie was the swimming competition with his brother. After already beating him once, beating him again was useless. They should have saved him beating his brother for the second time, having him lose the first time in his youth. This would have made it more powerful. While the swimming part was a bit corny, I couldn't think of any better way it could have been done. Finally, I believe Jerome's suicide at the end really solidified the meaning of spirit. He has felt his chance at greatness passed and has lived on through the main character, thus completing his life.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    We now have discrimination down to a science.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    JohnRouseMerriottChard
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Gattaca is written and directed by Andrew Niccol. It stars Ethan Hawke, Uma Thurman, Jude Law, Gore Vidal, Loren Dean, Xander Berkeley and Alan Arkin. Music is by Michael Nyman and cinematography by Slawomir Idziak. It's the near future and eugenics dominate a society where children are either "valids" (reproductive through eugenics) or "in-valids" (naturally birthed with inherent genetic flaws). One such "in-valid" is Vincent Anton Freeman (Hawke), who plots an intricate scheme to assume a "valid" person's identification so as to reach his dreams of being an astronaut. There is no gene for fate. Biopunk future meets tech-noir in this thought provoking and intelligent piece of sci-fi. There is a decent argument to suggest that Gattaca is more style over character substance, especially given that visually Niccol's movie is stunning. It's a near future world of genetic engineering where although discrimination is illegal, perfection rules the day and the "in-valids" are passed over for high grade employment. Identity, inferiority and bigotry are fused together to offer up moral quandaries and ethical conundrums, all set to an oppressive tech-noir backdrop painted by Idziak's deft choice of colour filters. There's a striking difference between the look of the Gattaca corporation compared to the rest of the outside world, this helps to keep the thematics at work rich and potent. As a thriller it barely raises the pulse, but this is deliberate, as is the pacing by Niccol. This is an emotionally stunted world and the ethereal atmosphere hovers continually over proceedings. There's a romance in the mix between Hawke and Thurman, which on the surface seems a token sub-plot and devoid of passion, but again this feels deliberate, lack of passion is actually the order of the day. Cast performances are well up to scratch, with Law stealing the film as a one time "valid" ironically invalidated by an incident. And while we could have done with more from top performers Arkin (as a copper attired like a classical film noir gumshoe) and Elias Koteas (as Vincent's father), it rounds out as an impressively constructed picture. Provocative and brainy, with visual pleasures unbound, Gattaca has many attributes that reward still further on repeat viewings. 8/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
 </reviews>
</filme>
