<filme>
 <id>
  273
 </id>
 <imdburl>
  http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0113277
 </imdburl>
 <ano>
  1995
 </ano>
 <titulo>
  Fogo Contra Fogo
 </titulo>
 <rating>
  8.3
 </rating>
 <sinopse>
  A group of professional bank robbers start to feel the heat from police when they unknowingly leave a clue at their latest heist.
 </sinopse>
 <storyline>
  Hunters and their prey--Neil and his professional criminal crew hunt to score big money targets (banks, vaults, armored cars) and are, in turn, hunted by Lt. Vincent Hanna and his team of cops in the Robbery/Homicide police division. A botched job puts Hanna onto their trail while they regroup and try to put together one last big 'retirement' score. Neil and Vincent are similar in many ways, including their troubled personal lives. At a crucial moment in his life, Neil disobeys the dictum taught to him long ago by his criminal mentor--'Never have anything in your life that you can't walk out on in thirty seconds flat, if you spot the heat coming around the corner'--as he falls in love. Thus the stage is set for the suspenseful ending....
 </storyline>
 <generos>
  <genero>
   Action
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Crime
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Drama
  </genero>
 </generos>
 <keywords>
  <keyword>
   bank
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   armored car
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   criminal
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   detective
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   police
  </keyword>
 </keywords>
 <diretores>
  <diretor>
   Michael Mann
  </diretor>
 </diretores>
 <escritores>
  <escritor>
   Michael Mann
  </escritor>
 </escritores>
 <atores>
  <ator>
   Al Pacino
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Robert De Niro
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Val Kilmer
  </ator>
 </atores>
 <reviews>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Proficient and Ingenious!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Govind Nair
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The movie is one of the most clever crime films ever made. It is another flick of the 'Police VS Thief' genre but is much more skilled and artistic than most of the movies of the same kind. It possesses one of the most striking concepts, which is exhibited to the viewers in the best possible manner. The movie in spite of having a long run time of 170 minutes doesn't seem to tire the audience. The movie has a slow pace at the start, but the latter part of the movie is breathtaking and intriguing. The star cast is absolutely outstanding. You can't expect a movie implicating greats like Al Pacino and Robert De Niro to let you down. Both have stood up to their standards, one playing a crucial police part and the other an adept gangster. The supporting roles played by Val Kimler, Diane Venora and Ashley Judd were slightly above average. Michael Mann, the writer and director, has done a splendid job indeed. The movie is an excellent portrayal of crime and redemption. The background score of the movie is intensified, yet extra ordinary. One hell of a movie! A collaboration involving legends.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    unforgettable
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Kris Mavericko
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    i'll say one thing about e climax scene of this film to indicate to you how powerful it was. I WATCHED THE CLIMAX FIVE TIMES. Five. In a row. and i could feel my eyes were wet. HUGE credits to e background score at that moment. michael mann reminds us that between two powerful individuals on either side of Law & Crime, there is a special BOND. and no other movie i've watched has exemplified this better than HEAT. it'll always be ranking among e top films ever in my heart & memory. now to e rest of e film. PACINO. DE NIRO. Guys, these two men literally run an acting class throughout e film, even during the breaths they take in this film & during their silences. me being an actor, i learnt an incredible lot from just this one film. there's a few lines that r memorable & quotable. Hanna's controlled rage & discipline are unmissable; McCauley's razor- sharp focus & ambition are ever-present. wonderful supporting cast. film takes its time to develop e sub-plots to let u soak it all in, in e heat of all e impending action. surely applaudable was e depth shown in e personal lives of both these professionals; and e trials they hv to put thru outside of their cat-&-mouse game. DON'T MISS.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Heat Sucks, sucks!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jessegehrig
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Eight hundred and twenty two people reviewed this movie before me, all of those people had something much much better to do. Heat was born from the idea that Pacino and DeNiro are two of this biggest tough-guys in Hollywood, although neither is over five foot ten. Some child-like emperor of a movie producer had a sad vision involving Pacino and DeNiro squaring off in a very ill-conceived action film. Val Kilmer has a bad wig, a fool cast Tom Sizemore, the script was written with a hammer and burned food, not with ink nor pen nor paper. Heat is the kind of movie thought up by some one who spends a lot of time at a gym or fitness club, which is the nice way of saying no artist or genius had any hand in crafting this wretched beast. Now, you might think,'what do we need artists and geniuses for anyways?', well without artists and geniuses you get movies like Heat, so there.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Lack of Action a Quiet Disappointing
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Fahad Mehar
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Guys. I always wanted to see this movie. I know "HEAT" movie since many years but never get chance to watch it, and many of my friends and cousins told me about this movie. It's very entertaining and action car chasing blah blah, Few days back. I downloaded "HEAT" I wanted to see a solid action movie. I downloaded this movie because of "Al Pacino" And" "Robert De Niro" Both are my favorite actors and let me tell you. I am giving 5 Starts just because of them not the movie 1st make it clear to you all. NOW come to the movie. I think I am the only one who giving the bad review of this movie. Well, I am a biggest action fan. I was expecting action from this movie but there was NONE. Well No Problem. BUT most Important part. If there is a less action then a good script covers it all. Movie PLOT was so dump No Solid story at all. Very very weak Plot. I think people like this movie just because of "Al Pacino" And" "Robert De Niro" And I don't see anything special in this movie. 2 Hours 50 minutes wasted. I don't mind there was lack of action but movie PLOT was worst.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Should have been called Baggage rather than Heat
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Cheese Hoven
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    An old piece of advice given to writers is "simplify". It is a pity such advice was not followed here, since the proliferation of subplots and other baggage (much of it irrelevant) make this film too unwieldy and long-winded for its own good. The build up to the much anticipated meeting between Pacino (Hanna) and De Niro (McCauley) sums up the film.. First Hanna is pointlessly seen in a helicopter before he is set down to follow McCauley in a car. Then Hanna has McCauley pull pver, McCauley is seen preparing to use his gun, Hanna gets out of his car, his own gun in hand, he steps up to McCauley's car and says "let's do coffee!" This was clearly meant to to an epic build up to an epic scene, but its effect is bathetic (and even pathetic).Even the meeting scene itself is mediocre, loosely written and rambling, like the film. Would there be anything notable about it if it were not Pacino and De Niro involved? The main plot is the hoary "heist goes wrong", but one of the criminal gang, Waingro, turns out to be a serial killer. He murders a prostitute in an unnecessary series of scenes, irrelevant to the main story arc since Waingro only gets his comeuppance (and not because of his serial killing) when he joins up with Van Zant (part of another sub-plot that I won't go into, although more integrated into the story). Most of the baggage here is of the emotional kind. Just about everyone has overwrought emotional scenes with their loved ones including the briefly seen black getaway driver (formerly working as a chef...the scenes of him before he makes his brief appearance as the driver had me scratching my head) and even the murdered prostitute has emotive shots of her family. Such scenes as this distract from the main narrative but there are even more anguished relationship scenes concerning the main protagonists. Neil McCauley (De Niro) has vowed to leave his woman at a drop of hat, but has apparently found 'true love'. Shiherlis (Kilmer) is a drunk gambler whose wife is leaving him until De Niro Godfather-like instructs her to stay. She has a lover who is blackmailed by the police into bringing her to them. Hanna (Pacino) has both wife and daughter problems. His wife is sleeping around while his daughter is suicidal. If all this sounds confusing, I can assure you there is much more and the film takes us down every one of these blind alleys one at a time. Despite the film lingering so lovingly on irrelevancies, important issues remain unresolved. Why, for instance, at the end does Hanna (the cop) take a fire arm from another policeman but not tell him to help him catch McCauley? This sets up an implausible and not very good, one on one shoot out and the unconvincing 'brothers in arms' handshake between the two as if Hanna had forgotten all those that McCauley (including cops) has murdered in cold blood. Likewise the relationships are left hanging at the end. What happens to Shiherlis and indeed his wife? Do they sail off into the sunset together? Not likely considering she is sleeping with someone else. And what about Hanna, his wife and their daughter? Nothing is resolved. The general look of the film is good but some shots are chosen more for their 'coolness' than their purpose. The action scenes are gory, perhaps unnecessarily so. The shoot-out, using sub machine guns, is overblown and unconvincing, and very Hollywoodian, including Hanna's "threading the eye of a needle" shot to kill one of the gang holding a child hostage. A note on performances. They tend to be rather overwrought at all times, with the cast being aware they are in an 'important' picture. Mumbling and histrionics are the order of the day. Pacino, in particular, delivers an over-the-top performance, often shouting his lines in a psychotic way that genuinely seems to surprise his fellow actors. If this was how Hanna was in real life, he would probably be under heavy sedation or psychiatric care. There is just about enough good stuff amid the padding to make this watchable. But only just.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Michael Mann's Masterpiece
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Hotwok2013
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I think it's fair to say that Robert De Niro & Al Pacino are not two of the greatest film actors of their generation, they ARE the best two actors. Making a movie that lives up to their talent was never going to be easy but Michael Mann's "HEAT" succeeds brilliantly. Led by De Niro, a crack team of professional thieves & bank robbers have carried out a number of unsolved crimes & detectives led by Pacino are determined to bring down the "crew" responsible. Along the way, Pacino's obsession for his job is causing his marriage to break down. Likewise, De Niro has fallen in love with a young lady causing him to forget the maxim taught him by his criminal mentor, "Never have anything in your life that you cannot walk away from in thirty seconds flat if you feel the heat coming round the corner". When the two adversaries finally meet over a cup of coffee in a cafe it is a spellbinding moment. Pacino coolly warns De Niro that he intends to take him & his gang down. De Niro responds by telling Pacino that if he gets in his way he will have no hesitation in killing him. Besides the two main men, there are many other great acting performances in a film which studies not only the crimes but characterisations of its participants. The final chase scenes between the two main protagonists is electrifyingly tense & "HEAT" is just a fabulous movie!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Best Action movie of all time
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    alienjm
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    We have a great masterpiece. Mann I am charmed with Michael, he make movies that are excellent.Heat and The last of the Mohican's are the best works that Michael Mann has done. Infected with striking and unforgettable scenes like the scene of the shootout in the Street, the best action scene in cinema history, or the face-to-face one between Pacino and Of Niro. This movie is completely loaded of action through, supports his plaster to the sofa and does not leave you to go until the end. You cannot leave her, it is necessary to see her until the end and the ending is awesome. A timeless classic action movie and of course it is my fourth favorite film of all time.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Spine-chilling
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    davigar1003
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It's a film that leaves you with chills in the body, so intense is unusual. Leave a bitter taste because you want the bad win the battle, but know that what happened is what was just and right. The film does a great realism in every scene. Full of expectations every second that makes you can not stop trying to guess what's coming. Valor, betrayal, courage and selflessness involved in a host of challenges to meet. Nobody like Michael Mann so beautifully exposes the individual lives of the characters to create this work of art, recreating with certainty the role of villain and defender of the law, accepted by each of the protagonist as their way of life ... and die!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A slick, polished thriller
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    RyanCShowers
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Movie fans and film snobs already acclaim Robert DeNiro and Al Pacino as two of the best actors in the history of entertainment. From the past experience of putting them in the same movie, The Godfather Part II, magic is bound to spark. While Heat isn't quite what one would assume it to be, it succeeds at being a mature, emotional experience that defines itself at the top of the action genre for years to come. Robert DeNiro has a beef with politicians during elections: they tear their opponents down and sacrifice their dignity instead of trying to prove themselves to the American people. Heat is an action thriller with dignity. While other action movies are concerned with what neat stunts can they throw at the audience, Heat internally speaks to the viewer as well as bringing well choreographed action scenes. Director Michael Mann, makes Heat more personal than most action thrillers. In fact, Mann doesn't tell the story as if it were a action movie at all. He tells a story centering in on the lives of two men who are connected by a few pieces of action. Mann delivers the film with a tense feeling, and establishes a gloomy tone. The engrossing score is cautiously placed the in the correct places. Heat succeeds technically, as well; the sound quality that adds to the excitement of the action scenes. The suspense is successful because Mann creates the film's tension sensitively. All the action and suspense is met perfectly because of the tender touch of Michael Mann. DeNiro and Pacino lead the adept cast creating one heck of an acting ensemble. Al Pacino has moments of greatness, but those are contrasted with some cringe-inducing moments. His highs are pretty high though and make up for the brief moments of instability. DeNiro, playing the darker character, is solid and consistent from his first scene to the last, giving him DeNiro the slight edge over Pacino. Both are great actors doing great work. Like their first appearance together, The Godfather Part II, they each lead their own section of the film, but in Heat they come into one-on-one contact half-way through the movie. It's a rare scene when the cop and the bad guy sit down for conversation and coffee. "Don't let yourself get attached to anything you are not willing to walk out on in thirty seconds flat if you the heat around the corner," is a line said by Robert DeNiro's character that resonates a lot of what the film is about. Heat is a slick polished thriller that holds carefully plotted action scenes while packing a powerful punch in the topics of abandonment, life, and admiration. The last scene's poignancy solidifies Heat as a movie to remember. Rating: 8/10 Grade: A-
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of the very great films.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ffreemon
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Real life does not divide all humans into good guys and bad guys and neither does this movie. The cops are a fellowship of dedicated men led by a loser who is so determined to perfect his craft that he has destroyed his three marriages. He has no friends and the only person he does not shout at is the head of the robbers. The gang of robbers are all individuals. They are honest with each other but do not hesitate to murder a guard who saw too much. So who are the good guys and the bad guys? There is a set of characters who are REALLY bad. The women are all individuals with their own hopes and lives. None are cops. One wonders if the fellowship of the homicide squad would have deteriorated if one of their numbers had been a woman. Do not miss this film. I recommend you see it twice, the second time you can appreciate the characters and the events without worrying about what happens next.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Proficient and Ingenious!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Govind Nair
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The movie is one of the most clever crime films ever made. It is another flick of the 'Police VS Thief' genre but is much more skilled and artistic than most of the movies of the same kind. It possesses one of the most striking concepts, which is exhibited to the viewers in the best possible manner. The movie in spite of having a long run time of 170 minutes doesn't seem to tire the audience. The movie has a slow pace at the start, but the latter part of the movie is breathtaking and intriguing. The star cast is absolutely outstanding. You can't expect a movie implicating greats like Al Pacino and Robert De Niro to let you down. Both have stood up to their standards, one playing a crucial police part and the other an adept gangster. The supporting roles played by Val Kimler, Diane Venora and Ashley Judd were slightly above average. Michael Mann, the writer and director, has done a splendid job indeed. The movie is an excellent portrayal of crime and redemption. The background score of the movie is intensified, yet extra ordinary. One hell of a movie! A collaboration involving legends.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    unforgettable
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Kris Mavericko
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    i'll say one thing about e climax scene of this film to indicate to you how powerful it was. I WATCHED THE CLIMAX FIVE TIMES. Five. In a row. and i could feel my eyes were wet. HUGE credits to e background score at that moment. michael mann reminds us that between two powerful individuals on either side of Law & Crime, there is a special BOND. and no other movie i've watched has exemplified this better than HEAT. it'll always be ranking among e top films ever in my heart & memory. now to e rest of e film. PACINO. DE NIRO. Guys, these two men literally run an acting class throughout e film, even during the breaths they take in this film & during their silences. me being an actor, i learnt an incredible lot from just this one film. there's a few lines that r memorable & quotable. Hanna's controlled rage & discipline are unmissable; McCauley's razor- sharp focus & ambition are ever-present. wonderful supporting cast. film takes its time to develop e sub-plots to let u soak it all in, in e heat of all e impending action. surely applaudable was e depth shown in e personal lives of both these professionals; and e trials they hv to put thru outside of their cat-&-mouse game. DON'T MISS.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Heat Sucks, sucks!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jessegehrig
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Eight hundred and twenty two people reviewed this movie before me, all of those people had something much much better to do. Heat was born from the idea that Pacino and DeNiro are two of this biggest tough-guys in Hollywood, although neither is over five foot ten. Some child-like emperor of a movie producer had a sad vision involving Pacino and DeNiro squaring off in a very ill-conceived action film. Val Kilmer has a bad wig, a fool cast Tom Sizemore, the script was written with a hammer and burned food, not with ink nor pen nor paper. Heat is the kind of movie thought up by some one who spends a lot of time at a gym or fitness club, which is the nice way of saying no artist or genius had any hand in crafting this wretched beast. Now, you might think,'what do we need artists and geniuses for anyways?', well without artists and geniuses you get movies like Heat, so there.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Lack of Action a Quiet Disappointing
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Fahad Mehar
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Guys. I always wanted to see this movie. I know "HEAT" movie since many years but never get chance to watch it, and many of my friends and cousins told me about this movie. It's very entertaining and action car chasing blah blah, Few days back. I downloaded "HEAT" I wanted to see a solid action movie. I downloaded this movie because of "Al Pacino" And" "Robert De Niro" Both are my favorite actors and let me tell you. I am giving 5 Starts just because of them not the movie 1st make it clear to you all. NOW come to the movie. I think I am the only one who giving the bad review of this movie. Well, I am a biggest action fan. I was expecting action from this movie but there was NONE. Well No Problem. BUT most Important part. If there is a less action then a good script covers it all. Movie PLOT was so dump No Solid story at all. Very very weak Plot. I think people like this movie just because of "Al Pacino" And" "Robert De Niro" And I don't see anything special in this movie. 2 Hours 50 minutes wasted. I don't mind there was lack of action but movie PLOT was worst.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Should have been called Baggage rather than Heat
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Cheese Hoven
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    An old piece of advice given to writers is "simplify". It is a pity such advice was not followed here, since the proliferation of subplots and other baggage (much of it irrelevant) make this film too unwieldy and long-winded for its own good. The build up to the much anticipated meeting between Pacino (Hanna) and De Niro (McCauley) sums up the film.. First Hanna is pointlessly seen in a helicopter before he is set down to follow McCauley in a car. Then Hanna has McCauley pull pver, McCauley is seen preparing to use his gun, Hanna gets out of his car, his own gun in hand, he steps up to McCauley's car and says "let's do coffee!" This was clearly meant to to an epic build up to an epic scene, but its effect is bathetic (and even pathetic).Even the meeting scene itself is mediocre, loosely written and rambling, like the film. Would there be anything notable about it if it were not Pacino and De Niro involved? The main plot is the hoary "heist goes wrong", but one of the criminal gang, Waingro, turns out to be a serial killer. He murders a prostitute in an unnecessary series of scenes, irrelevant to the main story arc since Waingro only gets his comeuppance (and not because of his serial killing) when he joins up with Van Zant (part of another sub-plot that I won't go into, although more integrated into the story). Most of the baggage here is of the emotional kind. Just about everyone has overwrought emotional scenes with their loved ones including the briefly seen black getaway driver (formerly working as a chef...the scenes of him before he makes his brief appearance as the driver had me scratching my head) and even the murdered prostitute has emotive shots of her family. Such scenes as this distract from the main narrative but there are even more anguished relationship scenes concerning the main protagonists. Neil McCauley (De Niro) has vowed to leave his woman at a drop of hat, but has apparently found 'true love'. Shiherlis (Kilmer) is a drunk gambler whose wife is leaving him until De Niro Godfather-like instructs her to stay. She has a lover who is blackmailed by the police into bringing her to them. Hanna (Pacino) has both wife and daughter problems. His wife is sleeping around while his daughter is suicidal. If all this sounds confusing, I can assure you there is much more and the film takes us down every one of these blind alleys one at a time. Despite the film lingering so lovingly on irrelevancies, important issues remain unresolved. Why, for instance, at the end does Hanna (the cop) take a fire arm from another policeman but not tell him to help him catch McCauley? This sets up an implausible and not very good, one on one shoot out and the unconvincing 'brothers in arms' handshake between the two as if Hanna had forgotten all those that McCauley (including cops) has murdered in cold blood. Likewise the relationships are left hanging at the end. What happens to Shiherlis and indeed his wife? Do they sail off into the sunset together? Not likely considering she is sleeping with someone else. And what about Hanna, his wife and their daughter? Nothing is resolved. The general look of the film is good but some shots are chosen more for their 'coolness' than their purpose. The action scenes are gory, perhaps unnecessarily so. The shoot-out, using sub machine guns, is overblown and unconvincing, and very Hollywoodian, including Hanna's "threading the eye of a needle" shot to kill one of the gang holding a child hostage. A note on performances. They tend to be rather overwrought at all times, with the cast being aware they are in an 'important' picture. Mumbling and histrionics are the order of the day. Pacino, in particular, delivers an over-the-top performance, often shouting his lines in a psychotic way that genuinely seems to surprise his fellow actors. If this was how Hanna was in real life, he would probably be under heavy sedation or psychiatric care. There is just about enough good stuff amid the padding to make this watchable. But only just.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Michael Mann's Masterpiece
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Hotwok2013
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I think it's fair to say that Robert De Niro & Al Pacino are not two of the greatest film actors of their generation, they ARE the best two actors. Making a movie that lives up to their talent was never going to be easy but Michael Mann's "HEAT" succeeds brilliantly. Led by De Niro, a crack team of professional thieves & bank robbers have carried out a number of unsolved crimes & detectives led by Pacino are determined to bring down the "crew" responsible. Along the way, Pacino's obsession for his job is causing his marriage to break down. Likewise, De Niro has fallen in love with a young lady causing him to forget the maxim taught him by his criminal mentor, "Never have anything in your life that you cannot walk away from in thirty seconds flat if you feel the heat coming round the corner". When the two adversaries finally meet over a cup of coffee in a cafe it is a spellbinding moment. Pacino coolly warns De Niro that he intends to take him & his gang down. De Niro responds by telling Pacino that if he gets in his way he will have no hesitation in killing him. Besides the two main men, there are many other great acting performances in a film which studies not only the crimes but characterisations of its participants. The final chase scenes between the two main protagonists is electrifyingly tense & "HEAT" is just a fabulous movie!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Best Action movie of all time
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    alienjm
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    We have a great masterpiece. Mann I am charmed with Michael, he make movies that are excellent.Heat and The last of the Mohican's are the best works that Michael Mann has done. Infected with striking and unforgettable scenes like the scene of the shootout in the Street, the best action scene in cinema history, or the face-to-face one between Pacino and Of Niro. This movie is completely loaded of action through, supports his plaster to the sofa and does not leave you to go until the end. You cannot leave her, it is necessary to see her until the end and the ending is awesome. A timeless classic action movie and of course it is my fourth favorite film of all time.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Spine-chilling
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    davigar1003
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It's a film that leaves you with chills in the body, so intense is unusual. Leave a bitter taste because you want the bad win the battle, but know that what happened is what was just and right. The film does a great realism in every scene. Full of expectations every second that makes you can not stop trying to guess what's coming. Valor, betrayal, courage and selflessness involved in a host of challenges to meet. Nobody like Michael Mann so beautifully exposes the individual lives of the characters to create this work of art, recreating with certainty the role of villain and defender of the law, accepted by each of the protagonist as their way of life ... and die!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A slick, polished thriller
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    RyanCShowers
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Movie fans and film snobs already acclaim Robert DeNiro and Al Pacino as two of the best actors in the history of entertainment. From the past experience of putting them in the same movie, The Godfather Part II, magic is bound to spark. While Heat isn't quite what one would assume it to be, it succeeds at being a mature, emotional experience that defines itself at the top of the action genre for years to come. Robert DeNiro has a beef with politicians during elections: they tear their opponents down and sacrifice their dignity instead of trying to prove themselves to the American people. Heat is an action thriller with dignity. While other action movies are concerned with what neat stunts can they throw at the audience, Heat internally speaks to the viewer as well as bringing well choreographed action scenes. Director Michael Mann, makes Heat more personal than most action thrillers. In fact, Mann doesn't tell the story as if it were a action movie at all. He tells a story centering in on the lives of two men who are connected by a few pieces of action. Mann delivers the film with a tense feeling, and establishes a gloomy tone. The engrossing score is cautiously placed the in the correct places. Heat succeeds technically, as well; the sound quality that adds to the excitement of the action scenes. The suspense is successful because Mann creates the film's tension sensitively. All the action and suspense is met perfectly because of the tender touch of Michael Mann. DeNiro and Pacino lead the adept cast creating one heck of an acting ensemble. Al Pacino has moments of greatness, but those are contrasted with some cringe-inducing moments. His highs are pretty high though and make up for the brief moments of instability. DeNiro, playing the darker character, is solid and consistent from his first scene to the last, giving him DeNiro the slight edge over Pacino. Both are great actors doing great work. Like their first appearance together, The Godfather Part II, they each lead their own section of the film, but in Heat they come into one-on-one contact half-way through the movie. It's a rare scene when the cop and the bad guy sit down for conversation and coffee. "Don't let yourself get attached to anything you are not willing to walk out on in thirty seconds flat if you the heat around the corner," is a line said by Robert DeNiro's character that resonates a lot of what the film is about. Heat is a slick polished thriller that holds carefully plotted action scenes while packing a powerful punch in the topics of abandonment, life, and admiration. The last scene's poignancy solidifies Heat as a movie to remember. Rating: 8/10 Grade: A-
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of the very great films.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ffreemon
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Real life does not divide all humans into good guys and bad guys and neither does this movie. The cops are a fellowship of dedicated men led by a loser who is so determined to perfect his craft that he has destroyed his three marriages. He has no friends and the only person he does not shout at is the head of the robbers. The gang of robbers are all individuals. They are honest with each other but do not hesitate to murder a guard who saw too much. So who are the good guys and the bad guys? There is a set of characters who are REALLY bad. The women are all individuals with their own hopes and lives. None are cops. One wonders if the fellowship of the homicide squad would have deteriorated if one of their numbers had been a woman. Do not miss this film. I recommend you see it twice, the second time you can appreciate the characters and the events without worrying about what happens next.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Proficient and Ingenious!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Govind Nair
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The movie is one of the most clever crime films ever made. It is another flick of the 'Police VS Thief' genre but is much more skilled and artistic than most of the movies of the same kind. It possesses one of the most striking concepts, which is exhibited to the viewers in the best possible manner. The movie in spite of having a long run time of 170 minutes doesn't seem to tire the audience. The movie has a slow pace at the start, but the latter part of the movie is breathtaking and intriguing. The star cast is absolutely outstanding. You can't expect a movie implicating greats like Al Pacino and Robert De Niro to let you down. Both have stood up to their standards, one playing a crucial police part and the other an adept gangster. The supporting roles played by Val Kimler, Diane Venora and Ashley Judd were slightly above average. Michael Mann, the writer and director, has done a splendid job indeed. The movie is an excellent portrayal of crime and redemption. The background score of the movie is intensified, yet extra ordinary. One hell of a movie! A collaboration involving legends.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    unforgettable
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Kris Mavericko
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    i'll say one thing about e climax scene of this film to indicate to you how powerful it was. I WATCHED THE CLIMAX FIVE TIMES. Five. In a row. and i could feel my eyes were wet. HUGE credits to e background score at that moment. michael mann reminds us that between two powerful individuals on either side of Law & Crime, there is a special BOND. and no other movie i've watched has exemplified this better than HEAT. it'll always be ranking among e top films ever in my heart & memory. now to e rest of e film. PACINO. DE NIRO. Guys, these two men literally run an acting class throughout e film, even during the breaths they take in this film & during their silences. me being an actor, i learnt an incredible lot from just this one film. there's a few lines that r memorable & quotable. Hanna's controlled rage & discipline are unmissable; McCauley's razor- sharp focus & ambition are ever-present. wonderful supporting cast. film takes its time to develop e sub-plots to let u soak it all in, in e heat of all e impending action. surely applaudable was e depth shown in e personal lives of both these professionals; and e trials they hv to put thru outside of their cat-&-mouse game. DON'T MISS.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Heat Sucks, sucks!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jessegehrig
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Eight hundred and twenty two people reviewed this movie before me, all of those people had something much much better to do. Heat was born from the idea that Pacino and DeNiro are two of this biggest tough-guys in Hollywood, although neither is over five foot ten. Some child-like emperor of a movie producer had a sad vision involving Pacino and DeNiro squaring off in a very ill-conceived action film. Val Kilmer has a bad wig, a fool cast Tom Sizemore, the script was written with a hammer and burned food, not with ink nor pen nor paper. Heat is the kind of movie thought up by some one who spends a lot of time at a gym or fitness club, which is the nice way of saying no artist or genius had any hand in crafting this wretched beast. Now, you might think,'what do we need artists and geniuses for anyways?', well without artists and geniuses you get movies like Heat, so there.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Lack of Action a Quiet Disappointing
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Fahad Mehar
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Guys. I always wanted to see this movie. I know "HEAT" movie since many years but never get chance to watch it, and many of my friends and cousins told me about this movie. It's very entertaining and action car chasing blah blah, Few days back. I downloaded "HEAT" I wanted to see a solid action movie. I downloaded this movie because of "Al Pacino" And" "Robert De Niro" Both are my favorite actors and let me tell you. I am giving 5 Starts just because of them not the movie 1st make it clear to you all. NOW come to the movie. I think I am the only one who giving the bad review of this movie. Well, I am a biggest action fan. I was expecting action from this movie but there was NONE. Well No Problem. BUT most Important part. If there is a less action then a good script covers it all. Movie PLOT was so dump No Solid story at all. Very very weak Plot. I think people like this movie just because of "Al Pacino" And" "Robert De Niro" And I don't see anything special in this movie. 2 Hours 50 minutes wasted. I don't mind there was lack of action but movie PLOT was worst.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Should have been called Baggage rather than Heat
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Cheese Hoven
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    An old piece of advice given to writers is "simplify". It is a pity such advice was not followed here, since the proliferation of subplots and other baggage (much of it irrelevant) make this film too unwieldy and long-winded for its own good. The build up to the much anticipated meeting between Pacino (Hanna) and De Niro (McCauley) sums up the film.. First Hanna is pointlessly seen in a helicopter before he is set down to follow McCauley in a car. Then Hanna has McCauley pull pver, McCauley is seen preparing to use his gun, Hanna gets out of his car, his own gun in hand, he steps up to McCauley's car and says "let's do coffee!" This was clearly meant to to an epic build up to an epic scene, but its effect is bathetic (and even pathetic).Even the meeting scene itself is mediocre, loosely written and rambling, like the film. Would there be anything notable about it if it were not Pacino and De Niro involved? The main plot is the hoary "heist goes wrong", but one of the criminal gang, Waingro, turns out to be a serial killer. He murders a prostitute in an unnecessary series of scenes, irrelevant to the main story arc since Waingro only gets his comeuppance (and not because of his serial killing) when he joins up with Van Zant (part of another sub-plot that I won't go into, although more integrated into the story). Most of the baggage here is of the emotional kind. Just about everyone has overwrought emotional scenes with their loved ones including the briefly seen black getaway driver (formerly working as a chef...the scenes of him before he makes his brief appearance as the driver had me scratching my head) and even the murdered prostitute has emotive shots of her family. Such scenes as this distract from the main narrative but there are even more anguished relationship scenes concerning the main protagonists. Neil McCauley (De Niro) has vowed to leave his woman at a drop of hat, but has apparently found 'true love'. Shiherlis (Kilmer) is a drunk gambler whose wife is leaving him until De Niro Godfather-like instructs her to stay. She has a lover who is blackmailed by the police into bringing her to them. Hanna (Pacino) has both wife and daughter problems. His wife is sleeping around while his daughter is suicidal. If all this sounds confusing, I can assure you there is much more and the film takes us down every one of these blind alleys one at a time. Despite the film lingering so lovingly on irrelevancies, important issues remain unresolved. Why, for instance, at the end does Hanna (the cop) take a fire arm from another policeman but not tell him to help him catch McCauley? This sets up an implausible and not very good, one on one shoot out and the unconvincing 'brothers in arms' handshake between the two as if Hanna had forgotten all those that McCauley (including cops) has murdered in cold blood. Likewise the relationships are left hanging at the end. What happens to Shiherlis and indeed his wife? Do they sail off into the sunset together? Not likely considering she is sleeping with someone else. And what about Hanna, his wife and their daughter? Nothing is resolved. The general look of the film is good but some shots are chosen more for their 'coolness' than their purpose. The action scenes are gory, perhaps unnecessarily so. The shoot-out, using sub machine guns, is overblown and unconvincing, and very Hollywoodian, including Hanna's "threading the eye of a needle" shot to kill one of the gang holding a child hostage. A note on performances. They tend to be rather overwrought at all times, with the cast being aware they are in an 'important' picture. Mumbling and histrionics are the order of the day. Pacino, in particular, delivers an over-the-top performance, often shouting his lines in a psychotic way that genuinely seems to surprise his fellow actors. If this was how Hanna was in real life, he would probably be under heavy sedation or psychiatric care. There is just about enough good stuff amid the padding to make this watchable. But only just.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Michael Mann's Masterpiece
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Hotwok2013
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I think it's fair to say that Robert De Niro & Al Pacino are not two of the greatest film actors of their generation, they ARE the best two actors. Making a movie that lives up to their talent was never going to be easy but Michael Mann's "HEAT" succeeds brilliantly. Led by De Niro, a crack team of professional thieves & bank robbers have carried out a number of unsolved crimes & detectives led by Pacino are determined to bring down the "crew" responsible. Along the way, Pacino's obsession for his job is causing his marriage to break down. Likewise, De Niro has fallen in love with a young lady causing him to forget the maxim taught him by his criminal mentor, "Never have anything in your life that you cannot walk away from in thirty seconds flat if you feel the heat coming round the corner". When the two adversaries finally meet over a cup of coffee in a cafe it is a spellbinding moment. Pacino coolly warns De Niro that he intends to take him & his gang down. De Niro responds by telling Pacino that if he gets in his way he will have no hesitation in killing him. Besides the two main men, there are many other great acting performances in a film which studies not only the crimes but characterisations of its participants. The final chase scenes between the two main protagonists is electrifyingly tense & "HEAT" is just a fabulous movie!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Best Action movie of all time
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    alienjm
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    We have a great masterpiece. Mann I am charmed with Michael, he make movies that are excellent.Heat and The last of the Mohican's are the best works that Michael Mann has done. Infected with striking and unforgettable scenes like the scene of the shootout in the Street, the best action scene in cinema history, or the face-to-face one between Pacino and Of Niro. This movie is completely loaded of action through, supports his plaster to the sofa and does not leave you to go until the end. You cannot leave her, it is necessary to see her until the end and the ending is awesome. A timeless classic action movie and of course it is my fourth favorite film of all time.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Spine-chilling
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    davigar1003
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It's a film that leaves you with chills in the body, so intense is unusual. Leave a bitter taste because you want the bad win the battle, but know that what happened is what was just and right. The film does a great realism in every scene. Full of expectations every second that makes you can not stop trying to guess what's coming. Valor, betrayal, courage and selflessness involved in a host of challenges to meet. Nobody like Michael Mann so beautifully exposes the individual lives of the characters to create this work of art, recreating with certainty the role of villain and defender of the law, accepted by each of the protagonist as their way of life ... and die!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A slick, polished thriller
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    RyanCShowers
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Movie fans and film snobs already acclaim Robert DeNiro and Al Pacino as two of the best actors in the history of entertainment. From the past experience of putting them in the same movie, The Godfather Part II, magic is bound to spark. While Heat isn't quite what one would assume it to be, it succeeds at being a mature, emotional experience that defines itself at the top of the action genre for years to come. Robert DeNiro has a beef with politicians during elections: they tear their opponents down and sacrifice their dignity instead of trying to prove themselves to the American people. Heat is an action thriller with dignity. While other action movies are concerned with what neat stunts can they throw at the audience, Heat internally speaks to the viewer as well as bringing well choreographed action scenes. Director Michael Mann, makes Heat more personal than most action thrillers. In fact, Mann doesn't tell the story as if it were a action movie at all. He tells a story centering in on the lives of two men who are connected by a few pieces of action. Mann delivers the film with a tense feeling, and establishes a gloomy tone. The engrossing score is cautiously placed the in the correct places. Heat succeeds technically, as well; the sound quality that adds to the excitement of the action scenes. The suspense is successful because Mann creates the film's tension sensitively. All the action and suspense is met perfectly because of the tender touch of Michael Mann. DeNiro and Pacino lead the adept cast creating one heck of an acting ensemble. Al Pacino has moments of greatness, but those are contrasted with some cringe-inducing moments. His highs are pretty high though and make up for the brief moments of instability. DeNiro, playing the darker character, is solid and consistent from his first scene to the last, giving him DeNiro the slight edge over Pacino. Both are great actors doing great work. Like their first appearance together, The Godfather Part II, they each lead their own section of the film, but in Heat they come into one-on-one contact half-way through the movie. It's a rare scene when the cop and the bad guy sit down for conversation and coffee. "Don't let yourself get attached to anything you are not willing to walk out on in thirty seconds flat if you the heat around the corner," is a line said by Robert DeNiro's character that resonates a lot of what the film is about. Heat is a slick polished thriller that holds carefully plotted action scenes while packing a powerful punch in the topics of abandonment, life, and admiration. The last scene's poignancy solidifies Heat as a movie to remember. Rating: 8/10 Grade: A-
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of the very great films.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ffreemon
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Real life does not divide all humans into good guys and bad guys and neither does this movie. The cops are a fellowship of dedicated men led by a loser who is so determined to perfect his craft that he has destroyed his three marriages. He has no friends and the only person he does not shout at is the head of the robbers. The gang of robbers are all individuals. They are honest with each other but do not hesitate to murder a guard who saw too much. So who are the good guys and the bad guys? There is a set of characters who are REALLY bad. The women are all individuals with their own hopes and lives. None are cops. One wonders if the fellowship of the homicide squad would have deteriorated if one of their numbers had been a woman. Do not miss this film. I recommend you see it twice, the second time you can appreciate the characters and the events without worrying about what happens next.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Proficient and Ingenious!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Govind Nair
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The movie is one of the most clever crime films ever made. It is another flick of the 'Police VS Thief' genre but is much more skilled and artistic than most of the movies of the same kind. It possesses one of the most striking concepts, which is exhibited to the viewers in the best possible manner. The movie in spite of having a long run time of 170 minutes doesn't seem to tire the audience. The movie has a slow pace at the start, but the latter part of the movie is breathtaking and intriguing. The star cast is absolutely outstanding. You can't expect a movie implicating greats like Al Pacino and Robert De Niro to let you down. Both have stood up to their standards, one playing a crucial police part and the other an adept gangster. The supporting roles played by Val Kimler, Diane Venora and Ashley Judd were slightly above average. Michael Mann, the writer and director, has done a splendid job indeed. The movie is an excellent portrayal of crime and redemption. The background score of the movie is intensified, yet extra ordinary. One hell of a movie! A collaboration involving legends.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    unforgettable
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Kris Mavericko
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    i'll say one thing about e climax scene of this film to indicate to you how powerful it was. I WATCHED THE CLIMAX FIVE TIMES. Five. In a row. and i could feel my eyes were wet. HUGE credits to e background score at that moment. michael mann reminds us that between two powerful individuals on either side of Law & Crime, there is a special BOND. and no other movie i've watched has exemplified this better than HEAT. it'll always be ranking among e top films ever in my heart & memory. now to e rest of e film. PACINO. DE NIRO. Guys, these two men literally run an acting class throughout e film, even during the breaths they take in this film & during their silences. me being an actor, i learnt an incredible lot from just this one film. there's a few lines that r memorable & quotable. Hanna's controlled rage & discipline are unmissable; McCauley's razor- sharp focus & ambition are ever-present. wonderful supporting cast. film takes its time to develop e sub-plots to let u soak it all in, in e heat of all e impending action. surely applaudable was e depth shown in e personal lives of both these professionals; and e trials they hv to put thru outside of their cat-&-mouse game. DON'T MISS.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Heat Sucks, sucks!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jessegehrig
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Eight hundred and twenty two people reviewed this movie before me, all of those people had something much much better to do. Heat was born from the idea that Pacino and DeNiro are two of this biggest tough-guys in Hollywood, although neither is over five foot ten. Some child-like emperor of a movie producer had a sad vision involving Pacino and DeNiro squaring off in a very ill-conceived action film. Val Kilmer has a bad wig, a fool cast Tom Sizemore, the script was written with a hammer and burned food, not with ink nor pen nor paper. Heat is the kind of movie thought up by some one who spends a lot of time at a gym or fitness club, which is the nice way of saying no artist or genius had any hand in crafting this wretched beast. Now, you might think,'what do we need artists and geniuses for anyways?', well without artists and geniuses you get movies like Heat, so there.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Lack of Action a Quiet Disappointing
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Fahad Mehar
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Guys. I always wanted to see this movie. I know "HEAT" movie since many years but never get chance to watch it, and many of my friends and cousins told me about this movie. It's very entertaining and action car chasing blah blah, Few days back. I downloaded "HEAT" I wanted to see a solid action movie. I downloaded this movie because of "Al Pacino" And" "Robert De Niro" Both are my favorite actors and let me tell you. I am giving 5 Starts just because of them not the movie 1st make it clear to you all. NOW come to the movie. I think I am the only one who giving the bad review of this movie. Well, I am a biggest action fan. I was expecting action from this movie but there was NONE. Well No Problem. BUT most Important part. If there is a less action then a good script covers it all. Movie PLOT was so dump No Solid story at all. Very very weak Plot. I think people like this movie just because of "Al Pacino" And" "Robert De Niro" And I don't see anything special in this movie. 2 Hours 50 minutes wasted. I don't mind there was lack of action but movie PLOT was worst.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Should have been called Baggage rather than Heat
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Cheese Hoven
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    An old piece of advice given to writers is "simplify". It is a pity such advice was not followed here, since the proliferation of subplots and other baggage (much of it irrelevant) make this film too unwieldy and long-winded for its own good. The build up to the much anticipated meeting between Pacino (Hanna) and De Niro (McCauley) sums up the film.. First Hanna is pointlessly seen in a helicopter before he is set down to follow McCauley in a car. Then Hanna has McCauley pull pver, McCauley is seen preparing to use his gun, Hanna gets out of his car, his own gun in hand, he steps up to McCauley's car and says "let's do coffee!" This was clearly meant to to an epic build up to an epic scene, but its effect is bathetic (and even pathetic).Even the meeting scene itself is mediocre, loosely written and rambling, like the film. Would there be anything notable about it if it were not Pacino and De Niro involved? The main plot is the hoary "heist goes wrong", but one of the criminal gang, Waingro, turns out to be a serial killer. He murders a prostitute in an unnecessary series of scenes, irrelevant to the main story arc since Waingro only gets his comeuppance (and not because of his serial killing) when he joins up with Van Zant (part of another sub-plot that I won't go into, although more integrated into the story). Most of the baggage here is of the emotional kind. Just about everyone has overwrought emotional scenes with their loved ones including the briefly seen black getaway driver (formerly working as a chef...the scenes of him before he makes his brief appearance as the driver had me scratching my head) and even the murdered prostitute has emotive shots of her family. Such scenes as this distract from the main narrative but there are even more anguished relationship scenes concerning the main protagonists. Neil McCauley (De Niro) has vowed to leave his woman at a drop of hat, but has apparently found 'true love'. Shiherlis (Kilmer) is a drunk gambler whose wife is leaving him until De Niro Godfather-like instructs her to stay. She has a lover who is blackmailed by the police into bringing her to them. Hanna (Pacino) has both wife and daughter problems. His wife is sleeping around while his daughter is suicidal. If all this sounds confusing, I can assure you there is much more and the film takes us down every one of these blind alleys one at a time. Despite the film lingering so lovingly on irrelevancies, important issues remain unresolved. Why, for instance, at the end does Hanna (the cop) take a fire arm from another policeman but not tell him to help him catch McCauley? This sets up an implausible and not very good, one on one shoot out and the unconvincing 'brothers in arms' handshake between the two as if Hanna had forgotten all those that McCauley (including cops) has murdered in cold blood. Likewise the relationships are left hanging at the end. What happens to Shiherlis and indeed his wife? Do they sail off into the sunset together? Not likely considering she is sleeping with someone else. And what about Hanna, his wife and their daughter? Nothing is resolved. The general look of the film is good but some shots are chosen more for their 'coolness' than their purpose. The action scenes are gory, perhaps unnecessarily so. The shoot-out, using sub machine guns, is overblown and unconvincing, and very Hollywoodian, including Hanna's "threading the eye of a needle" shot to kill one of the gang holding a child hostage. A note on performances. They tend to be rather overwrought at all times, with the cast being aware they are in an 'important' picture. Mumbling and histrionics are the order of the day. Pacino, in particular, delivers an over-the-top performance, often shouting his lines in a psychotic way that genuinely seems to surprise his fellow actors. If this was how Hanna was in real life, he would probably be under heavy sedation or psychiatric care. There is just about enough good stuff amid the padding to make this watchable. But only just.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Michael Mann's Masterpiece
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Hotwok2013
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I think it's fair to say that Robert De Niro & Al Pacino are not two of the greatest film actors of their generation, they ARE the best two actors. Making a movie that lives up to their talent was never going to be easy but Michael Mann's "HEAT" succeeds brilliantly. Led by De Niro, a crack team of professional thieves & bank robbers have carried out a number of unsolved crimes & detectives led by Pacino are determined to bring down the "crew" responsible. Along the way, Pacino's obsession for his job is causing his marriage to break down. Likewise, De Niro has fallen in love with a young lady causing him to forget the maxim taught him by his criminal mentor, "Never have anything in your life that you cannot walk away from in thirty seconds flat if you feel the heat coming round the corner". When the two adversaries finally meet over a cup of coffee in a cafe it is a spellbinding moment. Pacino coolly warns De Niro that he intends to take him & his gang down. De Niro responds by telling Pacino that if he gets in his way he will have no hesitation in killing him. Besides the two main men, there are many other great acting performances in a film which studies not only the crimes but characterisations of its participants. The final chase scenes between the two main protagonists is electrifyingly tense & "HEAT" is just a fabulous movie!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Best Action movie of all time
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    alienjm
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    We have a great masterpiece. Mann I am charmed with Michael, he make movies that are excellent.Heat and The last of the Mohican's are the best works that Michael Mann has done. Infected with striking and unforgettable scenes like the scene of the shootout in the Street, the best action scene in cinema history, or the face-to-face one between Pacino and Of Niro. This movie is completely loaded of action through, supports his plaster to the sofa and does not leave you to go until the end. You cannot leave her, it is necessary to see her until the end and the ending is awesome. A timeless classic action movie and of course it is my fourth favorite film of all time.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Spine-chilling
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    davigar1003
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It's a film that leaves you with chills in the body, so intense is unusual. Leave a bitter taste because you want the bad win the battle, but know that what happened is what was just and right. The film does a great realism in every scene. Full of expectations every second that makes you can not stop trying to guess what's coming. Valor, betrayal, courage and selflessness involved in a host of challenges to meet. Nobody like Michael Mann so beautifully exposes the individual lives of the characters to create this work of art, recreating with certainty the role of villain and defender of the law, accepted by each of the protagonist as their way of life ... and die!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A slick, polished thriller
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    RyanCShowers
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Movie fans and film snobs already acclaim Robert DeNiro and Al Pacino as two of the best actors in the history of entertainment. From the past experience of putting them in the same movie, The Godfather Part II, magic is bound to spark. While Heat isn't quite what one would assume it to be, it succeeds at being a mature, emotional experience that defines itself at the top of the action genre for years to come. Robert DeNiro has a beef with politicians during elections: they tear their opponents down and sacrifice their dignity instead of trying to prove themselves to the American people. Heat is an action thriller with dignity. While other action movies are concerned with what neat stunts can they throw at the audience, Heat internally speaks to the viewer as well as bringing well choreographed action scenes. Director Michael Mann, makes Heat more personal than most action thrillers. In fact, Mann doesn't tell the story as if it were a action movie at all. He tells a story centering in on the lives of two men who are connected by a few pieces of action. Mann delivers the film with a tense feeling, and establishes a gloomy tone. The engrossing score is cautiously placed the in the correct places. Heat succeeds technically, as well; the sound quality that adds to the excitement of the action scenes. The suspense is successful because Mann creates the film's tension sensitively. All the action and suspense is met perfectly because of the tender touch of Michael Mann. DeNiro and Pacino lead the adept cast creating one heck of an acting ensemble. Al Pacino has moments of greatness, but those are contrasted with some cringe-inducing moments. His highs are pretty high though and make up for the brief moments of instability. DeNiro, playing the darker character, is solid and consistent from his first scene to the last, giving him DeNiro the slight edge over Pacino. Both are great actors doing great work. Like their first appearance together, The Godfather Part II, they each lead their own section of the film, but in Heat they come into one-on-one contact half-way through the movie. It's a rare scene when the cop and the bad guy sit down for conversation and coffee. "Don't let yourself get attached to anything you are not willing to walk out on in thirty seconds flat if you the heat around the corner," is a line said by Robert DeNiro's character that resonates a lot of what the film is about. Heat is a slick polished thriller that holds carefully plotted action scenes while packing a powerful punch in the topics of abandonment, life, and admiration. The last scene's poignancy solidifies Heat as a movie to remember. Rating: 8/10 Grade: A-
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of the very great films.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ffreemon
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Real life does not divide all humans into good guys and bad guys and neither does this movie. The cops are a fellowship of dedicated men led by a loser who is so determined to perfect his craft that he has destroyed his three marriages. He has no friends and the only person he does not shout at is the head of the robbers. The gang of robbers are all individuals. They are honest with each other but do not hesitate to murder a guard who saw too much. So who are the good guys and the bad guys? There is a set of characters who are REALLY bad. The women are all individuals with their own hopes and lives. None are cops. One wonders if the fellowship of the homicide squad would have deteriorated if one of their numbers had been a woman. Do not miss this film. I recommend you see it twice, the second time you can appreciate the characters and the events without worrying about what happens next.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Proficient and Ingenious!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Govind Nair
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The movie is one of the most clever crime films ever made. It is another flick of the 'Police VS Thief' genre but is much more skilled and artistic than most of the movies of the same kind. It possesses one of the most striking concepts, which is exhibited to the viewers in the best possible manner. The movie in spite of having a long run time of 170 minutes doesn't seem to tire the audience. The movie has a slow pace at the start, but the latter part of the movie is breathtaking and intriguing. The star cast is absolutely outstanding. You can't expect a movie implicating greats like Al Pacino and Robert De Niro to let you down. Both have stood up to their standards, one playing a crucial police part and the other an adept gangster. The supporting roles played by Val Kimler, Diane Venora and Ashley Judd were slightly above average. Michael Mann, the writer and director, has done a splendid job indeed. The movie is an excellent portrayal of crime and redemption. The background score of the movie is intensified, yet extra ordinary. One hell of a movie! A collaboration involving legends.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    unforgettable
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Kris Mavericko
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    i'll say one thing about e climax scene of this film to indicate to you how powerful it was. I WATCHED THE CLIMAX FIVE TIMES. Five. In a row. and i could feel my eyes were wet. HUGE credits to e background score at that moment. michael mann reminds us that between two powerful individuals on either side of Law & Crime, there is a special BOND. and no other movie i've watched has exemplified this better than HEAT. it'll always be ranking among e top films ever in my heart & memory. now to e rest of e film. PACINO. DE NIRO. Guys, these two men literally run an acting class throughout e film, even during the breaths they take in this film & during their silences. me being an actor, i learnt an incredible lot from just this one film. there's a few lines that r memorable & quotable. Hanna's controlled rage & discipline are unmissable; McCauley's razor- sharp focus & ambition are ever-present. wonderful supporting cast. film takes its time to develop e sub-plots to let u soak it all in, in e heat of all e impending action. surely applaudable was e depth shown in e personal lives of both these professionals; and e trials they hv to put thru outside of their cat-&-mouse game. DON'T MISS.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Heat Sucks, sucks!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jessegehrig
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Eight hundred and twenty two people reviewed this movie before me, all of those people had something much much better to do. Heat was born from the idea that Pacino and DeNiro are two of this biggest tough-guys in Hollywood, although neither is over five foot ten. Some child-like emperor of a movie producer had a sad vision involving Pacino and DeNiro squaring off in a very ill-conceived action film. Val Kilmer has a bad wig, a fool cast Tom Sizemore, the script was written with a hammer and burned food, not with ink nor pen nor paper. Heat is the kind of movie thought up by some one who spends a lot of time at a gym or fitness club, which is the nice way of saying no artist or genius had any hand in crafting this wretched beast. Now, you might think,'what do we need artists and geniuses for anyways?', well without artists and geniuses you get movies like Heat, so there.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Lack of Action a Quiet Disappointing
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Fahad Mehar
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Guys. I always wanted to see this movie. I know "HEAT" movie since many years but never get chance to watch it, and many of my friends and cousins told me about this movie. It's very entertaining and action car chasing blah blah, Few days back. I downloaded "HEAT" I wanted to see a solid action movie. I downloaded this movie because of "Al Pacino" And" "Robert De Niro" Both are my favorite actors and let me tell you. I am giving 5 Starts just because of them not the movie 1st make it clear to you all. NOW come to the movie. I think I am the only one who giving the bad review of this movie. Well, I am a biggest action fan. I was expecting action from this movie but there was NONE. Well No Problem. BUT most Important part. If there is a less action then a good script covers it all. Movie PLOT was so dump No Solid story at all. Very very weak Plot. I think people like this movie just because of "Al Pacino" And" "Robert De Niro" And I don't see anything special in this movie. 2 Hours 50 minutes wasted. I don't mind there was lack of action but movie PLOT was worst.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Should have been called Baggage rather than Heat
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Cheese Hoven
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    An old piece of advice given to writers is "simplify". It is a pity such advice was not followed here, since the proliferation of subplots and other baggage (much of it irrelevant) make this film too unwieldy and long-winded for its own good. The build up to the much anticipated meeting between Pacino (Hanna) and De Niro (McCauley) sums up the film.. First Hanna is pointlessly seen in a helicopter before he is set down to follow McCauley in a car. Then Hanna has McCauley pull pver, McCauley is seen preparing to use his gun, Hanna gets out of his car, his own gun in hand, he steps up to McCauley's car and says "let's do coffee!" This was clearly meant to to an epic build up to an epic scene, but its effect is bathetic (and even pathetic).Even the meeting scene itself is mediocre, loosely written and rambling, like the film. Would there be anything notable about it if it were not Pacino and De Niro involved? The main plot is the hoary "heist goes wrong", but one of the criminal gang, Waingro, turns out to be a serial killer. He murders a prostitute in an unnecessary series of scenes, irrelevant to the main story arc since Waingro only gets his comeuppance (and not because of his serial killing) when he joins up with Van Zant (part of another sub-plot that I won't go into, although more integrated into the story). Most of the baggage here is of the emotional kind. Just about everyone has overwrought emotional scenes with their loved ones including the briefly seen black getaway driver (formerly working as a chef...the scenes of him before he makes his brief appearance as the driver had me scratching my head) and even the murdered prostitute has emotive shots of her family. Such scenes as this distract from the main narrative but there are even more anguished relationship scenes concerning the main protagonists. Neil McCauley (De Niro) has vowed to leave his woman at a drop of hat, but has apparently found 'true love'. Shiherlis (Kilmer) is a drunk gambler whose wife is leaving him until De Niro Godfather-like instructs her to stay. She has a lover who is blackmailed by the police into bringing her to them. Hanna (Pacino) has both wife and daughter problems. His wife is sleeping around while his daughter is suicidal. If all this sounds confusing, I can assure you there is much more and the film takes us down every one of these blind alleys one at a time. Despite the film lingering so lovingly on irrelevancies, important issues remain unresolved. Why, for instance, at the end does Hanna (the cop) take a fire arm from another policeman but not tell him to help him catch McCauley? This sets up an implausible and not very good, one on one shoot out and the unconvincing 'brothers in arms' handshake between the two as if Hanna had forgotten all those that McCauley (including cops) has murdered in cold blood. Likewise the relationships are left hanging at the end. What happens to Shiherlis and indeed his wife? Do they sail off into the sunset together? Not likely considering she is sleeping with someone else. And what about Hanna, his wife and their daughter? Nothing is resolved. The general look of the film is good but some shots are chosen more for their 'coolness' than their purpose. The action scenes are gory, perhaps unnecessarily so. The shoot-out, using sub machine guns, is overblown and unconvincing, and very Hollywoodian, including Hanna's "threading the eye of a needle" shot to kill one of the gang holding a child hostage. A note on performances. They tend to be rather overwrought at all times, with the cast being aware they are in an 'important' picture. Mumbling and histrionics are the order of the day. Pacino, in particular, delivers an over-the-top performance, often shouting his lines in a psychotic way that genuinely seems to surprise his fellow actors. If this was how Hanna was in real life, he would probably be under heavy sedation or psychiatric care. There is just about enough good stuff amid the padding to make this watchable. But only just.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Michael Mann's Masterpiece
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Hotwok2013
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I think it's fair to say that Robert De Niro & Al Pacino are not two of the greatest film actors of their generation, they ARE the best two actors. Making a movie that lives up to their talent was never going to be easy but Michael Mann's "HEAT" succeeds brilliantly. Led by De Niro, a crack team of professional thieves & bank robbers have carried out a number of unsolved crimes & detectives led by Pacino are determined to bring down the "crew" responsible. Along the way, Pacino's obsession for his job is causing his marriage to break down. Likewise, De Niro has fallen in love with a young lady causing him to forget the maxim taught him by his criminal mentor, "Never have anything in your life that you cannot walk away from in thirty seconds flat if you feel the heat coming round the corner". When the two adversaries finally meet over a cup of coffee in a cafe it is a spellbinding moment. Pacino coolly warns De Niro that he intends to take him & his gang down. De Niro responds by telling Pacino that if he gets in his way he will have no hesitation in killing him. Besides the two main men, there are many other great acting performances in a film which studies not only the crimes but characterisations of its participants. The final chase scenes between the two main protagonists is electrifyingly tense & "HEAT" is just a fabulous movie!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Best Action movie of all time
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    alienjm
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    We have a great masterpiece. Mann I am charmed with Michael, he make movies that are excellent.Heat and The last of the Mohican's are the best works that Michael Mann has done. Infected with striking and unforgettable scenes like the scene of the shootout in the Street, the best action scene in cinema history, or the face-to-face one between Pacino and Of Niro. This movie is completely loaded of action through, supports his plaster to the sofa and does not leave you to go until the end. You cannot leave her, it is necessary to see her until the end and the ending is awesome. A timeless classic action movie and of course it is my fourth favorite film of all time.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Spine-chilling
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    davigar1003
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It's a film that leaves you with chills in the body, so intense is unusual. Leave a bitter taste because you want the bad win the battle, but know that what happened is what was just and right. The film does a great realism in every scene. Full of expectations every second that makes you can not stop trying to guess what's coming. Valor, betrayal, courage and selflessness involved in a host of challenges to meet. Nobody like Michael Mann so beautifully exposes the individual lives of the characters to create this work of art, recreating with certainty the role of villain and defender of the law, accepted by each of the protagonist as their way of life ... and die!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A slick, polished thriller
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    RyanCShowers
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Movie fans and film snobs already acclaim Robert DeNiro and Al Pacino as two of the best actors in the history of entertainment. From the past experience of putting them in the same movie, The Godfather Part II, magic is bound to spark. While Heat isn't quite what one would assume it to be, it succeeds at being a mature, emotional experience that defines itself at the top of the action genre for years to come. Robert DeNiro has a beef with politicians during elections: they tear their opponents down and sacrifice their dignity instead of trying to prove themselves to the American people. Heat is an action thriller with dignity. While other action movies are concerned with what neat stunts can they throw at the audience, Heat internally speaks to the viewer as well as bringing well choreographed action scenes. Director Michael Mann, makes Heat more personal than most action thrillers. In fact, Mann doesn't tell the story as if it were a action movie at all. He tells a story centering in on the lives of two men who are connected by a few pieces of action. Mann delivers the film with a tense feeling, and establishes a gloomy tone. The engrossing score is cautiously placed the in the correct places. Heat succeeds technically, as well; the sound quality that adds to the excitement of the action scenes. The suspense is successful because Mann creates the film's tension sensitively. All the action and suspense is met perfectly because of the tender touch of Michael Mann. DeNiro and Pacino lead the adept cast creating one heck of an acting ensemble. Al Pacino has moments of greatness, but those are contrasted with some cringe-inducing moments. His highs are pretty high though and make up for the brief moments of instability. DeNiro, playing the darker character, is solid and consistent from his first scene to the last, giving him DeNiro the slight edge over Pacino. Both are great actors doing great work. Like their first appearance together, The Godfather Part II, they each lead their own section of the film, but in Heat they come into one-on-one contact half-way through the movie. It's a rare scene when the cop and the bad guy sit down for conversation and coffee. "Don't let yourself get attached to anything you are not willing to walk out on in thirty seconds flat if you the heat around the corner," is a line said by Robert DeNiro's character that resonates a lot of what the film is about. Heat is a slick polished thriller that holds carefully plotted action scenes while packing a powerful punch in the topics of abandonment, life, and admiration. The last scene's poignancy solidifies Heat as a movie to remember. Rating: 8/10 Grade: A-
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of the very great films.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ffreemon
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Real life does not divide all humans into good guys and bad guys and neither does this movie. The cops are a fellowship of dedicated men led by a loser who is so determined to perfect his craft that he has destroyed his three marriages. He has no friends and the only person he does not shout at is the head of the robbers. The gang of robbers are all individuals. They are honest with each other but do not hesitate to murder a guard who saw too much. So who are the good guys and the bad guys? There is a set of characters who are REALLY bad. The women are all individuals with their own hopes and lives. None are cops. One wonders if the fellowship of the homicide squad would have deteriorated if one of their numbers had been a woman. Do not miss this film. I recommend you see it twice, the second time you can appreciate the characters and the events without worrying about what happens next.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Proficient and Ingenious!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Govind Nair
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The movie is one of the most clever crime films ever made. It is another flick of the 'Police VS Thief' genre but is much more skilled and artistic than most of the movies of the same kind. It possesses one of the most striking concepts, which is exhibited to the viewers in the best possible manner. The movie in spite of having a long run time of 170 minutes doesn't seem to tire the audience. The movie has a slow pace at the start, but the latter part of the movie is breathtaking and intriguing. The star cast is absolutely outstanding. You can't expect a movie implicating greats like Al Pacino and Robert De Niro to let you down. Both have stood up to their standards, one playing a crucial police part and the other an adept gangster. The supporting roles played by Val Kimler, Diane Venora and Ashley Judd were slightly above average. Michael Mann, the writer and director, has done a splendid job indeed. The movie is an excellent portrayal of crime and redemption. The background score of the movie is intensified, yet extra ordinary. One hell of a movie! A collaboration involving legends.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    unforgettable
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Kris Mavericko
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    i'll say one thing about e climax scene of this film to indicate to you how powerful it was. I WATCHED THE CLIMAX FIVE TIMES. Five. In a row. and i could feel my eyes were wet. HUGE credits to e background score at that moment. michael mann reminds us that between two powerful individuals on either side of Law & Crime, there is a special BOND. and no other movie i've watched has exemplified this better than HEAT. it'll always be ranking among e top films ever in my heart & memory. now to e rest of e film. PACINO. DE NIRO. Guys, these two men literally run an acting class throughout e film, even during the breaths they take in this film & during their silences. me being an actor, i learnt an incredible lot from just this one film. there's a few lines that r memorable & quotable. Hanna's controlled rage & discipline are unmissable; McCauley's razor- sharp focus & ambition are ever-present. wonderful supporting cast. film takes its time to develop e sub-plots to let u soak it all in, in e heat of all e impending action. surely applaudable was e depth shown in e personal lives of both these professionals; and e trials they hv to put thru outside of their cat-&-mouse game. DON'T MISS.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Heat Sucks, sucks!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jessegehrig
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Eight hundred and twenty two people reviewed this movie before me, all of those people had something much much better to do. Heat was born from the idea that Pacino and DeNiro are two of this biggest tough-guys in Hollywood, although neither is over five foot ten. Some child-like emperor of a movie producer had a sad vision involving Pacino and DeNiro squaring off in a very ill-conceived action film. Val Kilmer has a bad wig, a fool cast Tom Sizemore, the script was written with a hammer and burned food, not with ink nor pen nor paper. Heat is the kind of movie thought up by some one who spends a lot of time at a gym or fitness club, which is the nice way of saying no artist or genius had any hand in crafting this wretched beast. Now, you might think,'what do we need artists and geniuses for anyways?', well without artists and geniuses you get movies like Heat, so there.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Lack of Action a Quiet Disappointing
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Fahad Mehar
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Guys. I always wanted to see this movie. I know "HEAT" movie since many years but never get chance to watch it, and many of my friends and cousins told me about this movie. It's very entertaining and action car chasing blah blah, Few days back. I downloaded "HEAT" I wanted to see a solid action movie. I downloaded this movie because of "Al Pacino" And" "Robert De Niro" Both are my favorite actors and let me tell you. I am giving 5 Starts just because of them not the movie 1st make it clear to you all. NOW come to the movie. I think I am the only one who giving the bad review of this movie. Well, I am a biggest action fan. I was expecting action from this movie but there was NONE. Well No Problem. BUT most Important part. If there is a less action then a good script covers it all. Movie PLOT was so dump No Solid story at all. Very very weak Plot. I think people like this movie just because of "Al Pacino" And" "Robert De Niro" And I don't see anything special in this movie. 2 Hours 50 minutes wasted. I don't mind there was lack of action but movie PLOT was worst.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Should have been called Baggage rather than Heat
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Cheese Hoven
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    An old piece of advice given to writers is "simplify". It is a pity such advice was not followed here, since the proliferation of subplots and other baggage (much of it irrelevant) make this film too unwieldy and long-winded for its own good. The build up to the much anticipated meeting between Pacino (Hanna) and De Niro (McCauley) sums up the film.. First Hanna is pointlessly seen in a helicopter before he is set down to follow McCauley in a car. Then Hanna has McCauley pull pver, McCauley is seen preparing to use his gun, Hanna gets out of his car, his own gun in hand, he steps up to McCauley's car and says "let's do coffee!" This was clearly meant to to an epic build up to an epic scene, but its effect is bathetic (and even pathetic).Even the meeting scene itself is mediocre, loosely written and rambling, like the film. Would there be anything notable about it if it were not Pacino and De Niro involved? The main plot is the hoary "heist goes wrong", but one of the criminal gang, Waingro, turns out to be a serial killer. He murders a prostitute in an unnecessary series of scenes, irrelevant to the main story arc since Waingro only gets his comeuppance (and not because of his serial killing) when he joins up with Van Zant (part of another sub-plot that I won't go into, although more integrated into the story). Most of the baggage here is of the emotional kind. Just about everyone has overwrought emotional scenes with their loved ones including the briefly seen black getaway driver (formerly working as a chef...the scenes of him before he makes his brief appearance as the driver had me scratching my head) and even the murdered prostitute has emotive shots of her family. Such scenes as this distract from the main narrative but there are even more anguished relationship scenes concerning the main protagonists. Neil McCauley (De Niro) has vowed to leave his woman at a drop of hat, but has apparently found 'true love'. Shiherlis (Kilmer) is a drunk gambler whose wife is leaving him until De Niro Godfather-like instructs her to stay. She has a lover who is blackmailed by the police into bringing her to them. Hanna (Pacino) has both wife and daughter problems. His wife is sleeping around while his daughter is suicidal. If all this sounds confusing, I can assure you there is much more and the film takes us down every one of these blind alleys one at a time. Despite the film lingering so lovingly on irrelevancies, important issues remain unresolved. Why, for instance, at the end does Hanna (the cop) take a fire arm from another policeman but not tell him to help him catch McCauley? This sets up an implausible and not very good, one on one shoot out and the unconvincing 'brothers in arms' handshake between the two as if Hanna had forgotten all those that McCauley (including cops) has murdered in cold blood. Likewise the relationships are left hanging at the end. What happens to Shiherlis and indeed his wife? Do they sail off into the sunset together? Not likely considering she is sleeping with someone else. And what about Hanna, his wife and their daughter? Nothing is resolved. The general look of the film is good but some shots are chosen more for their 'coolness' than their purpose. The action scenes are gory, perhaps unnecessarily so. The shoot-out, using sub machine guns, is overblown and unconvincing, and very Hollywoodian, including Hanna's "threading the eye of a needle" shot to kill one of the gang holding a child hostage. A note on performances. They tend to be rather overwrought at all times, with the cast being aware they are in an 'important' picture. Mumbling and histrionics are the order of the day. Pacino, in particular, delivers an over-the-top performance, often shouting his lines in a psychotic way that genuinely seems to surprise his fellow actors. If this was how Hanna was in real life, he would probably be under heavy sedation or psychiatric care. There is just about enough good stuff amid the padding to make this watchable. But only just.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Michael Mann's Masterpiece
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Hotwok2013
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I think it's fair to say that Robert De Niro & Al Pacino are not two of the greatest film actors of their generation, they ARE the best two actors. Making a movie that lives up to their talent was never going to be easy but Michael Mann's "HEAT" succeeds brilliantly. Led by De Niro, a crack team of professional thieves & bank robbers have carried out a number of unsolved crimes & detectives led by Pacino are determined to bring down the "crew" responsible. Along the way, Pacino's obsession for his job is causing his marriage to break down. Likewise, De Niro has fallen in love with a young lady causing him to forget the maxim taught him by his criminal mentor, "Never have anything in your life that you cannot walk away from in thirty seconds flat if you feel the heat coming round the corner". When the two adversaries finally meet over a cup of coffee in a cafe it is a spellbinding moment. Pacino coolly warns De Niro that he intends to take him & his gang down. De Niro responds by telling Pacino that if he gets in his way he will have no hesitation in killing him. Besides the two main men, there are many other great acting performances in a film which studies not only the crimes but characterisations of its participants. The final chase scenes between the two main protagonists is electrifyingly tense & "HEAT" is just a fabulous movie!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Best Action movie of all time
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    alienjm
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    We have a great masterpiece. Mann I am charmed with Michael, he make movies that are excellent.Heat and The last of the Mohican's are the best works that Michael Mann has done. Infected with striking and unforgettable scenes like the scene of the shootout in the Street, the best action scene in cinema history, or the face-to-face one between Pacino and Of Niro. This movie is completely loaded of action through, supports his plaster to the sofa and does not leave you to go until the end. You cannot leave her, it is necessary to see her until the end and the ending is awesome. A timeless classic action movie and of course it is my fourth favorite film of all time.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Spine-chilling
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    davigar1003
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It's a film that leaves you with chills in the body, so intense is unusual. Leave a bitter taste because you want the bad win the battle, but know that what happened is what was just and right. The film does a great realism in every scene. Full of expectations every second that makes you can not stop trying to guess what's coming. Valor, betrayal, courage and selflessness involved in a host of challenges to meet. Nobody like Michael Mann so beautifully exposes the individual lives of the characters to create this work of art, recreating with certainty the role of villain and defender of the law, accepted by each of the protagonist as their way of life ... and die!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A slick, polished thriller
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    RyanCShowers
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Movie fans and film snobs already acclaim Robert DeNiro and Al Pacino as two of the best actors in the history of entertainment. From the past experience of putting them in the same movie, The Godfather Part II, magic is bound to spark. While Heat isn't quite what one would assume it to be, it succeeds at being a mature, emotional experience that defines itself at the top of the action genre for years to come. Robert DeNiro has a beef with politicians during elections: they tear their opponents down and sacrifice their dignity instead of trying to prove themselves to the American people. Heat is an action thriller with dignity. While other action movies are concerned with what neat stunts can they throw at the audience, Heat internally speaks to the viewer as well as bringing well choreographed action scenes. Director Michael Mann, makes Heat more personal than most action thrillers. In fact, Mann doesn't tell the story as if it were a action movie at all. He tells a story centering in on the lives of two men who are connected by a few pieces of action. Mann delivers the film with a tense feeling, and establishes a gloomy tone. The engrossing score is cautiously placed the in the correct places. Heat succeeds technically, as well; the sound quality that adds to the excitement of the action scenes. The suspense is successful because Mann creates the film's tension sensitively. All the action and suspense is met perfectly because of the tender touch of Michael Mann. DeNiro and Pacino lead the adept cast creating one heck of an acting ensemble. Al Pacino has moments of greatness, but those are contrasted with some cringe-inducing moments. His highs are pretty high though and make up for the brief moments of instability. DeNiro, playing the darker character, is solid and consistent from his first scene to the last, giving him DeNiro the slight edge over Pacino. Both are great actors doing great work. Like their first appearance together, The Godfather Part II, they each lead their own section of the film, but in Heat they come into one-on-one contact half-way through the movie. It's a rare scene when the cop and the bad guy sit down for conversation and coffee. "Don't let yourself get attached to anything you are not willing to walk out on in thirty seconds flat if you the heat around the corner," is a line said by Robert DeNiro's character that resonates a lot of what the film is about. Heat is a slick polished thriller that holds carefully plotted action scenes while packing a powerful punch in the topics of abandonment, life, and admiration. The last scene's poignancy solidifies Heat as a movie to remember. Rating: 8/10 Grade: A-
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of the very great films.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ffreemon
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Real life does not divide all humans into good guys and bad guys and neither does this movie. The cops are a fellowship of dedicated men led by a loser who is so determined to perfect his craft that he has destroyed his three marriages. He has no friends and the only person he does not shout at is the head of the robbers. The gang of robbers are all individuals. They are honest with each other but do not hesitate to murder a guard who saw too much. So who are the good guys and the bad guys? There is a set of characters who are REALLY bad. The women are all individuals with their own hopes and lives. None are cops. One wonders if the fellowship of the homicide squad would have deteriorated if one of their numbers had been a woman. Do not miss this film. I recommend you see it twice, the second time you can appreciate the characters and the events without worrying about what happens next.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Proficient and Ingenious!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Govind Nair
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The movie is one of the most clever crime films ever made. It is another flick of the 'Police VS Thief' genre but is much more skilled and artistic than most of the movies of the same kind. It possesses one of the most striking concepts, which is exhibited to the viewers in the best possible manner. The movie in spite of having a long run time of 170 minutes doesn't seem to tire the audience. The movie has a slow pace at the start, but the latter part of the movie is breathtaking and intriguing. The star cast is absolutely outstanding. You can't expect a movie implicating greats like Al Pacino and Robert De Niro to let you down. Both have stood up to their standards, one playing a crucial police part and the other an adept gangster. The supporting roles played by Val Kimler, Diane Venora and Ashley Judd were slightly above average. Michael Mann, the writer and director, has done a splendid job indeed. The movie is an excellent portrayal of crime and redemption. The background score of the movie is intensified, yet extra ordinary. One hell of a movie! A collaboration involving legends.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    unforgettable
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Kris Mavericko
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    i'll say one thing about e climax scene of this film to indicate to you how powerful it was. I WATCHED THE CLIMAX FIVE TIMES. Five. In a row. and i could feel my eyes were wet. HUGE credits to e background score at that moment. michael mann reminds us that between two powerful individuals on either side of Law & Crime, there is a special BOND. and no other movie i've watched has exemplified this better than HEAT. it'll always be ranking among e top films ever in my heart & memory. now to e rest of e film. PACINO. DE NIRO. Guys, these two men literally run an acting class throughout e film, even during the breaths they take in this film & during their silences. me being an actor, i learnt an incredible lot from just this one film. there's a few lines that r memorable & quotable. Hanna's controlled rage & discipline are unmissable; McCauley's razor- sharp focus & ambition are ever-present. wonderful supporting cast. film takes its time to develop e sub-plots to let u soak it all in, in e heat of all e impending action. surely applaudable was e depth shown in e personal lives of both these professionals; and e trials they hv to put thru outside of their cat-&-mouse game. DON'T MISS.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Heat Sucks, sucks!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jessegehrig
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Eight hundred and twenty two people reviewed this movie before me, all of those people had something much much better to do. Heat was born from the idea that Pacino and DeNiro are two of this biggest tough-guys in Hollywood, although neither is over five foot ten. Some child-like emperor of a movie producer had a sad vision involving Pacino and DeNiro squaring off in a very ill-conceived action film. Val Kilmer has a bad wig, a fool cast Tom Sizemore, the script was written with a hammer and burned food, not with ink nor pen nor paper. Heat is the kind of movie thought up by some one who spends a lot of time at a gym or fitness club, which is the nice way of saying no artist or genius had any hand in crafting this wretched beast. Now, you might think,'what do we need artists and geniuses for anyways?', well without artists and geniuses you get movies like Heat, so there.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Lack of Action a Quiet Disappointing
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Fahad Mehar
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Guys. I always wanted to see this movie. I know "HEAT" movie since many years but never get chance to watch it, and many of my friends and cousins told me about this movie. It's very entertaining and action car chasing blah blah, Few days back. I downloaded "HEAT" I wanted to see a solid action movie. I downloaded this movie because of "Al Pacino" And" "Robert De Niro" Both are my favorite actors and let me tell you. I am giving 5 Starts just because of them not the movie 1st make it clear to you all. NOW come to the movie. I think I am the only one who giving the bad review of this movie. Well, I am a biggest action fan. I was expecting action from this movie but there was NONE. Well No Problem. BUT most Important part. If there is a less action then a good script covers it all. Movie PLOT was so dump No Solid story at all. Very very weak Plot. I think people like this movie just because of "Al Pacino" And" "Robert De Niro" And I don't see anything special in this movie. 2 Hours 50 minutes wasted. I don't mind there was lack of action but movie PLOT was worst.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Should have been called Baggage rather than Heat
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Cheese Hoven
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    An old piece of advice given to writers is "simplify". It is a pity such advice was not followed here, since the proliferation of subplots and other baggage (much of it irrelevant) make this film too unwieldy and long-winded for its own good. The build up to the much anticipated meeting between Pacino (Hanna) and De Niro (McCauley) sums up the film.. First Hanna is pointlessly seen in a helicopter before he is set down to follow McCauley in a car. Then Hanna has McCauley pull pver, McCauley is seen preparing to use his gun, Hanna gets out of his car, his own gun in hand, he steps up to McCauley's car and says "let's do coffee!" This was clearly meant to to an epic build up to an epic scene, but its effect is bathetic (and even pathetic).Even the meeting scene itself is mediocre, loosely written and rambling, like the film. Would there be anything notable about it if it were not Pacino and De Niro involved? The main plot is the hoary "heist goes wrong", but one of the criminal gang, Waingro, turns out to be a serial killer. He murders a prostitute in an unnecessary series of scenes, irrelevant to the main story arc since Waingro only gets his comeuppance (and not because of his serial killing) when he joins up with Van Zant (part of another sub-plot that I won't go into, although more integrated into the story). Most of the baggage here is of the emotional kind. Just about everyone has overwrought emotional scenes with their loved ones including the briefly seen black getaway driver (formerly working as a chef...the scenes of him before he makes his brief appearance as the driver had me scratching my head) and even the murdered prostitute has emotive shots of her family. Such scenes as this distract from the main narrative but there are even more anguished relationship scenes concerning the main protagonists. Neil McCauley (De Niro) has vowed to leave his woman at a drop of hat, but has apparently found 'true love'. Shiherlis (Kilmer) is a drunk gambler whose wife is leaving him until De Niro Godfather-like instructs her to stay. She has a lover who is blackmailed by the police into bringing her to them. Hanna (Pacino) has both wife and daughter problems. His wife is sleeping around while his daughter is suicidal. If all this sounds confusing, I can assure you there is much more and the film takes us down every one of these blind alleys one at a time. Despite the film lingering so lovingly on irrelevancies, important issues remain unresolved. Why, for instance, at the end does Hanna (the cop) take a fire arm from another policeman but not tell him to help him catch McCauley? This sets up an implausible and not very good, one on one shoot out and the unconvincing 'brothers in arms' handshake between the two as if Hanna had forgotten all those that McCauley (including cops) has murdered in cold blood. Likewise the relationships are left hanging at the end. What happens to Shiherlis and indeed his wife? Do they sail off into the sunset together? Not likely considering she is sleeping with someone else. And what about Hanna, his wife and their daughter? Nothing is resolved. The general look of the film is good but some shots are chosen more for their 'coolness' than their purpose. The action scenes are gory, perhaps unnecessarily so. The shoot-out, using sub machine guns, is overblown and unconvincing, and very Hollywoodian, including Hanna's "threading the eye of a needle" shot to kill one of the gang holding a child hostage. A note on performances. They tend to be rather overwrought at all times, with the cast being aware they are in an 'important' picture. Mumbling and histrionics are the order of the day. Pacino, in particular, delivers an over-the-top performance, often shouting his lines in a psychotic way that genuinely seems to surprise his fellow actors. If this was how Hanna was in real life, he would probably be under heavy sedation or psychiatric care. There is just about enough good stuff amid the padding to make this watchable. But only just.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Michael Mann's Masterpiece
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Hotwok2013
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I think it's fair to say that Robert De Niro & Al Pacino are not two of the greatest film actors of their generation, they ARE the best two actors. Making a movie that lives up to their talent was never going to be easy but Michael Mann's "HEAT" succeeds brilliantly. Led by De Niro, a crack team of professional thieves & bank robbers have carried out a number of unsolved crimes & detectives led by Pacino are determined to bring down the "crew" responsible. Along the way, Pacino's obsession for his job is causing his marriage to break down. Likewise, De Niro has fallen in love with a young lady causing him to forget the maxim taught him by his criminal mentor, "Never have anything in your life that you cannot walk away from in thirty seconds flat if you feel the heat coming round the corner". When the two adversaries finally meet over a cup of coffee in a cafe it is a spellbinding moment. Pacino coolly warns De Niro that he intends to take him & his gang down. De Niro responds by telling Pacino that if he gets in his way he will have no hesitation in killing him. Besides the two main men, there are many other great acting performances in a film which studies not only the crimes but characterisations of its participants. The final chase scenes between the two main protagonists is electrifyingly tense & "HEAT" is just a fabulous movie!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Best Action movie of all time
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    alienjm
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    We have a great masterpiece. Mann I am charmed with Michael, he make movies that are excellent.Heat and The last of the Mohican's are the best works that Michael Mann has done. Infected with striking and unforgettable scenes like the scene of the shootout in the Street, the best action scene in cinema history, or the face-to-face one between Pacino and Of Niro. This movie is completely loaded of action through, supports his plaster to the sofa and does not leave you to go until the end. You cannot leave her, it is necessary to see her until the end and the ending is awesome. A timeless classic action movie and of course it is my fourth favorite film of all time.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Spine-chilling
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    davigar1003
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It's a film that leaves you with chills in the body, so intense is unusual. Leave a bitter taste because you want the bad win the battle, but know that what happened is what was just and right. The film does a great realism in every scene. Full of expectations every second that makes you can not stop trying to guess what's coming. Valor, betrayal, courage and selflessness involved in a host of challenges to meet. Nobody like Michael Mann so beautifully exposes the individual lives of the characters to create this work of art, recreating with certainty the role of villain and defender of the law, accepted by each of the protagonist as their way of life ... and die!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A slick, polished thriller
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    RyanCShowers
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Movie fans and film snobs already acclaim Robert DeNiro and Al Pacino as two of the best actors in the history of entertainment. From the past experience of putting them in the same movie, The Godfather Part II, magic is bound to spark. While Heat isn't quite what one would assume it to be, it succeeds at being a mature, emotional experience that defines itself at the top of the action genre for years to come. Robert DeNiro has a beef with politicians during elections: they tear their opponents down and sacrifice their dignity instead of trying to prove themselves to the American people. Heat is an action thriller with dignity. While other action movies are concerned with what neat stunts can they throw at the audience, Heat internally speaks to the viewer as well as bringing well choreographed action scenes. Director Michael Mann, makes Heat more personal than most action thrillers. In fact, Mann doesn't tell the story as if it were a action movie at all. He tells a story centering in on the lives of two men who are connected by a few pieces of action. Mann delivers the film with a tense feeling, and establishes a gloomy tone. The engrossing score is cautiously placed the in the correct places. Heat succeeds technically, as well; the sound quality that adds to the excitement of the action scenes. The suspense is successful because Mann creates the film's tension sensitively. All the action and suspense is met perfectly because of the tender touch of Michael Mann. DeNiro and Pacino lead the adept cast creating one heck of an acting ensemble. Al Pacino has moments of greatness, but those are contrasted with some cringe-inducing moments. His highs are pretty high though and make up for the brief moments of instability. DeNiro, playing the darker character, is solid and consistent from his first scene to the last, giving him DeNiro the slight edge over Pacino. Both are great actors doing great work. Like their first appearance together, The Godfather Part II, they each lead their own section of the film, but in Heat they come into one-on-one contact half-way through the movie. It's a rare scene when the cop and the bad guy sit down for conversation and coffee. "Don't let yourself get attached to anything you are not willing to walk out on in thirty seconds flat if you the heat around the corner," is a line said by Robert DeNiro's character that resonates a lot of what the film is about. Heat is a slick polished thriller that holds carefully plotted action scenes while packing a powerful punch in the topics of abandonment, life, and admiration. The last scene's poignancy solidifies Heat as a movie to remember. Rating: 8/10 Grade: A-
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of the very great films.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ffreemon
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Real life does not divide all humans into good guys and bad guys and neither does this movie. The cops are a fellowship of dedicated men led by a loser who is so determined to perfect his craft that he has destroyed his three marriages. He has no friends and the only person he does not shout at is the head of the robbers. The gang of robbers are all individuals. They are honest with each other but do not hesitate to murder a guard who saw too much. So who are the good guys and the bad guys? There is a set of characters who are REALLY bad. The women are all individuals with their own hopes and lives. None are cops. One wonders if the fellowship of the homicide squad would have deteriorated if one of their numbers had been a woman. Do not miss this film. I recommend you see it twice, the second time you can appreciate the characters and the events without worrying about what happens next.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Proficient and Ingenious!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Govind Nair
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The movie is one of the most clever crime films ever made. It is another flick of the 'Police VS Thief' genre but is much more skilled and artistic than most of the movies of the same kind. It possesses one of the most striking concepts, which is exhibited to the viewers in the best possible manner. The movie in spite of having a long run time of 170 minutes doesn't seem to tire the audience. The movie has a slow pace at the start, but the latter part of the movie is breathtaking and intriguing. The star cast is absolutely outstanding. You can't expect a movie implicating greats like Al Pacino and Robert De Niro to let you down. Both have stood up to their standards, one playing a crucial police part and the other an adept gangster. The supporting roles played by Val Kimler, Diane Venora and Ashley Judd were slightly above average. Michael Mann, the writer and director, has done a splendid job indeed. The movie is an excellent portrayal of crime and redemption. The background score of the movie is intensified, yet extra ordinary. One hell of a movie! A collaboration involving legends.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    unforgettable
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Kris Mavericko
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    i'll say one thing about e climax scene of this film to indicate to you how powerful it was. I WATCHED THE CLIMAX FIVE TIMES. Five. In a row. and i could feel my eyes were wet. HUGE credits to e background score at that moment. michael mann reminds us that between two powerful individuals on either side of Law & Crime, there is a special BOND. and no other movie i've watched has exemplified this better than HEAT. it'll always be ranking among e top films ever in my heart & memory. now to e rest of e film. PACINO. DE NIRO. Guys, these two men literally run an acting class throughout e film, even during the breaths they take in this film & during their silences. me being an actor, i learnt an incredible lot from just this one film. there's a few lines that r memorable & quotable. Hanna's controlled rage & discipline are unmissable; McCauley's razor- sharp focus & ambition are ever-present. wonderful supporting cast. film takes its time to develop e sub-plots to let u soak it all in, in e heat of all e impending action. surely applaudable was e depth shown in e personal lives of both these professionals; and e trials they hv to put thru outside of their cat-&-mouse game. DON'T MISS.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Heat Sucks, sucks!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jessegehrig
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Eight hundred and twenty two people reviewed this movie before me, all of those people had something much much better to do. Heat was born from the idea that Pacino and DeNiro are two of this biggest tough-guys in Hollywood, although neither is over five foot ten. Some child-like emperor of a movie producer had a sad vision involving Pacino and DeNiro squaring off in a very ill-conceived action film. Val Kilmer has a bad wig, a fool cast Tom Sizemore, the script was written with a hammer and burned food, not with ink nor pen nor paper. Heat is the kind of movie thought up by some one who spends a lot of time at a gym or fitness club, which is the nice way of saying no artist or genius had any hand in crafting this wretched beast. Now, you might think,'what do we need artists and geniuses for anyways?', well without artists and geniuses you get movies like Heat, so there.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Lack of Action a Quiet Disappointing
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Fahad Mehar
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Guys. I always wanted to see this movie. I know "HEAT" movie since many years but never get chance to watch it, and many of my friends and cousins told me about this movie. It's very entertaining and action car chasing blah blah, Few days back. I downloaded "HEAT" I wanted to see a solid action movie. I downloaded this movie because of "Al Pacino" And" "Robert De Niro" Both are my favorite actors and let me tell you. I am giving 5 Starts just because of them not the movie 1st make it clear to you all. NOW come to the movie. I think I am the only one who giving the bad review of this movie. Well, I am a biggest action fan. I was expecting action from this movie but there was NONE. Well No Problem. BUT most Important part. If there is a less action then a good script covers it all. Movie PLOT was so dump No Solid story at all. Very very weak Plot. I think people like this movie just because of "Al Pacino" And" "Robert De Niro" And I don't see anything special in this movie. 2 Hours 50 minutes wasted. I don't mind there was lack of action but movie PLOT was worst.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Should have been called Baggage rather than Heat
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Cheese Hoven
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    An old piece of advice given to writers is "simplify". It is a pity such advice was not followed here, since the proliferation of subplots and other baggage (much of it irrelevant) make this film too unwieldy and long-winded for its own good. The build up to the much anticipated meeting between Pacino (Hanna) and De Niro (McCauley) sums up the film.. First Hanna is pointlessly seen in a helicopter before he is set down to follow McCauley in a car. Then Hanna has McCauley pull pver, McCauley is seen preparing to use his gun, Hanna gets out of his car, his own gun in hand, he steps up to McCauley's car and says "let's do coffee!" This was clearly meant to to an epic build up to an epic scene, but its effect is bathetic (and even pathetic).Even the meeting scene itself is mediocre, loosely written and rambling, like the film. Would there be anything notable about it if it were not Pacino and De Niro involved? The main plot is the hoary "heist goes wrong", but one of the criminal gang, Waingro, turns out to be a serial killer. He murders a prostitute in an unnecessary series of scenes, irrelevant to the main story arc since Waingro only gets his comeuppance (and not because of his serial killing) when he joins up with Van Zant (part of another sub-plot that I won't go into, although more integrated into the story). Most of the baggage here is of the emotional kind. Just about everyone has overwrought emotional scenes with their loved ones including the briefly seen black getaway driver (formerly working as a chef...the scenes of him before he makes his brief appearance as the driver had me scratching my head) and even the murdered prostitute has emotive shots of her family. Such scenes as this distract from the main narrative but there are even more anguished relationship scenes concerning the main protagonists. Neil McCauley (De Niro) has vowed to leave his woman at a drop of hat, but has apparently found 'true love'. Shiherlis (Kilmer) is a drunk gambler whose wife is leaving him until De Niro Godfather-like instructs her to stay. She has a lover who is blackmailed by the police into bringing her to them. Hanna (Pacino) has both wife and daughter problems. His wife is sleeping around while his daughter is suicidal. If all this sounds confusing, I can assure you there is much more and the film takes us down every one of these blind alleys one at a time. Despite the film lingering so lovingly on irrelevancies, important issues remain unresolved. Why, for instance, at the end does Hanna (the cop) take a fire arm from another policeman but not tell him to help him catch McCauley? This sets up an implausible and not very good, one on one shoot out and the unconvincing 'brothers in arms' handshake between the two as if Hanna had forgotten all those that McCauley (including cops) has murdered in cold blood. Likewise the relationships are left hanging at the end. What happens to Shiherlis and indeed his wife? Do they sail off into the sunset together? Not likely considering she is sleeping with someone else. And what about Hanna, his wife and their daughter? Nothing is resolved. The general look of the film is good but some shots are chosen more for their 'coolness' than their purpose. The action scenes are gory, perhaps unnecessarily so. The shoot-out, using sub machine guns, is overblown and unconvincing, and very Hollywoodian, including Hanna's "threading the eye of a needle" shot to kill one of the gang holding a child hostage. A note on performances. They tend to be rather overwrought at all times, with the cast being aware they are in an 'important' picture. Mumbling and histrionics are the order of the day. Pacino, in particular, delivers an over-the-top performance, often shouting his lines in a psychotic way that genuinely seems to surprise his fellow actors. If this was how Hanna was in real life, he would probably be under heavy sedation or psychiatric care. There is just about enough good stuff amid the padding to make this watchable. But only just.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Michael Mann's Masterpiece
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Hotwok2013
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I think it's fair to say that Robert De Niro & Al Pacino are not two of the greatest film actors of their generation, they ARE the best two actors. Making a movie that lives up to their talent was never going to be easy but Michael Mann's "HEAT" succeeds brilliantly. Led by De Niro, a crack team of professional thieves & bank robbers have carried out a number of unsolved crimes & detectives led by Pacino are determined to bring down the "crew" responsible. Along the way, Pacino's obsession for his job is causing his marriage to break down. Likewise, De Niro has fallen in love with a young lady causing him to forget the maxim taught him by his criminal mentor, "Never have anything in your life that you cannot walk away from in thirty seconds flat if you feel the heat coming round the corner". When the two adversaries finally meet over a cup of coffee in a cafe it is a spellbinding moment. Pacino coolly warns De Niro that he intends to take him & his gang down. De Niro responds by telling Pacino that if he gets in his way he will have no hesitation in killing him. Besides the two main men, there are many other great acting performances in a film which studies not only the crimes but characterisations of its participants. The final chase scenes between the two main protagonists is electrifyingly tense & "HEAT" is just a fabulous movie!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Best Action movie of all time
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    alienjm
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    We have a great masterpiece. Mann I am charmed with Michael, he make movies that are excellent.Heat and The last of the Mohican's are the best works that Michael Mann has done. Infected with striking and unforgettable scenes like the scene of the shootout in the Street, the best action scene in cinema history, or the face-to-face one between Pacino and Of Niro. This movie is completely loaded of action through, supports his plaster to the sofa and does not leave you to go until the end. You cannot leave her, it is necessary to see her until the end and the ending is awesome. A timeless classic action movie and of course it is my fourth favorite film of all time.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Spine-chilling
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    davigar1003
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It's a film that leaves you with chills in the body, so intense is unusual. Leave a bitter taste because you want the bad win the battle, but know that what happened is what was just and right. The film does a great realism in every scene. Full of expectations every second that makes you can not stop trying to guess what's coming. Valor, betrayal, courage and selflessness involved in a host of challenges to meet. Nobody like Michael Mann so beautifully exposes the individual lives of the characters to create this work of art, recreating with certainty the role of villain and defender of the law, accepted by each of the protagonist as their way of life ... and die!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A slick, polished thriller
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    RyanCShowers
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Movie fans and film snobs already acclaim Robert DeNiro and Al Pacino as two of the best actors in the history of entertainment. From the past experience of putting them in the same movie, The Godfather Part II, magic is bound to spark. While Heat isn't quite what one would assume it to be, it succeeds at being a mature, emotional experience that defines itself at the top of the action genre for years to come. Robert DeNiro has a beef with politicians during elections: they tear their opponents down and sacrifice their dignity instead of trying to prove themselves to the American people. Heat is an action thriller with dignity. While other action movies are concerned with what neat stunts can they throw at the audience, Heat internally speaks to the viewer as well as bringing well choreographed action scenes. Director Michael Mann, makes Heat more personal than most action thrillers. In fact, Mann doesn't tell the story as if it were a action movie at all. He tells a story centering in on the lives of two men who are connected by a few pieces of action. Mann delivers the film with a tense feeling, and establishes a gloomy tone. The engrossing score is cautiously placed the in the correct places. Heat succeeds technically, as well; the sound quality that adds to the excitement of the action scenes. The suspense is successful because Mann creates the film's tension sensitively. All the action and suspense is met perfectly because of the tender touch of Michael Mann. DeNiro and Pacino lead the adept cast creating one heck of an acting ensemble. Al Pacino has moments of greatness, but those are contrasted with some cringe-inducing moments. His highs are pretty high though and make up for the brief moments of instability. DeNiro, playing the darker character, is solid and consistent from his first scene to the last, giving him DeNiro the slight edge over Pacino. Both are great actors doing great work. Like their first appearance together, The Godfather Part II, they each lead their own section of the film, but in Heat they come into one-on-one contact half-way through the movie. It's a rare scene when the cop and the bad guy sit down for conversation and coffee. "Don't let yourself get attached to anything you are not willing to walk out on in thirty seconds flat if you the heat around the corner," is a line said by Robert DeNiro's character that resonates a lot of what the film is about. Heat is a slick polished thriller that holds carefully plotted action scenes while packing a powerful punch in the topics of abandonment, life, and admiration. The last scene's poignancy solidifies Heat as a movie to remember. Rating: 8/10 Grade: A-
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of the very great films.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ffreemon
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Real life does not divide all humans into good guys and bad guys and neither does this movie. The cops are a fellowship of dedicated men led by a loser who is so determined to perfect his craft that he has destroyed his three marriages. He has no friends and the only person he does not shout at is the head of the robbers. The gang of robbers are all individuals. They are honest with each other but do not hesitate to murder a guard who saw too much. So who are the good guys and the bad guys? There is a set of characters who are REALLY bad. The women are all individuals with their own hopes and lives. None are cops. One wonders if the fellowship of the homicide squad would have deteriorated if one of their numbers had been a woman. Do not miss this film. I recommend you see it twice, the second time you can appreciate the characters and the events without worrying about what happens next.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Proficient and Ingenious!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Govind Nair
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The movie is one of the most clever crime films ever made. It is another flick of the 'Police VS Thief' genre but is much more skilled and artistic than most of the movies of the same kind. It possesses one of the most striking concepts, which is exhibited to the viewers in the best possible manner. The movie in spite of having a long run time of 170 minutes doesn't seem to tire the audience. The movie has a slow pace at the start, but the latter part of the movie is breathtaking and intriguing. The star cast is absolutely outstanding. You can't expect a movie implicating greats like Al Pacino and Robert De Niro to let you down. Both have stood up to their standards, one playing a crucial police part and the other an adept gangster. The supporting roles played by Val Kimler, Diane Venora and Ashley Judd were slightly above average. Michael Mann, the writer and director, has done a splendid job indeed. The movie is an excellent portrayal of crime and redemption. The background score of the movie is intensified, yet extra ordinary. One hell of a movie! A collaboration involving legends.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    unforgettable
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Kris Mavericko
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    i'll say one thing about e climax scene of this film to indicate to you how powerful it was. I WATCHED THE CLIMAX FIVE TIMES. Five. In a row. and i could feel my eyes were wet. HUGE credits to e background score at that moment. michael mann reminds us that between two powerful individuals on either side of Law & Crime, there is a special BOND. and no other movie i've watched has exemplified this better than HEAT. it'll always be ranking among e top films ever in my heart & memory. now to e rest of e film. PACINO. DE NIRO. Guys, these two men literally run an acting class throughout e film, even during the breaths they take in this film & during their silences. me being an actor, i learnt an incredible lot from just this one film. there's a few lines that r memorable & quotable. Hanna's controlled rage & discipline are unmissable; McCauley's razor- sharp focus & ambition are ever-present. wonderful supporting cast. film takes its time to develop e sub-plots to let u soak it all in, in e heat of all e impending action. surely applaudable was e depth shown in e personal lives of both these professionals; and e trials they hv to put thru outside of their cat-&-mouse game. DON'T MISS.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Heat Sucks, sucks!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jessegehrig
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Eight hundred and twenty two people reviewed this movie before me, all of those people had something much much better to do. Heat was born from the idea that Pacino and DeNiro are two of this biggest tough-guys in Hollywood, although neither is over five foot ten. Some child-like emperor of a movie producer had a sad vision involving Pacino and DeNiro squaring off in a very ill-conceived action film. Val Kilmer has a bad wig, a fool cast Tom Sizemore, the script was written with a hammer and burned food, not with ink nor pen nor paper. Heat is the kind of movie thought up by some one who spends a lot of time at a gym or fitness club, which is the nice way of saying no artist or genius had any hand in crafting this wretched beast. Now, you might think,'what do we need artists and geniuses for anyways?', well without artists and geniuses you get movies like Heat, so there.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Lack of Action a Quiet Disappointing
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Fahad Mehar
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Guys. I always wanted to see this movie. I know "HEAT" movie since many years but never get chance to watch it, and many of my friends and cousins told me about this movie. It's very entertaining and action car chasing blah blah, Few days back. I downloaded "HEAT" I wanted to see a solid action movie. I downloaded this movie because of "Al Pacino" And" "Robert De Niro" Both are my favorite actors and let me tell you. I am giving 5 Starts just because of them not the movie 1st make it clear to you all. NOW come to the movie. I think I am the only one who giving the bad review of this movie. Well, I am a biggest action fan. I was expecting action from this movie but there was NONE. Well No Problem. BUT most Important part. If there is a less action then a good script covers it all. Movie PLOT was so dump No Solid story at all. Very very weak Plot. I think people like this movie just because of "Al Pacino" And" "Robert De Niro" And I don't see anything special in this movie. 2 Hours 50 minutes wasted. I don't mind there was lack of action but movie PLOT was worst.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Should have been called Baggage rather than Heat
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Cheese Hoven
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    An old piece of advice given to writers is "simplify". It is a pity such advice was not followed here, since the proliferation of subplots and other baggage (much of it irrelevant) make this film too unwieldy and long-winded for its own good. The build up to the much anticipated meeting between Pacino (Hanna) and De Niro (McCauley) sums up the film.. First Hanna is pointlessly seen in a helicopter before he is set down to follow McCauley in a car. Then Hanna has McCauley pull pver, McCauley is seen preparing to use his gun, Hanna gets out of his car, his own gun in hand, he steps up to McCauley's car and says "let's do coffee!" This was clearly meant to to an epic build up to an epic scene, but its effect is bathetic (and even pathetic).Even the meeting scene itself is mediocre, loosely written and rambling, like the film. Would there be anything notable about it if it were not Pacino and De Niro involved? The main plot is the hoary "heist goes wrong", but one of the criminal gang, Waingro, turns out to be a serial killer. He murders a prostitute in an unnecessary series of scenes, irrelevant to the main story arc since Waingro only gets his comeuppance (and not because of his serial killing) when he joins up with Van Zant (part of another sub-plot that I won't go into, although more integrated into the story). Most of the baggage here is of the emotional kind. Just about everyone has overwrought emotional scenes with their loved ones including the briefly seen black getaway driver (formerly working as a chef...the scenes of him before he makes his brief appearance as the driver had me scratching my head) and even the murdered prostitute has emotive shots of her family. Such scenes as this distract from the main narrative but there are even more anguished relationship scenes concerning the main protagonists. Neil McCauley (De Niro) has vowed to leave his woman at a drop of hat, but has apparently found 'true love'. Shiherlis (Kilmer) is a drunk gambler whose wife is leaving him until De Niro Godfather-like instructs her to stay. She has a lover who is blackmailed by the police into bringing her to them. Hanna (Pacino) has both wife and daughter problems. His wife is sleeping around while his daughter is suicidal. If all this sounds confusing, I can assure you there is much more and the film takes us down every one of these blind alleys one at a time. Despite the film lingering so lovingly on irrelevancies, important issues remain unresolved. Why, for instance, at the end does Hanna (the cop) take a fire arm from another policeman but not tell him to help him catch McCauley? This sets up an implausible and not very good, one on one shoot out and the unconvincing 'brothers in arms' handshake between the two as if Hanna had forgotten all those that McCauley (including cops) has murdered in cold blood. Likewise the relationships are left hanging at the end. What happens to Shiherlis and indeed his wife? Do they sail off into the sunset together? Not likely considering she is sleeping with someone else. And what about Hanna, his wife and their daughter? Nothing is resolved. The general look of the film is good but some shots are chosen more for their 'coolness' than their purpose. The action scenes are gory, perhaps unnecessarily so. The shoot-out, using sub machine guns, is overblown and unconvincing, and very Hollywoodian, including Hanna's "threading the eye of a needle" shot to kill one of the gang holding a child hostage. A note on performances. They tend to be rather overwrought at all times, with the cast being aware they are in an 'important' picture. Mumbling and histrionics are the order of the day. Pacino, in particular, delivers an over-the-top performance, often shouting his lines in a psychotic way that genuinely seems to surprise his fellow actors. If this was how Hanna was in real life, he would probably be under heavy sedation or psychiatric care. There is just about enough good stuff amid the padding to make this watchable. But only just.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Michael Mann's Masterpiece
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Hotwok2013
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I think it's fair to say that Robert De Niro & Al Pacino are not two of the greatest film actors of their generation, they ARE the best two actors. Making a movie that lives up to their talent was never going to be easy but Michael Mann's "HEAT" succeeds brilliantly. Led by De Niro, a crack team of professional thieves & bank robbers have carried out a number of unsolved crimes & detectives led by Pacino are determined to bring down the "crew" responsible. Along the way, Pacino's obsession for his job is causing his marriage to break down. Likewise, De Niro has fallen in love with a young lady causing him to forget the maxim taught him by his criminal mentor, "Never have anything in your life that you cannot walk away from in thirty seconds flat if you feel the heat coming round the corner". When the two adversaries finally meet over a cup of coffee in a cafe it is a spellbinding moment. Pacino coolly warns De Niro that he intends to take him & his gang down. De Niro responds by telling Pacino that if he gets in his way he will have no hesitation in killing him. Besides the two main men, there are many other great acting performances in a film which studies not only the crimes but characterisations of its participants. The final chase scenes between the two main protagonists is electrifyingly tense & "HEAT" is just a fabulous movie!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Best Action movie of all time
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    alienjm
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    We have a great masterpiece. Mann I am charmed with Michael, he make movies that are excellent.Heat and The last of the Mohican's are the best works that Michael Mann has done. Infected with striking and unforgettable scenes like the scene of the shootout in the Street, the best action scene in cinema history, or the face-to-face one between Pacino and Of Niro. This movie is completely loaded of action through, supports his plaster to the sofa and does not leave you to go until the end. You cannot leave her, it is necessary to see her until the end and the ending is awesome. A timeless classic action movie and of course it is my fourth favorite film of all time.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Spine-chilling
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    davigar1003
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It's a film that leaves you with chills in the body, so intense is unusual. Leave a bitter taste because you want the bad win the battle, but know that what happened is what was just and right. The film does a great realism in every scene. Full of expectations every second that makes you can not stop trying to guess what's coming. Valor, betrayal, courage and selflessness involved in a host of challenges to meet. Nobody like Michael Mann so beautifully exposes the individual lives of the characters to create this work of art, recreating with certainty the role of villain and defender of the law, accepted by each of the protagonist as their way of life ... and die!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A slick, polished thriller
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    RyanCShowers
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Movie fans and film snobs already acclaim Robert DeNiro and Al Pacino as two of the best actors in the history of entertainment. From the past experience of putting them in the same movie, The Godfather Part II, magic is bound to spark. While Heat isn't quite what one would assume it to be, it succeeds at being a mature, emotional experience that defines itself at the top of the action genre for years to come. Robert DeNiro has a beef with politicians during elections: they tear their opponents down and sacrifice their dignity instead of trying to prove themselves to the American people. Heat is an action thriller with dignity. While other action movies are concerned with what neat stunts can they throw at the audience, Heat internally speaks to the viewer as well as bringing well choreographed action scenes. Director Michael Mann, makes Heat more personal than most action thrillers. In fact, Mann doesn't tell the story as if it were a action movie at all. He tells a story centering in on the lives of two men who are connected by a few pieces of action. Mann delivers the film with a tense feeling, and establishes a gloomy tone. The engrossing score is cautiously placed the in the correct places. Heat succeeds technically, as well; the sound quality that adds to the excitement of the action scenes. The suspense is successful because Mann creates the film's tension sensitively. All the action and suspense is met perfectly because of the tender touch of Michael Mann. DeNiro and Pacino lead the adept cast creating one heck of an acting ensemble. Al Pacino has moments of greatness, but those are contrasted with some cringe-inducing moments. His highs are pretty high though and make up for the brief moments of instability. DeNiro, playing the darker character, is solid and consistent from his first scene to the last, giving him DeNiro the slight edge over Pacino. Both are great actors doing great work. Like their first appearance together, The Godfather Part II, they each lead their own section of the film, but in Heat they come into one-on-one contact half-way through the movie. It's a rare scene when the cop and the bad guy sit down for conversation and coffee. "Don't let yourself get attached to anything you are not willing to walk out on in thirty seconds flat if you the heat around the corner," is a line said by Robert DeNiro's character that resonates a lot of what the film is about. Heat is a slick polished thriller that holds carefully plotted action scenes while packing a powerful punch in the topics of abandonment, life, and admiration. The last scene's poignancy solidifies Heat as a movie to remember. Rating: 8/10 Grade: A-
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of the very great films.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ffreemon
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Real life does not divide all humans into good guys and bad guys and neither does this movie. The cops are a fellowship of dedicated men led by a loser who is so determined to perfect his craft that he has destroyed his three marriages. He has no friends and the only person he does not shout at is the head of the robbers. The gang of robbers are all individuals. They are honest with each other but do not hesitate to murder a guard who saw too much. So who are the good guys and the bad guys? There is a set of characters who are REALLY bad. The women are all individuals with their own hopes and lives. None are cops. One wonders if the fellowship of the homicide squad would have deteriorated if one of their numbers had been a woman. Do not miss this film. I recommend you see it twice, the second time you can appreciate the characters and the events without worrying about what happens next.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Proficient and Ingenious!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Govind Nair
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The movie is one of the most clever crime films ever made. It is another flick of the 'Police VS Thief' genre but is much more skilled and artistic than most of the movies of the same kind. It possesses one of the most striking concepts, which is exhibited to the viewers in the best possible manner. The movie in spite of having a long run time of 170 minutes doesn't seem to tire the audience. The movie has a slow pace at the start, but the latter part of the movie is breathtaking and intriguing. The star cast is absolutely outstanding. You can't expect a movie implicating greats like Al Pacino and Robert De Niro to let you down. Both have stood up to their standards, one playing a crucial police part and the other an adept gangster. The supporting roles played by Val Kimler, Diane Venora and Ashley Judd were slightly above average. Michael Mann, the writer and director, has done a splendid job indeed. The movie is an excellent portrayal of crime and redemption. The background score of the movie is intensified, yet extra ordinary. One hell of a movie! A collaboration involving legends.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    unforgettable
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Kris Mavericko
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    i'll say one thing about e climax scene of this film to indicate to you how powerful it was. I WATCHED THE CLIMAX FIVE TIMES. Five. In a row. and i could feel my eyes were wet. HUGE credits to e background score at that moment. michael mann reminds us that between two powerful individuals on either side of Law & Crime, there is a special BOND. and no other movie i've watched has exemplified this better than HEAT. it'll always be ranking among e top films ever in my heart & memory. now to e rest of e film. PACINO. DE NIRO. Guys, these two men literally run an acting class throughout e film, even during the breaths they take in this film & during their silences. me being an actor, i learnt an incredible lot from just this one film. there's a few lines that r memorable & quotable. Hanna's controlled rage & discipline are unmissable; McCauley's razor- sharp focus & ambition are ever-present. wonderful supporting cast. film takes its time to develop e sub-plots to let u soak it all in, in e heat of all e impending action. surely applaudable was e depth shown in e personal lives of both these professionals; and e trials they hv to put thru outside of their cat-&-mouse game. DON'T MISS.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Heat Sucks, sucks!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jessegehrig
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Eight hundred and twenty two people reviewed this movie before me, all of those people had something much much better to do. Heat was born from the idea that Pacino and DeNiro are two of this biggest tough-guys in Hollywood, although neither is over five foot ten. Some child-like emperor of a movie producer had a sad vision involving Pacino and DeNiro squaring off in a very ill-conceived action film. Val Kilmer has a bad wig, a fool cast Tom Sizemore, the script was written with a hammer and burned food, not with ink nor pen nor paper. Heat is the kind of movie thought up by some one who spends a lot of time at a gym or fitness club, which is the nice way of saying no artist or genius had any hand in crafting this wretched beast. Now, you might think,'what do we need artists and geniuses for anyways?', well without artists and geniuses you get movies like Heat, so there.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Lack of Action a Quiet Disappointing
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Fahad Mehar
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Guys. I always wanted to see this movie. I know "HEAT" movie since many years but never get chance to watch it, and many of my friends and cousins told me about this movie. It's very entertaining and action car chasing blah blah, Few days back. I downloaded "HEAT" I wanted to see a solid action movie. I downloaded this movie because of "Al Pacino" And" "Robert De Niro" Both are my favorite actors and let me tell you. I am giving 5 Starts just because of them not the movie 1st make it clear to you all. NOW come to the movie. I think I am the only one who giving the bad review of this movie. Well, I am a biggest action fan. I was expecting action from this movie but there was NONE. Well No Problem. BUT most Important part. If there is a less action then a good script covers it all. Movie PLOT was so dump No Solid story at all. Very very weak Plot. I think people like this movie just because of "Al Pacino" And" "Robert De Niro" And I don't see anything special in this movie. 2 Hours 50 minutes wasted. I don't mind there was lack of action but movie PLOT was worst.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Should have been called Baggage rather than Heat
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Cheese Hoven
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    An old piece of advice given to writers is "simplify". It is a pity such advice was not followed here, since the proliferation of subplots and other baggage (much of it irrelevant) make this film too unwieldy and long-winded for its own good. The build up to the much anticipated meeting between Pacino (Hanna) and De Niro (McCauley) sums up the film.. First Hanna is pointlessly seen in a helicopter before he is set down to follow McCauley in a car. Then Hanna has McCauley pull pver, McCauley is seen preparing to use his gun, Hanna gets out of his car, his own gun in hand, he steps up to McCauley's car and says "let's do coffee!" This was clearly meant to to an epic build up to an epic scene, but its effect is bathetic (and even pathetic).Even the meeting scene itself is mediocre, loosely written and rambling, like the film. Would there be anything notable about it if it were not Pacino and De Niro involved? The main plot is the hoary "heist goes wrong", but one of the criminal gang, Waingro, turns out to be a serial killer. He murders a prostitute in an unnecessary series of scenes, irrelevant to the main story arc since Waingro only gets his comeuppance (and not because of his serial killing) when he joins up with Van Zant (part of another sub-plot that I won't go into, although more integrated into the story). Most of the baggage here is of the emotional kind. Just about everyone has overwrought emotional scenes with their loved ones including the briefly seen black getaway driver (formerly working as a chef...the scenes of him before he makes his brief appearance as the driver had me scratching my head) and even the murdered prostitute has emotive shots of her family. Such scenes as this distract from the main narrative but there are even more anguished relationship scenes concerning the main protagonists. Neil McCauley (De Niro) has vowed to leave his woman at a drop of hat, but has apparently found 'true love'. Shiherlis (Kilmer) is a drunk gambler whose wife is leaving him until De Niro Godfather-like instructs her to stay. She has a lover who is blackmailed by the police into bringing her to them. Hanna (Pacino) has both wife and daughter problems. His wife is sleeping around while his daughter is suicidal. If all this sounds confusing, I can assure you there is much more and the film takes us down every one of these blind alleys one at a time. Despite the film lingering so lovingly on irrelevancies, important issues remain unresolved. Why, for instance, at the end does Hanna (the cop) take a fire arm from another policeman but not tell him to help him catch McCauley? This sets up an implausible and not very good, one on one shoot out and the unconvincing 'brothers in arms' handshake between the two as if Hanna had forgotten all those that McCauley (including cops) has murdered in cold blood. Likewise the relationships are left hanging at the end. What happens to Shiherlis and indeed his wife? Do they sail off into the sunset together? Not likely considering she is sleeping with someone else. And what about Hanna, his wife and their daughter? Nothing is resolved. The general look of the film is good but some shots are chosen more for their 'coolness' than their purpose. The action scenes are gory, perhaps unnecessarily so. The shoot-out, using sub machine guns, is overblown and unconvincing, and very Hollywoodian, including Hanna's "threading the eye of a needle" shot to kill one of the gang holding a child hostage. A note on performances. They tend to be rather overwrought at all times, with the cast being aware they are in an 'important' picture. Mumbling and histrionics are the order of the day. Pacino, in particular, delivers an over-the-top performance, often shouting his lines in a psychotic way that genuinely seems to surprise his fellow actors. If this was how Hanna was in real life, he would probably be under heavy sedation or psychiatric care. There is just about enough good stuff amid the padding to make this watchable. But only just.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Michael Mann's Masterpiece
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Hotwok2013
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I think it's fair to say that Robert De Niro & Al Pacino are not two of the greatest film actors of their generation, they ARE the best two actors. Making a movie that lives up to their talent was never going to be easy but Michael Mann's "HEAT" succeeds brilliantly. Led by De Niro, a crack team of professional thieves & bank robbers have carried out a number of unsolved crimes & detectives led by Pacino are determined to bring down the "crew" responsible. Along the way, Pacino's obsession for his job is causing his marriage to break down. Likewise, De Niro has fallen in love with a young lady causing him to forget the maxim taught him by his criminal mentor, "Never have anything in your life that you cannot walk away from in thirty seconds flat if you feel the heat coming round the corner". When the two adversaries finally meet over a cup of coffee in a cafe it is a spellbinding moment. Pacino coolly warns De Niro that he intends to take him & his gang down. De Niro responds by telling Pacino that if he gets in his way he will have no hesitation in killing him. Besides the two main men, there are many other great acting performances in a film which studies not only the crimes but characterisations of its participants. The final chase scenes between the two main protagonists is electrifyingly tense & "HEAT" is just a fabulous movie!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Best Action movie of all time
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    alienjm
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    We have a great masterpiece. Mann I am charmed with Michael, he make movies that are excellent.Heat and The last of the Mohican's are the best works that Michael Mann has done. Infected with striking and unforgettable scenes like the scene of the shootout in the Street, the best action scene in cinema history, or the face-to-face one between Pacino and Of Niro. This movie is completely loaded of action through, supports his plaster to the sofa and does not leave you to go until the end. You cannot leave her, it is necessary to see her until the end and the ending is awesome. A timeless classic action movie and of course it is my fourth favorite film of all time.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Spine-chilling
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    davigar1003
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It's a film that leaves you with chills in the body, so intense is unusual. Leave a bitter taste because you want the bad win the battle, but know that what happened is what was just and right. The film does a great realism in every scene. Full of expectations every second that makes you can not stop trying to guess what's coming. Valor, betrayal, courage and selflessness involved in a host of challenges to meet. Nobody like Michael Mann so beautifully exposes the individual lives of the characters to create this work of art, recreating with certainty the role of villain and defender of the law, accepted by each of the protagonist as their way of life ... and die!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A slick, polished thriller
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    RyanCShowers
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Movie fans and film snobs already acclaim Robert DeNiro and Al Pacino as two of the best actors in the history of entertainment. From the past experience of putting them in the same movie, The Godfather Part II, magic is bound to spark. While Heat isn't quite what one would assume it to be, it succeeds at being a mature, emotional experience that defines itself at the top of the action genre for years to come. Robert DeNiro has a beef with politicians during elections: they tear their opponents down and sacrifice their dignity instead of trying to prove themselves to the American people. Heat is an action thriller with dignity. While other action movies are concerned with what neat stunts can they throw at the audience, Heat internally speaks to the viewer as well as bringing well choreographed action scenes. Director Michael Mann, makes Heat more personal than most action thrillers. In fact, Mann doesn't tell the story as if it were a action movie at all. He tells a story centering in on the lives of two men who are connected by a few pieces of action. Mann delivers the film with a tense feeling, and establishes a gloomy tone. The engrossing score is cautiously placed the in the correct places. Heat succeeds technically, as well; the sound quality that adds to the excitement of the action scenes. The suspense is successful because Mann creates the film's tension sensitively. All the action and suspense is met perfectly because of the tender touch of Michael Mann. DeNiro and Pacino lead the adept cast creating one heck of an acting ensemble. Al Pacino has moments of greatness, but those are contrasted with some cringe-inducing moments. His highs are pretty high though and make up for the brief moments of instability. DeNiro, playing the darker character, is solid and consistent from his first scene to the last, giving him DeNiro the slight edge over Pacino. Both are great actors doing great work. Like their first appearance together, The Godfather Part II, they each lead their own section of the film, but in Heat they come into one-on-one contact half-way through the movie. It's a rare scene when the cop and the bad guy sit down for conversation and coffee. "Don't let yourself get attached to anything you are not willing to walk out on in thirty seconds flat if you the heat around the corner," is a line said by Robert DeNiro's character that resonates a lot of what the film is about. Heat is a slick polished thriller that holds carefully plotted action scenes while packing a powerful punch in the topics of abandonment, life, and admiration. The last scene's poignancy solidifies Heat as a movie to remember. Rating: 8/10 Grade: A-
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of the very great films.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ffreemon
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Real life does not divide all humans into good guys and bad guys and neither does this movie. The cops are a fellowship of dedicated men led by a loser who is so determined to perfect his craft that he has destroyed his three marriages. He has no friends and the only person he does not shout at is the head of the robbers. The gang of robbers are all individuals. They are honest with each other but do not hesitate to murder a guard who saw too much. So who are the good guys and the bad guys? There is a set of characters who are REALLY bad. The women are all individuals with their own hopes and lives. None are cops. One wonders if the fellowship of the homicide squad would have deteriorated if one of their numbers had been a woman. Do not miss this film. I recommend you see it twice, the second time you can appreciate the characters and the events without worrying about what happens next.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
 </reviews>
</filme>
