<filme>
 <id>
  278
 </id>
 <imdburl>
  http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0115644
 </imdburl>
 <ano>
  1996
 </ano>
 <titulo>
  Bed of Roses
 </titulo>
 <rating>
  5.7
 </rating>
 <sinopse>
  Romantic drama about a young career girl who is swept off her feet by a shy florist, who fell in love with her after one glimpse through a shadowy window.
 </sinopse>
 <storyline>
  Romantic drama about a young career girl who is swept off her feet by a shy florist, who fell in love with her after one glimpse through a shadowy window.
 </storyline>
 <generos>
  <genero>
   Romance
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Drama
  </genero>
 </generos>
 <keywords>
  <keyword>
   florist
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   widower
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   family relationships
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   grief
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   title based on song
  </keyword>
 </keywords>
 <diretores>
  <diretor>
   Michael Goldenberg
  </diretor>
 </diretores>
 <escritores>
  <escritor>
   Michael Goldenberg
  </escritor>
 </escritores>
 <atores>
  <ator>
   Christian Slater
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Mary Stuart Masterson
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Pamela Adlon
  </ator>
 </atores>
 <reviews>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    To my surprise, better than average love story
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    vincentlynch-moonoi
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This film is from that time period when someone thought Christian Slater could be a quirky (if not slightly creepy) romantic lead. I never believed it, although he did have several good roles in such pics. But quirky and creepy don't play well for long. So, I was a little surprised to find myself watching this film...and liking it. Although it took a while. The first third of the film sort of meanders along with a slightly creepy Slater romancing a workaholic loner of a girl (Mary Stuart Masterson). I began to wonder if this film was going anywhere interesting...you can look at just so many flowers being delivered. Then they begin living together and she is invited to his family's home for Christmas. Can she do it? No. Christmas is a disaster. The romance is off. They go their separate ways. Will they get back together? I could see an ending where she wants to but he is already with someone new, and she realizes that once again she has lost happiness. Or, I could see the happy ending we expect. I thought Masterson was downright superb in her role. And, Mr. Slater surprised me, as well. In fact, the final scene -- where she expresses her need and he appears to think no, not again -- as fine a piece of acting as you're likely to see in a romantic film. Pamela Adlon is excellent here as the best friend. On the other hand, Josh Brolin has a pretty-much-nothing role as a sort of boyfriend of Masterson. So, this was a much better film than I expected (at least after the first third). If you like love stories, this is better than most.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Surprisingly interesting
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Johanna
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I kind of love romantic comedy's because they're easy to watch and they'll always turn out to be what you expected them to be. This movie had the same 'contents' as all romantic movies do. Two people meet each other in a way people will never meet. She's hard to get, but he is so romantic, she falls for him. They turn out to be perfect for each other, but she's not telling something important. They fight. They get back together. They live happily ever after. But it turned out to be quite different than all the other movies at the same time. Actually, I think the storyline is really boring. It's just not complete. They both have difficult backgrounds, but those story's are just 'put in to the movie', without expanding them. It's like pieces of a puzzle which are put in the right order, but they're not actually put together. So, its kind of a boring story, but it really intrigued me at the same time. I think it's because of the actors, like people in other reviews have said. They make the boring characters alive. And maybe it's because they talk really little, in my opinion. And their faces tell the story. So I actually loved watching this movie, just in a whole different way than I expected at first. Maybe you don't understand what I mean, but then you have to watch the movie. Just don't expect a regular romantic comedy.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Dropout and the Foundling
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bkoganbing
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/3/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    When you cast Christian Slater in a part where he sends flowers to a complete stranger you never know what you're going get. It's not like he hasn't played off balance people before. And some might consider what he does to Mary Stuart Masterson as stalking. But Slater and Masterson make a fetching romantic couple in Bed Of Roses as a pair of lonely people looking for something or someone to complete them as a line in another film done in late 90s said. Slater has never been this romantic before or since on the big screen. Parts like he had in Kuffs, Pump Up The Volume, and Heathers are more like what he's identified with. Slater in fact was once in Masterson's world, he was a runner with Goldman&Sachs who lost a wife and child in childbirth. After that he just dropped out of it all and became a florist delivery man because flowers are beautiful and everyone is happy to see him when he delivers. Masterson is in that world now, but all she has is work. She was a foundling who was left at the Pittsburgh airport and raised in a foster home with a man who drank considerably and its hinted he may have done other terrible things to her. She has no romantic illusions, she does have work though and the world of high finance demands her attention completely. Bed Of Roses is a good, but not great film. It's lack of development of supporting characters is a big weakness. Still it's the definition of a star vehicle and the stars do shine in this one.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    mediocre movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    didiermustntdie
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/2/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    let's value it. entertainment: a trashy script which has been typed by unintelligent people in front of typewriters a thousand times.. pathetic acting that is thwarted by the story...OK production value, including good set/location and gorgeous girl.. -rating 4/10 social message: the movie has no social message. it's thought free... .but if I pretend I were 10, and my IQ were 70. I feel the message is:don't be afraid to love? -rating 0/10 objectionable things: nothing special, just the mild Jewish hedonic and arrogant attitude that is presented by the writer/director. generally speaking, good , nothing degenerate -8/10 overall rating is 4/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    It had its ups and downs
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    romanseight2004
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/4/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I thought some of it was good, and there were some original lines that I will likely take with me and use in appropriate situations. Both Slater and Masterson are wonderful actors, but there just wasn't any chemistry between them.I was also bothered by the fact that the little girl in the play was adorable. Wasn't the whole purpose of the play supposed to be for the ugly duckling? She was not believable as a hard case. I realize that was just a detail in the story, but it's an example of the lack of follow through that the movie had in many areas. It was very sweet and romantic however, with some lines I will remember.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    OK as Romance Flick.. but, uh - where is last chapter of Script?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    canuckteach
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/10/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The sentiments of my wife and myself are echoed well by many discerning viewers here at IMDb: Slater is great as a wonderful guy who loves people and falls in love with a girl he sees, for the first time, under 'unusual' circumstances (trying not to give anything away here). Masterson is a needy, but accomplished workaholic, who appears to have found the ideal guy. And the movie does have some nice set designs, warm family moments, and music. But, the Script is skimpy in places, particularly at the end!! I mean, my goodness - supposing the plane in 'Casablanca' carrying Rick's long-lost love away forever had to force-land at the Airport. Wouldn't you expect another 15 minutes of story to wrap up the loose ends? lol - supposing Bogart just walks off and says 'This is the beginning of a great friendship' to his policeman friend, and leaves Ilsa staring into the fog? yikes! Well, we couldn't believe in this case that the film was over!! huh? did we get a defective copy of the DVD? 'Sorry - great price on this DVD, but the last chapter of the Script is on Disc 2 (not included).' Actually, it is 'sort' of a happy ending, but I think FilmMaking-101 includes the rule "Don't open up plot points you can't develop and wrap up satisfactorily". 6/10 Guys: watch with secure marriage mate, or watch NFL instead! (--:
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    it's a really big step-up from 13 going on 30 and others.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    highschoolteen
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/1/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Bed of roses was an excellent movie. after watching it I literally cried MSM and CS make a perfect couple in the movie.SPOILER: although i think its awkward that CS walks nights looking into people's windows, creepy. it is cute that he's sort of like a secret admirer. he sends her roses after seeing her crying in her window (how cute). after they kiss and she shreds the flowers she goes back to him and he talks about his dead wife. well anyways if any of you love romantic comedy's than you should get Bed Of Roses, its a great movie. Spoiler: at first i thought Bed of Roses was going to be weird but obviously I was wrong. i really like the fact that MSM has a Tazer (you need your protection) its funny that she carries it in her purse. believe me you'll love this movie.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A big bouquet of happiness will be delivered to any viewer who chooses to watch this fine film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Amy Adler
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/2/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Lisa (Mary Stuart Masterson) is a rising businesswoman who rarely devotes herself to anything but work and more work. This is, in part, because of events that occurred during her childhood. She has a drop-in boyfriend who doesn't really spend any quality time with her but, Lisa is certain she likes it that way. That is, until the day a gorgeous bouquet of flowers is delivered to her at the office, without a card. Lisa calls friends and work colleagues to try to determine who sent her this gift. No luck. As a last resort, she goes to the florist and begs for information about the giver. She is stunned to learn that the delivery man, Lewis (Christian Slater) is her unknown fan. Lewis tells her about his interest in her and Lisa is cautious, of course. But, over the next few weeks, Lisa and Lewis become closer. Yet, something is wrong. What could it be? This is a quietly beautiful love story. Masterson is pretty and touching as the woman who doesn't know much about love and Slater is wonderful as the florist who learns to open up his heart again, too. The rest of the cast is nice and the script, costumes, sets and production values are very good. If you are drawn to stories of romance, this one should land on your must-see list. It is a bouquet of humor, heartache, and happy endings that will have you floating on air, smiling like crazy.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Warm and Wonderful
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gospelpicker
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/10/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Bed of Roses is easily one of the best romance movies ever. Even if the movie wasn't as good as it is, the soundtrack alone would make it worth watching. But, the movie itself is wonderful and full of warmth. Bed of Roses has the kind of story you would like to live out for yourself. True, people don't usually meet and fall in love the way Lewis and Lisa do in this movie, but isn't that the purpose of movies and music? The story and characters are as unique as they are addictive. When the movie ended, I found myself wanting more. This is one movie that will stick with you. I dare you to watch it only once. If you enjoyed Bed of Roses, you might also like At First Sight with Val Kilmer and Mira Sorvino.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Restraining order please...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    socalcarli
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/7/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I've tried to like this film, really. In watching it, all I can think is, "This guy gives me the creeps, I would have gotten a restraining order". It also calls out CODEPENDENCE in capital letters. Was this really the conversation before making the movie? "Let's make a film that puts two chronically depressed, socially inept people into a relationship which deepens their isolation and encourages them to complain about how bad their lives are!" From what I've seen in life is that the last thing on earth we find attractive in a potential mate is constant self-pity. The mood of the movie is distinctly 80-ish; brooding and slow. Don't get me wrong, the film has its moments, just very few of them.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    To my surprise, better than average love story
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    vincentlynch-moonoi
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This film is from that time period when someone thought Christian Slater could be a quirky (if not slightly creepy) romantic lead. I never believed it, although he did have several good roles in such pics. But quirky and creepy don't play well for long. So, I was a little surprised to find myself watching this film...and liking it. Although it took a while. The first third of the film sort of meanders along with a slightly creepy Slater romancing a workaholic loner of a girl (Mary Stuart Masterson). I began to wonder if this film was going anywhere interesting...you can look at just so many flowers being delivered. Then they begin living together and she is invited to his family's home for Christmas. Can she do it? No. Christmas is a disaster. The romance is off. They go their separate ways. Will they get back together? I could see an ending where she wants to but he is already with someone new, and she realizes that once again she has lost happiness. Or, I could see the happy ending we expect. I thought Masterson was downright superb in her role. And, Mr. Slater surprised me, as well. In fact, the final scene -- where she expresses her need and he appears to think no, not again -- as fine a piece of acting as you're likely to see in a romantic film. Pamela Adlon is excellent here as the best friend. On the other hand, Josh Brolin has a pretty-much-nothing role as a sort of boyfriend of Masterson. So, this was a much better film than I expected (at least after the first third). If you like love stories, this is better than most.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Surprisingly interesting
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Johanna
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I kind of love romantic comedy's because they're easy to watch and they'll always turn out to be what you expected them to be. This movie had the same 'contents' as all romantic movies do. Two people meet each other in a way people will never meet. She's hard to get, but he is so romantic, she falls for him. They turn out to be perfect for each other, but she's not telling something important. They fight. They get back together. They live happily ever after. But it turned out to be quite different than all the other movies at the same time. Actually, I think the storyline is really boring. It's just not complete. They both have difficult backgrounds, but those story's are just 'put in to the movie', without expanding them. It's like pieces of a puzzle which are put in the right order, but they're not actually put together. So, its kind of a boring story, but it really intrigued me at the same time. I think it's because of the actors, like people in other reviews have said. They make the boring characters alive. And maybe it's because they talk really little, in my opinion. And their faces tell the story. So I actually loved watching this movie, just in a whole different way than I expected at first. Maybe you don't understand what I mean, but then you have to watch the movie. Just don't expect a regular romantic comedy.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Dropout and the Foundling
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bkoganbing
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/3/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    When you cast Christian Slater in a part where he sends flowers to a complete stranger you never know what you're going get. It's not like he hasn't played off balance people before. And some might consider what he does to Mary Stuart Masterson as stalking. But Slater and Masterson make a fetching romantic couple in Bed Of Roses as a pair of lonely people looking for something or someone to complete them as a line in another film done in late 90s said. Slater has never been this romantic before or since on the big screen. Parts like he had in Kuffs, Pump Up The Volume, and Heathers are more like what he's identified with. Slater in fact was once in Masterson's world, he was a runner with Goldman&Sachs who lost a wife and child in childbirth. After that he just dropped out of it all and became a florist delivery man because flowers are beautiful and everyone is happy to see him when he delivers. Masterson is in that world now, but all she has is work. She was a foundling who was left at the Pittsburgh airport and raised in a foster home with a man who drank considerably and its hinted he may have done other terrible things to her. She has no romantic illusions, she does have work though and the world of high finance demands her attention completely. Bed Of Roses is a good, but not great film. It's lack of development of supporting characters is a big weakness. Still it's the definition of a star vehicle and the stars do shine in this one.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    mediocre movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    didiermustntdie
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/2/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    let's value it. entertainment: a trashy script which has been typed by unintelligent people in front of typewriters a thousand times.. pathetic acting that is thwarted by the story...OK production value, including good set/location and gorgeous girl.. -rating 4/10 social message: the movie has no social message. it's thought free... .but if I pretend I were 10, and my IQ were 70. I feel the message is:don't be afraid to love? -rating 0/10 objectionable things: nothing special, just the mild Jewish hedonic and arrogant attitude that is presented by the writer/director. generally speaking, good , nothing degenerate -8/10 overall rating is 4/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    It had its ups and downs
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    romanseight2004
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/4/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I thought some of it was good, and there were some original lines that I will likely take with me and use in appropriate situations. Both Slater and Masterson are wonderful actors, but there just wasn't any chemistry between them.I was also bothered by the fact that the little girl in the play was adorable. Wasn't the whole purpose of the play supposed to be for the ugly duckling? She was not believable as a hard case. I realize that was just a detail in the story, but it's an example of the lack of follow through that the movie had in many areas. It was very sweet and romantic however, with some lines I will remember.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    OK as Romance Flick.. but, uh - where is last chapter of Script?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    canuckteach
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/10/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The sentiments of my wife and myself are echoed well by many discerning viewers here at IMDb: Slater is great as a wonderful guy who loves people and falls in love with a girl he sees, for the first time, under 'unusual' circumstances (trying not to give anything away here). Masterson is a needy, but accomplished workaholic, who appears to have found the ideal guy. And the movie does have some nice set designs, warm family moments, and music. But, the Script is skimpy in places, particularly at the end!! I mean, my goodness - supposing the plane in 'Casablanca' carrying Rick's long-lost love away forever had to force-land at the Airport. Wouldn't you expect another 15 minutes of story to wrap up the loose ends? lol - supposing Bogart just walks off and says 'This is the beginning of a great friendship' to his policeman friend, and leaves Ilsa staring into the fog? yikes! Well, we couldn't believe in this case that the film was over!! huh? did we get a defective copy of the DVD? 'Sorry - great price on this DVD, but the last chapter of the Script is on Disc 2 (not included).' Actually, it is 'sort' of a happy ending, but I think FilmMaking-101 includes the rule "Don't open up plot points you can't develop and wrap up satisfactorily". 6/10 Guys: watch with secure marriage mate, or watch NFL instead! (--:
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    it's a really big step-up from 13 going on 30 and others.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    highschoolteen
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/1/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Bed of roses was an excellent movie. after watching it I literally cried MSM and CS make a perfect couple in the movie.SPOILER: although i think its awkward that CS walks nights looking into people's windows, creepy. it is cute that he's sort of like a secret admirer. he sends her roses after seeing her crying in her window (how cute). after they kiss and she shreds the flowers she goes back to him and he talks about his dead wife. well anyways if any of you love romantic comedy's than you should get Bed Of Roses, its a great movie. Spoiler: at first i thought Bed of Roses was going to be weird but obviously I was wrong. i really like the fact that MSM has a Tazer (you need your protection) its funny that she carries it in her purse. believe me you'll love this movie.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A big bouquet of happiness will be delivered to any viewer who chooses to watch this fine film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Amy Adler
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/2/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Lisa (Mary Stuart Masterson) is a rising businesswoman who rarely devotes herself to anything but work and more work. This is, in part, because of events that occurred during her childhood. She has a drop-in boyfriend who doesn't really spend any quality time with her but, Lisa is certain she likes it that way. That is, until the day a gorgeous bouquet of flowers is delivered to her at the office, without a card. Lisa calls friends and work colleagues to try to determine who sent her this gift. No luck. As a last resort, she goes to the florist and begs for information about the giver. She is stunned to learn that the delivery man, Lewis (Christian Slater) is her unknown fan. Lewis tells her about his interest in her and Lisa is cautious, of course. But, over the next few weeks, Lisa and Lewis become closer. Yet, something is wrong. What could it be? This is a quietly beautiful love story. Masterson is pretty and touching as the woman who doesn't know much about love and Slater is wonderful as the florist who learns to open up his heart again, too. The rest of the cast is nice and the script, costumes, sets and production values are very good. If you are drawn to stories of romance, this one should land on your must-see list. It is a bouquet of humor, heartache, and happy endings that will have you floating on air, smiling like crazy.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Warm and Wonderful
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gospelpicker
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/10/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Bed of Roses is easily one of the best romance movies ever. Even if the movie wasn't as good as it is, the soundtrack alone would make it worth watching. But, the movie itself is wonderful and full of warmth. Bed of Roses has the kind of story you would like to live out for yourself. True, people don't usually meet and fall in love the way Lewis and Lisa do in this movie, but isn't that the purpose of movies and music? The story and characters are as unique as they are addictive. When the movie ended, I found myself wanting more. This is one movie that will stick with you. I dare you to watch it only once. If you enjoyed Bed of Roses, you might also like At First Sight with Val Kilmer and Mira Sorvino.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Restraining order please...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    socalcarli
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/7/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I've tried to like this film, really. In watching it, all I can think is, "This guy gives me the creeps, I would have gotten a restraining order". It also calls out CODEPENDENCE in capital letters. Was this really the conversation before making the movie? "Let's make a film that puts two chronically depressed, socially inept people into a relationship which deepens their isolation and encourages them to complain about how bad their lives are!" From what I've seen in life is that the last thing on earth we find attractive in a potential mate is constant self-pity. The mood of the movie is distinctly 80-ish; brooding and slow. Don't get me wrong, the film has its moments, just very few of them.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    To my surprise, better than average love story
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    vincentlynch-moonoi
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This film is from that time period when someone thought Christian Slater could be a quirky (if not slightly creepy) romantic lead. I never believed it, although he did have several good roles in such pics. But quirky and creepy don't play well for long. So, I was a little surprised to find myself watching this film...and liking it. Although it took a while. The first third of the film sort of meanders along with a slightly creepy Slater romancing a workaholic loner of a girl (Mary Stuart Masterson). I began to wonder if this film was going anywhere interesting...you can look at just so many flowers being delivered. Then they begin living together and she is invited to his family's home for Christmas. Can she do it? No. Christmas is a disaster. The romance is off. They go their separate ways. Will they get back together? I could see an ending where she wants to but he is already with someone new, and she realizes that once again she has lost happiness. Or, I could see the happy ending we expect. I thought Masterson was downright superb in her role. And, Mr. Slater surprised me, as well. In fact, the final scene -- where she expresses her need and he appears to think no, not again -- as fine a piece of acting as you're likely to see in a romantic film. Pamela Adlon is excellent here as the best friend. On the other hand, Josh Brolin has a pretty-much-nothing role as a sort of boyfriend of Masterson. So, this was a much better film than I expected (at least after the first third). If you like love stories, this is better than most.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Surprisingly interesting
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Johanna
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I kind of love romantic comedy's because they're easy to watch and they'll always turn out to be what you expected them to be. This movie had the same 'contents' as all romantic movies do. Two people meet each other in a way people will never meet. She's hard to get, but he is so romantic, she falls for him. They turn out to be perfect for each other, but she's not telling something important. They fight. They get back together. They live happily ever after. But it turned out to be quite different than all the other movies at the same time. Actually, I think the storyline is really boring. It's just not complete. They both have difficult backgrounds, but those story's are just 'put in to the movie', without expanding them. It's like pieces of a puzzle which are put in the right order, but they're not actually put together. So, its kind of a boring story, but it really intrigued me at the same time. I think it's because of the actors, like people in other reviews have said. They make the boring characters alive. And maybe it's because they talk really little, in my opinion. And their faces tell the story. So I actually loved watching this movie, just in a whole different way than I expected at first. Maybe you don't understand what I mean, but then you have to watch the movie. Just don't expect a regular romantic comedy.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Dropout and the Foundling
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bkoganbing
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/3/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    When you cast Christian Slater in a part where he sends flowers to a complete stranger you never know what you're going get. It's not like he hasn't played off balance people before. And some might consider what he does to Mary Stuart Masterson as stalking. But Slater and Masterson make a fetching romantic couple in Bed Of Roses as a pair of lonely people looking for something or someone to complete them as a line in another film done in late 90s said. Slater has never been this romantic before or since on the big screen. Parts like he had in Kuffs, Pump Up The Volume, and Heathers are more like what he's identified with. Slater in fact was once in Masterson's world, he was a runner with Goldman&Sachs who lost a wife and child in childbirth. After that he just dropped out of it all and became a florist delivery man because flowers are beautiful and everyone is happy to see him when he delivers. Masterson is in that world now, but all she has is work. She was a foundling who was left at the Pittsburgh airport and raised in a foster home with a man who drank considerably and its hinted he may have done other terrible things to her. She has no romantic illusions, she does have work though and the world of high finance demands her attention completely. Bed Of Roses is a good, but not great film. It's lack of development of supporting characters is a big weakness. Still it's the definition of a star vehicle and the stars do shine in this one.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    mediocre movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    didiermustntdie
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/2/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    let's value it. entertainment: a trashy script which has been typed by unintelligent people in front of typewriters a thousand times.. pathetic acting that is thwarted by the story...OK production value, including good set/location and gorgeous girl.. -rating 4/10 social message: the movie has no social message. it's thought free... .but if I pretend I were 10, and my IQ were 70. I feel the message is:don't be afraid to love? -rating 0/10 objectionable things: nothing special, just the mild Jewish hedonic and arrogant attitude that is presented by the writer/director. generally speaking, good , nothing degenerate -8/10 overall rating is 4/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    It had its ups and downs
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    romanseight2004
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/4/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I thought some of it was good, and there were some original lines that I will likely take with me and use in appropriate situations. Both Slater and Masterson are wonderful actors, but there just wasn't any chemistry between them.I was also bothered by the fact that the little girl in the play was adorable. Wasn't the whole purpose of the play supposed to be for the ugly duckling? She was not believable as a hard case. I realize that was just a detail in the story, but it's an example of the lack of follow through that the movie had in many areas. It was very sweet and romantic however, with some lines I will remember.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    OK as Romance Flick.. but, uh - where is last chapter of Script?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    canuckteach
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/10/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The sentiments of my wife and myself are echoed well by many discerning viewers here at IMDb: Slater is great as a wonderful guy who loves people and falls in love with a girl he sees, for the first time, under 'unusual' circumstances (trying not to give anything away here). Masterson is a needy, but accomplished workaholic, who appears to have found the ideal guy. And the movie does have some nice set designs, warm family moments, and music. But, the Script is skimpy in places, particularly at the end!! I mean, my goodness - supposing the plane in 'Casablanca' carrying Rick's long-lost love away forever had to force-land at the Airport. Wouldn't you expect another 15 minutes of story to wrap up the loose ends? lol - supposing Bogart just walks off and says 'This is the beginning of a great friendship' to his policeman friend, and leaves Ilsa staring into the fog? yikes! Well, we couldn't believe in this case that the film was over!! huh? did we get a defective copy of the DVD? 'Sorry - great price on this DVD, but the last chapter of the Script is on Disc 2 (not included).' Actually, it is 'sort' of a happy ending, but I think FilmMaking-101 includes the rule "Don't open up plot points you can't develop and wrap up satisfactorily". 6/10 Guys: watch with secure marriage mate, or watch NFL instead! (--:
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    it's a really big step-up from 13 going on 30 and others.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    highschoolteen
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/1/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Bed of roses was an excellent movie. after watching it I literally cried MSM and CS make a perfect couple in the movie.SPOILER: although i think its awkward that CS walks nights looking into people's windows, creepy. it is cute that he's sort of like a secret admirer. he sends her roses after seeing her crying in her window (how cute). after they kiss and she shreds the flowers she goes back to him and he talks about his dead wife. well anyways if any of you love romantic comedy's than you should get Bed Of Roses, its a great movie. Spoiler: at first i thought Bed of Roses was going to be weird but obviously I was wrong. i really like the fact that MSM has a Tazer (you need your protection) its funny that she carries it in her purse. believe me you'll love this movie.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A big bouquet of happiness will be delivered to any viewer who chooses to watch this fine film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Amy Adler
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/2/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Lisa (Mary Stuart Masterson) is a rising businesswoman who rarely devotes herself to anything but work and more work. This is, in part, because of events that occurred during her childhood. She has a drop-in boyfriend who doesn't really spend any quality time with her but, Lisa is certain she likes it that way. That is, until the day a gorgeous bouquet of flowers is delivered to her at the office, without a card. Lisa calls friends and work colleagues to try to determine who sent her this gift. No luck. As a last resort, she goes to the florist and begs for information about the giver. She is stunned to learn that the delivery man, Lewis (Christian Slater) is her unknown fan. Lewis tells her about his interest in her and Lisa is cautious, of course. But, over the next few weeks, Lisa and Lewis become closer. Yet, something is wrong. What could it be? This is a quietly beautiful love story. Masterson is pretty and touching as the woman who doesn't know much about love and Slater is wonderful as the florist who learns to open up his heart again, too. The rest of the cast is nice and the script, costumes, sets and production values are very good. If you are drawn to stories of romance, this one should land on your must-see list. It is a bouquet of humor, heartache, and happy endings that will have you floating on air, smiling like crazy.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Warm and Wonderful
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gospelpicker
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/10/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Bed of Roses is easily one of the best romance movies ever. Even if the movie wasn't as good as it is, the soundtrack alone would make it worth watching. But, the movie itself is wonderful and full of warmth. Bed of Roses has the kind of story you would like to live out for yourself. True, people don't usually meet and fall in love the way Lewis and Lisa do in this movie, but isn't that the purpose of movies and music? The story and characters are as unique as they are addictive. When the movie ended, I found myself wanting more. This is one movie that will stick with you. I dare you to watch it only once. If you enjoyed Bed of Roses, you might also like At First Sight with Val Kilmer and Mira Sorvino.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Restraining order please...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    socalcarli
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/7/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I've tried to like this film, really. In watching it, all I can think is, "This guy gives me the creeps, I would have gotten a restraining order". It also calls out CODEPENDENCE in capital letters. Was this really the conversation before making the movie? "Let's make a film that puts two chronically depressed, socially inept people into a relationship which deepens their isolation and encourages them to complain about how bad their lives are!" From what I've seen in life is that the last thing on earth we find attractive in a potential mate is constant self-pity. The mood of the movie is distinctly 80-ish; brooding and slow. Don't get me wrong, the film has its moments, just very few of them.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    To my surprise, better than average love story
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    vincentlynch-moonoi
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This film is from that time period when someone thought Christian Slater could be a quirky (if not slightly creepy) romantic lead. I never believed it, although he did have several good roles in such pics. But quirky and creepy don't play well for long. So, I was a little surprised to find myself watching this film...and liking it. Although it took a while. The first third of the film sort of meanders along with a slightly creepy Slater romancing a workaholic loner of a girl (Mary Stuart Masterson). I began to wonder if this film was going anywhere interesting...you can look at just so many flowers being delivered. Then they begin living together and she is invited to his family's home for Christmas. Can she do it? No. Christmas is a disaster. The romance is off. They go their separate ways. Will they get back together? I could see an ending where she wants to but he is already with someone new, and she realizes that once again she has lost happiness. Or, I could see the happy ending we expect. I thought Masterson was downright superb in her role. And, Mr. Slater surprised me, as well. In fact, the final scene -- where she expresses her need and he appears to think no, not again -- as fine a piece of acting as you're likely to see in a romantic film. Pamela Adlon is excellent here as the best friend. On the other hand, Josh Brolin has a pretty-much-nothing role as a sort of boyfriend of Masterson. So, this was a much better film than I expected (at least after the first third). If you like love stories, this is better than most.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Surprisingly interesting
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Johanna
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I kind of love romantic comedy's because they're easy to watch and they'll always turn out to be what you expected them to be. This movie had the same 'contents' as all romantic movies do. Two people meet each other in a way people will never meet. She's hard to get, but he is so romantic, she falls for him. They turn out to be perfect for each other, but she's not telling something important. They fight. They get back together. They live happily ever after. But it turned out to be quite different than all the other movies at the same time. Actually, I think the storyline is really boring. It's just not complete. They both have difficult backgrounds, but those story's are just 'put in to the movie', without expanding them. It's like pieces of a puzzle which are put in the right order, but they're not actually put together. So, its kind of a boring story, but it really intrigued me at the same time. I think it's because of the actors, like people in other reviews have said. They make the boring characters alive. And maybe it's because they talk really little, in my opinion. And their faces tell the story. So I actually loved watching this movie, just in a whole different way than I expected at first. Maybe you don't understand what I mean, but then you have to watch the movie. Just don't expect a regular romantic comedy.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Dropout and the Foundling
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bkoganbing
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/3/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    When you cast Christian Slater in a part where he sends flowers to a complete stranger you never know what you're going get. It's not like he hasn't played off balance people before. And some might consider what he does to Mary Stuart Masterson as stalking. But Slater and Masterson make a fetching romantic couple in Bed Of Roses as a pair of lonely people looking for something or someone to complete them as a line in another film done in late 90s said. Slater has never been this romantic before or since on the big screen. Parts like he had in Kuffs, Pump Up The Volume, and Heathers are more like what he's identified with. Slater in fact was once in Masterson's world, he was a runner with Goldman&Sachs who lost a wife and child in childbirth. After that he just dropped out of it all and became a florist delivery man because flowers are beautiful and everyone is happy to see him when he delivers. Masterson is in that world now, but all she has is work. She was a foundling who was left at the Pittsburgh airport and raised in a foster home with a man who drank considerably and its hinted he may have done other terrible things to her. She has no romantic illusions, she does have work though and the world of high finance demands her attention completely. Bed Of Roses is a good, but not great film. It's lack of development of supporting characters is a big weakness. Still it's the definition of a star vehicle and the stars do shine in this one.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    mediocre movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    didiermustntdie
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/2/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    let's value it. entertainment: a trashy script which has been typed by unintelligent people in front of typewriters a thousand times.. pathetic acting that is thwarted by the story...OK production value, including good set/location and gorgeous girl.. -rating 4/10 social message: the movie has no social message. it's thought free... .but if I pretend I were 10, and my IQ were 70. I feel the message is:don't be afraid to love? -rating 0/10 objectionable things: nothing special, just the mild Jewish hedonic and arrogant attitude that is presented by the writer/director. generally speaking, good , nothing degenerate -8/10 overall rating is 4/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    It had its ups and downs
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    romanseight2004
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/4/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I thought some of it was good, and there were some original lines that I will likely take with me and use in appropriate situations. Both Slater and Masterson are wonderful actors, but there just wasn't any chemistry between them.I was also bothered by the fact that the little girl in the play was adorable. Wasn't the whole purpose of the play supposed to be for the ugly duckling? She was not believable as a hard case. I realize that was just a detail in the story, but it's an example of the lack of follow through that the movie had in many areas. It was very sweet and romantic however, with some lines I will remember.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    OK as Romance Flick.. but, uh - where is last chapter of Script?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    canuckteach
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/10/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The sentiments of my wife and myself are echoed well by many discerning viewers here at IMDb: Slater is great as a wonderful guy who loves people and falls in love with a girl he sees, for the first time, under 'unusual' circumstances (trying not to give anything away here). Masterson is a needy, but accomplished workaholic, who appears to have found the ideal guy. And the movie does have some nice set designs, warm family moments, and music. But, the Script is skimpy in places, particularly at the end!! I mean, my goodness - supposing the plane in 'Casablanca' carrying Rick's long-lost love away forever had to force-land at the Airport. Wouldn't you expect another 15 minutes of story to wrap up the loose ends? lol - supposing Bogart just walks off and says 'This is the beginning of a great friendship' to his policeman friend, and leaves Ilsa staring into the fog? yikes! Well, we couldn't believe in this case that the film was over!! huh? did we get a defective copy of the DVD? 'Sorry - great price on this DVD, but the last chapter of the Script is on Disc 2 (not included).' Actually, it is 'sort' of a happy ending, but I think FilmMaking-101 includes the rule "Don't open up plot points you can't develop and wrap up satisfactorily". 6/10 Guys: watch with secure marriage mate, or watch NFL instead! (--:
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    it's a really big step-up from 13 going on 30 and others.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    highschoolteen
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/1/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Bed of roses was an excellent movie. after watching it I literally cried MSM and CS make a perfect couple in the movie.SPOILER: although i think its awkward that CS walks nights looking into people's windows, creepy. it is cute that he's sort of like a secret admirer. he sends her roses after seeing her crying in her window (how cute). after they kiss and she shreds the flowers she goes back to him and he talks about his dead wife. well anyways if any of you love romantic comedy's than you should get Bed Of Roses, its a great movie. Spoiler: at first i thought Bed of Roses was going to be weird but obviously I was wrong. i really like the fact that MSM has a Tazer (you need your protection) its funny that she carries it in her purse. believe me you'll love this movie.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A big bouquet of happiness will be delivered to any viewer who chooses to watch this fine film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Amy Adler
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/2/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Lisa (Mary Stuart Masterson) is a rising businesswoman who rarely devotes herself to anything but work and more work. This is, in part, because of events that occurred during her childhood. She has a drop-in boyfriend who doesn't really spend any quality time with her but, Lisa is certain she likes it that way. That is, until the day a gorgeous bouquet of flowers is delivered to her at the office, without a card. Lisa calls friends and work colleagues to try to determine who sent her this gift. No luck. As a last resort, she goes to the florist and begs for information about the giver. She is stunned to learn that the delivery man, Lewis (Christian Slater) is her unknown fan. Lewis tells her about his interest in her and Lisa is cautious, of course. But, over the next few weeks, Lisa and Lewis become closer. Yet, something is wrong. What could it be? This is a quietly beautiful love story. Masterson is pretty and touching as the woman who doesn't know much about love and Slater is wonderful as the florist who learns to open up his heart again, too. The rest of the cast is nice and the script, costumes, sets and production values are very good. If you are drawn to stories of romance, this one should land on your must-see list. It is a bouquet of humor, heartache, and happy endings that will have you floating on air, smiling like crazy.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Warm and Wonderful
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gospelpicker
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/10/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Bed of Roses is easily one of the best romance movies ever. Even if the movie wasn't as good as it is, the soundtrack alone would make it worth watching. But, the movie itself is wonderful and full of warmth. Bed of Roses has the kind of story you would like to live out for yourself. True, people don't usually meet and fall in love the way Lewis and Lisa do in this movie, but isn't that the purpose of movies and music? The story and characters are as unique as they are addictive. When the movie ended, I found myself wanting more. This is one movie that will stick with you. I dare you to watch it only once. If you enjoyed Bed of Roses, you might also like At First Sight with Val Kilmer and Mira Sorvino.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Restraining order please...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    socalcarli
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/7/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I've tried to like this film, really. In watching it, all I can think is, "This guy gives me the creeps, I would have gotten a restraining order". It also calls out CODEPENDENCE in capital letters. Was this really the conversation before making the movie? "Let's make a film that puts two chronically depressed, socially inept people into a relationship which deepens their isolation and encourages them to complain about how bad their lives are!" From what I've seen in life is that the last thing on earth we find attractive in a potential mate is constant self-pity. The mood of the movie is distinctly 80-ish; brooding and slow. Don't get me wrong, the film has its moments, just very few of them.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    To my surprise, better than average love story
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    vincentlynch-moonoi
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This film is from that time period when someone thought Christian Slater could be a quirky (if not slightly creepy) romantic lead. I never believed it, although he did have several good roles in such pics. But quirky and creepy don't play well for long. So, I was a little surprised to find myself watching this film...and liking it. Although it took a while. The first third of the film sort of meanders along with a slightly creepy Slater romancing a workaholic loner of a girl (Mary Stuart Masterson). I began to wonder if this film was going anywhere interesting...you can look at just so many flowers being delivered. Then they begin living together and she is invited to his family's home for Christmas. Can she do it? No. Christmas is a disaster. The romance is off. They go their separate ways. Will they get back together? I could see an ending where she wants to but he is already with someone new, and she realizes that once again she has lost happiness. Or, I could see the happy ending we expect. I thought Masterson was downright superb in her role. And, Mr. Slater surprised me, as well. In fact, the final scene -- where she expresses her need and he appears to think no, not again -- as fine a piece of acting as you're likely to see in a romantic film. Pamela Adlon is excellent here as the best friend. On the other hand, Josh Brolin has a pretty-much-nothing role as a sort of boyfriend of Masterson. So, this was a much better film than I expected (at least after the first third). If you like love stories, this is better than most.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Surprisingly interesting
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Johanna
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I kind of love romantic comedy's because they're easy to watch and they'll always turn out to be what you expected them to be. This movie had the same 'contents' as all romantic movies do. Two people meet each other in a way people will never meet. She's hard to get, but he is so romantic, she falls for him. They turn out to be perfect for each other, but she's not telling something important. They fight. They get back together. They live happily ever after. But it turned out to be quite different than all the other movies at the same time. Actually, I think the storyline is really boring. It's just not complete. They both have difficult backgrounds, but those story's are just 'put in to the movie', without expanding them. It's like pieces of a puzzle which are put in the right order, but they're not actually put together. So, its kind of a boring story, but it really intrigued me at the same time. I think it's because of the actors, like people in other reviews have said. They make the boring characters alive. And maybe it's because they talk really little, in my opinion. And their faces tell the story. So I actually loved watching this movie, just in a whole different way than I expected at first. Maybe you don't understand what I mean, but then you have to watch the movie. Just don't expect a regular romantic comedy.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Dropout and the Foundling
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bkoganbing
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/3/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    When you cast Christian Slater in a part where he sends flowers to a complete stranger you never know what you're going get. It's not like he hasn't played off balance people before. And some might consider what he does to Mary Stuart Masterson as stalking. But Slater and Masterson make a fetching romantic couple in Bed Of Roses as a pair of lonely people looking for something or someone to complete them as a line in another film done in late 90s said. Slater has never been this romantic before or since on the big screen. Parts like he had in Kuffs, Pump Up The Volume, and Heathers are more like what he's identified with. Slater in fact was once in Masterson's world, he was a runner with Goldman&Sachs who lost a wife and child in childbirth. After that he just dropped out of it all and became a florist delivery man because flowers are beautiful and everyone is happy to see him when he delivers. Masterson is in that world now, but all she has is work. She was a foundling who was left at the Pittsburgh airport and raised in a foster home with a man who drank considerably and its hinted he may have done other terrible things to her. She has no romantic illusions, she does have work though and the world of high finance demands her attention completely. Bed Of Roses is a good, but not great film. It's lack of development of supporting characters is a big weakness. Still it's the definition of a star vehicle and the stars do shine in this one.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    mediocre movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    didiermustntdie
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/2/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    let's value it. entertainment: a trashy script which has been typed by unintelligent people in front of typewriters a thousand times.. pathetic acting that is thwarted by the story...OK production value, including good set/location and gorgeous girl.. -rating 4/10 social message: the movie has no social message. it's thought free... .but if I pretend I were 10, and my IQ were 70. I feel the message is:don't be afraid to love? -rating 0/10 objectionable things: nothing special, just the mild Jewish hedonic and arrogant attitude that is presented by the writer/director. generally speaking, good , nothing degenerate -8/10 overall rating is 4/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    It had its ups and downs
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    romanseight2004
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/4/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I thought some of it was good, and there were some original lines that I will likely take with me and use in appropriate situations. Both Slater and Masterson are wonderful actors, but there just wasn't any chemistry between them.I was also bothered by the fact that the little girl in the play was adorable. Wasn't the whole purpose of the play supposed to be for the ugly duckling? She was not believable as a hard case. I realize that was just a detail in the story, but it's an example of the lack of follow through that the movie had in many areas. It was very sweet and romantic however, with some lines I will remember.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    OK as Romance Flick.. but, uh - where is last chapter of Script?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    canuckteach
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/10/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The sentiments of my wife and myself are echoed well by many discerning viewers here at IMDb: Slater is great as a wonderful guy who loves people and falls in love with a girl he sees, for the first time, under 'unusual' circumstances (trying not to give anything away here). Masterson is a needy, but accomplished workaholic, who appears to have found the ideal guy. And the movie does have some nice set designs, warm family moments, and music. But, the Script is skimpy in places, particularly at the end!! I mean, my goodness - supposing the plane in 'Casablanca' carrying Rick's long-lost love away forever had to force-land at the Airport. Wouldn't you expect another 15 minutes of story to wrap up the loose ends? lol - supposing Bogart just walks off and says 'This is the beginning of a great friendship' to his policeman friend, and leaves Ilsa staring into the fog? yikes! Well, we couldn't believe in this case that the film was over!! huh? did we get a defective copy of the DVD? 'Sorry - great price on this DVD, but the last chapter of the Script is on Disc 2 (not included).' Actually, it is 'sort' of a happy ending, but I think FilmMaking-101 includes the rule "Don't open up plot points you can't develop and wrap up satisfactorily". 6/10 Guys: watch with secure marriage mate, or watch NFL instead! (--:
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    it's a really big step-up from 13 going on 30 and others.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    highschoolteen
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/1/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Bed of roses was an excellent movie. after watching it I literally cried MSM and CS make a perfect couple in the movie.SPOILER: although i think its awkward that CS walks nights looking into people's windows, creepy. it is cute that he's sort of like a secret admirer. he sends her roses after seeing her crying in her window (how cute). after they kiss and she shreds the flowers she goes back to him and he talks about his dead wife. well anyways if any of you love romantic comedy's than you should get Bed Of Roses, its a great movie. Spoiler: at first i thought Bed of Roses was going to be weird but obviously I was wrong. i really like the fact that MSM has a Tazer (you need your protection) its funny that she carries it in her purse. believe me you'll love this movie.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A big bouquet of happiness will be delivered to any viewer who chooses to watch this fine film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Amy Adler
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/2/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Lisa (Mary Stuart Masterson) is a rising businesswoman who rarely devotes herself to anything but work and more work. This is, in part, because of events that occurred during her childhood. She has a drop-in boyfriend who doesn't really spend any quality time with her but, Lisa is certain she likes it that way. That is, until the day a gorgeous bouquet of flowers is delivered to her at the office, without a card. Lisa calls friends and work colleagues to try to determine who sent her this gift. No luck. As a last resort, she goes to the florist and begs for information about the giver. She is stunned to learn that the delivery man, Lewis (Christian Slater) is her unknown fan. Lewis tells her about his interest in her and Lisa is cautious, of course. But, over the next few weeks, Lisa and Lewis become closer. Yet, something is wrong. What could it be? This is a quietly beautiful love story. Masterson is pretty and touching as the woman who doesn't know much about love and Slater is wonderful as the florist who learns to open up his heart again, too. The rest of the cast is nice and the script, costumes, sets and production values are very good. If you are drawn to stories of romance, this one should land on your must-see list. It is a bouquet of humor, heartache, and happy endings that will have you floating on air, smiling like crazy.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Warm and Wonderful
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gospelpicker
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/10/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Bed of Roses is easily one of the best romance movies ever. Even if the movie wasn't as good as it is, the soundtrack alone would make it worth watching. But, the movie itself is wonderful and full of warmth. Bed of Roses has the kind of story you would like to live out for yourself. True, people don't usually meet and fall in love the way Lewis and Lisa do in this movie, but isn't that the purpose of movies and music? The story and characters are as unique as they are addictive. When the movie ended, I found myself wanting more. This is one movie that will stick with you. I dare you to watch it only once. If you enjoyed Bed of Roses, you might also like At First Sight with Val Kilmer and Mira Sorvino.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Restraining order please...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    socalcarli
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/7/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I've tried to like this film, really. In watching it, all I can think is, "This guy gives me the creeps, I would have gotten a restraining order". It also calls out CODEPENDENCE in capital letters. Was this really the conversation before making the movie? "Let's make a film that puts two chronically depressed, socially inept people into a relationship which deepens their isolation and encourages them to complain about how bad their lives are!" From what I've seen in life is that the last thing on earth we find attractive in a potential mate is constant self-pity. The mood of the movie is distinctly 80-ish; brooding and slow. Don't get me wrong, the film has its moments, just very few of them.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
 </reviews>
</filme>
