<filme>
 <id>
  284
 </id>
 <imdburl>
  http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0117918
 </imdburl>
 <ano>
  1996
 </ano>
 <titulo>
  O Jogo da Paix&atilde;o
 </titulo>
 <rating>
  6.2
 </rating>
 <sinopse>
  A washed up golf pro working at a driving range tries to qualify for the US Open in order to win the heart of his succesful rival's girlfriend.
 </sinopse>
 <storyline>
  Roy 'Tin cup' McAvoy, a failed pro golfer who lives at the run-down driving range which he manages with his sidekick and caddy Romeo in the West Texas tin pot town of Salome, ends up signing over ownership to a madam of 'show girls' to pay off debts. His foxy novice golf pupil, female psychiatrist Dr. Molly Griswold, turns out to be the new girlfriend of McAvoy's sarcastic one-time college golf partner, slick PGA superstar David Simms, who drops by to play into Roy's fatal flaw: the inability to resist a dare, all too often causing him to lose against lesser players, in this case gambling away his car. Falling for Molly, Roy decides to become her patient; in order to earn her respect, he decides to try to qualify for the US Open, after starting off as Simm's caddy 'for the benefit of his experience'. His talent proves more then adequate, but over-confident negligence of risks, while pleasing the crowds, is murder on his scores, while Simms spits on the fans but never wastes a point...
 </storyline>
 <generos>
  <genero>
   Comedy
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Drama
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Romance
  </genero>
 </generos>
 <keywords>
  <keyword>
   golf
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   golfer
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   golf pro
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   golf club
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   golf course
  </keyword>
 </keywords>
 <diretores>
  <diretor>
   Ron Shelton
  </diretor>
 </diretores>
 <escritores>
  <escritor>
   John Norville
  </escritor>
  <escritor>
   Ron Shelton
  </escritor>
 </escritores>
 <atores>
  <ator>
   Kevin Costner
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Rene Russo
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Don Johnson
  </ator>
 </atores>
 <reviews>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Tin Cup Makes Golf Entertaining
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    SiliconDesertMan40
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Tin Cup is a romantic comedy that is co-written and directed by Ron Shelton. It stars Kevin Costner and Rene Russo together with Cheech Marin and Don Johnson in major supporting roles.This quirky love story is about a washed-up golf pro Roy "Tin Cup" McAvoy, who has the singular misfortune of falling in love with the girlfriend of his arch rival. Although he is inspired to re-ignite his golf career, challenge his opponent in the U.S. Open, and win the affection of the woman of his dreams, McAvoy has just one flaw: he's a show off when he should just focus on playing the game. Amiable and constantly amusing rather than uproarious, this mangy tale of a never-do-well's fitful assault on personal and professional respectability benefits greatly from Kevin Costner's ingratiatingly comic star turn.Overall,it accomplishes the impossible, maybe the unimaginable which is it makes golf entertaining.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Very very boring
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    sanliizzet
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/11/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Tin cup is one of the most boring movies I have ever seen. (Only comparable to Phenomenon of Travolta) Put aside the last ten minutes of US Open scenes, the whole movie is full of dull and boring dialogs and sub plots. I slept most of it. The movie force you to doze off involuntarily and makes you wake up here and there probably due to a high pithced Dolby sound when the actors slam a door or ingite a car to drive. The only redeeming value of the film is the beautiful look of Rene Russo despite her age. The lead hero is disgusting and not one to root for. Never seen Kevin so desperate and shabby like this. Good as a sleep pill, otherwise hell of a boring movie.... Avoid.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Actual event was basis for this movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    KenH
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/6/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    During the US Open this year they accosted Gary McCord as being the story for the movie. He actually took an 18 in a PGA event trying to get over the water. He admitted to it!! He said he just knew he could get it over the water. He had no excuses. This is tough with the rules of ten lines. I actually liked the movie. Odd as I think Costner is over rated. He plays the same part in every movie. I only like Tin Cup and Water world. He has no stretch in his acting. Same character in every movie with different things happening. He has no range in his acting ability. Hopefully this is ten lines......
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Perhaps one of the best golf films of all time.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    kpulis
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/7/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The film is every amateur golfer dream.The best serious golf movie in my mind. As far as comedy golf films, Happy Gilmore and Caddyshack were fun, but Tin Cup played out the dream of contending at the US Open and letting it all hang out! I personally am not a huge Kevin Costner fan, however having said that a number of his films seem to be on my top ten list of favourite films. Untouchables, Tip Cup, Field of Dreams are all awesome films. I gotta say I do respect him. He chooses his films well. Personally I like the ending of the film. A man facing his demons and confronting them head on, even with all odds being against him. I loved this film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A little gem
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Neil Welch
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/6/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I could care less about golf, but that doesn't matter - golf is just the hook upon which this movie is hung. I'm not always a fan of Kevin Costner, but when they do a retrospective of his work, this will be among his 10 best. This story of one man and his unusually fixated approach to certain matters is actually a fairly slight affair, but it has some fun performances running through it, and it is bookended by two wonderful, wonderful sequences. The first, near the start, is when Costner's has-been golf pro delivers a beautifully elegiac speech about the aesthetics of golf to Renee Russo. As someone who isn't a sports fan, that hooked me right at the start (my metaphor here is fishing, not golf). And the fabulous ending, true to the character and not to Hollywood expectations, is something to be treasured. This film is a little bit special.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Sports and romance clich&eacute;s get smothered by the Costner-Shelton swagger
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Movie_Muse_Reviews
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/8/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Underdog sports movies walk a fine line with clich&eacute;s; romantic comedies walk a fine line with clich&eacute;s. "Tin Cup" is both these things and walks the finest of the fine lines, and though it leans toward the clich&eacute;, it never completely loses its balance. Its likable swagger behind star Kevin Costner -- a similar swagger to that of "Bull Durham," also directed by Ron Shelton -- is what makes it one of the more memorable fault-filled sports movies. Like the previous (and slightly better) Costner-Shelton collaboration of "Durham," this film is a romantic sports comedy about a trashy/washed-up athlete who wastes a lot of talent and somehow manages to attract sexual attention. Costner stars as West Texan Roy McAvoy, referred to sometimes as 'Tin Cup,' a talented college golfer who somehow ended up a golf pro at a downtrodden driving range with his amigo Romeo (Cheech Marin) while his college teammate David Simms (Don Johnson) went on to be a star. Roy is a betting man who goes with his gut, ignores reason and uses golf metaphors to make sense of life. When an anal retentive psychiatrist named Molly (Rene Russo) shows up at his range for lessons, Roy is smitten, only to find she's with Simms. Of course the only way to win her over is to try and make the U.S. Open, right? Costner and Russo have forced character chemistry. There's no reason for either of them to be interested in each other, save that Roy wants a challenge compared to the white trash women he's interested in. There's certainly no reason for Molly to leave her tournament- winning boyfriend for a sleazeball. And you know it's true when the dialogue directly addresses why they fell for the other like it's justification or something. The machismo fueling Roy and his buddies in the movie, constantly betting each other and insulting the other when he lays up and plays it safe is childish, but it brings the film its humor and keeps it from being a straight through underdog movie. Its more interested in its characters than building up plot suspense, which is a good thing, if only the characters behaved in realistic ways. "Tin Cup" is a giant golf metaphor for life, about how taking risks -- no matter how many times you fail -- is always worth it. Shelton's film is gutsy in the same way, finding different ways of telling a sports story that will make it feel different. It goes about it in an amateur way, but it's the bravado that it will be remembered for. Shelton's films have this miraculous tendency to only let their best parts stick with you. They're the kinds of movies that make for great channel-surfing finds on TV. That's really what "Tin Cup" is. ~Steven C Visit my site at http://moviemusereviews.blogspot.com
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Very different
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    vranger
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/6/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Tin Cup" is a unique experience, in that after viewing this movie, you won't automatically compare it to any other film ... there isn't another one like it. It wrote in another review that all sports films contains many clich&eacute;s. Well, I have to contradict myself in describing this film about golf. It starts many clich&eacute;s, and then breaks them in half, sometimes literally! LOL Funny, charming, romantic, and defiant, Tin Cup gives you a bit of everything ... even a realistic ending but with a crumb thrown to the future at the same time. And the phrase "Tin Cup" made its way into sports talk for an event where a golfer REALLY screws up on a hole, especially if from stubbornness.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Supporting Cast Makes It Barely Watchable
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    grandpagbm
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/11/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    There are three reasons to watch this movie: Rene Russo, Cheech Marin, and Don Johnson. The rest of it is a waste of time. Kevin Costner's character, the protagonist, is a jerk from beginning to end. He never changes, he never learns anything, he is a total loser. I don't know whether to blame the script writer, the director, or Costner, but it doesn't really matter. The main character is entirely unsympathetic. Marin has some great lines, and he delivers them beautifully. Russo is sexy and plays her part perfectly. Johnson's performance is excellent, except for the one scene in which the director or scrip writer or someone decided that he needed to play completely out of character in order to make him the villain. It even appeared that he was embarrassed to have to do that scene, since it was totally inconsistent with the rest of his role. I will watch the film again, but just to enjoy watching Russo, Marin, and Johnson.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I didn't like "Tin Cup" so much but I liked the performances
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    (butchfilms@hotmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/10/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I think "Tin Cup" had the potential to be a much better movie. If this movie would have lasted 100 minutes instead of its 135 "Tin Cup" would have more that 6 stars. I liked the performances of Kevin Costner as Roy 'Tin Cup' McAvoy, Rene Russo as Dr. Molly Griswold, Don Johnson as David Simms and Cheech Marin as Romeo Posar. The plot of the movie is about Roy 'Tin Cup' McAvoy, a golf teacher in a very poor golf field, who once was a great college golf player. One day Roy will see again to his old enemy David Simms, and because of David and David's girlfriend, Dr. Molly Griswold, Roy will train with his caddy Romeo Posar to get in the US OPEN and win the tournament.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Kevin Costner not being Kevin Costner
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bgm2005
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/3/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie is perhaps my most watched movie that I don't own. Every time it's on TV, it seems to find my TV screen... even if I'm not looking for it. But even after multitudes of viewings, something struck me after watching it again tonight... what a GREAT job Kevin Costner did in this role! And WHY do I say that? Because this is one of his few films where I didn't realize I was watching Kevin Costner! Usually, he plays a role that's too big for him to chew... and you painfully watch him try to make something of it, all the while your conscience says, "I'm watching a Kevin Costner flick... this is painful". BUT NOT WITH TIN CUP. I actually found myself 2/3 through the movie quizzing myself on who the actor was... I could swear I've seen him somewhere before... Keven Costner totally loses himself in this role... so much so that he wonderfully loses his identity as Kevin Costner.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Tin Cup Makes Golf Entertaining
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    SiliconDesertMan40
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Tin Cup is a romantic comedy that is co-written and directed by Ron Shelton. It stars Kevin Costner and Rene Russo together with Cheech Marin and Don Johnson in major supporting roles.This quirky love story is about a washed-up golf pro Roy "Tin Cup" McAvoy, who has the singular misfortune of falling in love with the girlfriend of his arch rival. Although he is inspired to re-ignite his golf career, challenge his opponent in the U.S. Open, and win the affection of the woman of his dreams, McAvoy has just one flaw: he's a show off when he should just focus on playing the game. Amiable and constantly amusing rather than uproarious, this mangy tale of a never-do-well's fitful assault on personal and professional respectability benefits greatly from Kevin Costner's ingratiatingly comic star turn.Overall,it accomplishes the impossible, maybe the unimaginable which is it makes golf entertaining.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Very very boring
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    sanliizzet
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/11/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Tin cup is one of the most boring movies I have ever seen. (Only comparable to Phenomenon of Travolta) Put aside the last ten minutes of US Open scenes, the whole movie is full of dull and boring dialogs and sub plots. I slept most of it. The movie force you to doze off involuntarily and makes you wake up here and there probably due to a high pithced Dolby sound when the actors slam a door or ingite a car to drive. The only redeeming value of the film is the beautiful look of Rene Russo despite her age. The lead hero is disgusting and not one to root for. Never seen Kevin so desperate and shabby like this. Good as a sleep pill, otherwise hell of a boring movie.... Avoid.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Actual event was basis for this movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    KenH
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/6/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    During the US Open this year they accosted Gary McCord as being the story for the movie. He actually took an 18 in a PGA event trying to get over the water. He admitted to it!! He said he just knew he could get it over the water. He had no excuses. This is tough with the rules of ten lines. I actually liked the movie. Odd as I think Costner is over rated. He plays the same part in every movie. I only like Tin Cup and Water world. He has no stretch in his acting. Same character in every movie with different things happening. He has no range in his acting ability. Hopefully this is ten lines......
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Perhaps one of the best golf films of all time.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    kpulis
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/7/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The film is every amateur golfer dream.The best serious golf movie in my mind. As far as comedy golf films, Happy Gilmore and Caddyshack were fun, but Tin Cup played out the dream of contending at the US Open and letting it all hang out! I personally am not a huge Kevin Costner fan, however having said that a number of his films seem to be on my top ten list of favourite films. Untouchables, Tip Cup, Field of Dreams are all awesome films. I gotta say I do respect him. He chooses his films well. Personally I like the ending of the film. A man facing his demons and confronting them head on, even with all odds being against him. I loved this film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A little gem
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Neil Welch
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/6/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I could care less about golf, but that doesn't matter - golf is just the hook upon which this movie is hung. I'm not always a fan of Kevin Costner, but when they do a retrospective of his work, this will be among his 10 best. This story of one man and his unusually fixated approach to certain matters is actually a fairly slight affair, but it has some fun performances running through it, and it is bookended by two wonderful, wonderful sequences. The first, near the start, is when Costner's has-been golf pro delivers a beautifully elegiac speech about the aesthetics of golf to Renee Russo. As someone who isn't a sports fan, that hooked me right at the start (my metaphor here is fishing, not golf). And the fabulous ending, true to the character and not to Hollywood expectations, is something to be treasured. This film is a little bit special.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Sports and romance clich&eacute;s get smothered by the Costner-Shelton swagger
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Movie_Muse_Reviews
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/8/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Underdog sports movies walk a fine line with clich&eacute;s; romantic comedies walk a fine line with clich&eacute;s. "Tin Cup" is both these things and walks the finest of the fine lines, and though it leans toward the clich&eacute;, it never completely loses its balance. Its likable swagger behind star Kevin Costner -- a similar swagger to that of "Bull Durham," also directed by Ron Shelton -- is what makes it one of the more memorable fault-filled sports movies. Like the previous (and slightly better) Costner-Shelton collaboration of "Durham," this film is a romantic sports comedy about a trashy/washed-up athlete who wastes a lot of talent and somehow manages to attract sexual attention. Costner stars as West Texan Roy McAvoy, referred to sometimes as 'Tin Cup,' a talented college golfer who somehow ended up a golf pro at a downtrodden driving range with his amigo Romeo (Cheech Marin) while his college teammate David Simms (Don Johnson) went on to be a star. Roy is a betting man who goes with his gut, ignores reason and uses golf metaphors to make sense of life. When an anal retentive psychiatrist named Molly (Rene Russo) shows up at his range for lessons, Roy is smitten, only to find she's with Simms. Of course the only way to win her over is to try and make the U.S. Open, right? Costner and Russo have forced character chemistry. There's no reason for either of them to be interested in each other, save that Roy wants a challenge compared to the white trash women he's interested in. There's certainly no reason for Molly to leave her tournament- winning boyfriend for a sleazeball. And you know it's true when the dialogue directly addresses why they fell for the other like it's justification or something. The machismo fueling Roy and his buddies in the movie, constantly betting each other and insulting the other when he lays up and plays it safe is childish, but it brings the film its humor and keeps it from being a straight through underdog movie. Its more interested in its characters than building up plot suspense, which is a good thing, if only the characters behaved in realistic ways. "Tin Cup" is a giant golf metaphor for life, about how taking risks -- no matter how many times you fail -- is always worth it. Shelton's film is gutsy in the same way, finding different ways of telling a sports story that will make it feel different. It goes about it in an amateur way, but it's the bravado that it will be remembered for. Shelton's films have this miraculous tendency to only let their best parts stick with you. They're the kinds of movies that make for great channel-surfing finds on TV. That's really what "Tin Cup" is. ~Steven C Visit my site at http://moviemusereviews.blogspot.com
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Very different
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    vranger
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/6/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Tin Cup" is a unique experience, in that after viewing this movie, you won't automatically compare it to any other film ... there isn't another one like it. It wrote in another review that all sports films contains many clich&eacute;s. Well, I have to contradict myself in describing this film about golf. It starts many clich&eacute;s, and then breaks them in half, sometimes literally! LOL Funny, charming, romantic, and defiant, Tin Cup gives you a bit of everything ... even a realistic ending but with a crumb thrown to the future at the same time. And the phrase "Tin Cup" made its way into sports talk for an event where a golfer REALLY screws up on a hole, especially if from stubbornness.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Supporting Cast Makes It Barely Watchable
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    grandpagbm
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/11/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    There are three reasons to watch this movie: Rene Russo, Cheech Marin, and Don Johnson. The rest of it is a waste of time. Kevin Costner's character, the protagonist, is a jerk from beginning to end. He never changes, he never learns anything, he is a total loser. I don't know whether to blame the script writer, the director, or Costner, but it doesn't really matter. The main character is entirely unsympathetic. Marin has some great lines, and he delivers them beautifully. Russo is sexy and plays her part perfectly. Johnson's performance is excellent, except for the one scene in which the director or scrip writer or someone decided that he needed to play completely out of character in order to make him the villain. It even appeared that he was embarrassed to have to do that scene, since it was totally inconsistent with the rest of his role. I will watch the film again, but just to enjoy watching Russo, Marin, and Johnson.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I didn't like "Tin Cup" so much but I liked the performances
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    (butchfilms@hotmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/10/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I think "Tin Cup" had the potential to be a much better movie. If this movie would have lasted 100 minutes instead of its 135 "Tin Cup" would have more that 6 stars. I liked the performances of Kevin Costner as Roy 'Tin Cup' McAvoy, Rene Russo as Dr. Molly Griswold, Don Johnson as David Simms and Cheech Marin as Romeo Posar. The plot of the movie is about Roy 'Tin Cup' McAvoy, a golf teacher in a very poor golf field, who once was a great college golf player. One day Roy will see again to his old enemy David Simms, and because of David and David's girlfriend, Dr. Molly Griswold, Roy will train with his caddy Romeo Posar to get in the US OPEN and win the tournament.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Kevin Costner not being Kevin Costner
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bgm2005
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/3/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie is perhaps my most watched movie that I don't own. Every time it's on TV, it seems to find my TV screen... even if I'm not looking for it. But even after multitudes of viewings, something struck me after watching it again tonight... what a GREAT job Kevin Costner did in this role! And WHY do I say that? Because this is one of his few films where I didn't realize I was watching Kevin Costner! Usually, he plays a role that's too big for him to chew... and you painfully watch him try to make something of it, all the while your conscience says, "I'm watching a Kevin Costner flick... this is painful". BUT NOT WITH TIN CUP. I actually found myself 2/3 through the movie quizzing myself on who the actor was... I could swear I've seen him somewhere before... Keven Costner totally loses himself in this role... so much so that he wonderfully loses his identity as Kevin Costner.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Tin Cup Makes Golf Entertaining
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    SiliconDesertMan40
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Tin Cup is a romantic comedy that is co-written and directed by Ron Shelton. It stars Kevin Costner and Rene Russo together with Cheech Marin and Don Johnson in major supporting roles.This quirky love story is about a washed-up golf pro Roy "Tin Cup" McAvoy, who has the singular misfortune of falling in love with the girlfriend of his arch rival. Although he is inspired to re-ignite his golf career, challenge his opponent in the U.S. Open, and win the affection of the woman of his dreams, McAvoy has just one flaw: he's a show off when he should just focus on playing the game. Amiable and constantly amusing rather than uproarious, this mangy tale of a never-do-well's fitful assault on personal and professional respectability benefits greatly from Kevin Costner's ingratiatingly comic star turn.Overall,it accomplishes the impossible, maybe the unimaginable which is it makes golf entertaining.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Very very boring
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    sanliizzet
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/11/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Tin cup is one of the most boring movies I have ever seen. (Only comparable to Phenomenon of Travolta) Put aside the last ten minutes of US Open scenes, the whole movie is full of dull and boring dialogs and sub plots. I slept most of it. The movie force you to doze off involuntarily and makes you wake up here and there probably due to a high pithced Dolby sound when the actors slam a door or ingite a car to drive. The only redeeming value of the film is the beautiful look of Rene Russo despite her age. The lead hero is disgusting and not one to root for. Never seen Kevin so desperate and shabby like this. Good as a sleep pill, otherwise hell of a boring movie.... Avoid.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Actual event was basis for this movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    KenH
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/6/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    During the US Open this year they accosted Gary McCord as being the story for the movie. He actually took an 18 in a PGA event trying to get over the water. He admitted to it!! He said he just knew he could get it over the water. He had no excuses. This is tough with the rules of ten lines. I actually liked the movie. Odd as I think Costner is over rated. He plays the same part in every movie. I only like Tin Cup and Water world. He has no stretch in his acting. Same character in every movie with different things happening. He has no range in his acting ability. Hopefully this is ten lines......
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Perhaps one of the best golf films of all time.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    kpulis
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/7/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The film is every amateur golfer dream.The best serious golf movie in my mind. As far as comedy golf films, Happy Gilmore and Caddyshack were fun, but Tin Cup played out the dream of contending at the US Open and letting it all hang out! I personally am not a huge Kevin Costner fan, however having said that a number of his films seem to be on my top ten list of favourite films. Untouchables, Tip Cup, Field of Dreams are all awesome films. I gotta say I do respect him. He chooses his films well. Personally I like the ending of the film. A man facing his demons and confronting them head on, even with all odds being against him. I loved this film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A little gem
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Neil Welch
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/6/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I could care less about golf, but that doesn't matter - golf is just the hook upon which this movie is hung. I'm not always a fan of Kevin Costner, but when they do a retrospective of his work, this will be among his 10 best. This story of one man and his unusually fixated approach to certain matters is actually a fairly slight affair, but it has some fun performances running through it, and it is bookended by two wonderful, wonderful sequences. The first, near the start, is when Costner's has-been golf pro delivers a beautifully elegiac speech about the aesthetics of golf to Renee Russo. As someone who isn't a sports fan, that hooked me right at the start (my metaphor here is fishing, not golf). And the fabulous ending, true to the character and not to Hollywood expectations, is something to be treasured. This film is a little bit special.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Sports and romance clich&eacute;s get smothered by the Costner-Shelton swagger
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Movie_Muse_Reviews
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/8/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Underdog sports movies walk a fine line with clich&eacute;s; romantic comedies walk a fine line with clich&eacute;s. "Tin Cup" is both these things and walks the finest of the fine lines, and though it leans toward the clich&eacute;, it never completely loses its balance. Its likable swagger behind star Kevin Costner -- a similar swagger to that of "Bull Durham," also directed by Ron Shelton -- is what makes it one of the more memorable fault-filled sports movies. Like the previous (and slightly better) Costner-Shelton collaboration of "Durham," this film is a romantic sports comedy about a trashy/washed-up athlete who wastes a lot of talent and somehow manages to attract sexual attention. Costner stars as West Texan Roy McAvoy, referred to sometimes as 'Tin Cup,' a talented college golfer who somehow ended up a golf pro at a downtrodden driving range with his amigo Romeo (Cheech Marin) while his college teammate David Simms (Don Johnson) went on to be a star. Roy is a betting man who goes with his gut, ignores reason and uses golf metaphors to make sense of life. When an anal retentive psychiatrist named Molly (Rene Russo) shows up at his range for lessons, Roy is smitten, only to find she's with Simms. Of course the only way to win her over is to try and make the U.S. Open, right? Costner and Russo have forced character chemistry. There's no reason for either of them to be interested in each other, save that Roy wants a challenge compared to the white trash women he's interested in. There's certainly no reason for Molly to leave her tournament- winning boyfriend for a sleazeball. And you know it's true when the dialogue directly addresses why they fell for the other like it's justification or something. The machismo fueling Roy and his buddies in the movie, constantly betting each other and insulting the other when he lays up and plays it safe is childish, but it brings the film its humor and keeps it from being a straight through underdog movie. Its more interested in its characters than building up plot suspense, which is a good thing, if only the characters behaved in realistic ways. "Tin Cup" is a giant golf metaphor for life, about how taking risks -- no matter how many times you fail -- is always worth it. Shelton's film is gutsy in the same way, finding different ways of telling a sports story that will make it feel different. It goes about it in an amateur way, but it's the bravado that it will be remembered for. Shelton's films have this miraculous tendency to only let their best parts stick with you. They're the kinds of movies that make for great channel-surfing finds on TV. That's really what "Tin Cup" is. ~Steven C Visit my site at http://moviemusereviews.blogspot.com
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Very different
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    vranger
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/6/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Tin Cup" is a unique experience, in that after viewing this movie, you won't automatically compare it to any other film ... there isn't another one like it. It wrote in another review that all sports films contains many clich&eacute;s. Well, I have to contradict myself in describing this film about golf. It starts many clich&eacute;s, and then breaks them in half, sometimes literally! LOL Funny, charming, romantic, and defiant, Tin Cup gives you a bit of everything ... even a realistic ending but with a crumb thrown to the future at the same time. And the phrase "Tin Cup" made its way into sports talk for an event where a golfer REALLY screws up on a hole, especially if from stubbornness.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Supporting Cast Makes It Barely Watchable
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    grandpagbm
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/11/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    There are three reasons to watch this movie: Rene Russo, Cheech Marin, and Don Johnson. The rest of it is a waste of time. Kevin Costner's character, the protagonist, is a jerk from beginning to end. He never changes, he never learns anything, he is a total loser. I don't know whether to blame the script writer, the director, or Costner, but it doesn't really matter. The main character is entirely unsympathetic. Marin has some great lines, and he delivers them beautifully. Russo is sexy and plays her part perfectly. Johnson's performance is excellent, except for the one scene in which the director or scrip writer or someone decided that he needed to play completely out of character in order to make him the villain. It even appeared that he was embarrassed to have to do that scene, since it was totally inconsistent with the rest of his role. I will watch the film again, but just to enjoy watching Russo, Marin, and Johnson.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I didn't like "Tin Cup" so much but I liked the performances
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    (butchfilms@hotmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/10/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I think "Tin Cup" had the potential to be a much better movie. If this movie would have lasted 100 minutes instead of its 135 "Tin Cup" would have more that 6 stars. I liked the performances of Kevin Costner as Roy 'Tin Cup' McAvoy, Rene Russo as Dr. Molly Griswold, Don Johnson as David Simms and Cheech Marin as Romeo Posar. The plot of the movie is about Roy 'Tin Cup' McAvoy, a golf teacher in a very poor golf field, who once was a great college golf player. One day Roy will see again to his old enemy David Simms, and because of David and David's girlfriend, Dr. Molly Griswold, Roy will train with his caddy Romeo Posar to get in the US OPEN and win the tournament.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Kevin Costner not being Kevin Costner
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bgm2005
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/3/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie is perhaps my most watched movie that I don't own. Every time it's on TV, it seems to find my TV screen... even if I'm not looking for it. But even after multitudes of viewings, something struck me after watching it again tonight... what a GREAT job Kevin Costner did in this role! And WHY do I say that? Because this is one of his few films where I didn't realize I was watching Kevin Costner! Usually, he plays a role that's too big for him to chew... and you painfully watch him try to make something of it, all the while your conscience says, "I'm watching a Kevin Costner flick... this is painful". BUT NOT WITH TIN CUP. I actually found myself 2/3 through the movie quizzing myself on who the actor was... I could swear I've seen him somewhere before... Keven Costner totally loses himself in this role... so much so that he wonderfully loses his identity as Kevin Costner.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Tin Cup Makes Golf Entertaining
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    SiliconDesertMan40
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Tin Cup is a romantic comedy that is co-written and directed by Ron Shelton. It stars Kevin Costner and Rene Russo together with Cheech Marin and Don Johnson in major supporting roles.This quirky love story is about a washed-up golf pro Roy "Tin Cup" McAvoy, who has the singular misfortune of falling in love with the girlfriend of his arch rival. Although he is inspired to re-ignite his golf career, challenge his opponent in the U.S. Open, and win the affection of the woman of his dreams, McAvoy has just one flaw: he's a show off when he should just focus on playing the game. Amiable and constantly amusing rather than uproarious, this mangy tale of a never-do-well's fitful assault on personal and professional respectability benefits greatly from Kevin Costner's ingratiatingly comic star turn.Overall,it accomplishes the impossible, maybe the unimaginable which is it makes golf entertaining.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Very very boring
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    sanliizzet
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/11/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Tin cup is one of the most boring movies I have ever seen. (Only comparable to Phenomenon of Travolta) Put aside the last ten minutes of US Open scenes, the whole movie is full of dull and boring dialogs and sub plots. I slept most of it. The movie force you to doze off involuntarily and makes you wake up here and there probably due to a high pithced Dolby sound when the actors slam a door or ingite a car to drive. The only redeeming value of the film is the beautiful look of Rene Russo despite her age. The lead hero is disgusting and not one to root for. Never seen Kevin so desperate and shabby like this. Good as a sleep pill, otherwise hell of a boring movie.... Avoid.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Actual event was basis for this movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    KenH
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/6/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    During the US Open this year they accosted Gary McCord as being the story for the movie. He actually took an 18 in a PGA event trying to get over the water. He admitted to it!! He said he just knew he could get it over the water. He had no excuses. This is tough with the rules of ten lines. I actually liked the movie. Odd as I think Costner is over rated. He plays the same part in every movie. I only like Tin Cup and Water world. He has no stretch in his acting. Same character in every movie with different things happening. He has no range in his acting ability. Hopefully this is ten lines......
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Perhaps one of the best golf films of all time.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    kpulis
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/7/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The film is every amateur golfer dream.The best serious golf movie in my mind. As far as comedy golf films, Happy Gilmore and Caddyshack were fun, but Tin Cup played out the dream of contending at the US Open and letting it all hang out! I personally am not a huge Kevin Costner fan, however having said that a number of his films seem to be on my top ten list of favourite films. Untouchables, Tip Cup, Field of Dreams are all awesome films. I gotta say I do respect him. He chooses his films well. Personally I like the ending of the film. A man facing his demons and confronting them head on, even with all odds being against him. I loved this film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A little gem
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Neil Welch
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/6/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I could care less about golf, but that doesn't matter - golf is just the hook upon which this movie is hung. I'm not always a fan of Kevin Costner, but when they do a retrospective of his work, this will be among his 10 best. This story of one man and his unusually fixated approach to certain matters is actually a fairly slight affair, but it has some fun performances running through it, and it is bookended by two wonderful, wonderful sequences. The first, near the start, is when Costner's has-been golf pro delivers a beautifully elegiac speech about the aesthetics of golf to Renee Russo. As someone who isn't a sports fan, that hooked me right at the start (my metaphor here is fishing, not golf). And the fabulous ending, true to the character and not to Hollywood expectations, is something to be treasured. This film is a little bit special.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Sports and romance clich&eacute;s get smothered by the Costner-Shelton swagger
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Movie_Muse_Reviews
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/8/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Underdog sports movies walk a fine line with clich&eacute;s; romantic comedies walk a fine line with clich&eacute;s. "Tin Cup" is both these things and walks the finest of the fine lines, and though it leans toward the clich&eacute;, it never completely loses its balance. Its likable swagger behind star Kevin Costner -- a similar swagger to that of "Bull Durham," also directed by Ron Shelton -- is what makes it one of the more memorable fault-filled sports movies. Like the previous (and slightly better) Costner-Shelton collaboration of "Durham," this film is a romantic sports comedy about a trashy/washed-up athlete who wastes a lot of talent and somehow manages to attract sexual attention. Costner stars as West Texan Roy McAvoy, referred to sometimes as 'Tin Cup,' a talented college golfer who somehow ended up a golf pro at a downtrodden driving range with his amigo Romeo (Cheech Marin) while his college teammate David Simms (Don Johnson) went on to be a star. Roy is a betting man who goes with his gut, ignores reason and uses golf metaphors to make sense of life. When an anal retentive psychiatrist named Molly (Rene Russo) shows up at his range for lessons, Roy is smitten, only to find she's with Simms. Of course the only way to win her over is to try and make the U.S. Open, right? Costner and Russo have forced character chemistry. There's no reason for either of them to be interested in each other, save that Roy wants a challenge compared to the white trash women he's interested in. There's certainly no reason for Molly to leave her tournament- winning boyfriend for a sleazeball. And you know it's true when the dialogue directly addresses why they fell for the other like it's justification or something. The machismo fueling Roy and his buddies in the movie, constantly betting each other and insulting the other when he lays up and plays it safe is childish, but it brings the film its humor and keeps it from being a straight through underdog movie. Its more interested in its characters than building up plot suspense, which is a good thing, if only the characters behaved in realistic ways. "Tin Cup" is a giant golf metaphor for life, about how taking risks -- no matter how many times you fail -- is always worth it. Shelton's film is gutsy in the same way, finding different ways of telling a sports story that will make it feel different. It goes about it in an amateur way, but it's the bravado that it will be remembered for. Shelton's films have this miraculous tendency to only let their best parts stick with you. They're the kinds of movies that make for great channel-surfing finds on TV. That's really what "Tin Cup" is. ~Steven C Visit my site at http://moviemusereviews.blogspot.com
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Very different
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    vranger
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/6/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Tin Cup" is a unique experience, in that after viewing this movie, you won't automatically compare it to any other film ... there isn't another one like it. It wrote in another review that all sports films contains many clich&eacute;s. Well, I have to contradict myself in describing this film about golf. It starts many clich&eacute;s, and then breaks them in half, sometimes literally! LOL Funny, charming, romantic, and defiant, Tin Cup gives you a bit of everything ... even a realistic ending but with a crumb thrown to the future at the same time. And the phrase "Tin Cup" made its way into sports talk for an event where a golfer REALLY screws up on a hole, especially if from stubbornness.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Supporting Cast Makes It Barely Watchable
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    grandpagbm
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/11/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    There are three reasons to watch this movie: Rene Russo, Cheech Marin, and Don Johnson. The rest of it is a waste of time. Kevin Costner's character, the protagonist, is a jerk from beginning to end. He never changes, he never learns anything, he is a total loser. I don't know whether to blame the script writer, the director, or Costner, but it doesn't really matter. The main character is entirely unsympathetic. Marin has some great lines, and he delivers them beautifully. Russo is sexy and plays her part perfectly. Johnson's performance is excellent, except for the one scene in which the director or scrip writer or someone decided that he needed to play completely out of character in order to make him the villain. It even appeared that he was embarrassed to have to do that scene, since it was totally inconsistent with the rest of his role. I will watch the film again, but just to enjoy watching Russo, Marin, and Johnson.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I didn't like "Tin Cup" so much but I liked the performances
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    (butchfilms@hotmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/10/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I think "Tin Cup" had the potential to be a much better movie. If this movie would have lasted 100 minutes instead of its 135 "Tin Cup" would have more that 6 stars. I liked the performances of Kevin Costner as Roy 'Tin Cup' McAvoy, Rene Russo as Dr. Molly Griswold, Don Johnson as David Simms and Cheech Marin as Romeo Posar. The plot of the movie is about Roy 'Tin Cup' McAvoy, a golf teacher in a very poor golf field, who once was a great college golf player. One day Roy will see again to his old enemy David Simms, and because of David and David's girlfriend, Dr. Molly Griswold, Roy will train with his caddy Romeo Posar to get in the US OPEN and win the tournament.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Kevin Costner not being Kevin Costner
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bgm2005
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/3/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie is perhaps my most watched movie that I don't own. Every time it's on TV, it seems to find my TV screen... even if I'm not looking for it. But even after multitudes of viewings, something struck me after watching it again tonight... what a GREAT job Kevin Costner did in this role! And WHY do I say that? Because this is one of his few films where I didn't realize I was watching Kevin Costner! Usually, he plays a role that's too big for him to chew... and you painfully watch him try to make something of it, all the while your conscience says, "I'm watching a Kevin Costner flick... this is painful". BUT NOT WITH TIN CUP. I actually found myself 2/3 through the movie quizzing myself on who the actor was... I could swear I've seen him somewhere before... Keven Costner totally loses himself in this role... so much so that he wonderfully loses his identity as Kevin Costner.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Tin Cup Makes Golf Entertaining
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    SiliconDesertMan40
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Tin Cup is a romantic comedy that is co-written and directed by Ron Shelton. It stars Kevin Costner and Rene Russo together with Cheech Marin and Don Johnson in major supporting roles.This quirky love story is about a washed-up golf pro Roy "Tin Cup" McAvoy, who has the singular misfortune of falling in love with the girlfriend of his arch rival. Although he is inspired to re-ignite his golf career, challenge his opponent in the U.S. Open, and win the affection of the woman of his dreams, McAvoy has just one flaw: he's a show off when he should just focus on playing the game. Amiable and constantly amusing rather than uproarious, this mangy tale of a never-do-well's fitful assault on personal and professional respectability benefits greatly from Kevin Costner's ingratiatingly comic star turn.Overall,it accomplishes the impossible, maybe the unimaginable which is it makes golf entertaining.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Very very boring
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    sanliizzet
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/11/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Tin cup is one of the most boring movies I have ever seen. (Only comparable to Phenomenon of Travolta) Put aside the last ten minutes of US Open scenes, the whole movie is full of dull and boring dialogs and sub plots. I slept most of it. The movie force you to doze off involuntarily and makes you wake up here and there probably due to a high pithced Dolby sound when the actors slam a door or ingite a car to drive. The only redeeming value of the film is the beautiful look of Rene Russo despite her age. The lead hero is disgusting and not one to root for. Never seen Kevin so desperate and shabby like this. Good as a sleep pill, otherwise hell of a boring movie.... Avoid.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Actual event was basis for this movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    KenH
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/6/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    During the US Open this year they accosted Gary McCord as being the story for the movie. He actually took an 18 in a PGA event trying to get over the water. He admitted to it!! He said he just knew he could get it over the water. He had no excuses. This is tough with the rules of ten lines. I actually liked the movie. Odd as I think Costner is over rated. He plays the same part in every movie. I only like Tin Cup and Water world. He has no stretch in his acting. Same character in every movie with different things happening. He has no range in his acting ability. Hopefully this is ten lines......
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Perhaps one of the best golf films of all time.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    kpulis
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/7/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The film is every amateur golfer dream.The best serious golf movie in my mind. As far as comedy golf films, Happy Gilmore and Caddyshack were fun, but Tin Cup played out the dream of contending at the US Open and letting it all hang out! I personally am not a huge Kevin Costner fan, however having said that a number of his films seem to be on my top ten list of favourite films. Untouchables, Tip Cup, Field of Dreams are all awesome films. I gotta say I do respect him. He chooses his films well. Personally I like the ending of the film. A man facing his demons and confronting them head on, even with all odds being against him. I loved this film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A little gem
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Neil Welch
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/6/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I could care less about golf, but that doesn't matter - golf is just the hook upon which this movie is hung. I'm not always a fan of Kevin Costner, but when they do a retrospective of his work, this will be among his 10 best. This story of one man and his unusually fixated approach to certain matters is actually a fairly slight affair, but it has some fun performances running through it, and it is bookended by two wonderful, wonderful sequences. The first, near the start, is when Costner's has-been golf pro delivers a beautifully elegiac speech about the aesthetics of golf to Renee Russo. As someone who isn't a sports fan, that hooked me right at the start (my metaphor here is fishing, not golf). And the fabulous ending, true to the character and not to Hollywood expectations, is something to be treasured. This film is a little bit special.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Sports and romance clich&eacute;s get smothered by the Costner-Shelton swagger
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Movie_Muse_Reviews
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/8/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Underdog sports movies walk a fine line with clich&eacute;s; romantic comedies walk a fine line with clich&eacute;s. "Tin Cup" is both these things and walks the finest of the fine lines, and though it leans toward the clich&eacute;, it never completely loses its balance. Its likable swagger behind star Kevin Costner -- a similar swagger to that of "Bull Durham," also directed by Ron Shelton -- is what makes it one of the more memorable fault-filled sports movies. Like the previous (and slightly better) Costner-Shelton collaboration of "Durham," this film is a romantic sports comedy about a trashy/washed-up athlete who wastes a lot of talent and somehow manages to attract sexual attention. Costner stars as West Texan Roy McAvoy, referred to sometimes as 'Tin Cup,' a talented college golfer who somehow ended up a golf pro at a downtrodden driving range with his amigo Romeo (Cheech Marin) while his college teammate David Simms (Don Johnson) went on to be a star. Roy is a betting man who goes with his gut, ignores reason and uses golf metaphors to make sense of life. When an anal retentive psychiatrist named Molly (Rene Russo) shows up at his range for lessons, Roy is smitten, only to find she's with Simms. Of course the only way to win her over is to try and make the U.S. Open, right? Costner and Russo have forced character chemistry. There's no reason for either of them to be interested in each other, save that Roy wants a challenge compared to the white trash women he's interested in. There's certainly no reason for Molly to leave her tournament- winning boyfriend for a sleazeball. And you know it's true when the dialogue directly addresses why they fell for the other like it's justification or something. The machismo fueling Roy and his buddies in the movie, constantly betting each other and insulting the other when he lays up and plays it safe is childish, but it brings the film its humor and keeps it from being a straight through underdog movie. Its more interested in its characters than building up plot suspense, which is a good thing, if only the characters behaved in realistic ways. "Tin Cup" is a giant golf metaphor for life, about how taking risks -- no matter how many times you fail -- is always worth it. Shelton's film is gutsy in the same way, finding different ways of telling a sports story that will make it feel different. It goes about it in an amateur way, but it's the bravado that it will be remembered for. Shelton's films have this miraculous tendency to only let their best parts stick with you. They're the kinds of movies that make for great channel-surfing finds on TV. That's really what "Tin Cup" is. ~Steven C Visit my site at http://moviemusereviews.blogspot.com
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Very different
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    vranger
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/6/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Tin Cup" is a unique experience, in that after viewing this movie, you won't automatically compare it to any other film ... there isn't another one like it. It wrote in another review that all sports films contains many clich&eacute;s. Well, I have to contradict myself in describing this film about golf. It starts many clich&eacute;s, and then breaks them in half, sometimes literally! LOL Funny, charming, romantic, and defiant, Tin Cup gives you a bit of everything ... even a realistic ending but with a crumb thrown to the future at the same time. And the phrase "Tin Cup" made its way into sports talk for an event where a golfer REALLY screws up on a hole, especially if from stubbornness.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Supporting Cast Makes It Barely Watchable
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    grandpagbm
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/11/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    There are three reasons to watch this movie: Rene Russo, Cheech Marin, and Don Johnson. The rest of it is a waste of time. Kevin Costner's character, the protagonist, is a jerk from beginning to end. He never changes, he never learns anything, he is a total loser. I don't know whether to blame the script writer, the director, or Costner, but it doesn't really matter. The main character is entirely unsympathetic. Marin has some great lines, and he delivers them beautifully. Russo is sexy and plays her part perfectly. Johnson's performance is excellent, except for the one scene in which the director or scrip writer or someone decided that he needed to play completely out of character in order to make him the villain. It even appeared that he was embarrassed to have to do that scene, since it was totally inconsistent with the rest of his role. I will watch the film again, but just to enjoy watching Russo, Marin, and Johnson.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I didn't like "Tin Cup" so much but I liked the performances
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    (butchfilms@hotmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/10/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I think "Tin Cup" had the potential to be a much better movie. If this movie would have lasted 100 minutes instead of its 135 "Tin Cup" would have more that 6 stars. I liked the performances of Kevin Costner as Roy 'Tin Cup' McAvoy, Rene Russo as Dr. Molly Griswold, Don Johnson as David Simms and Cheech Marin as Romeo Posar. The plot of the movie is about Roy 'Tin Cup' McAvoy, a golf teacher in a very poor golf field, who once was a great college golf player. One day Roy will see again to his old enemy David Simms, and because of David and David's girlfriend, Dr. Molly Griswold, Roy will train with his caddy Romeo Posar to get in the US OPEN and win the tournament.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Kevin Costner not being Kevin Costner
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bgm2005
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/3/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie is perhaps my most watched movie that I don't own. Every time it's on TV, it seems to find my TV screen... even if I'm not looking for it. But even after multitudes of viewings, something struck me after watching it again tonight... what a GREAT job Kevin Costner did in this role! And WHY do I say that? Because this is one of his few films where I didn't realize I was watching Kevin Costner! Usually, he plays a role that's too big for him to chew... and you painfully watch him try to make something of it, all the while your conscience says, "I'm watching a Kevin Costner flick... this is painful". BUT NOT WITH TIN CUP. I actually found myself 2/3 through the movie quizzing myself on who the actor was... I could swear I've seen him somewhere before... Keven Costner totally loses himself in this role... so much so that he wonderfully loses his identity as Kevin Costner.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Tin Cup Makes Golf Entertaining
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    SiliconDesertMan40
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Tin Cup is a romantic comedy that is co-written and directed by Ron Shelton. It stars Kevin Costner and Rene Russo together with Cheech Marin and Don Johnson in major supporting roles.This quirky love story is about a washed-up golf pro Roy "Tin Cup" McAvoy, who has the singular misfortune of falling in love with the girlfriend of his arch rival. Although he is inspired to re-ignite his golf career, challenge his opponent in the U.S. Open, and win the affection of the woman of his dreams, McAvoy has just one flaw: he's a show off when he should just focus on playing the game. Amiable and constantly amusing rather than uproarious, this mangy tale of a never-do-well's fitful assault on personal and professional respectability benefits greatly from Kevin Costner's ingratiatingly comic star turn.Overall,it accomplishes the impossible, maybe the unimaginable which is it makes golf entertaining.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Very very boring
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    sanliizzet
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/11/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Tin cup is one of the most boring movies I have ever seen. (Only comparable to Phenomenon of Travolta) Put aside the last ten minutes of US Open scenes, the whole movie is full of dull and boring dialogs and sub plots. I slept most of it. The movie force you to doze off involuntarily and makes you wake up here and there probably due to a high pithced Dolby sound when the actors slam a door or ingite a car to drive. The only redeeming value of the film is the beautiful look of Rene Russo despite her age. The lead hero is disgusting and not one to root for. Never seen Kevin so desperate and shabby like this. Good as a sleep pill, otherwise hell of a boring movie.... Avoid.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Actual event was basis for this movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    KenH
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/6/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    During the US Open this year they accosted Gary McCord as being the story for the movie. He actually took an 18 in a PGA event trying to get over the water. He admitted to it!! He said he just knew he could get it over the water. He had no excuses. This is tough with the rules of ten lines. I actually liked the movie. Odd as I think Costner is over rated. He plays the same part in every movie. I only like Tin Cup and Water world. He has no stretch in his acting. Same character in every movie with different things happening. He has no range in his acting ability. Hopefully this is ten lines......
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Perhaps one of the best golf films of all time.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    kpulis
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/7/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The film is every amateur golfer dream.The best serious golf movie in my mind. As far as comedy golf films, Happy Gilmore and Caddyshack were fun, but Tin Cup played out the dream of contending at the US Open and letting it all hang out! I personally am not a huge Kevin Costner fan, however having said that a number of his films seem to be on my top ten list of favourite films. Untouchables, Tip Cup, Field of Dreams are all awesome films. I gotta say I do respect him. He chooses his films well. Personally I like the ending of the film. A man facing his demons and confronting them head on, even with all odds being against him. I loved this film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A little gem
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Neil Welch
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/6/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I could care less about golf, but that doesn't matter - golf is just the hook upon which this movie is hung. I'm not always a fan of Kevin Costner, but when they do a retrospective of his work, this will be among his 10 best. This story of one man and his unusually fixated approach to certain matters is actually a fairly slight affair, but it has some fun performances running through it, and it is bookended by two wonderful, wonderful sequences. The first, near the start, is when Costner's has-been golf pro delivers a beautifully elegiac speech about the aesthetics of golf to Renee Russo. As someone who isn't a sports fan, that hooked me right at the start (my metaphor here is fishing, not golf). And the fabulous ending, true to the character and not to Hollywood expectations, is something to be treasured. This film is a little bit special.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Sports and romance clich&eacute;s get smothered by the Costner-Shelton swagger
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Movie_Muse_Reviews
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/8/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Underdog sports movies walk a fine line with clich&eacute;s; romantic comedies walk a fine line with clich&eacute;s. "Tin Cup" is both these things and walks the finest of the fine lines, and though it leans toward the clich&eacute;, it never completely loses its balance. Its likable swagger behind star Kevin Costner -- a similar swagger to that of "Bull Durham," also directed by Ron Shelton -- is what makes it one of the more memorable fault-filled sports movies. Like the previous (and slightly better) Costner-Shelton collaboration of "Durham," this film is a romantic sports comedy about a trashy/washed-up athlete who wastes a lot of talent and somehow manages to attract sexual attention. Costner stars as West Texan Roy McAvoy, referred to sometimes as 'Tin Cup,' a talented college golfer who somehow ended up a golf pro at a downtrodden driving range with his amigo Romeo (Cheech Marin) while his college teammate David Simms (Don Johnson) went on to be a star. Roy is a betting man who goes with his gut, ignores reason and uses golf metaphors to make sense of life. When an anal retentive psychiatrist named Molly (Rene Russo) shows up at his range for lessons, Roy is smitten, only to find she's with Simms. Of course the only way to win her over is to try and make the U.S. Open, right? Costner and Russo have forced character chemistry. There's no reason for either of them to be interested in each other, save that Roy wants a challenge compared to the white trash women he's interested in. There's certainly no reason for Molly to leave her tournament- winning boyfriend for a sleazeball. And you know it's true when the dialogue directly addresses why they fell for the other like it's justification or something. The machismo fueling Roy and his buddies in the movie, constantly betting each other and insulting the other when he lays up and plays it safe is childish, but it brings the film its humor and keeps it from being a straight through underdog movie. Its more interested in its characters than building up plot suspense, which is a good thing, if only the characters behaved in realistic ways. "Tin Cup" is a giant golf metaphor for life, about how taking risks -- no matter how many times you fail -- is always worth it. Shelton's film is gutsy in the same way, finding different ways of telling a sports story that will make it feel different. It goes about it in an amateur way, but it's the bravado that it will be remembered for. Shelton's films have this miraculous tendency to only let their best parts stick with you. They're the kinds of movies that make for great channel-surfing finds on TV. That's really what "Tin Cup" is. ~Steven C Visit my site at http://moviemusereviews.blogspot.com
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Very different
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    vranger
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/6/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Tin Cup" is a unique experience, in that after viewing this movie, you won't automatically compare it to any other film ... there isn't another one like it. It wrote in another review that all sports films contains many clich&eacute;s. Well, I have to contradict myself in describing this film about golf. It starts many clich&eacute;s, and then breaks them in half, sometimes literally! LOL Funny, charming, romantic, and defiant, Tin Cup gives you a bit of everything ... even a realistic ending but with a crumb thrown to the future at the same time. And the phrase "Tin Cup" made its way into sports talk for an event where a golfer REALLY screws up on a hole, especially if from stubbornness.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Supporting Cast Makes It Barely Watchable
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    grandpagbm
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/11/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    There are three reasons to watch this movie: Rene Russo, Cheech Marin, and Don Johnson. The rest of it is a waste of time. Kevin Costner's character, the protagonist, is a jerk from beginning to end. He never changes, he never learns anything, he is a total loser. I don't know whether to blame the script writer, the director, or Costner, but it doesn't really matter. The main character is entirely unsympathetic. Marin has some great lines, and he delivers them beautifully. Russo is sexy and plays her part perfectly. Johnson's performance is excellent, except for the one scene in which the director or scrip writer or someone decided that he needed to play completely out of character in order to make him the villain. It even appeared that he was embarrassed to have to do that scene, since it was totally inconsistent with the rest of his role. I will watch the film again, but just to enjoy watching Russo, Marin, and Johnson.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I didn't like "Tin Cup" so much but I liked the performances
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    (butchfilms@hotmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/10/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I think "Tin Cup" had the potential to be a much better movie. If this movie would have lasted 100 minutes instead of its 135 "Tin Cup" would have more that 6 stars. I liked the performances of Kevin Costner as Roy 'Tin Cup' McAvoy, Rene Russo as Dr. Molly Griswold, Don Johnson as David Simms and Cheech Marin as Romeo Posar. The plot of the movie is about Roy 'Tin Cup' McAvoy, a golf teacher in a very poor golf field, who once was a great college golf player. One day Roy will see again to his old enemy David Simms, and because of David and David's girlfriend, Dr. Molly Griswold, Roy will train with his caddy Romeo Posar to get in the US OPEN and win the tournament.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Kevin Costner not being Kevin Costner
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bgm2005
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/3/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie is perhaps my most watched movie that I don't own. Every time it's on TV, it seems to find my TV screen... even if I'm not looking for it. But even after multitudes of viewings, something struck me after watching it again tonight... what a GREAT job Kevin Costner did in this role! And WHY do I say that? Because this is one of his few films where I didn't realize I was watching Kevin Costner! Usually, he plays a role that's too big for him to chew... and you painfully watch him try to make something of it, all the while your conscience says, "I'm watching a Kevin Costner flick... this is painful". BUT NOT WITH TIN CUP. I actually found myself 2/3 through the movie quizzing myself on who the actor was... I could swear I've seen him somewhere before... Keven Costner totally loses himself in this role... so much so that he wonderfully loses his identity as Kevin Costner.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Tin Cup Makes Golf Entertaining
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    SiliconDesertMan40
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Tin Cup is a romantic comedy that is co-written and directed by Ron Shelton. It stars Kevin Costner and Rene Russo together with Cheech Marin and Don Johnson in major supporting roles.This quirky love story is about a washed-up golf pro Roy "Tin Cup" McAvoy, who has the singular misfortune of falling in love with the girlfriend of his arch rival. Although he is inspired to re-ignite his golf career, challenge his opponent in the U.S. Open, and win the affection of the woman of his dreams, McAvoy has just one flaw: he's a show off when he should just focus on playing the game. Amiable and constantly amusing rather than uproarious, this mangy tale of a never-do-well's fitful assault on personal and professional respectability benefits greatly from Kevin Costner's ingratiatingly comic star turn.Overall,it accomplishes the impossible, maybe the unimaginable which is it makes golf entertaining.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Very very boring
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    sanliizzet
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/11/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Tin cup is one of the most boring movies I have ever seen. (Only comparable to Phenomenon of Travolta) Put aside the last ten minutes of US Open scenes, the whole movie is full of dull and boring dialogs and sub plots. I slept most of it. The movie force you to doze off involuntarily and makes you wake up here and there probably due to a high pithced Dolby sound when the actors slam a door or ingite a car to drive. The only redeeming value of the film is the beautiful look of Rene Russo despite her age. The lead hero is disgusting and not one to root for. Never seen Kevin so desperate and shabby like this. Good as a sleep pill, otherwise hell of a boring movie.... Avoid.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Actual event was basis for this movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    KenH
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/6/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    During the US Open this year they accosted Gary McCord as being the story for the movie. He actually took an 18 in a PGA event trying to get over the water. He admitted to it!! He said he just knew he could get it over the water. He had no excuses. This is tough with the rules of ten lines. I actually liked the movie. Odd as I think Costner is over rated. He plays the same part in every movie. I only like Tin Cup and Water world. He has no stretch in his acting. Same character in every movie with different things happening. He has no range in his acting ability. Hopefully this is ten lines......
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Perhaps one of the best golf films of all time.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    kpulis
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/7/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The film is every amateur golfer dream.The best serious golf movie in my mind. As far as comedy golf films, Happy Gilmore and Caddyshack were fun, but Tin Cup played out the dream of contending at the US Open and letting it all hang out! I personally am not a huge Kevin Costner fan, however having said that a number of his films seem to be on my top ten list of favourite films. Untouchables, Tip Cup, Field of Dreams are all awesome films. I gotta say I do respect him. He chooses his films well. Personally I like the ending of the film. A man facing his demons and confronting them head on, even with all odds being against him. I loved this film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A little gem
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Neil Welch
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/6/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I could care less about golf, but that doesn't matter - golf is just the hook upon which this movie is hung. I'm not always a fan of Kevin Costner, but when they do a retrospective of his work, this will be among his 10 best. This story of one man and his unusually fixated approach to certain matters is actually a fairly slight affair, but it has some fun performances running through it, and it is bookended by two wonderful, wonderful sequences. The first, near the start, is when Costner's has-been golf pro delivers a beautifully elegiac speech about the aesthetics of golf to Renee Russo. As someone who isn't a sports fan, that hooked me right at the start (my metaphor here is fishing, not golf). And the fabulous ending, true to the character and not to Hollywood expectations, is something to be treasured. This film is a little bit special.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Sports and romance clich&eacute;s get smothered by the Costner-Shelton swagger
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Movie_Muse_Reviews
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/8/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Underdog sports movies walk a fine line with clich&eacute;s; romantic comedies walk a fine line with clich&eacute;s. "Tin Cup" is both these things and walks the finest of the fine lines, and though it leans toward the clich&eacute;, it never completely loses its balance. Its likable swagger behind star Kevin Costner -- a similar swagger to that of "Bull Durham," also directed by Ron Shelton -- is what makes it one of the more memorable fault-filled sports movies. Like the previous (and slightly better) Costner-Shelton collaboration of "Durham," this film is a romantic sports comedy about a trashy/washed-up athlete who wastes a lot of talent and somehow manages to attract sexual attention. Costner stars as West Texan Roy McAvoy, referred to sometimes as 'Tin Cup,' a talented college golfer who somehow ended up a golf pro at a downtrodden driving range with his amigo Romeo (Cheech Marin) while his college teammate David Simms (Don Johnson) went on to be a star. Roy is a betting man who goes with his gut, ignores reason and uses golf metaphors to make sense of life. When an anal retentive psychiatrist named Molly (Rene Russo) shows up at his range for lessons, Roy is smitten, only to find she's with Simms. Of course the only way to win her over is to try and make the U.S. Open, right? Costner and Russo have forced character chemistry. There's no reason for either of them to be interested in each other, save that Roy wants a challenge compared to the white trash women he's interested in. There's certainly no reason for Molly to leave her tournament- winning boyfriend for a sleazeball. And you know it's true when the dialogue directly addresses why they fell for the other like it's justification or something. The machismo fueling Roy and his buddies in the movie, constantly betting each other and insulting the other when he lays up and plays it safe is childish, but it brings the film its humor and keeps it from being a straight through underdog movie. Its more interested in its characters than building up plot suspense, which is a good thing, if only the characters behaved in realistic ways. "Tin Cup" is a giant golf metaphor for life, about how taking risks -- no matter how many times you fail -- is always worth it. Shelton's film is gutsy in the same way, finding different ways of telling a sports story that will make it feel different. It goes about it in an amateur way, but it's the bravado that it will be remembered for. Shelton's films have this miraculous tendency to only let their best parts stick with you. They're the kinds of movies that make for great channel-surfing finds on TV. That's really what "Tin Cup" is. ~Steven C Visit my site at http://moviemusereviews.blogspot.com
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Very different
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    vranger
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/6/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Tin Cup" is a unique experience, in that after viewing this movie, you won't automatically compare it to any other film ... there isn't another one like it. It wrote in another review that all sports films contains many clich&eacute;s. Well, I have to contradict myself in describing this film about golf. It starts many clich&eacute;s, and then breaks them in half, sometimes literally! LOL Funny, charming, romantic, and defiant, Tin Cup gives you a bit of everything ... even a realistic ending but with a crumb thrown to the future at the same time. And the phrase "Tin Cup" made its way into sports talk for an event where a golfer REALLY screws up on a hole, especially if from stubbornness.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Supporting Cast Makes It Barely Watchable
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    grandpagbm
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/11/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    There are three reasons to watch this movie: Rene Russo, Cheech Marin, and Don Johnson. The rest of it is a waste of time. Kevin Costner's character, the protagonist, is a jerk from beginning to end. He never changes, he never learns anything, he is a total loser. I don't know whether to blame the script writer, the director, or Costner, but it doesn't really matter. The main character is entirely unsympathetic. Marin has some great lines, and he delivers them beautifully. Russo is sexy and plays her part perfectly. Johnson's performance is excellent, except for the one scene in which the director or scrip writer or someone decided that he needed to play completely out of character in order to make him the villain. It even appeared that he was embarrassed to have to do that scene, since it was totally inconsistent with the rest of his role. I will watch the film again, but just to enjoy watching Russo, Marin, and Johnson.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I didn't like "Tin Cup" so much but I liked the performances
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    (butchfilms@hotmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/10/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I think "Tin Cup" had the potential to be a much better movie. If this movie would have lasted 100 minutes instead of its 135 "Tin Cup" would have more that 6 stars. I liked the performances of Kevin Costner as Roy 'Tin Cup' McAvoy, Rene Russo as Dr. Molly Griswold, Don Johnson as David Simms and Cheech Marin as Romeo Posar. The plot of the movie is about Roy 'Tin Cup' McAvoy, a golf teacher in a very poor golf field, who once was a great college golf player. One day Roy will see again to his old enemy David Simms, and because of David and David's girlfriend, Dr. Molly Griswold, Roy will train with his caddy Romeo Posar to get in the US OPEN and win the tournament.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Kevin Costner not being Kevin Costner
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bgm2005
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/3/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie is perhaps my most watched movie that I don't own. Every time it's on TV, it seems to find my TV screen... even if I'm not looking for it. But even after multitudes of viewings, something struck me after watching it again tonight... what a GREAT job Kevin Costner did in this role! And WHY do I say that? Because this is one of his few films where I didn't realize I was watching Kevin Costner! Usually, he plays a role that's too big for him to chew... and you painfully watch him try to make something of it, all the while your conscience says, "I'm watching a Kevin Costner flick... this is painful". BUT NOT WITH TIN CUP. I actually found myself 2/3 through the movie quizzing myself on who the actor was... I could swear I've seen him somewhere before... Keven Costner totally loses himself in this role... so much so that he wonderfully loses his identity as Kevin Costner.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
 </reviews>
</filme>
