<filme>
 <id>
  287
 </id>
 <imdburl>
  http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0116999
 </imdburl>
 <ano>
  1996
 </ano>
 <titulo>
  As Filhas de Marvin
 </titulo>
 <rating>
  6.6
 </rating>
 <sinopse>
  A leukemia patient attempts to end a 20-year feud with her sister to get her bone marrow.
 </sinopse>
 <storyline>
  Estranged since their father's first stroke some 17 years earlier, Lee and Bessie lead separate lives in separate states. Lee's son, Hank, finds himself committed to a mental institution after setting fire to his mother's house. His younger brother, Charlie, seems unfazed by his brother's eccentricities or his mother's seeming disinterest. When Lee comes to the asylum to spring Hank for a week in Florida so that he can be tested as a possible bone marrow donor for Bessie, Hank is incredulous. "I didn't even know you had a sister," he says. "Remember, every Christmas, when I used to say 'Well, looks like Aunt Bessie didn't send us a card again this year?'" "Oh yeah," Hank says. Meanwhile, Marvin, the two women's bedridden father, has "been dying for the past twenty years." "He's doing it real slow so I don't miss anything," Bessie tells Dr. Wally. In Bessie's regular doctor's absence, it has fallen to Dr. Wally to inform Bessie that she has leukemia and will die without a bone marrow ...
 </storyline>
 <generos>
  <genero>
   Drama
  </genero>
 </generos>
 <keywords>
  <keyword>
   leukemia
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   nursing home
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   doctor
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   fire
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   house
  </keyword>
 </keywords>
 <diretores>
  <diretor>
   Jerry Zaks
  </diretor>
 </diretores>
 <escritores>
  <escritor>
   Scott McPherson
  </escritor>
 </escritores>
 <atores>
  <ator>
   Meryl Streep
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Leonardo DiCaprio
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Diane Keaton
  </ator>
 </atores>
 <reviews>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Honoring a vision
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bkoganbing
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Even more interesting than the film Marvin's Room is the short tragic life of its creator Scott McPherson. Four years after he died after just completing the screenplay adaption of the play this film was based on, Marvin's Room came to the screen. No doubt the director and cast felt a particular responsibility to honor his vision. Watching Marvin's Room I was reminded of South Riding a novel that has been adapted once to the big screen and twice as mini-series for British television. The author Winifred Holtby had a short life as did McPherson and wrote a novel based on her love of the Yorkshire area of England and the people she grew up among. Though her story is an epic and McPherson's a family portrait both represent a race against mortality that both authors endured to have their work live. I recommend the film South Riding very highly, it stars Ralph Richardson and Edna Best, see my review here. Although Diane Keaton was honored with a Best Actress Oscar nomination the whole ensemble could have been honored. She plays a woman who is the chief caregiver for her aged father Hume Cronyn. Keaton has been diagnosed with leukemia and is in need of a bone marrow transplant. Among likely donors are her sister Meryl Streep and Meryl's sons, Leonardo DiCaprio and Hal Scardino. DiCaprio is a kid with some issues, he was in a mental institution for burning down their house and Streep has to get him sprung for the trip. Nothing is ever resolved for any of these people, but they do come together kind of in this crisis. That's as far as I'll go. One performance that doesn't seem to be talked about much is that of Hal Scardino as the younger son. He reminded me a lot of my younger brother, the age spread between DiCaprio and him is about the same. My family had a lot of drama as well and my brother developed certain defense mechanisms of observing silently what went on around him without necessarily participating thereof. Marvin's Room is a great ensemble production and I certainly hope that Scott McPherson one of the innumerable talents lost to the AIDS epidemic is pleased with what was done with his creation.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Oh what a difference a screenplay makes!!!!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Conork2
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/9/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I came across this movie on Netflix and thought I would give it a go! Surely a movie with Meryl Streep and Dianne Keaton wouldn't disappoint! It sure didn't! While the story has been done before in various formats it's the screenplay that makes this movie a real gem. The main three actors really do a great job. But with Streep, Keaton and DiCaprio one would expect nothing less. For me the the late Gwen Verdon steals the show. she really shows how comedy should be done. The scene with the orange is one that stands out. A mixture of comedy and heart wrenching reality showcases how underrated she has been. This for me should have definitely gained a nod in any supporting actress awards. This movie certainly won't change your life but it really does provide you with food for though about love, family and the importance of life! Give it a go. It won't disappoint.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    It's Never Too Late To Mend Broken Relationships Until You're Gone
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Chrysanthepop
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/3/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Scott McPherson adapts a beautiful screenplay from his own play. 'Marvin's Room' could have easily been just another one of those sentimental disease-of-the-weak type TV films but McPherson stays true to the story injecting it with a delightful dose of humour. The film focuses on broken relationships and how it's never too late to take the step to mend them until you're gone. The execution is simple and that works very well. The score is in sync with the flow. The writing is beautiful. The dialogues are cleverly written. Diane Keaton is marvelous in a role that could have easily turned out to be a clich&eacute; if it were played by a lesser actress. She plays her part naturally with a quiet and yet layered restraint. Meryl Streep does a fine job as the slightly more rebellious and estranged sister who had escaped from having to take care of her father and is proud of her diploma. Leonardo Dicaprio isn't bad either. Robert De Niro is great in a more laidback role. He also reveals a flare for comedy. His scenes with a splendid Dan Hedaya had me laughing. Gwen Verdon is a delight and she provides excellent comic relief. Hume Cronyn doesn't have a scene out of bed but he definitely makes the viewer take note of his performance. My favourite scene is towards the end when the two sisters chat in the kitchen. Keaton's Bessie may have been 'consumed' by taking care of her ailing father and aunt, not 'leading' her own life like the typical American woman but the amazing thing is that she doesn't regret it because she is proud that she has given them so much love and that she can do the same now with her sister and nephews. Then there's the ending which is superbly done. You're left wanting to know how these wonderful characters are doing but at the same time one can acknowledge that it's the best way to end.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Finely Acted Movie About Familial Bonds And Love
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    SiliconDesertMan40
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Two sisters try to set their familial differences aside -- one in hopes of saving her own life -- in this drama with comic accents.Marvin's Room is a film based on the play of the same name by Scott McPherson.The play, which was directed by David Petrarca, was adapted for the screen by McPherson and directed by Jerry Zaks. It stars Meryl Streep, Leonardo DiCaprio, Diane Keaton, Robert De Niro, Hume Cronyn, Gwen Verdon, Hal Scardino and Dan Hedaya. Bessie has lived in Florida for the past 20 years, where she's been caring for her chronically ill father Marvin and her Aunt Ruth, who does not seem well acquainted with reality. While Bessie's life has not been easy, she feels that it's rewarding in its way, and she's come to love her father very much. However, when Bessie is diagnosed with cancer, she's told that the only treatment likely to save her would be a bone marrow transplant from a close relative -- which leads Bessie to contact her sister Lee for the first time since their father fell ill. Bessie and Lee have a number of issues with each other that they've never resolved, many concerning their responses to Marvin's illness as Bessie rushed to his side, while Lee preferred to stay away, and Lee's own life has been difficult. She's gotten herself out of a bad marriage, has only recently started supporting herself as a beautician, and has to raise two kids on her own. Ten-year-old Charlie tries to simply ignore the chaos going on all round him, while Hank, a troubled 17-year-old, was recently institutionalized after burning down the family's home. As the straight-laced Bessie and the earthy Lee reestablish contact after two decades, they discover just how much emotional ground they have to cover before they can meet on common ground. Based on a play by Scott McPherson's who died of AIDS, it's impossible to watch the well-acted film particularly Diane Keaton, who got an Oscar nomination,as she was given a rare opportunity here to remind us that she's not simply a fine comedienne, and she's marvelous.Meryl Streep, Robert De Niro, Leonardo DiCaprio, Hume Cronyn and Gwen Verdon add to the greatness of the cast's brilliance and excellent performance.And most of all,it provides great themes about the various approaches to love; the strength of family bonds in times of death, aging parents, reconciliation; and the healing power of selfless love.It was one good movie inspite of being dull and slow at times.A can't miss movie.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Intimate dramas are the hardest to film - well worth the effort when they work though
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    eschetic-2
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/9/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Small cast, intimate dramas like MARVIN'S ROOM, NIGHT MOTHER or STEEL MAGNOLIAS are among the hardest to adapt from the confines of the stage where the imagination can open the plays ideas up and make what might seem maudlin, real and life affirming to the more realistic form of film where it is harder to see beyond the mundane "bed pan" realities of life. In order to reinvent the best of these - like the plays mentioned above - to the new genre, every break is needed starting with bravura casts who, one hopes, an audience will want to see even "reading the phone book." When a play turns around the characters dealing literally with confrontations with death at the core of the plot as in these three great plays, what HAD been on stage a single set intense evening is frequently "opened up" with all sorts of other locations and events almost as if to distract us from the very issues which we are supposed to be attending to. On stage and screen MARVIN'S ROOM may well be the best of these three "death plays," all of which started and thrived Off-Broadway (only NIGHT MOTHER made the leap to a Broadway house in its initial production). While, somewhat amazingly (considering that one of the standards of the award is "depiction of American life"), MARVIN'S ROOM was not even a finalist for the Pulitzer Prize for Drama in 1992, it did win a number of other accolades which virtually demanded that Hollywood attempt to bring it to the rest of the nation - and they certainly gave it their all starting with the genuinely all star cast which is both the movie's blessing and its curse. It enraptures with the bouquet of bravura performances even while moving focus away from the central "earth-mother" of the family forced to face her own mortality while trying to care for and hold her collapsing family together around her (Diane Keaton's Oscar nomination - the film's only - notwithstanding). Ultimately, the film gets where the play was going (as well it ought to have, since Scott McPherson had the luxury of adapting his own play - he may have written his screenplay simultaneously with, if not before the tighter stage version, since he died in 1992, the year MARVIN'S ROOM received its Off-Broadway production at Playwrights' Horizons, winning the Outer Critics' Circle and Drama Desk Awards as best Play of the Year), but the power seems to have shifted from the play's revelations themselves to the dazzling performances. It's still well worth taking the trip, but more to appreciate a monument to more than a dozen brilliant stage and screen careers than a revelatory experience on the meaning of humanity in the face of life and death that the play had been. Do, by all means see the movie. It works. ...but if you ever get a chance to see the play which either suggested it or grew from it, by all means do - it's smaller but even better.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Brilliant !
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    scottshak_111
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/11/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Marvin's room turned out to be a brilliant movie assisted well by a great performance by some veteran actors like Meryl Streep, Diane Keaton, Leonardo DiCaprio, Robert De Niro ( although he wasn't the center of attraction as he was the doctor ). Meryl Streep and Diane Keaton are two sisters who have estranged each other for 20 years and Diane calls upon her sister to take care of their father as she herself realized that she was suffering from Leukemia. Leonardo portrays the character of Hank who does not get along with his mother Meryl on account of her abusive behaviour. Diane Keaton wants Meryl to take care of her Aunt Roth and their father when she would be gone. Meryl portrays a mean woman who is afraid of responsibilities and is troubled by the deliberate acts of her son Hank (Leo). The movie is a beautiful depiction of how Meryl Streep decides to eventually aid her dying sister by stepping into her shoes and taking enough pluck to set things right between herself and Hank. Diane Keaton and Meryl Streep acted exceptionally well not to forget Leo. Altogether their performance was brilliant. I was touched by the movie. I'd rate it a 7 on 10. It was certainly one of the finest flicks that I've watched.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Better Than It Should Have Been
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    brocksilvey
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/6/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This stage to screen adaptation about two estranged sisters attempting a reconciliation after one is diagnosed with cancer is sentimental to the extreme, manipulative beyond forgiveness.....and had me close to blubbering like a baby by the time it was over. Chalk it up to the fact that I had recently lost a grandmother to cancer, but this film nearly devastated me even as I was mad that it was so maudlin. The fact that it works as well as it does is due largely to the fact that such good actors are cast in it. Meryl Streep and Diane Keaton play the sisters (Keaton is the ill one), and while it would never have occurred to me to put these two actresses together, the decision was inspired. And right before he rocketed to international fame, Leonardo DiCaprio does strong work as Keaton's troubled nephew. I won't even try to defend this film against those who say it's too schmaltzy to bear, but please let the rest of us enjoy it in blubbery peace. Grade: A-
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An Underrated Gem
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    olivia porazzi
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/5/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I happen to rank this movie as one of Leo's finest. It is definitely not as main-stream as his others, but the content and the acting was brilliant. I am a sucker for movies about dysfunctional families and this one takes the cake. It was so human...there was nothing "Hollywood" about this at all. Each character has their own emotional turmoil and when Lee comes down with Hank and Charlie, the characters are forced to come to terms with it. Leo delivered a stand-out performance in a cast of film legends. Meryl Streep is also wonderful as Lee, the self-centered mom who left her family behind in search of her own dreams.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    i liked it
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    disdressed12
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/4/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    i liked this drama starring Meryl Streep and Diane Keaton.the movie starts out as two seemingly separate stories,which end up connecting together under less than ideal circumstances.Leonardo DiCaprio also stars.the acting is good here,particularly from Streep,although Dianne Keaton is good too.DiCaprio(one year before he exploded into super stardom from Titanic)is good but his role is small.Robert De Niro has a role in what amounts to a bit more than a cameo appearance as does Dan Hedaya.you would think the movie would be depressing,but i didn't think it was.it is however,all about the drama,and so it's not fast moving,so that could be a put off for some.if you like dramatic movies,you might like this one.for me,Marvin's Room is a 7/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Exceptional
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    blanche-2
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/4/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Marvin's Room" is a 1996 film that stars Meryl Streep, Diane Keaton, Leonardo DiCaprio, Hume Cronyn, Gwen Verdon, Robert DeNiro and Dan Hedaya. Just goes to show you the kind of cast a good script can attract, even for a little film. Little film, big emotions. "Marvin's Room" is about two sisters who haven't been in touch for 20 years. Diane Keaton is Bessie, the sister who stayed home and took care of her elderly relatives - her father, Marvin (Cronyn), who is bedridden and non-verbal, and her dizzy but sweet Aunt Ruth (Verdon). Meryl Streep is Lee, the sister who got out of Dodge (Dodge being Florida), got married, had kids, got divorced, and is about to get her cosmetology license. When Bessie is diagnosed with leukemia and is told she needs a relative's bone marrow, she calls Lee. Lee packs up the kids and drives to Florida so they can all be tested. The film begins with Lee's son Hank (DiCaprio) burning down the family dwelling and getting arrested. It's an understatement to say he's angry with his mother, blaming her for the divorce. He forms a bond with his Aunt Bessie, and doesn't want to leave. His mother vehemently doesn't want to stay. In their big confrontation, Bessie accuses Lee of being selfish in not staying and sharing the burden of taking care of their family. "I took care of my family," Lee reminds her. "I had a husband and children, and I never heard from any of you people." This is one of those family dramas that hits home, and with the boomers now in the position of taking care of their parents, it's even more relevant than it was 13 years ago. Each member of the cast gives an honest and realistic performance. As the smoking, no-nonsense, nothing can touch me Lee, Meryl Streep is marvelous. I have to admit that I am not always a fan of hers, only because I can sometimes see her making acting choices. Lee is one role where she just IS the character. Keaton is excellent as the softer, warmer, more nurturing Bessie, who sublimated many of her own dreams. As the rebellious teen, Leonardo DiCaprio gives a wonderful performance as the confused Hank, who discovers family he knew nothing about. There are two sisters, and there are also two brothers - Robert DeNiro, who plays Bessie's doctor, Dr. Wally, and Dan Hedaya, the doctor's slow brother Bob who works in Wally's office. Bob isn't much help, but Wally seems to tolerate him with no problem. He's family, and Wally's responsibility. One scene that really cracked me up - Aunt Ruth loves soap operas, and when we first see her, she's watching a soap opera scene with veteran soap star John Callahan (All My Children) and Kelly Ripa. It's hilarious. I mention it because later on, it comes into play. Jerry Zaks' directing is excellent. Just have a box of tissues nearby. It's a story about a family, with lots of love underneath the problems.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Honoring a vision
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bkoganbing
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Even more interesting than the film Marvin's Room is the short tragic life of its creator Scott McPherson. Four years after he died after just completing the screenplay adaption of the play this film was based on, Marvin's Room came to the screen. No doubt the director and cast felt a particular responsibility to honor his vision. Watching Marvin's Room I was reminded of South Riding a novel that has been adapted once to the big screen and twice as mini-series for British television. The author Winifred Holtby had a short life as did McPherson and wrote a novel based on her love of the Yorkshire area of England and the people she grew up among. Though her story is an epic and McPherson's a family portrait both represent a race against mortality that both authors endured to have their work live. I recommend the film South Riding very highly, it stars Ralph Richardson and Edna Best, see my review here. Although Diane Keaton was honored with a Best Actress Oscar nomination the whole ensemble could have been honored. She plays a woman who is the chief caregiver for her aged father Hume Cronyn. Keaton has been diagnosed with leukemia and is in need of a bone marrow transplant. Among likely donors are her sister Meryl Streep and Meryl's sons, Leonardo DiCaprio and Hal Scardino. DiCaprio is a kid with some issues, he was in a mental institution for burning down their house and Streep has to get him sprung for the trip. Nothing is ever resolved for any of these people, but they do come together kind of in this crisis. That's as far as I'll go. One performance that doesn't seem to be talked about much is that of Hal Scardino as the younger son. He reminded me a lot of my younger brother, the age spread between DiCaprio and him is about the same. My family had a lot of drama as well and my brother developed certain defense mechanisms of observing silently what went on around him without necessarily participating thereof. Marvin's Room is a great ensemble production and I certainly hope that Scott McPherson one of the innumerable talents lost to the AIDS epidemic is pleased with what was done with his creation.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Oh what a difference a screenplay makes!!!!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Conork2
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/9/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I came across this movie on Netflix and thought I would give it a go! Surely a movie with Meryl Streep and Dianne Keaton wouldn't disappoint! It sure didn't! While the story has been done before in various formats it's the screenplay that makes this movie a real gem. The main three actors really do a great job. But with Streep, Keaton and DiCaprio one would expect nothing less. For me the the late Gwen Verdon steals the show. she really shows how comedy should be done. The scene with the orange is one that stands out. A mixture of comedy and heart wrenching reality showcases how underrated she has been. This for me should have definitely gained a nod in any supporting actress awards. This movie certainly won't change your life but it really does provide you with food for though about love, family and the importance of life! Give it a go. It won't disappoint.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    It's Never Too Late To Mend Broken Relationships Until You're Gone
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Chrysanthepop
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/3/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Scott McPherson adapts a beautiful screenplay from his own play. 'Marvin's Room' could have easily been just another one of those sentimental disease-of-the-weak type TV films but McPherson stays true to the story injecting it with a delightful dose of humour. The film focuses on broken relationships and how it's never too late to take the step to mend them until you're gone. The execution is simple and that works very well. The score is in sync with the flow. The writing is beautiful. The dialogues are cleverly written. Diane Keaton is marvelous in a role that could have easily turned out to be a clich&eacute; if it were played by a lesser actress. She plays her part naturally with a quiet and yet layered restraint. Meryl Streep does a fine job as the slightly more rebellious and estranged sister who had escaped from having to take care of her father and is proud of her diploma. Leonardo Dicaprio isn't bad either. Robert De Niro is great in a more laidback role. He also reveals a flare for comedy. His scenes with a splendid Dan Hedaya had me laughing. Gwen Verdon is a delight and she provides excellent comic relief. Hume Cronyn doesn't have a scene out of bed but he definitely makes the viewer take note of his performance. My favourite scene is towards the end when the two sisters chat in the kitchen. Keaton's Bessie may have been 'consumed' by taking care of her ailing father and aunt, not 'leading' her own life like the typical American woman but the amazing thing is that she doesn't regret it because she is proud that she has given them so much love and that she can do the same now with her sister and nephews. Then there's the ending which is superbly done. You're left wanting to know how these wonderful characters are doing but at the same time one can acknowledge that it's the best way to end.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Finely Acted Movie About Familial Bonds And Love
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    SiliconDesertMan40
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Two sisters try to set their familial differences aside -- one in hopes of saving her own life -- in this drama with comic accents.Marvin's Room is a film based on the play of the same name by Scott McPherson.The play, which was directed by David Petrarca, was adapted for the screen by McPherson and directed by Jerry Zaks. It stars Meryl Streep, Leonardo DiCaprio, Diane Keaton, Robert De Niro, Hume Cronyn, Gwen Verdon, Hal Scardino and Dan Hedaya. Bessie has lived in Florida for the past 20 years, where she's been caring for her chronically ill father Marvin and her Aunt Ruth, who does not seem well acquainted with reality. While Bessie's life has not been easy, she feels that it's rewarding in its way, and she's come to love her father very much. However, when Bessie is diagnosed with cancer, she's told that the only treatment likely to save her would be a bone marrow transplant from a close relative -- which leads Bessie to contact her sister Lee for the first time since their father fell ill. Bessie and Lee have a number of issues with each other that they've never resolved, many concerning their responses to Marvin's illness as Bessie rushed to his side, while Lee preferred to stay away, and Lee's own life has been difficult. She's gotten herself out of a bad marriage, has only recently started supporting herself as a beautician, and has to raise two kids on her own. Ten-year-old Charlie tries to simply ignore the chaos going on all round him, while Hank, a troubled 17-year-old, was recently institutionalized after burning down the family's home. As the straight-laced Bessie and the earthy Lee reestablish contact after two decades, they discover just how much emotional ground they have to cover before they can meet on common ground. Based on a play by Scott McPherson's who died of AIDS, it's impossible to watch the well-acted film particularly Diane Keaton, who got an Oscar nomination,as she was given a rare opportunity here to remind us that she's not simply a fine comedienne, and she's marvelous.Meryl Streep, Robert De Niro, Leonardo DiCaprio, Hume Cronyn and Gwen Verdon add to the greatness of the cast's brilliance and excellent performance.And most of all,it provides great themes about the various approaches to love; the strength of family bonds in times of death, aging parents, reconciliation; and the healing power of selfless love.It was one good movie inspite of being dull and slow at times.A can't miss movie.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Intimate dramas are the hardest to film - well worth the effort when they work though
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    eschetic-2
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/9/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Small cast, intimate dramas like MARVIN'S ROOM, NIGHT MOTHER or STEEL MAGNOLIAS are among the hardest to adapt from the confines of the stage where the imagination can open the plays ideas up and make what might seem maudlin, real and life affirming to the more realistic form of film where it is harder to see beyond the mundane "bed pan" realities of life. In order to reinvent the best of these - like the plays mentioned above - to the new genre, every break is needed starting with bravura casts who, one hopes, an audience will want to see even "reading the phone book." When a play turns around the characters dealing literally with confrontations with death at the core of the plot as in these three great plays, what HAD been on stage a single set intense evening is frequently "opened up" with all sorts of other locations and events almost as if to distract us from the very issues which we are supposed to be attending to. On stage and screen MARVIN'S ROOM may well be the best of these three "death plays," all of which started and thrived Off-Broadway (only NIGHT MOTHER made the leap to a Broadway house in its initial production). While, somewhat amazingly (considering that one of the standards of the award is "depiction of American life"), MARVIN'S ROOM was not even a finalist for the Pulitzer Prize for Drama in 1992, it did win a number of other accolades which virtually demanded that Hollywood attempt to bring it to the rest of the nation - and they certainly gave it their all starting with the genuinely all star cast which is both the movie's blessing and its curse. It enraptures with the bouquet of bravura performances even while moving focus away from the central "earth-mother" of the family forced to face her own mortality while trying to care for and hold her collapsing family together around her (Diane Keaton's Oscar nomination - the film's only - notwithstanding). Ultimately, the film gets where the play was going (as well it ought to have, since Scott McPherson had the luxury of adapting his own play - he may have written his screenplay simultaneously with, if not before the tighter stage version, since he died in 1992, the year MARVIN'S ROOM received its Off-Broadway production at Playwrights' Horizons, winning the Outer Critics' Circle and Drama Desk Awards as best Play of the Year), but the power seems to have shifted from the play's revelations themselves to the dazzling performances. It's still well worth taking the trip, but more to appreciate a monument to more than a dozen brilliant stage and screen careers than a revelatory experience on the meaning of humanity in the face of life and death that the play had been. Do, by all means see the movie. It works. ...but if you ever get a chance to see the play which either suggested it or grew from it, by all means do - it's smaller but even better.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Brilliant !
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    scottshak_111
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/11/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Marvin's room turned out to be a brilliant movie assisted well by a great performance by some veteran actors like Meryl Streep, Diane Keaton, Leonardo DiCaprio, Robert De Niro ( although he wasn't the center of attraction as he was the doctor ). Meryl Streep and Diane Keaton are two sisters who have estranged each other for 20 years and Diane calls upon her sister to take care of their father as she herself realized that she was suffering from Leukemia. Leonardo portrays the character of Hank who does not get along with his mother Meryl on account of her abusive behaviour. Diane Keaton wants Meryl to take care of her Aunt Roth and their father when she would be gone. Meryl portrays a mean woman who is afraid of responsibilities and is troubled by the deliberate acts of her son Hank (Leo). The movie is a beautiful depiction of how Meryl Streep decides to eventually aid her dying sister by stepping into her shoes and taking enough pluck to set things right between herself and Hank. Diane Keaton and Meryl Streep acted exceptionally well not to forget Leo. Altogether their performance was brilliant. I was touched by the movie. I'd rate it a 7 on 10. It was certainly one of the finest flicks that I've watched.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Better Than It Should Have Been
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    brocksilvey
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/6/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This stage to screen adaptation about two estranged sisters attempting a reconciliation after one is diagnosed with cancer is sentimental to the extreme, manipulative beyond forgiveness.....and had me close to blubbering like a baby by the time it was over. Chalk it up to the fact that I had recently lost a grandmother to cancer, but this film nearly devastated me even as I was mad that it was so maudlin. The fact that it works as well as it does is due largely to the fact that such good actors are cast in it. Meryl Streep and Diane Keaton play the sisters (Keaton is the ill one), and while it would never have occurred to me to put these two actresses together, the decision was inspired. And right before he rocketed to international fame, Leonardo DiCaprio does strong work as Keaton's troubled nephew. I won't even try to defend this film against those who say it's too schmaltzy to bear, but please let the rest of us enjoy it in blubbery peace. Grade: A-
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An Underrated Gem
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    olivia porazzi
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/5/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I happen to rank this movie as one of Leo's finest. It is definitely not as main-stream as his others, but the content and the acting was brilliant. I am a sucker for movies about dysfunctional families and this one takes the cake. It was so human...there was nothing "Hollywood" about this at all. Each character has their own emotional turmoil and when Lee comes down with Hank and Charlie, the characters are forced to come to terms with it. Leo delivered a stand-out performance in a cast of film legends. Meryl Streep is also wonderful as Lee, the self-centered mom who left her family behind in search of her own dreams.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    i liked it
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    disdressed12
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/4/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    i liked this drama starring Meryl Streep and Diane Keaton.the movie starts out as two seemingly separate stories,which end up connecting together under less than ideal circumstances.Leonardo DiCaprio also stars.the acting is good here,particularly from Streep,although Dianne Keaton is good too.DiCaprio(one year before he exploded into super stardom from Titanic)is good but his role is small.Robert De Niro has a role in what amounts to a bit more than a cameo appearance as does Dan Hedaya.you would think the movie would be depressing,but i didn't think it was.it is however,all about the drama,and so it's not fast moving,so that could be a put off for some.if you like dramatic movies,you might like this one.for me,Marvin's Room is a 7/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Exceptional
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    blanche-2
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/4/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Marvin's Room" is a 1996 film that stars Meryl Streep, Diane Keaton, Leonardo DiCaprio, Hume Cronyn, Gwen Verdon, Robert DeNiro and Dan Hedaya. Just goes to show you the kind of cast a good script can attract, even for a little film. Little film, big emotions. "Marvin's Room" is about two sisters who haven't been in touch for 20 years. Diane Keaton is Bessie, the sister who stayed home and took care of her elderly relatives - her father, Marvin (Cronyn), who is bedridden and non-verbal, and her dizzy but sweet Aunt Ruth (Verdon). Meryl Streep is Lee, the sister who got out of Dodge (Dodge being Florida), got married, had kids, got divorced, and is about to get her cosmetology license. When Bessie is diagnosed with leukemia and is told she needs a relative's bone marrow, she calls Lee. Lee packs up the kids and drives to Florida so they can all be tested. The film begins with Lee's son Hank (DiCaprio) burning down the family dwelling and getting arrested. It's an understatement to say he's angry with his mother, blaming her for the divorce. He forms a bond with his Aunt Bessie, and doesn't want to leave. His mother vehemently doesn't want to stay. In their big confrontation, Bessie accuses Lee of being selfish in not staying and sharing the burden of taking care of their family. "I took care of my family," Lee reminds her. "I had a husband and children, and I never heard from any of you people." This is one of those family dramas that hits home, and with the boomers now in the position of taking care of their parents, it's even more relevant than it was 13 years ago. Each member of the cast gives an honest and realistic performance. As the smoking, no-nonsense, nothing can touch me Lee, Meryl Streep is marvelous. I have to admit that I am not always a fan of hers, only because I can sometimes see her making acting choices. Lee is one role where she just IS the character. Keaton is excellent as the softer, warmer, more nurturing Bessie, who sublimated many of her own dreams. As the rebellious teen, Leonardo DiCaprio gives a wonderful performance as the confused Hank, who discovers family he knew nothing about. There are two sisters, and there are also two brothers - Robert DeNiro, who plays Bessie's doctor, Dr. Wally, and Dan Hedaya, the doctor's slow brother Bob who works in Wally's office. Bob isn't much help, but Wally seems to tolerate him with no problem. He's family, and Wally's responsibility. One scene that really cracked me up - Aunt Ruth loves soap operas, and when we first see her, she's watching a soap opera scene with veteran soap star John Callahan (All My Children) and Kelly Ripa. It's hilarious. I mention it because later on, it comes into play. Jerry Zaks' directing is excellent. Just have a box of tissues nearby. It's a story about a family, with lots of love underneath the problems.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Honoring a vision
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bkoganbing
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Even more interesting than the film Marvin's Room is the short tragic life of its creator Scott McPherson. Four years after he died after just completing the screenplay adaption of the play this film was based on, Marvin's Room came to the screen. No doubt the director and cast felt a particular responsibility to honor his vision. Watching Marvin's Room I was reminded of South Riding a novel that has been adapted once to the big screen and twice as mini-series for British television. The author Winifred Holtby had a short life as did McPherson and wrote a novel based on her love of the Yorkshire area of England and the people she grew up among. Though her story is an epic and McPherson's a family portrait both represent a race against mortality that both authors endured to have their work live. I recommend the film South Riding very highly, it stars Ralph Richardson and Edna Best, see my review here. Although Diane Keaton was honored with a Best Actress Oscar nomination the whole ensemble could have been honored. She plays a woman who is the chief caregiver for her aged father Hume Cronyn. Keaton has been diagnosed with leukemia and is in need of a bone marrow transplant. Among likely donors are her sister Meryl Streep and Meryl's sons, Leonardo DiCaprio and Hal Scardino. DiCaprio is a kid with some issues, he was in a mental institution for burning down their house and Streep has to get him sprung for the trip. Nothing is ever resolved for any of these people, but they do come together kind of in this crisis. That's as far as I'll go. One performance that doesn't seem to be talked about much is that of Hal Scardino as the younger son. He reminded me a lot of my younger brother, the age spread between DiCaprio and him is about the same. My family had a lot of drama as well and my brother developed certain defense mechanisms of observing silently what went on around him without necessarily participating thereof. Marvin's Room is a great ensemble production and I certainly hope that Scott McPherson one of the innumerable talents lost to the AIDS epidemic is pleased with what was done with his creation.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Oh what a difference a screenplay makes!!!!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Conork2
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/9/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I came across this movie on Netflix and thought I would give it a go! Surely a movie with Meryl Streep and Dianne Keaton wouldn't disappoint! It sure didn't! While the story has been done before in various formats it's the screenplay that makes this movie a real gem. The main three actors really do a great job. But with Streep, Keaton and DiCaprio one would expect nothing less. For me the the late Gwen Verdon steals the show. she really shows how comedy should be done. The scene with the orange is one that stands out. A mixture of comedy and heart wrenching reality showcases how underrated she has been. This for me should have definitely gained a nod in any supporting actress awards. This movie certainly won't change your life but it really does provide you with food for though about love, family and the importance of life! Give it a go. It won't disappoint.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    It's Never Too Late To Mend Broken Relationships Until You're Gone
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Chrysanthepop
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/3/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Scott McPherson adapts a beautiful screenplay from his own play. 'Marvin's Room' could have easily been just another one of those sentimental disease-of-the-weak type TV films but McPherson stays true to the story injecting it with a delightful dose of humour. The film focuses on broken relationships and how it's never too late to take the step to mend them until you're gone. The execution is simple and that works very well. The score is in sync with the flow. The writing is beautiful. The dialogues are cleverly written. Diane Keaton is marvelous in a role that could have easily turned out to be a clich&eacute; if it were played by a lesser actress. She plays her part naturally with a quiet and yet layered restraint. Meryl Streep does a fine job as the slightly more rebellious and estranged sister who had escaped from having to take care of her father and is proud of her diploma. Leonardo Dicaprio isn't bad either. Robert De Niro is great in a more laidback role. He also reveals a flare for comedy. His scenes with a splendid Dan Hedaya had me laughing. Gwen Verdon is a delight and she provides excellent comic relief. Hume Cronyn doesn't have a scene out of bed but he definitely makes the viewer take note of his performance. My favourite scene is towards the end when the two sisters chat in the kitchen. Keaton's Bessie may have been 'consumed' by taking care of her ailing father and aunt, not 'leading' her own life like the typical American woman but the amazing thing is that she doesn't regret it because she is proud that she has given them so much love and that she can do the same now with her sister and nephews. Then there's the ending which is superbly done. You're left wanting to know how these wonderful characters are doing but at the same time one can acknowledge that it's the best way to end.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Finely Acted Movie About Familial Bonds And Love
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    SiliconDesertMan40
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Two sisters try to set their familial differences aside -- one in hopes of saving her own life -- in this drama with comic accents.Marvin's Room is a film based on the play of the same name by Scott McPherson.The play, which was directed by David Petrarca, was adapted for the screen by McPherson and directed by Jerry Zaks. It stars Meryl Streep, Leonardo DiCaprio, Diane Keaton, Robert De Niro, Hume Cronyn, Gwen Verdon, Hal Scardino and Dan Hedaya. Bessie has lived in Florida for the past 20 years, where she's been caring for her chronically ill father Marvin and her Aunt Ruth, who does not seem well acquainted with reality. While Bessie's life has not been easy, she feels that it's rewarding in its way, and she's come to love her father very much. However, when Bessie is diagnosed with cancer, she's told that the only treatment likely to save her would be a bone marrow transplant from a close relative -- which leads Bessie to contact her sister Lee for the first time since their father fell ill. Bessie and Lee have a number of issues with each other that they've never resolved, many concerning their responses to Marvin's illness as Bessie rushed to his side, while Lee preferred to stay away, and Lee's own life has been difficult. She's gotten herself out of a bad marriage, has only recently started supporting herself as a beautician, and has to raise two kids on her own. Ten-year-old Charlie tries to simply ignore the chaos going on all round him, while Hank, a troubled 17-year-old, was recently institutionalized after burning down the family's home. As the straight-laced Bessie and the earthy Lee reestablish contact after two decades, they discover just how much emotional ground they have to cover before they can meet on common ground. Based on a play by Scott McPherson's who died of AIDS, it's impossible to watch the well-acted film particularly Diane Keaton, who got an Oscar nomination,as she was given a rare opportunity here to remind us that she's not simply a fine comedienne, and she's marvelous.Meryl Streep, Robert De Niro, Leonardo DiCaprio, Hume Cronyn and Gwen Verdon add to the greatness of the cast's brilliance and excellent performance.And most of all,it provides great themes about the various approaches to love; the strength of family bonds in times of death, aging parents, reconciliation; and the healing power of selfless love.It was one good movie inspite of being dull and slow at times.A can't miss movie.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Intimate dramas are the hardest to film - well worth the effort when they work though
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    eschetic-2
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/9/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Small cast, intimate dramas like MARVIN'S ROOM, NIGHT MOTHER or STEEL MAGNOLIAS are among the hardest to adapt from the confines of the stage where the imagination can open the plays ideas up and make what might seem maudlin, real and life affirming to the more realistic form of film where it is harder to see beyond the mundane "bed pan" realities of life. In order to reinvent the best of these - like the plays mentioned above - to the new genre, every break is needed starting with bravura casts who, one hopes, an audience will want to see even "reading the phone book." When a play turns around the characters dealing literally with confrontations with death at the core of the plot as in these three great plays, what HAD been on stage a single set intense evening is frequently "opened up" with all sorts of other locations and events almost as if to distract us from the very issues which we are supposed to be attending to. On stage and screen MARVIN'S ROOM may well be the best of these three "death plays," all of which started and thrived Off-Broadway (only NIGHT MOTHER made the leap to a Broadway house in its initial production). While, somewhat amazingly (considering that one of the standards of the award is "depiction of American life"), MARVIN'S ROOM was not even a finalist for the Pulitzer Prize for Drama in 1992, it did win a number of other accolades which virtually demanded that Hollywood attempt to bring it to the rest of the nation - and they certainly gave it their all starting with the genuinely all star cast which is both the movie's blessing and its curse. It enraptures with the bouquet of bravura performances even while moving focus away from the central "earth-mother" of the family forced to face her own mortality while trying to care for and hold her collapsing family together around her (Diane Keaton's Oscar nomination - the film's only - notwithstanding). Ultimately, the film gets where the play was going (as well it ought to have, since Scott McPherson had the luxury of adapting his own play - he may have written his screenplay simultaneously with, if not before the tighter stage version, since he died in 1992, the year MARVIN'S ROOM received its Off-Broadway production at Playwrights' Horizons, winning the Outer Critics' Circle and Drama Desk Awards as best Play of the Year), but the power seems to have shifted from the play's revelations themselves to the dazzling performances. It's still well worth taking the trip, but more to appreciate a monument to more than a dozen brilliant stage and screen careers than a revelatory experience on the meaning of humanity in the face of life and death that the play had been. Do, by all means see the movie. It works. ...but if you ever get a chance to see the play which either suggested it or grew from it, by all means do - it's smaller but even better.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Brilliant !
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    scottshak_111
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/11/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Marvin's room turned out to be a brilliant movie assisted well by a great performance by some veteran actors like Meryl Streep, Diane Keaton, Leonardo DiCaprio, Robert De Niro ( although he wasn't the center of attraction as he was the doctor ). Meryl Streep and Diane Keaton are two sisters who have estranged each other for 20 years and Diane calls upon her sister to take care of their father as she herself realized that she was suffering from Leukemia. Leonardo portrays the character of Hank who does not get along with his mother Meryl on account of her abusive behaviour. Diane Keaton wants Meryl to take care of her Aunt Roth and their father when she would be gone. Meryl portrays a mean woman who is afraid of responsibilities and is troubled by the deliberate acts of her son Hank (Leo). The movie is a beautiful depiction of how Meryl Streep decides to eventually aid her dying sister by stepping into her shoes and taking enough pluck to set things right between herself and Hank. Diane Keaton and Meryl Streep acted exceptionally well not to forget Leo. Altogether their performance was brilliant. I was touched by the movie. I'd rate it a 7 on 10. It was certainly one of the finest flicks that I've watched.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Better Than It Should Have Been
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    brocksilvey
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/6/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This stage to screen adaptation about two estranged sisters attempting a reconciliation after one is diagnosed with cancer is sentimental to the extreme, manipulative beyond forgiveness.....and had me close to blubbering like a baby by the time it was over. Chalk it up to the fact that I had recently lost a grandmother to cancer, but this film nearly devastated me even as I was mad that it was so maudlin. The fact that it works as well as it does is due largely to the fact that such good actors are cast in it. Meryl Streep and Diane Keaton play the sisters (Keaton is the ill one), and while it would never have occurred to me to put these two actresses together, the decision was inspired. And right before he rocketed to international fame, Leonardo DiCaprio does strong work as Keaton's troubled nephew. I won't even try to defend this film against those who say it's too schmaltzy to bear, but please let the rest of us enjoy it in blubbery peace. Grade: A-
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An Underrated Gem
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    olivia porazzi
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/5/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I happen to rank this movie as one of Leo's finest. It is definitely not as main-stream as his others, but the content and the acting was brilliant. I am a sucker for movies about dysfunctional families and this one takes the cake. It was so human...there was nothing "Hollywood" about this at all. Each character has their own emotional turmoil and when Lee comes down with Hank and Charlie, the characters are forced to come to terms with it. Leo delivered a stand-out performance in a cast of film legends. Meryl Streep is also wonderful as Lee, the self-centered mom who left her family behind in search of her own dreams.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    i liked it
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    disdressed12
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/4/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    i liked this drama starring Meryl Streep and Diane Keaton.the movie starts out as two seemingly separate stories,which end up connecting together under less than ideal circumstances.Leonardo DiCaprio also stars.the acting is good here,particularly from Streep,although Dianne Keaton is good too.DiCaprio(one year before he exploded into super stardom from Titanic)is good but his role is small.Robert De Niro has a role in what amounts to a bit more than a cameo appearance as does Dan Hedaya.you would think the movie would be depressing,but i didn't think it was.it is however,all about the drama,and so it's not fast moving,so that could be a put off for some.if you like dramatic movies,you might like this one.for me,Marvin's Room is a 7/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Exceptional
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    blanche-2
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/4/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Marvin's Room" is a 1996 film that stars Meryl Streep, Diane Keaton, Leonardo DiCaprio, Hume Cronyn, Gwen Verdon, Robert DeNiro and Dan Hedaya. Just goes to show you the kind of cast a good script can attract, even for a little film. Little film, big emotions. "Marvin's Room" is about two sisters who haven't been in touch for 20 years. Diane Keaton is Bessie, the sister who stayed home and took care of her elderly relatives - her father, Marvin (Cronyn), who is bedridden and non-verbal, and her dizzy but sweet Aunt Ruth (Verdon). Meryl Streep is Lee, the sister who got out of Dodge (Dodge being Florida), got married, had kids, got divorced, and is about to get her cosmetology license. When Bessie is diagnosed with leukemia and is told she needs a relative's bone marrow, she calls Lee. Lee packs up the kids and drives to Florida so they can all be tested. The film begins with Lee's son Hank (DiCaprio) burning down the family dwelling and getting arrested. It's an understatement to say he's angry with his mother, blaming her for the divorce. He forms a bond with his Aunt Bessie, and doesn't want to leave. His mother vehemently doesn't want to stay. In their big confrontation, Bessie accuses Lee of being selfish in not staying and sharing the burden of taking care of their family. "I took care of my family," Lee reminds her. "I had a husband and children, and I never heard from any of you people." This is one of those family dramas that hits home, and with the boomers now in the position of taking care of their parents, it's even more relevant than it was 13 years ago. Each member of the cast gives an honest and realistic performance. As the smoking, no-nonsense, nothing can touch me Lee, Meryl Streep is marvelous. I have to admit that I am not always a fan of hers, only because I can sometimes see her making acting choices. Lee is one role where she just IS the character. Keaton is excellent as the softer, warmer, more nurturing Bessie, who sublimated many of her own dreams. As the rebellious teen, Leonardo DiCaprio gives a wonderful performance as the confused Hank, who discovers family he knew nothing about. There are two sisters, and there are also two brothers - Robert DeNiro, who plays Bessie's doctor, Dr. Wally, and Dan Hedaya, the doctor's slow brother Bob who works in Wally's office. Bob isn't much help, but Wally seems to tolerate him with no problem. He's family, and Wally's responsibility. One scene that really cracked me up - Aunt Ruth loves soap operas, and when we first see her, she's watching a soap opera scene with veteran soap star John Callahan (All My Children) and Kelly Ripa. It's hilarious. I mention it because later on, it comes into play. Jerry Zaks' directing is excellent. Just have a box of tissues nearby. It's a story about a family, with lots of love underneath the problems.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Honoring a vision
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bkoganbing
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Even more interesting than the film Marvin's Room is the short tragic life of its creator Scott McPherson. Four years after he died after just completing the screenplay adaption of the play this film was based on, Marvin's Room came to the screen. No doubt the director and cast felt a particular responsibility to honor his vision. Watching Marvin's Room I was reminded of South Riding a novel that has been adapted once to the big screen and twice as mini-series for British television. The author Winifred Holtby had a short life as did McPherson and wrote a novel based on her love of the Yorkshire area of England and the people she grew up among. Though her story is an epic and McPherson's a family portrait both represent a race against mortality that both authors endured to have their work live. I recommend the film South Riding very highly, it stars Ralph Richardson and Edna Best, see my review here. Although Diane Keaton was honored with a Best Actress Oscar nomination the whole ensemble could have been honored. She plays a woman who is the chief caregiver for her aged father Hume Cronyn. Keaton has been diagnosed with leukemia and is in need of a bone marrow transplant. Among likely donors are her sister Meryl Streep and Meryl's sons, Leonardo DiCaprio and Hal Scardino. DiCaprio is a kid with some issues, he was in a mental institution for burning down their house and Streep has to get him sprung for the trip. Nothing is ever resolved for any of these people, but they do come together kind of in this crisis. That's as far as I'll go. One performance that doesn't seem to be talked about much is that of Hal Scardino as the younger son. He reminded me a lot of my younger brother, the age spread between DiCaprio and him is about the same. My family had a lot of drama as well and my brother developed certain defense mechanisms of observing silently what went on around him without necessarily participating thereof. Marvin's Room is a great ensemble production and I certainly hope that Scott McPherson one of the innumerable talents lost to the AIDS epidemic is pleased with what was done with his creation.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Oh what a difference a screenplay makes!!!!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Conork2
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/9/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I came across this movie on Netflix and thought I would give it a go! Surely a movie with Meryl Streep and Dianne Keaton wouldn't disappoint! It sure didn't! While the story has been done before in various formats it's the screenplay that makes this movie a real gem. The main three actors really do a great job. But with Streep, Keaton and DiCaprio one would expect nothing less. For me the the late Gwen Verdon steals the show. she really shows how comedy should be done. The scene with the orange is one that stands out. A mixture of comedy and heart wrenching reality showcases how underrated she has been. This for me should have definitely gained a nod in any supporting actress awards. This movie certainly won't change your life but it really does provide you with food for though about love, family and the importance of life! Give it a go. It won't disappoint.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    It's Never Too Late To Mend Broken Relationships Until You're Gone
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Chrysanthepop
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/3/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Scott McPherson adapts a beautiful screenplay from his own play. 'Marvin's Room' could have easily been just another one of those sentimental disease-of-the-weak type TV films but McPherson stays true to the story injecting it with a delightful dose of humour. The film focuses on broken relationships and how it's never too late to take the step to mend them until you're gone. The execution is simple and that works very well. The score is in sync with the flow. The writing is beautiful. The dialogues are cleverly written. Diane Keaton is marvelous in a role that could have easily turned out to be a clich&eacute; if it were played by a lesser actress. She plays her part naturally with a quiet and yet layered restraint. Meryl Streep does a fine job as the slightly more rebellious and estranged sister who had escaped from having to take care of her father and is proud of her diploma. Leonardo Dicaprio isn't bad either. Robert De Niro is great in a more laidback role. He also reveals a flare for comedy. His scenes with a splendid Dan Hedaya had me laughing. Gwen Verdon is a delight and she provides excellent comic relief. Hume Cronyn doesn't have a scene out of bed but he definitely makes the viewer take note of his performance. My favourite scene is towards the end when the two sisters chat in the kitchen. Keaton's Bessie may have been 'consumed' by taking care of her ailing father and aunt, not 'leading' her own life like the typical American woman but the amazing thing is that she doesn't regret it because she is proud that she has given them so much love and that she can do the same now with her sister and nephews. Then there's the ending which is superbly done. You're left wanting to know how these wonderful characters are doing but at the same time one can acknowledge that it's the best way to end.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Finely Acted Movie About Familial Bonds And Love
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    SiliconDesertMan40
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Two sisters try to set their familial differences aside -- one in hopes of saving her own life -- in this drama with comic accents.Marvin's Room is a film based on the play of the same name by Scott McPherson.The play, which was directed by David Petrarca, was adapted for the screen by McPherson and directed by Jerry Zaks. It stars Meryl Streep, Leonardo DiCaprio, Diane Keaton, Robert De Niro, Hume Cronyn, Gwen Verdon, Hal Scardino and Dan Hedaya. Bessie has lived in Florida for the past 20 years, where she's been caring for her chronically ill father Marvin and her Aunt Ruth, who does not seem well acquainted with reality. While Bessie's life has not been easy, she feels that it's rewarding in its way, and she's come to love her father very much. However, when Bessie is diagnosed with cancer, she's told that the only treatment likely to save her would be a bone marrow transplant from a close relative -- which leads Bessie to contact her sister Lee for the first time since their father fell ill. Bessie and Lee have a number of issues with each other that they've never resolved, many concerning their responses to Marvin's illness as Bessie rushed to his side, while Lee preferred to stay away, and Lee's own life has been difficult. She's gotten herself out of a bad marriage, has only recently started supporting herself as a beautician, and has to raise two kids on her own. Ten-year-old Charlie tries to simply ignore the chaos going on all round him, while Hank, a troubled 17-year-old, was recently institutionalized after burning down the family's home. As the straight-laced Bessie and the earthy Lee reestablish contact after two decades, they discover just how much emotional ground they have to cover before they can meet on common ground. Based on a play by Scott McPherson's who died of AIDS, it's impossible to watch the well-acted film particularly Diane Keaton, who got an Oscar nomination,as she was given a rare opportunity here to remind us that she's not simply a fine comedienne, and she's marvelous.Meryl Streep, Robert De Niro, Leonardo DiCaprio, Hume Cronyn and Gwen Verdon add to the greatness of the cast's brilliance and excellent performance.And most of all,it provides great themes about the various approaches to love; the strength of family bonds in times of death, aging parents, reconciliation; and the healing power of selfless love.It was one good movie inspite of being dull and slow at times.A can't miss movie.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Intimate dramas are the hardest to film - well worth the effort when they work though
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    eschetic-2
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/9/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Small cast, intimate dramas like MARVIN'S ROOM, NIGHT MOTHER or STEEL MAGNOLIAS are among the hardest to adapt from the confines of the stage where the imagination can open the plays ideas up and make what might seem maudlin, real and life affirming to the more realistic form of film where it is harder to see beyond the mundane "bed pan" realities of life. In order to reinvent the best of these - like the plays mentioned above - to the new genre, every break is needed starting with bravura casts who, one hopes, an audience will want to see even "reading the phone book." When a play turns around the characters dealing literally with confrontations with death at the core of the plot as in these three great plays, what HAD been on stage a single set intense evening is frequently "opened up" with all sorts of other locations and events almost as if to distract us from the very issues which we are supposed to be attending to. On stage and screen MARVIN'S ROOM may well be the best of these three "death plays," all of which started and thrived Off-Broadway (only NIGHT MOTHER made the leap to a Broadway house in its initial production). While, somewhat amazingly (considering that one of the standards of the award is "depiction of American life"), MARVIN'S ROOM was not even a finalist for the Pulitzer Prize for Drama in 1992, it did win a number of other accolades which virtually demanded that Hollywood attempt to bring it to the rest of the nation - and they certainly gave it their all starting with the genuinely all star cast which is both the movie's blessing and its curse. It enraptures with the bouquet of bravura performances even while moving focus away from the central "earth-mother" of the family forced to face her own mortality while trying to care for and hold her collapsing family together around her (Diane Keaton's Oscar nomination - the film's only - notwithstanding). Ultimately, the film gets where the play was going (as well it ought to have, since Scott McPherson had the luxury of adapting his own play - he may have written his screenplay simultaneously with, if not before the tighter stage version, since he died in 1992, the year MARVIN'S ROOM received its Off-Broadway production at Playwrights' Horizons, winning the Outer Critics' Circle and Drama Desk Awards as best Play of the Year), but the power seems to have shifted from the play's revelations themselves to the dazzling performances. It's still well worth taking the trip, but more to appreciate a monument to more than a dozen brilliant stage and screen careers than a revelatory experience on the meaning of humanity in the face of life and death that the play had been. Do, by all means see the movie. It works. ...but if you ever get a chance to see the play which either suggested it or grew from it, by all means do - it's smaller but even better.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Brilliant !
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    scottshak_111
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/11/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Marvin's room turned out to be a brilliant movie assisted well by a great performance by some veteran actors like Meryl Streep, Diane Keaton, Leonardo DiCaprio, Robert De Niro ( although he wasn't the center of attraction as he was the doctor ). Meryl Streep and Diane Keaton are two sisters who have estranged each other for 20 years and Diane calls upon her sister to take care of their father as she herself realized that she was suffering from Leukemia. Leonardo portrays the character of Hank who does not get along with his mother Meryl on account of her abusive behaviour. Diane Keaton wants Meryl to take care of her Aunt Roth and their father when she would be gone. Meryl portrays a mean woman who is afraid of responsibilities and is troubled by the deliberate acts of her son Hank (Leo). The movie is a beautiful depiction of how Meryl Streep decides to eventually aid her dying sister by stepping into her shoes and taking enough pluck to set things right between herself and Hank. Diane Keaton and Meryl Streep acted exceptionally well not to forget Leo. Altogether their performance was brilliant. I was touched by the movie. I'd rate it a 7 on 10. It was certainly one of the finest flicks that I've watched.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Better Than It Should Have Been
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    brocksilvey
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/6/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This stage to screen adaptation about two estranged sisters attempting a reconciliation after one is diagnosed with cancer is sentimental to the extreme, manipulative beyond forgiveness.....and had me close to blubbering like a baby by the time it was over. Chalk it up to the fact that I had recently lost a grandmother to cancer, but this film nearly devastated me even as I was mad that it was so maudlin. The fact that it works as well as it does is due largely to the fact that such good actors are cast in it. Meryl Streep and Diane Keaton play the sisters (Keaton is the ill one), and while it would never have occurred to me to put these two actresses together, the decision was inspired. And right before he rocketed to international fame, Leonardo DiCaprio does strong work as Keaton's troubled nephew. I won't even try to defend this film against those who say it's too schmaltzy to bear, but please let the rest of us enjoy it in blubbery peace. Grade: A-
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An Underrated Gem
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    olivia porazzi
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/5/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I happen to rank this movie as one of Leo's finest. It is definitely not as main-stream as his others, but the content and the acting was brilliant. I am a sucker for movies about dysfunctional families and this one takes the cake. It was so human...there was nothing "Hollywood" about this at all. Each character has their own emotional turmoil and when Lee comes down with Hank and Charlie, the characters are forced to come to terms with it. Leo delivered a stand-out performance in a cast of film legends. Meryl Streep is also wonderful as Lee, the self-centered mom who left her family behind in search of her own dreams.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    i liked it
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    disdressed12
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/4/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    i liked this drama starring Meryl Streep and Diane Keaton.the movie starts out as two seemingly separate stories,which end up connecting together under less than ideal circumstances.Leonardo DiCaprio also stars.the acting is good here,particularly from Streep,although Dianne Keaton is good too.DiCaprio(one year before he exploded into super stardom from Titanic)is good but his role is small.Robert De Niro has a role in what amounts to a bit more than a cameo appearance as does Dan Hedaya.you would think the movie would be depressing,but i didn't think it was.it is however,all about the drama,and so it's not fast moving,so that could be a put off for some.if you like dramatic movies,you might like this one.for me,Marvin's Room is a 7/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Exceptional
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    blanche-2
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/4/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Marvin's Room" is a 1996 film that stars Meryl Streep, Diane Keaton, Leonardo DiCaprio, Hume Cronyn, Gwen Verdon, Robert DeNiro and Dan Hedaya. Just goes to show you the kind of cast a good script can attract, even for a little film. Little film, big emotions. "Marvin's Room" is about two sisters who haven't been in touch for 20 years. Diane Keaton is Bessie, the sister who stayed home and took care of her elderly relatives - her father, Marvin (Cronyn), who is bedridden and non-verbal, and her dizzy but sweet Aunt Ruth (Verdon). Meryl Streep is Lee, the sister who got out of Dodge (Dodge being Florida), got married, had kids, got divorced, and is about to get her cosmetology license. When Bessie is diagnosed with leukemia and is told she needs a relative's bone marrow, she calls Lee. Lee packs up the kids and drives to Florida so they can all be tested. The film begins with Lee's son Hank (DiCaprio) burning down the family dwelling and getting arrested. It's an understatement to say he's angry with his mother, blaming her for the divorce. He forms a bond with his Aunt Bessie, and doesn't want to leave. His mother vehemently doesn't want to stay. In their big confrontation, Bessie accuses Lee of being selfish in not staying and sharing the burden of taking care of their family. "I took care of my family," Lee reminds her. "I had a husband and children, and I never heard from any of you people." This is one of those family dramas that hits home, and with the boomers now in the position of taking care of their parents, it's even more relevant than it was 13 years ago. Each member of the cast gives an honest and realistic performance. As the smoking, no-nonsense, nothing can touch me Lee, Meryl Streep is marvelous. I have to admit that I am not always a fan of hers, only because I can sometimes see her making acting choices. Lee is one role where she just IS the character. Keaton is excellent as the softer, warmer, more nurturing Bessie, who sublimated many of her own dreams. As the rebellious teen, Leonardo DiCaprio gives a wonderful performance as the confused Hank, who discovers family he knew nothing about. There are two sisters, and there are also two brothers - Robert DeNiro, who plays Bessie's doctor, Dr. Wally, and Dan Hedaya, the doctor's slow brother Bob who works in Wally's office. Bob isn't much help, but Wally seems to tolerate him with no problem. He's family, and Wally's responsibility. One scene that really cracked me up - Aunt Ruth loves soap operas, and when we first see her, she's watching a soap opera scene with veteran soap star John Callahan (All My Children) and Kelly Ripa. It's hilarious. I mention it because later on, it comes into play. Jerry Zaks' directing is excellent. Just have a box of tissues nearby. It's a story about a family, with lots of love underneath the problems.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Honoring a vision
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bkoganbing
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Even more interesting than the film Marvin's Room is the short tragic life of its creator Scott McPherson. Four years after he died after just completing the screenplay adaption of the play this film was based on, Marvin's Room came to the screen. No doubt the director and cast felt a particular responsibility to honor his vision. Watching Marvin's Room I was reminded of South Riding a novel that has been adapted once to the big screen and twice as mini-series for British television. The author Winifred Holtby had a short life as did McPherson and wrote a novel based on her love of the Yorkshire area of England and the people she grew up among. Though her story is an epic and McPherson's a family portrait both represent a race against mortality that both authors endured to have their work live. I recommend the film South Riding very highly, it stars Ralph Richardson and Edna Best, see my review here. Although Diane Keaton was honored with a Best Actress Oscar nomination the whole ensemble could have been honored. She plays a woman who is the chief caregiver for her aged father Hume Cronyn. Keaton has been diagnosed with leukemia and is in need of a bone marrow transplant. Among likely donors are her sister Meryl Streep and Meryl's sons, Leonardo DiCaprio and Hal Scardino. DiCaprio is a kid with some issues, he was in a mental institution for burning down their house and Streep has to get him sprung for the trip. Nothing is ever resolved for any of these people, but they do come together kind of in this crisis. That's as far as I'll go. One performance that doesn't seem to be talked about much is that of Hal Scardino as the younger son. He reminded me a lot of my younger brother, the age spread between DiCaprio and him is about the same. My family had a lot of drama as well and my brother developed certain defense mechanisms of observing silently what went on around him without necessarily participating thereof. Marvin's Room is a great ensemble production and I certainly hope that Scott McPherson one of the innumerable talents lost to the AIDS epidemic is pleased with what was done with his creation.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Oh what a difference a screenplay makes!!!!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Conork2
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/9/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I came across this movie on Netflix and thought I would give it a go! Surely a movie with Meryl Streep and Dianne Keaton wouldn't disappoint! It sure didn't! While the story has been done before in various formats it's the screenplay that makes this movie a real gem. The main three actors really do a great job. But with Streep, Keaton and DiCaprio one would expect nothing less. For me the the late Gwen Verdon steals the show. she really shows how comedy should be done. The scene with the orange is one that stands out. A mixture of comedy and heart wrenching reality showcases how underrated she has been. This for me should have definitely gained a nod in any supporting actress awards. This movie certainly won't change your life but it really does provide you with food for though about love, family and the importance of life! Give it a go. It won't disappoint.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    It's Never Too Late To Mend Broken Relationships Until You're Gone
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Chrysanthepop
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/3/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Scott McPherson adapts a beautiful screenplay from his own play. 'Marvin's Room' could have easily been just another one of those sentimental disease-of-the-weak type TV films but McPherson stays true to the story injecting it with a delightful dose of humour. The film focuses on broken relationships and how it's never too late to take the step to mend them until you're gone. The execution is simple and that works very well. The score is in sync with the flow. The writing is beautiful. The dialogues are cleverly written. Diane Keaton is marvelous in a role that could have easily turned out to be a clich&eacute; if it were played by a lesser actress. She plays her part naturally with a quiet and yet layered restraint. Meryl Streep does a fine job as the slightly more rebellious and estranged sister who had escaped from having to take care of her father and is proud of her diploma. Leonardo Dicaprio isn't bad either. Robert De Niro is great in a more laidback role. He also reveals a flare for comedy. His scenes with a splendid Dan Hedaya had me laughing. Gwen Verdon is a delight and she provides excellent comic relief. Hume Cronyn doesn't have a scene out of bed but he definitely makes the viewer take note of his performance. My favourite scene is towards the end when the two sisters chat in the kitchen. Keaton's Bessie may have been 'consumed' by taking care of her ailing father and aunt, not 'leading' her own life like the typical American woman but the amazing thing is that she doesn't regret it because she is proud that she has given them so much love and that she can do the same now with her sister and nephews. Then there's the ending which is superbly done. You're left wanting to know how these wonderful characters are doing but at the same time one can acknowledge that it's the best way to end.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Finely Acted Movie About Familial Bonds And Love
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    SiliconDesertMan40
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Two sisters try to set their familial differences aside -- one in hopes of saving her own life -- in this drama with comic accents.Marvin's Room is a film based on the play of the same name by Scott McPherson.The play, which was directed by David Petrarca, was adapted for the screen by McPherson and directed by Jerry Zaks. It stars Meryl Streep, Leonardo DiCaprio, Diane Keaton, Robert De Niro, Hume Cronyn, Gwen Verdon, Hal Scardino and Dan Hedaya. Bessie has lived in Florida for the past 20 years, where she's been caring for her chronically ill father Marvin and her Aunt Ruth, who does not seem well acquainted with reality. While Bessie's life has not been easy, she feels that it's rewarding in its way, and she's come to love her father very much. However, when Bessie is diagnosed with cancer, she's told that the only treatment likely to save her would be a bone marrow transplant from a close relative -- which leads Bessie to contact her sister Lee for the first time since their father fell ill. Bessie and Lee have a number of issues with each other that they've never resolved, many concerning their responses to Marvin's illness as Bessie rushed to his side, while Lee preferred to stay away, and Lee's own life has been difficult. She's gotten herself out of a bad marriage, has only recently started supporting herself as a beautician, and has to raise two kids on her own. Ten-year-old Charlie tries to simply ignore the chaos going on all round him, while Hank, a troubled 17-year-old, was recently institutionalized after burning down the family's home. As the straight-laced Bessie and the earthy Lee reestablish contact after two decades, they discover just how much emotional ground they have to cover before they can meet on common ground. Based on a play by Scott McPherson's who died of AIDS, it's impossible to watch the well-acted film particularly Diane Keaton, who got an Oscar nomination,as she was given a rare opportunity here to remind us that she's not simply a fine comedienne, and she's marvelous.Meryl Streep, Robert De Niro, Leonardo DiCaprio, Hume Cronyn and Gwen Verdon add to the greatness of the cast's brilliance and excellent performance.And most of all,it provides great themes about the various approaches to love; the strength of family bonds in times of death, aging parents, reconciliation; and the healing power of selfless love.It was one good movie inspite of being dull and slow at times.A can't miss movie.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Intimate dramas are the hardest to film - well worth the effort when they work though
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    eschetic-2
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/9/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Small cast, intimate dramas like MARVIN'S ROOM, NIGHT MOTHER or STEEL MAGNOLIAS are among the hardest to adapt from the confines of the stage where the imagination can open the plays ideas up and make what might seem maudlin, real and life affirming to the more realistic form of film where it is harder to see beyond the mundane "bed pan" realities of life. In order to reinvent the best of these - like the plays mentioned above - to the new genre, every break is needed starting with bravura casts who, one hopes, an audience will want to see even "reading the phone book." When a play turns around the characters dealing literally with confrontations with death at the core of the plot as in these three great plays, what HAD been on stage a single set intense evening is frequently "opened up" with all sorts of other locations and events almost as if to distract us from the very issues which we are supposed to be attending to. On stage and screen MARVIN'S ROOM may well be the best of these three "death plays," all of which started and thrived Off-Broadway (only NIGHT MOTHER made the leap to a Broadway house in its initial production). While, somewhat amazingly (considering that one of the standards of the award is "depiction of American life"), MARVIN'S ROOM was not even a finalist for the Pulitzer Prize for Drama in 1992, it did win a number of other accolades which virtually demanded that Hollywood attempt to bring it to the rest of the nation - and they certainly gave it their all starting with the genuinely all star cast which is both the movie's blessing and its curse. It enraptures with the bouquet of bravura performances even while moving focus away from the central "earth-mother" of the family forced to face her own mortality while trying to care for and hold her collapsing family together around her (Diane Keaton's Oscar nomination - the film's only - notwithstanding). Ultimately, the film gets where the play was going (as well it ought to have, since Scott McPherson had the luxury of adapting his own play - he may have written his screenplay simultaneously with, if not before the tighter stage version, since he died in 1992, the year MARVIN'S ROOM received its Off-Broadway production at Playwrights' Horizons, winning the Outer Critics' Circle and Drama Desk Awards as best Play of the Year), but the power seems to have shifted from the play's revelations themselves to the dazzling performances. It's still well worth taking the trip, but more to appreciate a monument to more than a dozen brilliant stage and screen careers than a revelatory experience on the meaning of humanity in the face of life and death that the play had been. Do, by all means see the movie. It works. ...but if you ever get a chance to see the play which either suggested it or grew from it, by all means do - it's smaller but even better.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Brilliant !
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    scottshak_111
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/11/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Marvin's room turned out to be a brilliant movie assisted well by a great performance by some veteran actors like Meryl Streep, Diane Keaton, Leonardo DiCaprio, Robert De Niro ( although he wasn't the center of attraction as he was the doctor ). Meryl Streep and Diane Keaton are two sisters who have estranged each other for 20 years and Diane calls upon her sister to take care of their father as she herself realized that she was suffering from Leukemia. Leonardo portrays the character of Hank who does not get along with his mother Meryl on account of her abusive behaviour. Diane Keaton wants Meryl to take care of her Aunt Roth and their father when she would be gone. Meryl portrays a mean woman who is afraid of responsibilities and is troubled by the deliberate acts of her son Hank (Leo). The movie is a beautiful depiction of how Meryl Streep decides to eventually aid her dying sister by stepping into her shoes and taking enough pluck to set things right between herself and Hank. Diane Keaton and Meryl Streep acted exceptionally well not to forget Leo. Altogether their performance was brilliant. I was touched by the movie. I'd rate it a 7 on 10. It was certainly one of the finest flicks that I've watched.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Better Than It Should Have Been
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    brocksilvey
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/6/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This stage to screen adaptation about two estranged sisters attempting a reconciliation after one is diagnosed with cancer is sentimental to the extreme, manipulative beyond forgiveness.....and had me close to blubbering like a baby by the time it was over. Chalk it up to the fact that I had recently lost a grandmother to cancer, but this film nearly devastated me even as I was mad that it was so maudlin. The fact that it works as well as it does is due largely to the fact that such good actors are cast in it. Meryl Streep and Diane Keaton play the sisters (Keaton is the ill one), and while it would never have occurred to me to put these two actresses together, the decision was inspired. And right before he rocketed to international fame, Leonardo DiCaprio does strong work as Keaton's troubled nephew. I won't even try to defend this film against those who say it's too schmaltzy to bear, but please let the rest of us enjoy it in blubbery peace. Grade: A-
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An Underrated Gem
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    olivia porazzi
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/5/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I happen to rank this movie as one of Leo's finest. It is definitely not as main-stream as his others, but the content and the acting was brilliant. I am a sucker for movies about dysfunctional families and this one takes the cake. It was so human...there was nothing "Hollywood" about this at all. Each character has their own emotional turmoil and when Lee comes down with Hank and Charlie, the characters are forced to come to terms with it. Leo delivered a stand-out performance in a cast of film legends. Meryl Streep is also wonderful as Lee, the self-centered mom who left her family behind in search of her own dreams.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    i liked it
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    disdressed12
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/4/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    i liked this drama starring Meryl Streep and Diane Keaton.the movie starts out as two seemingly separate stories,which end up connecting together under less than ideal circumstances.Leonardo DiCaprio also stars.the acting is good here,particularly from Streep,although Dianne Keaton is good too.DiCaprio(one year before he exploded into super stardom from Titanic)is good but his role is small.Robert De Niro has a role in what amounts to a bit more than a cameo appearance as does Dan Hedaya.you would think the movie would be depressing,but i didn't think it was.it is however,all about the drama,and so it's not fast moving,so that could be a put off for some.if you like dramatic movies,you might like this one.for me,Marvin's Room is a 7/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Exceptional
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    blanche-2
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/4/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Marvin's Room" is a 1996 film that stars Meryl Streep, Diane Keaton, Leonardo DiCaprio, Hume Cronyn, Gwen Verdon, Robert DeNiro and Dan Hedaya. Just goes to show you the kind of cast a good script can attract, even for a little film. Little film, big emotions. "Marvin's Room" is about two sisters who haven't been in touch for 20 years. Diane Keaton is Bessie, the sister who stayed home and took care of her elderly relatives - her father, Marvin (Cronyn), who is bedridden and non-verbal, and her dizzy but sweet Aunt Ruth (Verdon). Meryl Streep is Lee, the sister who got out of Dodge (Dodge being Florida), got married, had kids, got divorced, and is about to get her cosmetology license. When Bessie is diagnosed with leukemia and is told she needs a relative's bone marrow, she calls Lee. Lee packs up the kids and drives to Florida so they can all be tested. The film begins with Lee's son Hank (DiCaprio) burning down the family dwelling and getting arrested. It's an understatement to say he's angry with his mother, blaming her for the divorce. He forms a bond with his Aunt Bessie, and doesn't want to leave. His mother vehemently doesn't want to stay. In their big confrontation, Bessie accuses Lee of being selfish in not staying and sharing the burden of taking care of their family. "I took care of my family," Lee reminds her. "I had a husband and children, and I never heard from any of you people." This is one of those family dramas that hits home, and with the boomers now in the position of taking care of their parents, it's even more relevant than it was 13 years ago. Each member of the cast gives an honest and realistic performance. As the smoking, no-nonsense, nothing can touch me Lee, Meryl Streep is marvelous. I have to admit that I am not always a fan of hers, only because I can sometimes see her making acting choices. Lee is one role where she just IS the character. Keaton is excellent as the softer, warmer, more nurturing Bessie, who sublimated many of her own dreams. As the rebellious teen, Leonardo DiCaprio gives a wonderful performance as the confused Hank, who discovers family he knew nothing about. There are two sisters, and there are also two brothers - Robert DeNiro, who plays Bessie's doctor, Dr. Wally, and Dan Hedaya, the doctor's slow brother Bob who works in Wally's office. Bob isn't much help, but Wally seems to tolerate him with no problem. He's family, and Wally's responsibility. One scene that really cracked me up - Aunt Ruth loves soap operas, and when we first see her, she's watching a soap opera scene with veteran soap star John Callahan (All My Children) and Kelly Ripa. It's hilarious. I mention it because later on, it comes into play. Jerry Zaks' directing is excellent. Just have a box of tissues nearby. It's a story about a family, with lots of love underneath the problems.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Honoring a vision
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bkoganbing
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Even more interesting than the film Marvin's Room is the short tragic life of its creator Scott McPherson. Four years after he died after just completing the screenplay adaption of the play this film was based on, Marvin's Room came to the screen. No doubt the director and cast felt a particular responsibility to honor his vision. Watching Marvin's Room I was reminded of South Riding a novel that has been adapted once to the big screen and twice as mini-series for British television. The author Winifred Holtby had a short life as did McPherson and wrote a novel based on her love of the Yorkshire area of England and the people she grew up among. Though her story is an epic and McPherson's a family portrait both represent a race against mortality that both authors endured to have their work live. I recommend the film South Riding very highly, it stars Ralph Richardson and Edna Best, see my review here. Although Diane Keaton was honored with a Best Actress Oscar nomination the whole ensemble could have been honored. She plays a woman who is the chief caregiver for her aged father Hume Cronyn. Keaton has been diagnosed with leukemia and is in need of a bone marrow transplant. Among likely donors are her sister Meryl Streep and Meryl's sons, Leonardo DiCaprio and Hal Scardino. DiCaprio is a kid with some issues, he was in a mental institution for burning down their house and Streep has to get him sprung for the trip. Nothing is ever resolved for any of these people, but they do come together kind of in this crisis. That's as far as I'll go. One performance that doesn't seem to be talked about much is that of Hal Scardino as the younger son. He reminded me a lot of my younger brother, the age spread between DiCaprio and him is about the same. My family had a lot of drama as well and my brother developed certain defense mechanisms of observing silently what went on around him without necessarily participating thereof. Marvin's Room is a great ensemble production and I certainly hope that Scott McPherson one of the innumerable talents lost to the AIDS epidemic is pleased with what was done with his creation.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Oh what a difference a screenplay makes!!!!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Conork2
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/9/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I came across this movie on Netflix and thought I would give it a go! Surely a movie with Meryl Streep and Dianne Keaton wouldn't disappoint! It sure didn't! While the story has been done before in various formats it's the screenplay that makes this movie a real gem. The main three actors really do a great job. But with Streep, Keaton and DiCaprio one would expect nothing less. For me the the late Gwen Verdon steals the show. she really shows how comedy should be done. The scene with the orange is one that stands out. A mixture of comedy and heart wrenching reality showcases how underrated she has been. This for me should have definitely gained a nod in any supporting actress awards. This movie certainly won't change your life but it really does provide you with food for though about love, family and the importance of life! Give it a go. It won't disappoint.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    It's Never Too Late To Mend Broken Relationships Until You're Gone
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Chrysanthepop
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/3/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Scott McPherson adapts a beautiful screenplay from his own play. 'Marvin's Room' could have easily been just another one of those sentimental disease-of-the-weak type TV films but McPherson stays true to the story injecting it with a delightful dose of humour. The film focuses on broken relationships and how it's never too late to take the step to mend them until you're gone. The execution is simple and that works very well. The score is in sync with the flow. The writing is beautiful. The dialogues are cleverly written. Diane Keaton is marvelous in a role that could have easily turned out to be a clich&eacute; if it were played by a lesser actress. She plays her part naturally with a quiet and yet layered restraint. Meryl Streep does a fine job as the slightly more rebellious and estranged sister who had escaped from having to take care of her father and is proud of her diploma. Leonardo Dicaprio isn't bad either. Robert De Niro is great in a more laidback role. He also reveals a flare for comedy. His scenes with a splendid Dan Hedaya had me laughing. Gwen Verdon is a delight and she provides excellent comic relief. Hume Cronyn doesn't have a scene out of bed but he definitely makes the viewer take note of his performance. My favourite scene is towards the end when the two sisters chat in the kitchen. Keaton's Bessie may have been 'consumed' by taking care of her ailing father and aunt, not 'leading' her own life like the typical American woman but the amazing thing is that she doesn't regret it because she is proud that she has given them so much love and that she can do the same now with her sister and nephews. Then there's the ending which is superbly done. You're left wanting to know how these wonderful characters are doing but at the same time one can acknowledge that it's the best way to end.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Finely Acted Movie About Familial Bonds And Love
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    SiliconDesertMan40
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Two sisters try to set their familial differences aside -- one in hopes of saving her own life -- in this drama with comic accents.Marvin's Room is a film based on the play of the same name by Scott McPherson.The play, which was directed by David Petrarca, was adapted for the screen by McPherson and directed by Jerry Zaks. It stars Meryl Streep, Leonardo DiCaprio, Diane Keaton, Robert De Niro, Hume Cronyn, Gwen Verdon, Hal Scardino and Dan Hedaya. Bessie has lived in Florida for the past 20 years, where she's been caring for her chronically ill father Marvin and her Aunt Ruth, who does not seem well acquainted with reality. While Bessie's life has not been easy, she feels that it's rewarding in its way, and she's come to love her father very much. However, when Bessie is diagnosed with cancer, she's told that the only treatment likely to save her would be a bone marrow transplant from a close relative -- which leads Bessie to contact her sister Lee for the first time since their father fell ill. Bessie and Lee have a number of issues with each other that they've never resolved, many concerning their responses to Marvin's illness as Bessie rushed to his side, while Lee preferred to stay away, and Lee's own life has been difficult. She's gotten herself out of a bad marriage, has only recently started supporting herself as a beautician, and has to raise two kids on her own. Ten-year-old Charlie tries to simply ignore the chaos going on all round him, while Hank, a troubled 17-year-old, was recently institutionalized after burning down the family's home. As the straight-laced Bessie and the earthy Lee reestablish contact after two decades, they discover just how much emotional ground they have to cover before they can meet on common ground. Based on a play by Scott McPherson's who died of AIDS, it's impossible to watch the well-acted film particularly Diane Keaton, who got an Oscar nomination,as she was given a rare opportunity here to remind us that she's not simply a fine comedienne, and she's marvelous.Meryl Streep, Robert De Niro, Leonardo DiCaprio, Hume Cronyn and Gwen Verdon add to the greatness of the cast's brilliance and excellent performance.And most of all,it provides great themes about the various approaches to love; the strength of family bonds in times of death, aging parents, reconciliation; and the healing power of selfless love.It was one good movie inspite of being dull and slow at times.A can't miss movie.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Intimate dramas are the hardest to film - well worth the effort when they work though
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    eschetic-2
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/9/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Small cast, intimate dramas like MARVIN'S ROOM, NIGHT MOTHER or STEEL MAGNOLIAS are among the hardest to adapt from the confines of the stage where the imagination can open the plays ideas up and make what might seem maudlin, real and life affirming to the more realistic form of film where it is harder to see beyond the mundane "bed pan" realities of life. In order to reinvent the best of these - like the plays mentioned above - to the new genre, every break is needed starting with bravura casts who, one hopes, an audience will want to see even "reading the phone book." When a play turns around the characters dealing literally with confrontations with death at the core of the plot as in these three great plays, what HAD been on stage a single set intense evening is frequently "opened up" with all sorts of other locations and events almost as if to distract us from the very issues which we are supposed to be attending to. On stage and screen MARVIN'S ROOM may well be the best of these three "death plays," all of which started and thrived Off-Broadway (only NIGHT MOTHER made the leap to a Broadway house in its initial production). While, somewhat amazingly (considering that one of the standards of the award is "depiction of American life"), MARVIN'S ROOM was not even a finalist for the Pulitzer Prize for Drama in 1992, it did win a number of other accolades which virtually demanded that Hollywood attempt to bring it to the rest of the nation - and they certainly gave it their all starting with the genuinely all star cast which is both the movie's blessing and its curse. It enraptures with the bouquet of bravura performances even while moving focus away from the central "earth-mother" of the family forced to face her own mortality while trying to care for and hold her collapsing family together around her (Diane Keaton's Oscar nomination - the film's only - notwithstanding). Ultimately, the film gets where the play was going (as well it ought to have, since Scott McPherson had the luxury of adapting his own play - he may have written his screenplay simultaneously with, if not before the tighter stage version, since he died in 1992, the year MARVIN'S ROOM received its Off-Broadway production at Playwrights' Horizons, winning the Outer Critics' Circle and Drama Desk Awards as best Play of the Year), but the power seems to have shifted from the play's revelations themselves to the dazzling performances. It's still well worth taking the trip, but more to appreciate a monument to more than a dozen brilliant stage and screen careers than a revelatory experience on the meaning of humanity in the face of life and death that the play had been. Do, by all means see the movie. It works. ...but if you ever get a chance to see the play which either suggested it or grew from it, by all means do - it's smaller but even better.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Brilliant !
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    scottshak_111
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/11/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Marvin's room turned out to be a brilliant movie assisted well by a great performance by some veteran actors like Meryl Streep, Diane Keaton, Leonardo DiCaprio, Robert De Niro ( although he wasn't the center of attraction as he was the doctor ). Meryl Streep and Diane Keaton are two sisters who have estranged each other for 20 years and Diane calls upon her sister to take care of their father as she herself realized that she was suffering from Leukemia. Leonardo portrays the character of Hank who does not get along with his mother Meryl on account of her abusive behaviour. Diane Keaton wants Meryl to take care of her Aunt Roth and their father when she would be gone. Meryl portrays a mean woman who is afraid of responsibilities and is troubled by the deliberate acts of her son Hank (Leo). The movie is a beautiful depiction of how Meryl Streep decides to eventually aid her dying sister by stepping into her shoes and taking enough pluck to set things right between herself and Hank. Diane Keaton and Meryl Streep acted exceptionally well not to forget Leo. Altogether their performance was brilliant. I was touched by the movie. I'd rate it a 7 on 10. It was certainly one of the finest flicks that I've watched.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Better Than It Should Have Been
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    brocksilvey
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/6/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This stage to screen adaptation about two estranged sisters attempting a reconciliation after one is diagnosed with cancer is sentimental to the extreme, manipulative beyond forgiveness.....and had me close to blubbering like a baby by the time it was over. Chalk it up to the fact that I had recently lost a grandmother to cancer, but this film nearly devastated me even as I was mad that it was so maudlin. The fact that it works as well as it does is due largely to the fact that such good actors are cast in it. Meryl Streep and Diane Keaton play the sisters (Keaton is the ill one), and while it would never have occurred to me to put these two actresses together, the decision was inspired. And right before he rocketed to international fame, Leonardo DiCaprio does strong work as Keaton's troubled nephew. I won't even try to defend this film against those who say it's too schmaltzy to bear, but please let the rest of us enjoy it in blubbery peace. Grade: A-
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An Underrated Gem
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    olivia porazzi
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/5/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I happen to rank this movie as one of Leo's finest. It is definitely not as main-stream as his others, but the content and the acting was brilliant. I am a sucker for movies about dysfunctional families and this one takes the cake. It was so human...there was nothing "Hollywood" about this at all. Each character has their own emotional turmoil and when Lee comes down with Hank and Charlie, the characters are forced to come to terms with it. Leo delivered a stand-out performance in a cast of film legends. Meryl Streep is also wonderful as Lee, the self-centered mom who left her family behind in search of her own dreams.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    i liked it
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    disdressed12
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/4/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    i liked this drama starring Meryl Streep and Diane Keaton.the movie starts out as two seemingly separate stories,which end up connecting together under less than ideal circumstances.Leonardo DiCaprio also stars.the acting is good here,particularly from Streep,although Dianne Keaton is good too.DiCaprio(one year before he exploded into super stardom from Titanic)is good but his role is small.Robert De Niro has a role in what amounts to a bit more than a cameo appearance as does Dan Hedaya.you would think the movie would be depressing,but i didn't think it was.it is however,all about the drama,and so it's not fast moving,so that could be a put off for some.if you like dramatic movies,you might like this one.for me,Marvin's Room is a 7/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Exceptional
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    blanche-2
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/4/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Marvin's Room" is a 1996 film that stars Meryl Streep, Diane Keaton, Leonardo DiCaprio, Hume Cronyn, Gwen Verdon, Robert DeNiro and Dan Hedaya. Just goes to show you the kind of cast a good script can attract, even for a little film. Little film, big emotions. "Marvin's Room" is about two sisters who haven't been in touch for 20 years. Diane Keaton is Bessie, the sister who stayed home and took care of her elderly relatives - her father, Marvin (Cronyn), who is bedridden and non-verbal, and her dizzy but sweet Aunt Ruth (Verdon). Meryl Streep is Lee, the sister who got out of Dodge (Dodge being Florida), got married, had kids, got divorced, and is about to get her cosmetology license. When Bessie is diagnosed with leukemia and is told she needs a relative's bone marrow, she calls Lee. Lee packs up the kids and drives to Florida so they can all be tested. The film begins with Lee's son Hank (DiCaprio) burning down the family dwelling and getting arrested. It's an understatement to say he's angry with his mother, blaming her for the divorce. He forms a bond with his Aunt Bessie, and doesn't want to leave. His mother vehemently doesn't want to stay. In their big confrontation, Bessie accuses Lee of being selfish in not staying and sharing the burden of taking care of their family. "I took care of my family," Lee reminds her. "I had a husband and children, and I never heard from any of you people." This is one of those family dramas that hits home, and with the boomers now in the position of taking care of their parents, it's even more relevant than it was 13 years ago. Each member of the cast gives an honest and realistic performance. As the smoking, no-nonsense, nothing can touch me Lee, Meryl Streep is marvelous. I have to admit that I am not always a fan of hers, only because I can sometimes see her making acting choices. Lee is one role where she just IS the character. Keaton is excellent as the softer, warmer, more nurturing Bessie, who sublimated many of her own dreams. As the rebellious teen, Leonardo DiCaprio gives a wonderful performance as the confused Hank, who discovers family he knew nothing about. There are two sisters, and there are also two brothers - Robert DeNiro, who plays Bessie's doctor, Dr. Wally, and Dan Hedaya, the doctor's slow brother Bob who works in Wally's office. Bob isn't much help, but Wally seems to tolerate him with no problem. He's family, and Wally's responsibility. One scene that really cracked me up - Aunt Ruth loves soap operas, and when we first see her, she's watching a soap opera scene with veteran soap star John Callahan (All My Children) and Kelly Ripa. It's hilarious. I mention it because later on, it comes into play. Jerry Zaks' directing is excellent. Just have a box of tissues nearby. It's a story about a family, with lots of love underneath the problems.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Honoring a vision
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bkoganbing
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Even more interesting than the film Marvin's Room is the short tragic life of its creator Scott McPherson. Four years after he died after just completing the screenplay adaption of the play this film was based on, Marvin's Room came to the screen. No doubt the director and cast felt a particular responsibility to honor his vision. Watching Marvin's Room I was reminded of South Riding a novel that has been adapted once to the big screen and twice as mini-series for British television. The author Winifred Holtby had a short life as did McPherson and wrote a novel based on her love of the Yorkshire area of England and the people she grew up among. Though her story is an epic and McPherson's a family portrait both represent a race against mortality that both authors endured to have their work live. I recommend the film South Riding very highly, it stars Ralph Richardson and Edna Best, see my review here. Although Diane Keaton was honored with a Best Actress Oscar nomination the whole ensemble could have been honored. She plays a woman who is the chief caregiver for her aged father Hume Cronyn. Keaton has been diagnosed with leukemia and is in need of a bone marrow transplant. Among likely donors are her sister Meryl Streep and Meryl's sons, Leonardo DiCaprio and Hal Scardino. DiCaprio is a kid with some issues, he was in a mental institution for burning down their house and Streep has to get him sprung for the trip. Nothing is ever resolved for any of these people, but they do come together kind of in this crisis. That's as far as I'll go. One performance that doesn't seem to be talked about much is that of Hal Scardino as the younger son. He reminded me a lot of my younger brother, the age spread between DiCaprio and him is about the same. My family had a lot of drama as well and my brother developed certain defense mechanisms of observing silently what went on around him without necessarily participating thereof. Marvin's Room is a great ensemble production and I certainly hope that Scott McPherson one of the innumerable talents lost to the AIDS epidemic is pleased with what was done with his creation.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Oh what a difference a screenplay makes!!!!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Conork2
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/9/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I came across this movie on Netflix and thought I would give it a go! Surely a movie with Meryl Streep and Dianne Keaton wouldn't disappoint! It sure didn't! While the story has been done before in various formats it's the screenplay that makes this movie a real gem. The main three actors really do a great job. But with Streep, Keaton and DiCaprio one would expect nothing less. For me the the late Gwen Verdon steals the show. she really shows how comedy should be done. The scene with the orange is one that stands out. A mixture of comedy and heart wrenching reality showcases how underrated she has been. This for me should have definitely gained a nod in any supporting actress awards. This movie certainly won't change your life but it really does provide you with food for though about love, family and the importance of life! Give it a go. It won't disappoint.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    It's Never Too Late To Mend Broken Relationships Until You're Gone
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Chrysanthepop
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/3/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Scott McPherson adapts a beautiful screenplay from his own play. 'Marvin's Room' could have easily been just another one of those sentimental disease-of-the-weak type TV films but McPherson stays true to the story injecting it with a delightful dose of humour. The film focuses on broken relationships and how it's never too late to take the step to mend them until you're gone. The execution is simple and that works very well. The score is in sync with the flow. The writing is beautiful. The dialogues are cleverly written. Diane Keaton is marvelous in a role that could have easily turned out to be a clich&eacute; if it were played by a lesser actress. She plays her part naturally with a quiet and yet layered restraint. Meryl Streep does a fine job as the slightly more rebellious and estranged sister who had escaped from having to take care of her father and is proud of her diploma. Leonardo Dicaprio isn't bad either. Robert De Niro is great in a more laidback role. He also reveals a flare for comedy. His scenes with a splendid Dan Hedaya had me laughing. Gwen Verdon is a delight and she provides excellent comic relief. Hume Cronyn doesn't have a scene out of bed but he definitely makes the viewer take note of his performance. My favourite scene is towards the end when the two sisters chat in the kitchen. Keaton's Bessie may have been 'consumed' by taking care of her ailing father and aunt, not 'leading' her own life like the typical American woman but the amazing thing is that she doesn't regret it because she is proud that she has given them so much love and that she can do the same now with her sister and nephews. Then there's the ending which is superbly done. You're left wanting to know how these wonderful characters are doing but at the same time one can acknowledge that it's the best way to end.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Finely Acted Movie About Familial Bonds And Love
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    SiliconDesertMan40
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Two sisters try to set their familial differences aside -- one in hopes of saving her own life -- in this drama with comic accents.Marvin's Room is a film based on the play of the same name by Scott McPherson.The play, which was directed by David Petrarca, was adapted for the screen by McPherson and directed by Jerry Zaks. It stars Meryl Streep, Leonardo DiCaprio, Diane Keaton, Robert De Niro, Hume Cronyn, Gwen Verdon, Hal Scardino and Dan Hedaya. Bessie has lived in Florida for the past 20 years, where she's been caring for her chronically ill father Marvin and her Aunt Ruth, who does not seem well acquainted with reality. While Bessie's life has not been easy, she feels that it's rewarding in its way, and she's come to love her father very much. However, when Bessie is diagnosed with cancer, she's told that the only treatment likely to save her would be a bone marrow transplant from a close relative -- which leads Bessie to contact her sister Lee for the first time since their father fell ill. Bessie and Lee have a number of issues with each other that they've never resolved, many concerning their responses to Marvin's illness as Bessie rushed to his side, while Lee preferred to stay away, and Lee's own life has been difficult. She's gotten herself out of a bad marriage, has only recently started supporting herself as a beautician, and has to raise two kids on her own. Ten-year-old Charlie tries to simply ignore the chaos going on all round him, while Hank, a troubled 17-year-old, was recently institutionalized after burning down the family's home. As the straight-laced Bessie and the earthy Lee reestablish contact after two decades, they discover just how much emotional ground they have to cover before they can meet on common ground. Based on a play by Scott McPherson's who died of AIDS, it's impossible to watch the well-acted film particularly Diane Keaton, who got an Oscar nomination,as she was given a rare opportunity here to remind us that she's not simply a fine comedienne, and she's marvelous.Meryl Streep, Robert De Niro, Leonardo DiCaprio, Hume Cronyn and Gwen Verdon add to the greatness of the cast's brilliance and excellent performance.And most of all,it provides great themes about the various approaches to love; the strength of family bonds in times of death, aging parents, reconciliation; and the healing power of selfless love.It was one good movie inspite of being dull and slow at times.A can't miss movie.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Intimate dramas are the hardest to film - well worth the effort when they work though
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    eschetic-2
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/9/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Small cast, intimate dramas like MARVIN'S ROOM, NIGHT MOTHER or STEEL MAGNOLIAS are among the hardest to adapt from the confines of the stage where the imagination can open the plays ideas up and make what might seem maudlin, real and life affirming to the more realistic form of film where it is harder to see beyond the mundane "bed pan" realities of life. In order to reinvent the best of these - like the plays mentioned above - to the new genre, every break is needed starting with bravura casts who, one hopes, an audience will want to see even "reading the phone book." When a play turns around the characters dealing literally with confrontations with death at the core of the plot as in these three great plays, what HAD been on stage a single set intense evening is frequently "opened up" with all sorts of other locations and events almost as if to distract us from the very issues which we are supposed to be attending to. On stage and screen MARVIN'S ROOM may well be the best of these three "death plays," all of which started and thrived Off-Broadway (only NIGHT MOTHER made the leap to a Broadway house in its initial production). While, somewhat amazingly (considering that one of the standards of the award is "depiction of American life"), MARVIN'S ROOM was not even a finalist for the Pulitzer Prize for Drama in 1992, it did win a number of other accolades which virtually demanded that Hollywood attempt to bring it to the rest of the nation - and they certainly gave it their all starting with the genuinely all star cast which is both the movie's blessing and its curse. It enraptures with the bouquet of bravura performances even while moving focus away from the central "earth-mother" of the family forced to face her own mortality while trying to care for and hold her collapsing family together around her (Diane Keaton's Oscar nomination - the film's only - notwithstanding). Ultimately, the film gets where the play was going (as well it ought to have, since Scott McPherson had the luxury of adapting his own play - he may have written his screenplay simultaneously with, if not before the tighter stage version, since he died in 1992, the year MARVIN'S ROOM received its Off-Broadway production at Playwrights' Horizons, winning the Outer Critics' Circle and Drama Desk Awards as best Play of the Year), but the power seems to have shifted from the play's revelations themselves to the dazzling performances. It's still well worth taking the trip, but more to appreciate a monument to more than a dozen brilliant stage and screen careers than a revelatory experience on the meaning of humanity in the face of life and death that the play had been. Do, by all means see the movie. It works. ...but if you ever get a chance to see the play which either suggested it or grew from it, by all means do - it's smaller but even better.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Brilliant !
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    scottshak_111
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/11/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Marvin's room turned out to be a brilliant movie assisted well by a great performance by some veteran actors like Meryl Streep, Diane Keaton, Leonardo DiCaprio, Robert De Niro ( although he wasn't the center of attraction as he was the doctor ). Meryl Streep and Diane Keaton are two sisters who have estranged each other for 20 years and Diane calls upon her sister to take care of their father as she herself realized that she was suffering from Leukemia. Leonardo portrays the character of Hank who does not get along with his mother Meryl on account of her abusive behaviour. Diane Keaton wants Meryl to take care of her Aunt Roth and their father when she would be gone. Meryl portrays a mean woman who is afraid of responsibilities and is troubled by the deliberate acts of her son Hank (Leo). The movie is a beautiful depiction of how Meryl Streep decides to eventually aid her dying sister by stepping into her shoes and taking enough pluck to set things right between herself and Hank. Diane Keaton and Meryl Streep acted exceptionally well not to forget Leo. Altogether their performance was brilliant. I was touched by the movie. I'd rate it a 7 on 10. It was certainly one of the finest flicks that I've watched.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Better Than It Should Have Been
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    brocksilvey
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/6/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This stage to screen adaptation about two estranged sisters attempting a reconciliation after one is diagnosed with cancer is sentimental to the extreme, manipulative beyond forgiveness.....and had me close to blubbering like a baby by the time it was over. Chalk it up to the fact that I had recently lost a grandmother to cancer, but this film nearly devastated me even as I was mad that it was so maudlin. The fact that it works as well as it does is due largely to the fact that such good actors are cast in it. Meryl Streep and Diane Keaton play the sisters (Keaton is the ill one), and while it would never have occurred to me to put these two actresses together, the decision was inspired. And right before he rocketed to international fame, Leonardo DiCaprio does strong work as Keaton's troubled nephew. I won't even try to defend this film against those who say it's too schmaltzy to bear, but please let the rest of us enjoy it in blubbery peace. Grade: A-
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An Underrated Gem
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    olivia porazzi
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/5/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I happen to rank this movie as one of Leo's finest. It is definitely not as main-stream as his others, but the content and the acting was brilliant. I am a sucker for movies about dysfunctional families and this one takes the cake. It was so human...there was nothing "Hollywood" about this at all. Each character has their own emotional turmoil and when Lee comes down with Hank and Charlie, the characters are forced to come to terms with it. Leo delivered a stand-out performance in a cast of film legends. Meryl Streep is also wonderful as Lee, the self-centered mom who left her family behind in search of her own dreams.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    i liked it
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    disdressed12
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/4/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    i liked this drama starring Meryl Streep and Diane Keaton.the movie starts out as two seemingly separate stories,which end up connecting together under less than ideal circumstances.Leonardo DiCaprio also stars.the acting is good here,particularly from Streep,although Dianne Keaton is good too.DiCaprio(one year before he exploded into super stardom from Titanic)is good but his role is small.Robert De Niro has a role in what amounts to a bit more than a cameo appearance as does Dan Hedaya.you would think the movie would be depressing,but i didn't think it was.it is however,all about the drama,and so it's not fast moving,so that could be a put off for some.if you like dramatic movies,you might like this one.for me,Marvin's Room is a 7/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Exceptional
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    blanche-2
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/4/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Marvin's Room" is a 1996 film that stars Meryl Streep, Diane Keaton, Leonardo DiCaprio, Hume Cronyn, Gwen Verdon, Robert DeNiro and Dan Hedaya. Just goes to show you the kind of cast a good script can attract, even for a little film. Little film, big emotions. "Marvin's Room" is about two sisters who haven't been in touch for 20 years. Diane Keaton is Bessie, the sister who stayed home and took care of her elderly relatives - her father, Marvin (Cronyn), who is bedridden and non-verbal, and her dizzy but sweet Aunt Ruth (Verdon). Meryl Streep is Lee, the sister who got out of Dodge (Dodge being Florida), got married, had kids, got divorced, and is about to get her cosmetology license. When Bessie is diagnosed with leukemia and is told she needs a relative's bone marrow, she calls Lee. Lee packs up the kids and drives to Florida so they can all be tested. The film begins with Lee's son Hank (DiCaprio) burning down the family dwelling and getting arrested. It's an understatement to say he's angry with his mother, blaming her for the divorce. He forms a bond with his Aunt Bessie, and doesn't want to leave. His mother vehemently doesn't want to stay. In their big confrontation, Bessie accuses Lee of being selfish in not staying and sharing the burden of taking care of their family. "I took care of my family," Lee reminds her. "I had a husband and children, and I never heard from any of you people." This is one of those family dramas that hits home, and with the boomers now in the position of taking care of their parents, it's even more relevant than it was 13 years ago. Each member of the cast gives an honest and realistic performance. As the smoking, no-nonsense, nothing can touch me Lee, Meryl Streep is marvelous. I have to admit that I am not always a fan of hers, only because I can sometimes see her making acting choices. Lee is one role where she just IS the character. Keaton is excellent as the softer, warmer, more nurturing Bessie, who sublimated many of her own dreams. As the rebellious teen, Leonardo DiCaprio gives a wonderful performance as the confused Hank, who discovers family he knew nothing about. There are two sisters, and there are also two brothers - Robert DeNiro, who plays Bessie's doctor, Dr. Wally, and Dan Hedaya, the doctor's slow brother Bob who works in Wally's office. Bob isn't much help, but Wally seems to tolerate him with no problem. He's family, and Wally's responsibility. One scene that really cracked me up - Aunt Ruth loves soap operas, and when we first see her, she's watching a soap opera scene with veteran soap star John Callahan (All My Children) and Kelly Ripa. It's hilarious. I mention it because later on, it comes into play. Jerry Zaks' directing is excellent. Just have a box of tissues nearby. It's a story about a family, with lots of love underneath the problems.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
 </reviews>
</filme>
