<filme>
 <id>
  296
 </id>
 <imdburl>
  http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0117398
 </imdburl>
 <ano>
  1996
 </ano>
 <titulo>
  La promesse
 </titulo>
 <rating>
  7.7
 </rating>
 <sinopse>
  Igor and his father, Roger, are making a decent living renting apartments to illegal immigrants and sometimes working them illegally (among other scams). But when the building inspector ... &nbsp;&raquo;
 </sinopse>
 <storyline>
  Igor and his father, Roger, are making a decent living renting apartments to illegal immigrants and sometimes working them illegally (among other scams). But when the building inspector pays a surprise visit and Amidou falls off a scaffold in his hurry to hide, things start to unravel, particularly when Igor makes a promise to the injured Amidou that ultimately exposes the different values of Igor and Roger, and of Amidou's wife, Assita.
 </storyline>
 <generos>
  <genero>
   Drama
  </genero>
 </generos>
 <keywords>
  <keyword>
   ring
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   baby
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   illegal immigration
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   father son relationship
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   belgium
  </keyword>
 </keywords>
 <diretores>
  <diretor>
   Jean-Pierre Dardenne
  </diretor>
  <diretor>
   Luc Dardenne
  </diretor>
 </diretores>
 <escritores>
  <escritor>
   Luc Dardenne
  </escritor>
  <escritor>
   Jean-Pierre Dardenne
  </escritor>
 </escritores>
 <atores>
  <ator>
   J&eacute;r&eacute;mie Renier
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Olivier Gourmet
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Assita Ouedraogo
  </ator>
 </atores>
 <reviews>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Moral choices, and lack thereof
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bandw
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Roger is perhaps one of the most immoral people you are likely to meet. He is running a business that uses illegal immigrants for his construction business. He manages a complete operation, from sneaking the people into Belgium, to employing and housing them. He pays the workers minimum wages and charges them for their housing. The immigrants are little more than slave labor--if their financial situation does not keep them in line, their fear of discovery by the authorities seals the deal. But that works two ways, since Roger is in constant fear that his operation will be uncovered by the authorities. The topic of illegal immigration is controversial in many western countries and this movie indicates that not only do illegals have a tough time on the job, but they are also not welcome among the general citizenry, as illustrated here by an illegal being urinated on and having her possessions trashed. But the plight of the immigrants is a subplot, since the focus is on Roger's son Igor who works for his dad. Initially Igor seems to be following in Roger's footsteps as we see him execute a scheme to steal a woman's money from her car in such a casual way that we think we know the path his life will take. The genius of the movie has Igor experience a sequence of events that make him question his moral values, or, more accurately, the lack of such. Ultimately Igor's maturing sense of morality causes him to act in ways that put him in serious conflict with his father. A lot of gray areas are explored. Roger does love Igor and at one point says that everything he does is for his son. If there is truth in that, then Roger adheres to the philosophy that the end justifies the means and he has allowed himself to be blinded to the humanity of his workers. Roger's behavior is a small scale version of attitudes that have been responsible for many of the world's biggest horrors. In showing Igor's struggle with moral questions the Dardenne brothers seem to be making a case that morality is in part genetic and must serve an evolutionary purpose--Igor's upbringing would argue against his turning on his father. In the final scene did Igor make the right decision in being so honest? Could he not have withheld the most brutal fact? The ending left me wanting to know what happened next. Filmed with muted colors, no musical score, a grim urban background, and little comic relief, this is not for those looking for light entertainment.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An intense story of trespassing and change
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Ilpo Hirvonen
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/4/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    After ten years of directing documentaries the Dardenne brothers directed their first fictional film, Falsch (1987). In 1992 they finished their second one, Je pense &agrave; vous (I Think About You) which they didn't think as a good film. After four years, came their first real "Dardenne-film" The Promise. It was the first film where they found their own unique style. The Promise is a story of a father son relationship, which they had already dealt with in Falsch. Roger (Olivier Gourmet), with his 15-year-old son Igor (J&eacute;r&eacute;mie Renier), drives across industrial Belgium to get illegal immigrants from a truck. They bring them back to a block of flats they live in and start charging them for money. One of the immigrants is Assita who has come to Belgium with her husband to find a better future for them and their baby. One day when immigrant-inspectors pay a visit events start to have radical consequences. The films by the Dardenne brothers usually focus on the moral choices the characters have to make and what are the consequences. In The Promise Igor has to decide, whether to obey his father or to do what's right and help Assita. Then we get to the question what is the right thing to do? And this is what Luc & Jean-Pierre Dardenne want to do: let us observe and think. Luc Dardenne has said that the basic idea of film-making is to reconstruct new humane experiences. The Promise makes one think about these moral dilemmas and social issues but also associate the events with one's own life. Geographically Belgium is in between of Germany and France - Belgium is only a country for trespassing. For instance a harsh example; Hitler in WWII. This is the main theme of The Promise - it is a story of trespassing. For Assita Belgium is a metaphor of a certain state in life, which she is just passing by. No one stays in Belgium (or in that state of life). As is Assita in between of two worlds; her home country and Belgium, so is Igor. Igor feels himself grown-up when he's collecting taxes for his father and driving around Belgium. But on the other hand he's full of juvenile joy as he drives with his friends on a go-kart. Igor was played by J&eacute;r&eacute;mie Renier (L 'Enfant, Lorna's Silence). It was his first role and through that he brought a realistic life to the character who tries to free himself from the chains of his father - the brothers have always appreciated the idea of using amateur actors. Igor's father, Roger was played by the Golden Palm-winner Olivier Gourmet, who is in my opinion a very talented actor. He gives a great life to Roger, whose world is worthless and merciless. The Dardenne brothers were raised in an industrial town in Belgium, which is the milieu in all of their films. The sound scape is something that one should pay attention to. There's no musical score at all only the voices the characters hear, the voices of an industrial town - ambiance. In the end the industrial voices just keep going on as the credits come on the screen. It's like we can't handle them anymore, they're spreading off the screen. A bit like in Chaplin's City Lights. The minimalist style of The Promise is amazing. It's touching on a new level. The brothers have totally succeed in their mission to create new humane experiences. Luc Dardenne writes in his 'diary' Behind Our Pictures, that the more you take material away the closer you get to the humane emotions, which he achieves through the severe aesthetics, minimalism and ruthless sound scape. Faces are in an important role, when describing humane emotions in The Promise the faces have also a dramaturgical role. I'm going to quote Luc Dardenne here, translated in English: "In every scene with Igor and Assita where they look to each other, Igor is always the first to turn his head away. Igor isn't able to meet Assita's eyes, because he senses a moral command that he cannot reply. Except in the final scene." And what a redemption it is in the end. The meaning of facial expressions and the philosophy behind it comes from a French philosopher Emmanuel L&eacute;vinas, who both of the brothers admire and from whom they get background for their philosophy of film. The Promise is thinking - philosophy of film. The brothers have stabilized film as an instrument for philosophy. I hope that the true film fanatics get to see this and appreciate it as much as I do. In addition to its themes of change, father-son relationship and trespassing, The Promise challenges the viewer to think on its own. The brothers force us to meet the moral choices out there.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A melodramatic masterpiece
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Zmajina
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/9/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Despite the criminal setting, the human trafficking and what have you, don't be fooled by phrases like "socially relevant". This is pure melodrama. In fact, any soap opera writer would proudly exploit the plot elements of the film. But what makes it a masterpiece is the absolutely flawless direction. There is not a single scene that is superfluous. Blink and you'll miss an important link in the story. Behind the apparent simplicity of each scene there is a lot of careful planning. The feelings and actions of the characters are skilfully pointed out for exactly as long as it takes to understand them. The Dardenne brothers are helped by a cast that remains etched in your memory, but I doubt any of the actors would shine this much in a less carefully directed film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Low-key coming of age drama from the brothers Dardenne
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Graham Greene
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/4/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Brothers Jean-Pierre and Luc Dardenne concern themselves with creating films that put realism on the screen without using artifice or cinematic trickery to distract the audience from the socially aware message at the core of their narratives. Unlike the similarly themed dogme movement, or the more iconic works of Lars von Trier etc, the Dardenne brothers are unconcerned with changing the face of cinematic reality, but rather, take their cue from people like Ken Loach, Bruno Dumont and Robert Bresson; by creating honest, often-bleak works of film that take their character from despair, to hope, and sometimes, right back to despair, in order to give the audience a taste of a world away from the more comfortable social milieu we might be accustomed to. The concept could be read as hypocritical admittedly, and although the occasional heavy-handed quality of the brother's work does intermittently become preachy, there is ample opportunity to deliver some moments of earth-shattering drama. I first encountered the Dardenne's work back in 2001, when British film channel Film Four premiered their film The Promise (1996) in preparation for the premier of their highly acclaimed follow up film Rosetta (1999). Both films are here are heavily indebted to the naturalistic/realist work of Bresson and Loach, particularly films like Diary of a Country Priest (1951), Riff Raff (1990) and Raining Stones (1993); with the filmmakers presenting the viewer with a series of characters continually forced to the brink of despair, but desperate to pull themselves back. For me, out of the two films of theirs that I have thus far seen, The Promise is the one that makes the greatest impact. Here, The Dardenne's create a world that isn't a million miles away from the current social climate in the UK, with building sites, smoky pubs and migrant workers peppering what is essentially the typical rites-of-passage/coming of age movie so familiar even by Hollywood standards. The brothers rest their narrative firmly on the shoulders of young newcomer J&eacute;r&eacute;mie R&eacute;nier as Igor, a teenage tearaway forced into looking after a young black mother and her baby following the death of the woman's husband whilst working for the company run by Igor's father. The brothers season their film with an abundance of topical, moralistic issues such as the passage into adulthood, immigration and domestic abuse, but at the centre of the drama there is still room for hope in the touching father son relationship between Igor and his disparate dad (played here by award winning actor and regular Dardenne collaborator Olivier Gourmet). The Promise might not be a ground-breaking film; its ideas are well worn and its scenarios familiar from the classic kitchen-sink cinema of films like Saturday Night and Sunday Morning (1960) and A Taste of Honey (1961) to name only two, but the process of refinement that the brothers are able to create with the subtle shading of characters and the no-nonsense approach to film-making is really quite affecting on the most personal and emotional of levels.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    sincere and moving
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    dromasca
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/4/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    More than ten years after its release this film by the Dardenne brothers still looks fresh and actual. This is the story of a father and son who are involved in smuggling and hosting illegal immigrants in the European Community. When one of the immigrants dies in the accident the father imposes a cover-up. The boy cannot live quietly with this deed and slowly gets closer to the widow and her baby, filling in the promise to care for them that he had made to the dying immigrant, and redeeming himself and his humanity in the process. The quality and emotion of the film lie in the direct, almost documentary approach taken by the directors in telling the story, the realistic setting and especially in the splendid acting. Both Olivier Gourmet as the father and Jeremier Renier as the son give excellent performances, they are real, moving, caring for every detail. The two make this simple film a film to remember.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Another Dardenne Brothers Masterpiece
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    omalley-brendan
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/6/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The performance of J&eacute;r&eacute;mie Renier is memorable. (He's also great in L'infant). The Dardennes are obviously influenced by Robert Bresson and have a similar interest in use of realistic sound, and observation of everyday tasks. They especially like workshops, and woodworking tools. Like Bresson, they eschew incidental music and produce a very naturalistic view of events. And they do it so well. This film will remain in your conscience for a long time after you have seen it, and should satisfy those who need a resolution and a conclusion in their movies, by offering at least an answer to one "will he - won't he?" dilemma. These guys are making some of the best cinema of the present era.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    very gritty and odd little film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    planktonrules
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/12/2005
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I liked this film because it dared to be different. It was about as far from a "Hollywood-style" film as you can get! The story involves some pretty nasty characters. In particular, a teenage boy and his father. They make money by exploiting illegal immigrants in France--picking up the poor people and housing them in a tenement--all as exorbitant rates. This pair appear to be people without souls as they lie and cheat again and again. However, when one of these illegals accidentally dies, the paths of the two diverge. Dad just wants to dump the body and could care less about the man's widow and young child (wanting to sell her into a life of prostitution), while the boy who witnessed the final words of the dying man promised to look after the family. What, exactly, happened next I'll leave for the viewer. Provided you have a tolerance for movies about realistically seedy people, this is a film worth seeing. An interesting twist, not taken in the film, would have been if later the boy had found out that his father was not really his biological dad--but the "dad" raised him from infancy after his own real family died while being smuggled into France by him. This could be an interesting path.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Promise Kept
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    writers_reign
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/11/2004
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is available with Rosetta on one DVD and it's a welcome change to discover a double DVD where both films are equal in quality. I'm not usually a fan of the 'hand-held' camera school of film making but in the case of Rosetta and this film I am happy to make an exception. It may well be noted that the freres Dardennes tend to load the dice in their own favor but there are times when a case can be made for playing with a stacked deck and this is one of them. Not too much happens. We meet Igor (Jeremie Regnier) and his father Roger (Olivier Gourmet) almost from Frame #1. Teenage Igor, pumping gas is not above stealing a purse from an elderly lady and if we find this a tad amoral it is as nothing compared to his old man who has a nice line in illegal immigrants, demanding their passports - or rather delegating Igor to collect them - in return for a few square meters of squalor and a fifty-fifty chance of deportation if and when they prove unable and/or unwilling to pay the extortionate 'rent'. The first and literal promise is the one made by Igor to the African who has fallen from a ladder whilst renovating the clapped-out house owned by Roger and is subsequently finished off by Roger lest his injuries prove an embarrassment. The injured man charges Igor with being responsible for the welfare of his wife and child and Igor, being still impressionable, takes this seriously, so much so, that he severs relations with his father thus bringing into play the secondary meaning of the title, the promise shown by Igor of getting under the wire as a human being. Excellent acting all round, complete lack of background music and a plot that ultimate involves make for a highly satisfying movie. 8/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A promise (Echo and the Bunnymen)
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    dbdumonteil
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/4/2004
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Spoilers, spoilers, spoilers... In the nineties, Belgium gave us two or rather three great directors: Jaco Van Dormael (the terrific "Toto the hero" 1991) and the Dardenne brothers. But the cinema of the latter is more realist and matter-of-fact. Furthermore, it evokes Ken Loach's with a difference: if Ken Loach presents the pains of Western society by introducing humor, it isn't the same thing with the Dardenne brothers where humor is absent. For "the promise", the Dardenne brothers opted for neutrality and sobriety: short and quick dialogs, a film that essentially relies on the characters' gestures and countenances, no music, a vivid and rough directing that often shows the actors with back turned and especially a will to show a bleak social reality (the migrant workers' exploitation) and for this the movie almost takes a documentary aspect. The authors don't pass judgment, they don't feel pity. They just take a gritty and harsh look on these emigrants who live in dilapidated flats with a starvation wage. Besides, we can take down a significant detail: their hard living conditions echoes to a gray sky and it gives to the film a dull atmosphere. An important point of the film is the relationship between Igor and his father. The beginning of the film presents a relationship between a father and his son that we could describe as complicity. At this moment, the movie becomes tinged with tenderness. But throughout the movie, this complicity gradually turns into an open opposition and the consequences of Igor's promise open his eyes on his fathers' cruelty. "The promise" is also a movie that includes powerful moments because the suggested has the edge on the showed: Hammidou's mortal accident, the very last sequence of the movie when Igor decides to reveal the truth to Assita about her husband (we don't see her face but the simple view of her bent back makes us suggest her sadness. The performance is also remarkable. Beginning with J&eacute;r&eacute;mie R&eacute;gnier who brings a lot of freshness to his character and the authors gave him the picture of a friendly boy. It is interesting to notice that he and "Rosetta" (1999) have a few common points. For example, they evolute in a tough environment. Moreover, Olivier Gourmet's awesome performance in the role of the father adds to the success of the film. "The promise" shows the Dardenne's brothers' talent who are the main leaders of Belgian cinema.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Belgian immigration problems
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    calculo
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/2/2003
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The brothers Dardenne understand how to tell a story without narration. The characters in this movie are strong enough to develop their own lines and short dialogues without commentary. There is no music or sound. The problem of this movie is apparent to "Baran (2001)" but in a different context and country. The style is near to "La Vie de J&eacute;sus (1997)" by Bruno Dumont and the hardness of life close to "Seul contre Tous (1998)" by Gaspar No&eacute;. Those last two movies have something more in common: they are situated in the old industrial country of the north of France and the south of Belgium. One could explore a stylistic nearness to Ken Loach but the narration goes deeper. It is the sole existence of mankind who is put into question. Father, why do we live? Igor (J&eacute;r&eacute;mie R&eacute;nier) seems to ask continuously to his father Roger (Olivier Gourmet). This film is a good attempt to make something as Belgian social realism without a parade or a revolution by the workers. They seem now to be more isolated (some exception: "Fermeture des usines Renault &agrave; Vilvoorde (1998))" and confined to villages with a non-existing working-class. The unemployed seem to have replaced the workers. A strange situation happens when Assita goes to a clairvoyant to know what happened with Amadou and the answer will be as cryptic as the situation wherein she is. Is the promise that Igor made (in fact it was his father) so important? The movie seems to suggest that a 14-year old boy could change the situation and ameliorate the fate of Assita. The real problem is that illegal immigration is a crime that has many consequences and at least it creates innumerable problems when something happens and it is a waste for the society and what more is, it puts the illegal workers into great danger because they come into the hands of people without conscience or humanity.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Moral choices, and lack thereof
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bandw
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Roger is perhaps one of the most immoral people you are likely to meet. He is running a business that uses illegal immigrants for his construction business. He manages a complete operation, from sneaking the people into Belgium, to employing and housing them. He pays the workers minimum wages and charges them for their housing. The immigrants are little more than slave labor--if their financial situation does not keep them in line, their fear of discovery by the authorities seals the deal. But that works two ways, since Roger is in constant fear that his operation will be uncovered by the authorities. The topic of illegal immigration is controversial in many western countries and this movie indicates that not only do illegals have a tough time on the job, but they are also not welcome among the general citizenry, as illustrated here by an illegal being urinated on and having her possessions trashed. But the plight of the immigrants is a subplot, since the focus is on Roger's son Igor who works for his dad. Initially Igor seems to be following in Roger's footsteps as we see him execute a scheme to steal a woman's money from her car in such a casual way that we think we know the path his life will take. The genius of the movie has Igor experience a sequence of events that make him question his moral values, or, more accurately, the lack of such. Ultimately Igor's maturing sense of morality causes him to act in ways that put him in serious conflict with his father. A lot of gray areas are explored. Roger does love Igor and at one point says that everything he does is for his son. If there is truth in that, then Roger adheres to the philosophy that the end justifies the means and he has allowed himself to be blinded to the humanity of his workers. Roger's behavior is a small scale version of attitudes that have been responsible for many of the world's biggest horrors. In showing Igor's struggle with moral questions the Dardenne brothers seem to be making a case that morality is in part genetic and must serve an evolutionary purpose--Igor's upbringing would argue against his turning on his father. In the final scene did Igor make the right decision in being so honest? Could he not have withheld the most brutal fact? The ending left me wanting to know what happened next. Filmed with muted colors, no musical score, a grim urban background, and little comic relief, this is not for those looking for light entertainment.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An intense story of trespassing and change
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Ilpo Hirvonen
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/4/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    After ten years of directing documentaries the Dardenne brothers directed their first fictional film, Falsch (1987). In 1992 they finished their second one, Je pense &agrave; vous (I Think About You) which they didn't think as a good film. After four years, came their first real "Dardenne-film" The Promise. It was the first film where they found their own unique style. The Promise is a story of a father son relationship, which they had already dealt with in Falsch. Roger (Olivier Gourmet), with his 15-year-old son Igor (J&eacute;r&eacute;mie Renier), drives across industrial Belgium to get illegal immigrants from a truck. They bring them back to a block of flats they live in and start charging them for money. One of the immigrants is Assita who has come to Belgium with her husband to find a better future for them and their baby. One day when immigrant-inspectors pay a visit events start to have radical consequences. The films by the Dardenne brothers usually focus on the moral choices the characters have to make and what are the consequences. In The Promise Igor has to decide, whether to obey his father or to do what's right and help Assita. Then we get to the question what is the right thing to do? And this is what Luc & Jean-Pierre Dardenne want to do: let us observe and think. Luc Dardenne has said that the basic idea of film-making is to reconstruct new humane experiences. The Promise makes one think about these moral dilemmas and social issues but also associate the events with one's own life. Geographically Belgium is in between of Germany and France - Belgium is only a country for trespassing. For instance a harsh example; Hitler in WWII. This is the main theme of The Promise - it is a story of trespassing. For Assita Belgium is a metaphor of a certain state in life, which she is just passing by. No one stays in Belgium (or in that state of life). As is Assita in between of two worlds; her home country and Belgium, so is Igor. Igor feels himself grown-up when he's collecting taxes for his father and driving around Belgium. But on the other hand he's full of juvenile joy as he drives with his friends on a go-kart. Igor was played by J&eacute;r&eacute;mie Renier (L 'Enfant, Lorna's Silence). It was his first role and through that he brought a realistic life to the character who tries to free himself from the chains of his father - the brothers have always appreciated the idea of using amateur actors. Igor's father, Roger was played by the Golden Palm-winner Olivier Gourmet, who is in my opinion a very talented actor. He gives a great life to Roger, whose world is worthless and merciless. The Dardenne brothers were raised in an industrial town in Belgium, which is the milieu in all of their films. The sound scape is something that one should pay attention to. There's no musical score at all only the voices the characters hear, the voices of an industrial town - ambiance. In the end the industrial voices just keep going on as the credits come on the screen. It's like we can't handle them anymore, they're spreading off the screen. A bit like in Chaplin's City Lights. The minimalist style of The Promise is amazing. It's touching on a new level. The brothers have totally succeed in their mission to create new humane experiences. Luc Dardenne writes in his 'diary' Behind Our Pictures, that the more you take material away the closer you get to the humane emotions, which he achieves through the severe aesthetics, minimalism and ruthless sound scape. Faces are in an important role, when describing humane emotions in The Promise the faces have also a dramaturgical role. I'm going to quote Luc Dardenne here, translated in English: "In every scene with Igor and Assita where they look to each other, Igor is always the first to turn his head away. Igor isn't able to meet Assita's eyes, because he senses a moral command that he cannot reply. Except in the final scene." And what a redemption it is in the end. The meaning of facial expressions and the philosophy behind it comes from a French philosopher Emmanuel L&eacute;vinas, who both of the brothers admire and from whom they get background for their philosophy of film. The Promise is thinking - philosophy of film. The brothers have stabilized film as an instrument for philosophy. I hope that the true film fanatics get to see this and appreciate it as much as I do. In addition to its themes of change, father-son relationship and trespassing, The Promise challenges the viewer to think on its own. The brothers force us to meet the moral choices out there.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A melodramatic masterpiece
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Zmajina
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/9/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Despite the criminal setting, the human trafficking and what have you, don't be fooled by phrases like "socially relevant". This is pure melodrama. In fact, any soap opera writer would proudly exploit the plot elements of the film. But what makes it a masterpiece is the absolutely flawless direction. There is not a single scene that is superfluous. Blink and you'll miss an important link in the story. Behind the apparent simplicity of each scene there is a lot of careful planning. The feelings and actions of the characters are skilfully pointed out for exactly as long as it takes to understand them. The Dardenne brothers are helped by a cast that remains etched in your memory, but I doubt any of the actors would shine this much in a less carefully directed film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Low-key coming of age drama from the brothers Dardenne
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Graham Greene
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/4/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Brothers Jean-Pierre and Luc Dardenne concern themselves with creating films that put realism on the screen without using artifice or cinematic trickery to distract the audience from the socially aware message at the core of their narratives. Unlike the similarly themed dogme movement, or the more iconic works of Lars von Trier etc, the Dardenne brothers are unconcerned with changing the face of cinematic reality, but rather, take their cue from people like Ken Loach, Bruno Dumont and Robert Bresson; by creating honest, often-bleak works of film that take their character from despair, to hope, and sometimes, right back to despair, in order to give the audience a taste of a world away from the more comfortable social milieu we might be accustomed to. The concept could be read as hypocritical admittedly, and although the occasional heavy-handed quality of the brother's work does intermittently become preachy, there is ample opportunity to deliver some moments of earth-shattering drama. I first encountered the Dardenne's work back in 2001, when British film channel Film Four premiered their film The Promise (1996) in preparation for the premier of their highly acclaimed follow up film Rosetta (1999). Both films are here are heavily indebted to the naturalistic/realist work of Bresson and Loach, particularly films like Diary of a Country Priest (1951), Riff Raff (1990) and Raining Stones (1993); with the filmmakers presenting the viewer with a series of characters continually forced to the brink of despair, but desperate to pull themselves back. For me, out of the two films of theirs that I have thus far seen, The Promise is the one that makes the greatest impact. Here, The Dardenne's create a world that isn't a million miles away from the current social climate in the UK, with building sites, smoky pubs and migrant workers peppering what is essentially the typical rites-of-passage/coming of age movie so familiar even by Hollywood standards. The brothers rest their narrative firmly on the shoulders of young newcomer J&eacute;r&eacute;mie R&eacute;nier as Igor, a teenage tearaway forced into looking after a young black mother and her baby following the death of the woman's husband whilst working for the company run by Igor's father. The brothers season their film with an abundance of topical, moralistic issues such as the passage into adulthood, immigration and domestic abuse, but at the centre of the drama there is still room for hope in the touching father son relationship between Igor and his disparate dad (played here by award winning actor and regular Dardenne collaborator Olivier Gourmet). The Promise might not be a ground-breaking film; its ideas are well worn and its scenarios familiar from the classic kitchen-sink cinema of films like Saturday Night and Sunday Morning (1960) and A Taste of Honey (1961) to name only two, but the process of refinement that the brothers are able to create with the subtle shading of characters and the no-nonsense approach to film-making is really quite affecting on the most personal and emotional of levels.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    sincere and moving
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    dromasca
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/4/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    More than ten years after its release this film by the Dardenne brothers still looks fresh and actual. This is the story of a father and son who are involved in smuggling and hosting illegal immigrants in the European Community. When one of the immigrants dies in the accident the father imposes a cover-up. The boy cannot live quietly with this deed and slowly gets closer to the widow and her baby, filling in the promise to care for them that he had made to the dying immigrant, and redeeming himself and his humanity in the process. The quality and emotion of the film lie in the direct, almost documentary approach taken by the directors in telling the story, the realistic setting and especially in the splendid acting. Both Olivier Gourmet as the father and Jeremier Renier as the son give excellent performances, they are real, moving, caring for every detail. The two make this simple film a film to remember.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Another Dardenne Brothers Masterpiece
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    omalley-brendan
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/6/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The performance of J&eacute;r&eacute;mie Renier is memorable. (He's also great in L'infant). The Dardennes are obviously influenced by Robert Bresson and have a similar interest in use of realistic sound, and observation of everyday tasks. They especially like workshops, and woodworking tools. Like Bresson, they eschew incidental music and produce a very naturalistic view of events. And they do it so well. This film will remain in your conscience for a long time after you have seen it, and should satisfy those who need a resolution and a conclusion in their movies, by offering at least an answer to one "will he - won't he?" dilemma. These guys are making some of the best cinema of the present era.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    very gritty and odd little film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    planktonrules
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/12/2005
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I liked this film because it dared to be different. It was about as far from a "Hollywood-style" film as you can get! The story involves some pretty nasty characters. In particular, a teenage boy and his father. They make money by exploiting illegal immigrants in France--picking up the poor people and housing them in a tenement--all as exorbitant rates. This pair appear to be people without souls as they lie and cheat again and again. However, when one of these illegals accidentally dies, the paths of the two diverge. Dad just wants to dump the body and could care less about the man's widow and young child (wanting to sell her into a life of prostitution), while the boy who witnessed the final words of the dying man promised to look after the family. What, exactly, happened next I'll leave for the viewer. Provided you have a tolerance for movies about realistically seedy people, this is a film worth seeing. An interesting twist, not taken in the film, would have been if later the boy had found out that his father was not really his biological dad--but the "dad" raised him from infancy after his own real family died while being smuggled into France by him. This could be an interesting path.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Promise Kept
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    writers_reign
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/11/2004
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is available with Rosetta on one DVD and it's a welcome change to discover a double DVD where both films are equal in quality. I'm not usually a fan of the 'hand-held' camera school of film making but in the case of Rosetta and this film I am happy to make an exception. It may well be noted that the freres Dardennes tend to load the dice in their own favor but there are times when a case can be made for playing with a stacked deck and this is one of them. Not too much happens. We meet Igor (Jeremie Regnier) and his father Roger (Olivier Gourmet) almost from Frame #1. Teenage Igor, pumping gas is not above stealing a purse from an elderly lady and if we find this a tad amoral it is as nothing compared to his old man who has a nice line in illegal immigrants, demanding their passports - or rather delegating Igor to collect them - in return for a few square meters of squalor and a fifty-fifty chance of deportation if and when they prove unable and/or unwilling to pay the extortionate 'rent'. The first and literal promise is the one made by Igor to the African who has fallen from a ladder whilst renovating the clapped-out house owned by Roger and is subsequently finished off by Roger lest his injuries prove an embarrassment. The injured man charges Igor with being responsible for the welfare of his wife and child and Igor, being still impressionable, takes this seriously, so much so, that he severs relations with his father thus bringing into play the secondary meaning of the title, the promise shown by Igor of getting under the wire as a human being. Excellent acting all round, complete lack of background music and a plot that ultimate involves make for a highly satisfying movie. 8/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A promise (Echo and the Bunnymen)
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    dbdumonteil
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/4/2004
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Spoilers, spoilers, spoilers... In the nineties, Belgium gave us two or rather three great directors: Jaco Van Dormael (the terrific "Toto the hero" 1991) and the Dardenne brothers. But the cinema of the latter is more realist and matter-of-fact. Furthermore, it evokes Ken Loach's with a difference: if Ken Loach presents the pains of Western society by introducing humor, it isn't the same thing with the Dardenne brothers where humor is absent. For "the promise", the Dardenne brothers opted for neutrality and sobriety: short and quick dialogs, a film that essentially relies on the characters' gestures and countenances, no music, a vivid and rough directing that often shows the actors with back turned and especially a will to show a bleak social reality (the migrant workers' exploitation) and for this the movie almost takes a documentary aspect. The authors don't pass judgment, they don't feel pity. They just take a gritty and harsh look on these emigrants who live in dilapidated flats with a starvation wage. Besides, we can take down a significant detail: their hard living conditions echoes to a gray sky and it gives to the film a dull atmosphere. An important point of the film is the relationship between Igor and his father. The beginning of the film presents a relationship between a father and his son that we could describe as complicity. At this moment, the movie becomes tinged with tenderness. But throughout the movie, this complicity gradually turns into an open opposition and the consequences of Igor's promise open his eyes on his fathers' cruelty. "The promise" is also a movie that includes powerful moments because the suggested has the edge on the showed: Hammidou's mortal accident, the very last sequence of the movie when Igor decides to reveal the truth to Assita about her husband (we don't see her face but the simple view of her bent back makes us suggest her sadness. The performance is also remarkable. Beginning with J&eacute;r&eacute;mie R&eacute;gnier who brings a lot of freshness to his character and the authors gave him the picture of a friendly boy. It is interesting to notice that he and "Rosetta" (1999) have a few common points. For example, they evolute in a tough environment. Moreover, Olivier Gourmet's awesome performance in the role of the father adds to the success of the film. "The promise" shows the Dardenne's brothers' talent who are the main leaders of Belgian cinema.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Belgian immigration problems
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    calculo
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/2/2003
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The brothers Dardenne understand how to tell a story without narration. The characters in this movie are strong enough to develop their own lines and short dialogues without commentary. There is no music or sound. The problem of this movie is apparent to "Baran (2001)" but in a different context and country. The style is near to "La Vie de J&eacute;sus (1997)" by Bruno Dumont and the hardness of life close to "Seul contre Tous (1998)" by Gaspar No&eacute;. Those last two movies have something more in common: they are situated in the old industrial country of the north of France and the south of Belgium. One could explore a stylistic nearness to Ken Loach but the narration goes deeper. It is the sole existence of mankind who is put into question. Father, why do we live? Igor (J&eacute;r&eacute;mie R&eacute;nier) seems to ask continuously to his father Roger (Olivier Gourmet). This film is a good attempt to make something as Belgian social realism without a parade or a revolution by the workers. They seem now to be more isolated (some exception: "Fermeture des usines Renault &agrave; Vilvoorde (1998))" and confined to villages with a non-existing working-class. The unemployed seem to have replaced the workers. A strange situation happens when Assita goes to a clairvoyant to know what happened with Amadou and the answer will be as cryptic as the situation wherein she is. Is the promise that Igor made (in fact it was his father) so important? The movie seems to suggest that a 14-year old boy could change the situation and ameliorate the fate of Assita. The real problem is that illegal immigration is a crime that has many consequences and at least it creates innumerable problems when something happens and it is a waste for the society and what more is, it puts the illegal workers into great danger because they come into the hands of people without conscience or humanity.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Moral choices, and lack thereof
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bandw
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Roger is perhaps one of the most immoral people you are likely to meet. He is running a business that uses illegal immigrants for his construction business. He manages a complete operation, from sneaking the people into Belgium, to employing and housing them. He pays the workers minimum wages and charges them for their housing. The immigrants are little more than slave labor--if their financial situation does not keep them in line, their fear of discovery by the authorities seals the deal. But that works two ways, since Roger is in constant fear that his operation will be uncovered by the authorities. The topic of illegal immigration is controversial in many western countries and this movie indicates that not only do illegals have a tough time on the job, but they are also not welcome among the general citizenry, as illustrated here by an illegal being urinated on and having her possessions trashed. But the plight of the immigrants is a subplot, since the focus is on Roger's son Igor who works for his dad. Initially Igor seems to be following in Roger's footsteps as we see him execute a scheme to steal a woman's money from her car in such a casual way that we think we know the path his life will take. The genius of the movie has Igor experience a sequence of events that make him question his moral values, or, more accurately, the lack of such. Ultimately Igor's maturing sense of morality causes him to act in ways that put him in serious conflict with his father. A lot of gray areas are explored. Roger does love Igor and at one point says that everything he does is for his son. If there is truth in that, then Roger adheres to the philosophy that the end justifies the means and he has allowed himself to be blinded to the humanity of his workers. Roger's behavior is a small scale version of attitudes that have been responsible for many of the world's biggest horrors. In showing Igor's struggle with moral questions the Dardenne brothers seem to be making a case that morality is in part genetic and must serve an evolutionary purpose--Igor's upbringing would argue against his turning on his father. In the final scene did Igor make the right decision in being so honest? Could he not have withheld the most brutal fact? The ending left me wanting to know what happened next. Filmed with muted colors, no musical score, a grim urban background, and little comic relief, this is not for those looking for light entertainment.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An intense story of trespassing and change
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Ilpo Hirvonen
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/4/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    After ten years of directing documentaries the Dardenne brothers directed their first fictional film, Falsch (1987). In 1992 they finished their second one, Je pense &agrave; vous (I Think About You) which they didn't think as a good film. After four years, came their first real "Dardenne-film" The Promise. It was the first film where they found their own unique style. The Promise is a story of a father son relationship, which they had already dealt with in Falsch. Roger (Olivier Gourmet), with his 15-year-old son Igor (J&eacute;r&eacute;mie Renier), drives across industrial Belgium to get illegal immigrants from a truck. They bring them back to a block of flats they live in and start charging them for money. One of the immigrants is Assita who has come to Belgium with her husband to find a better future for them and their baby. One day when immigrant-inspectors pay a visit events start to have radical consequences. The films by the Dardenne brothers usually focus on the moral choices the characters have to make and what are the consequences. In The Promise Igor has to decide, whether to obey his father or to do what's right and help Assita. Then we get to the question what is the right thing to do? And this is what Luc & Jean-Pierre Dardenne want to do: let us observe and think. Luc Dardenne has said that the basic idea of film-making is to reconstruct new humane experiences. The Promise makes one think about these moral dilemmas and social issues but also associate the events with one's own life. Geographically Belgium is in between of Germany and France - Belgium is only a country for trespassing. For instance a harsh example; Hitler in WWII. This is the main theme of The Promise - it is a story of trespassing. For Assita Belgium is a metaphor of a certain state in life, which she is just passing by. No one stays in Belgium (or in that state of life). As is Assita in between of two worlds; her home country and Belgium, so is Igor. Igor feels himself grown-up when he's collecting taxes for his father and driving around Belgium. But on the other hand he's full of juvenile joy as he drives with his friends on a go-kart. Igor was played by J&eacute;r&eacute;mie Renier (L 'Enfant, Lorna's Silence). It was his first role and through that he brought a realistic life to the character who tries to free himself from the chains of his father - the brothers have always appreciated the idea of using amateur actors. Igor's father, Roger was played by the Golden Palm-winner Olivier Gourmet, who is in my opinion a very talented actor. He gives a great life to Roger, whose world is worthless and merciless. The Dardenne brothers were raised in an industrial town in Belgium, which is the milieu in all of their films. The sound scape is something that one should pay attention to. There's no musical score at all only the voices the characters hear, the voices of an industrial town - ambiance. In the end the industrial voices just keep going on as the credits come on the screen. It's like we can't handle them anymore, they're spreading off the screen. A bit like in Chaplin's City Lights. The minimalist style of The Promise is amazing. It's touching on a new level. The brothers have totally succeed in their mission to create new humane experiences. Luc Dardenne writes in his 'diary' Behind Our Pictures, that the more you take material away the closer you get to the humane emotions, which he achieves through the severe aesthetics, minimalism and ruthless sound scape. Faces are in an important role, when describing humane emotions in The Promise the faces have also a dramaturgical role. I'm going to quote Luc Dardenne here, translated in English: "In every scene with Igor and Assita where they look to each other, Igor is always the first to turn his head away. Igor isn't able to meet Assita's eyes, because he senses a moral command that he cannot reply. Except in the final scene." And what a redemption it is in the end. The meaning of facial expressions and the philosophy behind it comes from a French philosopher Emmanuel L&eacute;vinas, who both of the brothers admire and from whom they get background for their philosophy of film. The Promise is thinking - philosophy of film. The brothers have stabilized film as an instrument for philosophy. I hope that the true film fanatics get to see this and appreciate it as much as I do. In addition to its themes of change, father-son relationship and trespassing, The Promise challenges the viewer to think on its own. The brothers force us to meet the moral choices out there.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A melodramatic masterpiece
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Zmajina
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/9/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Despite the criminal setting, the human trafficking and what have you, don't be fooled by phrases like "socially relevant". This is pure melodrama. In fact, any soap opera writer would proudly exploit the plot elements of the film. But what makes it a masterpiece is the absolutely flawless direction. There is not a single scene that is superfluous. Blink and you'll miss an important link in the story. Behind the apparent simplicity of each scene there is a lot of careful planning. The feelings and actions of the characters are skilfully pointed out for exactly as long as it takes to understand them. The Dardenne brothers are helped by a cast that remains etched in your memory, but I doubt any of the actors would shine this much in a less carefully directed film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Low-key coming of age drama from the brothers Dardenne
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Graham Greene
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/4/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Brothers Jean-Pierre and Luc Dardenne concern themselves with creating films that put realism on the screen without using artifice or cinematic trickery to distract the audience from the socially aware message at the core of their narratives. Unlike the similarly themed dogme movement, or the more iconic works of Lars von Trier etc, the Dardenne brothers are unconcerned with changing the face of cinematic reality, but rather, take their cue from people like Ken Loach, Bruno Dumont and Robert Bresson; by creating honest, often-bleak works of film that take their character from despair, to hope, and sometimes, right back to despair, in order to give the audience a taste of a world away from the more comfortable social milieu we might be accustomed to. The concept could be read as hypocritical admittedly, and although the occasional heavy-handed quality of the brother's work does intermittently become preachy, there is ample opportunity to deliver some moments of earth-shattering drama. I first encountered the Dardenne's work back in 2001, when British film channel Film Four premiered their film The Promise (1996) in preparation for the premier of their highly acclaimed follow up film Rosetta (1999). Both films are here are heavily indebted to the naturalistic/realist work of Bresson and Loach, particularly films like Diary of a Country Priest (1951), Riff Raff (1990) and Raining Stones (1993); with the filmmakers presenting the viewer with a series of characters continually forced to the brink of despair, but desperate to pull themselves back. For me, out of the two films of theirs that I have thus far seen, The Promise is the one that makes the greatest impact. Here, The Dardenne's create a world that isn't a million miles away from the current social climate in the UK, with building sites, smoky pubs and migrant workers peppering what is essentially the typical rites-of-passage/coming of age movie so familiar even by Hollywood standards. The brothers rest their narrative firmly on the shoulders of young newcomer J&eacute;r&eacute;mie R&eacute;nier as Igor, a teenage tearaway forced into looking after a young black mother and her baby following the death of the woman's husband whilst working for the company run by Igor's father. The brothers season their film with an abundance of topical, moralistic issues such as the passage into adulthood, immigration and domestic abuse, but at the centre of the drama there is still room for hope in the touching father son relationship between Igor and his disparate dad (played here by award winning actor and regular Dardenne collaborator Olivier Gourmet). The Promise might not be a ground-breaking film; its ideas are well worn and its scenarios familiar from the classic kitchen-sink cinema of films like Saturday Night and Sunday Morning (1960) and A Taste of Honey (1961) to name only two, but the process of refinement that the brothers are able to create with the subtle shading of characters and the no-nonsense approach to film-making is really quite affecting on the most personal and emotional of levels.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    sincere and moving
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    dromasca
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/4/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    More than ten years after its release this film by the Dardenne brothers still looks fresh and actual. This is the story of a father and son who are involved in smuggling and hosting illegal immigrants in the European Community. When one of the immigrants dies in the accident the father imposes a cover-up. The boy cannot live quietly with this deed and slowly gets closer to the widow and her baby, filling in the promise to care for them that he had made to the dying immigrant, and redeeming himself and his humanity in the process. The quality and emotion of the film lie in the direct, almost documentary approach taken by the directors in telling the story, the realistic setting and especially in the splendid acting. Both Olivier Gourmet as the father and Jeremier Renier as the son give excellent performances, they are real, moving, caring for every detail. The two make this simple film a film to remember.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Another Dardenne Brothers Masterpiece
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    omalley-brendan
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/6/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The performance of J&eacute;r&eacute;mie Renier is memorable. (He's also great in L'infant). The Dardennes are obviously influenced by Robert Bresson and have a similar interest in use of realistic sound, and observation of everyday tasks. They especially like workshops, and woodworking tools. Like Bresson, they eschew incidental music and produce a very naturalistic view of events. And they do it so well. This film will remain in your conscience for a long time after you have seen it, and should satisfy those who need a resolution and a conclusion in their movies, by offering at least an answer to one "will he - won't he?" dilemma. These guys are making some of the best cinema of the present era.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    very gritty and odd little film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    planktonrules
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/12/2005
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I liked this film because it dared to be different. It was about as far from a "Hollywood-style" film as you can get! The story involves some pretty nasty characters. In particular, a teenage boy and his father. They make money by exploiting illegal immigrants in France--picking up the poor people and housing them in a tenement--all as exorbitant rates. This pair appear to be people without souls as they lie and cheat again and again. However, when one of these illegals accidentally dies, the paths of the two diverge. Dad just wants to dump the body and could care less about the man's widow and young child (wanting to sell her into a life of prostitution), while the boy who witnessed the final words of the dying man promised to look after the family. What, exactly, happened next I'll leave for the viewer. Provided you have a tolerance for movies about realistically seedy people, this is a film worth seeing. An interesting twist, not taken in the film, would have been if later the boy had found out that his father was not really his biological dad--but the "dad" raised him from infancy after his own real family died while being smuggled into France by him. This could be an interesting path.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Promise Kept
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    writers_reign
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/11/2004
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is available with Rosetta on one DVD and it's a welcome change to discover a double DVD where both films are equal in quality. I'm not usually a fan of the 'hand-held' camera school of film making but in the case of Rosetta and this film I am happy to make an exception. It may well be noted that the freres Dardennes tend to load the dice in their own favor but there are times when a case can be made for playing with a stacked deck and this is one of them. Not too much happens. We meet Igor (Jeremie Regnier) and his father Roger (Olivier Gourmet) almost from Frame #1. Teenage Igor, pumping gas is not above stealing a purse from an elderly lady and if we find this a tad amoral it is as nothing compared to his old man who has a nice line in illegal immigrants, demanding their passports - or rather delegating Igor to collect them - in return for a few square meters of squalor and a fifty-fifty chance of deportation if and when they prove unable and/or unwilling to pay the extortionate 'rent'. The first and literal promise is the one made by Igor to the African who has fallen from a ladder whilst renovating the clapped-out house owned by Roger and is subsequently finished off by Roger lest his injuries prove an embarrassment. The injured man charges Igor with being responsible for the welfare of his wife and child and Igor, being still impressionable, takes this seriously, so much so, that he severs relations with his father thus bringing into play the secondary meaning of the title, the promise shown by Igor of getting under the wire as a human being. Excellent acting all round, complete lack of background music and a plot that ultimate involves make for a highly satisfying movie. 8/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A promise (Echo and the Bunnymen)
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    dbdumonteil
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/4/2004
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Spoilers, spoilers, spoilers... In the nineties, Belgium gave us two or rather three great directors: Jaco Van Dormael (the terrific "Toto the hero" 1991) and the Dardenne brothers. But the cinema of the latter is more realist and matter-of-fact. Furthermore, it evokes Ken Loach's with a difference: if Ken Loach presents the pains of Western society by introducing humor, it isn't the same thing with the Dardenne brothers where humor is absent. For "the promise", the Dardenne brothers opted for neutrality and sobriety: short and quick dialogs, a film that essentially relies on the characters' gestures and countenances, no music, a vivid and rough directing that often shows the actors with back turned and especially a will to show a bleak social reality (the migrant workers' exploitation) and for this the movie almost takes a documentary aspect. The authors don't pass judgment, they don't feel pity. They just take a gritty and harsh look on these emigrants who live in dilapidated flats with a starvation wage. Besides, we can take down a significant detail: their hard living conditions echoes to a gray sky and it gives to the film a dull atmosphere. An important point of the film is the relationship between Igor and his father. The beginning of the film presents a relationship between a father and his son that we could describe as complicity. At this moment, the movie becomes tinged with tenderness. But throughout the movie, this complicity gradually turns into an open opposition and the consequences of Igor's promise open his eyes on his fathers' cruelty. "The promise" is also a movie that includes powerful moments because the suggested has the edge on the showed: Hammidou's mortal accident, the very last sequence of the movie when Igor decides to reveal the truth to Assita about her husband (we don't see her face but the simple view of her bent back makes us suggest her sadness. The performance is also remarkable. Beginning with J&eacute;r&eacute;mie R&eacute;gnier who brings a lot of freshness to his character and the authors gave him the picture of a friendly boy. It is interesting to notice that he and "Rosetta" (1999) have a few common points. For example, they evolute in a tough environment. Moreover, Olivier Gourmet's awesome performance in the role of the father adds to the success of the film. "The promise" shows the Dardenne's brothers' talent who are the main leaders of Belgian cinema.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Belgian immigration problems
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    calculo
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/2/2003
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The brothers Dardenne understand how to tell a story without narration. The characters in this movie are strong enough to develop their own lines and short dialogues without commentary. There is no music or sound. The problem of this movie is apparent to "Baran (2001)" but in a different context and country. The style is near to "La Vie de J&eacute;sus (1997)" by Bruno Dumont and the hardness of life close to "Seul contre Tous (1998)" by Gaspar No&eacute;. Those last two movies have something more in common: they are situated in the old industrial country of the north of France and the south of Belgium. One could explore a stylistic nearness to Ken Loach but the narration goes deeper. It is the sole existence of mankind who is put into question. Father, why do we live? Igor (J&eacute;r&eacute;mie R&eacute;nier) seems to ask continuously to his father Roger (Olivier Gourmet). This film is a good attempt to make something as Belgian social realism without a parade or a revolution by the workers. They seem now to be more isolated (some exception: "Fermeture des usines Renault &agrave; Vilvoorde (1998))" and confined to villages with a non-existing working-class. The unemployed seem to have replaced the workers. A strange situation happens when Assita goes to a clairvoyant to know what happened with Amadou and the answer will be as cryptic as the situation wherein she is. Is the promise that Igor made (in fact it was his father) so important? The movie seems to suggest that a 14-year old boy could change the situation and ameliorate the fate of Assita. The real problem is that illegal immigration is a crime that has many consequences and at least it creates innumerable problems when something happens and it is a waste for the society and what more is, it puts the illegal workers into great danger because they come into the hands of people without conscience or humanity.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
 </reviews>
</filme>
