<filme>
 <id>
  3
 </id>
 <imdburl>
  http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0113101
 </imdburl>
 <ano>
  1995
 </ano>
 <titulo>
  Grand Hotel
 </titulo>
 <rating>
  6.5
 </rating>
 <sinopse>
  Four interlocking tales that take place in a fading hotel on New Year's Eve.
 </sinopse>
 <storyline>
  This movie features the collaborative directorial efforts of four new filmmakers, each of whom directs a segment of this comedy. It's New Year's Eve at the Mon Signor Hotel, a former grand old Hollywood hotel, now fallen upon hard times. Often using physical comedy and sight gags, this movie chronicles the slapstick misadventures of Ted, the Bellhop. He's on his first night on the job, when he's asked to help out a coven of witches in the Honeymoon Suite. Things only get worse when he delivers ice to the wrong room and ends up in a domestic argument at a really bad time. Next, he foolishly agrees to watch a gangster's kids for him while he's away. Finally, he finishes off the night refereeing a ghastly wager.
 </storyline>
 <generos>
  <genero>
   Comedy
  </genero>
 </generos>
 <keywords>
  <keyword>
   hotel
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   new year's eve
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   bellhop
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   coven
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   gangster
  </keyword>
 </keywords>
 <diretores>
  <diretor>
   Allison Anders
  </diretor>
  <diretor>
   Alexandre Rockwell
  </diretor>
 </diretores>
 <escritores>
  <escritor>
   Allison Anders
  </escritor>
  <escritor>
   Alexandre Rockwell
  </escritor>
 </escritores>
 <atores>
  <ator>
   Tim Roth
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Amanda De Cadenet
  </ator>
  <ator>
   David Proval
  </ator>
 </atores>
 <reviews>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Unbelievably vacuous
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    David Frenkiel
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I registered to this site especially to warn the world: don't waste your time on this movie. It seems to be the result of overconfident Hollywood producers who figured that some critical mass of props, make up, "atmosphere", homages and mannerisms can create a masterpiece. Or at least a watchable feature film. The result is a collection of four pointless sequences (definitely not "stories"), only the third of which is mildly entertaining. I know that almost 20 years after its production, very few people will come across this movie. However, if my review can deter even one human from throwing away 90 minutes of his/her life, it's worth the effort. Oh, and in case you're a fan of the "colossal failure" genre - this thing is not colossal in any sense. It doesn't even deserve sarcasm. Just ignore it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Probably worth it for the Rodriguez and Tarantino segments
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    zetes
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    When I was in high school, anything Tarantino-related was required to be memorized. Yes, even this one was insisted upon in high school, though perhaps not as strongly as QT's first two. This portmanteau follows bellhop Tim Roth as he gets into several adventures over New Year's Eve. I remember liking this one quite a bit, but, viewing it now, it's just too uneven to be worthwhile. Anders' first segment is easily the low point, thankfully. Any film starring Madonna should be immediately suspect, and everything about this tale of witches is awful. Rockwell's segment is a bit of an improvement, but too forgettable. Rodriguez's segment is the one I remember being the best, and it thankfully does hold up okay. Antonio Banderas is hilarious in it, and most of the jokes hit. I remember QT's segment being the worst originally, but I actually thought it was by far the best this time around. It usually gets flack, I think, because it stars Tarantino, but he's comfortable here playing a pompous movie director. It's honestly his best performance (if it had been readily available, I might have suffered through Destiny Turns on the Radio again) and his direction is pretty brilliant. The one thing that really drags this whole movie down is Tim Roth. Man, I remember loving him when I was a teenager, and, though I criticized his performance in Reservoir Dogs above, he's on Olivier's level there compared to his awful mugging here. Even if QT's segment were the weakest, it would automatically be upgraded to the strongest just because he's the only one who settles Roth the crap down, a bit at least.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Loved it!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    niklas_austrheim
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie is a fantastic piece of work - I love the way four writers/directors have cooperated here. I will say though, that it starts with a let down. It increases in quality throughout the entire film, and the last segment, "The Man From Hollywood" is brilliant! Quentin Tarantino brings his characters to life unlike any other director, with his long shots and genius dialogue. The third segment, "The Misbehavers", is funny in another way, it holds a lot of the childish humor we can recognize from "Desperado" and the "Spy Kids"-franchise. The second installment is a very well-written piece of work, but gets overshadowed by what is yet to come. Tim Roth's performance is phenomenal, he dares to bring his acting to the very limit of what could be called "over-acting", but doesn't cross the line entirely, and it brings the movie a very eccentric energy. All together a very good film, and I would recommend all of you to watch it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Peculiar and sophisticated, but uneven coherence
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Bene Cumb
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    One should clearly admit that Rodriguez and Tarantino are better directors and screenwriters than the other two, episodes No 3 and 4 are much more "ripe" and interesting. No 3 by Rodriguez is probably the most stylish, Tarantino, on the other hand, is the master of intense, funny and smutty dialogs. Most of male performances are excellent, especially Roth and Banderas, Willis and Tarantino are outstanding as well. Unlike other similar films, female parts are quite dull and mediocre, the cast in the episode No 1 is rather poor. Awkward characters and witty scenes are still worth watching (total length less than 1,5 hours), although Four Rooms is not among the best films where Rodriguez and Tarantino have participated.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Decent Anthology
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    billcr12
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/7/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Four Rooms is an anthology by different directors, taking place on New Year's Eve at a hotel. The Missing Ingredient is the first one by Allison Anders. Ted, a bellhop, helps a group of strange women to the honeymoon suite, where they have a large cauldron in the middle of the room in order to brew a potion to summon a goddess. They each add something to the mix, until the last witch needs to find semen within an hour to complete the potion. She works on Ted for a donation. I liked this one and give it 8/10. The Wrong Man by Alexandre Rockwell places Ted in an awkward situation in the middle of a fight between a husband and wife. Ted is accused of a sexual encounter with the lady by her husband and after Ted escapes, another guest goes through the same insanity. So so, and a 5/10. The Misbehavers by Robert Rodriguez puts Ted in the position of babysitter for two little brats. Antonio Banderas and his wife leave their boy and girl in the room and pay Ted $500 to make sure that the children behave. The bellhop places them in front of a television, and when he returns, the girl has a bottle of champagne in her hand, the boy is smoking a cigarette, and the TV is on an adult channel. Rodriguez must have had some bad experiences with children to come up with this one. It is funny and a 7.5/10. The last and not least is by my favorite director, Quentin Tarantino, who plays a movie director(talk about typecasting) who is gathered with others who enjoy a good bet. The wager involves a guy being able to light a Zippo lighter ten times in a row. If he succeeds, he wins a car; if not, his pinky will be chopped off with an extremely sharp hatchet. Ted is drafted to be the executioner with the promise of $1,000. Though a quicky by Tarantino standards, it contains the expected darkness of the diabolical genius. An 8.5/10. The combined score is a 7.5 and a decent assembly of talent.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Interesting Concept That Bathes in a Sea of Cheese
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Sean Lamberger
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/5/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Tim Roth stars as a twitchy, maligned bellhop in this wacky anthology of four loosely-linked short films. With a different director behind the wheel for each chapter, it shouldn't come as much surprise to hear this is an uneven tale that never settles on a firm identity for itself. The underlying theme is light slapstick suspense with a vibrant collection of supporting players, but each act also has its share of dark secrets and sinister overtones. The first two portions are colorful, but too thin for my taste. It seems like both had a solid beginning and ending in mind, and only set about painting by numbers to bring the two together. It's Robert Rodriguez's third act and Quentin Tarantino's closer, though, that drew me to the show anyway. Both serve as bite-sized capsules of both the best and worst traits and habits that have come to define each director. Rodriguez's arc, which naturally features both Antonio Banderas and Salma Hayeck (albeit in short cameos) is a middle ground of sorts between Spy Kids and Planet Terror. It's part kid-focused mayhem and part pulpy, black, gross-out trauma; an enthusiastic, if shallow, ride. Tarantino's adventurous final chapter is more dialog driven, with the director (of course) playing the leading role. Like a caricature of himself, he spends a good ninety percent of the scene spewing pop culture references and jazzy one-liners before the whole drama culminates in a jolting, blunt burst of adrenaline. Overall, Four Rooms is a mixed bag, and apart from the Tarantino chapter, none of the acts stand up particularly well. While fans of the director will no doubt love Quentin's arc, it's short enough that it would probably be just as easily - and effectively - viewed on YouTube or Vimeo.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    ever building humor
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Patrick Mulligan
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/3/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Four Rooms is a slap stick four part tale of a Bell hop (Tim Roth) who encounters witches, crazed couples, trouble making kids, and drunken movie makers on new years eve at a once great Hollywood hotel. The brand of humor usually isn't up my alley, being very physical and less dialogue driven. But this movie still had me cracking me up. Each room is brought to you by way of a different director. Going in order you have Allison Anders, Alexandre Rockwell, Robert Rodriguez, and Quentin Tarantino. For me each segment was better than the last, Tarantino's being my favorite. I enjoyed watching the style change from scene to scene. I am not familiar with the work of the first two directors so there influence was less obvious to me than that of Rodriguez and Tarantino. Maybe that's why I enjoyed there scenes the most, but everyone is a little biased. Everything from writing to camera work shifts with the changing of directors. That is probably my favorite thing about Four Rooms. It's interesting to see Ted the bell hop interact with the different worlds painted for him by the directors. Even if your not into physical humor, you can get a certain amount of enjoyment just watching the camera change hands. But if you like feminist witches, marital problems refereed by revolvers, dead hookers, and wagers worth a little finger and a slick ride, this is a movie for you.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Terrible First Half, With a Pretty Good Second Half
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    DoctorKingSchultz
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I'll admit, I do have a bias towards Tarantino. I love the guy's stuff. Not a single one of his films do I dislike in the slightest. However, he has dabbled in some side projects that don't carry the full "Written and Directed by..." promise of, say Pulp Fiction or Kill Bill, that aren't the biggest successes. But for a single segment of the four that make up Four Rooms, we have Tarantino behind the pen, the camera, and in front of the screen! It's no coincidence that his segment is actually entertaining. But I'm ahead of myself. Let me review this piece by piece. The Missing Ingredient is both the opening chapter and the worst chapter. It's terrible. A group of witches (Real witches, apparently.) are trying to reincarnate their goddess, but require several specific items, the only of which they don't have is a man's sperm. I'm not joking. So, the witch who hasn't fulfilled her part must acquire her item within the hour. It sounds like the plot of a pornographic film. It's just stupid. The witch seduces Tim Roth's Ted the Bellhop, and some silly special effects later, she has her final item. I can't tell you how much I hated this. Not once during this chapter did I crack a smile, I was just hoping the next part was better. It is, but not substantially so. The Wrong Man is the second chapter. A little more interesting and far less ridiculous, Ted the Bellhop finds himself staring down the barrel of a revolver when he accidentally enters the wrong room when responding to a call. The chaos that comes from a mistaken identity ensues, and Ted is put between a man with a gun and his gagged wife. What I found to be one of the best quotes from the movie comes up here. Something about wearing a bonnet, I can't recall it right now. Though, I felt the situation was a little hard to follow here. Maybe I wasn't really paying attention, maybe it was supposed to be convoluted. Maybe it was because Tim Roth is delivering his lines in an angry whisper the entire time.Seriously, I like Timothy Roth, he's had some great roles in some great films, but god he chose the wrong role here. Ted the Bellhop is a flamboyant, fast-talking wreck. I couldn't understand him sometimes. Maybe that's what made the movie "funny" but I found it annoying. It was like watching the protagonist of a kid's movie trying to get laughs from children by acting silly, but surrounded by swearing and adult themes. With the third chapter, thing get better. Perhaps it's because it focuses less on Roth's silly character. The Misbehavers is directed and written by Robert Rodriguez. In this fun little short, a tough husband and his wife leave their children in their hotel room for the evening, hiring Ted to check up on them now and then. "Don't misbehave" he warns. The two kids are portrayed in a funny, childish way and their innocence leads to a gruesome discovery that I won't spoil here; it's one of the few parts worth not spoiling. Rodriguez really gives us this picture of a dysfunctional family headed by a strict father-figure (Who MAY or may not be a gangster!) And this chapter ends with a great scene. The moment I'm sure many had been waiting for was Quentin Tarantino's segment: The Man from Hollywood. QT stars in this segment as a drunk, rich movie star. He and his posse are drinking, having a good time. The alcohol in their system leads to them recreating a scene from a Hitchcock story where one of the men must light his lighter ten times in a row, or have his pinkie chopped off. It's really well played out here as the drunk trio of friends (And a character from a previous chapter.) move about their suite, throwing their money around like it's nothing. If you like Tarantino's writing, you'll like this segment. If not, you won't! It's classic Tarantino. Again, Roth is sort of put in the background, behind this intoxicated cast of characters. I think Roth was the problem with the movie, possibly. Or rather, Roth's character. So there. It's an interesting concept that, with four skilled directors, could have been phenomenal. But alas, the filmmakers who directed the first two chapters are unknown for a reason. I think I'd have to say Rodriguez's segment was the best. So, I give this a 6/10. Really, the second chapters are fun little shorts, and even the second one isn't all that bad. But the opening part is so unforgivable. It sets such a negative tone for the rest of the movie. And since these segments are all part of one film, they must be given a rating as one.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of the funniest movies ever!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Dylan Greenberg
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/7/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I saw this movie at 10, and loved it! Yesterday, I saw the movie again, and it was even funnier! Tim Roth was hysterically cartoonish in his movements, hand gestures, and facial expressions. He really stole the show. The Misbehavers was my favorite section of the four that make up the film. I also like the Easter Egg of the TV playing Bedhead in the background during that scene. As the movie progresses further, it gets funnier and funnier. In the beginning, it was like "meh", but at the end, I was in tears of laughter! If you have Netflix, stop reading this review, and watch it immediately. It's on instant play. I highly, HIGHLY recommend it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A complete waste of film!!!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    2fresh 2clean
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/7/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie was horrible. It was the worst movie I have seen since How High. Quentin has definitely redeemed himself since he made this movie. It was amazing to see such big named actors such as Bruce Willis and Antonio Banderas in this movie. The only reason I can see why they decided to play in this film was to give a fresh starting Quentin Tarantino a chance. This movie stunk so bad I can still smell it even after I returned it to the video store. This movie just didn't do anything. It was boring and flat from start to finish. Please do not rent this movie. Spend your money on some gum or a coke. You'll definitely be spending your money on something more meaningful.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Unbelievably vacuous
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    David Frenkiel
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I registered to this site especially to warn the world: don't waste your time on this movie. It seems to be the result of overconfident Hollywood producers who figured that some critical mass of props, make up, "atmosphere", homages and mannerisms can create a masterpiece. Or at least a watchable feature film. The result is a collection of four pointless sequences (definitely not "stories"), only the third of which is mildly entertaining. I know that almost 20 years after its production, very few people will come across this movie. However, if my review can deter even one human from throwing away 90 minutes of his/her life, it's worth the effort. Oh, and in case you're a fan of the "colossal failure" genre - this thing is not colossal in any sense. It doesn't even deserve sarcasm. Just ignore it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Probably worth it for the Rodriguez and Tarantino segments
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    zetes
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    When I was in high school, anything Tarantino-related was required to be memorized. Yes, even this one was insisted upon in high school, though perhaps not as strongly as QT's first two. This portmanteau follows bellhop Tim Roth as he gets into several adventures over New Year's Eve. I remember liking this one quite a bit, but, viewing it now, it's just too uneven to be worthwhile. Anders' first segment is easily the low point, thankfully. Any film starring Madonna should be immediately suspect, and everything about this tale of witches is awful. Rockwell's segment is a bit of an improvement, but too forgettable. Rodriguez's segment is the one I remember being the best, and it thankfully does hold up okay. Antonio Banderas is hilarious in it, and most of the jokes hit. I remember QT's segment being the worst originally, but I actually thought it was by far the best this time around. It usually gets flack, I think, because it stars Tarantino, but he's comfortable here playing a pompous movie director. It's honestly his best performance (if it had been readily available, I might have suffered through Destiny Turns on the Radio again) and his direction is pretty brilliant. The one thing that really drags this whole movie down is Tim Roth. Man, I remember loving him when I was a teenager, and, though I criticized his performance in Reservoir Dogs above, he's on Olivier's level there compared to his awful mugging here. Even if QT's segment were the weakest, it would automatically be upgraded to the strongest just because he's the only one who settles Roth the crap down, a bit at least.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Loved it!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    niklas_austrheim
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie is a fantastic piece of work - I love the way four writers/directors have cooperated here. I will say though, that it starts with a let down. It increases in quality throughout the entire film, and the last segment, "The Man From Hollywood" is brilliant! Quentin Tarantino brings his characters to life unlike any other director, with his long shots and genius dialogue. The third segment, "The Misbehavers", is funny in another way, it holds a lot of the childish humor we can recognize from "Desperado" and the "Spy Kids"-franchise. The second installment is a very well-written piece of work, but gets overshadowed by what is yet to come. Tim Roth's performance is phenomenal, he dares to bring his acting to the very limit of what could be called "over-acting", but doesn't cross the line entirely, and it brings the movie a very eccentric energy. All together a very good film, and I would recommend all of you to watch it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Peculiar and sophisticated, but uneven coherence
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Bene Cumb
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    One should clearly admit that Rodriguez and Tarantino are better directors and screenwriters than the other two, episodes No 3 and 4 are much more "ripe" and interesting. No 3 by Rodriguez is probably the most stylish, Tarantino, on the other hand, is the master of intense, funny and smutty dialogs. Most of male performances are excellent, especially Roth and Banderas, Willis and Tarantino are outstanding as well. Unlike other similar films, female parts are quite dull and mediocre, the cast in the episode No 1 is rather poor. Awkward characters and witty scenes are still worth watching (total length less than 1,5 hours), although Four Rooms is not among the best films where Rodriguez and Tarantino have participated.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Decent Anthology
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    billcr12
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/7/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Four Rooms is an anthology by different directors, taking place on New Year's Eve at a hotel. The Missing Ingredient is the first one by Allison Anders. Ted, a bellhop, helps a group of strange women to the honeymoon suite, where they have a large cauldron in the middle of the room in order to brew a potion to summon a goddess. They each add something to the mix, until the last witch needs to find semen within an hour to complete the potion. She works on Ted for a donation. I liked this one and give it 8/10. The Wrong Man by Alexandre Rockwell places Ted in an awkward situation in the middle of a fight between a husband and wife. Ted is accused of a sexual encounter with the lady by her husband and after Ted escapes, another guest goes through the same insanity. So so, and a 5/10. The Misbehavers by Robert Rodriguez puts Ted in the position of babysitter for two little brats. Antonio Banderas and his wife leave their boy and girl in the room and pay Ted $500 to make sure that the children behave. The bellhop places them in front of a television, and when he returns, the girl has a bottle of champagne in her hand, the boy is smoking a cigarette, and the TV is on an adult channel. Rodriguez must have had some bad experiences with children to come up with this one. It is funny and a 7.5/10. The last and not least is by my favorite director, Quentin Tarantino, who plays a movie director(talk about typecasting) who is gathered with others who enjoy a good bet. The wager involves a guy being able to light a Zippo lighter ten times in a row. If he succeeds, he wins a car; if not, his pinky will be chopped off with an extremely sharp hatchet. Ted is drafted to be the executioner with the promise of $1,000. Though a quicky by Tarantino standards, it contains the expected darkness of the diabolical genius. An 8.5/10. The combined score is a 7.5 and a decent assembly of talent.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Interesting Concept That Bathes in a Sea of Cheese
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Sean Lamberger
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/5/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Tim Roth stars as a twitchy, maligned bellhop in this wacky anthology of four loosely-linked short films. With a different director behind the wheel for each chapter, it shouldn't come as much surprise to hear this is an uneven tale that never settles on a firm identity for itself. The underlying theme is light slapstick suspense with a vibrant collection of supporting players, but each act also has its share of dark secrets and sinister overtones. The first two portions are colorful, but too thin for my taste. It seems like both had a solid beginning and ending in mind, and only set about painting by numbers to bring the two together. It's Robert Rodriguez's third act and Quentin Tarantino's closer, though, that drew me to the show anyway. Both serve as bite-sized capsules of both the best and worst traits and habits that have come to define each director. Rodriguez's arc, which naturally features both Antonio Banderas and Salma Hayeck (albeit in short cameos) is a middle ground of sorts between Spy Kids and Planet Terror. It's part kid-focused mayhem and part pulpy, black, gross-out trauma; an enthusiastic, if shallow, ride. Tarantino's adventurous final chapter is more dialog driven, with the director (of course) playing the leading role. Like a caricature of himself, he spends a good ninety percent of the scene spewing pop culture references and jazzy one-liners before the whole drama culminates in a jolting, blunt burst of adrenaline. Overall, Four Rooms is a mixed bag, and apart from the Tarantino chapter, none of the acts stand up particularly well. While fans of the director will no doubt love Quentin's arc, it's short enough that it would probably be just as easily - and effectively - viewed on YouTube or Vimeo.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    ever building humor
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Patrick Mulligan
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/3/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Four Rooms is a slap stick four part tale of a Bell hop (Tim Roth) who encounters witches, crazed couples, trouble making kids, and drunken movie makers on new years eve at a once great Hollywood hotel. The brand of humor usually isn't up my alley, being very physical and less dialogue driven. But this movie still had me cracking me up. Each room is brought to you by way of a different director. Going in order you have Allison Anders, Alexandre Rockwell, Robert Rodriguez, and Quentin Tarantino. For me each segment was better than the last, Tarantino's being my favorite. I enjoyed watching the style change from scene to scene. I am not familiar with the work of the first two directors so there influence was less obvious to me than that of Rodriguez and Tarantino. Maybe that's why I enjoyed there scenes the most, but everyone is a little biased. Everything from writing to camera work shifts with the changing of directors. That is probably my favorite thing about Four Rooms. It's interesting to see Ted the bell hop interact with the different worlds painted for him by the directors. Even if your not into physical humor, you can get a certain amount of enjoyment just watching the camera change hands. But if you like feminist witches, marital problems refereed by revolvers, dead hookers, and wagers worth a little finger and a slick ride, this is a movie for you.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Terrible First Half, With a Pretty Good Second Half
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    DoctorKingSchultz
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I'll admit, I do have a bias towards Tarantino. I love the guy's stuff. Not a single one of his films do I dislike in the slightest. However, he has dabbled in some side projects that don't carry the full "Written and Directed by..." promise of, say Pulp Fiction or Kill Bill, that aren't the biggest successes. But for a single segment of the four that make up Four Rooms, we have Tarantino behind the pen, the camera, and in front of the screen! It's no coincidence that his segment is actually entertaining. But I'm ahead of myself. Let me review this piece by piece. The Missing Ingredient is both the opening chapter and the worst chapter. It's terrible. A group of witches (Real witches, apparently.) are trying to reincarnate their goddess, but require several specific items, the only of which they don't have is a man's sperm. I'm not joking. So, the witch who hasn't fulfilled her part must acquire her item within the hour. It sounds like the plot of a pornographic film. It's just stupid. The witch seduces Tim Roth's Ted the Bellhop, and some silly special effects later, she has her final item. I can't tell you how much I hated this. Not once during this chapter did I crack a smile, I was just hoping the next part was better. It is, but not substantially so. The Wrong Man is the second chapter. A little more interesting and far less ridiculous, Ted the Bellhop finds himself staring down the barrel of a revolver when he accidentally enters the wrong room when responding to a call. The chaos that comes from a mistaken identity ensues, and Ted is put between a man with a gun and his gagged wife. What I found to be one of the best quotes from the movie comes up here. Something about wearing a bonnet, I can't recall it right now. Though, I felt the situation was a little hard to follow here. Maybe I wasn't really paying attention, maybe it was supposed to be convoluted. Maybe it was because Tim Roth is delivering his lines in an angry whisper the entire time.Seriously, I like Timothy Roth, he's had some great roles in some great films, but god he chose the wrong role here. Ted the Bellhop is a flamboyant, fast-talking wreck. I couldn't understand him sometimes. Maybe that's what made the movie "funny" but I found it annoying. It was like watching the protagonist of a kid's movie trying to get laughs from children by acting silly, but surrounded by swearing and adult themes. With the third chapter, thing get better. Perhaps it's because it focuses less on Roth's silly character. The Misbehavers is directed and written by Robert Rodriguez. In this fun little short, a tough husband and his wife leave their children in their hotel room for the evening, hiring Ted to check up on them now and then. "Don't misbehave" he warns. The two kids are portrayed in a funny, childish way and their innocence leads to a gruesome discovery that I won't spoil here; it's one of the few parts worth not spoiling. Rodriguez really gives us this picture of a dysfunctional family headed by a strict father-figure (Who MAY or may not be a gangster!) And this chapter ends with a great scene. The moment I'm sure many had been waiting for was Quentin Tarantino's segment: The Man from Hollywood. QT stars in this segment as a drunk, rich movie star. He and his posse are drinking, having a good time. The alcohol in their system leads to them recreating a scene from a Hitchcock story where one of the men must light his lighter ten times in a row, or have his pinkie chopped off. It's really well played out here as the drunk trio of friends (And a character from a previous chapter.) move about their suite, throwing their money around like it's nothing. If you like Tarantino's writing, you'll like this segment. If not, you won't! It's classic Tarantino. Again, Roth is sort of put in the background, behind this intoxicated cast of characters. I think Roth was the problem with the movie, possibly. Or rather, Roth's character. So there. It's an interesting concept that, with four skilled directors, could have been phenomenal. But alas, the filmmakers who directed the first two chapters are unknown for a reason. I think I'd have to say Rodriguez's segment was the best. So, I give this a 6/10. Really, the second chapters are fun little shorts, and even the second one isn't all that bad. But the opening part is so unforgivable. It sets such a negative tone for the rest of the movie. And since these segments are all part of one film, they must be given a rating as one.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of the funniest movies ever!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Dylan Greenberg
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/7/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I saw this movie at 10, and loved it! Yesterday, I saw the movie again, and it was even funnier! Tim Roth was hysterically cartoonish in his movements, hand gestures, and facial expressions. He really stole the show. The Misbehavers was my favorite section of the four that make up the film. I also like the Easter Egg of the TV playing Bedhead in the background during that scene. As the movie progresses further, it gets funnier and funnier. In the beginning, it was like "meh", but at the end, I was in tears of laughter! If you have Netflix, stop reading this review, and watch it immediately. It's on instant play. I highly, HIGHLY recommend it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A complete waste of film!!!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    2fresh 2clean
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/7/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie was horrible. It was the worst movie I have seen since How High. Quentin has definitely redeemed himself since he made this movie. It was amazing to see such big named actors such as Bruce Willis and Antonio Banderas in this movie. The only reason I can see why they decided to play in this film was to give a fresh starting Quentin Tarantino a chance. This movie stunk so bad I can still smell it even after I returned it to the video store. This movie just didn't do anything. It was boring and flat from start to finish. Please do not rent this movie. Spend your money on some gum or a coke. You'll definitely be spending your money on something more meaningful.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Unbelievably vacuous
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    David Frenkiel
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I registered to this site especially to warn the world: don't waste your time on this movie. It seems to be the result of overconfident Hollywood producers who figured that some critical mass of props, make up, "atmosphere", homages and mannerisms can create a masterpiece. Or at least a watchable feature film. The result is a collection of four pointless sequences (definitely not "stories"), only the third of which is mildly entertaining. I know that almost 20 years after its production, very few people will come across this movie. However, if my review can deter even one human from throwing away 90 minutes of his/her life, it's worth the effort. Oh, and in case you're a fan of the "colossal failure" genre - this thing is not colossal in any sense. It doesn't even deserve sarcasm. Just ignore it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Probably worth it for the Rodriguez and Tarantino segments
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    zetes
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    When I was in high school, anything Tarantino-related was required to be memorized. Yes, even this one was insisted upon in high school, though perhaps not as strongly as QT's first two. This portmanteau follows bellhop Tim Roth as he gets into several adventures over New Year's Eve. I remember liking this one quite a bit, but, viewing it now, it's just too uneven to be worthwhile. Anders' first segment is easily the low point, thankfully. Any film starring Madonna should be immediately suspect, and everything about this tale of witches is awful. Rockwell's segment is a bit of an improvement, but too forgettable. Rodriguez's segment is the one I remember being the best, and it thankfully does hold up okay. Antonio Banderas is hilarious in it, and most of the jokes hit. I remember QT's segment being the worst originally, but I actually thought it was by far the best this time around. It usually gets flack, I think, because it stars Tarantino, but he's comfortable here playing a pompous movie director. It's honestly his best performance (if it had been readily available, I might have suffered through Destiny Turns on the Radio again) and his direction is pretty brilliant. The one thing that really drags this whole movie down is Tim Roth. Man, I remember loving him when I was a teenager, and, though I criticized his performance in Reservoir Dogs above, he's on Olivier's level there compared to his awful mugging here. Even if QT's segment were the weakest, it would automatically be upgraded to the strongest just because he's the only one who settles Roth the crap down, a bit at least.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Loved it!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    niklas_austrheim
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie is a fantastic piece of work - I love the way four writers/directors have cooperated here. I will say though, that it starts with a let down. It increases in quality throughout the entire film, and the last segment, "The Man From Hollywood" is brilliant! Quentin Tarantino brings his characters to life unlike any other director, with his long shots and genius dialogue. The third segment, "The Misbehavers", is funny in another way, it holds a lot of the childish humor we can recognize from "Desperado" and the "Spy Kids"-franchise. The second installment is a very well-written piece of work, but gets overshadowed by what is yet to come. Tim Roth's performance is phenomenal, he dares to bring his acting to the very limit of what could be called "over-acting", but doesn't cross the line entirely, and it brings the movie a very eccentric energy. All together a very good film, and I would recommend all of you to watch it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Peculiar and sophisticated, but uneven coherence
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Bene Cumb
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    One should clearly admit that Rodriguez and Tarantino are better directors and screenwriters than the other two, episodes No 3 and 4 are much more "ripe" and interesting. No 3 by Rodriguez is probably the most stylish, Tarantino, on the other hand, is the master of intense, funny and smutty dialogs. Most of male performances are excellent, especially Roth and Banderas, Willis and Tarantino are outstanding as well. Unlike other similar films, female parts are quite dull and mediocre, the cast in the episode No 1 is rather poor. Awkward characters and witty scenes are still worth watching (total length less than 1,5 hours), although Four Rooms is not among the best films where Rodriguez and Tarantino have participated.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Decent Anthology
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    billcr12
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/7/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Four Rooms is an anthology by different directors, taking place on New Year's Eve at a hotel. The Missing Ingredient is the first one by Allison Anders. Ted, a bellhop, helps a group of strange women to the honeymoon suite, where they have a large cauldron in the middle of the room in order to brew a potion to summon a goddess. They each add something to the mix, until the last witch needs to find semen within an hour to complete the potion. She works on Ted for a donation. I liked this one and give it 8/10. The Wrong Man by Alexandre Rockwell places Ted in an awkward situation in the middle of a fight between a husband and wife. Ted is accused of a sexual encounter with the lady by her husband and after Ted escapes, another guest goes through the same insanity. So so, and a 5/10. The Misbehavers by Robert Rodriguez puts Ted in the position of babysitter for two little brats. Antonio Banderas and his wife leave their boy and girl in the room and pay Ted $500 to make sure that the children behave. The bellhop places them in front of a television, and when he returns, the girl has a bottle of champagne in her hand, the boy is smoking a cigarette, and the TV is on an adult channel. Rodriguez must have had some bad experiences with children to come up with this one. It is funny and a 7.5/10. The last and not least is by my favorite director, Quentin Tarantino, who plays a movie director(talk about typecasting) who is gathered with others who enjoy a good bet. The wager involves a guy being able to light a Zippo lighter ten times in a row. If he succeeds, he wins a car; if not, his pinky will be chopped off with an extremely sharp hatchet. Ted is drafted to be the executioner with the promise of $1,000. Though a quicky by Tarantino standards, it contains the expected darkness of the diabolical genius. An 8.5/10. The combined score is a 7.5 and a decent assembly of talent.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Interesting Concept That Bathes in a Sea of Cheese
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Sean Lamberger
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/5/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Tim Roth stars as a twitchy, maligned bellhop in this wacky anthology of four loosely-linked short films. With a different director behind the wheel for each chapter, it shouldn't come as much surprise to hear this is an uneven tale that never settles on a firm identity for itself. The underlying theme is light slapstick suspense with a vibrant collection of supporting players, but each act also has its share of dark secrets and sinister overtones. The first two portions are colorful, but too thin for my taste. It seems like both had a solid beginning and ending in mind, and only set about painting by numbers to bring the two together. It's Robert Rodriguez's third act and Quentin Tarantino's closer, though, that drew me to the show anyway. Both serve as bite-sized capsules of both the best and worst traits and habits that have come to define each director. Rodriguez's arc, which naturally features both Antonio Banderas and Salma Hayeck (albeit in short cameos) is a middle ground of sorts between Spy Kids and Planet Terror. It's part kid-focused mayhem and part pulpy, black, gross-out trauma; an enthusiastic, if shallow, ride. Tarantino's adventurous final chapter is more dialog driven, with the director (of course) playing the leading role. Like a caricature of himself, he spends a good ninety percent of the scene spewing pop culture references and jazzy one-liners before the whole drama culminates in a jolting, blunt burst of adrenaline. Overall, Four Rooms is a mixed bag, and apart from the Tarantino chapter, none of the acts stand up particularly well. While fans of the director will no doubt love Quentin's arc, it's short enough that it would probably be just as easily - and effectively - viewed on YouTube or Vimeo.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    ever building humor
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Patrick Mulligan
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/3/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Four Rooms is a slap stick four part tale of a Bell hop (Tim Roth) who encounters witches, crazed couples, trouble making kids, and drunken movie makers on new years eve at a once great Hollywood hotel. The brand of humor usually isn't up my alley, being very physical and less dialogue driven. But this movie still had me cracking me up. Each room is brought to you by way of a different director. Going in order you have Allison Anders, Alexandre Rockwell, Robert Rodriguez, and Quentin Tarantino. For me each segment was better than the last, Tarantino's being my favorite. I enjoyed watching the style change from scene to scene. I am not familiar with the work of the first two directors so there influence was less obvious to me than that of Rodriguez and Tarantino. Maybe that's why I enjoyed there scenes the most, but everyone is a little biased. Everything from writing to camera work shifts with the changing of directors. That is probably my favorite thing about Four Rooms. It's interesting to see Ted the bell hop interact with the different worlds painted for him by the directors. Even if your not into physical humor, you can get a certain amount of enjoyment just watching the camera change hands. But if you like feminist witches, marital problems refereed by revolvers, dead hookers, and wagers worth a little finger and a slick ride, this is a movie for you.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Terrible First Half, With a Pretty Good Second Half
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    DoctorKingSchultz
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I'll admit, I do have a bias towards Tarantino. I love the guy's stuff. Not a single one of his films do I dislike in the slightest. However, he has dabbled in some side projects that don't carry the full "Written and Directed by..." promise of, say Pulp Fiction or Kill Bill, that aren't the biggest successes. But for a single segment of the four that make up Four Rooms, we have Tarantino behind the pen, the camera, and in front of the screen! It's no coincidence that his segment is actually entertaining. But I'm ahead of myself. Let me review this piece by piece. The Missing Ingredient is both the opening chapter and the worst chapter. It's terrible. A group of witches (Real witches, apparently.) are trying to reincarnate their goddess, but require several specific items, the only of which they don't have is a man's sperm. I'm not joking. So, the witch who hasn't fulfilled her part must acquire her item within the hour. It sounds like the plot of a pornographic film. It's just stupid. The witch seduces Tim Roth's Ted the Bellhop, and some silly special effects later, she has her final item. I can't tell you how much I hated this. Not once during this chapter did I crack a smile, I was just hoping the next part was better. It is, but not substantially so. The Wrong Man is the second chapter. A little more interesting and far less ridiculous, Ted the Bellhop finds himself staring down the barrel of a revolver when he accidentally enters the wrong room when responding to a call. The chaos that comes from a mistaken identity ensues, and Ted is put between a man with a gun and his gagged wife. What I found to be one of the best quotes from the movie comes up here. Something about wearing a bonnet, I can't recall it right now. Though, I felt the situation was a little hard to follow here. Maybe I wasn't really paying attention, maybe it was supposed to be convoluted. Maybe it was because Tim Roth is delivering his lines in an angry whisper the entire time.Seriously, I like Timothy Roth, he's had some great roles in some great films, but god he chose the wrong role here. Ted the Bellhop is a flamboyant, fast-talking wreck. I couldn't understand him sometimes. Maybe that's what made the movie "funny" but I found it annoying. It was like watching the protagonist of a kid's movie trying to get laughs from children by acting silly, but surrounded by swearing and adult themes. With the third chapter, thing get better. Perhaps it's because it focuses less on Roth's silly character. The Misbehavers is directed and written by Robert Rodriguez. In this fun little short, a tough husband and his wife leave their children in their hotel room for the evening, hiring Ted to check up on them now and then. "Don't misbehave" he warns. The two kids are portrayed in a funny, childish way and their innocence leads to a gruesome discovery that I won't spoil here; it's one of the few parts worth not spoiling. Rodriguez really gives us this picture of a dysfunctional family headed by a strict father-figure (Who MAY or may not be a gangster!) And this chapter ends with a great scene. The moment I'm sure many had been waiting for was Quentin Tarantino's segment: The Man from Hollywood. QT stars in this segment as a drunk, rich movie star. He and his posse are drinking, having a good time. The alcohol in their system leads to them recreating a scene from a Hitchcock story where one of the men must light his lighter ten times in a row, or have his pinkie chopped off. It's really well played out here as the drunk trio of friends (And a character from a previous chapter.) move about their suite, throwing their money around like it's nothing. If you like Tarantino's writing, you'll like this segment. If not, you won't! It's classic Tarantino. Again, Roth is sort of put in the background, behind this intoxicated cast of characters. I think Roth was the problem with the movie, possibly. Or rather, Roth's character. So there. It's an interesting concept that, with four skilled directors, could have been phenomenal. But alas, the filmmakers who directed the first two chapters are unknown for a reason. I think I'd have to say Rodriguez's segment was the best. So, I give this a 6/10. Really, the second chapters are fun little shorts, and even the second one isn't all that bad. But the opening part is so unforgivable. It sets such a negative tone for the rest of the movie. And since these segments are all part of one film, they must be given a rating as one.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of the funniest movies ever!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Dylan Greenberg
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/7/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I saw this movie at 10, and loved it! Yesterday, I saw the movie again, and it was even funnier! Tim Roth was hysterically cartoonish in his movements, hand gestures, and facial expressions. He really stole the show. The Misbehavers was my favorite section of the four that make up the film. I also like the Easter Egg of the TV playing Bedhead in the background during that scene. As the movie progresses further, it gets funnier and funnier. In the beginning, it was like "meh", but at the end, I was in tears of laughter! If you have Netflix, stop reading this review, and watch it immediately. It's on instant play. I highly, HIGHLY recommend it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A complete waste of film!!!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    2fresh 2clean
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/7/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie was horrible. It was the worst movie I have seen since How High. Quentin has definitely redeemed himself since he made this movie. It was amazing to see such big named actors such as Bruce Willis and Antonio Banderas in this movie. The only reason I can see why they decided to play in this film was to give a fresh starting Quentin Tarantino a chance. This movie stunk so bad I can still smell it even after I returned it to the video store. This movie just didn't do anything. It was boring and flat from start to finish. Please do not rent this movie. Spend your money on some gum or a coke. You'll definitely be spending your money on something more meaningful.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Unbelievably vacuous
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    David Frenkiel
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I registered to this site especially to warn the world: don't waste your time on this movie. It seems to be the result of overconfident Hollywood producers who figured that some critical mass of props, make up, "atmosphere", homages and mannerisms can create a masterpiece. Or at least a watchable feature film. The result is a collection of four pointless sequences (definitely not "stories"), only the third of which is mildly entertaining. I know that almost 20 years after its production, very few people will come across this movie. However, if my review can deter even one human from throwing away 90 minutes of his/her life, it's worth the effort. Oh, and in case you're a fan of the "colossal failure" genre - this thing is not colossal in any sense. It doesn't even deserve sarcasm. Just ignore it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Probably worth it for the Rodriguez and Tarantino segments
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    zetes
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    When I was in high school, anything Tarantino-related was required to be memorized. Yes, even this one was insisted upon in high school, though perhaps not as strongly as QT's first two. This portmanteau follows bellhop Tim Roth as he gets into several adventures over New Year's Eve. I remember liking this one quite a bit, but, viewing it now, it's just too uneven to be worthwhile. Anders' first segment is easily the low point, thankfully. Any film starring Madonna should be immediately suspect, and everything about this tale of witches is awful. Rockwell's segment is a bit of an improvement, but too forgettable. Rodriguez's segment is the one I remember being the best, and it thankfully does hold up okay. Antonio Banderas is hilarious in it, and most of the jokes hit. I remember QT's segment being the worst originally, but I actually thought it was by far the best this time around. It usually gets flack, I think, because it stars Tarantino, but he's comfortable here playing a pompous movie director. It's honestly his best performance (if it had been readily available, I might have suffered through Destiny Turns on the Radio again) and his direction is pretty brilliant. The one thing that really drags this whole movie down is Tim Roth. Man, I remember loving him when I was a teenager, and, though I criticized his performance in Reservoir Dogs above, he's on Olivier's level there compared to his awful mugging here. Even if QT's segment were the weakest, it would automatically be upgraded to the strongest just because he's the only one who settles Roth the crap down, a bit at least.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Loved it!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    niklas_austrheim
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie is a fantastic piece of work - I love the way four writers/directors have cooperated here. I will say though, that it starts with a let down. It increases in quality throughout the entire film, and the last segment, "The Man From Hollywood" is brilliant! Quentin Tarantino brings his characters to life unlike any other director, with his long shots and genius dialogue. The third segment, "The Misbehavers", is funny in another way, it holds a lot of the childish humor we can recognize from "Desperado" and the "Spy Kids"-franchise. The second installment is a very well-written piece of work, but gets overshadowed by what is yet to come. Tim Roth's performance is phenomenal, he dares to bring his acting to the very limit of what could be called "over-acting", but doesn't cross the line entirely, and it brings the movie a very eccentric energy. All together a very good film, and I would recommend all of you to watch it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Peculiar and sophisticated, but uneven coherence
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Bene Cumb
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    One should clearly admit that Rodriguez and Tarantino are better directors and screenwriters than the other two, episodes No 3 and 4 are much more "ripe" and interesting. No 3 by Rodriguez is probably the most stylish, Tarantino, on the other hand, is the master of intense, funny and smutty dialogs. Most of male performances are excellent, especially Roth and Banderas, Willis and Tarantino are outstanding as well. Unlike other similar films, female parts are quite dull and mediocre, the cast in the episode No 1 is rather poor. Awkward characters and witty scenes are still worth watching (total length less than 1,5 hours), although Four Rooms is not among the best films where Rodriguez and Tarantino have participated.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Decent Anthology
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    billcr12
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/7/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Four Rooms is an anthology by different directors, taking place on New Year's Eve at a hotel. The Missing Ingredient is the first one by Allison Anders. Ted, a bellhop, helps a group of strange women to the honeymoon suite, where they have a large cauldron in the middle of the room in order to brew a potion to summon a goddess. They each add something to the mix, until the last witch needs to find semen within an hour to complete the potion. She works on Ted for a donation. I liked this one and give it 8/10. The Wrong Man by Alexandre Rockwell places Ted in an awkward situation in the middle of a fight between a husband and wife. Ted is accused of a sexual encounter with the lady by her husband and after Ted escapes, another guest goes through the same insanity. So so, and a 5/10. The Misbehavers by Robert Rodriguez puts Ted in the position of babysitter for two little brats. Antonio Banderas and his wife leave their boy and girl in the room and pay Ted $500 to make sure that the children behave. The bellhop places them in front of a television, and when he returns, the girl has a bottle of champagne in her hand, the boy is smoking a cigarette, and the TV is on an adult channel. Rodriguez must have had some bad experiences with children to come up with this one. It is funny and a 7.5/10. The last and not least is by my favorite director, Quentin Tarantino, who plays a movie director(talk about typecasting) who is gathered with others who enjoy a good bet. The wager involves a guy being able to light a Zippo lighter ten times in a row. If he succeeds, he wins a car; if not, his pinky will be chopped off with an extremely sharp hatchet. Ted is drafted to be the executioner with the promise of $1,000. Though a quicky by Tarantino standards, it contains the expected darkness of the diabolical genius. An 8.5/10. The combined score is a 7.5 and a decent assembly of talent.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Interesting Concept That Bathes in a Sea of Cheese
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Sean Lamberger
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/5/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Tim Roth stars as a twitchy, maligned bellhop in this wacky anthology of four loosely-linked short films. With a different director behind the wheel for each chapter, it shouldn't come as much surprise to hear this is an uneven tale that never settles on a firm identity for itself. The underlying theme is light slapstick suspense with a vibrant collection of supporting players, but each act also has its share of dark secrets and sinister overtones. The first two portions are colorful, but too thin for my taste. It seems like both had a solid beginning and ending in mind, and only set about painting by numbers to bring the two together. It's Robert Rodriguez's third act and Quentin Tarantino's closer, though, that drew me to the show anyway. Both serve as bite-sized capsules of both the best and worst traits and habits that have come to define each director. Rodriguez's arc, which naturally features both Antonio Banderas and Salma Hayeck (albeit in short cameos) is a middle ground of sorts between Spy Kids and Planet Terror. It's part kid-focused mayhem and part pulpy, black, gross-out trauma; an enthusiastic, if shallow, ride. Tarantino's adventurous final chapter is more dialog driven, with the director (of course) playing the leading role. Like a caricature of himself, he spends a good ninety percent of the scene spewing pop culture references and jazzy one-liners before the whole drama culminates in a jolting, blunt burst of adrenaline. Overall, Four Rooms is a mixed bag, and apart from the Tarantino chapter, none of the acts stand up particularly well. While fans of the director will no doubt love Quentin's arc, it's short enough that it would probably be just as easily - and effectively - viewed on YouTube or Vimeo.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    ever building humor
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Patrick Mulligan
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/3/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Four Rooms is a slap stick four part tale of a Bell hop (Tim Roth) who encounters witches, crazed couples, trouble making kids, and drunken movie makers on new years eve at a once great Hollywood hotel. The brand of humor usually isn't up my alley, being very physical and less dialogue driven. But this movie still had me cracking me up. Each room is brought to you by way of a different director. Going in order you have Allison Anders, Alexandre Rockwell, Robert Rodriguez, and Quentin Tarantino. For me each segment was better than the last, Tarantino's being my favorite. I enjoyed watching the style change from scene to scene. I am not familiar with the work of the first two directors so there influence was less obvious to me than that of Rodriguez and Tarantino. Maybe that's why I enjoyed there scenes the most, but everyone is a little biased. Everything from writing to camera work shifts with the changing of directors. That is probably my favorite thing about Four Rooms. It's interesting to see Ted the bell hop interact with the different worlds painted for him by the directors. Even if your not into physical humor, you can get a certain amount of enjoyment just watching the camera change hands. But if you like feminist witches, marital problems refereed by revolvers, dead hookers, and wagers worth a little finger and a slick ride, this is a movie for you.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Terrible First Half, With a Pretty Good Second Half
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    DoctorKingSchultz
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I'll admit, I do have a bias towards Tarantino. I love the guy's stuff. Not a single one of his films do I dislike in the slightest. However, he has dabbled in some side projects that don't carry the full "Written and Directed by..." promise of, say Pulp Fiction or Kill Bill, that aren't the biggest successes. But for a single segment of the four that make up Four Rooms, we have Tarantino behind the pen, the camera, and in front of the screen! It's no coincidence that his segment is actually entertaining. But I'm ahead of myself. Let me review this piece by piece. The Missing Ingredient is both the opening chapter and the worst chapter. It's terrible. A group of witches (Real witches, apparently.) are trying to reincarnate their goddess, but require several specific items, the only of which they don't have is a man's sperm. I'm not joking. So, the witch who hasn't fulfilled her part must acquire her item within the hour. It sounds like the plot of a pornographic film. It's just stupid. The witch seduces Tim Roth's Ted the Bellhop, and some silly special effects later, she has her final item. I can't tell you how much I hated this. Not once during this chapter did I crack a smile, I was just hoping the next part was better. It is, but not substantially so. The Wrong Man is the second chapter. A little more interesting and far less ridiculous, Ted the Bellhop finds himself staring down the barrel of a revolver when he accidentally enters the wrong room when responding to a call. The chaos that comes from a mistaken identity ensues, and Ted is put between a man with a gun and his gagged wife. What I found to be one of the best quotes from the movie comes up here. Something about wearing a bonnet, I can't recall it right now. Though, I felt the situation was a little hard to follow here. Maybe I wasn't really paying attention, maybe it was supposed to be convoluted. Maybe it was because Tim Roth is delivering his lines in an angry whisper the entire time.Seriously, I like Timothy Roth, he's had some great roles in some great films, but god he chose the wrong role here. Ted the Bellhop is a flamboyant, fast-talking wreck. I couldn't understand him sometimes. Maybe that's what made the movie "funny" but I found it annoying. It was like watching the protagonist of a kid's movie trying to get laughs from children by acting silly, but surrounded by swearing and adult themes. With the third chapter, thing get better. Perhaps it's because it focuses less on Roth's silly character. The Misbehavers is directed and written by Robert Rodriguez. In this fun little short, a tough husband and his wife leave their children in their hotel room for the evening, hiring Ted to check up on them now and then. "Don't misbehave" he warns. The two kids are portrayed in a funny, childish way and their innocence leads to a gruesome discovery that I won't spoil here; it's one of the few parts worth not spoiling. Rodriguez really gives us this picture of a dysfunctional family headed by a strict father-figure (Who MAY or may not be a gangster!) And this chapter ends with a great scene. The moment I'm sure many had been waiting for was Quentin Tarantino's segment: The Man from Hollywood. QT stars in this segment as a drunk, rich movie star. He and his posse are drinking, having a good time. The alcohol in their system leads to them recreating a scene from a Hitchcock story where one of the men must light his lighter ten times in a row, or have his pinkie chopped off. It's really well played out here as the drunk trio of friends (And a character from a previous chapter.) move about their suite, throwing their money around like it's nothing. If you like Tarantino's writing, you'll like this segment. If not, you won't! It's classic Tarantino. Again, Roth is sort of put in the background, behind this intoxicated cast of characters. I think Roth was the problem with the movie, possibly. Or rather, Roth's character. So there. It's an interesting concept that, with four skilled directors, could have been phenomenal. But alas, the filmmakers who directed the first two chapters are unknown for a reason. I think I'd have to say Rodriguez's segment was the best. So, I give this a 6/10. Really, the second chapters are fun little shorts, and even the second one isn't all that bad. But the opening part is so unforgivable. It sets such a negative tone for the rest of the movie. And since these segments are all part of one film, they must be given a rating as one.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of the funniest movies ever!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Dylan Greenberg
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/7/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I saw this movie at 10, and loved it! Yesterday, I saw the movie again, and it was even funnier! Tim Roth was hysterically cartoonish in his movements, hand gestures, and facial expressions. He really stole the show. The Misbehavers was my favorite section of the four that make up the film. I also like the Easter Egg of the TV playing Bedhead in the background during that scene. As the movie progresses further, it gets funnier and funnier. In the beginning, it was like "meh", but at the end, I was in tears of laughter! If you have Netflix, stop reading this review, and watch it immediately. It's on instant play. I highly, HIGHLY recommend it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A complete waste of film!!!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    2fresh 2clean
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/7/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie was horrible. It was the worst movie I have seen since How High. Quentin has definitely redeemed himself since he made this movie. It was amazing to see such big named actors such as Bruce Willis and Antonio Banderas in this movie. The only reason I can see why they decided to play in this film was to give a fresh starting Quentin Tarantino a chance. This movie stunk so bad I can still smell it even after I returned it to the video store. This movie just didn't do anything. It was boring and flat from start to finish. Please do not rent this movie. Spend your money on some gum or a coke. You'll definitely be spending your money on something more meaningful.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Unbelievably vacuous
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    David Frenkiel
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I registered to this site especially to warn the world: don't waste your time on this movie. It seems to be the result of overconfident Hollywood producers who figured that some critical mass of props, make up, "atmosphere", homages and mannerisms can create a masterpiece. Or at least a watchable feature film. The result is a collection of four pointless sequences (definitely not "stories"), only the third of which is mildly entertaining. I know that almost 20 years after its production, very few people will come across this movie. However, if my review can deter even one human from throwing away 90 minutes of his/her life, it's worth the effort. Oh, and in case you're a fan of the "colossal failure" genre - this thing is not colossal in any sense. It doesn't even deserve sarcasm. Just ignore it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Probably worth it for the Rodriguez and Tarantino segments
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    zetes
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    When I was in high school, anything Tarantino-related was required to be memorized. Yes, even this one was insisted upon in high school, though perhaps not as strongly as QT's first two. This portmanteau follows bellhop Tim Roth as he gets into several adventures over New Year's Eve. I remember liking this one quite a bit, but, viewing it now, it's just too uneven to be worthwhile. Anders' first segment is easily the low point, thankfully. Any film starring Madonna should be immediately suspect, and everything about this tale of witches is awful. Rockwell's segment is a bit of an improvement, but too forgettable. Rodriguez's segment is the one I remember being the best, and it thankfully does hold up okay. Antonio Banderas is hilarious in it, and most of the jokes hit. I remember QT's segment being the worst originally, but I actually thought it was by far the best this time around. It usually gets flack, I think, because it stars Tarantino, but he's comfortable here playing a pompous movie director. It's honestly his best performance (if it had been readily available, I might have suffered through Destiny Turns on the Radio again) and his direction is pretty brilliant. The one thing that really drags this whole movie down is Tim Roth. Man, I remember loving him when I was a teenager, and, though I criticized his performance in Reservoir Dogs above, he's on Olivier's level there compared to his awful mugging here. Even if QT's segment were the weakest, it would automatically be upgraded to the strongest just because he's the only one who settles Roth the crap down, a bit at least.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Loved it!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    niklas_austrheim
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie is a fantastic piece of work - I love the way four writers/directors have cooperated here. I will say though, that it starts with a let down. It increases in quality throughout the entire film, and the last segment, "The Man From Hollywood" is brilliant! Quentin Tarantino brings his characters to life unlike any other director, with his long shots and genius dialogue. The third segment, "The Misbehavers", is funny in another way, it holds a lot of the childish humor we can recognize from "Desperado" and the "Spy Kids"-franchise. The second installment is a very well-written piece of work, but gets overshadowed by what is yet to come. Tim Roth's performance is phenomenal, he dares to bring his acting to the very limit of what could be called "over-acting", but doesn't cross the line entirely, and it brings the movie a very eccentric energy. All together a very good film, and I would recommend all of you to watch it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Peculiar and sophisticated, but uneven coherence
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Bene Cumb
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    One should clearly admit that Rodriguez and Tarantino are better directors and screenwriters than the other two, episodes No 3 and 4 are much more "ripe" and interesting. No 3 by Rodriguez is probably the most stylish, Tarantino, on the other hand, is the master of intense, funny and smutty dialogs. Most of male performances are excellent, especially Roth and Banderas, Willis and Tarantino are outstanding as well. Unlike other similar films, female parts are quite dull and mediocre, the cast in the episode No 1 is rather poor. Awkward characters and witty scenes are still worth watching (total length less than 1,5 hours), although Four Rooms is not among the best films where Rodriguez and Tarantino have participated.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Decent Anthology
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    billcr12
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/7/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Four Rooms is an anthology by different directors, taking place on New Year's Eve at a hotel. The Missing Ingredient is the first one by Allison Anders. Ted, a bellhop, helps a group of strange women to the honeymoon suite, where they have a large cauldron in the middle of the room in order to brew a potion to summon a goddess. They each add something to the mix, until the last witch needs to find semen within an hour to complete the potion. She works on Ted for a donation. I liked this one and give it 8/10. The Wrong Man by Alexandre Rockwell places Ted in an awkward situation in the middle of a fight between a husband and wife. Ted is accused of a sexual encounter with the lady by her husband and after Ted escapes, another guest goes through the same insanity. So so, and a 5/10. The Misbehavers by Robert Rodriguez puts Ted in the position of babysitter for two little brats. Antonio Banderas and his wife leave their boy and girl in the room and pay Ted $500 to make sure that the children behave. The bellhop places them in front of a television, and when he returns, the girl has a bottle of champagne in her hand, the boy is smoking a cigarette, and the TV is on an adult channel. Rodriguez must have had some bad experiences with children to come up with this one. It is funny and a 7.5/10. The last and not least is by my favorite director, Quentin Tarantino, who plays a movie director(talk about typecasting) who is gathered with others who enjoy a good bet. The wager involves a guy being able to light a Zippo lighter ten times in a row. If he succeeds, he wins a car; if not, his pinky will be chopped off with an extremely sharp hatchet. Ted is drafted to be the executioner with the promise of $1,000. Though a quicky by Tarantino standards, it contains the expected darkness of the diabolical genius. An 8.5/10. The combined score is a 7.5 and a decent assembly of talent.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Interesting Concept That Bathes in a Sea of Cheese
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Sean Lamberger
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/5/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Tim Roth stars as a twitchy, maligned bellhop in this wacky anthology of four loosely-linked short films. With a different director behind the wheel for each chapter, it shouldn't come as much surprise to hear this is an uneven tale that never settles on a firm identity for itself. The underlying theme is light slapstick suspense with a vibrant collection of supporting players, but each act also has its share of dark secrets and sinister overtones. The first two portions are colorful, but too thin for my taste. It seems like both had a solid beginning and ending in mind, and only set about painting by numbers to bring the two together. It's Robert Rodriguez's third act and Quentin Tarantino's closer, though, that drew me to the show anyway. Both serve as bite-sized capsules of both the best and worst traits and habits that have come to define each director. Rodriguez's arc, which naturally features both Antonio Banderas and Salma Hayeck (albeit in short cameos) is a middle ground of sorts between Spy Kids and Planet Terror. It's part kid-focused mayhem and part pulpy, black, gross-out trauma; an enthusiastic, if shallow, ride. Tarantino's adventurous final chapter is more dialog driven, with the director (of course) playing the leading role. Like a caricature of himself, he spends a good ninety percent of the scene spewing pop culture references and jazzy one-liners before the whole drama culminates in a jolting, blunt burst of adrenaline. Overall, Four Rooms is a mixed bag, and apart from the Tarantino chapter, none of the acts stand up particularly well. While fans of the director will no doubt love Quentin's arc, it's short enough that it would probably be just as easily - and effectively - viewed on YouTube or Vimeo.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    ever building humor
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Patrick Mulligan
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/3/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Four Rooms is a slap stick four part tale of a Bell hop (Tim Roth) who encounters witches, crazed couples, trouble making kids, and drunken movie makers on new years eve at a once great Hollywood hotel. The brand of humor usually isn't up my alley, being very physical and less dialogue driven. But this movie still had me cracking me up. Each room is brought to you by way of a different director. Going in order you have Allison Anders, Alexandre Rockwell, Robert Rodriguez, and Quentin Tarantino. For me each segment was better than the last, Tarantino's being my favorite. I enjoyed watching the style change from scene to scene. I am not familiar with the work of the first two directors so there influence was less obvious to me than that of Rodriguez and Tarantino. Maybe that's why I enjoyed there scenes the most, but everyone is a little biased. Everything from writing to camera work shifts with the changing of directors. That is probably my favorite thing about Four Rooms. It's interesting to see Ted the bell hop interact with the different worlds painted for him by the directors. Even if your not into physical humor, you can get a certain amount of enjoyment just watching the camera change hands. But if you like feminist witches, marital problems refereed by revolvers, dead hookers, and wagers worth a little finger and a slick ride, this is a movie for you.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Terrible First Half, With a Pretty Good Second Half
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    DoctorKingSchultz
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I'll admit, I do have a bias towards Tarantino. I love the guy's stuff. Not a single one of his films do I dislike in the slightest. However, he has dabbled in some side projects that don't carry the full "Written and Directed by..." promise of, say Pulp Fiction or Kill Bill, that aren't the biggest successes. But for a single segment of the four that make up Four Rooms, we have Tarantino behind the pen, the camera, and in front of the screen! It's no coincidence that his segment is actually entertaining. But I'm ahead of myself. Let me review this piece by piece. The Missing Ingredient is both the opening chapter and the worst chapter. It's terrible. A group of witches (Real witches, apparently.) are trying to reincarnate their goddess, but require several specific items, the only of which they don't have is a man's sperm. I'm not joking. So, the witch who hasn't fulfilled her part must acquire her item within the hour. It sounds like the plot of a pornographic film. It's just stupid. The witch seduces Tim Roth's Ted the Bellhop, and some silly special effects later, she has her final item. I can't tell you how much I hated this. Not once during this chapter did I crack a smile, I was just hoping the next part was better. It is, but not substantially so. The Wrong Man is the second chapter. A little more interesting and far less ridiculous, Ted the Bellhop finds himself staring down the barrel of a revolver when he accidentally enters the wrong room when responding to a call. The chaos that comes from a mistaken identity ensues, and Ted is put between a man with a gun and his gagged wife. What I found to be one of the best quotes from the movie comes up here. Something about wearing a bonnet, I can't recall it right now. Though, I felt the situation was a little hard to follow here. Maybe I wasn't really paying attention, maybe it was supposed to be convoluted. Maybe it was because Tim Roth is delivering his lines in an angry whisper the entire time.Seriously, I like Timothy Roth, he's had some great roles in some great films, but god he chose the wrong role here. Ted the Bellhop is a flamboyant, fast-talking wreck. I couldn't understand him sometimes. Maybe that's what made the movie "funny" but I found it annoying. It was like watching the protagonist of a kid's movie trying to get laughs from children by acting silly, but surrounded by swearing and adult themes. With the third chapter, thing get better. Perhaps it's because it focuses less on Roth's silly character. The Misbehavers is directed and written by Robert Rodriguez. In this fun little short, a tough husband and his wife leave their children in their hotel room for the evening, hiring Ted to check up on them now and then. "Don't misbehave" he warns. The two kids are portrayed in a funny, childish way and their innocence leads to a gruesome discovery that I won't spoil here; it's one of the few parts worth not spoiling. Rodriguez really gives us this picture of a dysfunctional family headed by a strict father-figure (Who MAY or may not be a gangster!) And this chapter ends with a great scene. The moment I'm sure many had been waiting for was Quentin Tarantino's segment: The Man from Hollywood. QT stars in this segment as a drunk, rich movie star. He and his posse are drinking, having a good time. The alcohol in their system leads to them recreating a scene from a Hitchcock story where one of the men must light his lighter ten times in a row, or have his pinkie chopped off. It's really well played out here as the drunk trio of friends (And a character from a previous chapter.) move about their suite, throwing their money around like it's nothing. If you like Tarantino's writing, you'll like this segment. If not, you won't! It's classic Tarantino. Again, Roth is sort of put in the background, behind this intoxicated cast of characters. I think Roth was the problem with the movie, possibly. Or rather, Roth's character. So there. It's an interesting concept that, with four skilled directors, could have been phenomenal. But alas, the filmmakers who directed the first two chapters are unknown for a reason. I think I'd have to say Rodriguez's segment was the best. So, I give this a 6/10. Really, the second chapters are fun little shorts, and even the second one isn't all that bad. But the opening part is so unforgivable. It sets such a negative tone for the rest of the movie. And since these segments are all part of one film, they must be given a rating as one.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of the funniest movies ever!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Dylan Greenberg
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/7/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I saw this movie at 10, and loved it! Yesterday, I saw the movie again, and it was even funnier! Tim Roth was hysterically cartoonish in his movements, hand gestures, and facial expressions. He really stole the show. The Misbehavers was my favorite section of the four that make up the film. I also like the Easter Egg of the TV playing Bedhead in the background during that scene. As the movie progresses further, it gets funnier and funnier. In the beginning, it was like "meh", but at the end, I was in tears of laughter! If you have Netflix, stop reading this review, and watch it immediately. It's on instant play. I highly, HIGHLY recommend it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A complete waste of film!!!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    2fresh 2clean
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/7/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie was horrible. It was the worst movie I have seen since How High. Quentin has definitely redeemed himself since he made this movie. It was amazing to see such big named actors such as Bruce Willis and Antonio Banderas in this movie. The only reason I can see why they decided to play in this film was to give a fresh starting Quentin Tarantino a chance. This movie stunk so bad I can still smell it even after I returned it to the video store. This movie just didn't do anything. It was boring and flat from start to finish. Please do not rent this movie. Spend your money on some gum or a coke. You'll definitely be spending your money on something more meaningful.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Unbelievably vacuous
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    David Frenkiel
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I registered to this site especially to warn the world: don't waste your time on this movie. It seems to be the result of overconfident Hollywood producers who figured that some critical mass of props, make up, "atmosphere", homages and mannerisms can create a masterpiece. Or at least a watchable feature film. The result is a collection of four pointless sequences (definitely not "stories"), only the third of which is mildly entertaining. I know that almost 20 years after its production, very few people will come across this movie. However, if my review can deter even one human from throwing away 90 minutes of his/her life, it's worth the effort. Oh, and in case you're a fan of the "colossal failure" genre - this thing is not colossal in any sense. It doesn't even deserve sarcasm. Just ignore it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Probably worth it for the Rodriguez and Tarantino segments
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    zetes
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    When I was in high school, anything Tarantino-related was required to be memorized. Yes, even this one was insisted upon in high school, though perhaps not as strongly as QT's first two. This portmanteau follows bellhop Tim Roth as he gets into several adventures over New Year's Eve. I remember liking this one quite a bit, but, viewing it now, it's just too uneven to be worthwhile. Anders' first segment is easily the low point, thankfully. Any film starring Madonna should be immediately suspect, and everything about this tale of witches is awful. Rockwell's segment is a bit of an improvement, but too forgettable. Rodriguez's segment is the one I remember being the best, and it thankfully does hold up okay. Antonio Banderas is hilarious in it, and most of the jokes hit. I remember QT's segment being the worst originally, but I actually thought it was by far the best this time around. It usually gets flack, I think, because it stars Tarantino, but he's comfortable here playing a pompous movie director. It's honestly his best performance (if it had been readily available, I might have suffered through Destiny Turns on the Radio again) and his direction is pretty brilliant. The one thing that really drags this whole movie down is Tim Roth. Man, I remember loving him when I was a teenager, and, though I criticized his performance in Reservoir Dogs above, he's on Olivier's level there compared to his awful mugging here. Even if QT's segment were the weakest, it would automatically be upgraded to the strongest just because he's the only one who settles Roth the crap down, a bit at least.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Loved it!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    niklas_austrheim
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie is a fantastic piece of work - I love the way four writers/directors have cooperated here. I will say though, that it starts with a let down. It increases in quality throughout the entire film, and the last segment, "The Man From Hollywood" is brilliant! Quentin Tarantino brings his characters to life unlike any other director, with his long shots and genius dialogue. The third segment, "The Misbehavers", is funny in another way, it holds a lot of the childish humor we can recognize from "Desperado" and the "Spy Kids"-franchise. The second installment is a very well-written piece of work, but gets overshadowed by what is yet to come. Tim Roth's performance is phenomenal, he dares to bring his acting to the very limit of what could be called "over-acting", but doesn't cross the line entirely, and it brings the movie a very eccentric energy. All together a very good film, and I would recommend all of you to watch it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Peculiar and sophisticated, but uneven coherence
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Bene Cumb
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    One should clearly admit that Rodriguez and Tarantino are better directors and screenwriters than the other two, episodes No 3 and 4 are much more "ripe" and interesting. No 3 by Rodriguez is probably the most stylish, Tarantino, on the other hand, is the master of intense, funny and smutty dialogs. Most of male performances are excellent, especially Roth and Banderas, Willis and Tarantino are outstanding as well. Unlike other similar films, female parts are quite dull and mediocre, the cast in the episode No 1 is rather poor. Awkward characters and witty scenes are still worth watching (total length less than 1,5 hours), although Four Rooms is not among the best films where Rodriguez and Tarantino have participated.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Decent Anthology
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    billcr12
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/7/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Four Rooms is an anthology by different directors, taking place on New Year's Eve at a hotel. The Missing Ingredient is the first one by Allison Anders. Ted, a bellhop, helps a group of strange women to the honeymoon suite, where they have a large cauldron in the middle of the room in order to brew a potion to summon a goddess. They each add something to the mix, until the last witch needs to find semen within an hour to complete the potion. She works on Ted for a donation. I liked this one and give it 8/10. The Wrong Man by Alexandre Rockwell places Ted in an awkward situation in the middle of a fight between a husband and wife. Ted is accused of a sexual encounter with the lady by her husband and after Ted escapes, another guest goes through the same insanity. So so, and a 5/10. The Misbehavers by Robert Rodriguez puts Ted in the position of babysitter for two little brats. Antonio Banderas and his wife leave their boy and girl in the room and pay Ted $500 to make sure that the children behave. The bellhop places them in front of a television, and when he returns, the girl has a bottle of champagne in her hand, the boy is smoking a cigarette, and the TV is on an adult channel. Rodriguez must have had some bad experiences with children to come up with this one. It is funny and a 7.5/10. The last and not least is by my favorite director, Quentin Tarantino, who plays a movie director(talk about typecasting) who is gathered with others who enjoy a good bet. The wager involves a guy being able to light a Zippo lighter ten times in a row. If he succeeds, he wins a car; if not, his pinky will be chopped off with an extremely sharp hatchet. Ted is drafted to be the executioner with the promise of $1,000. Though a quicky by Tarantino standards, it contains the expected darkness of the diabolical genius. An 8.5/10. The combined score is a 7.5 and a decent assembly of talent.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Interesting Concept That Bathes in a Sea of Cheese
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Sean Lamberger
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/5/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Tim Roth stars as a twitchy, maligned bellhop in this wacky anthology of four loosely-linked short films. With a different director behind the wheel for each chapter, it shouldn't come as much surprise to hear this is an uneven tale that never settles on a firm identity for itself. The underlying theme is light slapstick suspense with a vibrant collection of supporting players, but each act also has its share of dark secrets and sinister overtones. The first two portions are colorful, but too thin for my taste. It seems like both had a solid beginning and ending in mind, and only set about painting by numbers to bring the two together. It's Robert Rodriguez's third act and Quentin Tarantino's closer, though, that drew me to the show anyway. Both serve as bite-sized capsules of both the best and worst traits and habits that have come to define each director. Rodriguez's arc, which naturally features both Antonio Banderas and Salma Hayeck (albeit in short cameos) is a middle ground of sorts between Spy Kids and Planet Terror. It's part kid-focused mayhem and part pulpy, black, gross-out trauma; an enthusiastic, if shallow, ride. Tarantino's adventurous final chapter is more dialog driven, with the director (of course) playing the leading role. Like a caricature of himself, he spends a good ninety percent of the scene spewing pop culture references and jazzy one-liners before the whole drama culminates in a jolting, blunt burst of adrenaline. Overall, Four Rooms is a mixed bag, and apart from the Tarantino chapter, none of the acts stand up particularly well. While fans of the director will no doubt love Quentin's arc, it's short enough that it would probably be just as easily - and effectively - viewed on YouTube or Vimeo.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    ever building humor
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Patrick Mulligan
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/3/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Four Rooms is a slap stick four part tale of a Bell hop (Tim Roth) who encounters witches, crazed couples, trouble making kids, and drunken movie makers on new years eve at a once great Hollywood hotel. The brand of humor usually isn't up my alley, being very physical and less dialogue driven. But this movie still had me cracking me up. Each room is brought to you by way of a different director. Going in order you have Allison Anders, Alexandre Rockwell, Robert Rodriguez, and Quentin Tarantino. For me each segment was better than the last, Tarantino's being my favorite. I enjoyed watching the style change from scene to scene. I am not familiar with the work of the first two directors so there influence was less obvious to me than that of Rodriguez and Tarantino. Maybe that's why I enjoyed there scenes the most, but everyone is a little biased. Everything from writing to camera work shifts with the changing of directors. That is probably my favorite thing about Four Rooms. It's interesting to see Ted the bell hop interact with the different worlds painted for him by the directors. Even if your not into physical humor, you can get a certain amount of enjoyment just watching the camera change hands. But if you like feminist witches, marital problems refereed by revolvers, dead hookers, and wagers worth a little finger and a slick ride, this is a movie for you.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Terrible First Half, With a Pretty Good Second Half
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    DoctorKingSchultz
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I'll admit, I do have a bias towards Tarantino. I love the guy's stuff. Not a single one of his films do I dislike in the slightest. However, he has dabbled in some side projects that don't carry the full "Written and Directed by..." promise of, say Pulp Fiction or Kill Bill, that aren't the biggest successes. But for a single segment of the four that make up Four Rooms, we have Tarantino behind the pen, the camera, and in front of the screen! It's no coincidence that his segment is actually entertaining. But I'm ahead of myself. Let me review this piece by piece. The Missing Ingredient is both the opening chapter and the worst chapter. It's terrible. A group of witches (Real witches, apparently.) are trying to reincarnate their goddess, but require several specific items, the only of which they don't have is a man's sperm. I'm not joking. So, the witch who hasn't fulfilled her part must acquire her item within the hour. It sounds like the plot of a pornographic film. It's just stupid. The witch seduces Tim Roth's Ted the Bellhop, and some silly special effects later, she has her final item. I can't tell you how much I hated this. Not once during this chapter did I crack a smile, I was just hoping the next part was better. It is, but not substantially so. The Wrong Man is the second chapter. A little more interesting and far less ridiculous, Ted the Bellhop finds himself staring down the barrel of a revolver when he accidentally enters the wrong room when responding to a call. The chaos that comes from a mistaken identity ensues, and Ted is put between a man with a gun and his gagged wife. What I found to be one of the best quotes from the movie comes up here. Something about wearing a bonnet, I can't recall it right now. Though, I felt the situation was a little hard to follow here. Maybe I wasn't really paying attention, maybe it was supposed to be convoluted. Maybe it was because Tim Roth is delivering his lines in an angry whisper the entire time.Seriously, I like Timothy Roth, he's had some great roles in some great films, but god he chose the wrong role here. Ted the Bellhop is a flamboyant, fast-talking wreck. I couldn't understand him sometimes. Maybe that's what made the movie "funny" but I found it annoying. It was like watching the protagonist of a kid's movie trying to get laughs from children by acting silly, but surrounded by swearing and adult themes. With the third chapter, thing get better. Perhaps it's because it focuses less on Roth's silly character. The Misbehavers is directed and written by Robert Rodriguez. In this fun little short, a tough husband and his wife leave their children in their hotel room for the evening, hiring Ted to check up on them now and then. "Don't misbehave" he warns. The two kids are portrayed in a funny, childish way and their innocence leads to a gruesome discovery that I won't spoil here; it's one of the few parts worth not spoiling. Rodriguez really gives us this picture of a dysfunctional family headed by a strict father-figure (Who MAY or may not be a gangster!) And this chapter ends with a great scene. The moment I'm sure many had been waiting for was Quentin Tarantino's segment: The Man from Hollywood. QT stars in this segment as a drunk, rich movie star. He and his posse are drinking, having a good time. The alcohol in their system leads to them recreating a scene from a Hitchcock story where one of the men must light his lighter ten times in a row, or have his pinkie chopped off. It's really well played out here as the drunk trio of friends (And a character from a previous chapter.) move about their suite, throwing their money around like it's nothing. If you like Tarantino's writing, you'll like this segment. If not, you won't! It's classic Tarantino. Again, Roth is sort of put in the background, behind this intoxicated cast of characters. I think Roth was the problem with the movie, possibly. Or rather, Roth's character. So there. It's an interesting concept that, with four skilled directors, could have been phenomenal. But alas, the filmmakers who directed the first two chapters are unknown for a reason. I think I'd have to say Rodriguez's segment was the best. So, I give this a 6/10. Really, the second chapters are fun little shorts, and even the second one isn't all that bad. But the opening part is so unforgivable. It sets such a negative tone for the rest of the movie. And since these segments are all part of one film, they must be given a rating as one.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of the funniest movies ever!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Dylan Greenberg
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/7/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I saw this movie at 10, and loved it! Yesterday, I saw the movie again, and it was even funnier! Tim Roth was hysterically cartoonish in his movements, hand gestures, and facial expressions. He really stole the show. The Misbehavers was my favorite section of the four that make up the film. I also like the Easter Egg of the TV playing Bedhead in the background during that scene. As the movie progresses further, it gets funnier and funnier. In the beginning, it was like "meh", but at the end, I was in tears of laughter! If you have Netflix, stop reading this review, and watch it immediately. It's on instant play. I highly, HIGHLY recommend it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A complete waste of film!!!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    2fresh 2clean
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/7/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie was horrible. It was the worst movie I have seen since How High. Quentin has definitely redeemed himself since he made this movie. It was amazing to see such big named actors such as Bruce Willis and Antonio Banderas in this movie. The only reason I can see why they decided to play in this film was to give a fresh starting Quentin Tarantino a chance. This movie stunk so bad I can still smell it even after I returned it to the video store. This movie just didn't do anything. It was boring and flat from start to finish. Please do not rent this movie. Spend your money on some gum or a coke. You'll definitely be spending your money on something more meaningful.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Unbelievably vacuous
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    David Frenkiel
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I registered to this site especially to warn the world: don't waste your time on this movie. It seems to be the result of overconfident Hollywood producers who figured that some critical mass of props, make up, "atmosphere", homages and mannerisms can create a masterpiece. Or at least a watchable feature film. The result is a collection of four pointless sequences (definitely not "stories"), only the third of which is mildly entertaining. I know that almost 20 years after its production, very few people will come across this movie. However, if my review can deter even one human from throwing away 90 minutes of his/her life, it's worth the effort. Oh, and in case you're a fan of the "colossal failure" genre - this thing is not colossal in any sense. It doesn't even deserve sarcasm. Just ignore it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Probably worth it for the Rodriguez and Tarantino segments
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    zetes
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    When I was in high school, anything Tarantino-related was required to be memorized. Yes, even this one was insisted upon in high school, though perhaps not as strongly as QT's first two. This portmanteau follows bellhop Tim Roth as he gets into several adventures over New Year's Eve. I remember liking this one quite a bit, but, viewing it now, it's just too uneven to be worthwhile. Anders' first segment is easily the low point, thankfully. Any film starring Madonna should be immediately suspect, and everything about this tale of witches is awful. Rockwell's segment is a bit of an improvement, but too forgettable. Rodriguez's segment is the one I remember being the best, and it thankfully does hold up okay. Antonio Banderas is hilarious in it, and most of the jokes hit. I remember QT's segment being the worst originally, but I actually thought it was by far the best this time around. It usually gets flack, I think, because it stars Tarantino, but he's comfortable here playing a pompous movie director. It's honestly his best performance (if it had been readily available, I might have suffered through Destiny Turns on the Radio again) and his direction is pretty brilliant. The one thing that really drags this whole movie down is Tim Roth. Man, I remember loving him when I was a teenager, and, though I criticized his performance in Reservoir Dogs above, he's on Olivier's level there compared to his awful mugging here. Even if QT's segment were the weakest, it would automatically be upgraded to the strongest just because he's the only one who settles Roth the crap down, a bit at least.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Loved it!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    niklas_austrheim
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie is a fantastic piece of work - I love the way four writers/directors have cooperated here. I will say though, that it starts with a let down. It increases in quality throughout the entire film, and the last segment, "The Man From Hollywood" is brilliant! Quentin Tarantino brings his characters to life unlike any other director, with his long shots and genius dialogue. The third segment, "The Misbehavers", is funny in another way, it holds a lot of the childish humor we can recognize from "Desperado" and the "Spy Kids"-franchise. The second installment is a very well-written piece of work, but gets overshadowed by what is yet to come. Tim Roth's performance is phenomenal, he dares to bring his acting to the very limit of what could be called "over-acting", but doesn't cross the line entirely, and it brings the movie a very eccentric energy. All together a very good film, and I would recommend all of you to watch it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Peculiar and sophisticated, but uneven coherence
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Bene Cumb
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    One should clearly admit that Rodriguez and Tarantino are better directors and screenwriters than the other two, episodes No 3 and 4 are much more "ripe" and interesting. No 3 by Rodriguez is probably the most stylish, Tarantino, on the other hand, is the master of intense, funny and smutty dialogs. Most of male performances are excellent, especially Roth and Banderas, Willis and Tarantino are outstanding as well. Unlike other similar films, female parts are quite dull and mediocre, the cast in the episode No 1 is rather poor. Awkward characters and witty scenes are still worth watching (total length less than 1,5 hours), although Four Rooms is not among the best films where Rodriguez and Tarantino have participated.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Decent Anthology
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    billcr12
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/7/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Four Rooms is an anthology by different directors, taking place on New Year's Eve at a hotel. The Missing Ingredient is the first one by Allison Anders. Ted, a bellhop, helps a group of strange women to the honeymoon suite, where they have a large cauldron in the middle of the room in order to brew a potion to summon a goddess. They each add something to the mix, until the last witch needs to find semen within an hour to complete the potion. She works on Ted for a donation. I liked this one and give it 8/10. The Wrong Man by Alexandre Rockwell places Ted in an awkward situation in the middle of a fight between a husband and wife. Ted is accused of a sexual encounter with the lady by her husband and after Ted escapes, another guest goes through the same insanity. So so, and a 5/10. The Misbehavers by Robert Rodriguez puts Ted in the position of babysitter for two little brats. Antonio Banderas and his wife leave their boy and girl in the room and pay Ted $500 to make sure that the children behave. The bellhop places them in front of a television, and when he returns, the girl has a bottle of champagne in her hand, the boy is smoking a cigarette, and the TV is on an adult channel. Rodriguez must have had some bad experiences with children to come up with this one. It is funny and a 7.5/10. The last and not least is by my favorite director, Quentin Tarantino, who plays a movie director(talk about typecasting) who is gathered with others who enjoy a good bet. The wager involves a guy being able to light a Zippo lighter ten times in a row. If he succeeds, he wins a car; if not, his pinky will be chopped off with an extremely sharp hatchet. Ted is drafted to be the executioner with the promise of $1,000. Though a quicky by Tarantino standards, it contains the expected darkness of the diabolical genius. An 8.5/10. The combined score is a 7.5 and a decent assembly of talent.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Interesting Concept That Bathes in a Sea of Cheese
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Sean Lamberger
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/5/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Tim Roth stars as a twitchy, maligned bellhop in this wacky anthology of four loosely-linked short films. With a different director behind the wheel for each chapter, it shouldn't come as much surprise to hear this is an uneven tale that never settles on a firm identity for itself. The underlying theme is light slapstick suspense with a vibrant collection of supporting players, but each act also has its share of dark secrets and sinister overtones. The first two portions are colorful, but too thin for my taste. It seems like both had a solid beginning and ending in mind, and only set about painting by numbers to bring the two together. It's Robert Rodriguez's third act and Quentin Tarantino's closer, though, that drew me to the show anyway. Both serve as bite-sized capsules of both the best and worst traits and habits that have come to define each director. Rodriguez's arc, which naturally features both Antonio Banderas and Salma Hayeck (albeit in short cameos) is a middle ground of sorts between Spy Kids and Planet Terror. It's part kid-focused mayhem and part pulpy, black, gross-out trauma; an enthusiastic, if shallow, ride. Tarantino's adventurous final chapter is more dialog driven, with the director (of course) playing the leading role. Like a caricature of himself, he spends a good ninety percent of the scene spewing pop culture references and jazzy one-liners before the whole drama culminates in a jolting, blunt burst of adrenaline. Overall, Four Rooms is a mixed bag, and apart from the Tarantino chapter, none of the acts stand up particularly well. While fans of the director will no doubt love Quentin's arc, it's short enough that it would probably be just as easily - and effectively - viewed on YouTube or Vimeo.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    ever building humor
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Patrick Mulligan
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/3/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Four Rooms is a slap stick four part tale of a Bell hop (Tim Roth) who encounters witches, crazed couples, trouble making kids, and drunken movie makers on new years eve at a once great Hollywood hotel. The brand of humor usually isn't up my alley, being very physical and less dialogue driven. But this movie still had me cracking me up. Each room is brought to you by way of a different director. Going in order you have Allison Anders, Alexandre Rockwell, Robert Rodriguez, and Quentin Tarantino. For me each segment was better than the last, Tarantino's being my favorite. I enjoyed watching the style change from scene to scene. I am not familiar with the work of the first two directors so there influence was less obvious to me than that of Rodriguez and Tarantino. Maybe that's why I enjoyed there scenes the most, but everyone is a little biased. Everything from writing to camera work shifts with the changing of directors. That is probably my favorite thing about Four Rooms. It's interesting to see Ted the bell hop interact with the different worlds painted for him by the directors. Even if your not into physical humor, you can get a certain amount of enjoyment just watching the camera change hands. But if you like feminist witches, marital problems refereed by revolvers, dead hookers, and wagers worth a little finger and a slick ride, this is a movie for you.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Terrible First Half, With a Pretty Good Second Half
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    DoctorKingSchultz
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I'll admit, I do have a bias towards Tarantino. I love the guy's stuff. Not a single one of his films do I dislike in the slightest. However, he has dabbled in some side projects that don't carry the full "Written and Directed by..." promise of, say Pulp Fiction or Kill Bill, that aren't the biggest successes. But for a single segment of the four that make up Four Rooms, we have Tarantino behind the pen, the camera, and in front of the screen! It's no coincidence that his segment is actually entertaining. But I'm ahead of myself. Let me review this piece by piece. The Missing Ingredient is both the opening chapter and the worst chapter. It's terrible. A group of witches (Real witches, apparently.) are trying to reincarnate their goddess, but require several specific items, the only of which they don't have is a man's sperm. I'm not joking. So, the witch who hasn't fulfilled her part must acquire her item within the hour. It sounds like the plot of a pornographic film. It's just stupid. The witch seduces Tim Roth's Ted the Bellhop, and some silly special effects later, she has her final item. I can't tell you how much I hated this. Not once during this chapter did I crack a smile, I was just hoping the next part was better. It is, but not substantially so. The Wrong Man is the second chapter. A little more interesting and far less ridiculous, Ted the Bellhop finds himself staring down the barrel of a revolver when he accidentally enters the wrong room when responding to a call. The chaos that comes from a mistaken identity ensues, and Ted is put between a man with a gun and his gagged wife. What I found to be one of the best quotes from the movie comes up here. Something about wearing a bonnet, I can't recall it right now. Though, I felt the situation was a little hard to follow here. Maybe I wasn't really paying attention, maybe it was supposed to be convoluted. Maybe it was because Tim Roth is delivering his lines in an angry whisper the entire time.Seriously, I like Timothy Roth, he's had some great roles in some great films, but god he chose the wrong role here. Ted the Bellhop is a flamboyant, fast-talking wreck. I couldn't understand him sometimes. Maybe that's what made the movie "funny" but I found it annoying. It was like watching the protagonist of a kid's movie trying to get laughs from children by acting silly, but surrounded by swearing and adult themes. With the third chapter, thing get better. Perhaps it's because it focuses less on Roth's silly character. The Misbehavers is directed and written by Robert Rodriguez. In this fun little short, a tough husband and his wife leave their children in their hotel room for the evening, hiring Ted to check up on them now and then. "Don't misbehave" he warns. The two kids are portrayed in a funny, childish way and their innocence leads to a gruesome discovery that I won't spoil here; it's one of the few parts worth not spoiling. Rodriguez really gives us this picture of a dysfunctional family headed by a strict father-figure (Who MAY or may not be a gangster!) And this chapter ends with a great scene. The moment I'm sure many had been waiting for was Quentin Tarantino's segment: The Man from Hollywood. QT stars in this segment as a drunk, rich movie star. He and his posse are drinking, having a good time. The alcohol in their system leads to them recreating a scene from a Hitchcock story where one of the men must light his lighter ten times in a row, or have his pinkie chopped off. It's really well played out here as the drunk trio of friends (And a character from a previous chapter.) move about their suite, throwing their money around like it's nothing. If you like Tarantino's writing, you'll like this segment. If not, you won't! It's classic Tarantino. Again, Roth is sort of put in the background, behind this intoxicated cast of characters. I think Roth was the problem with the movie, possibly. Or rather, Roth's character. So there. It's an interesting concept that, with four skilled directors, could have been phenomenal. But alas, the filmmakers who directed the first two chapters are unknown for a reason. I think I'd have to say Rodriguez's segment was the best. So, I give this a 6/10. Really, the second chapters are fun little shorts, and even the second one isn't all that bad. But the opening part is so unforgivable. It sets such a negative tone for the rest of the movie. And since these segments are all part of one film, they must be given a rating as one.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of the funniest movies ever!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Dylan Greenberg
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/7/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I saw this movie at 10, and loved it! Yesterday, I saw the movie again, and it was even funnier! Tim Roth was hysterically cartoonish in his movements, hand gestures, and facial expressions. He really stole the show. The Misbehavers was my favorite section of the four that make up the film. I also like the Easter Egg of the TV playing Bedhead in the background during that scene. As the movie progresses further, it gets funnier and funnier. In the beginning, it was like "meh", but at the end, I was in tears of laughter! If you have Netflix, stop reading this review, and watch it immediately. It's on instant play. I highly, HIGHLY recommend it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A complete waste of film!!!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    2fresh 2clean
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/7/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie was horrible. It was the worst movie I have seen since How High. Quentin has definitely redeemed himself since he made this movie. It was amazing to see such big named actors such as Bruce Willis and Antonio Banderas in this movie. The only reason I can see why they decided to play in this film was to give a fresh starting Quentin Tarantino a chance. This movie stunk so bad I can still smell it even after I returned it to the video store. This movie just didn't do anything. It was boring and flat from start to finish. Please do not rent this movie. Spend your money on some gum or a coke. You'll definitely be spending your money on something more meaningful.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Unbelievably vacuous
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    David Frenkiel
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I registered to this site especially to warn the world: don't waste your time on this movie. It seems to be the result of overconfident Hollywood producers who figured that some critical mass of props, make up, "atmosphere", homages and mannerisms can create a masterpiece. Or at least a watchable feature film. The result is a collection of four pointless sequences (definitely not "stories"), only the third of which is mildly entertaining. I know that almost 20 years after its production, very few people will come across this movie. However, if my review can deter even one human from throwing away 90 minutes of his/her life, it's worth the effort. Oh, and in case you're a fan of the "colossal failure" genre - this thing is not colossal in any sense. It doesn't even deserve sarcasm. Just ignore it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Probably worth it for the Rodriguez and Tarantino segments
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    zetes
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    When I was in high school, anything Tarantino-related was required to be memorized. Yes, even this one was insisted upon in high school, though perhaps not as strongly as QT's first two. This portmanteau follows bellhop Tim Roth as he gets into several adventures over New Year's Eve. I remember liking this one quite a bit, but, viewing it now, it's just too uneven to be worthwhile. Anders' first segment is easily the low point, thankfully. Any film starring Madonna should be immediately suspect, and everything about this tale of witches is awful. Rockwell's segment is a bit of an improvement, but too forgettable. Rodriguez's segment is the one I remember being the best, and it thankfully does hold up okay. Antonio Banderas is hilarious in it, and most of the jokes hit. I remember QT's segment being the worst originally, but I actually thought it was by far the best this time around. It usually gets flack, I think, because it stars Tarantino, but he's comfortable here playing a pompous movie director. It's honestly his best performance (if it had been readily available, I might have suffered through Destiny Turns on the Radio again) and his direction is pretty brilliant. The one thing that really drags this whole movie down is Tim Roth. Man, I remember loving him when I was a teenager, and, though I criticized his performance in Reservoir Dogs above, he's on Olivier's level there compared to his awful mugging here. Even if QT's segment were the weakest, it would automatically be upgraded to the strongest just because he's the only one who settles Roth the crap down, a bit at least.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Loved it!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    niklas_austrheim
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie is a fantastic piece of work - I love the way four writers/directors have cooperated here. I will say though, that it starts with a let down. It increases in quality throughout the entire film, and the last segment, "The Man From Hollywood" is brilliant! Quentin Tarantino brings his characters to life unlike any other director, with his long shots and genius dialogue. The third segment, "The Misbehavers", is funny in another way, it holds a lot of the childish humor we can recognize from "Desperado" and the "Spy Kids"-franchise. The second installment is a very well-written piece of work, but gets overshadowed by what is yet to come. Tim Roth's performance is phenomenal, he dares to bring his acting to the very limit of what could be called "over-acting", but doesn't cross the line entirely, and it brings the movie a very eccentric energy. All together a very good film, and I would recommend all of you to watch it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Peculiar and sophisticated, but uneven coherence
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Bene Cumb
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    One should clearly admit that Rodriguez and Tarantino are better directors and screenwriters than the other two, episodes No 3 and 4 are much more "ripe" and interesting. No 3 by Rodriguez is probably the most stylish, Tarantino, on the other hand, is the master of intense, funny and smutty dialogs. Most of male performances are excellent, especially Roth and Banderas, Willis and Tarantino are outstanding as well. Unlike other similar films, female parts are quite dull and mediocre, the cast in the episode No 1 is rather poor. Awkward characters and witty scenes are still worth watching (total length less than 1,5 hours), although Four Rooms is not among the best films where Rodriguez and Tarantino have participated.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Decent Anthology
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    billcr12
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/7/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Four Rooms is an anthology by different directors, taking place on New Year's Eve at a hotel. The Missing Ingredient is the first one by Allison Anders. Ted, a bellhop, helps a group of strange women to the honeymoon suite, where they have a large cauldron in the middle of the room in order to brew a potion to summon a goddess. They each add something to the mix, until the last witch needs to find semen within an hour to complete the potion. She works on Ted for a donation. I liked this one and give it 8/10. The Wrong Man by Alexandre Rockwell places Ted in an awkward situation in the middle of a fight between a husband and wife. Ted is accused of a sexual encounter with the lady by her husband and after Ted escapes, another guest goes through the same insanity. So so, and a 5/10. The Misbehavers by Robert Rodriguez puts Ted in the position of babysitter for two little brats. Antonio Banderas and his wife leave their boy and girl in the room and pay Ted $500 to make sure that the children behave. The bellhop places them in front of a television, and when he returns, the girl has a bottle of champagne in her hand, the boy is smoking a cigarette, and the TV is on an adult channel. Rodriguez must have had some bad experiences with children to come up with this one. It is funny and a 7.5/10. The last and not least is by my favorite director, Quentin Tarantino, who plays a movie director(talk about typecasting) who is gathered with others who enjoy a good bet. The wager involves a guy being able to light a Zippo lighter ten times in a row. If he succeeds, he wins a car; if not, his pinky will be chopped off with an extremely sharp hatchet. Ted is drafted to be the executioner with the promise of $1,000. Though a quicky by Tarantino standards, it contains the expected darkness of the diabolical genius. An 8.5/10. The combined score is a 7.5 and a decent assembly of talent.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Interesting Concept That Bathes in a Sea of Cheese
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Sean Lamberger
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/5/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Tim Roth stars as a twitchy, maligned bellhop in this wacky anthology of four loosely-linked short films. With a different director behind the wheel for each chapter, it shouldn't come as much surprise to hear this is an uneven tale that never settles on a firm identity for itself. The underlying theme is light slapstick suspense with a vibrant collection of supporting players, but each act also has its share of dark secrets and sinister overtones. The first two portions are colorful, but too thin for my taste. It seems like both had a solid beginning and ending in mind, and only set about painting by numbers to bring the two together. It's Robert Rodriguez's third act and Quentin Tarantino's closer, though, that drew me to the show anyway. Both serve as bite-sized capsules of both the best and worst traits and habits that have come to define each director. Rodriguez's arc, which naturally features both Antonio Banderas and Salma Hayeck (albeit in short cameos) is a middle ground of sorts between Spy Kids and Planet Terror. It's part kid-focused mayhem and part pulpy, black, gross-out trauma; an enthusiastic, if shallow, ride. Tarantino's adventurous final chapter is more dialog driven, with the director (of course) playing the leading role. Like a caricature of himself, he spends a good ninety percent of the scene spewing pop culture references and jazzy one-liners before the whole drama culminates in a jolting, blunt burst of adrenaline. Overall, Four Rooms is a mixed bag, and apart from the Tarantino chapter, none of the acts stand up particularly well. While fans of the director will no doubt love Quentin's arc, it's short enough that it would probably be just as easily - and effectively - viewed on YouTube or Vimeo.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    ever building humor
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Patrick Mulligan
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/3/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Four Rooms is a slap stick four part tale of a Bell hop (Tim Roth) who encounters witches, crazed couples, trouble making kids, and drunken movie makers on new years eve at a once great Hollywood hotel. The brand of humor usually isn't up my alley, being very physical and less dialogue driven. But this movie still had me cracking me up. Each room is brought to you by way of a different director. Going in order you have Allison Anders, Alexandre Rockwell, Robert Rodriguez, and Quentin Tarantino. For me each segment was better than the last, Tarantino's being my favorite. I enjoyed watching the style change from scene to scene. I am not familiar with the work of the first two directors so there influence was less obvious to me than that of Rodriguez and Tarantino. Maybe that's why I enjoyed there scenes the most, but everyone is a little biased. Everything from writing to camera work shifts with the changing of directors. That is probably my favorite thing about Four Rooms. It's interesting to see Ted the bell hop interact with the different worlds painted for him by the directors. Even if your not into physical humor, you can get a certain amount of enjoyment just watching the camera change hands. But if you like feminist witches, marital problems refereed by revolvers, dead hookers, and wagers worth a little finger and a slick ride, this is a movie for you.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Terrible First Half, With a Pretty Good Second Half
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    DoctorKingSchultz
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I'll admit, I do have a bias towards Tarantino. I love the guy's stuff. Not a single one of his films do I dislike in the slightest. However, he has dabbled in some side projects that don't carry the full "Written and Directed by..." promise of, say Pulp Fiction or Kill Bill, that aren't the biggest successes. But for a single segment of the four that make up Four Rooms, we have Tarantino behind the pen, the camera, and in front of the screen! It's no coincidence that his segment is actually entertaining. But I'm ahead of myself. Let me review this piece by piece. The Missing Ingredient is both the opening chapter and the worst chapter. It's terrible. A group of witches (Real witches, apparently.) are trying to reincarnate their goddess, but require several specific items, the only of which they don't have is a man's sperm. I'm not joking. So, the witch who hasn't fulfilled her part must acquire her item within the hour. It sounds like the plot of a pornographic film. It's just stupid. The witch seduces Tim Roth's Ted the Bellhop, and some silly special effects later, she has her final item. I can't tell you how much I hated this. Not once during this chapter did I crack a smile, I was just hoping the next part was better. It is, but not substantially so. The Wrong Man is the second chapter. A little more interesting and far less ridiculous, Ted the Bellhop finds himself staring down the barrel of a revolver when he accidentally enters the wrong room when responding to a call. The chaos that comes from a mistaken identity ensues, and Ted is put between a man with a gun and his gagged wife. What I found to be one of the best quotes from the movie comes up here. Something about wearing a bonnet, I can't recall it right now. Though, I felt the situation was a little hard to follow here. Maybe I wasn't really paying attention, maybe it was supposed to be convoluted. Maybe it was because Tim Roth is delivering his lines in an angry whisper the entire time.Seriously, I like Timothy Roth, he's had some great roles in some great films, but god he chose the wrong role here. Ted the Bellhop is a flamboyant, fast-talking wreck. I couldn't understand him sometimes. Maybe that's what made the movie "funny" but I found it annoying. It was like watching the protagonist of a kid's movie trying to get laughs from children by acting silly, but surrounded by swearing and adult themes. With the third chapter, thing get better. Perhaps it's because it focuses less on Roth's silly character. The Misbehavers is directed and written by Robert Rodriguez. In this fun little short, a tough husband and his wife leave their children in their hotel room for the evening, hiring Ted to check up on them now and then. "Don't misbehave" he warns. The two kids are portrayed in a funny, childish way and their innocence leads to a gruesome discovery that I won't spoil here; it's one of the few parts worth not spoiling. Rodriguez really gives us this picture of a dysfunctional family headed by a strict father-figure (Who MAY or may not be a gangster!) And this chapter ends with a great scene. The moment I'm sure many had been waiting for was Quentin Tarantino's segment: The Man from Hollywood. QT stars in this segment as a drunk, rich movie star. He and his posse are drinking, having a good time. The alcohol in their system leads to them recreating a scene from a Hitchcock story where one of the men must light his lighter ten times in a row, or have his pinkie chopped off. It's really well played out here as the drunk trio of friends (And a character from a previous chapter.) move about their suite, throwing their money around like it's nothing. If you like Tarantino's writing, you'll like this segment. If not, you won't! It's classic Tarantino. Again, Roth is sort of put in the background, behind this intoxicated cast of characters. I think Roth was the problem with the movie, possibly. Or rather, Roth's character. So there. It's an interesting concept that, with four skilled directors, could have been phenomenal. But alas, the filmmakers who directed the first two chapters are unknown for a reason. I think I'd have to say Rodriguez's segment was the best. So, I give this a 6/10. Really, the second chapters are fun little shorts, and even the second one isn't all that bad. But the opening part is so unforgivable. It sets such a negative tone for the rest of the movie. And since these segments are all part of one film, they must be given a rating as one.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of the funniest movies ever!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Dylan Greenberg
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/7/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I saw this movie at 10, and loved it! Yesterday, I saw the movie again, and it was even funnier! Tim Roth was hysterically cartoonish in his movements, hand gestures, and facial expressions. He really stole the show. The Misbehavers was my favorite section of the four that make up the film. I also like the Easter Egg of the TV playing Bedhead in the background during that scene. As the movie progresses further, it gets funnier and funnier. In the beginning, it was like "meh", but at the end, I was in tears of laughter! If you have Netflix, stop reading this review, and watch it immediately. It's on instant play. I highly, HIGHLY recommend it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A complete waste of film!!!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    2fresh 2clean
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/7/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie was horrible. It was the worst movie I have seen since How High. Quentin has definitely redeemed himself since he made this movie. It was amazing to see such big named actors such as Bruce Willis and Antonio Banderas in this movie. The only reason I can see why they decided to play in this film was to give a fresh starting Quentin Tarantino a chance. This movie stunk so bad I can still smell it even after I returned it to the video store. This movie just didn't do anything. It was boring and flat from start to finish. Please do not rent this movie. Spend your money on some gum or a coke. You'll definitely be spending your money on something more meaningful.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Unbelievably vacuous
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    David Frenkiel
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I registered to this site especially to warn the world: don't waste your time on this movie. It seems to be the result of overconfident Hollywood producers who figured that some critical mass of props, make up, "atmosphere", homages and mannerisms can create a masterpiece. Or at least a watchable feature film. The result is a collection of four pointless sequences (definitely not "stories"), only the third of which is mildly entertaining. I know that almost 20 years after its production, very few people will come across this movie. However, if my review can deter even one human from throwing away 90 minutes of his/her life, it's worth the effort. Oh, and in case you're a fan of the "colossal failure" genre - this thing is not colossal in any sense. It doesn't even deserve sarcasm. Just ignore it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Probably worth it for the Rodriguez and Tarantino segments
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    zetes
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    When I was in high school, anything Tarantino-related was required to be memorized. Yes, even this one was insisted upon in high school, though perhaps not as strongly as QT's first two. This portmanteau follows bellhop Tim Roth as he gets into several adventures over New Year's Eve. I remember liking this one quite a bit, but, viewing it now, it's just too uneven to be worthwhile. Anders' first segment is easily the low point, thankfully. Any film starring Madonna should be immediately suspect, and everything about this tale of witches is awful. Rockwell's segment is a bit of an improvement, but too forgettable. Rodriguez's segment is the one I remember being the best, and it thankfully does hold up okay. Antonio Banderas is hilarious in it, and most of the jokes hit. I remember QT's segment being the worst originally, but I actually thought it was by far the best this time around. It usually gets flack, I think, because it stars Tarantino, but he's comfortable here playing a pompous movie director. It's honestly his best performance (if it had been readily available, I might have suffered through Destiny Turns on the Radio again) and his direction is pretty brilliant. The one thing that really drags this whole movie down is Tim Roth. Man, I remember loving him when I was a teenager, and, though I criticized his performance in Reservoir Dogs above, he's on Olivier's level there compared to his awful mugging here. Even if QT's segment were the weakest, it would automatically be upgraded to the strongest just because he's the only one who settles Roth the crap down, a bit at least.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Loved it!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    niklas_austrheim
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie is a fantastic piece of work - I love the way four writers/directors have cooperated here. I will say though, that it starts with a let down. It increases in quality throughout the entire film, and the last segment, "The Man From Hollywood" is brilliant! Quentin Tarantino brings his characters to life unlike any other director, with his long shots and genius dialogue. The third segment, "The Misbehavers", is funny in another way, it holds a lot of the childish humor we can recognize from "Desperado" and the "Spy Kids"-franchise. The second installment is a very well-written piece of work, but gets overshadowed by what is yet to come. Tim Roth's performance is phenomenal, he dares to bring his acting to the very limit of what could be called "over-acting", but doesn't cross the line entirely, and it brings the movie a very eccentric energy. All together a very good film, and I would recommend all of you to watch it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Peculiar and sophisticated, but uneven coherence
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Bene Cumb
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    One should clearly admit that Rodriguez and Tarantino are better directors and screenwriters than the other two, episodes No 3 and 4 are much more "ripe" and interesting. No 3 by Rodriguez is probably the most stylish, Tarantino, on the other hand, is the master of intense, funny and smutty dialogs. Most of male performances are excellent, especially Roth and Banderas, Willis and Tarantino are outstanding as well. Unlike other similar films, female parts are quite dull and mediocre, the cast in the episode No 1 is rather poor. Awkward characters and witty scenes are still worth watching (total length less than 1,5 hours), although Four Rooms is not among the best films where Rodriguez and Tarantino have participated.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Decent Anthology
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    billcr12
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/7/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Four Rooms is an anthology by different directors, taking place on New Year's Eve at a hotel. The Missing Ingredient is the first one by Allison Anders. Ted, a bellhop, helps a group of strange women to the honeymoon suite, where they have a large cauldron in the middle of the room in order to brew a potion to summon a goddess. They each add something to the mix, until the last witch needs to find semen within an hour to complete the potion. She works on Ted for a donation. I liked this one and give it 8/10. The Wrong Man by Alexandre Rockwell places Ted in an awkward situation in the middle of a fight between a husband and wife. Ted is accused of a sexual encounter with the lady by her husband and after Ted escapes, another guest goes through the same insanity. So so, and a 5/10. The Misbehavers by Robert Rodriguez puts Ted in the position of babysitter for two little brats. Antonio Banderas and his wife leave their boy and girl in the room and pay Ted $500 to make sure that the children behave. The bellhop places them in front of a television, and when he returns, the girl has a bottle of champagne in her hand, the boy is smoking a cigarette, and the TV is on an adult channel. Rodriguez must have had some bad experiences with children to come up with this one. It is funny and a 7.5/10. The last and not least is by my favorite director, Quentin Tarantino, who plays a movie director(talk about typecasting) who is gathered with others who enjoy a good bet. The wager involves a guy being able to light a Zippo lighter ten times in a row. If he succeeds, he wins a car; if not, his pinky will be chopped off with an extremely sharp hatchet. Ted is drafted to be the executioner with the promise of $1,000. Though a quicky by Tarantino standards, it contains the expected darkness of the diabolical genius. An 8.5/10. The combined score is a 7.5 and a decent assembly of talent.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Interesting Concept That Bathes in a Sea of Cheese
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Sean Lamberger
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/5/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Tim Roth stars as a twitchy, maligned bellhop in this wacky anthology of four loosely-linked short films. With a different director behind the wheel for each chapter, it shouldn't come as much surprise to hear this is an uneven tale that never settles on a firm identity for itself. The underlying theme is light slapstick suspense with a vibrant collection of supporting players, but each act also has its share of dark secrets and sinister overtones. The first two portions are colorful, but too thin for my taste. It seems like both had a solid beginning and ending in mind, and only set about painting by numbers to bring the two together. It's Robert Rodriguez's third act and Quentin Tarantino's closer, though, that drew me to the show anyway. Both serve as bite-sized capsules of both the best and worst traits and habits that have come to define each director. Rodriguez's arc, which naturally features both Antonio Banderas and Salma Hayeck (albeit in short cameos) is a middle ground of sorts between Spy Kids and Planet Terror. It's part kid-focused mayhem and part pulpy, black, gross-out trauma; an enthusiastic, if shallow, ride. Tarantino's adventurous final chapter is more dialog driven, with the director (of course) playing the leading role. Like a caricature of himself, he spends a good ninety percent of the scene spewing pop culture references and jazzy one-liners before the whole drama culminates in a jolting, blunt burst of adrenaline. Overall, Four Rooms is a mixed bag, and apart from the Tarantino chapter, none of the acts stand up particularly well. While fans of the director will no doubt love Quentin's arc, it's short enough that it would probably be just as easily - and effectively - viewed on YouTube or Vimeo.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    ever building humor
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Patrick Mulligan
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/3/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Four Rooms is a slap stick four part tale of a Bell hop (Tim Roth) who encounters witches, crazed couples, trouble making kids, and drunken movie makers on new years eve at a once great Hollywood hotel. The brand of humor usually isn't up my alley, being very physical and less dialogue driven. But this movie still had me cracking me up. Each room is brought to you by way of a different director. Going in order you have Allison Anders, Alexandre Rockwell, Robert Rodriguez, and Quentin Tarantino. For me each segment was better than the last, Tarantino's being my favorite. I enjoyed watching the style change from scene to scene. I am not familiar with the work of the first two directors so there influence was less obvious to me than that of Rodriguez and Tarantino. Maybe that's why I enjoyed there scenes the most, but everyone is a little biased. Everything from writing to camera work shifts with the changing of directors. That is probably my favorite thing about Four Rooms. It's interesting to see Ted the bell hop interact with the different worlds painted for him by the directors. Even if your not into physical humor, you can get a certain amount of enjoyment just watching the camera change hands. But if you like feminist witches, marital problems refereed by revolvers, dead hookers, and wagers worth a little finger and a slick ride, this is a movie for you.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Terrible First Half, With a Pretty Good Second Half
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    DoctorKingSchultz
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I'll admit, I do have a bias towards Tarantino. I love the guy's stuff. Not a single one of his films do I dislike in the slightest. However, he has dabbled in some side projects that don't carry the full "Written and Directed by..." promise of, say Pulp Fiction or Kill Bill, that aren't the biggest successes. But for a single segment of the four that make up Four Rooms, we have Tarantino behind the pen, the camera, and in front of the screen! It's no coincidence that his segment is actually entertaining. But I'm ahead of myself. Let me review this piece by piece. The Missing Ingredient is both the opening chapter and the worst chapter. It's terrible. A group of witches (Real witches, apparently.) are trying to reincarnate their goddess, but require several specific items, the only of which they don't have is a man's sperm. I'm not joking. So, the witch who hasn't fulfilled her part must acquire her item within the hour. It sounds like the plot of a pornographic film. It's just stupid. The witch seduces Tim Roth's Ted the Bellhop, and some silly special effects later, she has her final item. I can't tell you how much I hated this. Not once during this chapter did I crack a smile, I was just hoping the next part was better. It is, but not substantially so. The Wrong Man is the second chapter. A little more interesting and far less ridiculous, Ted the Bellhop finds himself staring down the barrel of a revolver when he accidentally enters the wrong room when responding to a call. The chaos that comes from a mistaken identity ensues, and Ted is put between a man with a gun and his gagged wife. What I found to be one of the best quotes from the movie comes up here. Something about wearing a bonnet, I can't recall it right now. Though, I felt the situation was a little hard to follow here. Maybe I wasn't really paying attention, maybe it was supposed to be convoluted. Maybe it was because Tim Roth is delivering his lines in an angry whisper the entire time.Seriously, I like Timothy Roth, he's had some great roles in some great films, but god he chose the wrong role here. Ted the Bellhop is a flamboyant, fast-talking wreck. I couldn't understand him sometimes. Maybe that's what made the movie "funny" but I found it annoying. It was like watching the protagonist of a kid's movie trying to get laughs from children by acting silly, but surrounded by swearing and adult themes. With the third chapter, thing get better. Perhaps it's because it focuses less on Roth's silly character. The Misbehavers is directed and written by Robert Rodriguez. In this fun little short, a tough husband and his wife leave their children in their hotel room for the evening, hiring Ted to check up on them now and then. "Don't misbehave" he warns. The two kids are portrayed in a funny, childish way and their innocence leads to a gruesome discovery that I won't spoil here; it's one of the few parts worth not spoiling. Rodriguez really gives us this picture of a dysfunctional family headed by a strict father-figure (Who MAY or may not be a gangster!) And this chapter ends with a great scene. The moment I'm sure many had been waiting for was Quentin Tarantino's segment: The Man from Hollywood. QT stars in this segment as a drunk, rich movie star. He and his posse are drinking, having a good time. The alcohol in their system leads to them recreating a scene from a Hitchcock story where one of the men must light his lighter ten times in a row, or have his pinkie chopped off. It's really well played out here as the drunk trio of friends (And a character from a previous chapter.) move about their suite, throwing their money around like it's nothing. If you like Tarantino's writing, you'll like this segment. If not, you won't! It's classic Tarantino. Again, Roth is sort of put in the background, behind this intoxicated cast of characters. I think Roth was the problem with the movie, possibly. Or rather, Roth's character. So there. It's an interesting concept that, with four skilled directors, could have been phenomenal. But alas, the filmmakers who directed the first two chapters are unknown for a reason. I think I'd have to say Rodriguez's segment was the best. So, I give this a 6/10. Really, the second chapters are fun little shorts, and even the second one isn't all that bad. But the opening part is so unforgivable. It sets such a negative tone for the rest of the movie. And since these segments are all part of one film, they must be given a rating as one.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of the funniest movies ever!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Dylan Greenberg
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/7/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I saw this movie at 10, and loved it! Yesterday, I saw the movie again, and it was even funnier! Tim Roth was hysterically cartoonish in his movements, hand gestures, and facial expressions. He really stole the show. The Misbehavers was my favorite section of the four that make up the film. I also like the Easter Egg of the TV playing Bedhead in the background during that scene. As the movie progresses further, it gets funnier and funnier. In the beginning, it was like "meh", but at the end, I was in tears of laughter! If you have Netflix, stop reading this review, and watch it immediately. It's on instant play. I highly, HIGHLY recommend it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A complete waste of film!!!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    2fresh 2clean
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/7/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie was horrible. It was the worst movie I have seen since How High. Quentin has definitely redeemed himself since he made this movie. It was amazing to see such big named actors such as Bruce Willis and Antonio Banderas in this movie. The only reason I can see why they decided to play in this film was to give a fresh starting Quentin Tarantino a chance. This movie stunk so bad I can still smell it even after I returned it to the video store. This movie just didn't do anything. It was boring and flat from start to finish. Please do not rent this movie. Spend your money on some gum or a coke. You'll definitely be spending your money on something more meaningful.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Unbelievably vacuous
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    David Frenkiel
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I registered to this site especially to warn the world: don't waste your time on this movie. It seems to be the result of overconfident Hollywood producers who figured that some critical mass of props, make up, "atmosphere", homages and mannerisms can create a masterpiece. Or at least a watchable feature film. The result is a collection of four pointless sequences (definitely not "stories"), only the third of which is mildly entertaining. I know that almost 20 years after its production, very few people will come across this movie. However, if my review can deter even one human from throwing away 90 minutes of his/her life, it's worth the effort. Oh, and in case you're a fan of the "colossal failure" genre - this thing is not colossal in any sense. It doesn't even deserve sarcasm. Just ignore it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Probably worth it for the Rodriguez and Tarantino segments
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    zetes
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    When I was in high school, anything Tarantino-related was required to be memorized. Yes, even this one was insisted upon in high school, though perhaps not as strongly as QT's first two. This portmanteau follows bellhop Tim Roth as he gets into several adventures over New Year's Eve. I remember liking this one quite a bit, but, viewing it now, it's just too uneven to be worthwhile. Anders' first segment is easily the low point, thankfully. Any film starring Madonna should be immediately suspect, and everything about this tale of witches is awful. Rockwell's segment is a bit of an improvement, but too forgettable. Rodriguez's segment is the one I remember being the best, and it thankfully does hold up okay. Antonio Banderas is hilarious in it, and most of the jokes hit. I remember QT's segment being the worst originally, but I actually thought it was by far the best this time around. It usually gets flack, I think, because it stars Tarantino, but he's comfortable here playing a pompous movie director. It's honestly his best performance (if it had been readily available, I might have suffered through Destiny Turns on the Radio again) and his direction is pretty brilliant. The one thing that really drags this whole movie down is Tim Roth. Man, I remember loving him when I was a teenager, and, though I criticized his performance in Reservoir Dogs above, he's on Olivier's level there compared to his awful mugging here. Even if QT's segment were the weakest, it would automatically be upgraded to the strongest just because he's the only one who settles Roth the crap down, a bit at least.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Loved it!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    niklas_austrheim
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie is a fantastic piece of work - I love the way four writers/directors have cooperated here. I will say though, that it starts with a let down. It increases in quality throughout the entire film, and the last segment, "The Man From Hollywood" is brilliant! Quentin Tarantino brings his characters to life unlike any other director, with his long shots and genius dialogue. The third segment, "The Misbehavers", is funny in another way, it holds a lot of the childish humor we can recognize from "Desperado" and the "Spy Kids"-franchise. The second installment is a very well-written piece of work, but gets overshadowed by what is yet to come. Tim Roth's performance is phenomenal, he dares to bring his acting to the very limit of what could be called "over-acting", but doesn't cross the line entirely, and it brings the movie a very eccentric energy. All together a very good film, and I would recommend all of you to watch it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Peculiar and sophisticated, but uneven coherence
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Bene Cumb
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    One should clearly admit that Rodriguez and Tarantino are better directors and screenwriters than the other two, episodes No 3 and 4 are much more "ripe" and interesting. No 3 by Rodriguez is probably the most stylish, Tarantino, on the other hand, is the master of intense, funny and smutty dialogs. Most of male performances are excellent, especially Roth and Banderas, Willis and Tarantino are outstanding as well. Unlike other similar films, female parts are quite dull and mediocre, the cast in the episode No 1 is rather poor. Awkward characters and witty scenes are still worth watching (total length less than 1,5 hours), although Four Rooms is not among the best films where Rodriguez and Tarantino have participated.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Decent Anthology
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    billcr12
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/7/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Four Rooms is an anthology by different directors, taking place on New Year's Eve at a hotel. The Missing Ingredient is the first one by Allison Anders. Ted, a bellhop, helps a group of strange women to the honeymoon suite, where they have a large cauldron in the middle of the room in order to brew a potion to summon a goddess. They each add something to the mix, until the last witch needs to find semen within an hour to complete the potion. She works on Ted for a donation. I liked this one and give it 8/10. The Wrong Man by Alexandre Rockwell places Ted in an awkward situation in the middle of a fight between a husband and wife. Ted is accused of a sexual encounter with the lady by her husband and after Ted escapes, another guest goes through the same insanity. So so, and a 5/10. The Misbehavers by Robert Rodriguez puts Ted in the position of babysitter for two little brats. Antonio Banderas and his wife leave their boy and girl in the room and pay Ted $500 to make sure that the children behave. The bellhop places them in front of a television, and when he returns, the girl has a bottle of champagne in her hand, the boy is smoking a cigarette, and the TV is on an adult channel. Rodriguez must have had some bad experiences with children to come up with this one. It is funny and a 7.5/10. The last and not least is by my favorite director, Quentin Tarantino, who plays a movie director(talk about typecasting) who is gathered with others who enjoy a good bet. The wager involves a guy being able to light a Zippo lighter ten times in a row. If he succeeds, he wins a car; if not, his pinky will be chopped off with an extremely sharp hatchet. Ted is drafted to be the executioner with the promise of $1,000. Though a quicky by Tarantino standards, it contains the expected darkness of the diabolical genius. An 8.5/10. The combined score is a 7.5 and a decent assembly of talent.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Interesting Concept That Bathes in a Sea of Cheese
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Sean Lamberger
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/5/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Tim Roth stars as a twitchy, maligned bellhop in this wacky anthology of four loosely-linked short films. With a different director behind the wheel for each chapter, it shouldn't come as much surprise to hear this is an uneven tale that never settles on a firm identity for itself. The underlying theme is light slapstick suspense with a vibrant collection of supporting players, but each act also has its share of dark secrets and sinister overtones. The first two portions are colorful, but too thin for my taste. It seems like both had a solid beginning and ending in mind, and only set about painting by numbers to bring the two together. It's Robert Rodriguez's third act and Quentin Tarantino's closer, though, that drew me to the show anyway. Both serve as bite-sized capsules of both the best and worst traits and habits that have come to define each director. Rodriguez's arc, which naturally features both Antonio Banderas and Salma Hayeck (albeit in short cameos) is a middle ground of sorts between Spy Kids and Planet Terror. It's part kid-focused mayhem and part pulpy, black, gross-out trauma; an enthusiastic, if shallow, ride. Tarantino's adventurous final chapter is more dialog driven, with the director (of course) playing the leading role. Like a caricature of himself, he spends a good ninety percent of the scene spewing pop culture references and jazzy one-liners before the whole drama culminates in a jolting, blunt burst of adrenaline. Overall, Four Rooms is a mixed bag, and apart from the Tarantino chapter, none of the acts stand up particularly well. While fans of the director will no doubt love Quentin's arc, it's short enough that it would probably be just as easily - and effectively - viewed on YouTube or Vimeo.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    ever building humor
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Patrick Mulligan
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/3/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Four Rooms is a slap stick four part tale of a Bell hop (Tim Roth) who encounters witches, crazed couples, trouble making kids, and drunken movie makers on new years eve at a once great Hollywood hotel. The brand of humor usually isn't up my alley, being very physical and less dialogue driven. But this movie still had me cracking me up. Each room is brought to you by way of a different director. Going in order you have Allison Anders, Alexandre Rockwell, Robert Rodriguez, and Quentin Tarantino. For me each segment was better than the last, Tarantino's being my favorite. I enjoyed watching the style change from scene to scene. I am not familiar with the work of the first two directors so there influence was less obvious to me than that of Rodriguez and Tarantino. Maybe that's why I enjoyed there scenes the most, but everyone is a little biased. Everything from writing to camera work shifts with the changing of directors. That is probably my favorite thing about Four Rooms. It's interesting to see Ted the bell hop interact with the different worlds painted for him by the directors. Even if your not into physical humor, you can get a certain amount of enjoyment just watching the camera change hands. But if you like feminist witches, marital problems refereed by revolvers, dead hookers, and wagers worth a little finger and a slick ride, this is a movie for you.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Terrible First Half, With a Pretty Good Second Half
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    DoctorKingSchultz
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I'll admit, I do have a bias towards Tarantino. I love the guy's stuff. Not a single one of his films do I dislike in the slightest. However, he has dabbled in some side projects that don't carry the full "Written and Directed by..." promise of, say Pulp Fiction or Kill Bill, that aren't the biggest successes. But for a single segment of the four that make up Four Rooms, we have Tarantino behind the pen, the camera, and in front of the screen! It's no coincidence that his segment is actually entertaining. But I'm ahead of myself. Let me review this piece by piece. The Missing Ingredient is both the opening chapter and the worst chapter. It's terrible. A group of witches (Real witches, apparently.) are trying to reincarnate their goddess, but require several specific items, the only of which they don't have is a man's sperm. I'm not joking. So, the witch who hasn't fulfilled her part must acquire her item within the hour. It sounds like the plot of a pornographic film. It's just stupid. The witch seduces Tim Roth's Ted the Bellhop, and some silly special effects later, she has her final item. I can't tell you how much I hated this. Not once during this chapter did I crack a smile, I was just hoping the next part was better. It is, but not substantially so. The Wrong Man is the second chapter. A little more interesting and far less ridiculous, Ted the Bellhop finds himself staring down the barrel of a revolver when he accidentally enters the wrong room when responding to a call. The chaos that comes from a mistaken identity ensues, and Ted is put between a man with a gun and his gagged wife. What I found to be one of the best quotes from the movie comes up here. Something about wearing a bonnet, I can't recall it right now. Though, I felt the situation was a little hard to follow here. Maybe I wasn't really paying attention, maybe it was supposed to be convoluted. Maybe it was because Tim Roth is delivering his lines in an angry whisper the entire time.Seriously, I like Timothy Roth, he's had some great roles in some great films, but god he chose the wrong role here. Ted the Bellhop is a flamboyant, fast-talking wreck. I couldn't understand him sometimes. Maybe that's what made the movie "funny" but I found it annoying. It was like watching the protagonist of a kid's movie trying to get laughs from children by acting silly, but surrounded by swearing and adult themes. With the third chapter, thing get better. Perhaps it's because it focuses less on Roth's silly character. The Misbehavers is directed and written by Robert Rodriguez. In this fun little short, a tough husband and his wife leave their children in their hotel room for the evening, hiring Ted to check up on them now and then. "Don't misbehave" he warns. The two kids are portrayed in a funny, childish way and their innocence leads to a gruesome discovery that I won't spoil here; it's one of the few parts worth not spoiling. Rodriguez really gives us this picture of a dysfunctional family headed by a strict father-figure (Who MAY or may not be a gangster!) And this chapter ends with a great scene. The moment I'm sure many had been waiting for was Quentin Tarantino's segment: The Man from Hollywood. QT stars in this segment as a drunk, rich movie star. He and his posse are drinking, having a good time. The alcohol in their system leads to them recreating a scene from a Hitchcock story where one of the men must light his lighter ten times in a row, or have his pinkie chopped off. It's really well played out here as the drunk trio of friends (And a character from a previous chapter.) move about their suite, throwing their money around like it's nothing. If you like Tarantino's writing, you'll like this segment. If not, you won't! It's classic Tarantino. Again, Roth is sort of put in the background, behind this intoxicated cast of characters. I think Roth was the problem with the movie, possibly. Or rather, Roth's character. So there. It's an interesting concept that, with four skilled directors, could have been phenomenal. But alas, the filmmakers who directed the first two chapters are unknown for a reason. I think I'd have to say Rodriguez's segment was the best. So, I give this a 6/10. Really, the second chapters are fun little shorts, and even the second one isn't all that bad. But the opening part is so unforgivable. It sets such a negative tone for the rest of the movie. And since these segments are all part of one film, they must be given a rating as one.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of the funniest movies ever!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Dylan Greenberg
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/7/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I saw this movie at 10, and loved it! Yesterday, I saw the movie again, and it was even funnier! Tim Roth was hysterically cartoonish in his movements, hand gestures, and facial expressions. He really stole the show. The Misbehavers was my favorite section of the four that make up the film. I also like the Easter Egg of the TV playing Bedhead in the background during that scene. As the movie progresses further, it gets funnier and funnier. In the beginning, it was like "meh", but at the end, I was in tears of laughter! If you have Netflix, stop reading this review, and watch it immediately. It's on instant play. I highly, HIGHLY recommend it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A complete waste of film!!!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    2fresh 2clean
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/7/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie was horrible. It was the worst movie I have seen since How High. Quentin has definitely redeemed himself since he made this movie. It was amazing to see such big named actors such as Bruce Willis and Antonio Banderas in this movie. The only reason I can see why they decided to play in this film was to give a fresh starting Quentin Tarantino a chance. This movie stunk so bad I can still smell it even after I returned it to the video store. This movie just didn't do anything. It was boring and flat from start to finish. Please do not rent this movie. Spend your money on some gum or a coke. You'll definitely be spending your money on something more meaningful.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
 </reviews>
</filme>
